<filme>
 <id>
  545
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0114825
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1995
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Um Vampiro no Brooklyn
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  4.3
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Maximillian is the only survivor from a race of vampires on a Caribbean Island, and as a vampire, he must find a mate to keep the line from ending. He knows that a child had been born to a ... &nbsp;&raquo;
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Maximillian is the only survivor from a race of vampires on a Caribbean Island, and as a vampire, he must find a mate to keep the line from ending. He knows that a child had been born to a woman who had a vampire father, and he searches for her in Brooklyn. Rita's mother, who has died in an asylum, was that woman and Rita has nightmares that she does not understand. Not knowing that she is part vampire, Max woos her and attempts to bring her to her blood sucking destiny. Even though Rita has strange dreams and actions, Justice, her partner, has feelings for her and does not want her involved with this stranger Max. But it is Rita who must decide her destiny.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Horror
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Romance
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   vampire
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   destiny
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   partner
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   blood
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   brooklyn bridge
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Wes Craven
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Eddie Murphy
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Vernon Lynch
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Eddie Murphy
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Angela Bassett
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Allen Payne
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Murphys' Most Underrated Movie ( next to Distinguished Gentelman)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Itsthatguyme
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    So many Bad Reviews for such a Good Movie. Folks are taking this movie waay too serious. Its a Horror COMEDY. I Repeat...COMEDY. Its Classic Eddie Murphy at his best. This movie was ahead of its time in a lot of ways. Think about it. Without me giving away anything.. The whole Ghoul ,Zombie bit in a Comedy had never been done to this point. Ground Breaking if u ask me.. Now its common place. Kadeem Hardison is hilarious in this. The timing with him a Murphy is so good. Murphy is one of the most Versatile actors we have and we don't truly appreciate his genius. Bassett is is Bassett. Always Strong.John Witherspoon is maybe the funniest guy ever. Good Casting overall. Allen Payne ehhhh..take em or leave em..either way. It has a Craven feel to it in a lot of parts..its equal parts Murphy and Craven. Well done. Why this movie gets Butchered so much is beyond me. Im thinking its the Setting and all Black Casting maybe? Its definitely more of an Urban feeling movie. Most people today likely cant relate to this old Black 90's Formula. Soo many good movies came out of that era. This one is right on par with them. a Classic, very original film for the time especially. EVIL is GOOD -Preacher Pauly
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Bottom of the Pit for Both the Star and Director
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Vampire in Brooklyn (1995) * (out of 4) They say sometimes great artists must hit an ultimate low before they can fully bounce back and that has never been more true for both director Wes Craven and star Eddie Murphy. In the film Murphy plays Maximillian, a Caribbean vampire who comes to Brooklyn in search of a woman to carry on his race. He finds the beautiful Rita (Angela Bassett) but his plan isn't going to be as simple as he thought. It's worth noting that Craven's next film was SCREAM and Murphy followed this up with THE NUTTY PROFESSOR so it's easy to see that both of them were just at the bottom of their careers here. The shocking thing revisiting this film for the first time since it was released is that it's actually gotten much, much worse. For the life of me I can't understand what the two were trying to do here but I'm guessing they wanted to take both of what they were great at and put it together but the end result is just a complete disaster. The comedy is so forced and uneven that it's never once funny. The horror elements are just so silly that they're never scary and when the gore does happen it just seems out of place. The entire film has a very ugly pacing and a lot of the blame has to go to Craven for not pulling the picture together but I'd still place more blame on Murphy, the producers, for hiring him. I'm not sure if Murphy and John Landis had a falling out on BEVERLY HILLS COP III but it's clear that he would have been much better with the (bad) material. The performances are all pretty weak with Murphy leading the way in an embarrassing piece of work. Allen Payne is wasted in his supporting role and Kadeem Hardison is just so in-your-face that the entire act just falls apart. VAMPIRE IN BROOKLYN is a perfect example of something that has talent but it just never came together for anything.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    How Stella got her Vamp back? Not really...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dcobbimdb
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Okay so heads up, this is a black / African American film, and for those who didn't know that initially (such as myself) and just went into it for a free vamp movie might / aught to know this. It's Stella got her Boomerang and at a low budget and that about sums it up... That said (and again I'm mentioning this as I saw it for free) honestly it kind of sucked far as a vamp movie goes. the whole premise is to get the main girl which IMHO is kind of retarded to begin with far as a vamp movie goes. At any rate the movie is quite lack luster in the action department as well as the general story and the Kobe Bryant look alike Allen Payne doesn't do it any more justice. It fails as a vamp movie and I don't care if it's trying to be sarcastic or not it really doesn't sell on any level. So here's my advice, the rating is as it deserves. If you're up late one night with nothing else to watch and a few too many in you, then feel free, I was in such a case and still found it a mess honestly. There are better things to waste two hours of your life on (like sleep), but that's just my opinion, you be the judge... If anything the movie is out of date, not due to special effects nor music as it really doesn't have any but for characters and if nothing else lack of anything good Eddie, I like what you've done in the past, but damn...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Murphy and Craven both try to win - the viewer is the loser.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    oneguyrambling
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A Vampire in Brooklyn suffers primarily due to four main factors: 1. / It is directed by Wes Craven, a successful horror director who truth be told has a track record that is extremely hit and miss. 2. / It stars Eddie Murphy, already on the downslope after a scintillating run of success in the 80s and early 90s. 3. / It sucks 4. / Apparently Wes and Ed wrestled for control of the film, arguing over whether it should be a horror with comedic elements, or a comedy with horror elements. Neither man won  or more accurately  both lost. The end result is a half-hearted (excuse the pun) effort with smatterings of everything and lots of nothing. A film that has no idea what it wants to be and how it might go about getting there. A film bereft of laughs, scares, and ultimately viewer interest. Murphy plays Maximillian, a smooth undead vampire from the West Indies who must come to Brooklyn for one reason, some vampire poontang that legend has it will help prolong his lifespan. Upon arriving in the city Maximillian enlists Julian (Kadeem Hardison) as his zombified yet still yappy go-fer ghoul. Their repartee is supposed to provide much of what passes as humour in the film, in truth it is merely a series of lamentable puns ("Put a little heart into it") and gross out sight gags that often seem out of place. Max's romantical target is an already half-vampire (due to some ancestral shenanigans) named Rita (Angela Bassett), a cop with a jealous partner named Justice (Allen Payne). Despite her instincts Rita finds herself drawn to this pimp looking pointy toothed sleaze merchant due to some unknown connection, but as the legend states that she must give herself to Max via dance the usual "Holla at ya' Boi" tactics aren't destined to work for Max. Cue the clumsy mix of bad horror, bad comedy and still more bad puns. The film uses the usual vampire rulebook of mirrors, sunlight, mist, crosses and garlic but awkwardly shoehorns jokes on the back of gore and vice versa. An overrated director and a fading comedian in a relationship doomed to failure, thankfully this genre confusing flop was their only offspring. A sequel was set up that thankfully never came, and Murphy fled back to more familiar territory of cop comedies (Metro) and fart gags (The Nutty Professor). Craven on the other hand started churning out Scream movies one after the other. Final Rating  4 / 10. Too little of one thing or the other ends up culminating in not much of anything. A big budget smear on Murphy's resume.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Put a little heart into it......
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Maximillian is the only survivor from a race of vampires on a Caribbean Island, and as a vampire, he must find a mate to keep the line from ending. He knows that a child had been born to a woman who had a vampire father, and he searches for her in Brooklyn. Rita's mother, who has died in an asylum, was that woman, and Rita has nightmares that she does not understand. Not knowing that she is part vampire, Max woos her and attempts to bring her to her blood sucking destiny.... The ironic thing about his dirge is that in the same year Craven and Murphy had the career resurgences that they both desperately needed. The big problem with this movie is that it cannot decide to be a horror,comedy or dark romance. And it fails on all three accounts. Murphy looks bored in his role, a cross between Blacula, Prince Akeem of Zamunda and a cachexic Barry White. The rest of the cast look wholly confused and put in risible performances. Hardison s the worse culprit, putting in a performance so hammy, you want to switch off wherever he appears (think Chris Tucker n anything, and your there). The first tn minutes, especially the boat heading toward the dock, is pure Craven and quite tense, but when Maximillian starts biting people, the whole movie fails on every account. It's a pity, because this movie had potential and it's aching to get out, but it's a dog of a movie, with only the beginning worth anything. Avoid.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A comedy/horror that fails to deliver much of either.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BA_Harrison
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Wes Craven is one of the most inconsistent directors in horror cinema: when on top form, he is a genius, taking risks with unpredictable projects and as a result, often giving the genre a much needed shot in the arm, as proved by groundbreaking movies like Last House On The Left, A Nightmare on Elm Street and Scream; at his least inspired, he is a hack, delivering predictably dumb (but still surprisingly enjoyable) trash like Shocker, Deadly Friend and Cursed. Vampire in Brooklyn is something of an oddity in Craven's erratic career: it's definitely not a predictable project for the directora comedy/horror featuring a predominantly black castbut it certainly is dumb. Written by Eddie Murphy (obviously having a bit of an off day), the script fails to deliver consistent laughs, and even some inspired imagery from Craven cannot prevent this one from being a somewhat disappointing title in the canon of both star and director. It's a shame, because Murphy can be hilarious and makes for a cool vampire, whilst we all know that Craven is capable of creating iconic scary moments; on this particular occasion, however, the magic just isn't there, and although the film cannot ever be accused of being dull, it is ultimately a forgettable flick that rabid Murphy fans might find enjoyable (the star hams it up to the max), but will probably only be of passing interest to horror fans. 5.5 out of 10, rounded up to 6 for IMDb.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Glorious entrance, embarrassing retreat
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Coventry
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/10/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I always deliberately avoided watching "Vampire in Brooklyn" because, quite frankly, the idea of a collaboration between horror-director Wes Craven and comedy-actor Eddie Murphy sounds about as appealing as going on a picnic trip with a tribe of cannibals You just don't do that! But hey, every horror movie eventually deserves a fair chance  especially when it airs on TV for free  and, who knows, maybe all your prejudices might be proved wrong. Of course your instincts and premonitions are rarely ever wrong, and "Vampire in Brooklyn" definitely isn't what one would call a good film, but at least the opening sequences mislead me into believing it actually could have become one! The opening is simply terrific and honestly deserves to be part of a different and much better horror movie. Eddie Murphy literally makes a great entrance in the horror genre, but then inevitably ruins it himself by exaggeratedly trying to showcase his "talents" as a comedian and a master of disguise. After a brief voice-over intro, explaining Maximillian is the last survivor of a breed of vampires that emigrated to the Bermuda triangle who now needs to go to Brooklyn in search for a half-vampire woman, we witness an immense and rudderless ghost-vessel entering the harbor and wildly crushing several yachts like they're ordinary paper boats. Marvellous intro, but unfortunately the film immediately goes downhill after that. The plot still shows a lot of potential, since the half-blood Maximillian finds is an emotionally troubled cop, but lame and totally unnecessary comical "sketches" continuously interrupt the tension and substantial coherence. The absolute low-points are two overlong and dull scenes with Eddie Murphy transforming into a whiny preacher and an Italian gangster in order to get closer to his muse. Also, and as expected, Murphy isn't the least bit impressive as the supposedly fierce and charismatic vampire. Maybe it's because you automatically associate his face with a series of comedy movies, but as a horror character he's just lousy. Kadeem Hardison provides a couple of noteworthy moments as the ghoul assistant in a constant state of decomposition, but also his rattling and swearing quickly becomes irritating. Wes Craven's style and usual trademarks are hardly ever noticeable and I suspect Eddie Murphy pretty much behaved like he pleased on the shooting. I'm generously rating "Vampire in Brooklyn" four out of ten, and most of these points go to the great opening and the indescribably beautiful Angela Bassett.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Blackula this is not
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ed_two_o_nine
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/7/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Why oh why, oh why? This film is bad, very bad indeed with little to no redeeming features. I have read that Wes Craven had real problems with Eddie Murphy on set and am prepared to cut him some slack for the films he had previously and subsequently made, as for Mr. Murphy this man had had enough chances he should not be allowed near a screen again (even 'Donkey' in wearing thin). This 'urban' take on the classic Dracula story is lame with Murphy hogging the screen and showing the acting subtlety of a nuclear missile. One wonders what the very talented Angela Basset must have been thinking during the production of this movie. The supporting cast are such run of the mill black stereotypes with nothing to flesh out their characters and Murphy really does not understand his role. Avoid this like the plague.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This movie bites!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Brian T. Whitlock (GOWBTW)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/2/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one Eddie Murphy movie that didn't get my goat. I've heard of "Blackula", this movie doesn't amuse me that well. You got some multiple characters there: There's this vampire from the Caribbean who was in a boat, that wiped out all the crew, and crashed somewhere in New York. This vampire goes to find a bride, who happens to be a cop(Angela Bassett). She's half-vampire. Kadeem Hardison from "A Different World" fame plays a servant, just like Dracula have only a little sillier. Some scenes in the movie were out of line, especially when the vampire came in form of a preacher. Just like all vampire lords, they go down the usual way, stake, sunlight, holy cross, or head cut off. Wes Craven gives this movie a try, since he's the horror master. However, this horror movie just didn't go for the jugular, it went for the funny bone. It didn't tickle mine though. Sorry! 1 out of 5 stars!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A horror comedy that's neither scary nor funny, a none starter really.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Paul Andrews (poolandrews@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Vampire in Brooklyn starts as a large boat crashes into a Brooklyn dock, on-board the whole crew are discovered murdered. They were murdered by Maximillian (Eddie Murphy) a Vampire from the Caribbean who happens to be the last of his kind & needs to mate with another Vampire & the closet thing left is half Vampire half human NYPD cop Detective Rita Veder (Angela Bassett) who doesn't yet know she's half Vampire, Maximillian has to convince her she is a Vampire & then to mate with her otherwise the Vampire race will die out... Directed by Wes Craven this is a romantic comedy horror with an almost entirely black cast that doesn't really work in any respect. The script by Charles Murphy (Eddie's brother), Michael Lucker & Chris Parker quite simply is a laugh free zone, hell I didn't even crack a smile during this. The film starts off very horror orientated then it becomes very comedic before romance takes over, none of these genres particularly go well together & the film feels very uneven, I suppose it moves along at a fair pace & the basic story is alright but it's a bit of a chore to sit through as nothing on screen works that well & a constant stream of profanity is not funny on it's own, is a very lazy way to write & starts to become annoying. The scene when Murphy impersonates the preacher is just plain embarrassing & I hated the ending as well. Director Craven had never made a comedy before & it show's as the comedy scenes just don't work, the horror & gore scenes are far more effective & it's a shame there's not more of them. By the time Craven teamed up with Murphy to make this both needed a hit after their careers both hit slumps, Vampire in Brooklyn was a poor choice of film although the story does have a happy ending as Craven went on to make the mega hit teen horror slasher Scream (1996) & Murphy made the successful children's comedy The Nutty Professor (1996) as their next films respectively. Angela Bassett's stunt double Sonya Davis died went a stunt went wrong where she was supposed to fall from a building onto an airbag but she actually hit her head on the solid ground. There's some gore here, there's a ripped out heart, various dead bodies with slit throats, some blood drinking & a stake through the heart although the special make-up effects on Murphy at the end look terrible. With a supposed budget of about $14,000,000 this had a decent amount of cash thrown at it, I don't think it flopped at the box-office but it didn't do that well either. It's well made with decent production values. The acting isn't that great & surprisingly Murphy is the only one who plays it straight which is very odd, Bassett is forgettable & Kadeem Hardison as the comedy relief ghoul is terrible. Vampire in Brooklyn is a horror film that isn't scary, a comedy that isn't funny & it's got a black cast directed by a white man brought in for his name & as a whole it just doesn't work on any level. One to avoid.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Murphys' Most Underrated Movie ( next to Distinguished Gentelman)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Itsthatguyme
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    So many Bad Reviews for such a Good Movie. Folks are taking this movie waay too serious. Its a Horror COMEDY. I Repeat...COMEDY. Its Classic Eddie Murphy at his best. This movie was ahead of its time in a lot of ways. Think about it. Without me giving away anything.. The whole Ghoul ,Zombie bit in a Comedy had never been done to this point. Ground Breaking if u ask me.. Now its common place. Kadeem Hardison is hilarious in this. The timing with him a Murphy is so good. Murphy is one of the most Versatile actors we have and we don't truly appreciate his genius. Bassett is is Bassett. Always Strong.John Witherspoon is maybe the funniest guy ever. Good Casting overall. Allen Payne ehhhh..take em or leave em..either way. It has a Craven feel to it in a lot of parts..its equal parts Murphy and Craven. Well done. Why this movie gets Butchered so much is beyond me. Im thinking its the Setting and all Black Casting maybe? Its definitely more of an Urban feeling movie. Most people today likely cant relate to this old Black 90's Formula. Soo many good movies came out of that era. This one is right on par with them. a Classic, very original film for the time especially. EVIL is GOOD -Preacher Pauly
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Bottom of the Pit for Both the Star and Director
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Vampire in Brooklyn (1995) * (out of 4) They say sometimes great artists must hit an ultimate low before they can fully bounce back and that has never been more true for both director Wes Craven and star Eddie Murphy. In the film Murphy plays Maximillian, a Caribbean vampire who comes to Brooklyn in search of a woman to carry on his race. He finds the beautiful Rita (Angela Bassett) but his plan isn't going to be as simple as he thought. It's worth noting that Craven's next film was SCREAM and Murphy followed this up with THE NUTTY PROFESSOR so it's easy to see that both of them were just at the bottom of their careers here. The shocking thing revisiting this film for the first time since it was released is that it's actually gotten much, much worse. For the life of me I can't understand what the two were trying to do here but I'm guessing they wanted to take both of what they were great at and put it together but the end result is just a complete disaster. The comedy is so forced and uneven that it's never once funny. The horror elements are just so silly that they're never scary and when the gore does happen it just seems out of place. The entire film has a very ugly pacing and a lot of the blame has to go to Craven for not pulling the picture together but I'd still place more blame on Murphy, the producers, for hiring him. I'm not sure if Murphy and John Landis had a falling out on BEVERLY HILLS COP III but it's clear that he would have been much better with the (bad) material. The performances are all pretty weak with Murphy leading the way in an embarrassing piece of work. Allen Payne is wasted in his supporting role and Kadeem Hardison is just so in-your-face that the entire act just falls apart. VAMPIRE IN BROOKLYN is a perfect example of something that has talent but it just never came together for anything.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    How Stella got her Vamp back? Not really...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dcobbimdb
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Okay so heads up, this is a black / African American film, and for those who didn't know that initially (such as myself) and just went into it for a free vamp movie might / aught to know this. It's Stella got her Boomerang and at a low budget and that about sums it up... That said (and again I'm mentioning this as I saw it for free) honestly it kind of sucked far as a vamp movie goes. the whole premise is to get the main girl which IMHO is kind of retarded to begin with far as a vamp movie goes. At any rate the movie is quite lack luster in the action department as well as the general story and the Kobe Bryant look alike Allen Payne doesn't do it any more justice. It fails as a vamp movie and I don't care if it's trying to be sarcastic or not it really doesn't sell on any level. So here's my advice, the rating is as it deserves. If you're up late one night with nothing else to watch and a few too many in you, then feel free, I was in such a case and still found it a mess honestly. There are better things to waste two hours of your life on (like sleep), but that's just my opinion, you be the judge... If anything the movie is out of date, not due to special effects nor music as it really doesn't have any but for characters and if nothing else lack of anything good Eddie, I like what you've done in the past, but damn...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Murphy and Craven both try to win - the viewer is the loser.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    oneguyrambling
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A Vampire in Brooklyn suffers primarily due to four main factors: 1. / It is directed by Wes Craven, a successful horror director who truth be told has a track record that is extremely hit and miss. 2. / It stars Eddie Murphy, already on the downslope after a scintillating run of success in the 80s and early 90s. 3. / It sucks 4. / Apparently Wes and Ed wrestled for control of the film, arguing over whether it should be a horror with comedic elements, or a comedy with horror elements. Neither man won  or more accurately  both lost. The end result is a half-hearted (excuse the pun) effort with smatterings of everything and lots of nothing. A film that has no idea what it wants to be and how it might go about getting there. A film bereft of laughs, scares, and ultimately viewer interest. Murphy plays Maximillian, a smooth undead vampire from the West Indies who must come to Brooklyn for one reason, some vampire poontang that legend has it will help prolong his lifespan. Upon arriving in the city Maximillian enlists Julian (Kadeem Hardison) as his zombified yet still yappy go-fer ghoul. Their repartee is supposed to provide much of what passes as humour in the film, in truth it is merely a series of lamentable puns ("Put a little heart into it") and gross out sight gags that often seem out of place. Max's romantical target is an already half-vampire (due to some ancestral shenanigans) named Rita (Angela Bassett), a cop with a jealous partner named Justice (Allen Payne). Despite her instincts Rita finds herself drawn to this pimp looking pointy toothed sleaze merchant due to some unknown connection, but as the legend states that she must give herself to Max via dance the usual "Holla at ya' Boi" tactics aren't destined to work for Max. Cue the clumsy mix of bad horror, bad comedy and still more bad puns. The film uses the usual vampire rulebook of mirrors, sunlight, mist, crosses and garlic but awkwardly shoehorns jokes on the back of gore and vice versa. An overrated director and a fading comedian in a relationship doomed to failure, thankfully this genre confusing flop was their only offspring. A sequel was set up that thankfully never came, and Murphy fled back to more familiar territory of cop comedies (Metro) and fart gags (The Nutty Professor). Craven on the other hand started churning out Scream movies one after the other. Final Rating  4 / 10. Too little of one thing or the other ends up culminating in not much of anything. A big budget smear on Murphy's resume.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Put a little heart into it......
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Maximillian is the only survivor from a race of vampires on a Caribbean Island, and as a vampire, he must find a mate to keep the line from ending. He knows that a child had been born to a woman who had a vampire father, and he searches for her in Brooklyn. Rita's mother, who has died in an asylum, was that woman, and Rita has nightmares that she does not understand. Not knowing that she is part vampire, Max woos her and attempts to bring her to her blood sucking destiny.... The ironic thing about his dirge is that in the same year Craven and Murphy had the career resurgences that they both desperately needed. The big problem with this movie is that it cannot decide to be a horror,comedy or dark romance. And it fails on all three accounts. Murphy looks bored in his role, a cross between Blacula, Prince Akeem of Zamunda and a cachexic Barry White. The rest of the cast look wholly confused and put in risible performances. Hardison s the worse culprit, putting in a performance so hammy, you want to switch off wherever he appears (think Chris Tucker n anything, and your there). The first tn minutes, especially the boat heading toward the dock, is pure Craven and quite tense, but when Maximillian starts biting people, the whole movie fails on every account. It's a pity, because this movie had potential and it's aching to get out, but it's a dog of a movie, with only the beginning worth anything. Avoid.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A comedy/horror that fails to deliver much of either.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BA_Harrison
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Wes Craven is one of the most inconsistent directors in horror cinema: when on top form, he is a genius, taking risks with unpredictable projects and as a result, often giving the genre a much needed shot in the arm, as proved by groundbreaking movies like Last House On The Left, A Nightmare on Elm Street and Scream; at his least inspired, he is a hack, delivering predictably dumb (but still surprisingly enjoyable) trash like Shocker, Deadly Friend and Cursed. Vampire in Brooklyn is something of an oddity in Craven's erratic career: it's definitely not a predictable project for the directora comedy/horror featuring a predominantly black castbut it certainly is dumb. Written by Eddie Murphy (obviously having a bit of an off day), the script fails to deliver consistent laughs, and even some inspired imagery from Craven cannot prevent this one from being a somewhat disappointing title in the canon of both star and director. It's a shame, because Murphy can be hilarious and makes for a cool vampire, whilst we all know that Craven is capable of creating iconic scary moments; on this particular occasion, however, the magic just isn't there, and although the film cannot ever be accused of being dull, it is ultimately a forgettable flick that rabid Murphy fans might find enjoyable (the star hams it up to the max), but will probably only be of passing interest to horror fans. 5.5 out of 10, rounded up to 6 for IMDb.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Glorious entrance, embarrassing retreat
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Coventry
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/10/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I always deliberately avoided watching "Vampire in Brooklyn" because, quite frankly, the idea of a collaboration between horror-director Wes Craven and comedy-actor Eddie Murphy sounds about as appealing as going on a picnic trip with a tribe of cannibals You just don't do that! But hey, every horror movie eventually deserves a fair chance  especially when it airs on TV for free  and, who knows, maybe all your prejudices might be proved wrong. Of course your instincts and premonitions are rarely ever wrong, and "Vampire in Brooklyn" definitely isn't what one would call a good film, but at least the opening sequences mislead me into believing it actually could have become one! The opening is simply terrific and honestly deserves to be part of a different and much better horror movie. Eddie Murphy literally makes a great entrance in the horror genre, but then inevitably ruins it himself by exaggeratedly trying to showcase his "talents" as a comedian and a master of disguise. After a brief voice-over intro, explaining Maximillian is the last survivor of a breed of vampires that emigrated to the Bermuda triangle who now needs to go to Brooklyn in search for a half-vampire woman, we witness an immense and rudderless ghost-vessel entering the harbor and wildly crushing several yachts like they're ordinary paper boats. Marvellous intro, but unfortunately the film immediately goes downhill after that. The plot still shows a lot of potential, since the half-blood Maximillian finds is an emotionally troubled cop, but lame and totally unnecessary comical "sketches" continuously interrupt the tension and substantial coherence. The absolute low-points are two overlong and dull scenes with Eddie Murphy transforming into a whiny preacher and an Italian gangster in order to get closer to his muse. Also, and as expected, Murphy isn't the least bit impressive as the supposedly fierce and charismatic vampire. Maybe it's because you automatically associate his face with a series of comedy movies, but as a horror character he's just lousy. Kadeem Hardison provides a couple of noteworthy moments as the ghoul assistant in a constant state of decomposition, but also his rattling and swearing quickly becomes irritating. Wes Craven's style and usual trademarks are hardly ever noticeable and I suspect Eddie Murphy pretty much behaved like he pleased on the shooting. I'm generously rating "Vampire in Brooklyn" four out of ten, and most of these points go to the great opening and the indescribably beautiful Angela Bassett.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Blackula this is not
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ed_two_o_nine
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/7/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Why oh why, oh why? This film is bad, very bad indeed with little to no redeeming features. I have read that Wes Craven had real problems with Eddie Murphy on set and am prepared to cut him some slack for the films he had previously and subsequently made, as for Mr. Murphy this man had had enough chances he should not be allowed near a screen again (even 'Donkey' in wearing thin). This 'urban' take on the classic Dracula story is lame with Murphy hogging the screen and showing the acting subtlety of a nuclear missile. One wonders what the very talented Angela Basset must have been thinking during the production of this movie. The supporting cast are such run of the mill black stereotypes with nothing to flesh out their characters and Murphy really does not understand his role. Avoid this like the plague.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This movie bites!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Brian T. Whitlock (GOWBTW)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/2/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one Eddie Murphy movie that didn't get my goat. I've heard of "Blackula", this movie doesn't amuse me that well. You got some multiple characters there: There's this vampire from the Caribbean who was in a boat, that wiped out all the crew, and crashed somewhere in New York. This vampire goes to find a bride, who happens to be a cop(Angela Bassett). She's half-vampire. Kadeem Hardison from "A Different World" fame plays a servant, just like Dracula have only a little sillier. Some scenes in the movie were out of line, especially when the vampire came in form of a preacher. Just like all vampire lords, they go down the usual way, stake, sunlight, holy cross, or head cut off. Wes Craven gives this movie a try, since he's the horror master. However, this horror movie just didn't go for the jugular, it went for the funny bone. It didn't tickle mine though. Sorry! 1 out of 5 stars!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A horror comedy that's neither scary nor funny, a none starter really.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Paul Andrews (poolandrews@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Vampire in Brooklyn starts as a large boat crashes into a Brooklyn dock, on-board the whole crew are discovered murdered. They were murdered by Maximillian (Eddie Murphy) a Vampire from the Caribbean who happens to be the last of his kind & needs to mate with another Vampire & the closet thing left is half Vampire half human NYPD cop Detective Rita Veder (Angela Bassett) who doesn't yet know she's half Vampire, Maximillian has to convince her she is a Vampire & then to mate with her otherwise the Vampire race will die out... Directed by Wes Craven this is a romantic comedy horror with an almost entirely black cast that doesn't really work in any respect. The script by Charles Murphy (Eddie's brother), Michael Lucker & Chris Parker quite simply is a laugh free zone, hell I didn't even crack a smile during this. The film starts off very horror orientated then it becomes very comedic before romance takes over, none of these genres particularly go well together & the film feels very uneven, I suppose it moves along at a fair pace & the basic story is alright but it's a bit of a chore to sit through as nothing on screen works that well & a constant stream of profanity is not funny on it's own, is a very lazy way to write & starts to become annoying. The scene when Murphy impersonates the preacher is just plain embarrassing & I hated the ending as well. Director Craven had never made a comedy before & it show's as the comedy scenes just don't work, the horror & gore scenes are far more effective & it's a shame there's not more of them. By the time Craven teamed up with Murphy to make this both needed a hit after their careers both hit slumps, Vampire in Brooklyn was a poor choice of film although the story does have a happy ending as Craven went on to make the mega hit teen horror slasher Scream (1996) & Murphy made the successful children's comedy The Nutty Professor (1996) as their next films respectively. Angela Bassett's stunt double Sonya Davis died went a stunt went wrong where she was supposed to fall from a building onto an airbag but she actually hit her head on the solid ground. There's some gore here, there's a ripped out heart, various dead bodies with slit throats, some blood drinking & a stake through the heart although the special make-up effects on Murphy at the end look terrible. With a supposed budget of about $14,000,000 this had a decent amount of cash thrown at it, I don't think it flopped at the box-office but it didn't do that well either. It's well made with decent production values. The acting isn't that great & surprisingly Murphy is the only one who plays it straight which is very odd, Bassett is forgettable & Kadeem Hardison as the comedy relief ghoul is terrible. Vampire in Brooklyn is a horror film that isn't scary, a comedy that isn't funny & it's got a black cast directed by a white man brought in for his name & as a whole it just doesn't work on any level. One to avoid.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Murphys' Most Underrated Movie ( next to Distinguished Gentelman)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Itsthatguyme
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    So many Bad Reviews for such a Good Movie. Folks are taking this movie waay too serious. Its a Horror COMEDY. I Repeat...COMEDY. Its Classic Eddie Murphy at his best. This movie was ahead of its time in a lot of ways. Think about it. Without me giving away anything.. The whole Ghoul ,Zombie bit in a Comedy had never been done to this point. Ground Breaking if u ask me.. Now its common place. Kadeem Hardison is hilarious in this. The timing with him a Murphy is so good. Murphy is one of the most Versatile actors we have and we don't truly appreciate his genius. Bassett is is Bassett. Always Strong.John Witherspoon is maybe the funniest guy ever. Good Casting overall. Allen Payne ehhhh..take em or leave em..either way. It has a Craven feel to it in a lot of parts..its equal parts Murphy and Craven. Well done. Why this movie gets Butchered so much is beyond me. Im thinking its the Setting and all Black Casting maybe? Its definitely more of an Urban feeling movie. Most people today likely cant relate to this old Black 90's Formula. Soo many good movies came out of that era. This one is right on par with them. a Classic, very original film for the time especially. EVIL is GOOD -Preacher Pauly
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Bottom of the Pit for Both the Star and Director
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Vampire in Brooklyn (1995) * (out of 4) They say sometimes great artists must hit an ultimate low before they can fully bounce back and that has never been more true for both director Wes Craven and star Eddie Murphy. In the film Murphy plays Maximillian, a Caribbean vampire who comes to Brooklyn in search of a woman to carry on his race. He finds the beautiful Rita (Angela Bassett) but his plan isn't going to be as simple as he thought. It's worth noting that Craven's next film was SCREAM and Murphy followed this up with THE NUTTY PROFESSOR so it's easy to see that both of them were just at the bottom of their careers here. The shocking thing revisiting this film for the first time since it was released is that it's actually gotten much, much worse. For the life of me I can't understand what the two were trying to do here but I'm guessing they wanted to take both of what they were great at and put it together but the end result is just a complete disaster. The comedy is so forced and uneven that it's never once funny. The horror elements are just so silly that they're never scary and when the gore does happen it just seems out of place. The entire film has a very ugly pacing and a lot of the blame has to go to Craven for not pulling the picture together but I'd still place more blame on Murphy, the producers, for hiring him. I'm not sure if Murphy and John Landis had a falling out on BEVERLY HILLS COP III but it's clear that he would have been much better with the (bad) material. The performances are all pretty weak with Murphy leading the way in an embarrassing piece of work. Allen Payne is wasted in his supporting role and Kadeem Hardison is just so in-your-face that the entire act just falls apart. VAMPIRE IN BROOKLYN is a perfect example of something that has talent but it just never came together for anything.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    How Stella got her Vamp back? Not really...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dcobbimdb
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Okay so heads up, this is a black / African American film, and for those who didn't know that initially (such as myself) and just went into it for a free vamp movie might / aught to know this. It's Stella got her Boomerang and at a low budget and that about sums it up... That said (and again I'm mentioning this as I saw it for free) honestly it kind of sucked far as a vamp movie goes. the whole premise is to get the main girl which IMHO is kind of retarded to begin with far as a vamp movie goes. At any rate the movie is quite lack luster in the action department as well as the general story and the Kobe Bryant look alike Allen Payne doesn't do it any more justice. It fails as a vamp movie and I don't care if it's trying to be sarcastic or not it really doesn't sell on any level. So here's my advice, the rating is as it deserves. If you're up late one night with nothing else to watch and a few too many in you, then feel free, I was in such a case and still found it a mess honestly. There are better things to waste two hours of your life on (like sleep), but that's just my opinion, you be the judge... If anything the movie is out of date, not due to special effects nor music as it really doesn't have any but for characters and if nothing else lack of anything good Eddie, I like what you've done in the past, but damn...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Murphy and Craven both try to win - the viewer is the loser.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    oneguyrambling
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A Vampire in Brooklyn suffers primarily due to four main factors: 1. / It is directed by Wes Craven, a successful horror director who truth be told has a track record that is extremely hit and miss. 2. / It stars Eddie Murphy, already on the downslope after a scintillating run of success in the 80s and early 90s. 3. / It sucks 4. / Apparently Wes and Ed wrestled for control of the film, arguing over whether it should be a horror with comedic elements, or a comedy with horror elements. Neither man won  or more accurately  both lost. The end result is a half-hearted (excuse the pun) effort with smatterings of everything and lots of nothing. A film that has no idea what it wants to be and how it might go about getting there. A film bereft of laughs, scares, and ultimately viewer interest. Murphy plays Maximillian, a smooth undead vampire from the West Indies who must come to Brooklyn for one reason, some vampire poontang that legend has it will help prolong his lifespan. Upon arriving in the city Maximillian enlists Julian (Kadeem Hardison) as his zombified yet still yappy go-fer ghoul. Their repartee is supposed to provide much of what passes as humour in the film, in truth it is merely a series of lamentable puns ("Put a little heart into it") and gross out sight gags that often seem out of place. Max's romantical target is an already half-vampire (due to some ancestral shenanigans) named Rita (Angela Bassett), a cop with a jealous partner named Justice (Allen Payne). Despite her instincts Rita finds herself drawn to this pimp looking pointy toothed sleaze merchant due to some unknown connection, but as the legend states that she must give herself to Max via dance the usual "Holla at ya' Boi" tactics aren't destined to work for Max. Cue the clumsy mix of bad horror, bad comedy and still more bad puns. The film uses the usual vampire rulebook of mirrors, sunlight, mist, crosses and garlic but awkwardly shoehorns jokes on the back of gore and vice versa. An overrated director and a fading comedian in a relationship doomed to failure, thankfully this genre confusing flop was their only offspring. A sequel was set up that thankfully never came, and Murphy fled back to more familiar territory of cop comedies (Metro) and fart gags (The Nutty Professor). Craven on the other hand started churning out Scream movies one after the other. Final Rating  4 / 10. Too little of one thing or the other ends up culminating in not much of anything. A big budget smear on Murphy's resume.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Put a little heart into it......
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Maximillian is the only survivor from a race of vampires on a Caribbean Island, and as a vampire, he must find a mate to keep the line from ending. He knows that a child had been born to a woman who had a vampire father, and he searches for her in Brooklyn. Rita's mother, who has died in an asylum, was that woman, and Rita has nightmares that she does not understand. Not knowing that she is part vampire, Max woos her and attempts to bring her to her blood sucking destiny.... The ironic thing about his dirge is that in the same year Craven and Murphy had the career resurgences that they both desperately needed. The big problem with this movie is that it cannot decide to be a horror,comedy or dark romance. And it fails on all three accounts. Murphy looks bored in his role, a cross between Blacula, Prince Akeem of Zamunda and a cachexic Barry White. The rest of the cast look wholly confused and put in risible performances. Hardison s the worse culprit, putting in a performance so hammy, you want to switch off wherever he appears (think Chris Tucker n anything, and your there). The first tn minutes, especially the boat heading toward the dock, is pure Craven and quite tense, but when Maximillian starts biting people, the whole movie fails on every account. It's a pity, because this movie had potential and it's aching to get out, but it's a dog of a movie, with only the beginning worth anything. Avoid.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A comedy/horror that fails to deliver much of either.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BA_Harrison
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Wes Craven is one of the most inconsistent directors in horror cinema: when on top form, he is a genius, taking risks with unpredictable projects and as a result, often giving the genre a much needed shot in the arm, as proved by groundbreaking movies like Last House On The Left, A Nightmare on Elm Street and Scream; at his least inspired, he is a hack, delivering predictably dumb (but still surprisingly enjoyable) trash like Shocker, Deadly Friend and Cursed. Vampire in Brooklyn is something of an oddity in Craven's erratic career: it's definitely not a predictable project for the directora comedy/horror featuring a predominantly black castbut it certainly is dumb. Written by Eddie Murphy (obviously having a bit of an off day), the script fails to deliver consistent laughs, and even some inspired imagery from Craven cannot prevent this one from being a somewhat disappointing title in the canon of both star and director. It's a shame, because Murphy can be hilarious and makes for a cool vampire, whilst we all know that Craven is capable of creating iconic scary moments; on this particular occasion, however, the magic just isn't there, and although the film cannot ever be accused of being dull, it is ultimately a forgettable flick that rabid Murphy fans might find enjoyable (the star hams it up to the max), but will probably only be of passing interest to horror fans. 5.5 out of 10, rounded up to 6 for IMDb.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Glorious entrance, embarrassing retreat
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Coventry
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/10/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I always deliberately avoided watching "Vampire in Brooklyn" because, quite frankly, the idea of a collaboration between horror-director Wes Craven and comedy-actor Eddie Murphy sounds about as appealing as going on a picnic trip with a tribe of cannibals You just don't do that! But hey, every horror movie eventually deserves a fair chance  especially when it airs on TV for free  and, who knows, maybe all your prejudices might be proved wrong. Of course your instincts and premonitions are rarely ever wrong, and "Vampire in Brooklyn" definitely isn't what one would call a good film, but at least the opening sequences mislead me into believing it actually could have become one! The opening is simply terrific and honestly deserves to be part of a different and much better horror movie. Eddie Murphy literally makes a great entrance in the horror genre, but then inevitably ruins it himself by exaggeratedly trying to showcase his "talents" as a comedian and a master of disguise. After a brief voice-over intro, explaining Maximillian is the last survivor of a breed of vampires that emigrated to the Bermuda triangle who now needs to go to Brooklyn in search for a half-vampire woman, we witness an immense and rudderless ghost-vessel entering the harbor and wildly crushing several yachts like they're ordinary paper boats. Marvellous intro, but unfortunately the film immediately goes downhill after that. The plot still shows a lot of potential, since the half-blood Maximillian finds is an emotionally troubled cop, but lame and totally unnecessary comical "sketches" continuously interrupt the tension and substantial coherence. The absolute low-points are two overlong and dull scenes with Eddie Murphy transforming into a whiny preacher and an Italian gangster in order to get closer to his muse. Also, and as expected, Murphy isn't the least bit impressive as the supposedly fierce and charismatic vampire. Maybe it's because you automatically associate his face with a series of comedy movies, but as a horror character he's just lousy. Kadeem Hardison provides a couple of noteworthy moments as the ghoul assistant in a constant state of decomposition, but also his rattling and swearing quickly becomes irritating. Wes Craven's style and usual trademarks are hardly ever noticeable and I suspect Eddie Murphy pretty much behaved like he pleased on the shooting. I'm generously rating "Vampire in Brooklyn" four out of ten, and most of these points go to the great opening and the indescribably beautiful Angela Bassett.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Blackula this is not
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ed_two_o_nine
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/7/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Why oh why, oh why? This film is bad, very bad indeed with little to no redeeming features. I have read that Wes Craven had real problems with Eddie Murphy on set and am prepared to cut him some slack for the films he had previously and subsequently made, as for Mr. Murphy this man had had enough chances he should not be allowed near a screen again (even 'Donkey' in wearing thin). This 'urban' take on the classic Dracula story is lame with Murphy hogging the screen and showing the acting subtlety of a nuclear missile. One wonders what the very talented Angela Basset must have been thinking during the production of this movie. The supporting cast are such run of the mill black stereotypes with nothing to flesh out their characters and Murphy really does not understand his role. Avoid this like the plague.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This movie bites!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Brian T. Whitlock (GOWBTW)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/2/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one Eddie Murphy movie that didn't get my goat. I've heard of "Blackula", this movie doesn't amuse me that well. You got some multiple characters there: There's this vampire from the Caribbean who was in a boat, that wiped out all the crew, and crashed somewhere in New York. This vampire goes to find a bride, who happens to be a cop(Angela Bassett). She's half-vampire. Kadeem Hardison from "A Different World" fame plays a servant, just like Dracula have only a little sillier. Some scenes in the movie were out of line, especially when the vampire came in form of a preacher. Just like all vampire lords, they go down the usual way, stake, sunlight, holy cross, or head cut off. Wes Craven gives this movie a try, since he's the horror master. However, this horror movie just didn't go for the jugular, it went for the funny bone. It didn't tickle mine though. Sorry! 1 out of 5 stars!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A horror comedy that's neither scary nor funny, a none starter really.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Paul Andrews (poolandrews@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Vampire in Brooklyn starts as a large boat crashes into a Brooklyn dock, on-board the whole crew are discovered murdered. They were murdered by Maximillian (Eddie Murphy) a Vampire from the Caribbean who happens to be the last of his kind & needs to mate with another Vampire & the closet thing left is half Vampire half human NYPD cop Detective Rita Veder (Angela Bassett) who doesn't yet know she's half Vampire, Maximillian has to convince her she is a Vampire & then to mate with her otherwise the Vampire race will die out... Directed by Wes Craven this is a romantic comedy horror with an almost entirely black cast that doesn't really work in any respect. The script by Charles Murphy (Eddie's brother), Michael Lucker & Chris Parker quite simply is a laugh free zone, hell I didn't even crack a smile during this. The film starts off very horror orientated then it becomes very comedic before romance takes over, none of these genres particularly go well together & the film feels very uneven, I suppose it moves along at a fair pace & the basic story is alright but it's a bit of a chore to sit through as nothing on screen works that well & a constant stream of profanity is not funny on it's own, is a very lazy way to write & starts to become annoying. The scene when Murphy impersonates the preacher is just plain embarrassing & I hated the ending as well. Director Craven had never made a comedy before & it show's as the comedy scenes just don't work, the horror & gore scenes are far more effective & it's a shame there's not more of them. By the time Craven teamed up with Murphy to make this both needed a hit after their careers both hit slumps, Vampire in Brooklyn was a poor choice of film although the story does have a happy ending as Craven went on to make the mega hit teen horror slasher Scream (1996) & Murphy made the successful children's comedy The Nutty Professor (1996) as their next films respectively. Angela Bassett's stunt double Sonya Davis died went a stunt went wrong where she was supposed to fall from a building onto an airbag but she actually hit her head on the solid ground. There's some gore here, there's a ripped out heart, various dead bodies with slit throats, some blood drinking & a stake through the heart although the special make-up effects on Murphy at the end look terrible. With a supposed budget of about $14,000,000 this had a decent amount of cash thrown at it, I don't think it flopped at the box-office but it didn't do that well either. It's well made with decent production values. The acting isn't that great & surprisingly Murphy is the only one who plays it straight which is very odd, Bassett is forgettable & Kadeem Hardison as the comedy relief ghoul is terrible. Vampire in Brooklyn is a horror film that isn't scary, a comedy that isn't funny & it's got a black cast directed by a white man brought in for his name & as a whole it just doesn't work on any level. One to avoid.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Murphys' Most Underrated Movie ( next to Distinguished Gentelman)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Itsthatguyme
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    So many Bad Reviews for such a Good Movie. Folks are taking this movie waay too serious. Its a Horror COMEDY. I Repeat...COMEDY. Its Classic Eddie Murphy at his best. This movie was ahead of its time in a lot of ways. Think about it. Without me giving away anything.. The whole Ghoul ,Zombie bit in a Comedy had never been done to this point. Ground Breaking if u ask me.. Now its common place. Kadeem Hardison is hilarious in this. The timing with him a Murphy is so good. Murphy is one of the most Versatile actors we have and we don't truly appreciate his genius. Bassett is is Bassett. Always Strong.John Witherspoon is maybe the funniest guy ever. Good Casting overall. Allen Payne ehhhh..take em or leave em..either way. It has a Craven feel to it in a lot of parts..its equal parts Murphy and Craven. Well done. Why this movie gets Butchered so much is beyond me. Im thinking its the Setting and all Black Casting maybe? Its definitely more of an Urban feeling movie. Most people today likely cant relate to this old Black 90's Formula. Soo many good movies came out of that era. This one is right on par with them. a Classic, very original film for the time especially. EVIL is GOOD -Preacher Pauly
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Bottom of the Pit for Both the Star and Director
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Vampire in Brooklyn (1995) * (out of 4) They say sometimes great artists must hit an ultimate low before they can fully bounce back and that has never been more true for both director Wes Craven and star Eddie Murphy. In the film Murphy plays Maximillian, a Caribbean vampire who comes to Brooklyn in search of a woman to carry on his race. He finds the beautiful Rita (Angela Bassett) but his plan isn't going to be as simple as he thought. It's worth noting that Craven's next film was SCREAM and Murphy followed this up with THE NUTTY PROFESSOR so it's easy to see that both of them were just at the bottom of their careers here. The shocking thing revisiting this film for the first time since it was released is that it's actually gotten much, much worse. For the life of me I can't understand what the two were trying to do here but I'm guessing they wanted to take both of what they were great at and put it together but the end result is just a complete disaster. The comedy is so forced and uneven that it's never once funny. The horror elements are just so silly that they're never scary and when the gore does happen it just seems out of place. The entire film has a very ugly pacing and a lot of the blame has to go to Craven for not pulling the picture together but I'd still place more blame on Murphy, the producers, for hiring him. I'm not sure if Murphy and John Landis had a falling out on BEVERLY HILLS COP III but it's clear that he would have been much better with the (bad) material. The performances are all pretty weak with Murphy leading the way in an embarrassing piece of work. Allen Payne is wasted in his supporting role and Kadeem Hardison is just so in-your-face that the entire act just falls apart. VAMPIRE IN BROOKLYN is a perfect example of something that has talent but it just never came together for anything.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    How Stella got her Vamp back? Not really...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dcobbimdb
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Okay so heads up, this is a black / African American film, and for those who didn't know that initially (such as myself) and just went into it for a free vamp movie might / aught to know this. It's Stella got her Boomerang and at a low budget and that about sums it up... That said (and again I'm mentioning this as I saw it for free) honestly it kind of sucked far as a vamp movie goes. the whole premise is to get the main girl which IMHO is kind of retarded to begin with far as a vamp movie goes. At any rate the movie is quite lack luster in the action department as well as the general story and the Kobe Bryant look alike Allen Payne doesn't do it any more justice. It fails as a vamp movie and I don't care if it's trying to be sarcastic or not it really doesn't sell on any level. So here's my advice, the rating is as it deserves. If you're up late one night with nothing else to watch and a few too many in you, then feel free, I was in such a case and still found it a mess honestly. There are better things to waste two hours of your life on (like sleep), but that's just my opinion, you be the judge... If anything the movie is out of date, not due to special effects nor music as it really doesn't have any but for characters and if nothing else lack of anything good Eddie, I like what you've done in the past, but damn...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Murphy and Craven both try to win - the viewer is the loser.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    oneguyrambling
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A Vampire in Brooklyn suffers primarily due to four main factors: 1. / It is directed by Wes Craven, a successful horror director who truth be told has a track record that is extremely hit and miss. 2. / It stars Eddie Murphy, already on the downslope after a scintillating run of success in the 80s and early 90s. 3. / It sucks 4. / Apparently Wes and Ed wrestled for control of the film, arguing over whether it should be a horror with comedic elements, or a comedy with horror elements. Neither man won  or more accurately  both lost. The end result is a half-hearted (excuse the pun) effort with smatterings of everything and lots of nothing. A film that has no idea what it wants to be and how it might go about getting there. A film bereft of laughs, scares, and ultimately viewer interest. Murphy plays Maximillian, a smooth undead vampire from the West Indies who must come to Brooklyn for one reason, some vampire poontang that legend has it will help prolong his lifespan. Upon arriving in the city Maximillian enlists Julian (Kadeem Hardison) as his zombified yet still yappy go-fer ghoul. Their repartee is supposed to provide much of what passes as humour in the film, in truth it is merely a series of lamentable puns ("Put a little heart into it") and gross out sight gags that often seem out of place. Max's romantical target is an already half-vampire (due to some ancestral shenanigans) named Rita (Angela Bassett), a cop with a jealous partner named Justice (Allen Payne). Despite her instincts Rita finds herself drawn to this pimp looking pointy toothed sleaze merchant due to some unknown connection, but as the legend states that she must give herself to Max via dance the usual "Holla at ya' Boi" tactics aren't destined to work for Max. Cue the clumsy mix of bad horror, bad comedy and still more bad puns. The film uses the usual vampire rulebook of mirrors, sunlight, mist, crosses and garlic but awkwardly shoehorns jokes on the back of gore and vice versa. An overrated director and a fading comedian in a relationship doomed to failure, thankfully this genre confusing flop was their only offspring. A sequel was set up that thankfully never came, and Murphy fled back to more familiar territory of cop comedies (Metro) and fart gags (The Nutty Professor). Craven on the other hand started churning out Scream movies one after the other. Final Rating  4 / 10. Too little of one thing or the other ends up culminating in not much of anything. A big budget smear on Murphy's resume.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Put a little heart into it......
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Maximillian is the only survivor from a race of vampires on a Caribbean Island, and as a vampire, he must find a mate to keep the line from ending. He knows that a child had been born to a woman who had a vampire father, and he searches for her in Brooklyn. Rita's mother, who has died in an asylum, was that woman, and Rita has nightmares that she does not understand. Not knowing that she is part vampire, Max woos her and attempts to bring her to her blood sucking destiny.... The ironic thing about his dirge is that in the same year Craven and Murphy had the career resurgences that they both desperately needed. The big problem with this movie is that it cannot decide to be a horror,comedy or dark romance. And it fails on all three accounts. Murphy looks bored in his role, a cross between Blacula, Prince Akeem of Zamunda and a cachexic Barry White. The rest of the cast look wholly confused and put in risible performances. Hardison s the worse culprit, putting in a performance so hammy, you want to switch off wherever he appears (think Chris Tucker n anything, and your there). The first tn minutes, especially the boat heading toward the dock, is pure Craven and quite tense, but when Maximillian starts biting people, the whole movie fails on every account. It's a pity, because this movie had potential and it's aching to get out, but it's a dog of a movie, with only the beginning worth anything. Avoid.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A comedy/horror that fails to deliver much of either.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BA_Harrison
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Wes Craven is one of the most inconsistent directors in horror cinema: when on top form, he is a genius, taking risks with unpredictable projects and as a result, often giving the genre a much needed shot in the arm, as proved by groundbreaking movies like Last House On The Left, A Nightmare on Elm Street and Scream; at his least inspired, he is a hack, delivering predictably dumb (but still surprisingly enjoyable) trash like Shocker, Deadly Friend and Cursed. Vampire in Brooklyn is something of an oddity in Craven's erratic career: it's definitely not a predictable project for the directora comedy/horror featuring a predominantly black castbut it certainly is dumb. Written by Eddie Murphy (obviously having a bit of an off day), the script fails to deliver consistent laughs, and even some inspired imagery from Craven cannot prevent this one from being a somewhat disappointing title in the canon of both star and director. It's a shame, because Murphy can be hilarious and makes for a cool vampire, whilst we all know that Craven is capable of creating iconic scary moments; on this particular occasion, however, the magic just isn't there, and although the film cannot ever be accused of being dull, it is ultimately a forgettable flick that rabid Murphy fans might find enjoyable (the star hams it up to the max), but will probably only be of passing interest to horror fans. 5.5 out of 10, rounded up to 6 for IMDb.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Glorious entrance, embarrassing retreat
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Coventry
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/10/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I always deliberately avoided watching "Vampire in Brooklyn" because, quite frankly, the idea of a collaboration between horror-director Wes Craven and comedy-actor Eddie Murphy sounds about as appealing as going on a picnic trip with a tribe of cannibals You just don't do that! But hey, every horror movie eventually deserves a fair chance  especially when it airs on TV for free  and, who knows, maybe all your prejudices might be proved wrong. Of course your instincts and premonitions are rarely ever wrong, and "Vampire in Brooklyn" definitely isn't what one would call a good film, but at least the opening sequences mislead me into believing it actually could have become one! The opening is simply terrific and honestly deserves to be part of a different and much better horror movie. Eddie Murphy literally makes a great entrance in the horror genre, but then inevitably ruins it himself by exaggeratedly trying to showcase his "talents" as a comedian and a master of disguise. After a brief voice-over intro, explaining Maximillian is the last survivor of a breed of vampires that emigrated to the Bermuda triangle who now needs to go to Brooklyn in search for a half-vampire woman, we witness an immense and rudderless ghost-vessel entering the harbor and wildly crushing several yachts like they're ordinary paper boats. Marvellous intro, but unfortunately the film immediately goes downhill after that. The plot still shows a lot of potential, since the half-blood Maximillian finds is an emotionally troubled cop, but lame and totally unnecessary comical "sketches" continuously interrupt the tension and substantial coherence. The absolute low-points are two overlong and dull scenes with Eddie Murphy transforming into a whiny preacher and an Italian gangster in order to get closer to his muse. Also, and as expected, Murphy isn't the least bit impressive as the supposedly fierce and charismatic vampire. Maybe it's because you automatically associate his face with a series of comedy movies, but as a horror character he's just lousy. Kadeem Hardison provides a couple of noteworthy moments as the ghoul assistant in a constant state of decomposition, but also his rattling and swearing quickly becomes irritating. Wes Craven's style and usual trademarks are hardly ever noticeable and I suspect Eddie Murphy pretty much behaved like he pleased on the shooting. I'm generously rating "Vampire in Brooklyn" four out of ten, and most of these points go to the great opening and the indescribably beautiful Angela Bassett.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Blackula this is not
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ed_two_o_nine
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/7/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Why oh why, oh why? This film is bad, very bad indeed with little to no redeeming features. I have read that Wes Craven had real problems with Eddie Murphy on set and am prepared to cut him some slack for the films he had previously and subsequently made, as for Mr. Murphy this man had had enough chances he should not be allowed near a screen again (even 'Donkey' in wearing thin). This 'urban' take on the classic Dracula story is lame with Murphy hogging the screen and showing the acting subtlety of a nuclear missile. One wonders what the very talented Angela Basset must have been thinking during the production of this movie. The supporting cast are such run of the mill black stereotypes with nothing to flesh out their characters and Murphy really does not understand his role. Avoid this like the plague.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This movie bites!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Brian T. Whitlock (GOWBTW)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/2/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one Eddie Murphy movie that didn't get my goat. I've heard of "Blackula", this movie doesn't amuse me that well. You got some multiple characters there: There's this vampire from the Caribbean who was in a boat, that wiped out all the crew, and crashed somewhere in New York. This vampire goes to find a bride, who happens to be a cop(Angela Bassett). She's half-vampire. Kadeem Hardison from "A Different World" fame plays a servant, just like Dracula have only a little sillier. Some scenes in the movie were out of line, especially when the vampire came in form of a preacher. Just like all vampire lords, they go down the usual way, stake, sunlight, holy cross, or head cut off. Wes Craven gives this movie a try, since he's the horror master. However, this horror movie just didn't go for the jugular, it went for the funny bone. It didn't tickle mine though. Sorry! 1 out of 5 stars!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A horror comedy that's neither scary nor funny, a none starter really.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Paul Andrews (poolandrews@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Vampire in Brooklyn starts as a large boat crashes into a Brooklyn dock, on-board the whole crew are discovered murdered. They were murdered by Maximillian (Eddie Murphy) a Vampire from the Caribbean who happens to be the last of his kind & needs to mate with another Vampire & the closet thing left is half Vampire half human NYPD cop Detective Rita Veder (Angela Bassett) who doesn't yet know she's half Vampire, Maximillian has to convince her she is a Vampire & then to mate with her otherwise the Vampire race will die out... Directed by Wes Craven this is a romantic comedy horror with an almost entirely black cast that doesn't really work in any respect. The script by Charles Murphy (Eddie's brother), Michael Lucker & Chris Parker quite simply is a laugh free zone, hell I didn't even crack a smile during this. The film starts off very horror orientated then it becomes very comedic before romance takes over, none of these genres particularly go well together & the film feels very uneven, I suppose it moves along at a fair pace & the basic story is alright but it's a bit of a chore to sit through as nothing on screen works that well & a constant stream of profanity is not funny on it's own, is a very lazy way to write & starts to become annoying. The scene when Murphy impersonates the preacher is just plain embarrassing & I hated the ending as well. Director Craven had never made a comedy before & it show's as the comedy scenes just don't work, the horror & gore scenes are far more effective & it's a shame there's not more of them. By the time Craven teamed up with Murphy to make this both needed a hit after their careers both hit slumps, Vampire in Brooklyn was a poor choice of film although the story does have a happy ending as Craven went on to make the mega hit teen horror slasher Scream (1996) & Murphy made the successful children's comedy The Nutty Professor (1996) as their next films respectively. Angela Bassett's stunt double Sonya Davis died went a stunt went wrong where she was supposed to fall from a building onto an airbag but she actually hit her head on the solid ground. There's some gore here, there's a ripped out heart, various dead bodies with slit throats, some blood drinking & a stake through the heart although the special make-up effects on Murphy at the end look terrible. With a supposed budget of about $14,000,000 this had a decent amount of cash thrown at it, I don't think it flopped at the box-office but it didn't do that well either. It's well made with decent production values. The acting isn't that great & surprisingly Murphy is the only one who plays it straight which is very odd, Bassett is forgettable & Kadeem Hardison as the comedy relief ghoul is terrible. Vampire in Brooklyn is a horror film that isn't scary, a comedy that isn't funny & it's got a black cast directed by a white man brought in for his name & as a whole it just doesn't work on any level. One to avoid.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Murphys' Most Underrated Movie ( next to Distinguished Gentelman)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Itsthatguyme
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    So many Bad Reviews for such a Good Movie. Folks are taking this movie waay too serious. Its a Horror COMEDY. I Repeat...COMEDY. Its Classic Eddie Murphy at his best. This movie was ahead of its time in a lot of ways. Think about it. Without me giving away anything.. The whole Ghoul ,Zombie bit in a Comedy had never been done to this point. Ground Breaking if u ask me.. Now its common place. Kadeem Hardison is hilarious in this. The timing with him a Murphy is so good. Murphy is one of the most Versatile actors we have and we don't truly appreciate his genius. Bassett is is Bassett. Always Strong.John Witherspoon is maybe the funniest guy ever. Good Casting overall. Allen Payne ehhhh..take em or leave em..either way. It has a Craven feel to it in a lot of parts..its equal parts Murphy and Craven. Well done. Why this movie gets Butchered so much is beyond me. Im thinking its the Setting and all Black Casting maybe? Its definitely more of an Urban feeling movie. Most people today likely cant relate to this old Black 90's Formula. Soo many good movies came out of that era. This one is right on par with them. a Classic, very original film for the time especially. EVIL is GOOD -Preacher Pauly
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Bottom of the Pit for Both the Star and Director
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Vampire in Brooklyn (1995) * (out of 4) They say sometimes great artists must hit an ultimate low before they can fully bounce back and that has never been more true for both director Wes Craven and star Eddie Murphy. In the film Murphy plays Maximillian, a Caribbean vampire who comes to Brooklyn in search of a woman to carry on his race. He finds the beautiful Rita (Angela Bassett) but his plan isn't going to be as simple as he thought. It's worth noting that Craven's next film was SCREAM and Murphy followed this up with THE NUTTY PROFESSOR so it's easy to see that both of them were just at the bottom of their careers here. The shocking thing revisiting this film for the first time since it was released is that it's actually gotten much, much worse. For the life of me I can't understand what the two were trying to do here but I'm guessing they wanted to take both of what they were great at and put it together but the end result is just a complete disaster. The comedy is so forced and uneven that it's never once funny. The horror elements are just so silly that they're never scary and when the gore does happen it just seems out of place. The entire film has a very ugly pacing and a lot of the blame has to go to Craven for not pulling the picture together but I'd still place more blame on Murphy, the producers, for hiring him. I'm not sure if Murphy and John Landis had a falling out on BEVERLY HILLS COP III but it's clear that he would have been much better with the (bad) material. The performances are all pretty weak with Murphy leading the way in an embarrassing piece of work. Allen Payne is wasted in his supporting role and Kadeem Hardison is just so in-your-face that the entire act just falls apart. VAMPIRE IN BROOKLYN is a perfect example of something that has talent but it just never came together for anything.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    How Stella got her Vamp back? Not really...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dcobbimdb
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Okay so heads up, this is a black / African American film, and for those who didn't know that initially (such as myself) and just went into it for a free vamp movie might / aught to know this. It's Stella got her Boomerang and at a low budget and that about sums it up... That said (and again I'm mentioning this as I saw it for free) honestly it kind of sucked far as a vamp movie goes. the whole premise is to get the main girl which IMHO is kind of retarded to begin with far as a vamp movie goes. At any rate the movie is quite lack luster in the action department as well as the general story and the Kobe Bryant look alike Allen Payne doesn't do it any more justice. It fails as a vamp movie and I don't care if it's trying to be sarcastic or not it really doesn't sell on any level. So here's my advice, the rating is as it deserves. If you're up late one night with nothing else to watch and a few too many in you, then feel free, I was in such a case and still found it a mess honestly. There are better things to waste two hours of your life on (like sleep), but that's just my opinion, you be the judge... If anything the movie is out of date, not due to special effects nor music as it really doesn't have any but for characters and if nothing else lack of anything good Eddie, I like what you've done in the past, but damn...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Murphy and Craven both try to win - the viewer is the loser.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    oneguyrambling
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A Vampire in Brooklyn suffers primarily due to four main factors: 1. / It is directed by Wes Craven, a successful horror director who truth be told has a track record that is extremely hit and miss. 2. / It stars Eddie Murphy, already on the downslope after a scintillating run of success in the 80s and early 90s. 3. / It sucks 4. / Apparently Wes and Ed wrestled for control of the film, arguing over whether it should be a horror with comedic elements, or a comedy with horror elements. Neither man won  or more accurately  both lost. The end result is a half-hearted (excuse the pun) effort with smatterings of everything and lots of nothing. A film that has no idea what it wants to be and how it might go about getting there. A film bereft of laughs, scares, and ultimately viewer interest. Murphy plays Maximillian, a smooth undead vampire from the West Indies who must come to Brooklyn for one reason, some vampire poontang that legend has it will help prolong his lifespan. Upon arriving in the city Maximillian enlists Julian (Kadeem Hardison) as his zombified yet still yappy go-fer ghoul. Their repartee is supposed to provide much of what passes as humour in the film, in truth it is merely a series of lamentable puns ("Put a little heart into it") and gross out sight gags that often seem out of place. Max's romantical target is an already half-vampire (due to some ancestral shenanigans) named Rita (Angela Bassett), a cop with a jealous partner named Justice (Allen Payne). Despite her instincts Rita finds herself drawn to this pimp looking pointy toothed sleaze merchant due to some unknown connection, but as the legend states that she must give herself to Max via dance the usual "Holla at ya' Boi" tactics aren't destined to work for Max. Cue the clumsy mix of bad horror, bad comedy and still more bad puns. The film uses the usual vampire rulebook of mirrors, sunlight, mist, crosses and garlic but awkwardly shoehorns jokes on the back of gore and vice versa. An overrated director and a fading comedian in a relationship doomed to failure, thankfully this genre confusing flop was their only offspring. A sequel was set up that thankfully never came, and Murphy fled back to more familiar territory of cop comedies (Metro) and fart gags (The Nutty Professor). Craven on the other hand started churning out Scream movies one after the other. Final Rating  4 / 10. Too little of one thing or the other ends up culminating in not much of anything. A big budget smear on Murphy's resume.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Put a little heart into it......
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Maximillian is the only survivor from a race of vampires on a Caribbean Island, and as a vampire, he must find a mate to keep the line from ending. He knows that a child had been born to a woman who had a vampire father, and he searches for her in Brooklyn. Rita's mother, who has died in an asylum, was that woman, and Rita has nightmares that she does not understand. Not knowing that she is part vampire, Max woos her and attempts to bring her to her blood sucking destiny.... The ironic thing about his dirge is that in the same year Craven and Murphy had the career resurgences that they both desperately needed. The big problem with this movie is that it cannot decide to be a horror,comedy or dark romance. And it fails on all three accounts. Murphy looks bored in his role, a cross between Blacula, Prince Akeem of Zamunda and a cachexic Barry White. The rest of the cast look wholly confused and put in risible performances. Hardison s the worse culprit, putting in a performance so hammy, you want to switch off wherever he appears (think Chris Tucker n anything, and your there). The first tn minutes, especially the boat heading toward the dock, is pure Craven and quite tense, but when Maximillian starts biting people, the whole movie fails on every account. It's a pity, because this movie had potential and it's aching to get out, but it's a dog of a movie, with only the beginning worth anything. Avoid.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A comedy/horror that fails to deliver much of either.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BA_Harrison
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Wes Craven is one of the most inconsistent directors in horror cinema: when on top form, he is a genius, taking risks with unpredictable projects and as a result, often giving the genre a much needed shot in the arm, as proved by groundbreaking movies like Last House On The Left, A Nightmare on Elm Street and Scream; at his least inspired, he is a hack, delivering predictably dumb (but still surprisingly enjoyable) trash like Shocker, Deadly Friend and Cursed. Vampire in Brooklyn is something of an oddity in Craven's erratic career: it's definitely not a predictable project for the directora comedy/horror featuring a predominantly black castbut it certainly is dumb. Written by Eddie Murphy (obviously having a bit of an off day), the script fails to deliver consistent laughs, and even some inspired imagery from Craven cannot prevent this one from being a somewhat disappointing title in the canon of both star and director. It's a shame, because Murphy can be hilarious and makes for a cool vampire, whilst we all know that Craven is capable of creating iconic scary moments; on this particular occasion, however, the magic just isn't there, and although the film cannot ever be accused of being dull, it is ultimately a forgettable flick that rabid Murphy fans might find enjoyable (the star hams it up to the max), but will probably only be of passing interest to horror fans. 5.5 out of 10, rounded up to 6 for IMDb.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Glorious entrance, embarrassing retreat
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Coventry
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/10/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I always deliberately avoided watching "Vampire in Brooklyn" because, quite frankly, the idea of a collaboration between horror-director Wes Craven and comedy-actor Eddie Murphy sounds about as appealing as going on a picnic trip with a tribe of cannibals You just don't do that! But hey, every horror movie eventually deserves a fair chance  especially when it airs on TV for free  and, who knows, maybe all your prejudices might be proved wrong. Of course your instincts and premonitions are rarely ever wrong, and "Vampire in Brooklyn" definitely isn't what one would call a good film, but at least the opening sequences mislead me into believing it actually could have become one! The opening is simply terrific and honestly deserves to be part of a different and much better horror movie. Eddie Murphy literally makes a great entrance in the horror genre, but then inevitably ruins it himself by exaggeratedly trying to showcase his "talents" as a comedian and a master of disguise. After a brief voice-over intro, explaining Maximillian is the last survivor of a breed of vampires that emigrated to the Bermuda triangle who now needs to go to Brooklyn in search for a half-vampire woman, we witness an immense and rudderless ghost-vessel entering the harbor and wildly crushing several yachts like they're ordinary paper boats. Marvellous intro, but unfortunately the film immediately goes downhill after that. The plot still shows a lot of potential, since the half-blood Maximillian finds is an emotionally troubled cop, but lame and totally unnecessary comical "sketches" continuously interrupt the tension and substantial coherence. The absolute low-points are two overlong and dull scenes with Eddie Murphy transforming into a whiny preacher and an Italian gangster in order to get closer to his muse. Also, and as expected, Murphy isn't the least bit impressive as the supposedly fierce and charismatic vampire. Maybe it's because you automatically associate his face with a series of comedy movies, but as a horror character he's just lousy. Kadeem Hardison provides a couple of noteworthy moments as the ghoul assistant in a constant state of decomposition, but also his rattling and swearing quickly becomes irritating. Wes Craven's style and usual trademarks are hardly ever noticeable and I suspect Eddie Murphy pretty much behaved like he pleased on the shooting. I'm generously rating "Vampire in Brooklyn" four out of ten, and most of these points go to the great opening and the indescribably beautiful Angela Bassett.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Blackula this is not
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ed_two_o_nine
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/7/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Why oh why, oh why? This film is bad, very bad indeed with little to no redeeming features. I have read that Wes Craven had real problems with Eddie Murphy on set and am prepared to cut him some slack for the films he had previously and subsequently made, as for Mr. Murphy this man had had enough chances he should not be allowed near a screen again (even 'Donkey' in wearing thin). This 'urban' take on the classic Dracula story is lame with Murphy hogging the screen and showing the acting subtlety of a nuclear missile. One wonders what the very talented Angela Basset must have been thinking during the production of this movie. The supporting cast are such run of the mill black stereotypes with nothing to flesh out their characters and Murphy really does not understand his role. Avoid this like the plague.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This movie bites!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Brian T. Whitlock (GOWBTW)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/2/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one Eddie Murphy movie that didn't get my goat. I've heard of "Blackula", this movie doesn't amuse me that well. You got some multiple characters there: There's this vampire from the Caribbean who was in a boat, that wiped out all the crew, and crashed somewhere in New York. This vampire goes to find a bride, who happens to be a cop(Angela Bassett). She's half-vampire. Kadeem Hardison from "A Different World" fame plays a servant, just like Dracula have only a little sillier. Some scenes in the movie were out of line, especially when the vampire came in form of a preacher. Just like all vampire lords, they go down the usual way, stake, sunlight, holy cross, or head cut off. Wes Craven gives this movie a try, since he's the horror master. However, this horror movie just didn't go for the jugular, it went for the funny bone. It didn't tickle mine though. Sorry! 1 out of 5 stars!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A horror comedy that's neither scary nor funny, a none starter really.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Paul Andrews (poolandrews@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Vampire in Brooklyn starts as a large boat crashes into a Brooklyn dock, on-board the whole crew are discovered murdered. They were murdered by Maximillian (Eddie Murphy) a Vampire from the Caribbean who happens to be the last of his kind & needs to mate with another Vampire & the closet thing left is half Vampire half human NYPD cop Detective Rita Veder (Angela Bassett) who doesn't yet know she's half Vampire, Maximillian has to convince her she is a Vampire & then to mate with her otherwise the Vampire race will die out... Directed by Wes Craven this is a romantic comedy horror with an almost entirely black cast that doesn't really work in any respect. The script by Charles Murphy (Eddie's brother), Michael Lucker & Chris Parker quite simply is a laugh free zone, hell I didn't even crack a smile during this. The film starts off very horror orientated then it becomes very comedic before romance takes over, none of these genres particularly go well together & the film feels very uneven, I suppose it moves along at a fair pace & the basic story is alright but it's a bit of a chore to sit through as nothing on screen works that well & a constant stream of profanity is not funny on it's own, is a very lazy way to write & starts to become annoying. The scene when Murphy impersonates the preacher is just plain embarrassing & I hated the ending as well. Director Craven had never made a comedy before & it show's as the comedy scenes just don't work, the horror & gore scenes are far more effective & it's a shame there's not more of them. By the time Craven teamed up with Murphy to make this both needed a hit after their careers both hit slumps, Vampire in Brooklyn was a poor choice of film although the story does have a happy ending as Craven went on to make the mega hit teen horror slasher Scream (1996) & Murphy made the successful children's comedy The Nutty Professor (1996) as their next films respectively. Angela Bassett's stunt double Sonya Davis died went a stunt went wrong where she was supposed to fall from a building onto an airbag but she actually hit her head on the solid ground. There's some gore here, there's a ripped out heart, various dead bodies with slit throats, some blood drinking & a stake through the heart although the special make-up effects on Murphy at the end look terrible. With a supposed budget of about $14,000,000 this had a decent amount of cash thrown at it, I don't think it flopped at the box-office but it didn't do that well either. It's well made with decent production values. The acting isn't that great & surprisingly Murphy is the only one who plays it straight which is very odd, Bassett is forgettable & Kadeem Hardison as the comedy relief ghoul is terrible. Vampire in Brooklyn is a horror film that isn't scary, a comedy that isn't funny & it's got a black cast directed by a white man brought in for his name & as a whole it just doesn't work on any level. One to avoid.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
