<filme>
 <id>
  55
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0110413
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1994
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  O Profissional
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  8.6
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  A professional assassin rescues a young girl whose parents were killed in a police raid.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Mathilda, a twelve-year old New York girl, is living an undesirable life among her half-family. Her father stores drugs for two-faced cop Norman Stansfield. Only her little brother keeps Mathilda from breaking apart. One day, Stansfield and his team take cruel revenge on her father for stretching the drugs a little, thus killing the whole family. Only Mathilda, who was out shopping, survives by finding shelter in L&eacute;on's apartment in the moment of highest need. Soon, she finds out about the strange neighbour's unusual profession - killing - and desperately seeks his help in taking revenge for her little brother. L&eacute;on, who is completely unexperienced in fatherly tasks, and in friendships, does his best to keep Mathilda out of trouble - unsuccessfully. Now, the conflict between a killer, who slowly discovers his abilities to live, to feel, to love and a corrupt police officer, who does anything in his might to get rid of an eye witness, arises to unmeasurable proportions - all for the ...
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Crime
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Thriller
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   girl
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   drugs
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   revenge
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   hitman
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   apartment
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Luc Besson
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Luc Besson
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Jean Reno
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Gary Oldman
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Natalie Portman
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    High Quality Crime Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    argo0403
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Leon is a brutal and veteran hit-man. He meets Mathilda, a young girl, and saves her from bad detectives. But, they kills her family so she lives with Leon. Although he declines her to live and talk with, he gradually becomes kind to her. At the same time, the remnants of the detectives tries to find them Though the story is very simple and there's no surprise, this crime movie compensates for that from brilliant performances by actors such as Jean Reno and Gary Oldman. I think Reno plays two roles in this. First is as a heartless assassin. This part is very cool. Second is as a friend or father of Mathilda. In contrast, this part is heart-warming and his smile is so charming that I can't help laughing. The thing I like in this movie is Oldman's madness. I have very strong impression from Darkknight series, so I can't believe that he plays such a crazy villain and I burst into laughs when his last scene. To be honest, I don't have sympathy with Mathilda so much. I always don't have it with young main character. Even though the last is predictable, it moves me. Good or worse, meeting someone really changes our life. &nbsp;This is not a masterpiece, but I'm very satisfied and touched by pure love of Leon.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A classic that totally holds up...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    agentvega
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film totally withstands the test of time. You can watch it today and it still feels just as fresh and relevant as when it came out. The international cut is better than the U.S. cut, but any version is worth the watch. Even as a kid, you can tell that Natalie Portman is destined for great things. I feel like even though Gary Oldman's character is a bit over the top, he still makes him as believable as possible. But, the stand out is obviously Jean Reno. Amazing as ever. Just a perfect roll for him. I must have seen this film at least 20 times, and every time I catch some little nuance that I missed in the past or just see something differently than I had before. It is just a great, if not underrated movie, and not only worth a viewing, but many. You surely will not be disappointed, and if you somehow are, give it another chance to grow on you. A very good friend of mine was not a fan upon first viewing, but now counts it as one of his favorites.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Violent movie with a heavy plot
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    digitalbeachbum
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I first saw this movie the only thing I could think about was the acting of Natalie Portman. Even at this age you could see her natural beauty and ability as an actor. The acting was awesome and the plot was well laid out, but I found several parts of the movie which weren't believable. I won't bother with them here, but you can see from my score that these scenes brought the movie down a few notches for me. I definitely would recommend this movie in HD or even 3D with a mega, killer sound system. It was really meant to be played on the big screen and small screens with crappy sound systems really do it an injustice. Every once in a while I see this on normal television and I watch it for laughs because they do the "pan and scan" which completely ruins the movie beyond words. I personally thing "pan and scan" should be against the law. Don't they already have this in France? Acting 1 Directing 1 Plot 1 Believability 0 Continuity .5 Natalie Portman 10 (no I'm not a pedo) Action 1 14.5 of 7
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent film with a gripping story!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Skyler Moody
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is absolutely brilliant and amazing! It is truly a unique film with fantastic acting and action that will hold you in its grasp. Where are the awards for this film? How come this film is unnoticed? With all of the amazing acting and great storyline, I am surprised this movie did not win an Oscar! Everybody was fantastic in this film! Jean Reno gives a heartwarming performance as a sad and lonely hit-man or "cleaner" named Leon who lives in a secluded world in a apartment complex and Natalie Portman's character Mathilda is the one that shatters Leon's secluded world. For this being her first feature film, Natalie Portman gives an amazing and astonishing performance as a troubled little girl with a desire for revenge. Gary Oldman is also fantastic as a twisted, sadistic, and corrupted DEA agent. He is on my list for Top 10 greatest villains ever! The unique love story and father-daughter type relationship between Leon and Mathilda is handled beautifully by director Luc Besson. You will feel so much sympathy for these characters. This movie is the perfect action with a unique love story and unforgettable characters and emotionally charged scenes! Everybody needs to see this movie!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Leon: The Professional (1994)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    William Richardson (valor992@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Personally this is the best movie I've ever seen. The character development, pacing, acting, and writing are so effective I always forget that Im even watching a movie. Another reason it draws you in so intuitively is the perfectly arranged soundtrack. Every scene is complimented with exactly the right number, allowing a deeper insight into the emotions being displayed on screen, weather it be a light of air of compassion or an adrenaline filled descant, the soundtrack never fails to hit its mark. This film has a special place in my life, for me its not just a movie, Its a piece of myself that I integrated into who I am and it forever changed me. Im so grateful to see that others understand the complexity and greatness of this movie and appreciate it as well. P.S. I love you Mathilda
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Admirable film.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Hannah Louise Mickleburgh
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    L&eacute;on, to put it simply, is a masterpiece. One of the greatest early-modern films, no doubt about it. Natalie Portman at 12 is already excellent, and given a chance so few have: while there are many younger actors a mere handful can win these starring roles, and in serious films they're too young to see. Comparable to Kick-Ass, though this original suspense flies past the modern indie-wannabe in daylight. Nothing was stilted nor pushed too far and the story, yet unmentioned, is simply insightful. The only reason I give an 8, not 9 or even 10, is because 8 is my favourite number, and so only given to those which are worthy. The actors own their roles, and should play these characters more often. (This is) A favourite that will (unexpectedly?) last a long time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the best films of all time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ABC DEF
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is one of my top 5 favorites of all time. Lot of reasons for it. It combines a great and interesting storyline, coupled with stellar acting performances. Oldman really puts the punch into the villainous role, he is terrific, but Portman steals away the show from everyone. It could be one of the top performances in a female role, and that too by a young girl. The novelty of the story is it's handling of the relationship between and elder man and young girl in an entirely different manner. The chemistry between Reno and Portman is amazing. Overall, the movie is great from the start to the end, including the climax.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "I Like These Calm Little Moments Before The Storm"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    CinemaClown
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    L&eacute;on is a stylish & solid action thriller that is today rightfully hailed as one of the greatest action films of all time. Superbly directed, swiftly paced, tightly edited & beautifully scored, L&eacute;on tells the story of a professional assassin who takes in a 12 year old girl when her family is brutally murdered by corrupt police officers and helps & trains her to exact revenge on those responsible for it. Also, this film is an odd look at their relationship which might turn out to be unsettling for some. Jean Reno stars as the best contract killer in town, L&eacute;on & did great justice to his character. Gary Oldman simply nailed his character by putting up a stupefying performance as corrupt DEA agent, Norman Stansfield, and also introducing Natalie Portman as Mathilda, who couldn't have asked for a more sensational debut. A classic in every way, L&eacute;on is violent, brutal & unsettling, yet is a brilliantly directed, superbly edited & beautifully photographed film that easily qualifies as a tremendously entertaining & memorable action masterpiece of all times. P.S. Make sure you grab the Extended Cut to fill up what might feel like loopholes in the Theatrical version.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    He's Venus As A Boy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bbcfilmlover
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Leon is another film i haven't watched for years but when i originally saw it, i really loved the film. Of course i am reviewing the original cinematic/DVD release. For your information, Director Luc Beeson classes this as 'The Director's Cut', as it has many scenes deleted from the original test showing. I believe, two years later, Beeson re-edited all of those scenes back in. Apparently 25 minutes extra. That version, confusingly, is known as 'The Director's Cut', though Beeson, keeping in mind his view of the naming of his Director's Cut, calls this 'The Internatinal Cut'. Confused? This is a really enthralling film which keeps you emotionally involved throughout. Yes, it is a violent film in places but that is not what the story is about. It is about finding yourself and who you are. Taking root and allowing people in, when you weren't able to before. Natalie Portman absolutely shines in this. Havig been cast at 11, now 12, she is totally believable as Mathilda. It must have been tough to pull off some scenes at such a young age. Whilst Jean Reno is wonderful as Leon, it is Portman's portrayal of the character dealing with the loss of her abusive, uncaring family, while grieving for the loss of her 4 year old brother and her subsequent journey of revenge and finding herself just like Leon, that makes her performance so strong. Now, it must be said there are elements of an undercurrent of a possible sexual relationship between them both. Early on Mathilda shows signs of holding herself in certain way that shows a possible move into puberty. Take a look at the scenes of her hanging over the staircase for this. It is clear that as the film develops there is a growing love between them. Look out for Mathilda sleeping with the pig oven glove on the first night. A subtle moments, easily missed. However, the way Reno plays his character with a few learning difficulties, naivety and his reluctance to accept anything outside his comfort zone, the sexuality elements do not come across as dirty at all. There really does seem to be a developing true love between them and it is touching to watch at times. Apparently, The International Cut has more interactions between Mathilda and Leon, which i haven't seen yet. I must also add that the original script, which is available online, does have them making love. Again, reading the script does put it into context as to how she feels towards Leon and why she feels the need/want to make love. It is clear that anything outside of Leon's job and he is lost. That is the beauty of this film, with all its violence and profanity, and equally so the fate of Leon itself, it really shows the development of what one person can give to another. Gary Oldman's deserves much credit too. I won't go into detail about his character but i will say he is damn good. Watch out for the "Ev-ery-one" line, which i can imagine, if watched on the big screen in the cinema must have reverberated half way around town! A mention also to the character of Tony. We never really get any in depth explanations about him. He clearly is underhand, always keeping Leon's money and then only offering Mathilda $100 to last a whole month. The way he would say things and his mannerisms certainly suggest there is a lot more to him that meets they eye. There are so many stand out scenes in this film, all subtle, that it is hard to pick any individually. The film pretty much grabs you from start to end. It is a funny juxtaposition really, you find yourself caring so much for a killer! The soundtrack is equally as subtle and helps too by not being overpowering. The end titles have Sting's 'Shape of my Heart' which actually fits perfectly. The other piece of music within the film is the sublime, 'Venus as a Boy' by Bjork, which on first hearing/watching seems a strange choice. But on closer inspection he budding sexual overtones and growing feelings of the song match the way Mathilda was beginning to feel. All in all this is a good film. You care about both off the main characters. The final scene with Matilda finally telling the truth, albeit, so way out there and the planting of Leon's 'best friend' to take root, gives you a wonderful sense of knowing Mathilda will be fine and has found herself and where she wants to be. Equally, albeit dead, Leon's plant taking root, metaphorically gives you that same feeling. I will be searching out the 'International Version' just to add to the story but i would suggest the viewer seek out the original version as, having not seen the other one, the story seems to the point and well contained as it is. As a final point, as a David Lynch fan, i found one or two shots reminding me of Lynch. Maybe that is just me and believe me that is no criticism. It just struck me when watching. This is a film not for everyone due to the violent content but if you want to submerge yourself in Beeson's world and watch a film with some depth of emotion, then this is the film for you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Disappointed, but still a good movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rydogbball34
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I haven't been this excited for a movie, besides Pan's Labyrinth; however, the film falls below my lofty expectations. Natalie Portman's acting gets hailed, but it was really rough to watch. Her performance was comparable to Macaulay Culkin's in Home Alone. The burden can't be attributed solely to her as the writing was pretty odd (the dress-up scene & Matilda's infatuation with Leon. The plot is a simplistic, predictable revenge story. The opening sequence is really great, while Gary Oldman is solid as always. Matilda never even killed anyone after training for that the entire movie; no self-delivered end of innocence. It's not an 8.6, but closer to the 7-8 range. I gave it a 7 because I just watched great child acting in Let the Right One In before viewing this film. Overall, though, it's much better than the average movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    High Quality Crime Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    argo0403
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Leon is a brutal and veteran hit-man. He meets Mathilda, a young girl, and saves her from bad detectives. But, they kills her family so she lives with Leon. Although he declines her to live and talk with, he gradually becomes kind to her. At the same time, the remnants of the detectives tries to find them Though the story is very simple and there's no surprise, this crime movie compensates for that from brilliant performances by actors such as Jean Reno and Gary Oldman. I think Reno plays two roles in this. First is as a heartless assassin. This part is very cool. Second is as a friend or father of Mathilda. In contrast, this part is heart-warming and his smile is so charming that I can't help laughing. The thing I like in this movie is Oldman's madness. I have very strong impression from Darkknight series, so I can't believe that he plays such a crazy villain and I burst into laughs when his last scene. To be honest, I don't have sympathy with Mathilda so much. I always don't have it with young main character. Even though the last is predictable, it moves me. Good or worse, meeting someone really changes our life. &nbsp;This is not a masterpiece, but I'm very satisfied and touched by pure love of Leon.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A classic that totally holds up...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    agentvega
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film totally withstands the test of time. You can watch it today and it still feels just as fresh and relevant as when it came out. The international cut is better than the U.S. cut, but any version is worth the watch. Even as a kid, you can tell that Natalie Portman is destined for great things. I feel like even though Gary Oldman's character is a bit over the top, he still makes him as believable as possible. But, the stand out is obviously Jean Reno. Amazing as ever. Just a perfect roll for him. I must have seen this film at least 20 times, and every time I catch some little nuance that I missed in the past or just see something differently than I had before. It is just a great, if not underrated movie, and not only worth a viewing, but many. You surely will not be disappointed, and if you somehow are, give it another chance to grow on you. A very good friend of mine was not a fan upon first viewing, but now counts it as one of his favorites.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Violent movie with a heavy plot
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    digitalbeachbum
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I first saw this movie the only thing I could think about was the acting of Natalie Portman. Even at this age you could see her natural beauty and ability as an actor. The acting was awesome and the plot was well laid out, but I found several parts of the movie which weren't believable. I won't bother with them here, but you can see from my score that these scenes brought the movie down a few notches for me. I definitely would recommend this movie in HD or even 3D with a mega, killer sound system. It was really meant to be played on the big screen and small screens with crappy sound systems really do it an injustice. Every once in a while I see this on normal television and I watch it for laughs because they do the "pan and scan" which completely ruins the movie beyond words. I personally thing "pan and scan" should be against the law. Don't they already have this in France? Acting 1 Directing 1 Plot 1 Believability 0 Continuity .5 Natalie Portman 10 (no I'm not a pedo) Action 1 14.5 of 7
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent film with a gripping story!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Skyler Moody
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is absolutely brilliant and amazing! It is truly a unique film with fantastic acting and action that will hold you in its grasp. Where are the awards for this film? How come this film is unnoticed? With all of the amazing acting and great storyline, I am surprised this movie did not win an Oscar! Everybody was fantastic in this film! Jean Reno gives a heartwarming performance as a sad and lonely hit-man or "cleaner" named Leon who lives in a secluded world in a apartment complex and Natalie Portman's character Mathilda is the one that shatters Leon's secluded world. For this being her first feature film, Natalie Portman gives an amazing and astonishing performance as a troubled little girl with a desire for revenge. Gary Oldman is also fantastic as a twisted, sadistic, and corrupted DEA agent. He is on my list for Top 10 greatest villains ever! The unique love story and father-daughter type relationship between Leon and Mathilda is handled beautifully by director Luc Besson. You will feel so much sympathy for these characters. This movie is the perfect action with a unique love story and unforgettable characters and emotionally charged scenes! Everybody needs to see this movie!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Leon: The Professional (1994)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    William Richardson (valor992@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Personally this is the best movie I've ever seen. The character development, pacing, acting, and writing are so effective I always forget that Im even watching a movie. Another reason it draws you in so intuitively is the perfectly arranged soundtrack. Every scene is complimented with exactly the right number, allowing a deeper insight into the emotions being displayed on screen, weather it be a light of air of compassion or an adrenaline filled descant, the soundtrack never fails to hit its mark. This film has a special place in my life, for me its not just a movie, Its a piece of myself that I integrated into who I am and it forever changed me. Im so grateful to see that others understand the complexity and greatness of this movie and appreciate it as well. P.S. I love you Mathilda
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Admirable film.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Hannah Louise Mickleburgh
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    L&eacute;on, to put it simply, is a masterpiece. One of the greatest early-modern films, no doubt about it. Natalie Portman at 12 is already excellent, and given a chance so few have: while there are many younger actors a mere handful can win these starring roles, and in serious films they're too young to see. Comparable to Kick-Ass, though this original suspense flies past the modern indie-wannabe in daylight. Nothing was stilted nor pushed too far and the story, yet unmentioned, is simply insightful. The only reason I give an 8, not 9 or even 10, is because 8 is my favourite number, and so only given to those which are worthy. The actors own their roles, and should play these characters more often. (This is) A favourite that will (unexpectedly?) last a long time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the best films of all time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ABC DEF
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is one of my top 5 favorites of all time. Lot of reasons for it. It combines a great and interesting storyline, coupled with stellar acting performances. Oldman really puts the punch into the villainous role, he is terrific, but Portman steals away the show from everyone. It could be one of the top performances in a female role, and that too by a young girl. The novelty of the story is it's handling of the relationship between and elder man and young girl in an entirely different manner. The chemistry between Reno and Portman is amazing. Overall, the movie is great from the start to the end, including the climax.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "I Like These Calm Little Moments Before The Storm"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    CinemaClown
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    L&eacute;on is a stylish & solid action thriller that is today rightfully hailed as one of the greatest action films of all time. Superbly directed, swiftly paced, tightly edited & beautifully scored, L&eacute;on tells the story of a professional assassin who takes in a 12 year old girl when her family is brutally murdered by corrupt police officers and helps & trains her to exact revenge on those responsible for it. Also, this film is an odd look at their relationship which might turn out to be unsettling for some. Jean Reno stars as the best contract killer in town, L&eacute;on & did great justice to his character. Gary Oldman simply nailed his character by putting up a stupefying performance as corrupt DEA agent, Norman Stansfield, and also introducing Natalie Portman as Mathilda, who couldn't have asked for a more sensational debut. A classic in every way, L&eacute;on is violent, brutal & unsettling, yet is a brilliantly directed, superbly edited & beautifully photographed film that easily qualifies as a tremendously entertaining & memorable action masterpiece of all times. P.S. Make sure you grab the Extended Cut to fill up what might feel like loopholes in the Theatrical version.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    He's Venus As A Boy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bbcfilmlover
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Leon is another film i haven't watched for years but when i originally saw it, i really loved the film. Of course i am reviewing the original cinematic/DVD release. For your information, Director Luc Beeson classes this as 'The Director's Cut', as it has many scenes deleted from the original test showing. I believe, two years later, Beeson re-edited all of those scenes back in. Apparently 25 minutes extra. That version, confusingly, is known as 'The Director's Cut', though Beeson, keeping in mind his view of the naming of his Director's Cut, calls this 'The Internatinal Cut'. Confused? This is a really enthralling film which keeps you emotionally involved throughout. Yes, it is a violent film in places but that is not what the story is about. It is about finding yourself and who you are. Taking root and allowing people in, when you weren't able to before. Natalie Portman absolutely shines in this. Havig been cast at 11, now 12, she is totally believable as Mathilda. It must have been tough to pull off some scenes at such a young age. Whilst Jean Reno is wonderful as Leon, it is Portman's portrayal of the character dealing with the loss of her abusive, uncaring family, while grieving for the loss of her 4 year old brother and her subsequent journey of revenge and finding herself just like Leon, that makes her performance so strong. Now, it must be said there are elements of an undercurrent of a possible sexual relationship between them both. Early on Mathilda shows signs of holding herself in certain way that shows a possible move into puberty. Take a look at the scenes of her hanging over the staircase for this. It is clear that as the film develops there is a growing love between them. Look out for Mathilda sleeping with the pig oven glove on the first night. A subtle moments, easily missed. However, the way Reno plays his character with a few learning difficulties, naivety and his reluctance to accept anything outside his comfort zone, the sexuality elements do not come across as dirty at all. There really does seem to be a developing true love between them and it is touching to watch at times. Apparently, The International Cut has more interactions between Mathilda and Leon, which i haven't seen yet. I must also add that the original script, which is available online, does have them making love. Again, reading the script does put it into context as to how she feels towards Leon and why she feels the need/want to make love. It is clear that anything outside of Leon's job and he is lost. That is the beauty of this film, with all its violence and profanity, and equally so the fate of Leon itself, it really shows the development of what one person can give to another. Gary Oldman's deserves much credit too. I won't go into detail about his character but i will say he is damn good. Watch out for the "Ev-ery-one" line, which i can imagine, if watched on the big screen in the cinema must have reverberated half way around town! A mention also to the character of Tony. We never really get any in depth explanations about him. He clearly is underhand, always keeping Leon's money and then only offering Mathilda $100 to last a whole month. The way he would say things and his mannerisms certainly suggest there is a lot more to him that meets they eye. There are so many stand out scenes in this film, all subtle, that it is hard to pick any individually. The film pretty much grabs you from start to end. It is a funny juxtaposition really, you find yourself caring so much for a killer! The soundtrack is equally as subtle and helps too by not being overpowering. The end titles have Sting's 'Shape of my Heart' which actually fits perfectly. The other piece of music within the film is the sublime, 'Venus as a Boy' by Bjork, which on first hearing/watching seems a strange choice. But on closer inspection he budding sexual overtones and growing feelings of the song match the way Mathilda was beginning to feel. All in all this is a good film. You care about both off the main characters. The final scene with Matilda finally telling the truth, albeit, so way out there and the planting of Leon's 'best friend' to take root, gives you a wonderful sense of knowing Mathilda will be fine and has found herself and where she wants to be. Equally, albeit dead, Leon's plant taking root, metaphorically gives you that same feeling. I will be searching out the 'International Version' just to add to the story but i would suggest the viewer seek out the original version as, having not seen the other one, the story seems to the point and well contained as it is. As a final point, as a David Lynch fan, i found one or two shots reminding me of Lynch. Maybe that is just me and believe me that is no criticism. It just struck me when watching. This is a film not for everyone due to the violent content but if you want to submerge yourself in Beeson's world and watch a film with some depth of emotion, then this is the film for you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Disappointed, but still a good movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rydogbball34
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I haven't been this excited for a movie, besides Pan's Labyrinth; however, the film falls below my lofty expectations. Natalie Portman's acting gets hailed, but it was really rough to watch. Her performance was comparable to Macaulay Culkin's in Home Alone. The burden can't be attributed solely to her as the writing was pretty odd (the dress-up scene & Matilda's infatuation with Leon. The plot is a simplistic, predictable revenge story. The opening sequence is really great, while Gary Oldman is solid as always. Matilda never even killed anyone after training for that the entire movie; no self-delivered end of innocence. It's not an 8.6, but closer to the 7-8 range. I gave it a 7 because I just watched great child acting in Let the Right One In before viewing this film. Overall, though, it's much better than the average movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    High Quality Crime Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    argo0403
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Leon is a brutal and veteran hit-man. He meets Mathilda, a young girl, and saves her from bad detectives. But, they kills her family so she lives with Leon. Although he declines her to live and talk with, he gradually becomes kind to her. At the same time, the remnants of the detectives tries to find them Though the story is very simple and there's no surprise, this crime movie compensates for that from brilliant performances by actors such as Jean Reno and Gary Oldman. I think Reno plays two roles in this. First is as a heartless assassin. This part is very cool. Second is as a friend or father of Mathilda. In contrast, this part is heart-warming and his smile is so charming that I can't help laughing. The thing I like in this movie is Oldman's madness. I have very strong impression from Darkknight series, so I can't believe that he plays such a crazy villain and I burst into laughs when his last scene. To be honest, I don't have sympathy with Mathilda so much. I always don't have it with young main character. Even though the last is predictable, it moves me. Good or worse, meeting someone really changes our life. &nbsp;This is not a masterpiece, but I'm very satisfied and touched by pure love of Leon.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A classic that totally holds up...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    agentvega
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film totally withstands the test of time. You can watch it today and it still feels just as fresh and relevant as when it came out. The international cut is better than the U.S. cut, but any version is worth the watch. Even as a kid, you can tell that Natalie Portman is destined for great things. I feel like even though Gary Oldman's character is a bit over the top, he still makes him as believable as possible. But, the stand out is obviously Jean Reno. Amazing as ever. Just a perfect roll for him. I must have seen this film at least 20 times, and every time I catch some little nuance that I missed in the past or just see something differently than I had before. It is just a great, if not underrated movie, and not only worth a viewing, but many. You surely will not be disappointed, and if you somehow are, give it another chance to grow on you. A very good friend of mine was not a fan upon first viewing, but now counts it as one of his favorites.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Violent movie with a heavy plot
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    digitalbeachbum
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I first saw this movie the only thing I could think about was the acting of Natalie Portman. Even at this age you could see her natural beauty and ability as an actor. The acting was awesome and the plot was well laid out, but I found several parts of the movie which weren't believable. I won't bother with them here, but you can see from my score that these scenes brought the movie down a few notches for me. I definitely would recommend this movie in HD or even 3D with a mega, killer sound system. It was really meant to be played on the big screen and small screens with crappy sound systems really do it an injustice. Every once in a while I see this on normal television and I watch it for laughs because they do the "pan and scan" which completely ruins the movie beyond words. I personally thing "pan and scan" should be against the law. Don't they already have this in France? Acting 1 Directing 1 Plot 1 Believability 0 Continuity .5 Natalie Portman 10 (no I'm not a pedo) Action 1 14.5 of 7
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent film with a gripping story!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Skyler Moody
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is absolutely brilliant and amazing! It is truly a unique film with fantastic acting and action that will hold you in its grasp. Where are the awards for this film? How come this film is unnoticed? With all of the amazing acting and great storyline, I am surprised this movie did not win an Oscar! Everybody was fantastic in this film! Jean Reno gives a heartwarming performance as a sad and lonely hit-man or "cleaner" named Leon who lives in a secluded world in a apartment complex and Natalie Portman's character Mathilda is the one that shatters Leon's secluded world. For this being her first feature film, Natalie Portman gives an amazing and astonishing performance as a troubled little girl with a desire for revenge. Gary Oldman is also fantastic as a twisted, sadistic, and corrupted DEA agent. He is on my list for Top 10 greatest villains ever! The unique love story and father-daughter type relationship between Leon and Mathilda is handled beautifully by director Luc Besson. You will feel so much sympathy for these characters. This movie is the perfect action with a unique love story and unforgettable characters and emotionally charged scenes! Everybody needs to see this movie!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Leon: The Professional (1994)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    William Richardson (valor992@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Personally this is the best movie I've ever seen. The character development, pacing, acting, and writing are so effective I always forget that Im even watching a movie. Another reason it draws you in so intuitively is the perfectly arranged soundtrack. Every scene is complimented with exactly the right number, allowing a deeper insight into the emotions being displayed on screen, weather it be a light of air of compassion or an adrenaline filled descant, the soundtrack never fails to hit its mark. This film has a special place in my life, for me its not just a movie, Its a piece of myself that I integrated into who I am and it forever changed me. Im so grateful to see that others understand the complexity and greatness of this movie and appreciate it as well. P.S. I love you Mathilda
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Admirable film.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Hannah Louise Mickleburgh
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    L&eacute;on, to put it simply, is a masterpiece. One of the greatest early-modern films, no doubt about it. Natalie Portman at 12 is already excellent, and given a chance so few have: while there are many younger actors a mere handful can win these starring roles, and in serious films they're too young to see. Comparable to Kick-Ass, though this original suspense flies past the modern indie-wannabe in daylight. Nothing was stilted nor pushed too far and the story, yet unmentioned, is simply insightful. The only reason I give an 8, not 9 or even 10, is because 8 is my favourite number, and so only given to those which are worthy. The actors own their roles, and should play these characters more often. (This is) A favourite that will (unexpectedly?) last a long time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the best films of all time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ABC DEF
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is one of my top 5 favorites of all time. Lot of reasons for it. It combines a great and interesting storyline, coupled with stellar acting performances. Oldman really puts the punch into the villainous role, he is terrific, but Portman steals away the show from everyone. It could be one of the top performances in a female role, and that too by a young girl. The novelty of the story is it's handling of the relationship between and elder man and young girl in an entirely different manner. The chemistry between Reno and Portman is amazing. Overall, the movie is great from the start to the end, including the climax.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "I Like These Calm Little Moments Before The Storm"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    CinemaClown
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    L&eacute;on is a stylish & solid action thriller that is today rightfully hailed as one of the greatest action films of all time. Superbly directed, swiftly paced, tightly edited & beautifully scored, L&eacute;on tells the story of a professional assassin who takes in a 12 year old girl when her family is brutally murdered by corrupt police officers and helps & trains her to exact revenge on those responsible for it. Also, this film is an odd look at their relationship which might turn out to be unsettling for some. Jean Reno stars as the best contract killer in town, L&eacute;on & did great justice to his character. Gary Oldman simply nailed his character by putting up a stupefying performance as corrupt DEA agent, Norman Stansfield, and also introducing Natalie Portman as Mathilda, who couldn't have asked for a more sensational debut. A classic in every way, L&eacute;on is violent, brutal & unsettling, yet is a brilliantly directed, superbly edited & beautifully photographed film that easily qualifies as a tremendously entertaining & memorable action masterpiece of all times. P.S. Make sure you grab the Extended Cut to fill up what might feel like loopholes in the Theatrical version.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    He's Venus As A Boy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bbcfilmlover
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Leon is another film i haven't watched for years but when i originally saw it, i really loved the film. Of course i am reviewing the original cinematic/DVD release. For your information, Director Luc Beeson classes this as 'The Director's Cut', as it has many scenes deleted from the original test showing. I believe, two years later, Beeson re-edited all of those scenes back in. Apparently 25 minutes extra. That version, confusingly, is known as 'The Director's Cut', though Beeson, keeping in mind his view of the naming of his Director's Cut, calls this 'The Internatinal Cut'. Confused? This is a really enthralling film which keeps you emotionally involved throughout. Yes, it is a violent film in places but that is not what the story is about. It is about finding yourself and who you are. Taking root and allowing people in, when you weren't able to before. Natalie Portman absolutely shines in this. Havig been cast at 11, now 12, she is totally believable as Mathilda. It must have been tough to pull off some scenes at such a young age. Whilst Jean Reno is wonderful as Leon, it is Portman's portrayal of the character dealing with the loss of her abusive, uncaring family, while grieving for the loss of her 4 year old brother and her subsequent journey of revenge and finding herself just like Leon, that makes her performance so strong. Now, it must be said there are elements of an undercurrent of a possible sexual relationship between them both. Early on Mathilda shows signs of holding herself in certain way that shows a possible move into puberty. Take a look at the scenes of her hanging over the staircase for this. It is clear that as the film develops there is a growing love between them. Look out for Mathilda sleeping with the pig oven glove on the first night. A subtle moments, easily missed. However, the way Reno plays his character with a few learning difficulties, naivety and his reluctance to accept anything outside his comfort zone, the sexuality elements do not come across as dirty at all. There really does seem to be a developing true love between them and it is touching to watch at times. Apparently, The International Cut has more interactions between Mathilda and Leon, which i haven't seen yet. I must also add that the original script, which is available online, does have them making love. Again, reading the script does put it into context as to how she feels towards Leon and why she feels the need/want to make love. It is clear that anything outside of Leon's job and he is lost. That is the beauty of this film, with all its violence and profanity, and equally so the fate of Leon itself, it really shows the development of what one person can give to another. Gary Oldman's deserves much credit too. I won't go into detail about his character but i will say he is damn good. Watch out for the "Ev-ery-one" line, which i can imagine, if watched on the big screen in the cinema must have reverberated half way around town! A mention also to the character of Tony. We never really get any in depth explanations about him. He clearly is underhand, always keeping Leon's money and then only offering Mathilda $100 to last a whole month. The way he would say things and his mannerisms certainly suggest there is a lot more to him that meets they eye. There are so many stand out scenes in this film, all subtle, that it is hard to pick any individually. The film pretty much grabs you from start to end. It is a funny juxtaposition really, you find yourself caring so much for a killer! The soundtrack is equally as subtle and helps too by not being overpowering. The end titles have Sting's 'Shape of my Heart' which actually fits perfectly. The other piece of music within the film is the sublime, 'Venus as a Boy' by Bjork, which on first hearing/watching seems a strange choice. But on closer inspection he budding sexual overtones and growing feelings of the song match the way Mathilda was beginning to feel. All in all this is a good film. You care about both off the main characters. The final scene with Matilda finally telling the truth, albeit, so way out there and the planting of Leon's 'best friend' to take root, gives you a wonderful sense of knowing Mathilda will be fine and has found herself and where she wants to be. Equally, albeit dead, Leon's plant taking root, metaphorically gives you that same feeling. I will be searching out the 'International Version' just to add to the story but i would suggest the viewer seek out the original version as, having not seen the other one, the story seems to the point and well contained as it is. As a final point, as a David Lynch fan, i found one or two shots reminding me of Lynch. Maybe that is just me and believe me that is no criticism. It just struck me when watching. This is a film not for everyone due to the violent content but if you want to submerge yourself in Beeson's world and watch a film with some depth of emotion, then this is the film for you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Disappointed, but still a good movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rydogbball34
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I haven't been this excited for a movie, besides Pan's Labyrinth; however, the film falls below my lofty expectations. Natalie Portman's acting gets hailed, but it was really rough to watch. Her performance was comparable to Macaulay Culkin's in Home Alone. The burden can't be attributed solely to her as the writing was pretty odd (the dress-up scene & Matilda's infatuation with Leon. The plot is a simplistic, predictable revenge story. The opening sequence is really great, while Gary Oldman is solid as always. Matilda never even killed anyone after training for that the entire movie; no self-delivered end of innocence. It's not an 8.6, but closer to the 7-8 range. I gave it a 7 because I just watched great child acting in Let the Right One In before viewing this film. Overall, though, it's much better than the average movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    High Quality Crime Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    argo0403
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Leon is a brutal and veteran hit-man. He meets Mathilda, a young girl, and saves her from bad detectives. But, they kills her family so she lives with Leon. Although he declines her to live and talk with, he gradually becomes kind to her. At the same time, the remnants of the detectives tries to find them Though the story is very simple and there's no surprise, this crime movie compensates for that from brilliant performances by actors such as Jean Reno and Gary Oldman. I think Reno plays two roles in this. First is as a heartless assassin. This part is very cool. Second is as a friend or father of Mathilda. In contrast, this part is heart-warming and his smile is so charming that I can't help laughing. The thing I like in this movie is Oldman's madness. I have very strong impression from Darkknight series, so I can't believe that he plays such a crazy villain and I burst into laughs when his last scene. To be honest, I don't have sympathy with Mathilda so much. I always don't have it with young main character. Even though the last is predictable, it moves me. Good or worse, meeting someone really changes our life. &nbsp;This is not a masterpiece, but I'm very satisfied and touched by pure love of Leon.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A classic that totally holds up...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    agentvega
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film totally withstands the test of time. You can watch it today and it still feels just as fresh and relevant as when it came out. The international cut is better than the U.S. cut, but any version is worth the watch. Even as a kid, you can tell that Natalie Portman is destined for great things. I feel like even though Gary Oldman's character is a bit over the top, he still makes him as believable as possible. But, the stand out is obviously Jean Reno. Amazing as ever. Just a perfect roll for him. I must have seen this film at least 20 times, and every time I catch some little nuance that I missed in the past or just see something differently than I had before. It is just a great, if not underrated movie, and not only worth a viewing, but many. You surely will not be disappointed, and if you somehow are, give it another chance to grow on you. A very good friend of mine was not a fan upon first viewing, but now counts it as one of his favorites.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Violent movie with a heavy plot
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    digitalbeachbum
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I first saw this movie the only thing I could think about was the acting of Natalie Portman. Even at this age you could see her natural beauty and ability as an actor. The acting was awesome and the plot was well laid out, but I found several parts of the movie which weren't believable. I won't bother with them here, but you can see from my score that these scenes brought the movie down a few notches for me. I definitely would recommend this movie in HD or even 3D with a mega, killer sound system. It was really meant to be played on the big screen and small screens with crappy sound systems really do it an injustice. Every once in a while I see this on normal television and I watch it for laughs because they do the "pan and scan" which completely ruins the movie beyond words. I personally thing "pan and scan" should be against the law. Don't they already have this in France? Acting 1 Directing 1 Plot 1 Believability 0 Continuity .5 Natalie Portman 10 (no I'm not a pedo) Action 1 14.5 of 7
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent film with a gripping story!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Skyler Moody
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is absolutely brilliant and amazing! It is truly a unique film with fantastic acting and action that will hold you in its grasp. Where are the awards for this film? How come this film is unnoticed? With all of the amazing acting and great storyline, I am surprised this movie did not win an Oscar! Everybody was fantastic in this film! Jean Reno gives a heartwarming performance as a sad and lonely hit-man or "cleaner" named Leon who lives in a secluded world in a apartment complex and Natalie Portman's character Mathilda is the one that shatters Leon's secluded world. For this being her first feature film, Natalie Portman gives an amazing and astonishing performance as a troubled little girl with a desire for revenge. Gary Oldman is also fantastic as a twisted, sadistic, and corrupted DEA agent. He is on my list for Top 10 greatest villains ever! The unique love story and father-daughter type relationship between Leon and Mathilda is handled beautifully by director Luc Besson. You will feel so much sympathy for these characters. This movie is the perfect action with a unique love story and unforgettable characters and emotionally charged scenes! Everybody needs to see this movie!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Leon: The Professional (1994)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    William Richardson (valor992@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Personally this is the best movie I've ever seen. The character development, pacing, acting, and writing are so effective I always forget that Im even watching a movie. Another reason it draws you in so intuitively is the perfectly arranged soundtrack. Every scene is complimented with exactly the right number, allowing a deeper insight into the emotions being displayed on screen, weather it be a light of air of compassion or an adrenaline filled descant, the soundtrack never fails to hit its mark. This film has a special place in my life, for me its not just a movie, Its a piece of myself that I integrated into who I am and it forever changed me. Im so grateful to see that others understand the complexity and greatness of this movie and appreciate it as well. P.S. I love you Mathilda
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Admirable film.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Hannah Louise Mickleburgh
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    L&eacute;on, to put it simply, is a masterpiece. One of the greatest early-modern films, no doubt about it. Natalie Portman at 12 is already excellent, and given a chance so few have: while there are many younger actors a mere handful can win these starring roles, and in serious films they're too young to see. Comparable to Kick-Ass, though this original suspense flies past the modern indie-wannabe in daylight. Nothing was stilted nor pushed too far and the story, yet unmentioned, is simply insightful. The only reason I give an 8, not 9 or even 10, is because 8 is my favourite number, and so only given to those which are worthy. The actors own their roles, and should play these characters more often. (This is) A favourite that will (unexpectedly?) last a long time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the best films of all time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ABC DEF
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is one of my top 5 favorites of all time. Lot of reasons for it. It combines a great and interesting storyline, coupled with stellar acting performances. Oldman really puts the punch into the villainous role, he is terrific, but Portman steals away the show from everyone. It could be one of the top performances in a female role, and that too by a young girl. The novelty of the story is it's handling of the relationship between and elder man and young girl in an entirely different manner. The chemistry between Reno and Portman is amazing. Overall, the movie is great from the start to the end, including the climax.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "I Like These Calm Little Moments Before The Storm"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    CinemaClown
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    L&eacute;on is a stylish & solid action thriller that is today rightfully hailed as one of the greatest action films of all time. Superbly directed, swiftly paced, tightly edited & beautifully scored, L&eacute;on tells the story of a professional assassin who takes in a 12 year old girl when her family is brutally murdered by corrupt police officers and helps & trains her to exact revenge on those responsible for it. Also, this film is an odd look at their relationship which might turn out to be unsettling for some. Jean Reno stars as the best contract killer in town, L&eacute;on & did great justice to his character. Gary Oldman simply nailed his character by putting up a stupefying performance as corrupt DEA agent, Norman Stansfield, and also introducing Natalie Portman as Mathilda, who couldn't have asked for a more sensational debut. A classic in every way, L&eacute;on is violent, brutal & unsettling, yet is a brilliantly directed, superbly edited & beautifully photographed film that easily qualifies as a tremendously entertaining & memorable action masterpiece of all times. P.S. Make sure you grab the Extended Cut to fill up what might feel like loopholes in the Theatrical version.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    He's Venus As A Boy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bbcfilmlover
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Leon is another film i haven't watched for years but when i originally saw it, i really loved the film. Of course i am reviewing the original cinematic/DVD release. For your information, Director Luc Beeson classes this as 'The Director's Cut', as it has many scenes deleted from the original test showing. I believe, two years later, Beeson re-edited all of those scenes back in. Apparently 25 minutes extra. That version, confusingly, is known as 'The Director's Cut', though Beeson, keeping in mind his view of the naming of his Director's Cut, calls this 'The Internatinal Cut'. Confused? This is a really enthralling film which keeps you emotionally involved throughout. Yes, it is a violent film in places but that is not what the story is about. It is about finding yourself and who you are. Taking root and allowing people in, when you weren't able to before. Natalie Portman absolutely shines in this. Havig been cast at 11, now 12, she is totally believable as Mathilda. It must have been tough to pull off some scenes at such a young age. Whilst Jean Reno is wonderful as Leon, it is Portman's portrayal of the character dealing with the loss of her abusive, uncaring family, while grieving for the loss of her 4 year old brother and her subsequent journey of revenge and finding herself just like Leon, that makes her performance so strong. Now, it must be said there are elements of an undercurrent of a possible sexual relationship between them both. Early on Mathilda shows signs of holding herself in certain way that shows a possible move into puberty. Take a look at the scenes of her hanging over the staircase for this. It is clear that as the film develops there is a growing love between them. Look out for Mathilda sleeping with the pig oven glove on the first night. A subtle moments, easily missed. However, the way Reno plays his character with a few learning difficulties, naivety and his reluctance to accept anything outside his comfort zone, the sexuality elements do not come across as dirty at all. There really does seem to be a developing true love between them and it is touching to watch at times. Apparently, The International Cut has more interactions between Mathilda and Leon, which i haven't seen yet. I must also add that the original script, which is available online, does have them making love. Again, reading the script does put it into context as to how she feels towards Leon and why she feels the need/want to make love. It is clear that anything outside of Leon's job and he is lost. That is the beauty of this film, with all its violence and profanity, and equally so the fate of Leon itself, it really shows the development of what one person can give to another. Gary Oldman's deserves much credit too. I won't go into detail about his character but i will say he is damn good. Watch out for the "Ev-ery-one" line, which i can imagine, if watched on the big screen in the cinema must have reverberated half way around town! A mention also to the character of Tony. We never really get any in depth explanations about him. He clearly is underhand, always keeping Leon's money and then only offering Mathilda $100 to last a whole month. The way he would say things and his mannerisms certainly suggest there is a lot more to him that meets they eye. There are so many stand out scenes in this film, all subtle, that it is hard to pick any individually. The film pretty much grabs you from start to end. It is a funny juxtaposition really, you find yourself caring so much for a killer! The soundtrack is equally as subtle and helps too by not being overpowering. The end titles have Sting's 'Shape of my Heart' which actually fits perfectly. The other piece of music within the film is the sublime, 'Venus as a Boy' by Bjork, which on first hearing/watching seems a strange choice. But on closer inspection he budding sexual overtones and growing feelings of the song match the way Mathilda was beginning to feel. All in all this is a good film. You care about both off the main characters. The final scene with Matilda finally telling the truth, albeit, so way out there and the planting of Leon's 'best friend' to take root, gives you a wonderful sense of knowing Mathilda will be fine and has found herself and where she wants to be. Equally, albeit dead, Leon's plant taking root, metaphorically gives you that same feeling. I will be searching out the 'International Version' just to add to the story but i would suggest the viewer seek out the original version as, having not seen the other one, the story seems to the point and well contained as it is. As a final point, as a David Lynch fan, i found one or two shots reminding me of Lynch. Maybe that is just me and believe me that is no criticism. It just struck me when watching. This is a film not for everyone due to the violent content but if you want to submerge yourself in Beeson's world and watch a film with some depth of emotion, then this is the film for you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Disappointed, but still a good movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rydogbball34
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I haven't been this excited for a movie, besides Pan's Labyrinth; however, the film falls below my lofty expectations. Natalie Portman's acting gets hailed, but it was really rough to watch. Her performance was comparable to Macaulay Culkin's in Home Alone. The burden can't be attributed solely to her as the writing was pretty odd (the dress-up scene & Matilda's infatuation with Leon. The plot is a simplistic, predictable revenge story. The opening sequence is really great, while Gary Oldman is solid as always. Matilda never even killed anyone after training for that the entire movie; no self-delivered end of innocence. It's not an 8.6, but closer to the 7-8 range. I gave it a 7 because I just watched great child acting in Let the Right One In before viewing this film. Overall, though, it's much better than the average movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    High Quality Crime Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    argo0403
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Leon is a brutal and veteran hit-man. He meets Mathilda, a young girl, and saves her from bad detectives. But, they kills her family so she lives with Leon. Although he declines her to live and talk with, he gradually becomes kind to her. At the same time, the remnants of the detectives tries to find them Though the story is very simple and there's no surprise, this crime movie compensates for that from brilliant performances by actors such as Jean Reno and Gary Oldman. I think Reno plays two roles in this. First is as a heartless assassin. This part is very cool. Second is as a friend or father of Mathilda. In contrast, this part is heart-warming and his smile is so charming that I can't help laughing. The thing I like in this movie is Oldman's madness. I have very strong impression from Darkknight series, so I can't believe that he plays such a crazy villain and I burst into laughs when his last scene. To be honest, I don't have sympathy with Mathilda so much. I always don't have it with young main character. Even though the last is predictable, it moves me. Good or worse, meeting someone really changes our life. &nbsp;This is not a masterpiece, but I'm very satisfied and touched by pure love of Leon.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A classic that totally holds up...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    agentvega
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film totally withstands the test of time. You can watch it today and it still feels just as fresh and relevant as when it came out. The international cut is better than the U.S. cut, but any version is worth the watch. Even as a kid, you can tell that Natalie Portman is destined for great things. I feel like even though Gary Oldman's character is a bit over the top, he still makes him as believable as possible. But, the stand out is obviously Jean Reno. Amazing as ever. Just a perfect roll for him. I must have seen this film at least 20 times, and every time I catch some little nuance that I missed in the past or just see something differently than I had before. It is just a great, if not underrated movie, and not only worth a viewing, but many. You surely will not be disappointed, and if you somehow are, give it another chance to grow on you. A very good friend of mine was not a fan upon first viewing, but now counts it as one of his favorites.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Violent movie with a heavy plot
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    digitalbeachbum
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I first saw this movie the only thing I could think about was the acting of Natalie Portman. Even at this age you could see her natural beauty and ability as an actor. The acting was awesome and the plot was well laid out, but I found several parts of the movie which weren't believable. I won't bother with them here, but you can see from my score that these scenes brought the movie down a few notches for me. I definitely would recommend this movie in HD or even 3D with a mega, killer sound system. It was really meant to be played on the big screen and small screens with crappy sound systems really do it an injustice. Every once in a while I see this on normal television and I watch it for laughs because they do the "pan and scan" which completely ruins the movie beyond words. I personally thing "pan and scan" should be against the law. Don't they already have this in France? Acting 1 Directing 1 Plot 1 Believability 0 Continuity .5 Natalie Portman 10 (no I'm not a pedo) Action 1 14.5 of 7
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent film with a gripping story!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Skyler Moody
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is absolutely brilliant and amazing! It is truly a unique film with fantastic acting and action that will hold you in its grasp. Where are the awards for this film? How come this film is unnoticed? With all of the amazing acting and great storyline, I am surprised this movie did not win an Oscar! Everybody was fantastic in this film! Jean Reno gives a heartwarming performance as a sad and lonely hit-man or "cleaner" named Leon who lives in a secluded world in a apartment complex and Natalie Portman's character Mathilda is the one that shatters Leon's secluded world. For this being her first feature film, Natalie Portman gives an amazing and astonishing performance as a troubled little girl with a desire for revenge. Gary Oldman is also fantastic as a twisted, sadistic, and corrupted DEA agent. He is on my list for Top 10 greatest villains ever! The unique love story and father-daughter type relationship between Leon and Mathilda is handled beautifully by director Luc Besson. You will feel so much sympathy for these characters. This movie is the perfect action with a unique love story and unforgettable characters and emotionally charged scenes! Everybody needs to see this movie!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Leon: The Professional (1994)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    William Richardson (valor992@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Personally this is the best movie I've ever seen. The character development, pacing, acting, and writing are so effective I always forget that Im even watching a movie. Another reason it draws you in so intuitively is the perfectly arranged soundtrack. Every scene is complimented with exactly the right number, allowing a deeper insight into the emotions being displayed on screen, weather it be a light of air of compassion or an adrenaline filled descant, the soundtrack never fails to hit its mark. This film has a special place in my life, for me its not just a movie, Its a piece of myself that I integrated into who I am and it forever changed me. Im so grateful to see that others understand the complexity and greatness of this movie and appreciate it as well. P.S. I love you Mathilda
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Admirable film.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Hannah Louise Mickleburgh
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    L&eacute;on, to put it simply, is a masterpiece. One of the greatest early-modern films, no doubt about it. Natalie Portman at 12 is already excellent, and given a chance so few have: while there are many younger actors a mere handful can win these starring roles, and in serious films they're too young to see. Comparable to Kick-Ass, though this original suspense flies past the modern indie-wannabe in daylight. Nothing was stilted nor pushed too far and the story, yet unmentioned, is simply insightful. The only reason I give an 8, not 9 or even 10, is because 8 is my favourite number, and so only given to those which are worthy. The actors own their roles, and should play these characters more often. (This is) A favourite that will (unexpectedly?) last a long time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the best films of all time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ABC DEF
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is one of my top 5 favorites of all time. Lot of reasons for it. It combines a great and interesting storyline, coupled with stellar acting performances. Oldman really puts the punch into the villainous role, he is terrific, but Portman steals away the show from everyone. It could be one of the top performances in a female role, and that too by a young girl. The novelty of the story is it's handling of the relationship between and elder man and young girl in an entirely different manner. The chemistry between Reno and Portman is amazing. Overall, the movie is great from the start to the end, including the climax.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "I Like These Calm Little Moments Before The Storm"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    CinemaClown
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    L&eacute;on is a stylish & solid action thriller that is today rightfully hailed as one of the greatest action films of all time. Superbly directed, swiftly paced, tightly edited & beautifully scored, L&eacute;on tells the story of a professional assassin who takes in a 12 year old girl when her family is brutally murdered by corrupt police officers and helps & trains her to exact revenge on those responsible for it. Also, this film is an odd look at their relationship which might turn out to be unsettling for some. Jean Reno stars as the best contract killer in town, L&eacute;on & did great justice to his character. Gary Oldman simply nailed his character by putting up a stupefying performance as corrupt DEA agent, Norman Stansfield, and also introducing Natalie Portman as Mathilda, who couldn't have asked for a more sensational debut. A classic in every way, L&eacute;on is violent, brutal & unsettling, yet is a brilliantly directed, superbly edited & beautifully photographed film that easily qualifies as a tremendously entertaining & memorable action masterpiece of all times. P.S. Make sure you grab the Extended Cut to fill up what might feel like loopholes in the Theatrical version.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    He's Venus As A Boy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bbcfilmlover
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Leon is another film i haven't watched for years but when i originally saw it, i really loved the film. Of course i am reviewing the original cinematic/DVD release. For your information, Director Luc Beeson classes this as 'The Director's Cut', as it has many scenes deleted from the original test showing. I believe, two years later, Beeson re-edited all of those scenes back in. Apparently 25 minutes extra. That version, confusingly, is known as 'The Director's Cut', though Beeson, keeping in mind his view of the naming of his Director's Cut, calls this 'The Internatinal Cut'. Confused? This is a really enthralling film which keeps you emotionally involved throughout. Yes, it is a violent film in places but that is not what the story is about. It is about finding yourself and who you are. Taking root and allowing people in, when you weren't able to before. Natalie Portman absolutely shines in this. Havig been cast at 11, now 12, she is totally believable as Mathilda. It must have been tough to pull off some scenes at such a young age. Whilst Jean Reno is wonderful as Leon, it is Portman's portrayal of the character dealing with the loss of her abusive, uncaring family, while grieving for the loss of her 4 year old brother and her subsequent journey of revenge and finding herself just like Leon, that makes her performance so strong. Now, it must be said there are elements of an undercurrent of a possible sexual relationship between them both. Early on Mathilda shows signs of holding herself in certain way that shows a possible move into puberty. Take a look at the scenes of her hanging over the staircase for this. It is clear that as the film develops there is a growing love between them. Look out for Mathilda sleeping with the pig oven glove on the first night. A subtle moments, easily missed. However, the way Reno plays his character with a few learning difficulties, naivety and his reluctance to accept anything outside his comfort zone, the sexuality elements do not come across as dirty at all. There really does seem to be a developing true love between them and it is touching to watch at times. Apparently, The International Cut has more interactions between Mathilda and Leon, which i haven't seen yet. I must also add that the original script, which is available online, does have them making love. Again, reading the script does put it into context as to how she feels towards Leon and why she feels the need/want to make love. It is clear that anything outside of Leon's job and he is lost. That is the beauty of this film, with all its violence and profanity, and equally so the fate of Leon itself, it really shows the development of what one person can give to another. Gary Oldman's deserves much credit too. I won't go into detail about his character but i will say he is damn good. Watch out for the "Ev-ery-one" line, which i can imagine, if watched on the big screen in the cinema must have reverberated half way around town! A mention also to the character of Tony. We never really get any in depth explanations about him. He clearly is underhand, always keeping Leon's money and then only offering Mathilda $100 to last a whole month. The way he would say things and his mannerisms certainly suggest there is a lot more to him that meets they eye. There are so many stand out scenes in this film, all subtle, that it is hard to pick any individually. The film pretty much grabs you from start to end. It is a funny juxtaposition really, you find yourself caring so much for a killer! The soundtrack is equally as subtle and helps too by not being overpowering. The end titles have Sting's 'Shape of my Heart' which actually fits perfectly. The other piece of music within the film is the sublime, 'Venus as a Boy' by Bjork, which on first hearing/watching seems a strange choice. But on closer inspection he budding sexual overtones and growing feelings of the song match the way Mathilda was beginning to feel. All in all this is a good film. You care about both off the main characters. The final scene with Matilda finally telling the truth, albeit, so way out there and the planting of Leon's 'best friend' to take root, gives you a wonderful sense of knowing Mathilda will be fine and has found herself and where she wants to be. Equally, albeit dead, Leon's plant taking root, metaphorically gives you that same feeling. I will be searching out the 'International Version' just to add to the story but i would suggest the viewer seek out the original version as, having not seen the other one, the story seems to the point and well contained as it is. As a final point, as a David Lynch fan, i found one or two shots reminding me of Lynch. Maybe that is just me and believe me that is no criticism. It just struck me when watching. This is a film not for everyone due to the violent content but if you want to submerge yourself in Beeson's world and watch a film with some depth of emotion, then this is the film for you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Disappointed, but still a good movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rydogbball34
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I haven't been this excited for a movie, besides Pan's Labyrinth; however, the film falls below my lofty expectations. Natalie Portman's acting gets hailed, but it was really rough to watch. Her performance was comparable to Macaulay Culkin's in Home Alone. The burden can't be attributed solely to her as the writing was pretty odd (the dress-up scene & Matilda's infatuation with Leon. The plot is a simplistic, predictable revenge story. The opening sequence is really great, while Gary Oldman is solid as always. Matilda never even killed anyone after training for that the entire movie; no self-delivered end of innocence. It's not an 8.6, but closer to the 7-8 range. I gave it a 7 because I just watched great child acting in Let the Right One In before viewing this film. Overall, though, it's much better than the average movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    High Quality Crime Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    argo0403
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Leon is a brutal and veteran hit-man. He meets Mathilda, a young girl, and saves her from bad detectives. But, they kills her family so she lives with Leon. Although he declines her to live and talk with, he gradually becomes kind to her. At the same time, the remnants of the detectives tries to find them Though the story is very simple and there's no surprise, this crime movie compensates for that from brilliant performances by actors such as Jean Reno and Gary Oldman. I think Reno plays two roles in this. First is as a heartless assassin. This part is very cool. Second is as a friend or father of Mathilda. In contrast, this part is heart-warming and his smile is so charming that I can't help laughing. The thing I like in this movie is Oldman's madness. I have very strong impression from Darkknight series, so I can't believe that he plays such a crazy villain and I burst into laughs when his last scene. To be honest, I don't have sympathy with Mathilda so much. I always don't have it with young main character. Even though the last is predictable, it moves me. Good or worse, meeting someone really changes our life. &nbsp;This is not a masterpiece, but I'm very satisfied and touched by pure love of Leon.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A classic that totally holds up...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    agentvega
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film totally withstands the test of time. You can watch it today and it still feels just as fresh and relevant as when it came out. The international cut is better than the U.S. cut, but any version is worth the watch. Even as a kid, you can tell that Natalie Portman is destined for great things. I feel like even though Gary Oldman's character is a bit over the top, he still makes him as believable as possible. But, the stand out is obviously Jean Reno. Amazing as ever. Just a perfect roll for him. I must have seen this film at least 20 times, and every time I catch some little nuance that I missed in the past or just see something differently than I had before. It is just a great, if not underrated movie, and not only worth a viewing, but many. You surely will not be disappointed, and if you somehow are, give it another chance to grow on you. A very good friend of mine was not a fan upon first viewing, but now counts it as one of his favorites.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Violent movie with a heavy plot
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    digitalbeachbum
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I first saw this movie the only thing I could think about was the acting of Natalie Portman. Even at this age you could see her natural beauty and ability as an actor. The acting was awesome and the plot was well laid out, but I found several parts of the movie which weren't believable. I won't bother with them here, but you can see from my score that these scenes brought the movie down a few notches for me. I definitely would recommend this movie in HD or even 3D with a mega, killer sound system. It was really meant to be played on the big screen and small screens with crappy sound systems really do it an injustice. Every once in a while I see this on normal television and I watch it for laughs because they do the "pan and scan" which completely ruins the movie beyond words. I personally thing "pan and scan" should be against the law. Don't they already have this in France? Acting 1 Directing 1 Plot 1 Believability 0 Continuity .5 Natalie Portman 10 (no I'm not a pedo) Action 1 14.5 of 7
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent film with a gripping story!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Skyler Moody
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is absolutely brilliant and amazing! It is truly a unique film with fantastic acting and action that will hold you in its grasp. Where are the awards for this film? How come this film is unnoticed? With all of the amazing acting and great storyline, I am surprised this movie did not win an Oscar! Everybody was fantastic in this film! Jean Reno gives a heartwarming performance as a sad and lonely hit-man or "cleaner" named Leon who lives in a secluded world in a apartment complex and Natalie Portman's character Mathilda is the one that shatters Leon's secluded world. For this being her first feature film, Natalie Portman gives an amazing and astonishing performance as a troubled little girl with a desire for revenge. Gary Oldman is also fantastic as a twisted, sadistic, and corrupted DEA agent. He is on my list for Top 10 greatest villains ever! The unique love story and father-daughter type relationship between Leon and Mathilda is handled beautifully by director Luc Besson. You will feel so much sympathy for these characters. This movie is the perfect action with a unique love story and unforgettable characters and emotionally charged scenes! Everybody needs to see this movie!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Leon: The Professional (1994)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    William Richardson (valor992@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Personally this is the best movie I've ever seen. The character development, pacing, acting, and writing are so effective I always forget that Im even watching a movie. Another reason it draws you in so intuitively is the perfectly arranged soundtrack. Every scene is complimented with exactly the right number, allowing a deeper insight into the emotions being displayed on screen, weather it be a light of air of compassion or an adrenaline filled descant, the soundtrack never fails to hit its mark. This film has a special place in my life, for me its not just a movie, Its a piece of myself that I integrated into who I am and it forever changed me. Im so grateful to see that others understand the complexity and greatness of this movie and appreciate it as well. P.S. I love you Mathilda
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Admirable film.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Hannah Louise Mickleburgh
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    L&eacute;on, to put it simply, is a masterpiece. One of the greatest early-modern films, no doubt about it. Natalie Portman at 12 is already excellent, and given a chance so few have: while there are many younger actors a mere handful can win these starring roles, and in serious films they're too young to see. Comparable to Kick-Ass, though this original suspense flies past the modern indie-wannabe in daylight. Nothing was stilted nor pushed too far and the story, yet unmentioned, is simply insightful. The only reason I give an 8, not 9 or even 10, is because 8 is my favourite number, and so only given to those which are worthy. The actors own their roles, and should play these characters more often. (This is) A favourite that will (unexpectedly?) last a long time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the best films of all time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ABC DEF
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is one of my top 5 favorites of all time. Lot of reasons for it. It combines a great and interesting storyline, coupled with stellar acting performances. Oldman really puts the punch into the villainous role, he is terrific, but Portman steals away the show from everyone. It could be one of the top performances in a female role, and that too by a young girl. The novelty of the story is it's handling of the relationship between and elder man and young girl in an entirely different manner. The chemistry between Reno and Portman is amazing. Overall, the movie is great from the start to the end, including the climax.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "I Like These Calm Little Moments Before The Storm"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    CinemaClown
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    L&eacute;on is a stylish & solid action thriller that is today rightfully hailed as one of the greatest action films of all time. Superbly directed, swiftly paced, tightly edited & beautifully scored, L&eacute;on tells the story of a professional assassin who takes in a 12 year old girl when her family is brutally murdered by corrupt police officers and helps & trains her to exact revenge on those responsible for it. Also, this film is an odd look at their relationship which might turn out to be unsettling for some. Jean Reno stars as the best contract killer in town, L&eacute;on & did great justice to his character. Gary Oldman simply nailed his character by putting up a stupefying performance as corrupt DEA agent, Norman Stansfield, and also introducing Natalie Portman as Mathilda, who couldn't have asked for a more sensational debut. A classic in every way, L&eacute;on is violent, brutal & unsettling, yet is a brilliantly directed, superbly edited & beautifully photographed film that easily qualifies as a tremendously entertaining & memorable action masterpiece of all times. P.S. Make sure you grab the Extended Cut to fill up what might feel like loopholes in the Theatrical version.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    He's Venus As A Boy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bbcfilmlover
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Leon is another film i haven't watched for years but when i originally saw it, i really loved the film. Of course i am reviewing the original cinematic/DVD release. For your information, Director Luc Beeson classes this as 'The Director's Cut', as it has many scenes deleted from the original test showing. I believe, two years later, Beeson re-edited all of those scenes back in. Apparently 25 minutes extra. That version, confusingly, is known as 'The Director's Cut', though Beeson, keeping in mind his view of the naming of his Director's Cut, calls this 'The Internatinal Cut'. Confused? This is a really enthralling film which keeps you emotionally involved throughout. Yes, it is a violent film in places but that is not what the story is about. It is about finding yourself and who you are. Taking root and allowing people in, when you weren't able to before. Natalie Portman absolutely shines in this. Havig been cast at 11, now 12, she is totally believable as Mathilda. It must have been tough to pull off some scenes at such a young age. Whilst Jean Reno is wonderful as Leon, it is Portman's portrayal of the character dealing with the loss of her abusive, uncaring family, while grieving for the loss of her 4 year old brother and her subsequent journey of revenge and finding herself just like Leon, that makes her performance so strong. Now, it must be said there are elements of an undercurrent of a possible sexual relationship between them both. Early on Mathilda shows signs of holding herself in certain way that shows a possible move into puberty. Take a look at the scenes of her hanging over the staircase for this. It is clear that as the film develops there is a growing love between them. Look out for Mathilda sleeping with the pig oven glove on the first night. A subtle moments, easily missed. However, the way Reno plays his character with a few learning difficulties, naivety and his reluctance to accept anything outside his comfort zone, the sexuality elements do not come across as dirty at all. There really does seem to be a developing true love between them and it is touching to watch at times. Apparently, The International Cut has more interactions between Mathilda and Leon, which i haven't seen yet. I must also add that the original script, which is available online, does have them making love. Again, reading the script does put it into context as to how she feels towards Leon and why she feels the need/want to make love. It is clear that anything outside of Leon's job and he is lost. That is the beauty of this film, with all its violence and profanity, and equally so the fate of Leon itself, it really shows the development of what one person can give to another. Gary Oldman's deserves much credit too. I won't go into detail about his character but i will say he is damn good. Watch out for the "Ev-ery-one" line, which i can imagine, if watched on the big screen in the cinema must have reverberated half way around town! A mention also to the character of Tony. We never really get any in depth explanations about him. He clearly is underhand, always keeping Leon's money and then only offering Mathilda $100 to last a whole month. The way he would say things and his mannerisms certainly suggest there is a lot more to him that meets they eye. There are so many stand out scenes in this film, all subtle, that it is hard to pick any individually. The film pretty much grabs you from start to end. It is a funny juxtaposition really, you find yourself caring so much for a killer! The soundtrack is equally as subtle and helps too by not being overpowering. The end titles have Sting's 'Shape of my Heart' which actually fits perfectly. The other piece of music within the film is the sublime, 'Venus as a Boy' by Bjork, which on first hearing/watching seems a strange choice. But on closer inspection he budding sexual overtones and growing feelings of the song match the way Mathilda was beginning to feel. All in all this is a good film. You care about both off the main characters. The final scene with Matilda finally telling the truth, albeit, so way out there and the planting of Leon's 'best friend' to take root, gives you a wonderful sense of knowing Mathilda will be fine and has found herself and where she wants to be. Equally, albeit dead, Leon's plant taking root, metaphorically gives you that same feeling. I will be searching out the 'International Version' just to add to the story but i would suggest the viewer seek out the original version as, having not seen the other one, the story seems to the point and well contained as it is. As a final point, as a David Lynch fan, i found one or two shots reminding me of Lynch. Maybe that is just me and believe me that is no criticism. It just struck me when watching. This is a film not for everyone due to the violent content but if you want to submerge yourself in Beeson's world and watch a film with some depth of emotion, then this is the film for you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Disappointed, but still a good movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rydogbball34
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I haven't been this excited for a movie, besides Pan's Labyrinth; however, the film falls below my lofty expectations. Natalie Portman's acting gets hailed, but it was really rough to watch. Her performance was comparable to Macaulay Culkin's in Home Alone. The burden can't be attributed solely to her as the writing was pretty odd (the dress-up scene & Matilda's infatuation with Leon. The plot is a simplistic, predictable revenge story. The opening sequence is really great, while Gary Oldman is solid as always. Matilda never even killed anyone after training for that the entire movie; no self-delivered end of innocence. It's not an 8.6, but closer to the 7-8 range. I gave it a 7 because I just watched great child acting in Let the Right One In before viewing this film. Overall, though, it's much better than the average movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    High Quality Crime Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    argo0403
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Leon is a brutal and veteran hit-man. He meets Mathilda, a young girl, and saves her from bad detectives. But, they kills her family so she lives with Leon. Although he declines her to live and talk with, he gradually becomes kind to her. At the same time, the remnants of the detectives tries to find them Though the story is very simple and there's no surprise, this crime movie compensates for that from brilliant performances by actors such as Jean Reno and Gary Oldman. I think Reno plays two roles in this. First is as a heartless assassin. This part is very cool. Second is as a friend or father of Mathilda. In contrast, this part is heart-warming and his smile is so charming that I can't help laughing. The thing I like in this movie is Oldman's madness. I have very strong impression from Darkknight series, so I can't believe that he plays such a crazy villain and I burst into laughs when his last scene. To be honest, I don't have sympathy with Mathilda so much. I always don't have it with young main character. Even though the last is predictable, it moves me. Good or worse, meeting someone really changes our life. &nbsp;This is not a masterpiece, but I'm very satisfied and touched by pure love of Leon.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A classic that totally holds up...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    agentvega
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film totally withstands the test of time. You can watch it today and it still feels just as fresh and relevant as when it came out. The international cut is better than the U.S. cut, but any version is worth the watch. Even as a kid, you can tell that Natalie Portman is destined for great things. I feel like even though Gary Oldman's character is a bit over the top, he still makes him as believable as possible. But, the stand out is obviously Jean Reno. Amazing as ever. Just a perfect roll for him. I must have seen this film at least 20 times, and every time I catch some little nuance that I missed in the past or just see something differently than I had before. It is just a great, if not underrated movie, and not only worth a viewing, but many. You surely will not be disappointed, and if you somehow are, give it another chance to grow on you. A very good friend of mine was not a fan upon first viewing, but now counts it as one of his favorites.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Violent movie with a heavy plot
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    digitalbeachbum
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I first saw this movie the only thing I could think about was the acting of Natalie Portman. Even at this age you could see her natural beauty and ability as an actor. The acting was awesome and the plot was well laid out, but I found several parts of the movie which weren't believable. I won't bother with them here, but you can see from my score that these scenes brought the movie down a few notches for me. I definitely would recommend this movie in HD or even 3D with a mega, killer sound system. It was really meant to be played on the big screen and small screens with crappy sound systems really do it an injustice. Every once in a while I see this on normal television and I watch it for laughs because they do the "pan and scan" which completely ruins the movie beyond words. I personally thing "pan and scan" should be against the law. Don't they already have this in France? Acting 1 Directing 1 Plot 1 Believability 0 Continuity .5 Natalie Portman 10 (no I'm not a pedo) Action 1 14.5 of 7
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent film with a gripping story!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Skyler Moody
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is absolutely brilliant and amazing! It is truly a unique film with fantastic acting and action that will hold you in its grasp. Where are the awards for this film? How come this film is unnoticed? With all of the amazing acting and great storyline, I am surprised this movie did not win an Oscar! Everybody was fantastic in this film! Jean Reno gives a heartwarming performance as a sad and lonely hit-man or "cleaner" named Leon who lives in a secluded world in a apartment complex and Natalie Portman's character Mathilda is the one that shatters Leon's secluded world. For this being her first feature film, Natalie Portman gives an amazing and astonishing performance as a troubled little girl with a desire for revenge. Gary Oldman is also fantastic as a twisted, sadistic, and corrupted DEA agent. He is on my list for Top 10 greatest villains ever! The unique love story and father-daughter type relationship between Leon and Mathilda is handled beautifully by director Luc Besson. You will feel so much sympathy for these characters. This movie is the perfect action with a unique love story and unforgettable characters and emotionally charged scenes! Everybody needs to see this movie!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Leon: The Professional (1994)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    William Richardson (valor992@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Personally this is the best movie I've ever seen. The character development, pacing, acting, and writing are so effective I always forget that Im even watching a movie. Another reason it draws you in so intuitively is the perfectly arranged soundtrack. Every scene is complimented with exactly the right number, allowing a deeper insight into the emotions being displayed on screen, weather it be a light of air of compassion or an adrenaline filled descant, the soundtrack never fails to hit its mark. This film has a special place in my life, for me its not just a movie, Its a piece of myself that I integrated into who I am and it forever changed me. Im so grateful to see that others understand the complexity and greatness of this movie and appreciate it as well. P.S. I love you Mathilda
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Admirable film.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Hannah Louise Mickleburgh
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    L&eacute;on, to put it simply, is a masterpiece. One of the greatest early-modern films, no doubt about it. Natalie Portman at 12 is already excellent, and given a chance so few have: while there are many younger actors a mere handful can win these starring roles, and in serious films they're too young to see. Comparable to Kick-Ass, though this original suspense flies past the modern indie-wannabe in daylight. Nothing was stilted nor pushed too far and the story, yet unmentioned, is simply insightful. The only reason I give an 8, not 9 or even 10, is because 8 is my favourite number, and so only given to those which are worthy. The actors own their roles, and should play these characters more often. (This is) A favourite that will (unexpectedly?) last a long time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the best films of all time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ABC DEF
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is one of my top 5 favorites of all time. Lot of reasons for it. It combines a great and interesting storyline, coupled with stellar acting performances. Oldman really puts the punch into the villainous role, he is terrific, but Portman steals away the show from everyone. It could be one of the top performances in a female role, and that too by a young girl. The novelty of the story is it's handling of the relationship between and elder man and young girl in an entirely different manner. The chemistry between Reno and Portman is amazing. Overall, the movie is great from the start to the end, including the climax.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "I Like These Calm Little Moments Before The Storm"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    CinemaClown
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    L&eacute;on is a stylish & solid action thriller that is today rightfully hailed as one of the greatest action films of all time. Superbly directed, swiftly paced, tightly edited & beautifully scored, L&eacute;on tells the story of a professional assassin who takes in a 12 year old girl when her family is brutally murdered by corrupt police officers and helps & trains her to exact revenge on those responsible for it. Also, this film is an odd look at their relationship which might turn out to be unsettling for some. Jean Reno stars as the best contract killer in town, L&eacute;on & did great justice to his character. Gary Oldman simply nailed his character by putting up a stupefying performance as corrupt DEA agent, Norman Stansfield, and also introducing Natalie Portman as Mathilda, who couldn't have asked for a more sensational debut. A classic in every way, L&eacute;on is violent, brutal & unsettling, yet is a brilliantly directed, superbly edited & beautifully photographed film that easily qualifies as a tremendously entertaining & memorable action masterpiece of all times. P.S. Make sure you grab the Extended Cut to fill up what might feel like loopholes in the Theatrical version.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    He's Venus As A Boy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bbcfilmlover
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Leon is another film i haven't watched for years but when i originally saw it, i really loved the film. Of course i am reviewing the original cinematic/DVD release. For your information, Director Luc Beeson classes this as 'The Director's Cut', as it has many scenes deleted from the original test showing. I believe, two years later, Beeson re-edited all of those scenes back in. Apparently 25 minutes extra. That version, confusingly, is known as 'The Director's Cut', though Beeson, keeping in mind his view of the naming of his Director's Cut, calls this 'The Internatinal Cut'. Confused? This is a really enthralling film which keeps you emotionally involved throughout. Yes, it is a violent film in places but that is not what the story is about. It is about finding yourself and who you are. Taking root and allowing people in, when you weren't able to before. Natalie Portman absolutely shines in this. Havig been cast at 11, now 12, she is totally believable as Mathilda. It must have been tough to pull off some scenes at such a young age. Whilst Jean Reno is wonderful as Leon, it is Portman's portrayal of the character dealing with the loss of her abusive, uncaring family, while grieving for the loss of her 4 year old brother and her subsequent journey of revenge and finding herself just like Leon, that makes her performance so strong. Now, it must be said there are elements of an undercurrent of a possible sexual relationship between them both. Early on Mathilda shows signs of holding herself in certain way that shows a possible move into puberty. Take a look at the scenes of her hanging over the staircase for this. It is clear that as the film develops there is a growing love between them. Look out for Mathilda sleeping with the pig oven glove on the first night. A subtle moments, easily missed. However, the way Reno plays his character with a few learning difficulties, naivety and his reluctance to accept anything outside his comfort zone, the sexuality elements do not come across as dirty at all. There really does seem to be a developing true love between them and it is touching to watch at times. Apparently, The International Cut has more interactions between Mathilda and Leon, which i haven't seen yet. I must also add that the original script, which is available online, does have them making love. Again, reading the script does put it into context as to how she feels towards Leon and why she feels the need/want to make love. It is clear that anything outside of Leon's job and he is lost. That is the beauty of this film, with all its violence and profanity, and equally so the fate of Leon itself, it really shows the development of what one person can give to another. Gary Oldman's deserves much credit too. I won't go into detail about his character but i will say he is damn good. Watch out for the "Ev-ery-one" line, which i can imagine, if watched on the big screen in the cinema must have reverberated half way around town! A mention also to the character of Tony. We never really get any in depth explanations about him. He clearly is underhand, always keeping Leon's money and then only offering Mathilda $100 to last a whole month. The way he would say things and his mannerisms certainly suggest there is a lot more to him that meets they eye. There are so many stand out scenes in this film, all subtle, that it is hard to pick any individually. The film pretty much grabs you from start to end. It is a funny juxtaposition really, you find yourself caring so much for a killer! The soundtrack is equally as subtle and helps too by not being overpowering. The end titles have Sting's 'Shape of my Heart' which actually fits perfectly. The other piece of music within the film is the sublime, 'Venus as a Boy' by Bjork, which on first hearing/watching seems a strange choice. But on closer inspection he budding sexual overtones and growing feelings of the song match the way Mathilda was beginning to feel. All in all this is a good film. You care about both off the main characters. The final scene with Matilda finally telling the truth, albeit, so way out there and the planting of Leon's 'best friend' to take root, gives you a wonderful sense of knowing Mathilda will be fine and has found herself and where she wants to be. Equally, albeit dead, Leon's plant taking root, metaphorically gives you that same feeling. I will be searching out the 'International Version' just to add to the story but i would suggest the viewer seek out the original version as, having not seen the other one, the story seems to the point and well contained as it is. As a final point, as a David Lynch fan, i found one or two shots reminding me of Lynch. Maybe that is just me and believe me that is no criticism. It just struck me when watching. This is a film not for everyone due to the violent content but if you want to submerge yourself in Beeson's world and watch a film with some depth of emotion, then this is the film for you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Disappointed, but still a good movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rydogbball34
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I haven't been this excited for a movie, besides Pan's Labyrinth; however, the film falls below my lofty expectations. Natalie Portman's acting gets hailed, but it was really rough to watch. Her performance was comparable to Macaulay Culkin's in Home Alone. The burden can't be attributed solely to her as the writing was pretty odd (the dress-up scene & Matilda's infatuation with Leon. The plot is a simplistic, predictable revenge story. The opening sequence is really great, while Gary Oldman is solid as always. Matilda never even killed anyone after training for that the entire movie; no self-delivered end of innocence. It's not an 8.6, but closer to the 7-8 range. I gave it a 7 because I just watched great child acting in Let the Right One In before viewing this film. Overall, though, it's much better than the average movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    High Quality Crime Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    argo0403
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Leon is a brutal and veteran hit-man. He meets Mathilda, a young girl, and saves her from bad detectives. But, they kills her family so she lives with Leon. Although he declines her to live and talk with, he gradually becomes kind to her. At the same time, the remnants of the detectives tries to find them Though the story is very simple and there's no surprise, this crime movie compensates for that from brilliant performances by actors such as Jean Reno and Gary Oldman. I think Reno plays two roles in this. First is as a heartless assassin. This part is very cool. Second is as a friend or father of Mathilda. In contrast, this part is heart-warming and his smile is so charming that I can't help laughing. The thing I like in this movie is Oldman's madness. I have very strong impression from Darkknight series, so I can't believe that he plays such a crazy villain and I burst into laughs when his last scene. To be honest, I don't have sympathy with Mathilda so much. I always don't have it with young main character. Even though the last is predictable, it moves me. Good or worse, meeting someone really changes our life. &nbsp;This is not a masterpiece, but I'm very satisfied and touched by pure love of Leon.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A classic that totally holds up...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    agentvega
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film totally withstands the test of time. You can watch it today and it still feels just as fresh and relevant as when it came out. The international cut is better than the U.S. cut, but any version is worth the watch. Even as a kid, you can tell that Natalie Portman is destined for great things. I feel like even though Gary Oldman's character is a bit over the top, he still makes him as believable as possible. But, the stand out is obviously Jean Reno. Amazing as ever. Just a perfect roll for him. I must have seen this film at least 20 times, and every time I catch some little nuance that I missed in the past or just see something differently than I had before. It is just a great, if not underrated movie, and not only worth a viewing, but many. You surely will not be disappointed, and if you somehow are, give it another chance to grow on you. A very good friend of mine was not a fan upon first viewing, but now counts it as one of his favorites.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Violent movie with a heavy plot
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    digitalbeachbum
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I first saw this movie the only thing I could think about was the acting of Natalie Portman. Even at this age you could see her natural beauty and ability as an actor. The acting was awesome and the plot was well laid out, but I found several parts of the movie which weren't believable. I won't bother with them here, but you can see from my score that these scenes brought the movie down a few notches for me. I definitely would recommend this movie in HD or even 3D with a mega, killer sound system. It was really meant to be played on the big screen and small screens with crappy sound systems really do it an injustice. Every once in a while I see this on normal television and I watch it for laughs because they do the "pan and scan" which completely ruins the movie beyond words. I personally thing "pan and scan" should be against the law. Don't they already have this in France? Acting 1 Directing 1 Plot 1 Believability 0 Continuity .5 Natalie Portman 10 (no I'm not a pedo) Action 1 14.5 of 7
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent film with a gripping story!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Skyler Moody
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is absolutely brilliant and amazing! It is truly a unique film with fantastic acting and action that will hold you in its grasp. Where are the awards for this film? How come this film is unnoticed? With all of the amazing acting and great storyline, I am surprised this movie did not win an Oscar! Everybody was fantastic in this film! Jean Reno gives a heartwarming performance as a sad and lonely hit-man or "cleaner" named Leon who lives in a secluded world in a apartment complex and Natalie Portman's character Mathilda is the one that shatters Leon's secluded world. For this being her first feature film, Natalie Portman gives an amazing and astonishing performance as a troubled little girl with a desire for revenge. Gary Oldman is also fantastic as a twisted, sadistic, and corrupted DEA agent. He is on my list for Top 10 greatest villains ever! The unique love story and father-daughter type relationship between Leon and Mathilda is handled beautifully by director Luc Besson. You will feel so much sympathy for these characters. This movie is the perfect action with a unique love story and unforgettable characters and emotionally charged scenes! Everybody needs to see this movie!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Leon: The Professional (1994)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    William Richardson (valor992@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Personally this is the best movie I've ever seen. The character development, pacing, acting, and writing are so effective I always forget that Im even watching a movie. Another reason it draws you in so intuitively is the perfectly arranged soundtrack. Every scene is complimented with exactly the right number, allowing a deeper insight into the emotions being displayed on screen, weather it be a light of air of compassion or an adrenaline filled descant, the soundtrack never fails to hit its mark. This film has a special place in my life, for me its not just a movie, Its a piece of myself that I integrated into who I am and it forever changed me. Im so grateful to see that others understand the complexity and greatness of this movie and appreciate it as well. P.S. I love you Mathilda
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Admirable film.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Hannah Louise Mickleburgh
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    L&eacute;on, to put it simply, is a masterpiece. One of the greatest early-modern films, no doubt about it. Natalie Portman at 12 is already excellent, and given a chance so few have: while there are many younger actors a mere handful can win these starring roles, and in serious films they're too young to see. Comparable to Kick-Ass, though this original suspense flies past the modern indie-wannabe in daylight. Nothing was stilted nor pushed too far and the story, yet unmentioned, is simply insightful. The only reason I give an 8, not 9 or even 10, is because 8 is my favourite number, and so only given to those which are worthy. The actors own their roles, and should play these characters more often. (This is) A favourite that will (unexpectedly?) last a long time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the best films of all time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ABC DEF
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is one of my top 5 favorites of all time. Lot of reasons for it. It combines a great and interesting storyline, coupled with stellar acting performances. Oldman really puts the punch into the villainous role, he is terrific, but Portman steals away the show from everyone. It could be one of the top performances in a female role, and that too by a young girl. The novelty of the story is it's handling of the relationship between and elder man and young girl in an entirely different manner. The chemistry between Reno and Portman is amazing. Overall, the movie is great from the start to the end, including the climax.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "I Like These Calm Little Moments Before The Storm"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    CinemaClown
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    L&eacute;on is a stylish & solid action thriller that is today rightfully hailed as one of the greatest action films of all time. Superbly directed, swiftly paced, tightly edited & beautifully scored, L&eacute;on tells the story of a professional assassin who takes in a 12 year old girl when her family is brutally murdered by corrupt police officers and helps & trains her to exact revenge on those responsible for it. Also, this film is an odd look at their relationship which might turn out to be unsettling for some. Jean Reno stars as the best contract killer in town, L&eacute;on & did great justice to his character. Gary Oldman simply nailed his character by putting up a stupefying performance as corrupt DEA agent, Norman Stansfield, and also introducing Natalie Portman as Mathilda, who couldn't have asked for a more sensational debut. A classic in every way, L&eacute;on is violent, brutal & unsettling, yet is a brilliantly directed, superbly edited & beautifully photographed film that easily qualifies as a tremendously entertaining & memorable action masterpiece of all times. P.S. Make sure you grab the Extended Cut to fill up what might feel like loopholes in the Theatrical version.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    He's Venus As A Boy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bbcfilmlover
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Leon is another film i haven't watched for years but when i originally saw it, i really loved the film. Of course i am reviewing the original cinematic/DVD release. For your information, Director Luc Beeson classes this as 'The Director's Cut', as it has many scenes deleted from the original test showing. I believe, two years later, Beeson re-edited all of those scenes back in. Apparently 25 minutes extra. That version, confusingly, is known as 'The Director's Cut', though Beeson, keeping in mind his view of the naming of his Director's Cut, calls this 'The Internatinal Cut'. Confused? This is a really enthralling film which keeps you emotionally involved throughout. Yes, it is a violent film in places but that is not what the story is about. It is about finding yourself and who you are. Taking root and allowing people in, when you weren't able to before. Natalie Portman absolutely shines in this. Havig been cast at 11, now 12, she is totally believable as Mathilda. It must have been tough to pull off some scenes at such a young age. Whilst Jean Reno is wonderful as Leon, it is Portman's portrayal of the character dealing with the loss of her abusive, uncaring family, while grieving for the loss of her 4 year old brother and her subsequent journey of revenge and finding herself just like Leon, that makes her performance so strong. Now, it must be said there are elements of an undercurrent of a possible sexual relationship between them both. Early on Mathilda shows signs of holding herself in certain way that shows a possible move into puberty. Take a look at the scenes of her hanging over the staircase for this. It is clear that as the film develops there is a growing love between them. Look out for Mathilda sleeping with the pig oven glove on the first night. A subtle moments, easily missed. However, the way Reno plays his character with a few learning difficulties, naivety and his reluctance to accept anything outside his comfort zone, the sexuality elements do not come across as dirty at all. There really does seem to be a developing true love between them and it is touching to watch at times. Apparently, The International Cut has more interactions between Mathilda and Leon, which i haven't seen yet. I must also add that the original script, which is available online, does have them making love. Again, reading the script does put it into context as to how she feels towards Leon and why she feels the need/want to make love. It is clear that anything outside of Leon's job and he is lost. That is the beauty of this film, with all its violence and profanity, and equally so the fate of Leon itself, it really shows the development of what one person can give to another. Gary Oldman's deserves much credit too. I won't go into detail about his character but i will say he is damn good. Watch out for the "Ev-ery-one" line, which i can imagine, if watched on the big screen in the cinema must have reverberated half way around town! A mention also to the character of Tony. We never really get any in depth explanations about him. He clearly is underhand, always keeping Leon's money and then only offering Mathilda $100 to last a whole month. The way he would say things and his mannerisms certainly suggest there is a lot more to him that meets they eye. There are so many stand out scenes in this film, all subtle, that it is hard to pick any individually. The film pretty much grabs you from start to end. It is a funny juxtaposition really, you find yourself caring so much for a killer! The soundtrack is equally as subtle and helps too by not being overpowering. The end titles have Sting's 'Shape of my Heart' which actually fits perfectly. The other piece of music within the film is the sublime, 'Venus as a Boy' by Bjork, which on first hearing/watching seems a strange choice. But on closer inspection he budding sexual overtones and growing feelings of the song match the way Mathilda was beginning to feel. All in all this is a good film. You care about both off the main characters. The final scene with Matilda finally telling the truth, albeit, so way out there and the planting of Leon's 'best friend' to take root, gives you a wonderful sense of knowing Mathilda will be fine and has found herself and where she wants to be. Equally, albeit dead, Leon's plant taking root, metaphorically gives you that same feeling. I will be searching out the 'International Version' just to add to the story but i would suggest the viewer seek out the original version as, having not seen the other one, the story seems to the point and well contained as it is. As a final point, as a David Lynch fan, i found one or two shots reminding me of Lynch. Maybe that is just me and believe me that is no criticism. It just struck me when watching. This is a film not for everyone due to the violent content but if you want to submerge yourself in Beeson's world and watch a film with some depth of emotion, then this is the film for you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Disappointed, but still a good movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rydogbball34
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I haven't been this excited for a movie, besides Pan's Labyrinth; however, the film falls below my lofty expectations. Natalie Portman's acting gets hailed, but it was really rough to watch. Her performance was comparable to Macaulay Culkin's in Home Alone. The burden can't be attributed solely to her as the writing was pretty odd (the dress-up scene & Matilda's infatuation with Leon. The plot is a simplistic, predictable revenge story. The opening sequence is really great, while Gary Oldman is solid as always. Matilda never even killed anyone after training for that the entire movie; no self-delivered end of innocence. It's not an 8.6, but closer to the 7-8 range. I gave it a 7 because I just watched great child acting in Let the Right One In before viewing this film. Overall, though, it's much better than the average movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    High Quality Crime Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    argo0403
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Leon is a brutal and veteran hit-man. He meets Mathilda, a young girl, and saves her from bad detectives. But, they kills her family so she lives with Leon. Although he declines her to live and talk with, he gradually becomes kind to her. At the same time, the remnants of the detectives tries to find them Though the story is very simple and there's no surprise, this crime movie compensates for that from brilliant performances by actors such as Jean Reno and Gary Oldman. I think Reno plays two roles in this. First is as a heartless assassin. This part is very cool. Second is as a friend or father of Mathilda. In contrast, this part is heart-warming and his smile is so charming that I can't help laughing. The thing I like in this movie is Oldman's madness. I have very strong impression from Darkknight series, so I can't believe that he plays such a crazy villain and I burst into laughs when his last scene. To be honest, I don't have sympathy with Mathilda so much. I always don't have it with young main character. Even though the last is predictable, it moves me. Good or worse, meeting someone really changes our life. &nbsp;This is not a masterpiece, but I'm very satisfied and touched by pure love of Leon.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A classic that totally holds up...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    agentvega
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film totally withstands the test of time. You can watch it today and it still feels just as fresh and relevant as when it came out. The international cut is better than the U.S. cut, but any version is worth the watch. Even as a kid, you can tell that Natalie Portman is destined for great things. I feel like even though Gary Oldman's character is a bit over the top, he still makes him as believable as possible. But, the stand out is obviously Jean Reno. Amazing as ever. Just a perfect roll for him. I must have seen this film at least 20 times, and every time I catch some little nuance that I missed in the past or just see something differently than I had before. It is just a great, if not underrated movie, and not only worth a viewing, but many. You surely will not be disappointed, and if you somehow are, give it another chance to grow on you. A very good friend of mine was not a fan upon first viewing, but now counts it as one of his favorites.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Violent movie with a heavy plot
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    digitalbeachbum
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I first saw this movie the only thing I could think about was the acting of Natalie Portman. Even at this age you could see her natural beauty and ability as an actor. The acting was awesome and the plot was well laid out, but I found several parts of the movie which weren't believable. I won't bother with them here, but you can see from my score that these scenes brought the movie down a few notches for me. I definitely would recommend this movie in HD or even 3D with a mega, killer sound system. It was really meant to be played on the big screen and small screens with crappy sound systems really do it an injustice. Every once in a while I see this on normal television and I watch it for laughs because they do the "pan and scan" which completely ruins the movie beyond words. I personally thing "pan and scan" should be against the law. Don't they already have this in France? Acting 1 Directing 1 Plot 1 Believability 0 Continuity .5 Natalie Portman 10 (no I'm not a pedo) Action 1 14.5 of 7
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent film with a gripping story!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Skyler Moody
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is absolutely brilliant and amazing! It is truly a unique film with fantastic acting and action that will hold you in its grasp. Where are the awards for this film? How come this film is unnoticed? With all of the amazing acting and great storyline, I am surprised this movie did not win an Oscar! Everybody was fantastic in this film! Jean Reno gives a heartwarming performance as a sad and lonely hit-man or "cleaner" named Leon who lives in a secluded world in a apartment complex and Natalie Portman's character Mathilda is the one that shatters Leon's secluded world. For this being her first feature film, Natalie Portman gives an amazing and astonishing performance as a troubled little girl with a desire for revenge. Gary Oldman is also fantastic as a twisted, sadistic, and corrupted DEA agent. He is on my list for Top 10 greatest villains ever! The unique love story and father-daughter type relationship between Leon and Mathilda is handled beautifully by director Luc Besson. You will feel so much sympathy for these characters. This movie is the perfect action with a unique love story and unforgettable characters and emotionally charged scenes! Everybody needs to see this movie!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Leon: The Professional (1994)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    William Richardson (valor992@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Personally this is the best movie I've ever seen. The character development, pacing, acting, and writing are so effective I always forget that Im even watching a movie. Another reason it draws you in so intuitively is the perfectly arranged soundtrack. Every scene is complimented with exactly the right number, allowing a deeper insight into the emotions being displayed on screen, weather it be a light of air of compassion or an adrenaline filled descant, the soundtrack never fails to hit its mark. This film has a special place in my life, for me its not just a movie, Its a piece of myself that I integrated into who I am and it forever changed me. Im so grateful to see that others understand the complexity and greatness of this movie and appreciate it as well. P.S. I love you Mathilda
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Admirable film.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Hannah Louise Mickleburgh
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    L&eacute;on, to put it simply, is a masterpiece. One of the greatest early-modern films, no doubt about it. Natalie Portman at 12 is already excellent, and given a chance so few have: while there are many younger actors a mere handful can win these starring roles, and in serious films they're too young to see. Comparable to Kick-Ass, though this original suspense flies past the modern indie-wannabe in daylight. Nothing was stilted nor pushed too far and the story, yet unmentioned, is simply insightful. The only reason I give an 8, not 9 or even 10, is because 8 is my favourite number, and so only given to those which are worthy. The actors own their roles, and should play these characters more often. (This is) A favourite that will (unexpectedly?) last a long time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the best films of all time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ABC DEF
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is one of my top 5 favorites of all time. Lot of reasons for it. It combines a great and interesting storyline, coupled with stellar acting performances. Oldman really puts the punch into the villainous role, he is terrific, but Portman steals away the show from everyone. It could be one of the top performances in a female role, and that too by a young girl. The novelty of the story is it's handling of the relationship between and elder man and young girl in an entirely different manner. The chemistry between Reno and Portman is amazing. Overall, the movie is great from the start to the end, including the climax.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "I Like These Calm Little Moments Before The Storm"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    CinemaClown
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    L&eacute;on is a stylish & solid action thriller that is today rightfully hailed as one of the greatest action films of all time. Superbly directed, swiftly paced, tightly edited & beautifully scored, L&eacute;on tells the story of a professional assassin who takes in a 12 year old girl when her family is brutally murdered by corrupt police officers and helps & trains her to exact revenge on those responsible for it. Also, this film is an odd look at their relationship which might turn out to be unsettling for some. Jean Reno stars as the best contract killer in town, L&eacute;on & did great justice to his character. Gary Oldman simply nailed his character by putting up a stupefying performance as corrupt DEA agent, Norman Stansfield, and also introducing Natalie Portman as Mathilda, who couldn't have asked for a more sensational debut. A classic in every way, L&eacute;on is violent, brutal & unsettling, yet is a brilliantly directed, superbly edited & beautifully photographed film that easily qualifies as a tremendously entertaining & memorable action masterpiece of all times. P.S. Make sure you grab the Extended Cut to fill up what might feel like loopholes in the Theatrical version.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    He's Venus As A Boy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bbcfilmlover
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Leon is another film i haven't watched for years but when i originally saw it, i really loved the film. Of course i am reviewing the original cinematic/DVD release. For your information, Director Luc Beeson classes this as 'The Director's Cut', as it has many scenes deleted from the original test showing. I believe, two years later, Beeson re-edited all of those scenes back in. Apparently 25 minutes extra. That version, confusingly, is known as 'The Director's Cut', though Beeson, keeping in mind his view of the naming of his Director's Cut, calls this 'The Internatinal Cut'. Confused? This is a really enthralling film which keeps you emotionally involved throughout. Yes, it is a violent film in places but that is not what the story is about. It is about finding yourself and who you are. Taking root and allowing people in, when you weren't able to before. Natalie Portman absolutely shines in this. Havig been cast at 11, now 12, she is totally believable as Mathilda. It must have been tough to pull off some scenes at such a young age. Whilst Jean Reno is wonderful as Leon, it is Portman's portrayal of the character dealing with the loss of her abusive, uncaring family, while grieving for the loss of her 4 year old brother and her subsequent journey of revenge and finding herself just like Leon, that makes her performance so strong. Now, it must be said there are elements of an undercurrent of a possible sexual relationship between them both. Early on Mathilda shows signs of holding herself in certain way that shows a possible move into puberty. Take a look at the scenes of her hanging over the staircase for this. It is clear that as the film develops there is a growing love between them. Look out for Mathilda sleeping with the pig oven glove on the first night. A subtle moments, easily missed. However, the way Reno plays his character with a few learning difficulties, naivety and his reluctance to accept anything outside his comfort zone, the sexuality elements do not come across as dirty at all. There really does seem to be a developing true love between them and it is touching to watch at times. Apparently, The International Cut has more interactions between Mathilda and Leon, which i haven't seen yet. I must also add that the original script, which is available online, does have them making love. Again, reading the script does put it into context as to how she feels towards Leon and why she feels the need/want to make love. It is clear that anything outside of Leon's job and he is lost. That is the beauty of this film, with all its violence and profanity, and equally so the fate of Leon itself, it really shows the development of what one person can give to another. Gary Oldman's deserves much credit too. I won't go into detail about his character but i will say he is damn good. Watch out for the "Ev-ery-one" line, which i can imagine, if watched on the big screen in the cinema must have reverberated half way around town! A mention also to the character of Tony. We never really get any in depth explanations about him. He clearly is underhand, always keeping Leon's money and then only offering Mathilda $100 to last a whole month. The way he would say things and his mannerisms certainly suggest there is a lot more to him that meets they eye. There are so many stand out scenes in this film, all subtle, that it is hard to pick any individually. The film pretty much grabs you from start to end. It is a funny juxtaposition really, you find yourself caring so much for a killer! The soundtrack is equally as subtle and helps too by not being overpowering. The end titles have Sting's 'Shape of my Heart' which actually fits perfectly. The other piece of music within the film is the sublime, 'Venus as a Boy' by Bjork, which on first hearing/watching seems a strange choice. But on closer inspection he budding sexual overtones and growing feelings of the song match the way Mathilda was beginning to feel. All in all this is a good film. You care about both off the main characters. The final scene with Matilda finally telling the truth, albeit, so way out there and the planting of Leon's 'best friend' to take root, gives you a wonderful sense of knowing Mathilda will be fine and has found herself and where she wants to be. Equally, albeit dead, Leon's plant taking root, metaphorically gives you that same feeling. I will be searching out the 'International Version' just to add to the story but i would suggest the viewer seek out the original version as, having not seen the other one, the story seems to the point and well contained as it is. As a final point, as a David Lynch fan, i found one or two shots reminding me of Lynch. Maybe that is just me and believe me that is no criticism. It just struck me when watching. This is a film not for everyone due to the violent content but if you want to submerge yourself in Beeson's world and watch a film with some depth of emotion, then this is the film for you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Disappointed, but still a good movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rydogbball34
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I haven't been this excited for a movie, besides Pan's Labyrinth; however, the film falls below my lofty expectations. Natalie Portman's acting gets hailed, but it was really rough to watch. Her performance was comparable to Macaulay Culkin's in Home Alone. The burden can't be attributed solely to her as the writing was pretty odd (the dress-up scene & Matilda's infatuation with Leon. The plot is a simplistic, predictable revenge story. The opening sequence is really great, while Gary Oldman is solid as always. Matilda never even killed anyone after training for that the entire movie; no self-delivered end of innocence. It's not an 8.6, but closer to the 7-8 range. I gave it a 7 because I just watched great child acting in Let the Right One In before viewing this film. Overall, though, it's much better than the average movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    High Quality Crime Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    argo0403
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Leon is a brutal and veteran hit-man. He meets Mathilda, a young girl, and saves her from bad detectives. But, they kills her family so she lives with Leon. Although he declines her to live and talk with, he gradually becomes kind to her. At the same time, the remnants of the detectives tries to find them Though the story is very simple and there's no surprise, this crime movie compensates for that from brilliant performances by actors such as Jean Reno and Gary Oldman. I think Reno plays two roles in this. First is as a heartless assassin. This part is very cool. Second is as a friend or father of Mathilda. In contrast, this part is heart-warming and his smile is so charming that I can't help laughing. The thing I like in this movie is Oldman's madness. I have very strong impression from Darkknight series, so I can't believe that he plays such a crazy villain and I burst into laughs when his last scene. To be honest, I don't have sympathy with Mathilda so much. I always don't have it with young main character. Even though the last is predictable, it moves me. Good or worse, meeting someone really changes our life. &nbsp;This is not a masterpiece, but I'm very satisfied and touched by pure love of Leon.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A classic that totally holds up...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    agentvega
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film totally withstands the test of time. You can watch it today and it still feels just as fresh and relevant as when it came out. The international cut is better than the U.S. cut, but any version is worth the watch. Even as a kid, you can tell that Natalie Portman is destined for great things. I feel like even though Gary Oldman's character is a bit over the top, he still makes him as believable as possible. But, the stand out is obviously Jean Reno. Amazing as ever. Just a perfect roll for him. I must have seen this film at least 20 times, and every time I catch some little nuance that I missed in the past or just see something differently than I had before. It is just a great, if not underrated movie, and not only worth a viewing, but many. You surely will not be disappointed, and if you somehow are, give it another chance to grow on you. A very good friend of mine was not a fan upon first viewing, but now counts it as one of his favorites.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Violent movie with a heavy plot
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    digitalbeachbum
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I first saw this movie the only thing I could think about was the acting of Natalie Portman. Even at this age you could see her natural beauty and ability as an actor. The acting was awesome and the plot was well laid out, but I found several parts of the movie which weren't believable. I won't bother with them here, but you can see from my score that these scenes brought the movie down a few notches for me. I definitely would recommend this movie in HD or even 3D with a mega, killer sound system. It was really meant to be played on the big screen and small screens with crappy sound systems really do it an injustice. Every once in a while I see this on normal television and I watch it for laughs because they do the "pan and scan" which completely ruins the movie beyond words. I personally thing "pan and scan" should be against the law. Don't they already have this in France? Acting 1 Directing 1 Plot 1 Believability 0 Continuity .5 Natalie Portman 10 (no I'm not a pedo) Action 1 14.5 of 7
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent film with a gripping story!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Skyler Moody
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is absolutely brilliant and amazing! It is truly a unique film with fantastic acting and action that will hold you in its grasp. Where are the awards for this film? How come this film is unnoticed? With all of the amazing acting and great storyline, I am surprised this movie did not win an Oscar! Everybody was fantastic in this film! Jean Reno gives a heartwarming performance as a sad and lonely hit-man or "cleaner" named Leon who lives in a secluded world in a apartment complex and Natalie Portman's character Mathilda is the one that shatters Leon's secluded world. For this being her first feature film, Natalie Portman gives an amazing and astonishing performance as a troubled little girl with a desire for revenge. Gary Oldman is also fantastic as a twisted, sadistic, and corrupted DEA agent. He is on my list for Top 10 greatest villains ever! The unique love story and father-daughter type relationship between Leon and Mathilda is handled beautifully by director Luc Besson. You will feel so much sympathy for these characters. This movie is the perfect action with a unique love story and unforgettable characters and emotionally charged scenes! Everybody needs to see this movie!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Leon: The Professional (1994)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    William Richardson (valor992@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Personally this is the best movie I've ever seen. The character development, pacing, acting, and writing are so effective I always forget that Im even watching a movie. Another reason it draws you in so intuitively is the perfectly arranged soundtrack. Every scene is complimented with exactly the right number, allowing a deeper insight into the emotions being displayed on screen, weather it be a light of air of compassion or an adrenaline filled descant, the soundtrack never fails to hit its mark. This film has a special place in my life, for me its not just a movie, Its a piece of myself that I integrated into who I am and it forever changed me. Im so grateful to see that others understand the complexity and greatness of this movie and appreciate it as well. P.S. I love you Mathilda
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Admirable film.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Hannah Louise Mickleburgh
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    L&eacute;on, to put it simply, is a masterpiece. One of the greatest early-modern films, no doubt about it. Natalie Portman at 12 is already excellent, and given a chance so few have: while there are many younger actors a mere handful can win these starring roles, and in serious films they're too young to see. Comparable to Kick-Ass, though this original suspense flies past the modern indie-wannabe in daylight. Nothing was stilted nor pushed too far and the story, yet unmentioned, is simply insightful. The only reason I give an 8, not 9 or even 10, is because 8 is my favourite number, and so only given to those which are worthy. The actors own their roles, and should play these characters more often. (This is) A favourite that will (unexpectedly?) last a long time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the best films of all time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ABC DEF
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is one of my top 5 favorites of all time. Lot of reasons for it. It combines a great and interesting storyline, coupled with stellar acting performances. Oldman really puts the punch into the villainous role, he is terrific, but Portman steals away the show from everyone. It could be one of the top performances in a female role, and that too by a young girl. The novelty of the story is it's handling of the relationship between and elder man and young girl in an entirely different manner. The chemistry between Reno and Portman is amazing. Overall, the movie is great from the start to the end, including the climax.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "I Like These Calm Little Moments Before The Storm"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    CinemaClown
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    L&eacute;on is a stylish & solid action thriller that is today rightfully hailed as one of the greatest action films of all time. Superbly directed, swiftly paced, tightly edited & beautifully scored, L&eacute;on tells the story of a professional assassin who takes in a 12 year old girl when her family is brutally murdered by corrupt police officers and helps & trains her to exact revenge on those responsible for it. Also, this film is an odd look at their relationship which might turn out to be unsettling for some. Jean Reno stars as the best contract killer in town, L&eacute;on & did great justice to his character. Gary Oldman simply nailed his character by putting up a stupefying performance as corrupt DEA agent, Norman Stansfield, and also introducing Natalie Portman as Mathilda, who couldn't have asked for a more sensational debut. A classic in every way, L&eacute;on is violent, brutal & unsettling, yet is a brilliantly directed, superbly edited & beautifully photographed film that easily qualifies as a tremendously entertaining & memorable action masterpiece of all times. P.S. Make sure you grab the Extended Cut to fill up what might feel like loopholes in the Theatrical version.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    He's Venus As A Boy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bbcfilmlover
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Leon is another film i haven't watched for years but when i originally saw it, i really loved the film. Of course i am reviewing the original cinematic/DVD release. For your information, Director Luc Beeson classes this as 'The Director's Cut', as it has many scenes deleted from the original test showing. I believe, two years later, Beeson re-edited all of those scenes back in. Apparently 25 minutes extra. That version, confusingly, is known as 'The Director's Cut', though Beeson, keeping in mind his view of the naming of his Director's Cut, calls this 'The Internatinal Cut'. Confused? This is a really enthralling film which keeps you emotionally involved throughout. Yes, it is a violent film in places but that is not what the story is about. It is about finding yourself and who you are. Taking root and allowing people in, when you weren't able to before. Natalie Portman absolutely shines in this. Havig been cast at 11, now 12, she is totally believable as Mathilda. It must have been tough to pull off some scenes at such a young age. Whilst Jean Reno is wonderful as Leon, it is Portman's portrayal of the character dealing with the loss of her abusive, uncaring family, while grieving for the loss of her 4 year old brother and her subsequent journey of revenge and finding herself just like Leon, that makes her performance so strong. Now, it must be said there are elements of an undercurrent of a possible sexual relationship between them both. Early on Mathilda shows signs of holding herself in certain way that shows a possible move into puberty. Take a look at the scenes of her hanging over the staircase for this. It is clear that as the film develops there is a growing love between them. Look out for Mathilda sleeping with the pig oven glove on the first night. A subtle moments, easily missed. However, the way Reno plays his character with a few learning difficulties, naivety and his reluctance to accept anything outside his comfort zone, the sexuality elements do not come across as dirty at all. There really does seem to be a developing true love between them and it is touching to watch at times. Apparently, The International Cut has more interactions between Mathilda and Leon, which i haven't seen yet. I must also add that the original script, which is available online, does have them making love. Again, reading the script does put it into context as to how she feels towards Leon and why she feels the need/want to make love. It is clear that anything outside of Leon's job and he is lost. That is the beauty of this film, with all its violence and profanity, and equally so the fate of Leon itself, it really shows the development of what one person can give to another. Gary Oldman's deserves much credit too. I won't go into detail about his character but i will say he is damn good. Watch out for the "Ev-ery-one" line, which i can imagine, if watched on the big screen in the cinema must have reverberated half way around town! A mention also to the character of Tony. We never really get any in depth explanations about him. He clearly is underhand, always keeping Leon's money and then only offering Mathilda $100 to last a whole month. The way he would say things and his mannerisms certainly suggest there is a lot more to him that meets they eye. There are so many stand out scenes in this film, all subtle, that it is hard to pick any individually. The film pretty much grabs you from start to end. It is a funny juxtaposition really, you find yourself caring so much for a killer! The soundtrack is equally as subtle and helps too by not being overpowering. The end titles have Sting's 'Shape of my Heart' which actually fits perfectly. The other piece of music within the film is the sublime, 'Venus as a Boy' by Bjork, which on first hearing/watching seems a strange choice. But on closer inspection he budding sexual overtones and growing feelings of the song match the way Mathilda was beginning to feel. All in all this is a good film. You care about both off the main characters. The final scene with Matilda finally telling the truth, albeit, so way out there and the planting of Leon's 'best friend' to take root, gives you a wonderful sense of knowing Mathilda will be fine and has found herself and where she wants to be. Equally, albeit dead, Leon's plant taking root, metaphorically gives you that same feeling. I will be searching out the 'International Version' just to add to the story but i would suggest the viewer seek out the original version as, having not seen the other one, the story seems to the point and well contained as it is. As a final point, as a David Lynch fan, i found one or two shots reminding me of Lynch. Maybe that is just me and believe me that is no criticism. It just struck me when watching. This is a film not for everyone due to the violent content but if you want to submerge yourself in Beeson's world and watch a film with some depth of emotion, then this is the film for you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Disappointed, but still a good movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rydogbball34
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I haven't been this excited for a movie, besides Pan's Labyrinth; however, the film falls below my lofty expectations. Natalie Portman's acting gets hailed, but it was really rough to watch. Her performance was comparable to Macaulay Culkin's in Home Alone. The burden can't be attributed solely to her as the writing was pretty odd (the dress-up scene & Matilda's infatuation with Leon. The plot is a simplistic, predictable revenge story. The opening sequence is really great, while Gary Oldman is solid as always. Matilda never even killed anyone after training for that the entire movie; no self-delivered end of innocence. It's not an 8.6, but closer to the 7-8 range. I gave it a 7 because I just watched great child acting in Let the Right One In before viewing this film. Overall, though, it's much better than the average movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
