<filme>
 <id>
  556
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0114938
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1995
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Wild Bill
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  5.8
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  The early career of legendary lawman Wild Bill Hickock is telescoped and culminates in his relocation in Deadwood and a reunion with Calamity Jane.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Wild Bill Hickok, famed lawman and gunman of the Old West, is haunted by his past and his reputation. He is loved by, but cannot love, Calamity Jane. Dogging his trail is young Jack McCall, who blames Bill for abandoning the boy's mother and destroying her life. McCall has sworn to kill Bill, and Bill's ghosts, his failing eyesight, and his fondness for opium may make McCall's task easier.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Action
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Biography
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Western
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   calamity jane
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   opium
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   hotel lobby
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   gunfight
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   buffalo bill cody
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Walter Hill
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Peter Dexter
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Thomas Babe
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Jeff Bridges
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Ellen Barkin
  </ator>
  <ator>
   John Hurt
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A pile of horse s**T
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rusty13252
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Out of every movie i have ever seen based on a legendary old west figure this movie was the largest pile of horse s**T i have ever seen.There is not 1/100 of fact base in this film i have spent 25 years of my life researching legendary western figures from Wyatt Earp to the back shooter Pat Garret and believe me they have made some stinkers but this is no doubt the worst pile of lies and misleads i ever saw. I WISH THERE WAS A RATING LESS THEN 1 BECAUSE THIS MOVIE WOULD RATE A - 10.Not to mention very bad acting from second rate actors.Walter Hill directed my favorite movie of all times the 1979 cult classic THE WARRIORS {in which he also used James Remar }so i expected better from him.This movie is a disgrace to a otherwise great director.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Awful film considering it was directed by Walter Hill....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rusoviet
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ...lousy: dialogue, special affects but the worst was the acting - reminds one of the 1970's and that decade's addiction to Gary Hart or Jimmah Carter... The film was akin to 'Little Big Man' - the sets were awful and the casting was even worse. Took me back 'War' film cast with Hollywood draft dodgers trying to show their manhood i.e. 'A Bridge Too Far' - Eliot Gould and Ryan O'Neal - that fight scene 10 minutes in where 'Wild Bill' takes/shoots down some four desperadoes was pathetic. Truly Hill's worst film - a real 'pc' pile of 'Hillary' and 'Debbie Wassserman Schultz...- castrated men regardless of the violence.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Never touch another mans hat.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Wild Bill Hickok, famed lawman and gunman of the Old West, is haunted by his past and his reputation. He is loved by, but cannot love, Calamity Jane. Dogging his trail is young Jack McCall, who blames Bill for abandoning the boy's mother and destroying her life. McCall has sworn to kill Bill, and Bill's ghosts, his failing eyesight, and his fondness for opium may make McCall's task easier.... One of the main reasons to watch this film is of course Bridges, who puts in a wonderful performance as the titular character. He is ably supported by Barkin and Hurt, and thats most of the positive things said. The film is shot beautifully, and does have an authentic feel to it, but Hill feels out of place directing this, and has made some evry odd choices with the uses of flashbacks, and using Arquette, who is not convincing, but you know the demise of Bill when you meet arquettes character. Reason being that the man is too slimy and typically evil in a Mike Myers way (not a compliment) and is the sole reason of making the film just that laughable. Sure, the history is a load of garbage, but that doesn't matter, all we want to know is how many people he shot, how drunk he got, and how well Bridges does to adapt the two aforementioned traits. it's watchable enough, with some silly scenes and misjudged narrative, but thanks to some good performances, the film isn't the turkey most say it is.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jeff Bridges is an ICON!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jeff Bridges is one of my all-time favorite actors. I guess he's not only prolific, but also an actor who has gained a "Cult" following over the years. In 'Wild Bill', he plays the late legendary lawman Wild Bill Hickok, with unseen ease. As a film, 'Wild Bill' is not an interesting watch, sure it offers some captivating moments, but they are few and far between. Walter Hill has directed this story passably, but the writing is not sharp enough. Be it based on a book, as a cinematic experience, it comes out very half-baked. It had tremendous scope to hold it's viewer, but that has not been tapped in here properly. Jeff Bridges quite frankly owns 'Wild Bill'. The kind of roles Bridges has managed to pull off, make him, probably, one of the finest actors in the History of World Cinema. Bridges goes down as an actor, who should inspire a set of new-born actors in the coming time. On the whole, Watch it only for 'The Dude', who goes 'Western' in here.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Overambitous but disappointing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Hunt2546
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/9/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Most reviews seem to look at this through the prism of "Deadwood," which seems unfair as the elongated TV format allows for far more character development. So to point out that the characters in "Wild Bill" aren't as-- well, you get the picture. Viewed alone, the movie deserves praise for performance, set design, a sense of period dialogue and historical accuracy in visual recreations. Yes, WB really did wear Navy Colts backwards, cavalry-style, in a red sash; yes, he did have greasy lanks of hair and wear a big floppy hat, a thick tie and a vest that didn't match his jacket which didn't match his pants. And for about an hour, I think the movie is pretty amusing. But when it sinks into Deadwood over its last hour, it appears to use too much of the stagey dialogue of one of its sources, a play by someone named Thomas Babe. At this point, it pretty much abandons history which is bad enough, but also cinematic fluency, of which Hill is a master: it becomes static, talky, dreary, and completely loses its momentum. And someone--Babe?--made the decision to give the McCall-Hickcock dynamic an Oedipal overtone--he's the "son" of a woman once loved , then abandoned, by Hickcock. This is an attempt at coherency, to bring the murder into some sort of classic framework. Yeah, swell, however: McCall was much older, a buffalo hunter who'd lost dough to Wild Bill the night before. He didn't stand for the abused son, he stood for the randomness of frontier violence, where booze, pride, stupidity and a culture of pointless aggression could easily spell an ambush murder like McCall's. THAT, to me, would not only have been more accurate, but more fluent and a better movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Someone should put a bullet in this one
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    samkay1
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Perhaps I love Deadwood too much; the critically praised, HBO series for which director Walter Hill appropriately won an Emmy for the pilot. I clearly set my expectations a little too high of this one, which predates the Deadwood series by eight years or so. Coming from Walter Hill, the man behind the Warriors and The Long Riders, there is no way that Wild Bill should have been this sloppy. His portrayal of the life and death of James Butler Hickok results in a motion picture that self-destructs in spectacular fashion. It is vastly underwritten, poorly acted, edited as if it were a labyrinth of jungle vines to be cut down by a machete, and on top of that the movie is also severely anti-climactic. All that Hill gets right is that parts of the movie are well shot, and he is able to capture the look of the times on screen, but on the pages, it is a different matter. The opening twenty minutes (give or take) are especially excruciating. What we see is almost a joke, totally amateurish and more oriented towards obnoxious gunplay than exposition. It is like watching kiddies play cowboys and Indians on the street with little wooded pistols. Hill should know better than that, as should Jeff Bridges, whose portrayal of Hickok is devoid of talent. It is so obviously a performance, and he delivers most of his lines in a hammy fashion, and there is nothing remotely human about this character. The movie does a poor job of showing his misery and self loathing. When all is said and done, Wild Bill is a dud. It is clumsy and careless, and is easily one of the worst westerns I have ever seen.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Underrated, psychedelic western by Walter Hill
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tieman64
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/5/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Wild Bill" was ripped to shreds by critics, ignored by audiences, and went on to become a huge box office failure. But with Jeff Bridges embraced as a bearded guru in the wake of "The Big Lebowski", the film has now become a huge cult favourite. And why not? It's a deliciously psychedelic western; an orgy of over the top violence and drunken wisecracks, the film would also give birth to the HBO series "Deadwood" decades later. Walter Hill spent his career making westerns and so by the time he directed "Wild Bill" he already knew the genre inside out. This is thus a film best appreciated by those familiar with and completely bored by the western genre. Those in search of something a little bit different. A little bit bizarre. The plot: Jeff Bridges plays Wild Bill Hickok, a half blind, always drunk, perpetually stoned lawman who lives out his remaining days at Deadwood, the infamous town in South Dakota. Deadwood is handled like George Lucas handled the town of Mos Eisley in "Star Wars". It's a "hive of scum and villainy", bar fights, gun battles and drunken brawls occurring left right and centre. The streets are muddy, opium dens are overbooked and a hellish rain beats down every night. "This town reminds me of something from the Bible," one character murmurs. "Which part?" Wild Bill asks. "The part right before God gets angry," comes the reply, summing up the tone of the film perfectly. Faced with "woman problems", weighed by his moustache and haunted by his past, Wild Bill mopes around Deadwood, unaware that a disgruntled young man is plotting to kill him. In typical western fashion, the film builds toward their final act face-off, but Hill subverts expectations at every turn. He's less interested in a mythological construction of Wild Bill than a trippy deconstruction, using flashbacks and a fragmented narrative to nosedive into both Bill's past and personal demons. But can we trust these flashbacks? Are these visions the truth or are they attempts by Bill to justify his violent past? In the film's present, Bill surrounds himself by those who blindly worship him. Calamity Jane, an old flame, spends the film lusting for Bill. Likewise Old Charlie, an Englishman who is always eager to defend Bill using charm and logic. Same story with California Joe, an old timer who is always spinning yarns and telling "tall tales" about Wild Bill. Bill, in other words, walks around with his own little propaganda machine, his circle of fawning friends all busy mythologising him. With Bill's real world an illusion, what exactly is there in the film's flashbacks which demonize him? He kills an Indian only because the Indian challenged him, he killed a man in a duel, but that jerk stole his watch. Likewise, he fights a guy in a wheelchair, but not before tying himself to a chair to make things fair. There's always the notion that these "flashbacks", these "traumas", are themselves part of the Wild Bill mythology. That perhaps it is the very falsity of these flashbacks, the very film, which is tormenting Bill. In any case, the film is primarily of interest because it allows us to watch Jeff Bridges chewing scenery. For all his wisecracks and violent flourishes, Bridges' Wild Bill is a fragile guy unable to relate to people, has no family, is going blind and is increasingly crushed as the film gets more and more claustrophobic. Hill's aesthetic strategy is such that you can feel the walls drawing in as the film progresses, the shadows, the mud, the rain, the walls themselves, closing inexorably in, until Bill finds himself at a cramped poker table, a gun behind his skull. But what's great is that Hill suggests that this "claustrophobia" is the result of the Wild Bill myth. That the "need" to constantly adhere to the public's perception of "who Wild Bill is", is ultimately what boxes Bill in and results in his demise. Trapped by his own lore, he sets about a chain of events which leads to his death. Ironically, while it is the "Wild Bill myth" which leads to a gunman seeking revenge on Bill, it is Bill's act of forgiveness toward this very man, his breaking of his dime-novel persona, that earns him a bullet in the brain. 8/10  Val Kilmer's performance as Doc Holiday in "Tombstone" was much lauded in the 90s, but Jeff Bridges' work here is equally awesome. Incidentally, Walter Hill directed the pilot episode of "Deadwood", this film serving as the template for the HBO series' tone and style. Thematically, the film does exactly what "The Assassination of Jesse James by the Coward Robert Ford" does, but arguably a bit better. Worth one viewing. See Hill's "The Warriors" and "The Long Riders".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    wild bilge
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (rcastl2335@aol.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/9/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I first saw this in the theater and found it forgettable. But I thought I'd watch again since it pops up a lot on cable. Now I believe it's too awful to be forgettable. This is a criminally bad film, easily the worst of director Walter Hill's spotty career, although it does seem to have pointed him towards the cable series Deadwood. That's another crime for another day, however. Except for some few expertly staged fight scenes and the performances of Jeff Bridges and Diane Lane, this is a low point in several usually reliable actor's careers. John Hurt is simply a windy fool, ditto James Gammon. Bruce Dern yells (yawn). And Ellen Barkin's Calamity Jane makes me long for Abby Dalton's performance in The Plainsman. Loud, broad, witless, with the worst Southern accent in the long history of bad Southern accents on film, this represents the nadir of her career. It's the only bad performance I've ever seen her give and I still can't imagine what she was thinking. Possibly the only way to enjoy this film is to turn it on, leave the room and, when you hear the sound of raised voices and gunfire, rush back in. Or you could just rent The Plainsman.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a dark and moody Western with an effective atmosphere and feeling to it, but is unfortunately bogged down by its disorganized running time and numerous defects
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheUnknown837-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/2/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Wild Bill is a dark, moody Western about the last days of legendary lawman James Butler Hickock that sometimes shows off its true colors (by that, I mean its riveting action sequences, not its appearance) but suffers from a disorganized screenplay, some dull characters, an imperfect running time, and while it's not a bad Western, it's not a great one either. Jeff Bridges gives a noteworthy performance as Wild Bill, John Hurt gives most of the movie's seldom-seen charisma as his friend Charley Prince (I'm not sure if this character is real or not) and then there is a truly great performance by Ellen Barkin as frontierswoman Calamity Jane. In shorter, laconic terms, Wild Bill boasts a great cast and some witty dialogue. Director Walter Hill (who also directed The Long Riders (1980) with the Carradine brothers) does a phenomenal job with the action scenes as well. The killings in this film look harsh and brutal as they in deed were. And the violence is not overdone to the point where it becomes depressing. But like I mentioned earlier, the story is disorganized. There were too many black-and-white flashback scenes, which I've seen many done better many times before in other films, that dragged on and slowed the movie down for me. John Hurt's narration was sometimes effective, sometimes overdrawn. And the pacing was in need of a revision. I'm sure the filmmakers could have worked it out a different way to tell the past of the characters without constantly using flashbacks and could have removed some additional scenes that went into and out of nowhere. Because they unfortunately are the movie's major flaws. They slow it down. Wild Bill, again is not necessarily a bad film. I did mildly enjoy it at times, but it is a very dark motion picture without much point behind itself. The action scenes are good, the acting is great, and the general atmosphere of a dark time in a weary man's life is convincing. But ultimately, Wild Bill is just too slow and kind of a disappointment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The acting is key in this movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    garotycoyote
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/7/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I thought this movie to be a truly great one and the key here is really great acting especially from Jeff Bridges. For that reason and that reason alone its worth seeing this movie. To actually experience the realism created by this level of acting is truly a feat that movie actors strive to achieve. Jeff Bridges has achieved that in this rendition of Wild Bill. I really do not have anything more I can say about this but its the sort of film that leaves you wishing there would be a sequel. If this were to become a TV series I would probably put money on it to say it would be a winner. So find it rent it sit back and watch one of the most enjoyable movies of all time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A pile of horse s**T
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rusty13252
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Out of every movie i have ever seen based on a legendary old west figure this movie was the largest pile of horse s**T i have ever seen.There is not 1/100 of fact base in this film i have spent 25 years of my life researching legendary western figures from Wyatt Earp to the back shooter Pat Garret and believe me they have made some stinkers but this is no doubt the worst pile of lies and misleads i ever saw. I WISH THERE WAS A RATING LESS THEN 1 BECAUSE THIS MOVIE WOULD RATE A - 10.Not to mention very bad acting from second rate actors.Walter Hill directed my favorite movie of all times the 1979 cult classic THE WARRIORS {in which he also used James Remar }so i expected better from him.This movie is a disgrace to a otherwise great director.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Awful film considering it was directed by Walter Hill....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rusoviet
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ...lousy: dialogue, special affects but the worst was the acting - reminds one of the 1970's and that decade's addiction to Gary Hart or Jimmah Carter... The film was akin to 'Little Big Man' - the sets were awful and the casting was even worse. Took me back 'War' film cast with Hollywood draft dodgers trying to show their manhood i.e. 'A Bridge Too Far' - Eliot Gould and Ryan O'Neal - that fight scene 10 minutes in where 'Wild Bill' takes/shoots down some four desperadoes was pathetic. Truly Hill's worst film - a real 'pc' pile of 'Hillary' and 'Debbie Wassserman Schultz...- castrated men regardless of the violence.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Never touch another mans hat.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Wild Bill Hickok, famed lawman and gunman of the Old West, is haunted by his past and his reputation. He is loved by, but cannot love, Calamity Jane. Dogging his trail is young Jack McCall, who blames Bill for abandoning the boy's mother and destroying her life. McCall has sworn to kill Bill, and Bill's ghosts, his failing eyesight, and his fondness for opium may make McCall's task easier.... One of the main reasons to watch this film is of course Bridges, who puts in a wonderful performance as the titular character. He is ably supported by Barkin and Hurt, and thats most of the positive things said. The film is shot beautifully, and does have an authentic feel to it, but Hill feels out of place directing this, and has made some evry odd choices with the uses of flashbacks, and using Arquette, who is not convincing, but you know the demise of Bill when you meet arquettes character. Reason being that the man is too slimy and typically evil in a Mike Myers way (not a compliment) and is the sole reason of making the film just that laughable. Sure, the history is a load of garbage, but that doesn't matter, all we want to know is how many people he shot, how drunk he got, and how well Bridges does to adapt the two aforementioned traits. it's watchable enough, with some silly scenes and misjudged narrative, but thanks to some good performances, the film isn't the turkey most say it is.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jeff Bridges is an ICON!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jeff Bridges is one of my all-time favorite actors. I guess he's not only prolific, but also an actor who has gained a "Cult" following over the years. In 'Wild Bill', he plays the late legendary lawman Wild Bill Hickok, with unseen ease. As a film, 'Wild Bill' is not an interesting watch, sure it offers some captivating moments, but they are few and far between. Walter Hill has directed this story passably, but the writing is not sharp enough. Be it based on a book, as a cinematic experience, it comes out very half-baked. It had tremendous scope to hold it's viewer, but that has not been tapped in here properly. Jeff Bridges quite frankly owns 'Wild Bill'. The kind of roles Bridges has managed to pull off, make him, probably, one of the finest actors in the History of World Cinema. Bridges goes down as an actor, who should inspire a set of new-born actors in the coming time. On the whole, Watch it only for 'The Dude', who goes 'Western' in here.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Overambitous but disappointing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Hunt2546
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/9/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Most reviews seem to look at this through the prism of "Deadwood," which seems unfair as the elongated TV format allows for far more character development. So to point out that the characters in "Wild Bill" aren't as-- well, you get the picture. Viewed alone, the movie deserves praise for performance, set design, a sense of period dialogue and historical accuracy in visual recreations. Yes, WB really did wear Navy Colts backwards, cavalry-style, in a red sash; yes, he did have greasy lanks of hair and wear a big floppy hat, a thick tie and a vest that didn't match his jacket which didn't match his pants. And for about an hour, I think the movie is pretty amusing. But when it sinks into Deadwood over its last hour, it appears to use too much of the stagey dialogue of one of its sources, a play by someone named Thomas Babe. At this point, it pretty much abandons history which is bad enough, but also cinematic fluency, of which Hill is a master: it becomes static, talky, dreary, and completely loses its momentum. And someone--Babe?--made the decision to give the McCall-Hickcock dynamic an Oedipal overtone--he's the "son" of a woman once loved , then abandoned, by Hickcock. This is an attempt at coherency, to bring the murder into some sort of classic framework. Yeah, swell, however: McCall was much older, a buffalo hunter who'd lost dough to Wild Bill the night before. He didn't stand for the abused son, he stood for the randomness of frontier violence, where booze, pride, stupidity and a culture of pointless aggression could easily spell an ambush murder like McCall's. THAT, to me, would not only have been more accurate, but more fluent and a better movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Someone should put a bullet in this one
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    samkay1
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Perhaps I love Deadwood too much; the critically praised, HBO series for which director Walter Hill appropriately won an Emmy for the pilot. I clearly set my expectations a little too high of this one, which predates the Deadwood series by eight years or so. Coming from Walter Hill, the man behind the Warriors and The Long Riders, there is no way that Wild Bill should have been this sloppy. His portrayal of the life and death of James Butler Hickok results in a motion picture that self-destructs in spectacular fashion. It is vastly underwritten, poorly acted, edited as if it were a labyrinth of jungle vines to be cut down by a machete, and on top of that the movie is also severely anti-climactic. All that Hill gets right is that parts of the movie are well shot, and he is able to capture the look of the times on screen, but on the pages, it is a different matter. The opening twenty minutes (give or take) are especially excruciating. What we see is almost a joke, totally amateurish and more oriented towards obnoxious gunplay than exposition. It is like watching kiddies play cowboys and Indians on the street with little wooded pistols. Hill should know better than that, as should Jeff Bridges, whose portrayal of Hickok is devoid of talent. It is so obviously a performance, and he delivers most of his lines in a hammy fashion, and there is nothing remotely human about this character. The movie does a poor job of showing his misery and self loathing. When all is said and done, Wild Bill is a dud. It is clumsy and careless, and is easily one of the worst westerns I have ever seen.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Underrated, psychedelic western by Walter Hill
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tieman64
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/5/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Wild Bill" was ripped to shreds by critics, ignored by audiences, and went on to become a huge box office failure. But with Jeff Bridges embraced as a bearded guru in the wake of "The Big Lebowski", the film has now become a huge cult favourite. And why not? It's a deliciously psychedelic western; an orgy of over the top violence and drunken wisecracks, the film would also give birth to the HBO series "Deadwood" decades later. Walter Hill spent his career making westerns and so by the time he directed "Wild Bill" he already knew the genre inside out. This is thus a film best appreciated by those familiar with and completely bored by the western genre. Those in search of something a little bit different. A little bit bizarre. The plot: Jeff Bridges plays Wild Bill Hickok, a half blind, always drunk, perpetually stoned lawman who lives out his remaining days at Deadwood, the infamous town in South Dakota. Deadwood is handled like George Lucas handled the town of Mos Eisley in "Star Wars". It's a "hive of scum and villainy", bar fights, gun battles and drunken brawls occurring left right and centre. The streets are muddy, opium dens are overbooked and a hellish rain beats down every night. "This town reminds me of something from the Bible," one character murmurs. "Which part?" Wild Bill asks. "The part right before God gets angry," comes the reply, summing up the tone of the film perfectly. Faced with "woman problems", weighed by his moustache and haunted by his past, Wild Bill mopes around Deadwood, unaware that a disgruntled young man is plotting to kill him. In typical western fashion, the film builds toward their final act face-off, but Hill subverts expectations at every turn. He's less interested in a mythological construction of Wild Bill than a trippy deconstruction, using flashbacks and a fragmented narrative to nosedive into both Bill's past and personal demons. But can we trust these flashbacks? Are these visions the truth or are they attempts by Bill to justify his violent past? In the film's present, Bill surrounds himself by those who blindly worship him. Calamity Jane, an old flame, spends the film lusting for Bill. Likewise Old Charlie, an Englishman who is always eager to defend Bill using charm and logic. Same story with California Joe, an old timer who is always spinning yarns and telling "tall tales" about Wild Bill. Bill, in other words, walks around with his own little propaganda machine, his circle of fawning friends all busy mythologising him. With Bill's real world an illusion, what exactly is there in the film's flashbacks which demonize him? He kills an Indian only because the Indian challenged him, he killed a man in a duel, but that jerk stole his watch. Likewise, he fights a guy in a wheelchair, but not before tying himself to a chair to make things fair. There's always the notion that these "flashbacks", these "traumas", are themselves part of the Wild Bill mythology. That perhaps it is the very falsity of these flashbacks, the very film, which is tormenting Bill. In any case, the film is primarily of interest because it allows us to watch Jeff Bridges chewing scenery. For all his wisecracks and violent flourishes, Bridges' Wild Bill is a fragile guy unable to relate to people, has no family, is going blind and is increasingly crushed as the film gets more and more claustrophobic. Hill's aesthetic strategy is such that you can feel the walls drawing in as the film progresses, the shadows, the mud, the rain, the walls themselves, closing inexorably in, until Bill finds himself at a cramped poker table, a gun behind his skull. But what's great is that Hill suggests that this "claustrophobia" is the result of the Wild Bill myth. That the "need" to constantly adhere to the public's perception of "who Wild Bill is", is ultimately what boxes Bill in and results in his demise. Trapped by his own lore, he sets about a chain of events which leads to his death. Ironically, while it is the "Wild Bill myth" which leads to a gunman seeking revenge on Bill, it is Bill's act of forgiveness toward this very man, his breaking of his dime-novel persona, that earns him a bullet in the brain. 8/10  Val Kilmer's performance as Doc Holiday in "Tombstone" was much lauded in the 90s, but Jeff Bridges' work here is equally awesome. Incidentally, Walter Hill directed the pilot episode of "Deadwood", this film serving as the template for the HBO series' tone and style. Thematically, the film does exactly what "The Assassination of Jesse James by the Coward Robert Ford" does, but arguably a bit better. Worth one viewing. See Hill's "The Warriors" and "The Long Riders".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    wild bilge
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (rcastl2335@aol.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/9/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I first saw this in the theater and found it forgettable. But I thought I'd watch again since it pops up a lot on cable. Now I believe it's too awful to be forgettable. This is a criminally bad film, easily the worst of director Walter Hill's spotty career, although it does seem to have pointed him towards the cable series Deadwood. That's another crime for another day, however. Except for some few expertly staged fight scenes and the performances of Jeff Bridges and Diane Lane, this is a low point in several usually reliable actor's careers. John Hurt is simply a windy fool, ditto James Gammon. Bruce Dern yells (yawn). And Ellen Barkin's Calamity Jane makes me long for Abby Dalton's performance in The Plainsman. Loud, broad, witless, with the worst Southern accent in the long history of bad Southern accents on film, this represents the nadir of her career. It's the only bad performance I've ever seen her give and I still can't imagine what she was thinking. Possibly the only way to enjoy this film is to turn it on, leave the room and, when you hear the sound of raised voices and gunfire, rush back in. Or you could just rent The Plainsman.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a dark and moody Western with an effective atmosphere and feeling to it, but is unfortunately bogged down by its disorganized running time and numerous defects
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheUnknown837-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/2/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Wild Bill is a dark, moody Western about the last days of legendary lawman James Butler Hickock that sometimes shows off its true colors (by that, I mean its riveting action sequences, not its appearance) but suffers from a disorganized screenplay, some dull characters, an imperfect running time, and while it's not a bad Western, it's not a great one either. Jeff Bridges gives a noteworthy performance as Wild Bill, John Hurt gives most of the movie's seldom-seen charisma as his friend Charley Prince (I'm not sure if this character is real or not) and then there is a truly great performance by Ellen Barkin as frontierswoman Calamity Jane. In shorter, laconic terms, Wild Bill boasts a great cast and some witty dialogue. Director Walter Hill (who also directed The Long Riders (1980) with the Carradine brothers) does a phenomenal job with the action scenes as well. The killings in this film look harsh and brutal as they in deed were. And the violence is not overdone to the point where it becomes depressing. But like I mentioned earlier, the story is disorganized. There were too many black-and-white flashback scenes, which I've seen many done better many times before in other films, that dragged on and slowed the movie down for me. John Hurt's narration was sometimes effective, sometimes overdrawn. And the pacing was in need of a revision. I'm sure the filmmakers could have worked it out a different way to tell the past of the characters without constantly using flashbacks and could have removed some additional scenes that went into and out of nowhere. Because they unfortunately are the movie's major flaws. They slow it down. Wild Bill, again is not necessarily a bad film. I did mildly enjoy it at times, but it is a very dark motion picture without much point behind itself. The action scenes are good, the acting is great, and the general atmosphere of a dark time in a weary man's life is convincing. But ultimately, Wild Bill is just too slow and kind of a disappointment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The acting is key in this movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    garotycoyote
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/7/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I thought this movie to be a truly great one and the key here is really great acting especially from Jeff Bridges. For that reason and that reason alone its worth seeing this movie. To actually experience the realism created by this level of acting is truly a feat that movie actors strive to achieve. Jeff Bridges has achieved that in this rendition of Wild Bill. I really do not have anything more I can say about this but its the sort of film that leaves you wishing there would be a sequel. If this were to become a TV series I would probably put money on it to say it would be a winner. So find it rent it sit back and watch one of the most enjoyable movies of all time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A pile of horse s**T
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rusty13252
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Out of every movie i have ever seen based on a legendary old west figure this movie was the largest pile of horse s**T i have ever seen.There is not 1/100 of fact base in this film i have spent 25 years of my life researching legendary western figures from Wyatt Earp to the back shooter Pat Garret and believe me they have made some stinkers but this is no doubt the worst pile of lies and misleads i ever saw. I WISH THERE WAS A RATING LESS THEN 1 BECAUSE THIS MOVIE WOULD RATE A - 10.Not to mention very bad acting from second rate actors.Walter Hill directed my favorite movie of all times the 1979 cult classic THE WARRIORS {in which he also used James Remar }so i expected better from him.This movie is a disgrace to a otherwise great director.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Awful film considering it was directed by Walter Hill....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rusoviet
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ...lousy: dialogue, special affects but the worst was the acting - reminds one of the 1970's and that decade's addiction to Gary Hart or Jimmah Carter... The film was akin to 'Little Big Man' - the sets were awful and the casting was even worse. Took me back 'War' film cast with Hollywood draft dodgers trying to show their manhood i.e. 'A Bridge Too Far' - Eliot Gould and Ryan O'Neal - that fight scene 10 minutes in where 'Wild Bill' takes/shoots down some four desperadoes was pathetic. Truly Hill's worst film - a real 'pc' pile of 'Hillary' and 'Debbie Wassserman Schultz...- castrated men regardless of the violence.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Never touch another mans hat.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Wild Bill Hickok, famed lawman and gunman of the Old West, is haunted by his past and his reputation. He is loved by, but cannot love, Calamity Jane. Dogging his trail is young Jack McCall, who blames Bill for abandoning the boy's mother and destroying her life. McCall has sworn to kill Bill, and Bill's ghosts, his failing eyesight, and his fondness for opium may make McCall's task easier.... One of the main reasons to watch this film is of course Bridges, who puts in a wonderful performance as the titular character. He is ably supported by Barkin and Hurt, and thats most of the positive things said. The film is shot beautifully, and does have an authentic feel to it, but Hill feels out of place directing this, and has made some evry odd choices with the uses of flashbacks, and using Arquette, who is not convincing, but you know the demise of Bill when you meet arquettes character. Reason being that the man is too slimy and typically evil in a Mike Myers way (not a compliment) and is the sole reason of making the film just that laughable. Sure, the history is a load of garbage, but that doesn't matter, all we want to know is how many people he shot, how drunk he got, and how well Bridges does to adapt the two aforementioned traits. it's watchable enough, with some silly scenes and misjudged narrative, but thanks to some good performances, the film isn't the turkey most say it is.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jeff Bridges is an ICON!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jeff Bridges is one of my all-time favorite actors. I guess he's not only prolific, but also an actor who has gained a "Cult" following over the years. In 'Wild Bill', he plays the late legendary lawman Wild Bill Hickok, with unseen ease. As a film, 'Wild Bill' is not an interesting watch, sure it offers some captivating moments, but they are few and far between. Walter Hill has directed this story passably, but the writing is not sharp enough. Be it based on a book, as a cinematic experience, it comes out very half-baked. It had tremendous scope to hold it's viewer, but that has not been tapped in here properly. Jeff Bridges quite frankly owns 'Wild Bill'. The kind of roles Bridges has managed to pull off, make him, probably, one of the finest actors in the History of World Cinema. Bridges goes down as an actor, who should inspire a set of new-born actors in the coming time. On the whole, Watch it only for 'The Dude', who goes 'Western' in here.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Overambitous but disappointing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Hunt2546
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/9/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Most reviews seem to look at this through the prism of "Deadwood," which seems unfair as the elongated TV format allows for far more character development. So to point out that the characters in "Wild Bill" aren't as-- well, you get the picture. Viewed alone, the movie deserves praise for performance, set design, a sense of period dialogue and historical accuracy in visual recreations. Yes, WB really did wear Navy Colts backwards, cavalry-style, in a red sash; yes, he did have greasy lanks of hair and wear a big floppy hat, a thick tie and a vest that didn't match his jacket which didn't match his pants. And for about an hour, I think the movie is pretty amusing. But when it sinks into Deadwood over its last hour, it appears to use too much of the stagey dialogue of one of its sources, a play by someone named Thomas Babe. At this point, it pretty much abandons history which is bad enough, but also cinematic fluency, of which Hill is a master: it becomes static, talky, dreary, and completely loses its momentum. And someone--Babe?--made the decision to give the McCall-Hickcock dynamic an Oedipal overtone--he's the "son" of a woman once loved , then abandoned, by Hickcock. This is an attempt at coherency, to bring the murder into some sort of classic framework. Yeah, swell, however: McCall was much older, a buffalo hunter who'd lost dough to Wild Bill the night before. He didn't stand for the abused son, he stood for the randomness of frontier violence, where booze, pride, stupidity and a culture of pointless aggression could easily spell an ambush murder like McCall's. THAT, to me, would not only have been more accurate, but more fluent and a better movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Someone should put a bullet in this one
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    samkay1
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Perhaps I love Deadwood too much; the critically praised, HBO series for which director Walter Hill appropriately won an Emmy for the pilot. I clearly set my expectations a little too high of this one, which predates the Deadwood series by eight years or so. Coming from Walter Hill, the man behind the Warriors and The Long Riders, there is no way that Wild Bill should have been this sloppy. His portrayal of the life and death of James Butler Hickok results in a motion picture that self-destructs in spectacular fashion. It is vastly underwritten, poorly acted, edited as if it were a labyrinth of jungle vines to be cut down by a machete, and on top of that the movie is also severely anti-climactic. All that Hill gets right is that parts of the movie are well shot, and he is able to capture the look of the times on screen, but on the pages, it is a different matter. The opening twenty minutes (give or take) are especially excruciating. What we see is almost a joke, totally amateurish and more oriented towards obnoxious gunplay than exposition. It is like watching kiddies play cowboys and Indians on the street with little wooded pistols. Hill should know better than that, as should Jeff Bridges, whose portrayal of Hickok is devoid of talent. It is so obviously a performance, and he delivers most of his lines in a hammy fashion, and there is nothing remotely human about this character. The movie does a poor job of showing his misery and self loathing. When all is said and done, Wild Bill is a dud. It is clumsy and careless, and is easily one of the worst westerns I have ever seen.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Underrated, psychedelic western by Walter Hill
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tieman64
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/5/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Wild Bill" was ripped to shreds by critics, ignored by audiences, and went on to become a huge box office failure. But with Jeff Bridges embraced as a bearded guru in the wake of "The Big Lebowski", the film has now become a huge cult favourite. And why not? It's a deliciously psychedelic western; an orgy of over the top violence and drunken wisecracks, the film would also give birth to the HBO series "Deadwood" decades later. Walter Hill spent his career making westerns and so by the time he directed "Wild Bill" he already knew the genre inside out. This is thus a film best appreciated by those familiar with and completely bored by the western genre. Those in search of something a little bit different. A little bit bizarre. The plot: Jeff Bridges plays Wild Bill Hickok, a half blind, always drunk, perpetually stoned lawman who lives out his remaining days at Deadwood, the infamous town in South Dakota. Deadwood is handled like George Lucas handled the town of Mos Eisley in "Star Wars". It's a "hive of scum and villainy", bar fights, gun battles and drunken brawls occurring left right and centre. The streets are muddy, opium dens are overbooked and a hellish rain beats down every night. "This town reminds me of something from the Bible," one character murmurs. "Which part?" Wild Bill asks. "The part right before God gets angry," comes the reply, summing up the tone of the film perfectly. Faced with "woman problems", weighed by his moustache and haunted by his past, Wild Bill mopes around Deadwood, unaware that a disgruntled young man is plotting to kill him. In typical western fashion, the film builds toward their final act face-off, but Hill subverts expectations at every turn. He's less interested in a mythological construction of Wild Bill than a trippy deconstruction, using flashbacks and a fragmented narrative to nosedive into both Bill's past and personal demons. But can we trust these flashbacks? Are these visions the truth or are they attempts by Bill to justify his violent past? In the film's present, Bill surrounds himself by those who blindly worship him. Calamity Jane, an old flame, spends the film lusting for Bill. Likewise Old Charlie, an Englishman who is always eager to defend Bill using charm and logic. Same story with California Joe, an old timer who is always spinning yarns and telling "tall tales" about Wild Bill. Bill, in other words, walks around with his own little propaganda machine, his circle of fawning friends all busy mythologising him. With Bill's real world an illusion, what exactly is there in the film's flashbacks which demonize him? He kills an Indian only because the Indian challenged him, he killed a man in a duel, but that jerk stole his watch. Likewise, he fights a guy in a wheelchair, but not before tying himself to a chair to make things fair. There's always the notion that these "flashbacks", these "traumas", are themselves part of the Wild Bill mythology. That perhaps it is the very falsity of these flashbacks, the very film, which is tormenting Bill. In any case, the film is primarily of interest because it allows us to watch Jeff Bridges chewing scenery. For all his wisecracks and violent flourishes, Bridges' Wild Bill is a fragile guy unable to relate to people, has no family, is going blind and is increasingly crushed as the film gets more and more claustrophobic. Hill's aesthetic strategy is such that you can feel the walls drawing in as the film progresses, the shadows, the mud, the rain, the walls themselves, closing inexorably in, until Bill finds himself at a cramped poker table, a gun behind his skull. But what's great is that Hill suggests that this "claustrophobia" is the result of the Wild Bill myth. That the "need" to constantly adhere to the public's perception of "who Wild Bill is", is ultimately what boxes Bill in and results in his demise. Trapped by his own lore, he sets about a chain of events which leads to his death. Ironically, while it is the "Wild Bill myth" which leads to a gunman seeking revenge on Bill, it is Bill's act of forgiveness toward this very man, his breaking of his dime-novel persona, that earns him a bullet in the brain. 8/10  Val Kilmer's performance as Doc Holiday in "Tombstone" was much lauded in the 90s, but Jeff Bridges' work here is equally awesome. Incidentally, Walter Hill directed the pilot episode of "Deadwood", this film serving as the template for the HBO series' tone and style. Thematically, the film does exactly what "The Assassination of Jesse James by the Coward Robert Ford" does, but arguably a bit better. Worth one viewing. See Hill's "The Warriors" and "The Long Riders".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    wild bilge
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (rcastl2335@aol.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/9/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I first saw this in the theater and found it forgettable. But I thought I'd watch again since it pops up a lot on cable. Now I believe it's too awful to be forgettable. This is a criminally bad film, easily the worst of director Walter Hill's spotty career, although it does seem to have pointed him towards the cable series Deadwood. That's another crime for another day, however. Except for some few expertly staged fight scenes and the performances of Jeff Bridges and Diane Lane, this is a low point in several usually reliable actor's careers. John Hurt is simply a windy fool, ditto James Gammon. Bruce Dern yells (yawn). And Ellen Barkin's Calamity Jane makes me long for Abby Dalton's performance in The Plainsman. Loud, broad, witless, with the worst Southern accent in the long history of bad Southern accents on film, this represents the nadir of her career. It's the only bad performance I've ever seen her give and I still can't imagine what she was thinking. Possibly the only way to enjoy this film is to turn it on, leave the room and, when you hear the sound of raised voices and gunfire, rush back in. Or you could just rent The Plainsman.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a dark and moody Western with an effective atmosphere and feeling to it, but is unfortunately bogged down by its disorganized running time and numerous defects
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheUnknown837-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/2/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Wild Bill is a dark, moody Western about the last days of legendary lawman James Butler Hickock that sometimes shows off its true colors (by that, I mean its riveting action sequences, not its appearance) but suffers from a disorganized screenplay, some dull characters, an imperfect running time, and while it's not a bad Western, it's not a great one either. Jeff Bridges gives a noteworthy performance as Wild Bill, John Hurt gives most of the movie's seldom-seen charisma as his friend Charley Prince (I'm not sure if this character is real or not) and then there is a truly great performance by Ellen Barkin as frontierswoman Calamity Jane. In shorter, laconic terms, Wild Bill boasts a great cast and some witty dialogue. Director Walter Hill (who also directed The Long Riders (1980) with the Carradine brothers) does a phenomenal job with the action scenes as well. The killings in this film look harsh and brutal as they in deed were. And the violence is not overdone to the point where it becomes depressing. But like I mentioned earlier, the story is disorganized. There were too many black-and-white flashback scenes, which I've seen many done better many times before in other films, that dragged on and slowed the movie down for me. John Hurt's narration was sometimes effective, sometimes overdrawn. And the pacing was in need of a revision. I'm sure the filmmakers could have worked it out a different way to tell the past of the characters without constantly using flashbacks and could have removed some additional scenes that went into and out of nowhere. Because they unfortunately are the movie's major flaws. They slow it down. Wild Bill, again is not necessarily a bad film. I did mildly enjoy it at times, but it is a very dark motion picture without much point behind itself. The action scenes are good, the acting is great, and the general atmosphere of a dark time in a weary man's life is convincing. But ultimately, Wild Bill is just too slow and kind of a disappointment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The acting is key in this movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    garotycoyote
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/7/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I thought this movie to be a truly great one and the key here is really great acting especially from Jeff Bridges. For that reason and that reason alone its worth seeing this movie. To actually experience the realism created by this level of acting is truly a feat that movie actors strive to achieve. Jeff Bridges has achieved that in this rendition of Wild Bill. I really do not have anything more I can say about this but its the sort of film that leaves you wishing there would be a sequel. If this were to become a TV series I would probably put money on it to say it would be a winner. So find it rent it sit back and watch one of the most enjoyable movies of all time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A pile of horse s**T
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rusty13252
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Out of every movie i have ever seen based on a legendary old west figure this movie was the largest pile of horse s**T i have ever seen.There is not 1/100 of fact base in this film i have spent 25 years of my life researching legendary western figures from Wyatt Earp to the back shooter Pat Garret and believe me they have made some stinkers but this is no doubt the worst pile of lies and misleads i ever saw. I WISH THERE WAS A RATING LESS THEN 1 BECAUSE THIS MOVIE WOULD RATE A - 10.Not to mention very bad acting from second rate actors.Walter Hill directed my favorite movie of all times the 1979 cult classic THE WARRIORS {in which he also used James Remar }so i expected better from him.This movie is a disgrace to a otherwise great director.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Awful film considering it was directed by Walter Hill....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rusoviet
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ...lousy: dialogue, special affects but the worst was the acting - reminds one of the 1970's and that decade's addiction to Gary Hart or Jimmah Carter... The film was akin to 'Little Big Man' - the sets were awful and the casting was even worse. Took me back 'War' film cast with Hollywood draft dodgers trying to show their manhood i.e. 'A Bridge Too Far' - Eliot Gould and Ryan O'Neal - that fight scene 10 minutes in where 'Wild Bill' takes/shoots down some four desperadoes was pathetic. Truly Hill's worst film - a real 'pc' pile of 'Hillary' and 'Debbie Wassserman Schultz...- castrated men regardless of the violence.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Never touch another mans hat.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Wild Bill Hickok, famed lawman and gunman of the Old West, is haunted by his past and his reputation. He is loved by, but cannot love, Calamity Jane. Dogging his trail is young Jack McCall, who blames Bill for abandoning the boy's mother and destroying her life. McCall has sworn to kill Bill, and Bill's ghosts, his failing eyesight, and his fondness for opium may make McCall's task easier.... One of the main reasons to watch this film is of course Bridges, who puts in a wonderful performance as the titular character. He is ably supported by Barkin and Hurt, and thats most of the positive things said. The film is shot beautifully, and does have an authentic feel to it, but Hill feels out of place directing this, and has made some evry odd choices with the uses of flashbacks, and using Arquette, who is not convincing, but you know the demise of Bill when you meet arquettes character. Reason being that the man is too slimy and typically evil in a Mike Myers way (not a compliment) and is the sole reason of making the film just that laughable. Sure, the history is a load of garbage, but that doesn't matter, all we want to know is how many people he shot, how drunk he got, and how well Bridges does to adapt the two aforementioned traits. it's watchable enough, with some silly scenes and misjudged narrative, but thanks to some good performances, the film isn't the turkey most say it is.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jeff Bridges is an ICON!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jeff Bridges is one of my all-time favorite actors. I guess he's not only prolific, but also an actor who has gained a "Cult" following over the years. In 'Wild Bill', he plays the late legendary lawman Wild Bill Hickok, with unseen ease. As a film, 'Wild Bill' is not an interesting watch, sure it offers some captivating moments, but they are few and far between. Walter Hill has directed this story passably, but the writing is not sharp enough. Be it based on a book, as a cinematic experience, it comes out very half-baked. It had tremendous scope to hold it's viewer, but that has not been tapped in here properly. Jeff Bridges quite frankly owns 'Wild Bill'. The kind of roles Bridges has managed to pull off, make him, probably, one of the finest actors in the History of World Cinema. Bridges goes down as an actor, who should inspire a set of new-born actors in the coming time. On the whole, Watch it only for 'The Dude', who goes 'Western' in here.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Overambitous but disappointing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Hunt2546
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/9/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Most reviews seem to look at this through the prism of "Deadwood," which seems unfair as the elongated TV format allows for far more character development. So to point out that the characters in "Wild Bill" aren't as-- well, you get the picture. Viewed alone, the movie deserves praise for performance, set design, a sense of period dialogue and historical accuracy in visual recreations. Yes, WB really did wear Navy Colts backwards, cavalry-style, in a red sash; yes, he did have greasy lanks of hair and wear a big floppy hat, a thick tie and a vest that didn't match his jacket which didn't match his pants. And for about an hour, I think the movie is pretty amusing. But when it sinks into Deadwood over its last hour, it appears to use too much of the stagey dialogue of one of its sources, a play by someone named Thomas Babe. At this point, it pretty much abandons history which is bad enough, but also cinematic fluency, of which Hill is a master: it becomes static, talky, dreary, and completely loses its momentum. And someone--Babe?--made the decision to give the McCall-Hickcock dynamic an Oedipal overtone--he's the "son" of a woman once loved , then abandoned, by Hickcock. This is an attempt at coherency, to bring the murder into some sort of classic framework. Yeah, swell, however: McCall was much older, a buffalo hunter who'd lost dough to Wild Bill the night before. He didn't stand for the abused son, he stood for the randomness of frontier violence, where booze, pride, stupidity and a culture of pointless aggression could easily spell an ambush murder like McCall's. THAT, to me, would not only have been more accurate, but more fluent and a better movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Someone should put a bullet in this one
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    samkay1
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Perhaps I love Deadwood too much; the critically praised, HBO series for which director Walter Hill appropriately won an Emmy for the pilot. I clearly set my expectations a little too high of this one, which predates the Deadwood series by eight years or so. Coming from Walter Hill, the man behind the Warriors and The Long Riders, there is no way that Wild Bill should have been this sloppy. His portrayal of the life and death of James Butler Hickok results in a motion picture that self-destructs in spectacular fashion. It is vastly underwritten, poorly acted, edited as if it were a labyrinth of jungle vines to be cut down by a machete, and on top of that the movie is also severely anti-climactic. All that Hill gets right is that parts of the movie are well shot, and he is able to capture the look of the times on screen, but on the pages, it is a different matter. The opening twenty minutes (give or take) are especially excruciating. What we see is almost a joke, totally amateurish and more oriented towards obnoxious gunplay than exposition. It is like watching kiddies play cowboys and Indians on the street with little wooded pistols. Hill should know better than that, as should Jeff Bridges, whose portrayal of Hickok is devoid of talent. It is so obviously a performance, and he delivers most of his lines in a hammy fashion, and there is nothing remotely human about this character. The movie does a poor job of showing his misery and self loathing. When all is said and done, Wild Bill is a dud. It is clumsy and careless, and is easily one of the worst westerns I have ever seen.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Underrated, psychedelic western by Walter Hill
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tieman64
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/5/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Wild Bill" was ripped to shreds by critics, ignored by audiences, and went on to become a huge box office failure. But with Jeff Bridges embraced as a bearded guru in the wake of "The Big Lebowski", the film has now become a huge cult favourite. And why not? It's a deliciously psychedelic western; an orgy of over the top violence and drunken wisecracks, the film would also give birth to the HBO series "Deadwood" decades later. Walter Hill spent his career making westerns and so by the time he directed "Wild Bill" he already knew the genre inside out. This is thus a film best appreciated by those familiar with and completely bored by the western genre. Those in search of something a little bit different. A little bit bizarre. The plot: Jeff Bridges plays Wild Bill Hickok, a half blind, always drunk, perpetually stoned lawman who lives out his remaining days at Deadwood, the infamous town in South Dakota. Deadwood is handled like George Lucas handled the town of Mos Eisley in "Star Wars". It's a "hive of scum and villainy", bar fights, gun battles and drunken brawls occurring left right and centre. The streets are muddy, opium dens are overbooked and a hellish rain beats down every night. "This town reminds me of something from the Bible," one character murmurs. "Which part?" Wild Bill asks. "The part right before God gets angry," comes the reply, summing up the tone of the film perfectly. Faced with "woman problems", weighed by his moustache and haunted by his past, Wild Bill mopes around Deadwood, unaware that a disgruntled young man is plotting to kill him. In typical western fashion, the film builds toward their final act face-off, but Hill subverts expectations at every turn. He's less interested in a mythological construction of Wild Bill than a trippy deconstruction, using flashbacks and a fragmented narrative to nosedive into both Bill's past and personal demons. But can we trust these flashbacks? Are these visions the truth or are they attempts by Bill to justify his violent past? In the film's present, Bill surrounds himself by those who blindly worship him. Calamity Jane, an old flame, spends the film lusting for Bill. Likewise Old Charlie, an Englishman who is always eager to defend Bill using charm and logic. Same story with California Joe, an old timer who is always spinning yarns and telling "tall tales" about Wild Bill. Bill, in other words, walks around with his own little propaganda machine, his circle of fawning friends all busy mythologising him. With Bill's real world an illusion, what exactly is there in the film's flashbacks which demonize him? He kills an Indian only because the Indian challenged him, he killed a man in a duel, but that jerk stole his watch. Likewise, he fights a guy in a wheelchair, but not before tying himself to a chair to make things fair. There's always the notion that these "flashbacks", these "traumas", are themselves part of the Wild Bill mythology. That perhaps it is the very falsity of these flashbacks, the very film, which is tormenting Bill. In any case, the film is primarily of interest because it allows us to watch Jeff Bridges chewing scenery. For all his wisecracks and violent flourishes, Bridges' Wild Bill is a fragile guy unable to relate to people, has no family, is going blind and is increasingly crushed as the film gets more and more claustrophobic. Hill's aesthetic strategy is such that you can feel the walls drawing in as the film progresses, the shadows, the mud, the rain, the walls themselves, closing inexorably in, until Bill finds himself at a cramped poker table, a gun behind his skull. But what's great is that Hill suggests that this "claustrophobia" is the result of the Wild Bill myth. That the "need" to constantly adhere to the public's perception of "who Wild Bill is", is ultimately what boxes Bill in and results in his demise. Trapped by his own lore, he sets about a chain of events which leads to his death. Ironically, while it is the "Wild Bill myth" which leads to a gunman seeking revenge on Bill, it is Bill's act of forgiveness toward this very man, his breaking of his dime-novel persona, that earns him a bullet in the brain. 8/10  Val Kilmer's performance as Doc Holiday in "Tombstone" was much lauded in the 90s, but Jeff Bridges' work here is equally awesome. Incidentally, Walter Hill directed the pilot episode of "Deadwood", this film serving as the template for the HBO series' tone and style. Thematically, the film does exactly what "The Assassination of Jesse James by the Coward Robert Ford" does, but arguably a bit better. Worth one viewing. See Hill's "The Warriors" and "The Long Riders".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    wild bilge
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (rcastl2335@aol.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/9/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I first saw this in the theater and found it forgettable. But I thought I'd watch again since it pops up a lot on cable. Now I believe it's too awful to be forgettable. This is a criminally bad film, easily the worst of director Walter Hill's spotty career, although it does seem to have pointed him towards the cable series Deadwood. That's another crime for another day, however. Except for some few expertly staged fight scenes and the performances of Jeff Bridges and Diane Lane, this is a low point in several usually reliable actor's careers. John Hurt is simply a windy fool, ditto James Gammon. Bruce Dern yells (yawn). And Ellen Barkin's Calamity Jane makes me long for Abby Dalton's performance in The Plainsman. Loud, broad, witless, with the worst Southern accent in the long history of bad Southern accents on film, this represents the nadir of her career. It's the only bad performance I've ever seen her give and I still can't imagine what she was thinking. Possibly the only way to enjoy this film is to turn it on, leave the room and, when you hear the sound of raised voices and gunfire, rush back in. Or you could just rent The Plainsman.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a dark and moody Western with an effective atmosphere and feeling to it, but is unfortunately bogged down by its disorganized running time and numerous defects
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheUnknown837-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/2/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Wild Bill is a dark, moody Western about the last days of legendary lawman James Butler Hickock that sometimes shows off its true colors (by that, I mean its riveting action sequences, not its appearance) but suffers from a disorganized screenplay, some dull characters, an imperfect running time, and while it's not a bad Western, it's not a great one either. Jeff Bridges gives a noteworthy performance as Wild Bill, John Hurt gives most of the movie's seldom-seen charisma as his friend Charley Prince (I'm not sure if this character is real or not) and then there is a truly great performance by Ellen Barkin as frontierswoman Calamity Jane. In shorter, laconic terms, Wild Bill boasts a great cast and some witty dialogue. Director Walter Hill (who also directed The Long Riders (1980) with the Carradine brothers) does a phenomenal job with the action scenes as well. The killings in this film look harsh and brutal as they in deed were. And the violence is not overdone to the point where it becomes depressing. But like I mentioned earlier, the story is disorganized. There were too many black-and-white flashback scenes, which I've seen many done better many times before in other films, that dragged on and slowed the movie down for me. John Hurt's narration was sometimes effective, sometimes overdrawn. And the pacing was in need of a revision. I'm sure the filmmakers could have worked it out a different way to tell the past of the characters without constantly using flashbacks and could have removed some additional scenes that went into and out of nowhere. Because they unfortunately are the movie's major flaws. They slow it down. Wild Bill, again is not necessarily a bad film. I did mildly enjoy it at times, but it is a very dark motion picture without much point behind itself. The action scenes are good, the acting is great, and the general atmosphere of a dark time in a weary man's life is convincing. But ultimately, Wild Bill is just too slow and kind of a disappointment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The acting is key in this movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    garotycoyote
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/7/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I thought this movie to be a truly great one and the key here is really great acting especially from Jeff Bridges. For that reason and that reason alone its worth seeing this movie. To actually experience the realism created by this level of acting is truly a feat that movie actors strive to achieve. Jeff Bridges has achieved that in this rendition of Wild Bill. I really do not have anything more I can say about this but its the sort of film that leaves you wishing there would be a sequel. If this were to become a TV series I would probably put money on it to say it would be a winner. So find it rent it sit back and watch one of the most enjoyable movies of all time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A pile of horse s**T
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rusty13252
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Out of every movie i have ever seen based on a legendary old west figure this movie was the largest pile of horse s**T i have ever seen.There is not 1/100 of fact base in this film i have spent 25 years of my life researching legendary western figures from Wyatt Earp to the back shooter Pat Garret and believe me they have made some stinkers but this is no doubt the worst pile of lies and misleads i ever saw. I WISH THERE WAS A RATING LESS THEN 1 BECAUSE THIS MOVIE WOULD RATE A - 10.Not to mention very bad acting from second rate actors.Walter Hill directed my favorite movie of all times the 1979 cult classic THE WARRIORS {in which he also used James Remar }so i expected better from him.This movie is a disgrace to a otherwise great director.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Awful film considering it was directed by Walter Hill....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rusoviet
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ...lousy: dialogue, special affects but the worst was the acting - reminds one of the 1970's and that decade's addiction to Gary Hart or Jimmah Carter... The film was akin to 'Little Big Man' - the sets were awful and the casting was even worse. Took me back 'War' film cast with Hollywood draft dodgers trying to show their manhood i.e. 'A Bridge Too Far' - Eliot Gould and Ryan O'Neal - that fight scene 10 minutes in where 'Wild Bill' takes/shoots down some four desperadoes was pathetic. Truly Hill's worst film - a real 'pc' pile of 'Hillary' and 'Debbie Wassserman Schultz...- castrated men regardless of the violence.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Never touch another mans hat.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Wild Bill Hickok, famed lawman and gunman of the Old West, is haunted by his past and his reputation. He is loved by, but cannot love, Calamity Jane. Dogging his trail is young Jack McCall, who blames Bill for abandoning the boy's mother and destroying her life. McCall has sworn to kill Bill, and Bill's ghosts, his failing eyesight, and his fondness for opium may make McCall's task easier.... One of the main reasons to watch this film is of course Bridges, who puts in a wonderful performance as the titular character. He is ably supported by Barkin and Hurt, and thats most of the positive things said. The film is shot beautifully, and does have an authentic feel to it, but Hill feels out of place directing this, and has made some evry odd choices with the uses of flashbacks, and using Arquette, who is not convincing, but you know the demise of Bill when you meet arquettes character. Reason being that the man is too slimy and typically evil in a Mike Myers way (not a compliment) and is the sole reason of making the film just that laughable. Sure, the history is a load of garbage, but that doesn't matter, all we want to know is how many people he shot, how drunk he got, and how well Bridges does to adapt the two aforementioned traits. it's watchable enough, with some silly scenes and misjudged narrative, but thanks to some good performances, the film isn't the turkey most say it is.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jeff Bridges is an ICON!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jeff Bridges is one of my all-time favorite actors. I guess he's not only prolific, but also an actor who has gained a "Cult" following over the years. In 'Wild Bill', he plays the late legendary lawman Wild Bill Hickok, with unseen ease. As a film, 'Wild Bill' is not an interesting watch, sure it offers some captivating moments, but they are few and far between. Walter Hill has directed this story passably, but the writing is not sharp enough. Be it based on a book, as a cinematic experience, it comes out very half-baked. It had tremendous scope to hold it's viewer, but that has not been tapped in here properly. Jeff Bridges quite frankly owns 'Wild Bill'. The kind of roles Bridges has managed to pull off, make him, probably, one of the finest actors in the History of World Cinema. Bridges goes down as an actor, who should inspire a set of new-born actors in the coming time. On the whole, Watch it only for 'The Dude', who goes 'Western' in here.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Overambitous but disappointing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Hunt2546
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/9/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Most reviews seem to look at this through the prism of "Deadwood," which seems unfair as the elongated TV format allows for far more character development. So to point out that the characters in "Wild Bill" aren't as-- well, you get the picture. Viewed alone, the movie deserves praise for performance, set design, a sense of period dialogue and historical accuracy in visual recreations. Yes, WB really did wear Navy Colts backwards, cavalry-style, in a red sash; yes, he did have greasy lanks of hair and wear a big floppy hat, a thick tie and a vest that didn't match his jacket which didn't match his pants. And for about an hour, I think the movie is pretty amusing. But when it sinks into Deadwood over its last hour, it appears to use too much of the stagey dialogue of one of its sources, a play by someone named Thomas Babe. At this point, it pretty much abandons history which is bad enough, but also cinematic fluency, of which Hill is a master: it becomes static, talky, dreary, and completely loses its momentum. And someone--Babe?--made the decision to give the McCall-Hickcock dynamic an Oedipal overtone--he's the "son" of a woman once loved , then abandoned, by Hickcock. This is an attempt at coherency, to bring the murder into some sort of classic framework. Yeah, swell, however: McCall was much older, a buffalo hunter who'd lost dough to Wild Bill the night before. He didn't stand for the abused son, he stood for the randomness of frontier violence, where booze, pride, stupidity and a culture of pointless aggression could easily spell an ambush murder like McCall's. THAT, to me, would not only have been more accurate, but more fluent and a better movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Someone should put a bullet in this one
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    samkay1
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Perhaps I love Deadwood too much; the critically praised, HBO series for which director Walter Hill appropriately won an Emmy for the pilot. I clearly set my expectations a little too high of this one, which predates the Deadwood series by eight years or so. Coming from Walter Hill, the man behind the Warriors and The Long Riders, there is no way that Wild Bill should have been this sloppy. His portrayal of the life and death of James Butler Hickok results in a motion picture that self-destructs in spectacular fashion. It is vastly underwritten, poorly acted, edited as if it were a labyrinth of jungle vines to be cut down by a machete, and on top of that the movie is also severely anti-climactic. All that Hill gets right is that parts of the movie are well shot, and he is able to capture the look of the times on screen, but on the pages, it is a different matter. The opening twenty minutes (give or take) are especially excruciating. What we see is almost a joke, totally amateurish and more oriented towards obnoxious gunplay than exposition. It is like watching kiddies play cowboys and Indians on the street with little wooded pistols. Hill should know better than that, as should Jeff Bridges, whose portrayal of Hickok is devoid of talent. It is so obviously a performance, and he delivers most of his lines in a hammy fashion, and there is nothing remotely human about this character. The movie does a poor job of showing his misery and self loathing. When all is said and done, Wild Bill is a dud. It is clumsy and careless, and is easily one of the worst westerns I have ever seen.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Underrated, psychedelic western by Walter Hill
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tieman64
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/5/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Wild Bill" was ripped to shreds by critics, ignored by audiences, and went on to become a huge box office failure. But with Jeff Bridges embraced as a bearded guru in the wake of "The Big Lebowski", the film has now become a huge cult favourite. And why not? It's a deliciously psychedelic western; an orgy of over the top violence and drunken wisecracks, the film would also give birth to the HBO series "Deadwood" decades later. Walter Hill spent his career making westerns and so by the time he directed "Wild Bill" he already knew the genre inside out. This is thus a film best appreciated by those familiar with and completely bored by the western genre. Those in search of something a little bit different. A little bit bizarre. The plot: Jeff Bridges plays Wild Bill Hickok, a half blind, always drunk, perpetually stoned lawman who lives out his remaining days at Deadwood, the infamous town in South Dakota. Deadwood is handled like George Lucas handled the town of Mos Eisley in "Star Wars". It's a "hive of scum and villainy", bar fights, gun battles and drunken brawls occurring left right and centre. The streets are muddy, opium dens are overbooked and a hellish rain beats down every night. "This town reminds me of something from the Bible," one character murmurs. "Which part?" Wild Bill asks. "The part right before God gets angry," comes the reply, summing up the tone of the film perfectly. Faced with "woman problems", weighed by his moustache and haunted by his past, Wild Bill mopes around Deadwood, unaware that a disgruntled young man is plotting to kill him. In typical western fashion, the film builds toward their final act face-off, but Hill subverts expectations at every turn. He's less interested in a mythological construction of Wild Bill than a trippy deconstruction, using flashbacks and a fragmented narrative to nosedive into both Bill's past and personal demons. But can we trust these flashbacks? Are these visions the truth or are they attempts by Bill to justify his violent past? In the film's present, Bill surrounds himself by those who blindly worship him. Calamity Jane, an old flame, spends the film lusting for Bill. Likewise Old Charlie, an Englishman who is always eager to defend Bill using charm and logic. Same story with California Joe, an old timer who is always spinning yarns and telling "tall tales" about Wild Bill. Bill, in other words, walks around with his own little propaganda machine, his circle of fawning friends all busy mythologising him. With Bill's real world an illusion, what exactly is there in the film's flashbacks which demonize him? He kills an Indian only because the Indian challenged him, he killed a man in a duel, but that jerk stole his watch. Likewise, he fights a guy in a wheelchair, but not before tying himself to a chair to make things fair. There's always the notion that these "flashbacks", these "traumas", are themselves part of the Wild Bill mythology. That perhaps it is the very falsity of these flashbacks, the very film, which is tormenting Bill. In any case, the film is primarily of interest because it allows us to watch Jeff Bridges chewing scenery. For all his wisecracks and violent flourishes, Bridges' Wild Bill is a fragile guy unable to relate to people, has no family, is going blind and is increasingly crushed as the film gets more and more claustrophobic. Hill's aesthetic strategy is such that you can feel the walls drawing in as the film progresses, the shadows, the mud, the rain, the walls themselves, closing inexorably in, until Bill finds himself at a cramped poker table, a gun behind his skull. But what's great is that Hill suggests that this "claustrophobia" is the result of the Wild Bill myth. That the "need" to constantly adhere to the public's perception of "who Wild Bill is", is ultimately what boxes Bill in and results in his demise. Trapped by his own lore, he sets about a chain of events which leads to his death. Ironically, while it is the "Wild Bill myth" which leads to a gunman seeking revenge on Bill, it is Bill's act of forgiveness toward this very man, his breaking of his dime-novel persona, that earns him a bullet in the brain. 8/10  Val Kilmer's performance as Doc Holiday in "Tombstone" was much lauded in the 90s, but Jeff Bridges' work here is equally awesome. Incidentally, Walter Hill directed the pilot episode of "Deadwood", this film serving as the template for the HBO series' tone and style. Thematically, the film does exactly what "The Assassination of Jesse James by the Coward Robert Ford" does, but arguably a bit better. Worth one viewing. See Hill's "The Warriors" and "The Long Riders".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    wild bilge
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (rcastl2335@aol.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/9/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I first saw this in the theater and found it forgettable. But I thought I'd watch again since it pops up a lot on cable. Now I believe it's too awful to be forgettable. This is a criminally bad film, easily the worst of director Walter Hill's spotty career, although it does seem to have pointed him towards the cable series Deadwood. That's another crime for another day, however. Except for some few expertly staged fight scenes and the performances of Jeff Bridges and Diane Lane, this is a low point in several usually reliable actor's careers. John Hurt is simply a windy fool, ditto James Gammon. Bruce Dern yells (yawn). And Ellen Barkin's Calamity Jane makes me long for Abby Dalton's performance in The Plainsman. Loud, broad, witless, with the worst Southern accent in the long history of bad Southern accents on film, this represents the nadir of her career. It's the only bad performance I've ever seen her give and I still can't imagine what she was thinking. Possibly the only way to enjoy this film is to turn it on, leave the room and, when you hear the sound of raised voices and gunfire, rush back in. Or you could just rent The Plainsman.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a dark and moody Western with an effective atmosphere and feeling to it, but is unfortunately bogged down by its disorganized running time and numerous defects
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheUnknown837-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/2/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Wild Bill is a dark, moody Western about the last days of legendary lawman James Butler Hickock that sometimes shows off its true colors (by that, I mean its riveting action sequences, not its appearance) but suffers from a disorganized screenplay, some dull characters, an imperfect running time, and while it's not a bad Western, it's not a great one either. Jeff Bridges gives a noteworthy performance as Wild Bill, John Hurt gives most of the movie's seldom-seen charisma as his friend Charley Prince (I'm not sure if this character is real or not) and then there is a truly great performance by Ellen Barkin as frontierswoman Calamity Jane. In shorter, laconic terms, Wild Bill boasts a great cast and some witty dialogue. Director Walter Hill (who also directed The Long Riders (1980) with the Carradine brothers) does a phenomenal job with the action scenes as well. The killings in this film look harsh and brutal as they in deed were. And the violence is not overdone to the point where it becomes depressing. But like I mentioned earlier, the story is disorganized. There were too many black-and-white flashback scenes, which I've seen many done better many times before in other films, that dragged on and slowed the movie down for me. John Hurt's narration was sometimes effective, sometimes overdrawn. And the pacing was in need of a revision. I'm sure the filmmakers could have worked it out a different way to tell the past of the characters without constantly using flashbacks and could have removed some additional scenes that went into and out of nowhere. Because they unfortunately are the movie's major flaws. They slow it down. Wild Bill, again is not necessarily a bad film. I did mildly enjoy it at times, but it is a very dark motion picture without much point behind itself. The action scenes are good, the acting is great, and the general atmosphere of a dark time in a weary man's life is convincing. But ultimately, Wild Bill is just too slow and kind of a disappointment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The acting is key in this movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    garotycoyote
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/7/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I thought this movie to be a truly great one and the key here is really great acting especially from Jeff Bridges. For that reason and that reason alone its worth seeing this movie. To actually experience the realism created by this level of acting is truly a feat that movie actors strive to achieve. Jeff Bridges has achieved that in this rendition of Wild Bill. I really do not have anything more I can say about this but its the sort of film that leaves you wishing there would be a sequel. If this were to become a TV series I would probably put money on it to say it would be a winner. So find it rent it sit back and watch one of the most enjoyable movies of all time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
