<filme>
 <id>
  563
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0112040
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1995
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Fenda No Tempo (TV Mini-Serie
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  5.9
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Most of the passengers on an airplane disappear, and the remainder land the plane in a mysteriously barren airport.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  On a red eye flight to Boston from LA 10 people wake up to a shock. All the passengers and crew have vanished. When they try to contact the ground they make no connections. They land the plane only to discover that things haven't changed. But its like the world is dead. No one is there, the air is still, sound doesn't echo, the food is tasteless. And a distant sound is heard coming closer. A race of monstrous beings bent on their destruction is heading for them, eating everything in sight.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Horror
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Mystery
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Sci-Fi
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   time warp
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   airport
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   airplane
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   businessman
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   pilot
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores></diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Laurel Entertainment Inc.
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Patricia Wettig
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Dean Stockwell
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Tom Holland
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Different Take On Time Travel.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Based on a Stephen King novel, this TV movie adaptation is about the passengers on a red-eye airplane flight from L.A to Boston who awaken to find that the rest of the passengers and crew are gone, and they are all alone on the plane, which will soon run out of fuel. Fortunately, there is a pilot on board, who tries to land the plane at a nearby airport, only to discover that it is also empty, and that they are being pursued by giant, howling monsters called Langoliers that seem to be devouring time itself... Potentially interesting take on time travel, with an appealing cast of characters(except Bronson Pinchot, quite good playing an obnoxious and terrified child-like man who knows all about the Langoliers from his hideous father.) cannot save far-fetched premise, and the primitive CGI Langoliers have not aged well... Still, not the worst way to kill three hours!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Spectacular Story!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    djk-930-38279
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love this movie so much! All of the sci-fi and mystery of it is exactly what I love in books and movies. In this feature, I first saw it on TV and then I read the book. The book is very good as well, but it gives out much more information, describes things in more detail, which in some ways is good, but for me, when it comes to the gore with Mr. Toomey, I would rather not know so much. So in that case, watching the movie is much more preferred than reading it in the book. I gave this movie a 9 because I love it so much, but I just have one problem with it. There was some especially terrible acting, mostly by Christopher Collet who played Albert Kaussner. In many instances, he would overact his lines, and/or his lines were just written very poorly for him. I think for the most part though, the other main characters did pretty well. Not the best acting, but it was good.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Most interesting TV adaptation of S. King's work
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sang Park
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I just didn't give higher vote just because of the low budget and the poor F/X alloted to this movie. I have full understanding that this is low budget TV movie. But I could resist watching it because I had such high expectation in David Morse and Dean Stockwell. Enough with background of my watching movie.. First I didn't realize that this movie is 3 hours long... Maybe when they aired on TV they could have broken into series, but I've watched this on Netflix as one piece and it is longer movie than the lord of the rings. But as others put it, the length was due to the faithful adaptation of the original novel. No jumps or gaps in plots. Whenever there requires some explanation, Dean Stockwell slides in exuberantly and fulfills duties (he is supposed to be the avatar of S. King in the movie). I too have some pet peeve on the crappy F/X (really cheesy C.G.), but the reaction of actors actress are good enough to convince me that the monsters are there creeping in. All the settings and actings are good enough to make me get the creeps from what is going on in the movie. (FYI, I am a seasoned pseudo-professional monster/scary movie tester). When compared with "Stand", I think this is descent TV movie and I enjoyed pretty much.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    bad acting...bad FX....but still an excellent TV movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    supreme_mamu
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Some people says that acting and FX are the main purpose in creating a good movie, but here, it was proved wrong. I have to admit that this movie are full of characters with bad acting, i mean all of them (except for Bronson Pinchot who gave an excellent performance as mad guy Mr Craig Toomey). But the worst goes to the little girl, the blind little girl who does not have any emotional feelings and not really up to the standard to what audience always wanted. And the FX is quite poor and cheesy, seems to be cartoons. It really looks funny to me! I wish it could be better in order to turn this into a great movie. But, none of these really affect the greatness of The Langoliers. The main purpose of why this movie is created is because of the storyline, the story written by the master of horror, Stephen King. And, the story are almost exactly accurate to the short story in 4 Past Midnight. The way the story tell us is very entertaining, until I didn't really focus myself on the acting and the FX. It is the story which keep me thinking and wait for what is going to happen at the end of the story. Even though the movie is 3 hours long, but it doesn't make me feel boring because the suspend is there. I'm gonna watch this movie again for the 10th times this afternoon :) forget about the acting and the FX, concentrate on the storyline! excellent (10/10 stars)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Amazingly bad
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    CinefanR
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Everything is this movie is painfully bad- acting, story-line, script, special effects. It's true that my expectations were high. I've heard a lot about Stephen King and I imagined that such a celebrated writer would come up with something brilliant and original. I was expecting to see a spark of genius from the so-called "master of horror". Boy, was I wrong... The first 10 minutes or so make a promising start and I thought the premise was intriguing. After that, it falls flat on all levels. Pretentious, uninteresting one-dimensional characters check. Terribly written dialogue check. Ridiculous special effects check. The acting is atrocious, check that too. The sense of mystery is basically zero, probably because the viewer can't ignore the fact that everything takes place in a cheap TV set. And the worst part is that it goes on and on, and on for 3 hours. The only reason I kept watching was to see if maybe a good conclusion or some clever twist in the story line would save it somehow, but no. This movie is nothing more than the usual sci-fi clich&eacute;s piled up to the very end, while the production standards are beyond embarrassing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    ..and then...and then..and then...NOTHING!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Carol Mckinley
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    THIS REVIEW CONTAINS (MILD) SPOILERS! This is hands down the worst movie I have ever seen in my life. I've read through the first few pages of reviews left on this movie and to see glowing reviews over this steaming pile of crap is laughable. Really...did we watch the same movie? Imagine getting on a roller coaster. The longest, scariest, and highest roller coaster in the entire theme park. You buy the ticket, wait in line, and board the roller coaster. You get on the ride and go through dark tunnels, loops, and curves.....for hours. Although the ride is tiring, and the wait was long, you are still caught up in the anticipation. After all, the suspense is killing you, and with all this prolonged anticipation, surely this is going to be a hell of a ride, right? Now imagine getting to the peak of the roller coaster. Finally, you are at the highest point. You're ready. You waited so long. Now all of your waiting is going to finally pay off. You look down and see the fall...now you are excited. You prepare yourself for the adrenaline rush and excitement of finally getting to the best part..and then...........you are immediately let off the ride. That is the best way to describe this movie. It is probably the most disappointing thriller film that one could possibly waste hours out of their day watching. I HIGHLY warn that people understand that you WILL with out a doubt be disappointed to an extreme extent if you watch this movie. In fact, do yourself a favor, and if you do decide to watch this garbage, watch the first two hours of it and then turn it off and come to your own logical conclusion of what happened. I find it more comforting to think that Mr. Toomey or the equally irritating Dianne girl and/or boy were controlling the plane and preventing the passengers from making it to their proper dimension the entire time. Langoliers is often times given a second glance because of it's so called "original plot" (albeit the many loopholes) and suspense. The terrible effects are also often excused due to the fact that this was a "made for TV" movie. Bull. I've seen movies made in the 20s with better effects. Do not be deceived. There is nothing original about this plot. I point anyone who is interested to Twilight Zone episode "The Odyssey of Flight 33". The only difference between the two is a more coherent and concise plot from Rod Sterling, minus the ridiculous "character development" of otherwise ridiculous characters and Chomp Chomp Pac-men monsters that take three hours to make their grand debut. Suspense is the highest point of this movie as well as it's down fall. For several hours we do not see these "Langoliers" we can only "hear" them (and by "hear" them, I mean the snap, crackle, pop noise one would hear from pouring milk over Rice Krispie cereal) as well as the suspense of knowing that they could jump out at any moment. As a viewer when 95% of a film is suspense without even a view of the alleged monster, one would expect an even bigger climax. .......so what are the Langoliers? Who knows. We are never told exactly "what" they are or the relevancy these creatures have on the story. The Langoliers could be absent from this movie, and it would still make sense, scratch that, the movie would make MORE sense if the Langoliers were not included. Are the Langoliers fabricated from Mr. Toomey's mind and simply "boogeymen" from his childhood past? Who knows. Are they simply the eaters of time and space? Who knows. Are they a mixed breed of Tazmanian Devil and Pac Men? Seems likely.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Like A 3 hour long episode of "The Twilight Zone"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stubbers
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am currently reading "Four Past Midnight", the book of four Stephen King novellas which opens with "The Langoliers". I have just finished reading this story and immediately checked out the movie version. I wasn't disappointed. Something about this story, like many of King's, really touches a nerve. The quality is mainly in the basic concept rather than the sometimes-clunky dialogue. I like the idea of the past still existing physically, until it eventually becomes swallowed up by the Langoliers, the so-called Housekeepers of Eternity who hoover up the past to make way for the present. Incidentally, while reading the book I assumed the emphasis in the word was on the "o" - langOliers, to rhyme with magnolias. But no, the emphasis is on the "i" - langol-Iers, to rhyme with chandeliers. Either way, it's a strange word used to describe a very strange (but somehow not totally unfeasible) type of creature. Like all good "Twilight Zone" episodes, which this reminds me of, such a great underlying premise leaves a really strong, unnerving impression. As such, it doesn't matter so much that the acting and special effects aren't amazing. The atmosphere and plot are totally faithful to the original book. In a way, the slightly wooden, stilted acting suits the wooden, stilted world in which the characters find themselves. An airless, stuffy, oppressive world where you can barely light a match, where the wind either doesn't blow (according to the book), or else blows on the ground level but doesn't move the clouds (according to the movie, because they couldn't stop the wind blowing on location!). A world lying in the dumpster, slowly atrophying, thrown on the scrapheap by the constant forward motion of time's winged chariot. Always good to see Dean Stockwell, a man who is no stranger to travelling through time! Not his greatest ever performance here, but he certainly brings enigma to the part of writer Bob Jenkins. Bronson Pinchot brought just the right amount of creepy-but-sympathetic insanity to Craig Toomey, the dictionary definition of a loser in life, and a stark warning to what can happen to children later in life if they are belittled by their over-demanding parents. By comparison, David Morse as Captain Brian Engel was low-key and understated, but that was the exact impression I got of him from the book. If you were flying in an airplane through a rip in the space-time continuum, you would certainly want your pilot to be calm and unflappable! Unlike some posters here, I actually thought Mark Lindsay Chapman's Anglo-American accent was spot on. And I say this as a Brit who has spent considerable time in America. Out of necessity for being understood clearly and not sounding too "plum in mouth", Brits in the States have to slip in a few American sounding inflections here and there. So kudos to Chapman for a great, convincing performance as Americanised British secret agent Nick Popewell. I'd go so far as to say that his English accent was better than Harry Shearer's immortal Derek Smalls character (Spinal Tap). As for the ladies - well thumbs up for both Patricia Wettig and Kimber Riddle for certainly being very watchable, if not the most three-dimensional performances I have ever seen. And unlike many people here, I had no issues with Kate Maberly as blind Dinah. Finally, the effects of the Langoliers themselves. No problem! Once again, my image of them from reading the book was as funny sort of bouncing balls with teeth, which is more or less how they turned out on screen. These are not hi-tech computer generated monsters full of whizzbang explosions, they are like parasitic insects that feed off the scraps of the past. I don't see how they could have been better represented to be honest. So what we have here is a TV movie that transcends the limitations of its slightly second-rate format, by dint of the strength of the basic source material and the fact that they adhered to all the elements of the book. If it ain't broke, don't fix it. I'm sorry that not everyone enjoyed the movie, and I appreciate the negative comments it has received from some. For me it boils down to the concept of the Langoliers being something that really intrigued me, in a scary way, and I can't get enough of reading about them or watching them. For that reason, the movie gave me exactly what I was looking for.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Faithful Adaptation
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ramin99
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I watched about half of this abomination then fittingly enough dropped like a sack of potatoes after drinking god knows how many beers; I mean is it possible to watch such rubbish with all of your intellectual faculties intact? The bad acting, especially by the blind girl, the young guy and the hot girl (she was pleasing to the eyes so I guess that makes her bad acting excusable), and deciding whether or not she wore bras was about all I can remember from the film now. I am befuddled to read, by a good number of reviewers, the following paradox: "the book is good but this particular adaptation is bad. I am a huge fan of that writer but this film sucks!" A movie follows a script thus the source material of a film, is, its script. If the script is good then there is a fat chance the movie turns out good; but if bad no one can turn it into a masterpiece. Do you see my point? Please get your heads out of your ***** and see things for what they are! A few hours later I woke up dizzy with accompanying headache and a bad taste in my mouth, then sat down to write this review, so I'm grumpier/crankier than usual.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An intriguing King mystery hampered down in TV land
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    DAVID SIM
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Stephen King is the world's most prolific horror novelist. His success lies in his writing, and in the sheer volume of films and TV movies adapting his work. The Langoliers is one of several King mini-series we've seen in recent years. Adapted from a short story in King's novella Four Past Midnight, it represents one of King's occasional detours from horror and into science-fiction. The premise is something that could easily fill an episode of The Twilight Zone (in fact the plot reminded me more of The Lost Hour, an episode from TV's Eerie Indiana). Ten airline passengers fall asleep on a red-eye flight to Boston. During the flight, the plane flew through a time-rip and when it came out the other side, it catapulted the plane back in time by a day. The sleeping passengers were the only ones to emerge unharmed. All the ones that were awake just vanished into the ether. When they land the plane, the people on the ground have disappeared as well. Its a dead, lifeless world with no electricity and vigour, and what's worse is the Langoliers, monsters from one of the passenger's childhood stories are coming to gobble them up. I always felt The Langoliers was one that straddled an uneasy line between science-fiction and horror. When most authors try to tackle different genres at the same time they often wind up shortchanging one at the expense of the other, or even worse is that they cancel each other out. One suspects the way King wrote the story, it was originally a time-travel piece, but when it got to the airport scenes, he decided to include the Langoliers to give it a bit more dramatic intensity. Without it, he would have been left with a not too terribly gripping storyline. Fill the airplane with fuel. Backtrack to the time-rip. Fly through it. They get home. The Langoliers was directed by genre regular Tom Holland. Holland emerged in the 80s with two above average horror movies, Fright Night and Child's Play. But then into the 90s, he seemed to disappear into TV land, and vanished after that, much like one of the passengers on Flight 29. Fright Night and Child's Play showed Holland with a fine grasp of horror mechanics. But whether its because they were feature films or its just the slimness of King's material, his work on The Langoliers disappoints. Certainly it begins well. Once the passengers vanish from the plane, it makes for a highly absorbing mystery. But eventually, the story begins to drag. And its not exactly helped by the TV production values Holland is forced to work with. The Langoliers are given such an inscrutable buildup (in a nice touch we hear they're approach even when they're still miles away) that when they finally arrive, we're almost breathless with anticipation. But as soon as you see them, you're howling with laughter. They look like giant meatballs with teeth, and the TV special effects play out the scene embarrassingly. Where The Langoliers is more successful is in some of the characterisations. Dean Stockwell, David Morse and Mark Lindsay Chapman all give capable performances. Especially Chapman, an actor better known for playing smarmy snake in the grasses, but gives surprising sympathy to the part of a special operator with a chequered past. His wry, guarded performance makes his character Nick Hopewell into the most well developed member of the cast. Kate Maberly has some creepy moments as the blind girl who sees more than the people around her. But even creepier is Bronson Pinchot, giving a highly live-wire performance as Craig Toomey, the psycho in they're midst who knows all about Langoliers from the horror stories his father delighted in telling him as a child. With the rest of the story stifled by TV movie surroundings, he brings a welcome surge of energy whenever he's in it. The other survivors could have been written out altogether to no noticeable effect. It does get itself together for an effective, slightly tragic finale, but The Langoliers lacks the childhood terrors of IT, or the assured storytelling of The Shining. King has given Tom Holland a slim story to work with, so amongst the TV versions of his work, The Langoliers ranks as one of the more anonymous.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A mixed blessing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Neil Welch
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Stephen King's enjoyable novella about a planeload of passengers who, thanks to a very odd storm and a warp in space/time, find themselves stranded in an unpopulated and rapidly decaying version of their own world (because time has moved on into the future) is turned into a possibly over-long three-part TV miniseries. There is much to like here. The adaptation is moderately faithful, the casting and performances are good (Bronson Pinchot is a bit over the top, but that is a requirement of the character), and there are some nice production touches - the gradual de-saturisation of the colour works well to demonstrate what is happening. Not so good are the Langoliers themselves. They had to be a special effect, but they could have usefully consumed a bigger chunk of budget: they should be terrifying because of what they do but, unfortunately, they come across as rather comical. And, as I said, the thing is too long. Three hours is taken to tell a story which could have been told in half that time, and you'd have been on the edge of your seat all the way through.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Different Take On Time Travel.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Based on a Stephen King novel, this TV movie adaptation is about the passengers on a red-eye airplane flight from L.A to Boston who awaken to find that the rest of the passengers and crew are gone, and they are all alone on the plane, which will soon run out of fuel. Fortunately, there is a pilot on board, who tries to land the plane at a nearby airport, only to discover that it is also empty, and that they are being pursued by giant, howling monsters called Langoliers that seem to be devouring time itself... Potentially interesting take on time travel, with an appealing cast of characters(except Bronson Pinchot, quite good playing an obnoxious and terrified child-like man who knows all about the Langoliers from his hideous father.) cannot save far-fetched premise, and the primitive CGI Langoliers have not aged well... Still, not the worst way to kill three hours!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Spectacular Story!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    djk-930-38279
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love this movie so much! All of the sci-fi and mystery of it is exactly what I love in books and movies. In this feature, I first saw it on TV and then I read the book. The book is very good as well, but it gives out much more information, describes things in more detail, which in some ways is good, but for me, when it comes to the gore with Mr. Toomey, I would rather not know so much. So in that case, watching the movie is much more preferred than reading it in the book. I gave this movie a 9 because I love it so much, but I just have one problem with it. There was some especially terrible acting, mostly by Christopher Collet who played Albert Kaussner. In many instances, he would overact his lines, and/or his lines were just written very poorly for him. I think for the most part though, the other main characters did pretty well. Not the best acting, but it was good.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Most interesting TV adaptation of S. King's work
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sang Park
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I just didn't give higher vote just because of the low budget and the poor F/X alloted to this movie. I have full understanding that this is low budget TV movie. But I could resist watching it because I had such high expectation in David Morse and Dean Stockwell. Enough with background of my watching movie.. First I didn't realize that this movie is 3 hours long... Maybe when they aired on TV they could have broken into series, but I've watched this on Netflix as one piece and it is longer movie than the lord of the rings. But as others put it, the length was due to the faithful adaptation of the original novel. No jumps or gaps in plots. Whenever there requires some explanation, Dean Stockwell slides in exuberantly and fulfills duties (he is supposed to be the avatar of S. King in the movie). I too have some pet peeve on the crappy F/X (really cheesy C.G.), but the reaction of actors actress are good enough to convince me that the monsters are there creeping in. All the settings and actings are good enough to make me get the creeps from what is going on in the movie. (FYI, I am a seasoned pseudo-professional monster/scary movie tester). When compared with "Stand", I think this is descent TV movie and I enjoyed pretty much.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    bad acting...bad FX....but still an excellent TV movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    supreme_mamu
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Some people says that acting and FX are the main purpose in creating a good movie, but here, it was proved wrong. I have to admit that this movie are full of characters with bad acting, i mean all of them (except for Bronson Pinchot who gave an excellent performance as mad guy Mr Craig Toomey). But the worst goes to the little girl, the blind little girl who does not have any emotional feelings and not really up to the standard to what audience always wanted. And the FX is quite poor and cheesy, seems to be cartoons. It really looks funny to me! I wish it could be better in order to turn this into a great movie. But, none of these really affect the greatness of The Langoliers. The main purpose of why this movie is created is because of the storyline, the story written by the master of horror, Stephen King. And, the story are almost exactly accurate to the short story in 4 Past Midnight. The way the story tell us is very entertaining, until I didn't really focus myself on the acting and the FX. It is the story which keep me thinking and wait for what is going to happen at the end of the story. Even though the movie is 3 hours long, but it doesn't make me feel boring because the suspend is there. I'm gonna watch this movie again for the 10th times this afternoon :) forget about the acting and the FX, concentrate on the storyline! excellent (10/10 stars)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Amazingly bad
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    CinefanR
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Everything is this movie is painfully bad- acting, story-line, script, special effects. It's true that my expectations were high. I've heard a lot about Stephen King and I imagined that such a celebrated writer would come up with something brilliant and original. I was expecting to see a spark of genius from the so-called "master of horror". Boy, was I wrong... The first 10 minutes or so make a promising start and I thought the premise was intriguing. After that, it falls flat on all levels. Pretentious, uninteresting one-dimensional characters check. Terribly written dialogue check. Ridiculous special effects check. The acting is atrocious, check that too. The sense of mystery is basically zero, probably because the viewer can't ignore the fact that everything takes place in a cheap TV set. And the worst part is that it goes on and on, and on for 3 hours. The only reason I kept watching was to see if maybe a good conclusion or some clever twist in the story line would save it somehow, but no. This movie is nothing more than the usual sci-fi clich&eacute;s piled up to the very end, while the production standards are beyond embarrassing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    ..and then...and then..and then...NOTHING!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Carol Mckinley
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    THIS REVIEW CONTAINS (MILD) SPOILERS! This is hands down the worst movie I have ever seen in my life. I've read through the first few pages of reviews left on this movie and to see glowing reviews over this steaming pile of crap is laughable. Really...did we watch the same movie? Imagine getting on a roller coaster. The longest, scariest, and highest roller coaster in the entire theme park. You buy the ticket, wait in line, and board the roller coaster. You get on the ride and go through dark tunnels, loops, and curves.....for hours. Although the ride is tiring, and the wait was long, you are still caught up in the anticipation. After all, the suspense is killing you, and with all this prolonged anticipation, surely this is going to be a hell of a ride, right? Now imagine getting to the peak of the roller coaster. Finally, you are at the highest point. You're ready. You waited so long. Now all of your waiting is going to finally pay off. You look down and see the fall...now you are excited. You prepare yourself for the adrenaline rush and excitement of finally getting to the best part..and then...........you are immediately let off the ride. That is the best way to describe this movie. It is probably the most disappointing thriller film that one could possibly waste hours out of their day watching. I HIGHLY warn that people understand that you WILL with out a doubt be disappointed to an extreme extent if you watch this movie. In fact, do yourself a favor, and if you do decide to watch this garbage, watch the first two hours of it and then turn it off and come to your own logical conclusion of what happened. I find it more comforting to think that Mr. Toomey or the equally irritating Dianne girl and/or boy were controlling the plane and preventing the passengers from making it to their proper dimension the entire time. Langoliers is often times given a second glance because of it's so called "original plot" (albeit the many loopholes) and suspense. The terrible effects are also often excused due to the fact that this was a "made for TV" movie. Bull. I've seen movies made in the 20s with better effects. Do not be deceived. There is nothing original about this plot. I point anyone who is interested to Twilight Zone episode "The Odyssey of Flight 33". The only difference between the two is a more coherent and concise plot from Rod Sterling, minus the ridiculous "character development" of otherwise ridiculous characters and Chomp Chomp Pac-men monsters that take three hours to make their grand debut. Suspense is the highest point of this movie as well as it's down fall. For several hours we do not see these "Langoliers" we can only "hear" them (and by "hear" them, I mean the snap, crackle, pop noise one would hear from pouring milk over Rice Krispie cereal) as well as the suspense of knowing that they could jump out at any moment. As a viewer when 95% of a film is suspense without even a view of the alleged monster, one would expect an even bigger climax. .......so what are the Langoliers? Who knows. We are never told exactly "what" they are or the relevancy these creatures have on the story. The Langoliers could be absent from this movie, and it would still make sense, scratch that, the movie would make MORE sense if the Langoliers were not included. Are the Langoliers fabricated from Mr. Toomey's mind and simply "boogeymen" from his childhood past? Who knows. Are they simply the eaters of time and space? Who knows. Are they a mixed breed of Tazmanian Devil and Pac Men? Seems likely.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Like A 3 hour long episode of "The Twilight Zone"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stubbers
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am currently reading "Four Past Midnight", the book of four Stephen King novellas which opens with "The Langoliers". I have just finished reading this story and immediately checked out the movie version. I wasn't disappointed. Something about this story, like many of King's, really touches a nerve. The quality is mainly in the basic concept rather than the sometimes-clunky dialogue. I like the idea of the past still existing physically, until it eventually becomes swallowed up by the Langoliers, the so-called Housekeepers of Eternity who hoover up the past to make way for the present. Incidentally, while reading the book I assumed the emphasis in the word was on the "o" - langOliers, to rhyme with magnolias. But no, the emphasis is on the "i" - langol-Iers, to rhyme with chandeliers. Either way, it's a strange word used to describe a very strange (but somehow not totally unfeasible) type of creature. Like all good "Twilight Zone" episodes, which this reminds me of, such a great underlying premise leaves a really strong, unnerving impression. As such, it doesn't matter so much that the acting and special effects aren't amazing. The atmosphere and plot are totally faithful to the original book. In a way, the slightly wooden, stilted acting suits the wooden, stilted world in which the characters find themselves. An airless, stuffy, oppressive world where you can barely light a match, where the wind either doesn't blow (according to the book), or else blows on the ground level but doesn't move the clouds (according to the movie, because they couldn't stop the wind blowing on location!). A world lying in the dumpster, slowly atrophying, thrown on the scrapheap by the constant forward motion of time's winged chariot. Always good to see Dean Stockwell, a man who is no stranger to travelling through time! Not his greatest ever performance here, but he certainly brings enigma to the part of writer Bob Jenkins. Bronson Pinchot brought just the right amount of creepy-but-sympathetic insanity to Craig Toomey, the dictionary definition of a loser in life, and a stark warning to what can happen to children later in life if they are belittled by their over-demanding parents. By comparison, David Morse as Captain Brian Engel was low-key and understated, but that was the exact impression I got of him from the book. If you were flying in an airplane through a rip in the space-time continuum, you would certainly want your pilot to be calm and unflappable! Unlike some posters here, I actually thought Mark Lindsay Chapman's Anglo-American accent was spot on. And I say this as a Brit who has spent considerable time in America. Out of necessity for being understood clearly and not sounding too "plum in mouth", Brits in the States have to slip in a few American sounding inflections here and there. So kudos to Chapman for a great, convincing performance as Americanised British secret agent Nick Popewell. I'd go so far as to say that his English accent was better than Harry Shearer's immortal Derek Smalls character (Spinal Tap). As for the ladies - well thumbs up for both Patricia Wettig and Kimber Riddle for certainly being very watchable, if not the most three-dimensional performances I have ever seen. And unlike many people here, I had no issues with Kate Maberly as blind Dinah. Finally, the effects of the Langoliers themselves. No problem! Once again, my image of them from reading the book was as funny sort of bouncing balls with teeth, which is more or less how they turned out on screen. These are not hi-tech computer generated monsters full of whizzbang explosions, they are like parasitic insects that feed off the scraps of the past. I don't see how they could have been better represented to be honest. So what we have here is a TV movie that transcends the limitations of its slightly second-rate format, by dint of the strength of the basic source material and the fact that they adhered to all the elements of the book. If it ain't broke, don't fix it. I'm sorry that not everyone enjoyed the movie, and I appreciate the negative comments it has received from some. For me it boils down to the concept of the Langoliers being something that really intrigued me, in a scary way, and I can't get enough of reading about them or watching them. For that reason, the movie gave me exactly what I was looking for.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Faithful Adaptation
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ramin99
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I watched about half of this abomination then fittingly enough dropped like a sack of potatoes after drinking god knows how many beers; I mean is it possible to watch such rubbish with all of your intellectual faculties intact? The bad acting, especially by the blind girl, the young guy and the hot girl (she was pleasing to the eyes so I guess that makes her bad acting excusable), and deciding whether or not she wore bras was about all I can remember from the film now. I am befuddled to read, by a good number of reviewers, the following paradox: "the book is good but this particular adaptation is bad. I am a huge fan of that writer but this film sucks!" A movie follows a script thus the source material of a film, is, its script. If the script is good then there is a fat chance the movie turns out good; but if bad no one can turn it into a masterpiece. Do you see my point? Please get your heads out of your ***** and see things for what they are! A few hours later I woke up dizzy with accompanying headache and a bad taste in my mouth, then sat down to write this review, so I'm grumpier/crankier than usual.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An intriguing King mystery hampered down in TV land
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    DAVID SIM
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Stephen King is the world's most prolific horror novelist. His success lies in his writing, and in the sheer volume of films and TV movies adapting his work. The Langoliers is one of several King mini-series we've seen in recent years. Adapted from a short story in King's novella Four Past Midnight, it represents one of King's occasional detours from horror and into science-fiction. The premise is something that could easily fill an episode of The Twilight Zone (in fact the plot reminded me more of The Lost Hour, an episode from TV's Eerie Indiana). Ten airline passengers fall asleep on a red-eye flight to Boston. During the flight, the plane flew through a time-rip and when it came out the other side, it catapulted the plane back in time by a day. The sleeping passengers were the only ones to emerge unharmed. All the ones that were awake just vanished into the ether. When they land the plane, the people on the ground have disappeared as well. Its a dead, lifeless world with no electricity and vigour, and what's worse is the Langoliers, monsters from one of the passenger's childhood stories are coming to gobble them up. I always felt The Langoliers was one that straddled an uneasy line between science-fiction and horror. When most authors try to tackle different genres at the same time they often wind up shortchanging one at the expense of the other, or even worse is that they cancel each other out. One suspects the way King wrote the story, it was originally a time-travel piece, but when it got to the airport scenes, he decided to include the Langoliers to give it a bit more dramatic intensity. Without it, he would have been left with a not too terribly gripping storyline. Fill the airplane with fuel. Backtrack to the time-rip. Fly through it. They get home. The Langoliers was directed by genre regular Tom Holland. Holland emerged in the 80s with two above average horror movies, Fright Night and Child's Play. But then into the 90s, he seemed to disappear into TV land, and vanished after that, much like one of the passengers on Flight 29. Fright Night and Child's Play showed Holland with a fine grasp of horror mechanics. But whether its because they were feature films or its just the slimness of King's material, his work on The Langoliers disappoints. Certainly it begins well. Once the passengers vanish from the plane, it makes for a highly absorbing mystery. But eventually, the story begins to drag. And its not exactly helped by the TV production values Holland is forced to work with. The Langoliers are given such an inscrutable buildup (in a nice touch we hear they're approach even when they're still miles away) that when they finally arrive, we're almost breathless with anticipation. But as soon as you see them, you're howling with laughter. They look like giant meatballs with teeth, and the TV special effects play out the scene embarrassingly. Where The Langoliers is more successful is in some of the characterisations. Dean Stockwell, David Morse and Mark Lindsay Chapman all give capable performances. Especially Chapman, an actor better known for playing smarmy snake in the grasses, but gives surprising sympathy to the part of a special operator with a chequered past. His wry, guarded performance makes his character Nick Hopewell into the most well developed member of the cast. Kate Maberly has some creepy moments as the blind girl who sees more than the people around her. But even creepier is Bronson Pinchot, giving a highly live-wire performance as Craig Toomey, the psycho in they're midst who knows all about Langoliers from the horror stories his father delighted in telling him as a child. With the rest of the story stifled by TV movie surroundings, he brings a welcome surge of energy whenever he's in it. The other survivors could have been written out altogether to no noticeable effect. It does get itself together for an effective, slightly tragic finale, but The Langoliers lacks the childhood terrors of IT, or the assured storytelling of The Shining. King has given Tom Holland a slim story to work with, so amongst the TV versions of his work, The Langoliers ranks as one of the more anonymous.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A mixed blessing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Neil Welch
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Stephen King's enjoyable novella about a planeload of passengers who, thanks to a very odd storm and a warp in space/time, find themselves stranded in an unpopulated and rapidly decaying version of their own world (because time has moved on into the future) is turned into a possibly over-long three-part TV miniseries. There is much to like here. The adaptation is moderately faithful, the casting and performances are good (Bronson Pinchot is a bit over the top, but that is a requirement of the character), and there are some nice production touches - the gradual de-saturisation of the colour works well to demonstrate what is happening. Not so good are the Langoliers themselves. They had to be a special effect, but they could have usefully consumed a bigger chunk of budget: they should be terrifying because of what they do but, unfortunately, they come across as rather comical. And, as I said, the thing is too long. Three hours is taken to tell a story which could have been told in half that time, and you'd have been on the edge of your seat all the way through.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Different Take On Time Travel.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Based on a Stephen King novel, this TV movie adaptation is about the passengers on a red-eye airplane flight from L.A to Boston who awaken to find that the rest of the passengers and crew are gone, and they are all alone on the plane, which will soon run out of fuel. Fortunately, there is a pilot on board, who tries to land the plane at a nearby airport, only to discover that it is also empty, and that they are being pursued by giant, howling monsters called Langoliers that seem to be devouring time itself... Potentially interesting take on time travel, with an appealing cast of characters(except Bronson Pinchot, quite good playing an obnoxious and terrified child-like man who knows all about the Langoliers from his hideous father.) cannot save far-fetched premise, and the primitive CGI Langoliers have not aged well... Still, not the worst way to kill three hours!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Spectacular Story!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    djk-930-38279
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love this movie so much! All of the sci-fi and mystery of it is exactly what I love in books and movies. In this feature, I first saw it on TV and then I read the book. The book is very good as well, but it gives out much more information, describes things in more detail, which in some ways is good, but for me, when it comes to the gore with Mr. Toomey, I would rather not know so much. So in that case, watching the movie is much more preferred than reading it in the book. I gave this movie a 9 because I love it so much, but I just have one problem with it. There was some especially terrible acting, mostly by Christopher Collet who played Albert Kaussner. In many instances, he would overact his lines, and/or his lines were just written very poorly for him. I think for the most part though, the other main characters did pretty well. Not the best acting, but it was good.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Most interesting TV adaptation of S. King's work
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sang Park
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I just didn't give higher vote just because of the low budget and the poor F/X alloted to this movie. I have full understanding that this is low budget TV movie. But I could resist watching it because I had such high expectation in David Morse and Dean Stockwell. Enough with background of my watching movie.. First I didn't realize that this movie is 3 hours long... Maybe when they aired on TV they could have broken into series, but I've watched this on Netflix as one piece and it is longer movie than the lord of the rings. But as others put it, the length was due to the faithful adaptation of the original novel. No jumps or gaps in plots. Whenever there requires some explanation, Dean Stockwell slides in exuberantly and fulfills duties (he is supposed to be the avatar of S. King in the movie). I too have some pet peeve on the crappy F/X (really cheesy C.G.), but the reaction of actors actress are good enough to convince me that the monsters are there creeping in. All the settings and actings are good enough to make me get the creeps from what is going on in the movie. (FYI, I am a seasoned pseudo-professional monster/scary movie tester). When compared with "Stand", I think this is descent TV movie and I enjoyed pretty much.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    bad acting...bad FX....but still an excellent TV movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    supreme_mamu
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Some people says that acting and FX are the main purpose in creating a good movie, but here, it was proved wrong. I have to admit that this movie are full of characters with bad acting, i mean all of them (except for Bronson Pinchot who gave an excellent performance as mad guy Mr Craig Toomey). But the worst goes to the little girl, the blind little girl who does not have any emotional feelings and not really up to the standard to what audience always wanted. And the FX is quite poor and cheesy, seems to be cartoons. It really looks funny to me! I wish it could be better in order to turn this into a great movie. But, none of these really affect the greatness of The Langoliers. The main purpose of why this movie is created is because of the storyline, the story written by the master of horror, Stephen King. And, the story are almost exactly accurate to the short story in 4 Past Midnight. The way the story tell us is very entertaining, until I didn't really focus myself on the acting and the FX. It is the story which keep me thinking and wait for what is going to happen at the end of the story. Even though the movie is 3 hours long, but it doesn't make me feel boring because the suspend is there. I'm gonna watch this movie again for the 10th times this afternoon :) forget about the acting and the FX, concentrate on the storyline! excellent (10/10 stars)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Amazingly bad
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    CinefanR
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Everything is this movie is painfully bad- acting, story-line, script, special effects. It's true that my expectations were high. I've heard a lot about Stephen King and I imagined that such a celebrated writer would come up with something brilliant and original. I was expecting to see a spark of genius from the so-called "master of horror". Boy, was I wrong... The first 10 minutes or so make a promising start and I thought the premise was intriguing. After that, it falls flat on all levels. Pretentious, uninteresting one-dimensional characters check. Terribly written dialogue check. Ridiculous special effects check. The acting is atrocious, check that too. The sense of mystery is basically zero, probably because the viewer can't ignore the fact that everything takes place in a cheap TV set. And the worst part is that it goes on and on, and on for 3 hours. The only reason I kept watching was to see if maybe a good conclusion or some clever twist in the story line would save it somehow, but no. This movie is nothing more than the usual sci-fi clich&eacute;s piled up to the very end, while the production standards are beyond embarrassing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    ..and then...and then..and then...NOTHING!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Carol Mckinley
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    THIS REVIEW CONTAINS (MILD) SPOILERS! This is hands down the worst movie I have ever seen in my life. I've read through the first few pages of reviews left on this movie and to see glowing reviews over this steaming pile of crap is laughable. Really...did we watch the same movie? Imagine getting on a roller coaster. The longest, scariest, and highest roller coaster in the entire theme park. You buy the ticket, wait in line, and board the roller coaster. You get on the ride and go through dark tunnels, loops, and curves.....for hours. Although the ride is tiring, and the wait was long, you are still caught up in the anticipation. After all, the suspense is killing you, and with all this prolonged anticipation, surely this is going to be a hell of a ride, right? Now imagine getting to the peak of the roller coaster. Finally, you are at the highest point. You're ready. You waited so long. Now all of your waiting is going to finally pay off. You look down and see the fall...now you are excited. You prepare yourself for the adrenaline rush and excitement of finally getting to the best part..and then...........you are immediately let off the ride. That is the best way to describe this movie. It is probably the most disappointing thriller film that one could possibly waste hours out of their day watching. I HIGHLY warn that people understand that you WILL with out a doubt be disappointed to an extreme extent if you watch this movie. In fact, do yourself a favor, and if you do decide to watch this garbage, watch the first two hours of it and then turn it off and come to your own logical conclusion of what happened. I find it more comforting to think that Mr. Toomey or the equally irritating Dianne girl and/or boy were controlling the plane and preventing the passengers from making it to their proper dimension the entire time. Langoliers is often times given a second glance because of it's so called "original plot" (albeit the many loopholes) and suspense. The terrible effects are also often excused due to the fact that this was a "made for TV" movie. Bull. I've seen movies made in the 20s with better effects. Do not be deceived. There is nothing original about this plot. I point anyone who is interested to Twilight Zone episode "The Odyssey of Flight 33". The only difference between the two is a more coherent and concise plot from Rod Sterling, minus the ridiculous "character development" of otherwise ridiculous characters and Chomp Chomp Pac-men monsters that take three hours to make their grand debut. Suspense is the highest point of this movie as well as it's down fall. For several hours we do not see these "Langoliers" we can only "hear" them (and by "hear" them, I mean the snap, crackle, pop noise one would hear from pouring milk over Rice Krispie cereal) as well as the suspense of knowing that they could jump out at any moment. As a viewer when 95% of a film is suspense without even a view of the alleged monster, one would expect an even bigger climax. .......so what are the Langoliers? Who knows. We are never told exactly "what" they are or the relevancy these creatures have on the story. The Langoliers could be absent from this movie, and it would still make sense, scratch that, the movie would make MORE sense if the Langoliers were not included. Are the Langoliers fabricated from Mr. Toomey's mind and simply "boogeymen" from his childhood past? Who knows. Are they simply the eaters of time and space? Who knows. Are they a mixed breed of Tazmanian Devil and Pac Men? Seems likely.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Like A 3 hour long episode of "The Twilight Zone"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stubbers
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am currently reading "Four Past Midnight", the book of four Stephen King novellas which opens with "The Langoliers". I have just finished reading this story and immediately checked out the movie version. I wasn't disappointed. Something about this story, like many of King's, really touches a nerve. The quality is mainly in the basic concept rather than the sometimes-clunky dialogue. I like the idea of the past still existing physically, until it eventually becomes swallowed up by the Langoliers, the so-called Housekeepers of Eternity who hoover up the past to make way for the present. Incidentally, while reading the book I assumed the emphasis in the word was on the "o" - langOliers, to rhyme with magnolias. But no, the emphasis is on the "i" - langol-Iers, to rhyme with chandeliers. Either way, it's a strange word used to describe a very strange (but somehow not totally unfeasible) type of creature. Like all good "Twilight Zone" episodes, which this reminds me of, such a great underlying premise leaves a really strong, unnerving impression. As such, it doesn't matter so much that the acting and special effects aren't amazing. The atmosphere and plot are totally faithful to the original book. In a way, the slightly wooden, stilted acting suits the wooden, stilted world in which the characters find themselves. An airless, stuffy, oppressive world where you can barely light a match, where the wind either doesn't blow (according to the book), or else blows on the ground level but doesn't move the clouds (according to the movie, because they couldn't stop the wind blowing on location!). A world lying in the dumpster, slowly atrophying, thrown on the scrapheap by the constant forward motion of time's winged chariot. Always good to see Dean Stockwell, a man who is no stranger to travelling through time! Not his greatest ever performance here, but he certainly brings enigma to the part of writer Bob Jenkins. Bronson Pinchot brought just the right amount of creepy-but-sympathetic insanity to Craig Toomey, the dictionary definition of a loser in life, and a stark warning to what can happen to children later in life if they are belittled by their over-demanding parents. By comparison, David Morse as Captain Brian Engel was low-key and understated, but that was the exact impression I got of him from the book. If you were flying in an airplane through a rip in the space-time continuum, you would certainly want your pilot to be calm and unflappable! Unlike some posters here, I actually thought Mark Lindsay Chapman's Anglo-American accent was spot on. And I say this as a Brit who has spent considerable time in America. Out of necessity for being understood clearly and not sounding too "plum in mouth", Brits in the States have to slip in a few American sounding inflections here and there. So kudos to Chapman for a great, convincing performance as Americanised British secret agent Nick Popewell. I'd go so far as to say that his English accent was better than Harry Shearer's immortal Derek Smalls character (Spinal Tap). As for the ladies - well thumbs up for both Patricia Wettig and Kimber Riddle for certainly being very watchable, if not the most three-dimensional performances I have ever seen. And unlike many people here, I had no issues with Kate Maberly as blind Dinah. Finally, the effects of the Langoliers themselves. No problem! Once again, my image of them from reading the book was as funny sort of bouncing balls with teeth, which is more or less how they turned out on screen. These are not hi-tech computer generated monsters full of whizzbang explosions, they are like parasitic insects that feed off the scraps of the past. I don't see how they could have been better represented to be honest. So what we have here is a TV movie that transcends the limitations of its slightly second-rate format, by dint of the strength of the basic source material and the fact that they adhered to all the elements of the book. If it ain't broke, don't fix it. I'm sorry that not everyone enjoyed the movie, and I appreciate the negative comments it has received from some. For me it boils down to the concept of the Langoliers being something that really intrigued me, in a scary way, and I can't get enough of reading about them or watching them. For that reason, the movie gave me exactly what I was looking for.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Faithful Adaptation
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ramin99
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I watched about half of this abomination then fittingly enough dropped like a sack of potatoes after drinking god knows how many beers; I mean is it possible to watch such rubbish with all of your intellectual faculties intact? The bad acting, especially by the blind girl, the young guy and the hot girl (she was pleasing to the eyes so I guess that makes her bad acting excusable), and deciding whether or not she wore bras was about all I can remember from the film now. I am befuddled to read, by a good number of reviewers, the following paradox: "the book is good but this particular adaptation is bad. I am a huge fan of that writer but this film sucks!" A movie follows a script thus the source material of a film, is, its script. If the script is good then there is a fat chance the movie turns out good; but if bad no one can turn it into a masterpiece. Do you see my point? Please get your heads out of your ***** and see things for what they are! A few hours later I woke up dizzy with accompanying headache and a bad taste in my mouth, then sat down to write this review, so I'm grumpier/crankier than usual.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An intriguing King mystery hampered down in TV land
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    DAVID SIM
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Stephen King is the world's most prolific horror novelist. His success lies in his writing, and in the sheer volume of films and TV movies adapting his work. The Langoliers is one of several King mini-series we've seen in recent years. Adapted from a short story in King's novella Four Past Midnight, it represents one of King's occasional detours from horror and into science-fiction. The premise is something that could easily fill an episode of The Twilight Zone (in fact the plot reminded me more of The Lost Hour, an episode from TV's Eerie Indiana). Ten airline passengers fall asleep on a red-eye flight to Boston. During the flight, the plane flew through a time-rip and when it came out the other side, it catapulted the plane back in time by a day. The sleeping passengers were the only ones to emerge unharmed. All the ones that were awake just vanished into the ether. When they land the plane, the people on the ground have disappeared as well. Its a dead, lifeless world with no electricity and vigour, and what's worse is the Langoliers, monsters from one of the passenger's childhood stories are coming to gobble them up. I always felt The Langoliers was one that straddled an uneasy line between science-fiction and horror. When most authors try to tackle different genres at the same time they often wind up shortchanging one at the expense of the other, or even worse is that they cancel each other out. One suspects the way King wrote the story, it was originally a time-travel piece, but when it got to the airport scenes, he decided to include the Langoliers to give it a bit more dramatic intensity. Without it, he would have been left with a not too terribly gripping storyline. Fill the airplane with fuel. Backtrack to the time-rip. Fly through it. They get home. The Langoliers was directed by genre regular Tom Holland. Holland emerged in the 80s with two above average horror movies, Fright Night and Child's Play. But then into the 90s, he seemed to disappear into TV land, and vanished after that, much like one of the passengers on Flight 29. Fright Night and Child's Play showed Holland with a fine grasp of horror mechanics. But whether its because they were feature films or its just the slimness of King's material, his work on The Langoliers disappoints. Certainly it begins well. Once the passengers vanish from the plane, it makes for a highly absorbing mystery. But eventually, the story begins to drag. And its not exactly helped by the TV production values Holland is forced to work with. The Langoliers are given such an inscrutable buildup (in a nice touch we hear they're approach even when they're still miles away) that when they finally arrive, we're almost breathless with anticipation. But as soon as you see them, you're howling with laughter. They look like giant meatballs with teeth, and the TV special effects play out the scene embarrassingly. Where The Langoliers is more successful is in some of the characterisations. Dean Stockwell, David Morse and Mark Lindsay Chapman all give capable performances. Especially Chapman, an actor better known for playing smarmy snake in the grasses, but gives surprising sympathy to the part of a special operator with a chequered past. His wry, guarded performance makes his character Nick Hopewell into the most well developed member of the cast. Kate Maberly has some creepy moments as the blind girl who sees more than the people around her. But even creepier is Bronson Pinchot, giving a highly live-wire performance as Craig Toomey, the psycho in they're midst who knows all about Langoliers from the horror stories his father delighted in telling him as a child. With the rest of the story stifled by TV movie surroundings, he brings a welcome surge of energy whenever he's in it. The other survivors could have been written out altogether to no noticeable effect. It does get itself together for an effective, slightly tragic finale, but The Langoliers lacks the childhood terrors of IT, or the assured storytelling of The Shining. King has given Tom Holland a slim story to work with, so amongst the TV versions of his work, The Langoliers ranks as one of the more anonymous.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A mixed blessing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Neil Welch
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Stephen King's enjoyable novella about a planeload of passengers who, thanks to a very odd storm and a warp in space/time, find themselves stranded in an unpopulated and rapidly decaying version of their own world (because time has moved on into the future) is turned into a possibly over-long three-part TV miniseries. There is much to like here. The adaptation is moderately faithful, the casting and performances are good (Bronson Pinchot is a bit over the top, but that is a requirement of the character), and there are some nice production touches - the gradual de-saturisation of the colour works well to demonstrate what is happening. Not so good are the Langoliers themselves. They had to be a special effect, but they could have usefully consumed a bigger chunk of budget: they should be terrifying because of what they do but, unfortunately, they come across as rather comical. And, as I said, the thing is too long. Three hours is taken to tell a story which could have been told in half that time, and you'd have been on the edge of your seat all the way through.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Different Take On Time Travel.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Based on a Stephen King novel, this TV movie adaptation is about the passengers on a red-eye airplane flight from L.A to Boston who awaken to find that the rest of the passengers and crew are gone, and they are all alone on the plane, which will soon run out of fuel. Fortunately, there is a pilot on board, who tries to land the plane at a nearby airport, only to discover that it is also empty, and that they are being pursued by giant, howling monsters called Langoliers that seem to be devouring time itself... Potentially interesting take on time travel, with an appealing cast of characters(except Bronson Pinchot, quite good playing an obnoxious and terrified child-like man who knows all about the Langoliers from his hideous father.) cannot save far-fetched premise, and the primitive CGI Langoliers have not aged well... Still, not the worst way to kill three hours!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Spectacular Story!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    djk-930-38279
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love this movie so much! All of the sci-fi and mystery of it is exactly what I love in books and movies. In this feature, I first saw it on TV and then I read the book. The book is very good as well, but it gives out much more information, describes things in more detail, which in some ways is good, but for me, when it comes to the gore with Mr. Toomey, I would rather not know so much. So in that case, watching the movie is much more preferred than reading it in the book. I gave this movie a 9 because I love it so much, but I just have one problem with it. There was some especially terrible acting, mostly by Christopher Collet who played Albert Kaussner. In many instances, he would overact his lines, and/or his lines were just written very poorly for him. I think for the most part though, the other main characters did pretty well. Not the best acting, but it was good.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Most interesting TV adaptation of S. King's work
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sang Park
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I just didn't give higher vote just because of the low budget and the poor F/X alloted to this movie. I have full understanding that this is low budget TV movie. But I could resist watching it because I had such high expectation in David Morse and Dean Stockwell. Enough with background of my watching movie.. First I didn't realize that this movie is 3 hours long... Maybe when they aired on TV they could have broken into series, but I've watched this on Netflix as one piece and it is longer movie than the lord of the rings. But as others put it, the length was due to the faithful adaptation of the original novel. No jumps or gaps in plots. Whenever there requires some explanation, Dean Stockwell slides in exuberantly and fulfills duties (he is supposed to be the avatar of S. King in the movie). I too have some pet peeve on the crappy F/X (really cheesy C.G.), but the reaction of actors actress are good enough to convince me that the monsters are there creeping in. All the settings and actings are good enough to make me get the creeps from what is going on in the movie. (FYI, I am a seasoned pseudo-professional monster/scary movie tester). When compared with "Stand", I think this is descent TV movie and I enjoyed pretty much.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    bad acting...bad FX....but still an excellent TV movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    supreme_mamu
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Some people says that acting and FX are the main purpose in creating a good movie, but here, it was proved wrong. I have to admit that this movie are full of characters with bad acting, i mean all of them (except for Bronson Pinchot who gave an excellent performance as mad guy Mr Craig Toomey). But the worst goes to the little girl, the blind little girl who does not have any emotional feelings and not really up to the standard to what audience always wanted. And the FX is quite poor and cheesy, seems to be cartoons. It really looks funny to me! I wish it could be better in order to turn this into a great movie. But, none of these really affect the greatness of The Langoliers. The main purpose of why this movie is created is because of the storyline, the story written by the master of horror, Stephen King. And, the story are almost exactly accurate to the short story in 4 Past Midnight. The way the story tell us is very entertaining, until I didn't really focus myself on the acting and the FX. It is the story which keep me thinking and wait for what is going to happen at the end of the story. Even though the movie is 3 hours long, but it doesn't make me feel boring because the suspend is there. I'm gonna watch this movie again for the 10th times this afternoon :) forget about the acting and the FX, concentrate on the storyline! excellent (10/10 stars)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Amazingly bad
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    CinefanR
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Everything is this movie is painfully bad- acting, story-line, script, special effects. It's true that my expectations were high. I've heard a lot about Stephen King and I imagined that such a celebrated writer would come up with something brilliant and original. I was expecting to see a spark of genius from the so-called "master of horror". Boy, was I wrong... The first 10 minutes or so make a promising start and I thought the premise was intriguing. After that, it falls flat on all levels. Pretentious, uninteresting one-dimensional characters check. Terribly written dialogue check. Ridiculous special effects check. The acting is atrocious, check that too. The sense of mystery is basically zero, probably because the viewer can't ignore the fact that everything takes place in a cheap TV set. And the worst part is that it goes on and on, and on for 3 hours. The only reason I kept watching was to see if maybe a good conclusion or some clever twist in the story line would save it somehow, but no. This movie is nothing more than the usual sci-fi clich&eacute;s piled up to the very end, while the production standards are beyond embarrassing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    ..and then...and then..and then...NOTHING!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Carol Mckinley
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    THIS REVIEW CONTAINS (MILD) SPOILERS! This is hands down the worst movie I have ever seen in my life. I've read through the first few pages of reviews left on this movie and to see glowing reviews over this steaming pile of crap is laughable. Really...did we watch the same movie? Imagine getting on a roller coaster. The longest, scariest, and highest roller coaster in the entire theme park. You buy the ticket, wait in line, and board the roller coaster. You get on the ride and go through dark tunnels, loops, and curves.....for hours. Although the ride is tiring, and the wait was long, you are still caught up in the anticipation. After all, the suspense is killing you, and with all this prolonged anticipation, surely this is going to be a hell of a ride, right? Now imagine getting to the peak of the roller coaster. Finally, you are at the highest point. You're ready. You waited so long. Now all of your waiting is going to finally pay off. You look down and see the fall...now you are excited. You prepare yourself for the adrenaline rush and excitement of finally getting to the best part..and then...........you are immediately let off the ride. That is the best way to describe this movie. It is probably the most disappointing thriller film that one could possibly waste hours out of their day watching. I HIGHLY warn that people understand that you WILL with out a doubt be disappointed to an extreme extent if you watch this movie. In fact, do yourself a favor, and if you do decide to watch this garbage, watch the first two hours of it and then turn it off and come to your own logical conclusion of what happened. I find it more comforting to think that Mr. Toomey or the equally irritating Dianne girl and/or boy were controlling the plane and preventing the passengers from making it to their proper dimension the entire time. Langoliers is often times given a second glance because of it's so called "original plot" (albeit the many loopholes) and suspense. The terrible effects are also often excused due to the fact that this was a "made for TV" movie. Bull. I've seen movies made in the 20s with better effects. Do not be deceived. There is nothing original about this plot. I point anyone who is interested to Twilight Zone episode "The Odyssey of Flight 33". The only difference between the two is a more coherent and concise plot from Rod Sterling, minus the ridiculous "character development" of otherwise ridiculous characters and Chomp Chomp Pac-men monsters that take three hours to make their grand debut. Suspense is the highest point of this movie as well as it's down fall. For several hours we do not see these "Langoliers" we can only "hear" them (and by "hear" them, I mean the snap, crackle, pop noise one would hear from pouring milk over Rice Krispie cereal) as well as the suspense of knowing that they could jump out at any moment. As a viewer when 95% of a film is suspense without even a view of the alleged monster, one would expect an even bigger climax. .......so what are the Langoliers? Who knows. We are never told exactly "what" they are or the relevancy these creatures have on the story. The Langoliers could be absent from this movie, and it would still make sense, scratch that, the movie would make MORE sense if the Langoliers were not included. Are the Langoliers fabricated from Mr. Toomey's mind and simply "boogeymen" from his childhood past? Who knows. Are they simply the eaters of time and space? Who knows. Are they a mixed breed of Tazmanian Devil and Pac Men? Seems likely.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Like A 3 hour long episode of "The Twilight Zone"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stubbers
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am currently reading "Four Past Midnight", the book of four Stephen King novellas which opens with "The Langoliers". I have just finished reading this story and immediately checked out the movie version. I wasn't disappointed. Something about this story, like many of King's, really touches a nerve. The quality is mainly in the basic concept rather than the sometimes-clunky dialogue. I like the idea of the past still existing physically, until it eventually becomes swallowed up by the Langoliers, the so-called Housekeepers of Eternity who hoover up the past to make way for the present. Incidentally, while reading the book I assumed the emphasis in the word was on the "o" - langOliers, to rhyme with magnolias. But no, the emphasis is on the "i" - langol-Iers, to rhyme with chandeliers. Either way, it's a strange word used to describe a very strange (but somehow not totally unfeasible) type of creature. Like all good "Twilight Zone" episodes, which this reminds me of, such a great underlying premise leaves a really strong, unnerving impression. As such, it doesn't matter so much that the acting and special effects aren't amazing. The atmosphere and plot are totally faithful to the original book. In a way, the slightly wooden, stilted acting suits the wooden, stilted world in which the characters find themselves. An airless, stuffy, oppressive world where you can barely light a match, where the wind either doesn't blow (according to the book), or else blows on the ground level but doesn't move the clouds (according to the movie, because they couldn't stop the wind blowing on location!). A world lying in the dumpster, slowly atrophying, thrown on the scrapheap by the constant forward motion of time's winged chariot. Always good to see Dean Stockwell, a man who is no stranger to travelling through time! Not his greatest ever performance here, but he certainly brings enigma to the part of writer Bob Jenkins. Bronson Pinchot brought just the right amount of creepy-but-sympathetic insanity to Craig Toomey, the dictionary definition of a loser in life, and a stark warning to what can happen to children later in life if they are belittled by their over-demanding parents. By comparison, David Morse as Captain Brian Engel was low-key and understated, but that was the exact impression I got of him from the book. If you were flying in an airplane through a rip in the space-time continuum, you would certainly want your pilot to be calm and unflappable! Unlike some posters here, I actually thought Mark Lindsay Chapman's Anglo-American accent was spot on. And I say this as a Brit who has spent considerable time in America. Out of necessity for being understood clearly and not sounding too "plum in mouth", Brits in the States have to slip in a few American sounding inflections here and there. So kudos to Chapman for a great, convincing performance as Americanised British secret agent Nick Popewell. I'd go so far as to say that his English accent was better than Harry Shearer's immortal Derek Smalls character (Spinal Tap). As for the ladies - well thumbs up for both Patricia Wettig and Kimber Riddle for certainly being very watchable, if not the most three-dimensional performances I have ever seen. And unlike many people here, I had no issues with Kate Maberly as blind Dinah. Finally, the effects of the Langoliers themselves. No problem! Once again, my image of them from reading the book was as funny sort of bouncing balls with teeth, which is more or less how they turned out on screen. These are not hi-tech computer generated monsters full of whizzbang explosions, they are like parasitic insects that feed off the scraps of the past. I don't see how they could have been better represented to be honest. So what we have here is a TV movie that transcends the limitations of its slightly second-rate format, by dint of the strength of the basic source material and the fact that they adhered to all the elements of the book. If it ain't broke, don't fix it. I'm sorry that not everyone enjoyed the movie, and I appreciate the negative comments it has received from some. For me it boils down to the concept of the Langoliers being something that really intrigued me, in a scary way, and I can't get enough of reading about them or watching them. For that reason, the movie gave me exactly what I was looking for.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Faithful Adaptation
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ramin99
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I watched about half of this abomination then fittingly enough dropped like a sack of potatoes after drinking god knows how many beers; I mean is it possible to watch such rubbish with all of your intellectual faculties intact? The bad acting, especially by the blind girl, the young guy and the hot girl (she was pleasing to the eyes so I guess that makes her bad acting excusable), and deciding whether or not she wore bras was about all I can remember from the film now. I am befuddled to read, by a good number of reviewers, the following paradox: "the book is good but this particular adaptation is bad. I am a huge fan of that writer but this film sucks!" A movie follows a script thus the source material of a film, is, its script. If the script is good then there is a fat chance the movie turns out good; but if bad no one can turn it into a masterpiece. Do you see my point? Please get your heads out of your ***** and see things for what they are! A few hours later I woke up dizzy with accompanying headache and a bad taste in my mouth, then sat down to write this review, so I'm grumpier/crankier than usual.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An intriguing King mystery hampered down in TV land
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    DAVID SIM
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Stephen King is the world's most prolific horror novelist. His success lies in his writing, and in the sheer volume of films and TV movies adapting his work. The Langoliers is one of several King mini-series we've seen in recent years. Adapted from a short story in King's novella Four Past Midnight, it represents one of King's occasional detours from horror and into science-fiction. The premise is something that could easily fill an episode of The Twilight Zone (in fact the plot reminded me more of The Lost Hour, an episode from TV's Eerie Indiana). Ten airline passengers fall asleep on a red-eye flight to Boston. During the flight, the plane flew through a time-rip and when it came out the other side, it catapulted the plane back in time by a day. The sleeping passengers were the only ones to emerge unharmed. All the ones that were awake just vanished into the ether. When they land the plane, the people on the ground have disappeared as well. Its a dead, lifeless world with no electricity and vigour, and what's worse is the Langoliers, monsters from one of the passenger's childhood stories are coming to gobble them up. I always felt The Langoliers was one that straddled an uneasy line between science-fiction and horror. When most authors try to tackle different genres at the same time they often wind up shortchanging one at the expense of the other, or even worse is that they cancel each other out. One suspects the way King wrote the story, it was originally a time-travel piece, but when it got to the airport scenes, he decided to include the Langoliers to give it a bit more dramatic intensity. Without it, he would have been left with a not too terribly gripping storyline. Fill the airplane with fuel. Backtrack to the time-rip. Fly through it. They get home. The Langoliers was directed by genre regular Tom Holland. Holland emerged in the 80s with two above average horror movies, Fright Night and Child's Play. But then into the 90s, he seemed to disappear into TV land, and vanished after that, much like one of the passengers on Flight 29. Fright Night and Child's Play showed Holland with a fine grasp of horror mechanics. But whether its because they were feature films or its just the slimness of King's material, his work on The Langoliers disappoints. Certainly it begins well. Once the passengers vanish from the plane, it makes for a highly absorbing mystery. But eventually, the story begins to drag. And its not exactly helped by the TV production values Holland is forced to work with. The Langoliers are given such an inscrutable buildup (in a nice touch we hear they're approach even when they're still miles away) that when they finally arrive, we're almost breathless with anticipation. But as soon as you see them, you're howling with laughter. They look like giant meatballs with teeth, and the TV special effects play out the scene embarrassingly. Where The Langoliers is more successful is in some of the characterisations. Dean Stockwell, David Morse and Mark Lindsay Chapman all give capable performances. Especially Chapman, an actor better known for playing smarmy snake in the grasses, but gives surprising sympathy to the part of a special operator with a chequered past. His wry, guarded performance makes his character Nick Hopewell into the most well developed member of the cast. Kate Maberly has some creepy moments as the blind girl who sees more than the people around her. But even creepier is Bronson Pinchot, giving a highly live-wire performance as Craig Toomey, the psycho in they're midst who knows all about Langoliers from the horror stories his father delighted in telling him as a child. With the rest of the story stifled by TV movie surroundings, he brings a welcome surge of energy whenever he's in it. The other survivors could have been written out altogether to no noticeable effect. It does get itself together for an effective, slightly tragic finale, but The Langoliers lacks the childhood terrors of IT, or the assured storytelling of The Shining. King has given Tom Holland a slim story to work with, so amongst the TV versions of his work, The Langoliers ranks as one of the more anonymous.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A mixed blessing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Neil Welch
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Stephen King's enjoyable novella about a planeload of passengers who, thanks to a very odd storm and a warp in space/time, find themselves stranded in an unpopulated and rapidly decaying version of their own world (because time has moved on into the future) is turned into a possibly over-long three-part TV miniseries. There is much to like here. The adaptation is moderately faithful, the casting and performances are good (Bronson Pinchot is a bit over the top, but that is a requirement of the character), and there are some nice production touches - the gradual de-saturisation of the colour works well to demonstrate what is happening. Not so good are the Langoliers themselves. They had to be a special effect, but they could have usefully consumed a bigger chunk of budget: they should be terrifying because of what they do but, unfortunately, they come across as rather comical. And, as I said, the thing is too long. Three hours is taken to tell a story which could have been told in half that time, and you'd have been on the edge of your seat all the way through.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Different Take On Time Travel.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Based on a Stephen King novel, this TV movie adaptation is about the passengers on a red-eye airplane flight from L.A to Boston who awaken to find that the rest of the passengers and crew are gone, and they are all alone on the plane, which will soon run out of fuel. Fortunately, there is a pilot on board, who tries to land the plane at a nearby airport, only to discover that it is also empty, and that they are being pursued by giant, howling monsters called Langoliers that seem to be devouring time itself... Potentially interesting take on time travel, with an appealing cast of characters(except Bronson Pinchot, quite good playing an obnoxious and terrified child-like man who knows all about the Langoliers from his hideous father.) cannot save far-fetched premise, and the primitive CGI Langoliers have not aged well... Still, not the worst way to kill three hours!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Spectacular Story!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    djk-930-38279
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love this movie so much! All of the sci-fi and mystery of it is exactly what I love in books and movies. In this feature, I first saw it on TV and then I read the book. The book is very good as well, but it gives out much more information, describes things in more detail, which in some ways is good, but for me, when it comes to the gore with Mr. Toomey, I would rather not know so much. So in that case, watching the movie is much more preferred than reading it in the book. I gave this movie a 9 because I love it so much, but I just have one problem with it. There was some especially terrible acting, mostly by Christopher Collet who played Albert Kaussner. In many instances, he would overact his lines, and/or his lines were just written very poorly for him. I think for the most part though, the other main characters did pretty well. Not the best acting, but it was good.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Most interesting TV adaptation of S. King's work
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sang Park
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I just didn't give higher vote just because of the low budget and the poor F/X alloted to this movie. I have full understanding that this is low budget TV movie. But I could resist watching it because I had such high expectation in David Morse and Dean Stockwell. Enough with background of my watching movie.. First I didn't realize that this movie is 3 hours long... Maybe when they aired on TV they could have broken into series, but I've watched this on Netflix as one piece and it is longer movie than the lord of the rings. But as others put it, the length was due to the faithful adaptation of the original novel. No jumps or gaps in plots. Whenever there requires some explanation, Dean Stockwell slides in exuberantly and fulfills duties (he is supposed to be the avatar of S. King in the movie). I too have some pet peeve on the crappy F/X (really cheesy C.G.), but the reaction of actors actress are good enough to convince me that the monsters are there creeping in. All the settings and actings are good enough to make me get the creeps from what is going on in the movie. (FYI, I am a seasoned pseudo-professional monster/scary movie tester). When compared with "Stand", I think this is descent TV movie and I enjoyed pretty much.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    bad acting...bad FX....but still an excellent TV movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    supreme_mamu
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Some people says that acting and FX are the main purpose in creating a good movie, but here, it was proved wrong. I have to admit that this movie are full of characters with bad acting, i mean all of them (except for Bronson Pinchot who gave an excellent performance as mad guy Mr Craig Toomey). But the worst goes to the little girl, the blind little girl who does not have any emotional feelings and not really up to the standard to what audience always wanted. And the FX is quite poor and cheesy, seems to be cartoons. It really looks funny to me! I wish it could be better in order to turn this into a great movie. But, none of these really affect the greatness of The Langoliers. The main purpose of why this movie is created is because of the storyline, the story written by the master of horror, Stephen King. And, the story are almost exactly accurate to the short story in 4 Past Midnight. The way the story tell us is very entertaining, until I didn't really focus myself on the acting and the FX. It is the story which keep me thinking and wait for what is going to happen at the end of the story. Even though the movie is 3 hours long, but it doesn't make me feel boring because the suspend is there. I'm gonna watch this movie again for the 10th times this afternoon :) forget about the acting and the FX, concentrate on the storyline! excellent (10/10 stars)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Amazingly bad
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    CinefanR
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Everything is this movie is painfully bad- acting, story-line, script, special effects. It's true that my expectations were high. I've heard a lot about Stephen King and I imagined that such a celebrated writer would come up with something brilliant and original. I was expecting to see a spark of genius from the so-called "master of horror". Boy, was I wrong... The first 10 minutes or so make a promising start and I thought the premise was intriguing. After that, it falls flat on all levels. Pretentious, uninteresting one-dimensional characters check. Terribly written dialogue check. Ridiculous special effects check. The acting is atrocious, check that too. The sense of mystery is basically zero, probably because the viewer can't ignore the fact that everything takes place in a cheap TV set. And the worst part is that it goes on and on, and on for 3 hours. The only reason I kept watching was to see if maybe a good conclusion or some clever twist in the story line would save it somehow, but no. This movie is nothing more than the usual sci-fi clich&eacute;s piled up to the very end, while the production standards are beyond embarrassing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    ..and then...and then..and then...NOTHING!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Carol Mckinley
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    THIS REVIEW CONTAINS (MILD) SPOILERS! This is hands down the worst movie I have ever seen in my life. I've read through the first few pages of reviews left on this movie and to see glowing reviews over this steaming pile of crap is laughable. Really...did we watch the same movie? Imagine getting on a roller coaster. The longest, scariest, and highest roller coaster in the entire theme park. You buy the ticket, wait in line, and board the roller coaster. You get on the ride and go through dark tunnels, loops, and curves.....for hours. Although the ride is tiring, and the wait was long, you are still caught up in the anticipation. After all, the suspense is killing you, and with all this prolonged anticipation, surely this is going to be a hell of a ride, right? Now imagine getting to the peak of the roller coaster. Finally, you are at the highest point. You're ready. You waited so long. Now all of your waiting is going to finally pay off. You look down and see the fall...now you are excited. You prepare yourself for the adrenaline rush and excitement of finally getting to the best part..and then...........you are immediately let off the ride. That is the best way to describe this movie. It is probably the most disappointing thriller film that one could possibly waste hours out of their day watching. I HIGHLY warn that people understand that you WILL with out a doubt be disappointed to an extreme extent if you watch this movie. In fact, do yourself a favor, and if you do decide to watch this garbage, watch the first two hours of it and then turn it off and come to your own logical conclusion of what happened. I find it more comforting to think that Mr. Toomey or the equally irritating Dianne girl and/or boy were controlling the plane and preventing the passengers from making it to their proper dimension the entire time. Langoliers is often times given a second glance because of it's so called "original plot" (albeit the many loopholes) and suspense. The terrible effects are also often excused due to the fact that this was a "made for TV" movie. Bull. I've seen movies made in the 20s with better effects. Do not be deceived. There is nothing original about this plot. I point anyone who is interested to Twilight Zone episode "The Odyssey of Flight 33". The only difference between the two is a more coherent and concise plot from Rod Sterling, minus the ridiculous "character development" of otherwise ridiculous characters and Chomp Chomp Pac-men monsters that take three hours to make their grand debut. Suspense is the highest point of this movie as well as it's down fall. For several hours we do not see these "Langoliers" we can only "hear" them (and by "hear" them, I mean the snap, crackle, pop noise one would hear from pouring milk over Rice Krispie cereal) as well as the suspense of knowing that they could jump out at any moment. As a viewer when 95% of a film is suspense without even a view of the alleged monster, one would expect an even bigger climax. .......so what are the Langoliers? Who knows. We are never told exactly "what" they are or the relevancy these creatures have on the story. The Langoliers could be absent from this movie, and it would still make sense, scratch that, the movie would make MORE sense if the Langoliers were not included. Are the Langoliers fabricated from Mr. Toomey's mind and simply "boogeymen" from his childhood past? Who knows. Are they simply the eaters of time and space? Who knows. Are they a mixed breed of Tazmanian Devil and Pac Men? Seems likely.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Like A 3 hour long episode of "The Twilight Zone"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stubbers
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am currently reading "Four Past Midnight", the book of four Stephen King novellas which opens with "The Langoliers". I have just finished reading this story and immediately checked out the movie version. I wasn't disappointed. Something about this story, like many of King's, really touches a nerve. The quality is mainly in the basic concept rather than the sometimes-clunky dialogue. I like the idea of the past still existing physically, until it eventually becomes swallowed up by the Langoliers, the so-called Housekeepers of Eternity who hoover up the past to make way for the present. Incidentally, while reading the book I assumed the emphasis in the word was on the "o" - langOliers, to rhyme with magnolias. But no, the emphasis is on the "i" - langol-Iers, to rhyme with chandeliers. Either way, it's a strange word used to describe a very strange (but somehow not totally unfeasible) type of creature. Like all good "Twilight Zone" episodes, which this reminds me of, such a great underlying premise leaves a really strong, unnerving impression. As such, it doesn't matter so much that the acting and special effects aren't amazing. The atmosphere and plot are totally faithful to the original book. In a way, the slightly wooden, stilted acting suits the wooden, stilted world in which the characters find themselves. An airless, stuffy, oppressive world where you can barely light a match, where the wind either doesn't blow (according to the book), or else blows on the ground level but doesn't move the clouds (according to the movie, because they couldn't stop the wind blowing on location!). A world lying in the dumpster, slowly atrophying, thrown on the scrapheap by the constant forward motion of time's winged chariot. Always good to see Dean Stockwell, a man who is no stranger to travelling through time! Not his greatest ever performance here, but he certainly brings enigma to the part of writer Bob Jenkins. Bronson Pinchot brought just the right amount of creepy-but-sympathetic insanity to Craig Toomey, the dictionary definition of a loser in life, and a stark warning to what can happen to children later in life if they are belittled by their over-demanding parents. By comparison, David Morse as Captain Brian Engel was low-key and understated, but that was the exact impression I got of him from the book. If you were flying in an airplane through a rip in the space-time continuum, you would certainly want your pilot to be calm and unflappable! Unlike some posters here, I actually thought Mark Lindsay Chapman's Anglo-American accent was spot on. And I say this as a Brit who has spent considerable time in America. Out of necessity for being understood clearly and not sounding too "plum in mouth", Brits in the States have to slip in a few American sounding inflections here and there. So kudos to Chapman for a great, convincing performance as Americanised British secret agent Nick Popewell. I'd go so far as to say that his English accent was better than Harry Shearer's immortal Derek Smalls character (Spinal Tap). As for the ladies - well thumbs up for both Patricia Wettig and Kimber Riddle for certainly being very watchable, if not the most three-dimensional performances I have ever seen. And unlike many people here, I had no issues with Kate Maberly as blind Dinah. Finally, the effects of the Langoliers themselves. No problem! Once again, my image of them from reading the book was as funny sort of bouncing balls with teeth, which is more or less how they turned out on screen. These are not hi-tech computer generated monsters full of whizzbang explosions, they are like parasitic insects that feed off the scraps of the past. I don't see how they could have been better represented to be honest. So what we have here is a TV movie that transcends the limitations of its slightly second-rate format, by dint of the strength of the basic source material and the fact that they adhered to all the elements of the book. If it ain't broke, don't fix it. I'm sorry that not everyone enjoyed the movie, and I appreciate the negative comments it has received from some. For me it boils down to the concept of the Langoliers being something that really intrigued me, in a scary way, and I can't get enough of reading about them or watching them. For that reason, the movie gave me exactly what I was looking for.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Faithful Adaptation
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ramin99
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I watched about half of this abomination then fittingly enough dropped like a sack of potatoes after drinking god knows how many beers; I mean is it possible to watch such rubbish with all of your intellectual faculties intact? The bad acting, especially by the blind girl, the young guy and the hot girl (she was pleasing to the eyes so I guess that makes her bad acting excusable), and deciding whether or not she wore bras was about all I can remember from the film now. I am befuddled to read, by a good number of reviewers, the following paradox: "the book is good but this particular adaptation is bad. I am a huge fan of that writer but this film sucks!" A movie follows a script thus the source material of a film, is, its script. If the script is good then there is a fat chance the movie turns out good; but if bad no one can turn it into a masterpiece. Do you see my point? Please get your heads out of your ***** and see things for what they are! A few hours later I woke up dizzy with accompanying headache and a bad taste in my mouth, then sat down to write this review, so I'm grumpier/crankier than usual.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An intriguing King mystery hampered down in TV land
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    DAVID SIM
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Stephen King is the world's most prolific horror novelist. His success lies in his writing, and in the sheer volume of films and TV movies adapting his work. The Langoliers is one of several King mini-series we've seen in recent years. Adapted from a short story in King's novella Four Past Midnight, it represents one of King's occasional detours from horror and into science-fiction. The premise is something that could easily fill an episode of The Twilight Zone (in fact the plot reminded me more of The Lost Hour, an episode from TV's Eerie Indiana). Ten airline passengers fall asleep on a red-eye flight to Boston. During the flight, the plane flew through a time-rip and when it came out the other side, it catapulted the plane back in time by a day. The sleeping passengers were the only ones to emerge unharmed. All the ones that were awake just vanished into the ether. When they land the plane, the people on the ground have disappeared as well. Its a dead, lifeless world with no electricity and vigour, and what's worse is the Langoliers, monsters from one of the passenger's childhood stories are coming to gobble them up. I always felt The Langoliers was one that straddled an uneasy line between science-fiction and horror. When most authors try to tackle different genres at the same time they often wind up shortchanging one at the expense of the other, or even worse is that they cancel each other out. One suspects the way King wrote the story, it was originally a time-travel piece, but when it got to the airport scenes, he decided to include the Langoliers to give it a bit more dramatic intensity. Without it, he would have been left with a not too terribly gripping storyline. Fill the airplane with fuel. Backtrack to the time-rip. Fly through it. They get home. The Langoliers was directed by genre regular Tom Holland. Holland emerged in the 80s with two above average horror movies, Fright Night and Child's Play. But then into the 90s, he seemed to disappear into TV land, and vanished after that, much like one of the passengers on Flight 29. Fright Night and Child's Play showed Holland with a fine grasp of horror mechanics. But whether its because they were feature films or its just the slimness of King's material, his work on The Langoliers disappoints. Certainly it begins well. Once the passengers vanish from the plane, it makes for a highly absorbing mystery. But eventually, the story begins to drag. And its not exactly helped by the TV production values Holland is forced to work with. The Langoliers are given such an inscrutable buildup (in a nice touch we hear they're approach even when they're still miles away) that when they finally arrive, we're almost breathless with anticipation. But as soon as you see them, you're howling with laughter. They look like giant meatballs with teeth, and the TV special effects play out the scene embarrassingly. Where The Langoliers is more successful is in some of the characterisations. Dean Stockwell, David Morse and Mark Lindsay Chapman all give capable performances. Especially Chapman, an actor better known for playing smarmy snake in the grasses, but gives surprising sympathy to the part of a special operator with a chequered past. His wry, guarded performance makes his character Nick Hopewell into the most well developed member of the cast. Kate Maberly has some creepy moments as the blind girl who sees more than the people around her. But even creepier is Bronson Pinchot, giving a highly live-wire performance as Craig Toomey, the psycho in they're midst who knows all about Langoliers from the horror stories his father delighted in telling him as a child. With the rest of the story stifled by TV movie surroundings, he brings a welcome surge of energy whenever he's in it. The other survivors could have been written out altogether to no noticeable effect. It does get itself together for an effective, slightly tragic finale, but The Langoliers lacks the childhood terrors of IT, or the assured storytelling of The Shining. King has given Tom Holland a slim story to work with, so amongst the TV versions of his work, The Langoliers ranks as one of the more anonymous.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A mixed blessing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Neil Welch
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Stephen King's enjoyable novella about a planeload of passengers who, thanks to a very odd storm and a warp in space/time, find themselves stranded in an unpopulated and rapidly decaying version of their own world (because time has moved on into the future) is turned into a possibly over-long three-part TV miniseries. There is much to like here. The adaptation is moderately faithful, the casting and performances are good (Bronson Pinchot is a bit over the top, but that is a requirement of the character), and there are some nice production touches - the gradual de-saturisation of the colour works well to demonstrate what is happening. Not so good are the Langoliers themselves. They had to be a special effect, but they could have usefully consumed a bigger chunk of budget: they should be terrifying because of what they do but, unfortunately, they come across as rather comical. And, as I said, the thing is too long. Three hours is taken to tell a story which could have been told in half that time, and you'd have been on the edge of your seat all the way through.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Different Take On Time Travel.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Based on a Stephen King novel, this TV movie adaptation is about the passengers on a red-eye airplane flight from L.A to Boston who awaken to find that the rest of the passengers and crew are gone, and they are all alone on the plane, which will soon run out of fuel. Fortunately, there is a pilot on board, who tries to land the plane at a nearby airport, only to discover that it is also empty, and that they are being pursued by giant, howling monsters called Langoliers that seem to be devouring time itself... Potentially interesting take on time travel, with an appealing cast of characters(except Bronson Pinchot, quite good playing an obnoxious and terrified child-like man who knows all about the Langoliers from his hideous father.) cannot save far-fetched premise, and the primitive CGI Langoliers have not aged well... Still, not the worst way to kill three hours!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Spectacular Story!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    djk-930-38279
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love this movie so much! All of the sci-fi and mystery of it is exactly what I love in books and movies. In this feature, I first saw it on TV and then I read the book. The book is very good as well, but it gives out much more information, describes things in more detail, which in some ways is good, but for me, when it comes to the gore with Mr. Toomey, I would rather not know so much. So in that case, watching the movie is much more preferred than reading it in the book. I gave this movie a 9 because I love it so much, but I just have one problem with it. There was some especially terrible acting, mostly by Christopher Collet who played Albert Kaussner. In many instances, he would overact his lines, and/or his lines were just written very poorly for him. I think for the most part though, the other main characters did pretty well. Not the best acting, but it was good.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Most interesting TV adaptation of S. King's work
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sang Park
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I just didn't give higher vote just because of the low budget and the poor F/X alloted to this movie. I have full understanding that this is low budget TV movie. But I could resist watching it because I had such high expectation in David Morse and Dean Stockwell. Enough with background of my watching movie.. First I didn't realize that this movie is 3 hours long... Maybe when they aired on TV they could have broken into series, but I've watched this on Netflix as one piece and it is longer movie than the lord of the rings. But as others put it, the length was due to the faithful adaptation of the original novel. No jumps or gaps in plots. Whenever there requires some explanation, Dean Stockwell slides in exuberantly and fulfills duties (he is supposed to be the avatar of S. King in the movie). I too have some pet peeve on the crappy F/X (really cheesy C.G.), but the reaction of actors actress are good enough to convince me that the monsters are there creeping in. All the settings and actings are good enough to make me get the creeps from what is going on in the movie. (FYI, I am a seasoned pseudo-professional monster/scary movie tester). When compared with "Stand", I think this is descent TV movie and I enjoyed pretty much.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    bad acting...bad FX....but still an excellent TV movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    supreme_mamu
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Some people says that acting and FX are the main purpose in creating a good movie, but here, it was proved wrong. I have to admit that this movie are full of characters with bad acting, i mean all of them (except for Bronson Pinchot who gave an excellent performance as mad guy Mr Craig Toomey). But the worst goes to the little girl, the blind little girl who does not have any emotional feelings and not really up to the standard to what audience always wanted. And the FX is quite poor and cheesy, seems to be cartoons. It really looks funny to me! I wish it could be better in order to turn this into a great movie. But, none of these really affect the greatness of The Langoliers. The main purpose of why this movie is created is because of the storyline, the story written by the master of horror, Stephen King. And, the story are almost exactly accurate to the short story in 4 Past Midnight. The way the story tell us is very entertaining, until I didn't really focus myself on the acting and the FX. It is the story which keep me thinking and wait for what is going to happen at the end of the story. Even though the movie is 3 hours long, but it doesn't make me feel boring because the suspend is there. I'm gonna watch this movie again for the 10th times this afternoon :) forget about the acting and the FX, concentrate on the storyline! excellent (10/10 stars)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Amazingly bad
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    CinefanR
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Everything is this movie is painfully bad- acting, story-line, script, special effects. It's true that my expectations were high. I've heard a lot about Stephen King and I imagined that such a celebrated writer would come up with something brilliant and original. I was expecting to see a spark of genius from the so-called "master of horror". Boy, was I wrong... The first 10 minutes or so make a promising start and I thought the premise was intriguing. After that, it falls flat on all levels. Pretentious, uninteresting one-dimensional characters check. Terribly written dialogue check. Ridiculous special effects check. The acting is atrocious, check that too. The sense of mystery is basically zero, probably because the viewer can't ignore the fact that everything takes place in a cheap TV set. And the worst part is that it goes on and on, and on for 3 hours. The only reason I kept watching was to see if maybe a good conclusion or some clever twist in the story line would save it somehow, but no. This movie is nothing more than the usual sci-fi clich&eacute;s piled up to the very end, while the production standards are beyond embarrassing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    ..and then...and then..and then...NOTHING!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Carol Mckinley
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    THIS REVIEW CONTAINS (MILD) SPOILERS! This is hands down the worst movie I have ever seen in my life. I've read through the first few pages of reviews left on this movie and to see glowing reviews over this steaming pile of crap is laughable. Really...did we watch the same movie? Imagine getting on a roller coaster. The longest, scariest, and highest roller coaster in the entire theme park. You buy the ticket, wait in line, and board the roller coaster. You get on the ride and go through dark tunnels, loops, and curves.....for hours. Although the ride is tiring, and the wait was long, you are still caught up in the anticipation. After all, the suspense is killing you, and with all this prolonged anticipation, surely this is going to be a hell of a ride, right? Now imagine getting to the peak of the roller coaster. Finally, you are at the highest point. You're ready. You waited so long. Now all of your waiting is going to finally pay off. You look down and see the fall...now you are excited. You prepare yourself for the adrenaline rush and excitement of finally getting to the best part..and then...........you are immediately let off the ride. That is the best way to describe this movie. It is probably the most disappointing thriller film that one could possibly waste hours out of their day watching. I HIGHLY warn that people understand that you WILL with out a doubt be disappointed to an extreme extent if you watch this movie. In fact, do yourself a favor, and if you do decide to watch this garbage, watch the first two hours of it and then turn it off and come to your own logical conclusion of what happened. I find it more comforting to think that Mr. Toomey or the equally irritating Dianne girl and/or boy were controlling the plane and preventing the passengers from making it to their proper dimension the entire time. Langoliers is often times given a second glance because of it's so called "original plot" (albeit the many loopholes) and suspense. The terrible effects are also often excused due to the fact that this was a "made for TV" movie. Bull. I've seen movies made in the 20s with better effects. Do not be deceived. There is nothing original about this plot. I point anyone who is interested to Twilight Zone episode "The Odyssey of Flight 33". The only difference between the two is a more coherent and concise plot from Rod Sterling, minus the ridiculous "character development" of otherwise ridiculous characters and Chomp Chomp Pac-men monsters that take three hours to make their grand debut. Suspense is the highest point of this movie as well as it's down fall. For several hours we do not see these "Langoliers" we can only "hear" them (and by "hear" them, I mean the snap, crackle, pop noise one would hear from pouring milk over Rice Krispie cereal) as well as the suspense of knowing that they could jump out at any moment. As a viewer when 95% of a film is suspense without even a view of the alleged monster, one would expect an even bigger climax. .......so what are the Langoliers? Who knows. We are never told exactly "what" they are or the relevancy these creatures have on the story. The Langoliers could be absent from this movie, and it would still make sense, scratch that, the movie would make MORE sense if the Langoliers were not included. Are the Langoliers fabricated from Mr. Toomey's mind and simply "boogeymen" from his childhood past? Who knows. Are they simply the eaters of time and space? Who knows. Are they a mixed breed of Tazmanian Devil and Pac Men? Seems likely.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Like A 3 hour long episode of "The Twilight Zone"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stubbers
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am currently reading "Four Past Midnight", the book of four Stephen King novellas which opens with "The Langoliers". I have just finished reading this story and immediately checked out the movie version. I wasn't disappointed. Something about this story, like many of King's, really touches a nerve. The quality is mainly in the basic concept rather than the sometimes-clunky dialogue. I like the idea of the past still existing physically, until it eventually becomes swallowed up by the Langoliers, the so-called Housekeepers of Eternity who hoover up the past to make way for the present. Incidentally, while reading the book I assumed the emphasis in the word was on the "o" - langOliers, to rhyme with magnolias. But no, the emphasis is on the "i" - langol-Iers, to rhyme with chandeliers. Either way, it's a strange word used to describe a very strange (but somehow not totally unfeasible) type of creature. Like all good "Twilight Zone" episodes, which this reminds me of, such a great underlying premise leaves a really strong, unnerving impression. As such, it doesn't matter so much that the acting and special effects aren't amazing. The atmosphere and plot are totally faithful to the original book. In a way, the slightly wooden, stilted acting suits the wooden, stilted world in which the characters find themselves. An airless, stuffy, oppressive world where you can barely light a match, where the wind either doesn't blow (according to the book), or else blows on the ground level but doesn't move the clouds (according to the movie, because they couldn't stop the wind blowing on location!). A world lying in the dumpster, slowly atrophying, thrown on the scrapheap by the constant forward motion of time's winged chariot. Always good to see Dean Stockwell, a man who is no stranger to travelling through time! Not his greatest ever performance here, but he certainly brings enigma to the part of writer Bob Jenkins. Bronson Pinchot brought just the right amount of creepy-but-sympathetic insanity to Craig Toomey, the dictionary definition of a loser in life, and a stark warning to what can happen to children later in life if they are belittled by their over-demanding parents. By comparison, David Morse as Captain Brian Engel was low-key and understated, but that was the exact impression I got of him from the book. If you were flying in an airplane through a rip in the space-time continuum, you would certainly want your pilot to be calm and unflappable! Unlike some posters here, I actually thought Mark Lindsay Chapman's Anglo-American accent was spot on. And I say this as a Brit who has spent considerable time in America. Out of necessity for being understood clearly and not sounding too "plum in mouth", Brits in the States have to slip in a few American sounding inflections here and there. So kudos to Chapman for a great, convincing performance as Americanised British secret agent Nick Popewell. I'd go so far as to say that his English accent was better than Harry Shearer's immortal Derek Smalls character (Spinal Tap). As for the ladies - well thumbs up for both Patricia Wettig and Kimber Riddle for certainly being very watchable, if not the most three-dimensional performances I have ever seen. And unlike many people here, I had no issues with Kate Maberly as blind Dinah. Finally, the effects of the Langoliers themselves. No problem! Once again, my image of them from reading the book was as funny sort of bouncing balls with teeth, which is more or less how they turned out on screen. These are not hi-tech computer generated monsters full of whizzbang explosions, they are like parasitic insects that feed off the scraps of the past. I don't see how they could have been better represented to be honest. So what we have here is a TV movie that transcends the limitations of its slightly second-rate format, by dint of the strength of the basic source material and the fact that they adhered to all the elements of the book. If it ain't broke, don't fix it. I'm sorry that not everyone enjoyed the movie, and I appreciate the negative comments it has received from some. For me it boils down to the concept of the Langoliers being something that really intrigued me, in a scary way, and I can't get enough of reading about them or watching them. For that reason, the movie gave me exactly what I was looking for.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Faithful Adaptation
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ramin99
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I watched about half of this abomination then fittingly enough dropped like a sack of potatoes after drinking god knows how many beers; I mean is it possible to watch such rubbish with all of your intellectual faculties intact? The bad acting, especially by the blind girl, the young guy and the hot girl (she was pleasing to the eyes so I guess that makes her bad acting excusable), and deciding whether or not she wore bras was about all I can remember from the film now. I am befuddled to read, by a good number of reviewers, the following paradox: "the book is good but this particular adaptation is bad. I am a huge fan of that writer but this film sucks!" A movie follows a script thus the source material of a film, is, its script. If the script is good then there is a fat chance the movie turns out good; but if bad no one can turn it into a masterpiece. Do you see my point? Please get your heads out of your ***** and see things for what they are! A few hours later I woke up dizzy with accompanying headache and a bad taste in my mouth, then sat down to write this review, so I'm grumpier/crankier than usual.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An intriguing King mystery hampered down in TV land
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    DAVID SIM
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Stephen King is the world's most prolific horror novelist. His success lies in his writing, and in the sheer volume of films and TV movies adapting his work. The Langoliers is one of several King mini-series we've seen in recent years. Adapted from a short story in King's novella Four Past Midnight, it represents one of King's occasional detours from horror and into science-fiction. The premise is something that could easily fill an episode of The Twilight Zone (in fact the plot reminded me more of The Lost Hour, an episode from TV's Eerie Indiana). Ten airline passengers fall asleep on a red-eye flight to Boston. During the flight, the plane flew through a time-rip and when it came out the other side, it catapulted the plane back in time by a day. The sleeping passengers were the only ones to emerge unharmed. All the ones that were awake just vanished into the ether. When they land the plane, the people on the ground have disappeared as well. Its a dead, lifeless world with no electricity and vigour, and what's worse is the Langoliers, monsters from one of the passenger's childhood stories are coming to gobble them up. I always felt The Langoliers was one that straddled an uneasy line between science-fiction and horror. When most authors try to tackle different genres at the same time they often wind up shortchanging one at the expense of the other, or even worse is that they cancel each other out. One suspects the way King wrote the story, it was originally a time-travel piece, but when it got to the airport scenes, he decided to include the Langoliers to give it a bit more dramatic intensity. Without it, he would have been left with a not too terribly gripping storyline. Fill the airplane with fuel. Backtrack to the time-rip. Fly through it. They get home. The Langoliers was directed by genre regular Tom Holland. Holland emerged in the 80s with two above average horror movies, Fright Night and Child's Play. But then into the 90s, he seemed to disappear into TV land, and vanished after that, much like one of the passengers on Flight 29. Fright Night and Child's Play showed Holland with a fine grasp of horror mechanics. But whether its because they were feature films or its just the slimness of King's material, his work on The Langoliers disappoints. Certainly it begins well. Once the passengers vanish from the plane, it makes for a highly absorbing mystery. But eventually, the story begins to drag. And its not exactly helped by the TV production values Holland is forced to work with. The Langoliers are given such an inscrutable buildup (in a nice touch we hear they're approach even when they're still miles away) that when they finally arrive, we're almost breathless with anticipation. But as soon as you see them, you're howling with laughter. They look like giant meatballs with teeth, and the TV special effects play out the scene embarrassingly. Where The Langoliers is more successful is in some of the characterisations. Dean Stockwell, David Morse and Mark Lindsay Chapman all give capable performances. Especially Chapman, an actor better known for playing smarmy snake in the grasses, but gives surprising sympathy to the part of a special operator with a chequered past. His wry, guarded performance makes his character Nick Hopewell into the most well developed member of the cast. Kate Maberly has some creepy moments as the blind girl who sees more than the people around her. But even creepier is Bronson Pinchot, giving a highly live-wire performance as Craig Toomey, the psycho in they're midst who knows all about Langoliers from the horror stories his father delighted in telling him as a child. With the rest of the story stifled by TV movie surroundings, he brings a welcome surge of energy whenever he's in it. The other survivors could have been written out altogether to no noticeable effect. It does get itself together for an effective, slightly tragic finale, but The Langoliers lacks the childhood terrors of IT, or the assured storytelling of The Shining. King has given Tom Holland a slim story to work with, so amongst the TV versions of his work, The Langoliers ranks as one of the more anonymous.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A mixed blessing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Neil Welch
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Stephen King's enjoyable novella about a planeload of passengers who, thanks to a very odd storm and a warp in space/time, find themselves stranded in an unpopulated and rapidly decaying version of their own world (because time has moved on into the future) is turned into a possibly over-long three-part TV miniseries. There is much to like here. The adaptation is moderately faithful, the casting and performances are good (Bronson Pinchot is a bit over the top, but that is a requirement of the character), and there are some nice production touches - the gradual de-saturisation of the colour works well to demonstrate what is happening. Not so good are the Langoliers themselves. They had to be a special effect, but they could have usefully consumed a bigger chunk of budget: they should be terrifying because of what they do but, unfortunately, they come across as rather comical. And, as I said, the thing is too long. Three hours is taken to tell a story which could have been told in half that time, and you'd have been on the edge of your seat all the way through.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Different Take On Time Travel.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Based on a Stephen King novel, this TV movie adaptation is about the passengers on a red-eye airplane flight from L.A to Boston who awaken to find that the rest of the passengers and crew are gone, and they are all alone on the plane, which will soon run out of fuel. Fortunately, there is a pilot on board, who tries to land the plane at a nearby airport, only to discover that it is also empty, and that they are being pursued by giant, howling monsters called Langoliers that seem to be devouring time itself... Potentially interesting take on time travel, with an appealing cast of characters(except Bronson Pinchot, quite good playing an obnoxious and terrified child-like man who knows all about the Langoliers from his hideous father.) cannot save far-fetched premise, and the primitive CGI Langoliers have not aged well... Still, not the worst way to kill three hours!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Spectacular Story!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    djk-930-38279
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love this movie so much! All of the sci-fi and mystery of it is exactly what I love in books and movies. In this feature, I first saw it on TV and then I read the book. The book is very good as well, but it gives out much more information, describes things in more detail, which in some ways is good, but for me, when it comes to the gore with Mr. Toomey, I would rather not know so much. So in that case, watching the movie is much more preferred than reading it in the book. I gave this movie a 9 because I love it so much, but I just have one problem with it. There was some especially terrible acting, mostly by Christopher Collet who played Albert Kaussner. In many instances, he would overact his lines, and/or his lines were just written very poorly for him. I think for the most part though, the other main characters did pretty well. Not the best acting, but it was good.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Most interesting TV adaptation of S. King's work
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sang Park
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I just didn't give higher vote just because of the low budget and the poor F/X alloted to this movie. I have full understanding that this is low budget TV movie. But I could resist watching it because I had such high expectation in David Morse and Dean Stockwell. Enough with background of my watching movie.. First I didn't realize that this movie is 3 hours long... Maybe when they aired on TV they could have broken into series, but I've watched this on Netflix as one piece and it is longer movie than the lord of the rings. But as others put it, the length was due to the faithful adaptation of the original novel. No jumps or gaps in plots. Whenever there requires some explanation, Dean Stockwell slides in exuberantly and fulfills duties (he is supposed to be the avatar of S. King in the movie). I too have some pet peeve on the crappy F/X (really cheesy C.G.), but the reaction of actors actress are good enough to convince me that the monsters are there creeping in. All the settings and actings are good enough to make me get the creeps from what is going on in the movie. (FYI, I am a seasoned pseudo-professional monster/scary movie tester). When compared with "Stand", I think this is descent TV movie and I enjoyed pretty much.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    bad acting...bad FX....but still an excellent TV movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    supreme_mamu
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Some people says that acting and FX are the main purpose in creating a good movie, but here, it was proved wrong. I have to admit that this movie are full of characters with bad acting, i mean all of them (except for Bronson Pinchot who gave an excellent performance as mad guy Mr Craig Toomey). But the worst goes to the little girl, the blind little girl who does not have any emotional feelings and not really up to the standard to what audience always wanted. And the FX is quite poor and cheesy, seems to be cartoons. It really looks funny to me! I wish it could be better in order to turn this into a great movie. But, none of these really affect the greatness of The Langoliers. The main purpose of why this movie is created is because of the storyline, the story written by the master of horror, Stephen King. And, the story are almost exactly accurate to the short story in 4 Past Midnight. The way the story tell us is very entertaining, until I didn't really focus myself on the acting and the FX. It is the story which keep me thinking and wait for what is going to happen at the end of the story. Even though the movie is 3 hours long, but it doesn't make me feel boring because the suspend is there. I'm gonna watch this movie again for the 10th times this afternoon :) forget about the acting and the FX, concentrate on the storyline! excellent (10/10 stars)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Amazingly bad
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    CinefanR
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Everything is this movie is painfully bad- acting, story-line, script, special effects. It's true that my expectations were high. I've heard a lot about Stephen King and I imagined that such a celebrated writer would come up with something brilliant and original. I was expecting to see a spark of genius from the so-called "master of horror". Boy, was I wrong... The first 10 minutes or so make a promising start and I thought the premise was intriguing. After that, it falls flat on all levels. Pretentious, uninteresting one-dimensional characters check. Terribly written dialogue check. Ridiculous special effects check. The acting is atrocious, check that too. The sense of mystery is basically zero, probably because the viewer can't ignore the fact that everything takes place in a cheap TV set. And the worst part is that it goes on and on, and on for 3 hours. The only reason I kept watching was to see if maybe a good conclusion or some clever twist in the story line would save it somehow, but no. This movie is nothing more than the usual sci-fi clich&eacute;s piled up to the very end, while the production standards are beyond embarrassing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    ..and then...and then..and then...NOTHING!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Carol Mckinley
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    THIS REVIEW CONTAINS (MILD) SPOILERS! This is hands down the worst movie I have ever seen in my life. I've read through the first few pages of reviews left on this movie and to see glowing reviews over this steaming pile of crap is laughable. Really...did we watch the same movie? Imagine getting on a roller coaster. The longest, scariest, and highest roller coaster in the entire theme park. You buy the ticket, wait in line, and board the roller coaster. You get on the ride and go through dark tunnels, loops, and curves.....for hours. Although the ride is tiring, and the wait was long, you are still caught up in the anticipation. After all, the suspense is killing you, and with all this prolonged anticipation, surely this is going to be a hell of a ride, right? Now imagine getting to the peak of the roller coaster. Finally, you are at the highest point. You're ready. You waited so long. Now all of your waiting is going to finally pay off. You look down and see the fall...now you are excited. You prepare yourself for the adrenaline rush and excitement of finally getting to the best part..and then...........you are immediately let off the ride. That is the best way to describe this movie. It is probably the most disappointing thriller film that one could possibly waste hours out of their day watching. I HIGHLY warn that people understand that you WILL with out a doubt be disappointed to an extreme extent if you watch this movie. In fact, do yourself a favor, and if you do decide to watch this garbage, watch the first two hours of it and then turn it off and come to your own logical conclusion of what happened. I find it more comforting to think that Mr. Toomey or the equally irritating Dianne girl and/or boy were controlling the plane and preventing the passengers from making it to their proper dimension the entire time. Langoliers is often times given a second glance because of it's so called "original plot" (albeit the many loopholes) and suspense. The terrible effects are also often excused due to the fact that this was a "made for TV" movie. Bull. I've seen movies made in the 20s with better effects. Do not be deceived. There is nothing original about this plot. I point anyone who is interested to Twilight Zone episode "The Odyssey of Flight 33". The only difference between the two is a more coherent and concise plot from Rod Sterling, minus the ridiculous "character development" of otherwise ridiculous characters and Chomp Chomp Pac-men monsters that take three hours to make their grand debut. Suspense is the highest point of this movie as well as it's down fall. For several hours we do not see these "Langoliers" we can only "hear" them (and by "hear" them, I mean the snap, crackle, pop noise one would hear from pouring milk over Rice Krispie cereal) as well as the suspense of knowing that they could jump out at any moment. As a viewer when 95% of a film is suspense without even a view of the alleged monster, one would expect an even bigger climax. .......so what are the Langoliers? Who knows. We are never told exactly "what" they are or the relevancy these creatures have on the story. The Langoliers could be absent from this movie, and it would still make sense, scratch that, the movie would make MORE sense if the Langoliers were not included. Are the Langoliers fabricated from Mr. Toomey's mind and simply "boogeymen" from his childhood past? Who knows. Are they simply the eaters of time and space? Who knows. Are they a mixed breed of Tazmanian Devil and Pac Men? Seems likely.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Like A 3 hour long episode of "The Twilight Zone"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stubbers
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am currently reading "Four Past Midnight", the book of four Stephen King novellas which opens with "The Langoliers". I have just finished reading this story and immediately checked out the movie version. I wasn't disappointed. Something about this story, like many of King's, really touches a nerve. The quality is mainly in the basic concept rather than the sometimes-clunky dialogue. I like the idea of the past still existing physically, until it eventually becomes swallowed up by the Langoliers, the so-called Housekeepers of Eternity who hoover up the past to make way for the present. Incidentally, while reading the book I assumed the emphasis in the word was on the "o" - langOliers, to rhyme with magnolias. But no, the emphasis is on the "i" - langol-Iers, to rhyme with chandeliers. Either way, it's a strange word used to describe a very strange (but somehow not totally unfeasible) type of creature. Like all good "Twilight Zone" episodes, which this reminds me of, such a great underlying premise leaves a really strong, unnerving impression. As such, it doesn't matter so much that the acting and special effects aren't amazing. The atmosphere and plot are totally faithful to the original book. In a way, the slightly wooden, stilted acting suits the wooden, stilted world in which the characters find themselves. An airless, stuffy, oppressive world where you can barely light a match, where the wind either doesn't blow (according to the book), or else blows on the ground level but doesn't move the clouds (according to the movie, because they couldn't stop the wind blowing on location!). A world lying in the dumpster, slowly atrophying, thrown on the scrapheap by the constant forward motion of time's winged chariot. Always good to see Dean Stockwell, a man who is no stranger to travelling through time! Not his greatest ever performance here, but he certainly brings enigma to the part of writer Bob Jenkins. Bronson Pinchot brought just the right amount of creepy-but-sympathetic insanity to Craig Toomey, the dictionary definition of a loser in life, and a stark warning to what can happen to children later in life if they are belittled by their over-demanding parents. By comparison, David Morse as Captain Brian Engel was low-key and understated, but that was the exact impression I got of him from the book. If you were flying in an airplane through a rip in the space-time continuum, you would certainly want your pilot to be calm and unflappable! Unlike some posters here, I actually thought Mark Lindsay Chapman's Anglo-American accent was spot on. And I say this as a Brit who has spent considerable time in America. Out of necessity for being understood clearly and not sounding too "plum in mouth", Brits in the States have to slip in a few American sounding inflections here and there. So kudos to Chapman for a great, convincing performance as Americanised British secret agent Nick Popewell. I'd go so far as to say that his English accent was better than Harry Shearer's immortal Derek Smalls character (Spinal Tap). As for the ladies - well thumbs up for both Patricia Wettig and Kimber Riddle for certainly being very watchable, if not the most three-dimensional performances I have ever seen. And unlike many people here, I had no issues with Kate Maberly as blind Dinah. Finally, the effects of the Langoliers themselves. No problem! Once again, my image of them from reading the book was as funny sort of bouncing balls with teeth, which is more or less how they turned out on screen. These are not hi-tech computer generated monsters full of whizzbang explosions, they are like parasitic insects that feed off the scraps of the past. I don't see how they could have been better represented to be honest. So what we have here is a TV movie that transcends the limitations of its slightly second-rate format, by dint of the strength of the basic source material and the fact that they adhered to all the elements of the book. If it ain't broke, don't fix it. I'm sorry that not everyone enjoyed the movie, and I appreciate the negative comments it has received from some. For me it boils down to the concept of the Langoliers being something that really intrigued me, in a scary way, and I can't get enough of reading about them or watching them. For that reason, the movie gave me exactly what I was looking for.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Faithful Adaptation
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ramin99
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I watched about half of this abomination then fittingly enough dropped like a sack of potatoes after drinking god knows how many beers; I mean is it possible to watch such rubbish with all of your intellectual faculties intact? The bad acting, especially by the blind girl, the young guy and the hot girl (she was pleasing to the eyes so I guess that makes her bad acting excusable), and deciding whether or not she wore bras was about all I can remember from the film now. I am befuddled to read, by a good number of reviewers, the following paradox: "the book is good but this particular adaptation is bad. I am a huge fan of that writer but this film sucks!" A movie follows a script thus the source material of a film, is, its script. If the script is good then there is a fat chance the movie turns out good; but if bad no one can turn it into a masterpiece. Do you see my point? Please get your heads out of your ***** and see things for what they are! A few hours later I woke up dizzy with accompanying headache and a bad taste in my mouth, then sat down to write this review, so I'm grumpier/crankier than usual.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An intriguing King mystery hampered down in TV land
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    DAVID SIM
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Stephen King is the world's most prolific horror novelist. His success lies in his writing, and in the sheer volume of films and TV movies adapting his work. The Langoliers is one of several King mini-series we've seen in recent years. Adapted from a short story in King's novella Four Past Midnight, it represents one of King's occasional detours from horror and into science-fiction. The premise is something that could easily fill an episode of The Twilight Zone (in fact the plot reminded me more of The Lost Hour, an episode from TV's Eerie Indiana). Ten airline passengers fall asleep on a red-eye flight to Boston. During the flight, the plane flew through a time-rip and when it came out the other side, it catapulted the plane back in time by a day. The sleeping passengers were the only ones to emerge unharmed. All the ones that were awake just vanished into the ether. When they land the plane, the people on the ground have disappeared as well. Its a dead, lifeless world with no electricity and vigour, and what's worse is the Langoliers, monsters from one of the passenger's childhood stories are coming to gobble them up. I always felt The Langoliers was one that straddled an uneasy line between science-fiction and horror. When most authors try to tackle different genres at the same time they often wind up shortchanging one at the expense of the other, or even worse is that they cancel each other out. One suspects the way King wrote the story, it was originally a time-travel piece, but when it got to the airport scenes, he decided to include the Langoliers to give it a bit more dramatic intensity. Without it, he would have been left with a not too terribly gripping storyline. Fill the airplane with fuel. Backtrack to the time-rip. Fly through it. They get home. The Langoliers was directed by genre regular Tom Holland. Holland emerged in the 80s with two above average horror movies, Fright Night and Child's Play. But then into the 90s, he seemed to disappear into TV land, and vanished after that, much like one of the passengers on Flight 29. Fright Night and Child's Play showed Holland with a fine grasp of horror mechanics. But whether its because they were feature films or its just the slimness of King's material, his work on The Langoliers disappoints. Certainly it begins well. Once the passengers vanish from the plane, it makes for a highly absorbing mystery. But eventually, the story begins to drag. And its not exactly helped by the TV production values Holland is forced to work with. The Langoliers are given such an inscrutable buildup (in a nice touch we hear they're approach even when they're still miles away) that when they finally arrive, we're almost breathless with anticipation. But as soon as you see them, you're howling with laughter. They look like giant meatballs with teeth, and the TV special effects play out the scene embarrassingly. Where The Langoliers is more successful is in some of the characterisations. Dean Stockwell, David Morse and Mark Lindsay Chapman all give capable performances. Especially Chapman, an actor better known for playing smarmy snake in the grasses, but gives surprising sympathy to the part of a special operator with a chequered past. His wry, guarded performance makes his character Nick Hopewell into the most well developed member of the cast. Kate Maberly has some creepy moments as the blind girl who sees more than the people around her. But even creepier is Bronson Pinchot, giving a highly live-wire performance as Craig Toomey, the psycho in they're midst who knows all about Langoliers from the horror stories his father delighted in telling him as a child. With the rest of the story stifled by TV movie surroundings, he brings a welcome surge of energy whenever he's in it. The other survivors could have been written out altogether to no noticeable effect. It does get itself together for an effective, slightly tragic finale, but The Langoliers lacks the childhood terrors of IT, or the assured storytelling of The Shining. King has given Tom Holland a slim story to work with, so amongst the TV versions of his work, The Langoliers ranks as one of the more anonymous.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A mixed blessing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Neil Welch
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Stephen King's enjoyable novella about a planeload of passengers who, thanks to a very odd storm and a warp in space/time, find themselves stranded in an unpopulated and rapidly decaying version of their own world (because time has moved on into the future) is turned into a possibly over-long three-part TV miniseries. There is much to like here. The adaptation is moderately faithful, the casting and performances are good (Bronson Pinchot is a bit over the top, but that is a requirement of the character), and there are some nice production touches - the gradual de-saturisation of the colour works well to demonstrate what is happening. Not so good are the Langoliers themselves. They had to be a special effect, but they could have usefully consumed a bigger chunk of budget: they should be terrifying because of what they do but, unfortunately, they come across as rather comical. And, as I said, the thing is too long. Three hours is taken to tell a story which could have been told in half that time, and you'd have been on the edge of your seat all the way through.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Different Take On Time Travel.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Based on a Stephen King novel, this TV movie adaptation is about the passengers on a red-eye airplane flight from L.A to Boston who awaken to find that the rest of the passengers and crew are gone, and they are all alone on the plane, which will soon run out of fuel. Fortunately, there is a pilot on board, who tries to land the plane at a nearby airport, only to discover that it is also empty, and that they are being pursued by giant, howling monsters called Langoliers that seem to be devouring time itself... Potentially interesting take on time travel, with an appealing cast of characters(except Bronson Pinchot, quite good playing an obnoxious and terrified child-like man who knows all about the Langoliers from his hideous father.) cannot save far-fetched premise, and the primitive CGI Langoliers have not aged well... Still, not the worst way to kill three hours!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Spectacular Story!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    djk-930-38279
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love this movie so much! All of the sci-fi and mystery of it is exactly what I love in books and movies. In this feature, I first saw it on TV and then I read the book. The book is very good as well, but it gives out much more information, describes things in more detail, which in some ways is good, but for me, when it comes to the gore with Mr. Toomey, I would rather not know so much. So in that case, watching the movie is much more preferred than reading it in the book. I gave this movie a 9 because I love it so much, but I just have one problem with it. There was some especially terrible acting, mostly by Christopher Collet who played Albert Kaussner. In many instances, he would overact his lines, and/or his lines were just written very poorly for him. I think for the most part though, the other main characters did pretty well. Not the best acting, but it was good.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Most interesting TV adaptation of S. King's work
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sang Park
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I just didn't give higher vote just because of the low budget and the poor F/X alloted to this movie. I have full understanding that this is low budget TV movie. But I could resist watching it because I had such high expectation in David Morse and Dean Stockwell. Enough with background of my watching movie.. First I didn't realize that this movie is 3 hours long... Maybe when they aired on TV they could have broken into series, but I've watched this on Netflix as one piece and it is longer movie than the lord of the rings. But as others put it, the length was due to the faithful adaptation of the original novel. No jumps or gaps in plots. Whenever there requires some explanation, Dean Stockwell slides in exuberantly and fulfills duties (he is supposed to be the avatar of S. King in the movie). I too have some pet peeve on the crappy F/X (really cheesy C.G.), but the reaction of actors actress are good enough to convince me that the monsters are there creeping in. All the settings and actings are good enough to make me get the creeps from what is going on in the movie. (FYI, I am a seasoned pseudo-professional monster/scary movie tester). When compared with "Stand", I think this is descent TV movie and I enjoyed pretty much.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    bad acting...bad FX....but still an excellent TV movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    supreme_mamu
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Some people says that acting and FX are the main purpose in creating a good movie, but here, it was proved wrong. I have to admit that this movie are full of characters with bad acting, i mean all of them (except for Bronson Pinchot who gave an excellent performance as mad guy Mr Craig Toomey). But the worst goes to the little girl, the blind little girl who does not have any emotional feelings and not really up to the standard to what audience always wanted. And the FX is quite poor and cheesy, seems to be cartoons. It really looks funny to me! I wish it could be better in order to turn this into a great movie. But, none of these really affect the greatness of The Langoliers. The main purpose of why this movie is created is because of the storyline, the story written by the master of horror, Stephen King. And, the story are almost exactly accurate to the short story in 4 Past Midnight. The way the story tell us is very entertaining, until I didn't really focus myself on the acting and the FX. It is the story which keep me thinking and wait for what is going to happen at the end of the story. Even though the movie is 3 hours long, but it doesn't make me feel boring because the suspend is there. I'm gonna watch this movie again for the 10th times this afternoon :) forget about the acting and the FX, concentrate on the storyline! excellent (10/10 stars)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Amazingly bad
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    CinefanR
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Everything is this movie is painfully bad- acting, story-line, script, special effects. It's true that my expectations were high. I've heard a lot about Stephen King and I imagined that such a celebrated writer would come up with something brilliant and original. I was expecting to see a spark of genius from the so-called "master of horror". Boy, was I wrong... The first 10 minutes or so make a promising start and I thought the premise was intriguing. After that, it falls flat on all levels. Pretentious, uninteresting one-dimensional characters check. Terribly written dialogue check. Ridiculous special effects check. The acting is atrocious, check that too. The sense of mystery is basically zero, probably because the viewer can't ignore the fact that everything takes place in a cheap TV set. And the worst part is that it goes on and on, and on for 3 hours. The only reason I kept watching was to see if maybe a good conclusion or some clever twist in the story line would save it somehow, but no. This movie is nothing more than the usual sci-fi clich&eacute;s piled up to the very end, while the production standards are beyond embarrassing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    ..and then...and then..and then...NOTHING!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Carol Mckinley
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    THIS REVIEW CONTAINS (MILD) SPOILERS! This is hands down the worst movie I have ever seen in my life. I've read through the first few pages of reviews left on this movie and to see glowing reviews over this steaming pile of crap is laughable. Really...did we watch the same movie? Imagine getting on a roller coaster. The longest, scariest, and highest roller coaster in the entire theme park. You buy the ticket, wait in line, and board the roller coaster. You get on the ride and go through dark tunnels, loops, and curves.....for hours. Although the ride is tiring, and the wait was long, you are still caught up in the anticipation. After all, the suspense is killing you, and with all this prolonged anticipation, surely this is going to be a hell of a ride, right? Now imagine getting to the peak of the roller coaster. Finally, you are at the highest point. You're ready. You waited so long. Now all of your waiting is going to finally pay off. You look down and see the fall...now you are excited. You prepare yourself for the adrenaline rush and excitement of finally getting to the best part..and then...........you are immediately let off the ride. That is the best way to describe this movie. It is probably the most disappointing thriller film that one could possibly waste hours out of their day watching. I HIGHLY warn that people understand that you WILL with out a doubt be disappointed to an extreme extent if you watch this movie. In fact, do yourself a favor, and if you do decide to watch this garbage, watch the first two hours of it and then turn it off and come to your own logical conclusion of what happened. I find it more comforting to think that Mr. Toomey or the equally irritating Dianne girl and/or boy were controlling the plane and preventing the passengers from making it to their proper dimension the entire time. Langoliers is often times given a second glance because of it's so called "original plot" (albeit the many loopholes) and suspense. The terrible effects are also often excused due to the fact that this was a "made for TV" movie. Bull. I've seen movies made in the 20s with better effects. Do not be deceived. There is nothing original about this plot. I point anyone who is interested to Twilight Zone episode "The Odyssey of Flight 33". The only difference between the two is a more coherent and concise plot from Rod Sterling, minus the ridiculous "character development" of otherwise ridiculous characters and Chomp Chomp Pac-men monsters that take three hours to make their grand debut. Suspense is the highest point of this movie as well as it's down fall. For several hours we do not see these "Langoliers" we can only "hear" them (and by "hear" them, I mean the snap, crackle, pop noise one would hear from pouring milk over Rice Krispie cereal) as well as the suspense of knowing that they could jump out at any moment. As a viewer when 95% of a film is suspense without even a view of the alleged monster, one would expect an even bigger climax. .......so what are the Langoliers? Who knows. We are never told exactly "what" they are or the relevancy these creatures have on the story. The Langoliers could be absent from this movie, and it would still make sense, scratch that, the movie would make MORE sense if the Langoliers were not included. Are the Langoliers fabricated from Mr. Toomey's mind and simply "boogeymen" from his childhood past? Who knows. Are they simply the eaters of time and space? Who knows. Are they a mixed breed of Tazmanian Devil and Pac Men? Seems likely.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Like A 3 hour long episode of "The Twilight Zone"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stubbers
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am currently reading "Four Past Midnight", the book of four Stephen King novellas which opens with "The Langoliers". I have just finished reading this story and immediately checked out the movie version. I wasn't disappointed. Something about this story, like many of King's, really touches a nerve. The quality is mainly in the basic concept rather than the sometimes-clunky dialogue. I like the idea of the past still existing physically, until it eventually becomes swallowed up by the Langoliers, the so-called Housekeepers of Eternity who hoover up the past to make way for the present. Incidentally, while reading the book I assumed the emphasis in the word was on the "o" - langOliers, to rhyme with magnolias. But no, the emphasis is on the "i" - langol-Iers, to rhyme with chandeliers. Either way, it's a strange word used to describe a very strange (but somehow not totally unfeasible) type of creature. Like all good "Twilight Zone" episodes, which this reminds me of, such a great underlying premise leaves a really strong, unnerving impression. As such, it doesn't matter so much that the acting and special effects aren't amazing. The atmosphere and plot are totally faithful to the original book. In a way, the slightly wooden, stilted acting suits the wooden, stilted world in which the characters find themselves. An airless, stuffy, oppressive world where you can barely light a match, where the wind either doesn't blow (according to the book), or else blows on the ground level but doesn't move the clouds (according to the movie, because they couldn't stop the wind blowing on location!). A world lying in the dumpster, slowly atrophying, thrown on the scrapheap by the constant forward motion of time's winged chariot. Always good to see Dean Stockwell, a man who is no stranger to travelling through time! Not his greatest ever performance here, but he certainly brings enigma to the part of writer Bob Jenkins. Bronson Pinchot brought just the right amount of creepy-but-sympathetic insanity to Craig Toomey, the dictionary definition of a loser in life, and a stark warning to what can happen to children later in life if they are belittled by their over-demanding parents. By comparison, David Morse as Captain Brian Engel was low-key and understated, but that was the exact impression I got of him from the book. If you were flying in an airplane through a rip in the space-time continuum, you would certainly want your pilot to be calm and unflappable! Unlike some posters here, I actually thought Mark Lindsay Chapman's Anglo-American accent was spot on. And I say this as a Brit who has spent considerable time in America. Out of necessity for being understood clearly and not sounding too "plum in mouth", Brits in the States have to slip in a few American sounding inflections here and there. So kudos to Chapman for a great, convincing performance as Americanised British secret agent Nick Popewell. I'd go so far as to say that his English accent was better than Harry Shearer's immortal Derek Smalls character (Spinal Tap). As for the ladies - well thumbs up for both Patricia Wettig and Kimber Riddle for certainly being very watchable, if not the most three-dimensional performances I have ever seen. And unlike many people here, I had no issues with Kate Maberly as blind Dinah. Finally, the effects of the Langoliers themselves. No problem! Once again, my image of them from reading the book was as funny sort of bouncing balls with teeth, which is more or less how they turned out on screen. These are not hi-tech computer generated monsters full of whizzbang explosions, they are like parasitic insects that feed off the scraps of the past. I don't see how they could have been better represented to be honest. So what we have here is a TV movie that transcends the limitations of its slightly second-rate format, by dint of the strength of the basic source material and the fact that they adhered to all the elements of the book. If it ain't broke, don't fix it. I'm sorry that not everyone enjoyed the movie, and I appreciate the negative comments it has received from some. For me it boils down to the concept of the Langoliers being something that really intrigued me, in a scary way, and I can't get enough of reading about them or watching them. For that reason, the movie gave me exactly what I was looking for.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Faithful Adaptation
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ramin99
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I watched about half of this abomination then fittingly enough dropped like a sack of potatoes after drinking god knows how many beers; I mean is it possible to watch such rubbish with all of your intellectual faculties intact? The bad acting, especially by the blind girl, the young guy and the hot girl (she was pleasing to the eyes so I guess that makes her bad acting excusable), and deciding whether or not she wore bras was about all I can remember from the film now. I am befuddled to read, by a good number of reviewers, the following paradox: "the book is good but this particular adaptation is bad. I am a huge fan of that writer but this film sucks!" A movie follows a script thus the source material of a film, is, its script. If the script is good then there is a fat chance the movie turns out good; but if bad no one can turn it into a masterpiece. Do you see my point? Please get your heads out of your ***** and see things for what they are! A few hours later I woke up dizzy with accompanying headache and a bad taste in my mouth, then sat down to write this review, so I'm grumpier/crankier than usual.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An intriguing King mystery hampered down in TV land
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    DAVID SIM
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Stephen King is the world's most prolific horror novelist. His success lies in his writing, and in the sheer volume of films and TV movies adapting his work. The Langoliers is one of several King mini-series we've seen in recent years. Adapted from a short story in King's novella Four Past Midnight, it represents one of King's occasional detours from horror and into science-fiction. The premise is something that could easily fill an episode of The Twilight Zone (in fact the plot reminded me more of The Lost Hour, an episode from TV's Eerie Indiana). Ten airline passengers fall asleep on a red-eye flight to Boston. During the flight, the plane flew through a time-rip and when it came out the other side, it catapulted the plane back in time by a day. The sleeping passengers were the only ones to emerge unharmed. All the ones that were awake just vanished into the ether. When they land the plane, the people on the ground have disappeared as well. Its a dead, lifeless world with no electricity and vigour, and what's worse is the Langoliers, monsters from one of the passenger's childhood stories are coming to gobble them up. I always felt The Langoliers was one that straddled an uneasy line between science-fiction and horror. When most authors try to tackle different genres at the same time they often wind up shortchanging one at the expense of the other, or even worse is that they cancel each other out. One suspects the way King wrote the story, it was originally a time-travel piece, but when it got to the airport scenes, he decided to include the Langoliers to give it a bit more dramatic intensity. Without it, he would have been left with a not too terribly gripping storyline. Fill the airplane with fuel. Backtrack to the time-rip. Fly through it. They get home. The Langoliers was directed by genre regular Tom Holland. Holland emerged in the 80s with two above average horror movies, Fright Night and Child's Play. But then into the 90s, he seemed to disappear into TV land, and vanished after that, much like one of the passengers on Flight 29. Fright Night and Child's Play showed Holland with a fine grasp of horror mechanics. But whether its because they were feature films or its just the slimness of King's material, his work on The Langoliers disappoints. Certainly it begins well. Once the passengers vanish from the plane, it makes for a highly absorbing mystery. But eventually, the story begins to drag. And its not exactly helped by the TV production values Holland is forced to work with. The Langoliers are given such an inscrutable buildup (in a nice touch we hear they're approach even when they're still miles away) that when they finally arrive, we're almost breathless with anticipation. But as soon as you see them, you're howling with laughter. They look like giant meatballs with teeth, and the TV special effects play out the scene embarrassingly. Where The Langoliers is more successful is in some of the characterisations. Dean Stockwell, David Morse and Mark Lindsay Chapman all give capable performances. Especially Chapman, an actor better known for playing smarmy snake in the grasses, but gives surprising sympathy to the part of a special operator with a chequered past. His wry, guarded performance makes his character Nick Hopewell into the most well developed member of the cast. Kate Maberly has some creepy moments as the blind girl who sees more than the people around her. But even creepier is Bronson Pinchot, giving a highly live-wire performance as Craig Toomey, the psycho in they're midst who knows all about Langoliers from the horror stories his father delighted in telling him as a child. With the rest of the story stifled by TV movie surroundings, he brings a welcome surge of energy whenever he's in it. The other survivors could have been written out altogether to no noticeable effect. It does get itself together for an effective, slightly tragic finale, but The Langoliers lacks the childhood terrors of IT, or the assured storytelling of The Shining. King has given Tom Holland a slim story to work with, so amongst the TV versions of his work, The Langoliers ranks as one of the more anonymous.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A mixed blessing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Neil Welch
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Stephen King's enjoyable novella about a planeload of passengers who, thanks to a very odd storm and a warp in space/time, find themselves stranded in an unpopulated and rapidly decaying version of their own world (because time has moved on into the future) is turned into a possibly over-long three-part TV miniseries. There is much to like here. The adaptation is moderately faithful, the casting and performances are good (Bronson Pinchot is a bit over the top, but that is a requirement of the character), and there are some nice production touches - the gradual de-saturisation of the colour works well to demonstrate what is happening. Not so good are the Langoliers themselves. They had to be a special effect, but they could have usefully consumed a bigger chunk of budget: they should be terrifying because of what they do but, unfortunately, they come across as rather comical. And, as I said, the thing is too long. Three hours is taken to tell a story which could have been told in half that time, and you'd have been on the edge of your seat all the way through.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Different Take On Time Travel.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Based on a Stephen King novel, this TV movie adaptation is about the passengers on a red-eye airplane flight from L.A to Boston who awaken to find that the rest of the passengers and crew are gone, and they are all alone on the plane, which will soon run out of fuel. Fortunately, there is a pilot on board, who tries to land the plane at a nearby airport, only to discover that it is also empty, and that they are being pursued by giant, howling monsters called Langoliers that seem to be devouring time itself... Potentially interesting take on time travel, with an appealing cast of characters(except Bronson Pinchot, quite good playing an obnoxious and terrified child-like man who knows all about the Langoliers from his hideous father.) cannot save far-fetched premise, and the primitive CGI Langoliers have not aged well... Still, not the worst way to kill three hours!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Spectacular Story!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    djk-930-38279
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love this movie so much! All of the sci-fi and mystery of it is exactly what I love in books and movies. In this feature, I first saw it on TV and then I read the book. The book is very good as well, but it gives out much more information, describes things in more detail, which in some ways is good, but for me, when it comes to the gore with Mr. Toomey, I would rather not know so much. So in that case, watching the movie is much more preferred than reading it in the book. I gave this movie a 9 because I love it so much, but I just have one problem with it. There was some especially terrible acting, mostly by Christopher Collet who played Albert Kaussner. In many instances, he would overact his lines, and/or his lines were just written very poorly for him. I think for the most part though, the other main characters did pretty well. Not the best acting, but it was good.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Most interesting TV adaptation of S. King's work
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sang Park
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I just didn't give higher vote just because of the low budget and the poor F/X alloted to this movie. I have full understanding that this is low budget TV movie. But I could resist watching it because I had such high expectation in David Morse and Dean Stockwell. Enough with background of my watching movie.. First I didn't realize that this movie is 3 hours long... Maybe when they aired on TV they could have broken into series, but I've watched this on Netflix as one piece and it is longer movie than the lord of the rings. But as others put it, the length was due to the faithful adaptation of the original novel. No jumps or gaps in plots. Whenever there requires some explanation, Dean Stockwell slides in exuberantly and fulfills duties (he is supposed to be the avatar of S. King in the movie). I too have some pet peeve on the crappy F/X (really cheesy C.G.), but the reaction of actors actress are good enough to convince me that the monsters are there creeping in. All the settings and actings are good enough to make me get the creeps from what is going on in the movie. (FYI, I am a seasoned pseudo-professional monster/scary movie tester). When compared with "Stand", I think this is descent TV movie and I enjoyed pretty much.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    bad acting...bad FX....but still an excellent TV movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    supreme_mamu
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Some people says that acting and FX are the main purpose in creating a good movie, but here, it was proved wrong. I have to admit that this movie are full of characters with bad acting, i mean all of them (except for Bronson Pinchot who gave an excellent performance as mad guy Mr Craig Toomey). But the worst goes to the little girl, the blind little girl who does not have any emotional feelings and not really up to the standard to what audience always wanted. And the FX is quite poor and cheesy, seems to be cartoons. It really looks funny to me! I wish it could be better in order to turn this into a great movie. But, none of these really affect the greatness of The Langoliers. The main purpose of why this movie is created is because of the storyline, the story written by the master of horror, Stephen King. And, the story are almost exactly accurate to the short story in 4 Past Midnight. The way the story tell us is very entertaining, until I didn't really focus myself on the acting and the FX. It is the story which keep me thinking and wait for what is going to happen at the end of the story. Even though the movie is 3 hours long, but it doesn't make me feel boring because the suspend is there. I'm gonna watch this movie again for the 10th times this afternoon :) forget about the acting and the FX, concentrate on the storyline! excellent (10/10 stars)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Amazingly bad
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    CinefanR
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Everything is this movie is painfully bad- acting, story-line, script, special effects. It's true that my expectations were high. I've heard a lot about Stephen King and I imagined that such a celebrated writer would come up with something brilliant and original. I was expecting to see a spark of genius from the so-called "master of horror". Boy, was I wrong... The first 10 minutes or so make a promising start and I thought the premise was intriguing. After that, it falls flat on all levels. Pretentious, uninteresting one-dimensional characters check. Terribly written dialogue check. Ridiculous special effects check. The acting is atrocious, check that too. The sense of mystery is basically zero, probably because the viewer can't ignore the fact that everything takes place in a cheap TV set. And the worst part is that it goes on and on, and on for 3 hours. The only reason I kept watching was to see if maybe a good conclusion or some clever twist in the story line would save it somehow, but no. This movie is nothing more than the usual sci-fi clich&eacute;s piled up to the very end, while the production standards are beyond embarrassing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    ..and then...and then..and then...NOTHING!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Carol Mckinley
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    THIS REVIEW CONTAINS (MILD) SPOILERS! This is hands down the worst movie I have ever seen in my life. I've read through the first few pages of reviews left on this movie and to see glowing reviews over this steaming pile of crap is laughable. Really...did we watch the same movie? Imagine getting on a roller coaster. The longest, scariest, and highest roller coaster in the entire theme park. You buy the ticket, wait in line, and board the roller coaster. You get on the ride and go through dark tunnels, loops, and curves.....for hours. Although the ride is tiring, and the wait was long, you are still caught up in the anticipation. After all, the suspense is killing you, and with all this prolonged anticipation, surely this is going to be a hell of a ride, right? Now imagine getting to the peak of the roller coaster. Finally, you are at the highest point. You're ready. You waited so long. Now all of your waiting is going to finally pay off. You look down and see the fall...now you are excited. You prepare yourself for the adrenaline rush and excitement of finally getting to the best part..and then...........you are immediately let off the ride. That is the best way to describe this movie. It is probably the most disappointing thriller film that one could possibly waste hours out of their day watching. I HIGHLY warn that people understand that you WILL with out a doubt be disappointed to an extreme extent if you watch this movie. In fact, do yourself a favor, and if you do decide to watch this garbage, watch the first two hours of it and then turn it off and come to your own logical conclusion of what happened. I find it more comforting to think that Mr. Toomey or the equally irritating Dianne girl and/or boy were controlling the plane and preventing the passengers from making it to their proper dimension the entire time. Langoliers is often times given a second glance because of it's so called "original plot" (albeit the many loopholes) and suspense. The terrible effects are also often excused due to the fact that this was a "made for TV" movie. Bull. I've seen movies made in the 20s with better effects. Do not be deceived. There is nothing original about this plot. I point anyone who is interested to Twilight Zone episode "The Odyssey of Flight 33". The only difference between the two is a more coherent and concise plot from Rod Sterling, minus the ridiculous "character development" of otherwise ridiculous characters and Chomp Chomp Pac-men monsters that take three hours to make their grand debut. Suspense is the highest point of this movie as well as it's down fall. For several hours we do not see these "Langoliers" we can only "hear" them (and by "hear" them, I mean the snap, crackle, pop noise one would hear from pouring milk over Rice Krispie cereal) as well as the suspense of knowing that they could jump out at any moment. As a viewer when 95% of a film is suspense without even a view of the alleged monster, one would expect an even bigger climax. .......so what are the Langoliers? Who knows. We are never told exactly "what" they are or the relevancy these creatures have on the story. The Langoliers could be absent from this movie, and it would still make sense, scratch that, the movie would make MORE sense if the Langoliers were not included. Are the Langoliers fabricated from Mr. Toomey's mind and simply "boogeymen" from his childhood past? Who knows. Are they simply the eaters of time and space? Who knows. Are they a mixed breed of Tazmanian Devil and Pac Men? Seems likely.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Like A 3 hour long episode of "The Twilight Zone"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stubbers
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am currently reading "Four Past Midnight", the book of four Stephen King novellas which opens with "The Langoliers". I have just finished reading this story and immediately checked out the movie version. I wasn't disappointed. Something about this story, like many of King's, really touches a nerve. The quality is mainly in the basic concept rather than the sometimes-clunky dialogue. I like the idea of the past still existing physically, until it eventually becomes swallowed up by the Langoliers, the so-called Housekeepers of Eternity who hoover up the past to make way for the present. Incidentally, while reading the book I assumed the emphasis in the word was on the "o" - langOliers, to rhyme with magnolias. But no, the emphasis is on the "i" - langol-Iers, to rhyme with chandeliers. Either way, it's a strange word used to describe a very strange (but somehow not totally unfeasible) type of creature. Like all good "Twilight Zone" episodes, which this reminds me of, such a great underlying premise leaves a really strong, unnerving impression. As such, it doesn't matter so much that the acting and special effects aren't amazing. The atmosphere and plot are totally faithful to the original book. In a way, the slightly wooden, stilted acting suits the wooden, stilted world in which the characters find themselves. An airless, stuffy, oppressive world where you can barely light a match, where the wind either doesn't blow (according to the book), or else blows on the ground level but doesn't move the clouds (according to the movie, because they couldn't stop the wind blowing on location!). A world lying in the dumpster, slowly atrophying, thrown on the scrapheap by the constant forward motion of time's winged chariot. Always good to see Dean Stockwell, a man who is no stranger to travelling through time! Not his greatest ever performance here, but he certainly brings enigma to the part of writer Bob Jenkins. Bronson Pinchot brought just the right amount of creepy-but-sympathetic insanity to Craig Toomey, the dictionary definition of a loser in life, and a stark warning to what can happen to children later in life if they are belittled by their over-demanding parents. By comparison, David Morse as Captain Brian Engel was low-key and understated, but that was the exact impression I got of him from the book. If you were flying in an airplane through a rip in the space-time continuum, you would certainly want your pilot to be calm and unflappable! Unlike some posters here, I actually thought Mark Lindsay Chapman's Anglo-American accent was spot on. And I say this as a Brit who has spent considerable time in America. Out of necessity for being understood clearly and not sounding too "plum in mouth", Brits in the States have to slip in a few American sounding inflections here and there. So kudos to Chapman for a great, convincing performance as Americanised British secret agent Nick Popewell. I'd go so far as to say that his English accent was better than Harry Shearer's immortal Derek Smalls character (Spinal Tap). As for the ladies - well thumbs up for both Patricia Wettig and Kimber Riddle for certainly being very watchable, if not the most three-dimensional performances I have ever seen. And unlike many people here, I had no issues with Kate Maberly as blind Dinah. Finally, the effects of the Langoliers themselves. No problem! Once again, my image of them from reading the book was as funny sort of bouncing balls with teeth, which is more or less how they turned out on screen. These are not hi-tech computer generated monsters full of whizzbang explosions, they are like parasitic insects that feed off the scraps of the past. I don't see how they could have been better represented to be honest. So what we have here is a TV movie that transcends the limitations of its slightly second-rate format, by dint of the strength of the basic source material and the fact that they adhered to all the elements of the book. If it ain't broke, don't fix it. I'm sorry that not everyone enjoyed the movie, and I appreciate the negative comments it has received from some. For me it boils down to the concept of the Langoliers being something that really intrigued me, in a scary way, and I can't get enough of reading about them or watching them. For that reason, the movie gave me exactly what I was looking for.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Faithful Adaptation
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ramin99
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I watched about half of this abomination then fittingly enough dropped like a sack of potatoes after drinking god knows how many beers; I mean is it possible to watch such rubbish with all of your intellectual faculties intact? The bad acting, especially by the blind girl, the young guy and the hot girl (she was pleasing to the eyes so I guess that makes her bad acting excusable), and deciding whether or not she wore bras was about all I can remember from the film now. I am befuddled to read, by a good number of reviewers, the following paradox: "the book is good but this particular adaptation is bad. I am a huge fan of that writer but this film sucks!" A movie follows a script thus the source material of a film, is, its script. If the script is good then there is a fat chance the movie turns out good; but if bad no one can turn it into a masterpiece. Do you see my point? Please get your heads out of your ***** and see things for what they are! A few hours later I woke up dizzy with accompanying headache and a bad taste in my mouth, then sat down to write this review, so I'm grumpier/crankier than usual.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An intriguing King mystery hampered down in TV land
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    DAVID SIM
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Stephen King is the world's most prolific horror novelist. His success lies in his writing, and in the sheer volume of films and TV movies adapting his work. The Langoliers is one of several King mini-series we've seen in recent years. Adapted from a short story in King's novella Four Past Midnight, it represents one of King's occasional detours from horror and into science-fiction. The premise is something that could easily fill an episode of The Twilight Zone (in fact the plot reminded me more of The Lost Hour, an episode from TV's Eerie Indiana). Ten airline passengers fall asleep on a red-eye flight to Boston. During the flight, the plane flew through a time-rip and when it came out the other side, it catapulted the plane back in time by a day. The sleeping passengers were the only ones to emerge unharmed. All the ones that were awake just vanished into the ether. When they land the plane, the people on the ground have disappeared as well. Its a dead, lifeless world with no electricity and vigour, and what's worse is the Langoliers, monsters from one of the passenger's childhood stories are coming to gobble them up. I always felt The Langoliers was one that straddled an uneasy line between science-fiction and horror. When most authors try to tackle different genres at the same time they often wind up shortchanging one at the expense of the other, or even worse is that they cancel each other out. One suspects the way King wrote the story, it was originally a time-travel piece, but when it got to the airport scenes, he decided to include the Langoliers to give it a bit more dramatic intensity. Without it, he would have been left with a not too terribly gripping storyline. Fill the airplane with fuel. Backtrack to the time-rip. Fly through it. They get home. The Langoliers was directed by genre regular Tom Holland. Holland emerged in the 80s with two above average horror movies, Fright Night and Child's Play. But then into the 90s, he seemed to disappear into TV land, and vanished after that, much like one of the passengers on Flight 29. Fright Night and Child's Play showed Holland with a fine grasp of horror mechanics. But whether its because they were feature films or its just the slimness of King's material, his work on The Langoliers disappoints. Certainly it begins well. Once the passengers vanish from the plane, it makes for a highly absorbing mystery. But eventually, the story begins to drag. And its not exactly helped by the TV production values Holland is forced to work with. The Langoliers are given such an inscrutable buildup (in a nice touch we hear they're approach even when they're still miles away) that when they finally arrive, we're almost breathless with anticipation. But as soon as you see them, you're howling with laughter. They look like giant meatballs with teeth, and the TV special effects play out the scene embarrassingly. Where The Langoliers is more successful is in some of the characterisations. Dean Stockwell, David Morse and Mark Lindsay Chapman all give capable performances. Especially Chapman, an actor better known for playing smarmy snake in the grasses, but gives surprising sympathy to the part of a special operator with a chequered past. His wry, guarded performance makes his character Nick Hopewell into the most well developed member of the cast. Kate Maberly has some creepy moments as the blind girl who sees more than the people around her. But even creepier is Bronson Pinchot, giving a highly live-wire performance as Craig Toomey, the psycho in they're midst who knows all about Langoliers from the horror stories his father delighted in telling him as a child. With the rest of the story stifled by TV movie surroundings, he brings a welcome surge of energy whenever he's in it. The other survivors could have been written out altogether to no noticeable effect. It does get itself together for an effective, slightly tragic finale, but The Langoliers lacks the childhood terrors of IT, or the assured storytelling of The Shining. King has given Tom Holland a slim story to work with, so amongst the TV versions of his work, The Langoliers ranks as one of the more anonymous.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A mixed blessing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Neil Welch
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Stephen King's enjoyable novella about a planeload of passengers who, thanks to a very odd storm and a warp in space/time, find themselves stranded in an unpopulated and rapidly decaying version of their own world (because time has moved on into the future) is turned into a possibly over-long three-part TV miniseries. There is much to like here. The adaptation is moderately faithful, the casting and performances are good (Bronson Pinchot is a bit over the top, but that is a requirement of the character), and there are some nice production touches - the gradual de-saturisation of the colour works well to demonstrate what is happening. Not so good are the Langoliers themselves. They had to be a special effect, but they could have usefully consumed a bigger chunk of budget: they should be terrifying because of what they do but, unfortunately, they come across as rather comical. And, as I said, the thing is too long. Three hours is taken to tell a story which could have been told in half that time, and you'd have been on the edge of your seat all the way through.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Different Take On Time Travel.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Based on a Stephen King novel, this TV movie adaptation is about the passengers on a red-eye airplane flight from L.A to Boston who awaken to find that the rest of the passengers and crew are gone, and they are all alone on the plane, which will soon run out of fuel. Fortunately, there is a pilot on board, who tries to land the plane at a nearby airport, only to discover that it is also empty, and that they are being pursued by giant, howling monsters called Langoliers that seem to be devouring time itself... Potentially interesting take on time travel, with an appealing cast of characters(except Bronson Pinchot, quite good playing an obnoxious and terrified child-like man who knows all about the Langoliers from his hideous father.) cannot save far-fetched premise, and the primitive CGI Langoliers have not aged well... Still, not the worst way to kill three hours!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Spectacular Story!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    djk-930-38279
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love this movie so much! All of the sci-fi and mystery of it is exactly what I love in books and movies. In this feature, I first saw it on TV and then I read the book. The book is very good as well, but it gives out much more information, describes things in more detail, which in some ways is good, but for me, when it comes to the gore with Mr. Toomey, I would rather not know so much. So in that case, watching the movie is much more preferred than reading it in the book. I gave this movie a 9 because I love it so much, but I just have one problem with it. There was some especially terrible acting, mostly by Christopher Collet who played Albert Kaussner. In many instances, he would overact his lines, and/or his lines were just written very poorly for him. I think for the most part though, the other main characters did pretty well. Not the best acting, but it was good.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Most interesting TV adaptation of S. King's work
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sang Park
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I just didn't give higher vote just because of the low budget and the poor F/X alloted to this movie. I have full understanding that this is low budget TV movie. But I could resist watching it because I had such high expectation in David Morse and Dean Stockwell. Enough with background of my watching movie.. First I didn't realize that this movie is 3 hours long... Maybe when they aired on TV they could have broken into series, but I've watched this on Netflix as one piece and it is longer movie than the lord of the rings. But as others put it, the length was due to the faithful adaptation of the original novel. No jumps or gaps in plots. Whenever there requires some explanation, Dean Stockwell slides in exuberantly and fulfills duties (he is supposed to be the avatar of S. King in the movie). I too have some pet peeve on the crappy F/X (really cheesy C.G.), but the reaction of actors actress are good enough to convince me that the monsters are there creeping in. All the settings and actings are good enough to make me get the creeps from what is going on in the movie. (FYI, I am a seasoned pseudo-professional monster/scary movie tester). When compared with "Stand", I think this is descent TV movie and I enjoyed pretty much.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    bad acting...bad FX....but still an excellent TV movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    supreme_mamu
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Some people says that acting and FX are the main purpose in creating a good movie, but here, it was proved wrong. I have to admit that this movie are full of characters with bad acting, i mean all of them (except for Bronson Pinchot who gave an excellent performance as mad guy Mr Craig Toomey). But the worst goes to the little girl, the blind little girl who does not have any emotional feelings and not really up to the standard to what audience always wanted. And the FX is quite poor and cheesy, seems to be cartoons. It really looks funny to me! I wish it could be better in order to turn this into a great movie. But, none of these really affect the greatness of The Langoliers. The main purpose of why this movie is created is because of the storyline, the story written by the master of horror, Stephen King. And, the story are almost exactly accurate to the short story in 4 Past Midnight. The way the story tell us is very entertaining, until I didn't really focus myself on the acting and the FX. It is the story which keep me thinking and wait for what is going to happen at the end of the story. Even though the movie is 3 hours long, but it doesn't make me feel boring because the suspend is there. I'm gonna watch this movie again for the 10th times this afternoon :) forget about the acting and the FX, concentrate on the storyline! excellent (10/10 stars)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Amazingly bad
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    CinefanR
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Everything is this movie is painfully bad- acting, story-line, script, special effects. It's true that my expectations were high. I've heard a lot about Stephen King and I imagined that such a celebrated writer would come up with something brilliant and original. I was expecting to see a spark of genius from the so-called "master of horror". Boy, was I wrong... The first 10 minutes or so make a promising start and I thought the premise was intriguing. After that, it falls flat on all levels. Pretentious, uninteresting one-dimensional characters check. Terribly written dialogue check. Ridiculous special effects check. The acting is atrocious, check that too. The sense of mystery is basically zero, probably because the viewer can't ignore the fact that everything takes place in a cheap TV set. And the worst part is that it goes on and on, and on for 3 hours. The only reason I kept watching was to see if maybe a good conclusion or some clever twist in the story line would save it somehow, but no. This movie is nothing more than the usual sci-fi clich&eacute;s piled up to the very end, while the production standards are beyond embarrassing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    ..and then...and then..and then...NOTHING!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Carol Mckinley
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    THIS REVIEW CONTAINS (MILD) SPOILERS! This is hands down the worst movie I have ever seen in my life. I've read through the first few pages of reviews left on this movie and to see glowing reviews over this steaming pile of crap is laughable. Really...did we watch the same movie? Imagine getting on a roller coaster. The longest, scariest, and highest roller coaster in the entire theme park. You buy the ticket, wait in line, and board the roller coaster. You get on the ride and go through dark tunnels, loops, and curves.....for hours. Although the ride is tiring, and the wait was long, you are still caught up in the anticipation. After all, the suspense is killing you, and with all this prolonged anticipation, surely this is going to be a hell of a ride, right? Now imagine getting to the peak of the roller coaster. Finally, you are at the highest point. You're ready. You waited so long. Now all of your waiting is going to finally pay off. You look down and see the fall...now you are excited. You prepare yourself for the adrenaline rush and excitement of finally getting to the best part..and then...........you are immediately let off the ride. That is the best way to describe this movie. It is probably the most disappointing thriller film that one could possibly waste hours out of their day watching. I HIGHLY warn that people understand that you WILL with out a doubt be disappointed to an extreme extent if you watch this movie. In fact, do yourself a favor, and if you do decide to watch this garbage, watch the first two hours of it and then turn it off and come to your own logical conclusion of what happened. I find it more comforting to think that Mr. Toomey or the equally irritating Dianne girl and/or boy were controlling the plane and preventing the passengers from making it to their proper dimension the entire time. Langoliers is often times given a second glance because of it's so called "original plot" (albeit the many loopholes) and suspense. The terrible effects are also often excused due to the fact that this was a "made for TV" movie. Bull. I've seen movies made in the 20s with better effects. Do not be deceived. There is nothing original about this plot. I point anyone who is interested to Twilight Zone episode "The Odyssey of Flight 33". The only difference between the two is a more coherent and concise plot from Rod Sterling, minus the ridiculous "character development" of otherwise ridiculous characters and Chomp Chomp Pac-men monsters that take three hours to make their grand debut. Suspense is the highest point of this movie as well as it's down fall. For several hours we do not see these "Langoliers" we can only "hear" them (and by "hear" them, I mean the snap, crackle, pop noise one would hear from pouring milk over Rice Krispie cereal) as well as the suspense of knowing that they could jump out at any moment. As a viewer when 95% of a film is suspense without even a view of the alleged monster, one would expect an even bigger climax. .......so what are the Langoliers? Who knows. We are never told exactly "what" they are or the relevancy these creatures have on the story. The Langoliers could be absent from this movie, and it would still make sense, scratch that, the movie would make MORE sense if the Langoliers were not included. Are the Langoliers fabricated from Mr. Toomey's mind and simply "boogeymen" from his childhood past? Who knows. Are they simply the eaters of time and space? Who knows. Are they a mixed breed of Tazmanian Devil and Pac Men? Seems likely.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Like A 3 hour long episode of "The Twilight Zone"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stubbers
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am currently reading "Four Past Midnight", the book of four Stephen King novellas which opens with "The Langoliers". I have just finished reading this story and immediately checked out the movie version. I wasn't disappointed. Something about this story, like many of King's, really touches a nerve. The quality is mainly in the basic concept rather than the sometimes-clunky dialogue. I like the idea of the past still existing physically, until it eventually becomes swallowed up by the Langoliers, the so-called Housekeepers of Eternity who hoover up the past to make way for the present. Incidentally, while reading the book I assumed the emphasis in the word was on the "o" - langOliers, to rhyme with magnolias. But no, the emphasis is on the "i" - langol-Iers, to rhyme with chandeliers. Either way, it's a strange word used to describe a very strange (but somehow not totally unfeasible) type of creature. Like all good "Twilight Zone" episodes, which this reminds me of, such a great underlying premise leaves a really strong, unnerving impression. As such, it doesn't matter so much that the acting and special effects aren't amazing. The atmosphere and plot are totally faithful to the original book. In a way, the slightly wooden, stilted acting suits the wooden, stilted world in which the characters find themselves. An airless, stuffy, oppressive world where you can barely light a match, where the wind either doesn't blow (according to the book), or else blows on the ground level but doesn't move the clouds (according to the movie, because they couldn't stop the wind blowing on location!). A world lying in the dumpster, slowly atrophying, thrown on the scrapheap by the constant forward motion of time's winged chariot. Always good to see Dean Stockwell, a man who is no stranger to travelling through time! Not his greatest ever performance here, but he certainly brings enigma to the part of writer Bob Jenkins. Bronson Pinchot brought just the right amount of creepy-but-sympathetic insanity to Craig Toomey, the dictionary definition of a loser in life, and a stark warning to what can happen to children later in life if they are belittled by their over-demanding parents. By comparison, David Morse as Captain Brian Engel was low-key and understated, but that was the exact impression I got of him from the book. If you were flying in an airplane through a rip in the space-time continuum, you would certainly want your pilot to be calm and unflappable! Unlike some posters here, I actually thought Mark Lindsay Chapman's Anglo-American accent was spot on. And I say this as a Brit who has spent considerable time in America. Out of necessity for being understood clearly and not sounding too "plum in mouth", Brits in the States have to slip in a few American sounding inflections here and there. So kudos to Chapman for a great, convincing performance as Americanised British secret agent Nick Popewell. I'd go so far as to say that his English accent was better than Harry Shearer's immortal Derek Smalls character (Spinal Tap). As for the ladies - well thumbs up for both Patricia Wettig and Kimber Riddle for certainly being very watchable, if not the most three-dimensional performances I have ever seen. And unlike many people here, I had no issues with Kate Maberly as blind Dinah. Finally, the effects of the Langoliers themselves. No problem! Once again, my image of them from reading the book was as funny sort of bouncing balls with teeth, which is more or less how they turned out on screen. These are not hi-tech computer generated monsters full of whizzbang explosions, they are like parasitic insects that feed off the scraps of the past. I don't see how they could have been better represented to be honest. So what we have here is a TV movie that transcends the limitations of its slightly second-rate format, by dint of the strength of the basic source material and the fact that they adhered to all the elements of the book. If it ain't broke, don't fix it. I'm sorry that not everyone enjoyed the movie, and I appreciate the negative comments it has received from some. For me it boils down to the concept of the Langoliers being something that really intrigued me, in a scary way, and I can't get enough of reading about them or watching them. For that reason, the movie gave me exactly what I was looking for.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Faithful Adaptation
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ramin99
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I watched about half of this abomination then fittingly enough dropped like a sack of potatoes after drinking god knows how many beers; I mean is it possible to watch such rubbish with all of your intellectual faculties intact? The bad acting, especially by the blind girl, the young guy and the hot girl (she was pleasing to the eyes so I guess that makes her bad acting excusable), and deciding whether or not she wore bras was about all I can remember from the film now. I am befuddled to read, by a good number of reviewers, the following paradox: "the book is good but this particular adaptation is bad. I am a huge fan of that writer but this film sucks!" A movie follows a script thus the source material of a film, is, its script. If the script is good then there is a fat chance the movie turns out good; but if bad no one can turn it into a masterpiece. Do you see my point? Please get your heads out of your ***** and see things for what they are! A few hours later I woke up dizzy with accompanying headache and a bad taste in my mouth, then sat down to write this review, so I'm grumpier/crankier than usual.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An intriguing King mystery hampered down in TV land
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    DAVID SIM
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Stephen King is the world's most prolific horror novelist. His success lies in his writing, and in the sheer volume of films and TV movies adapting his work. The Langoliers is one of several King mini-series we've seen in recent years. Adapted from a short story in King's novella Four Past Midnight, it represents one of King's occasional detours from horror and into science-fiction. The premise is something that could easily fill an episode of The Twilight Zone (in fact the plot reminded me more of The Lost Hour, an episode from TV's Eerie Indiana). Ten airline passengers fall asleep on a red-eye flight to Boston. During the flight, the plane flew through a time-rip and when it came out the other side, it catapulted the plane back in time by a day. The sleeping passengers were the only ones to emerge unharmed. All the ones that were awake just vanished into the ether. When they land the plane, the people on the ground have disappeared as well. Its a dead, lifeless world with no electricity and vigour, and what's worse is the Langoliers, monsters from one of the passenger's childhood stories are coming to gobble them up. I always felt The Langoliers was one that straddled an uneasy line between science-fiction and horror. When most authors try to tackle different genres at the same time they often wind up shortchanging one at the expense of the other, or even worse is that they cancel each other out. One suspects the way King wrote the story, it was originally a time-travel piece, but when it got to the airport scenes, he decided to include the Langoliers to give it a bit more dramatic intensity. Without it, he would have been left with a not too terribly gripping storyline. Fill the airplane with fuel. Backtrack to the time-rip. Fly through it. They get home. The Langoliers was directed by genre regular Tom Holland. Holland emerged in the 80s with two above average horror movies, Fright Night and Child's Play. But then into the 90s, he seemed to disappear into TV land, and vanished after that, much like one of the passengers on Flight 29. Fright Night and Child's Play showed Holland with a fine grasp of horror mechanics. But whether its because they were feature films or its just the slimness of King's material, his work on The Langoliers disappoints. Certainly it begins well. Once the passengers vanish from the plane, it makes for a highly absorbing mystery. But eventually, the story begins to drag. And its not exactly helped by the TV production values Holland is forced to work with. The Langoliers are given such an inscrutable buildup (in a nice touch we hear they're approach even when they're still miles away) that when they finally arrive, we're almost breathless with anticipation. But as soon as you see them, you're howling with laughter. They look like giant meatballs with teeth, and the TV special effects play out the scene embarrassingly. Where The Langoliers is more successful is in some of the characterisations. Dean Stockwell, David Morse and Mark Lindsay Chapman all give capable performances. Especially Chapman, an actor better known for playing smarmy snake in the grasses, but gives surprising sympathy to the part of a special operator with a chequered past. His wry, guarded performance makes his character Nick Hopewell into the most well developed member of the cast. Kate Maberly has some creepy moments as the blind girl who sees more than the people around her. But even creepier is Bronson Pinchot, giving a highly live-wire performance as Craig Toomey, the psycho in they're midst who knows all about Langoliers from the horror stories his father delighted in telling him as a child. With the rest of the story stifled by TV movie surroundings, he brings a welcome surge of energy whenever he's in it. The other survivors could have been written out altogether to no noticeable effect. It does get itself together for an effective, slightly tragic finale, but The Langoliers lacks the childhood terrors of IT, or the assured storytelling of The Shining. King has given Tom Holland a slim story to work with, so amongst the TV versions of his work, The Langoliers ranks as one of the more anonymous.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A mixed blessing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Neil Welch
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Stephen King's enjoyable novella about a planeload of passengers who, thanks to a very odd storm and a warp in space/time, find themselves stranded in an unpopulated and rapidly decaying version of their own world (because time has moved on into the future) is turned into a possibly over-long three-part TV miniseries. There is much to like here. The adaptation is moderately faithful, the casting and performances are good (Bronson Pinchot is a bit over the top, but that is a requirement of the character), and there are some nice production touches - the gradual de-saturisation of the colour works well to demonstrate what is happening. Not so good are the Langoliers themselves. They had to be a special effect, but they could have usefully consumed a bigger chunk of budget: they should be terrifying because of what they do but, unfortunately, they come across as rather comical. And, as I said, the thing is too long. Three hours is taken to tell a story which could have been told in half that time, and you'd have been on the edge of your seat all the way through.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
