<filme>
 <id>
  564
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0114609
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1995
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Tales from the Hood
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  5.8
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  A strange funeral director tells four strange tales of horror with an African American focus to three drug dealers he traps in his place of business.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Four short, moralistic horror vignettes (a la EC Comics) that deal with mostly black characters. The framing story introduces three youths out to pick up a drug shipment at a funeral parlor from the strange director, Mr. Simms. As the three punks wind their way through the parlor, Mr. Simms tells them the last stories of some of his more interesting clients.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Horror
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Thriller
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   drugs
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   african american
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   death
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   funeral home
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   police
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Rusty Cundieff
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Rusty Cundieff
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Darin Scott
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Clarence Williams III
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Corbin Bernsen
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Joe Torry
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Enjoyable, quirky vignette horror. Worth investigating
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cjmccracken
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Vignette Horror is one of my favourite types, it's not just the accessibility of the format, but the deftness and wit that is required to create a sequence of short stories usually bypasses the problems which certain horror films have in terms of an overstayed welcome. The structure used in Tales From The Hood is the classic one which was perfected by the Amicus and Hammer studios in the 1960′s and 1970′s, only minus Joan Collins. The 'cryptkeeper' in this case is played by Clarence Williams III, who is a drastically underused actor and always a delight to see on screen. He draws the attention of three local gangstas through the promise of a large amount of drugs which have come into his possession. The catch being that they must first listen to him tell several stories relating to the bodies which currently lie displayed within his funeral home. It only has a running time of 98 minutes which is part of the reason why it is so successful and enjoyable. I am very much of the opinion that a great deal of horror movies now unnecessarily approach the 120 minute (and beyond) when they could have been infinitely more successful if shortened. There are four stories on show here, each relating to a particular hardship or struggle faced by the African American communities of the early 1990′s. It's important to remember that this was an America which was still sore after the chaos of the LA Riots and the exposure of a crooked police force through the Rodney King videotape leak. Once you see that Spike Lee was drafted in as an executive producer, the social elements of the movie become contextualised to a greater extent. The topics of the cautionary tales cover areas such as police brutality and racism withing law enforcement (Rogue Cop Revelation), domestic abuse against women and children (Boys Do Get Bruised), racism within politics (KKK Comeuppance) and the futility of gang culture and the violence it creates (Hard Core Convert). All are delivered with a supernatural twist which places the movie strongly into the horror genre and making it not only groundbreaking, unique for it's time, but also helps it to maintain a strength when watched today. I was aware of the soundtrack before I was aware of the film itself as it was given to me shortly after its release in 1995, it would be a couple of years before I was able to track down a VHS copy. The OST features some fantastic tracks by Gravediggaz, Wu Tang Clan and a brilliant Ol Dirty Bastard track and is well worth locating a copy of. When one considers the depths to which 'hood' based horror movies became after this ('Snoop Dogg's Hood of Horror' and 'Leprechaun back 2 Da Hood' being just two examples), it is all the more reason to revisit Tales From the Hood. There's something about it which will greatly appeal to a certain horror fan, particularly those fond of the genre output of the early 90′s. I'd tell you to go to your local video store to acquire a copy, but there probably isn't even one left in your town. Get it whatever way you can, you won't regret it. Read more at zombiehamster.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the better horror anthologies
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Matt Kracht (krachtm@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Yes, it's flawed, and it's cheesy, and it's over-the-top. It's equal parts clever satire, straight-up homage, and occasionally even a parody. There are many horror, exploitation, and black humor elements sprinkled throughout the movie. I just can't understand why this movie isn't beloved by more people. Maybe it's because the cast is mostly black, and the stories revolve around inner city, black youth? Well, as a white guy from the suburbs, I absolutely loved this movie. It's flawed, of course, but when it works, it works better than most other movies of this type. If you're not familiar with it, this is a horror anthology highly influenced by Tales from the Crypt, an old 50s horror comic book series that birthed several spin-off movies and an influential TV series. It also takes ample inspiration from the Twilight Zone, Tales from the Dark Side, and Creepshow franchises. If you're a fan of any of these, I'd have to highly recommend Tales from the Hood, especially if you're also into Blaxploitation, from which it also takes some inspiration. In the time honored tradition of horror/exploitation movies everywhere, the guilty are punished with gory deaths and lessons are learned (frequently too late). Is it preachy, didactic social satire? Perhaps, at times. But it's also entertaining as hell. It has a great cast, some really cheesy, over-top-the-top acting, and was produced by Spike Lee. For me, that makes it almost required viewing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    your own private mortality
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A tribute to movies like "Dr. Terror's House of Horrors" and "Tales from the Crypt", "Tales from the Hood" presents some horror vignettes centering on life in the black ghetto. Some drug dealers go to a funeral home to pick up their "s**t", only to have the eccentric owner (Clarence Williams III) tell them about the fates of some recent customers...with a twist at the end. At once a fun horror flick and also warning about getting mixed up with the wrong people, this is a cool one. A particular scene in the fourth vignette appears to be a tribute to "A Clockwork Orange". All in all, a real credit for director Rusty Cundieff and executive producer Spike Lee. Featuring Tom Wright (the hitchhiker in "Creepshow 2"), David Alan Grier, Corbin Bernsen and Rosalind Cash (in her final role).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Rented this for the first time at age 15, own it now, very enjoyable for any horror fan
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tbald1980-1 (tbald1980@aol.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I wrote a review for this on Amazon a couple years ago, I figured I'd do one here as well. The first time I saw this, I expected a comedy, boy! I was dead wrong! To be honest, the first two stories were so freaky, I had my mom turn it off. Obviously, I'm a lot harder to scare now and like it overall, despite the constant language. It's kind of a social commentary with realism and supernatural overtones mixed together. This was my first horror anthology, followed by several others It's got a decent script, even though some will say 'I've seen all this before' but to me, clich&eacute;d doesn't have to mean bad, if the right people are in it/behind and in front of the camera, this was also my first Spike Lee film, so I won't judge it on those merits. I know he didn't direct it, but I've heard about a lot of his movies, some look pretty good. By the way, I'm not black either, but I have a large amount of respect for them. I'm getting off track here, bottom line: if you like horror stories with some semblance of reality, you'll probably enjoy this too, but you'll have to overlook the language.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    you might just want to skip to the last one
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    marymorrissey
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For all but the last vignette this movie seems to be the occasion for lots and lots of gleeful indulgence in pretty disgusting racist profanity and other really offensive material - eg the violence at home chez monster in the closet which was really really over the top and next to nauseating and all the stuff that comes out of "duke's" mouth as he's chased around by the little dolls. there are lots and lots of roles of the sort that black actors really hate to play and constantly complain of being stuck with the 2 exceptions being those in which CW III and Roger GS are cast, both of them being a little too classy to offer any of the other negative-stereotypical central casting black roles that comprise the rest of the film. The white actors in this film, actually, are subjected to that sort of casting that blacks have to put up with lol so that's kind of funny. Poor Corbin Bernsen not that LA Law was such a great height to fall from but still . . . But it's OK ya dig cause it's directed by a black guy and co written by him with a white guy (let's sing together now, "ebony... and ivory..." etc) Well, it all sort of makes sense when you see the producer is spike lee, and so . . . I mean basically it has the same problem as the other spike lee films I've seen in that it's fundamentally separatist and whites and blacks can both enjoy making boogie men of each other in this movie. lucky audience eh? makes very strange viewing. The last story, though, was pretty cool though and sort of a tour de force all around, even if it was a copy of another film it was certainly freshened up. I would like to see its equivalent in Gay Cinema which is so full of us vs them BS. It was really cute how they made use of CWII's gap tooth smile :) This is a really tough one to rate so I'll give it a 7!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rpattz3000
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As Mr.Simms says......ahhh....the s***. I really liked this movie.When I first saw this movie I was 15 yrs old and it scared the crap out of me.Especially the first story where those cops beat up Mr.Moorhouse and drove him to the deck and the cops put him in his car and drove his car into the water after they had over dosed him with drugs and after that he was calling out for Clarence to bring the cops to him and when the police came and that one cop whizzed on Moorhouses grave and he made his other partner whiz on the grave too and Moorhouse grabbed the cop and pulled him in the grave and tore his heart out and they showed Moorehouse standing there holding the cops beating heart and then he went after those other 2 cops.I didn't sleep for 2 weeks.I kept thinking I was gonna see Moorhouse standing over my bed or something when I woke up.I liked the story about the the boy who was being abused by his step dad and he said his step dad was a monster.And the one about the dolls was good too.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A superb mid-90's horror anthology tale with macabre humor and confronting topics
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (Vomitron_G)
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I had to wait more than 10 years to finally see this one. Not one single copy seemed to be available over here in Europe. That was until 2007, when I finally got my hands on a Region 1 DVD copy. If you like anthology movies, then you have no excuse for not seeing this one. One of the best anthology movies of the 90's (it's up there with "Tales From The Dark Side: The Movie" and "Necronomicon", if you ask me). And probably the best horror movie from the hood with a nearly all Afro-American cast ever made (because I can't really say I've ever seen a ghetto-horror flick that was actually any good). Three hood-rats, out to collect some 'shiiit', visit a freaky coroner who tells them 4 terrifying tales of the supernatural. The first tale is about three corrupt white cops who had it coming... Wings Hauser is especially enjoyable in this one. He already evoked my interest at the time after having seen his enjoyable performance in "Night Shadows" (AKA "Mutant"). And by know I simply love the man. Second story is about a boy and his bruises, which are being caused by... a monster supposedly living in his house. Great and fascinating conclusion this one had. The third tale has some killer-puppet action going on in it of which Charles Band could easily be very jealous. Corbin"The Dentist"Bernsen stars in this segment that revolves around voodoo and slavery. The fourth and last segment gives a big nod to Kubrick's "A Clockwork Orange". Enough said about that one. The wrap-around story wraps it all up nicely, and has a very satisfying conclusion. "Tales From The Hood" is actually more than 'just a horror movie'. With Spike Lee being executive producer, you can rightfully expect that this movie will carry important themes & topics like racism, politics, police brutality, guilt, child abuse, brothers killing brothers, etc. The message always comes across, but possible statements & points of view never become too dominant. This film's primary goal is to entertain a horror audience. And it splendidly succeeds in that. The filmmakers also clearly know the rules of the horror-anthology-genre as well as the tricks of the trade, all to great success. Need I even say that the make-up and special effects are darn excellent too? The tales from this hood, are all winners.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A poor rip-off
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    doomchild-635-982234
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/1/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    i watched this movie from start to finish with a few of my friends and i have to say that is a horrible movie. Before anyone says that i am racist i want you to know that i am not. This movie had very poor acting, the stories were very dull, and the ending was a direct rip-off of the ending of the classic Tales From the Crypt. I am sorry but the only thing i could do while i was watching this film was laugh, and not in a good way like with Blood Feast, i was laughing in a way that was saying that it was one of the worst films that i ever saw. I understand that the movie is trying to say some sort of message but come on it is just way to generic. If you want a good film that tells short stories I would recommend Tales From the Crypt, Vault of Horror, Creepshow (both 1 & 2), and Tales From the Darkside,and skip this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A really good movie!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Noakk
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/2/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm not going to add much, since most has been said already. I just wanted to state that I really enjoyed this movie. It not only pays a good homage to the classic EC comics (or at least the adapted early movie versions or series) but it manages to portray profound messages in a very powerful manner. The effects are pretty good as well and there's some nice gore so horror fans should be satisfied. I think that it's really one of the few movies that successfully combine horror and moral. The soundtrack is also very good - This movie was made in 95' - a time where hip hop in my opinion had reached it's highest point. So it's definitely worth a look!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A little racist but the morals are good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    KHayes666
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As a white American, I view this movie a lot differently than its intended audience...lemme tell you why. The movie is basically a Tales From the Crypt like setting with a black cultured twist. It starts off with 3 homeboys checking out "the shyt" from a mortician (played brilliantly by Clarence Williams the 3rd who ironically was in an episode of Tales From the Crypt years earlier). The mortician then tells 4 tales centered around real life issues. Tale 1 is about 3 white cops who murder a black politician while a rookie black cop looks on. A year later the politician rises from the grave to extract revenge. Its your basic police brutality and one of the weaker stories because its not very realistic, which I thought this movie was supposed to be. Tale 2 is the second best in my opinion. A child on the first day of school is examined by his teacher to find bruises all over him, he claims the "monster" at home did it. This one centers around child abuse with the awesome moral that there are monsters in real life, just not in the form everyone thinks. Tale 3 is another weak one but Corbin Bernsen is the man, he absolutely rules so I refuse to hate it no matter how absurd it is. This one's about a former KKK member who's moving into a mansion that was once the sight of a brutal slave massacre back in the civil war days. Once he move in the ghosts of the pasts haunt him and his associate to drive home the fact that someone always pays for the sins of the past. I don't know whether it was a casting goof, but Corbin's associate was a black man so if he was a racist then why would he choose this guy as a partner? The whole dolls come to life idea is another cheesy idea (coming off about 5 Puppet Master and Child's Play movies) and if anyone else was playing the role, I would have hit the fast forward button. Tale 4 is my personal favorite...it involves a young black gangster who will kill everyone and anyone with no remorse or fear. After murdering some homeboy, the cops catch him and throw him in jail. This is where he meets a white supremacist who thanks him for "doing his job for him." which leads to one of the most sickest, eye opening montages in film history. Basically the moral is, what's the difference between white lynch mobs of the 19th and 20th century and gang bangers from today? Gang violence is murder any way you look at it, and it doesn't matter if the parties are black or white, people suffer and die just the same. The film is done incredibly well but it does portray the white race as the bad guys with all the characters being racist (3 cops, politician, prisoner in the cell), but I guess that's payback for all the black characters being petty thugs and thieves in the Dirty Harry series. The tales themselves offer morals that people in every day life deal with, whether it was cheesy or not. Child abuse, crooked cops, corrupt politicians and gang warfare are an unfortunate but very real situations that this movie shines the light on beautifully. I won't give away the ending but Clarence Williams is the man of the hour and the one with the power, too sweet to be sour. I guess the highlight for me was when Corbin Bernsen calls the media "spooky reporters" 7 out of 10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Enjoyable, quirky vignette horror. Worth investigating
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cjmccracken
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Vignette Horror is one of my favourite types, it's not just the accessibility of the format, but the deftness and wit that is required to create a sequence of short stories usually bypasses the problems which certain horror films have in terms of an overstayed welcome. The structure used in Tales From The Hood is the classic one which was perfected by the Amicus and Hammer studios in the 1960′s and 1970′s, only minus Joan Collins. The 'cryptkeeper' in this case is played by Clarence Williams III, who is a drastically underused actor and always a delight to see on screen. He draws the attention of three local gangstas through the promise of a large amount of drugs which have come into his possession. The catch being that they must first listen to him tell several stories relating to the bodies which currently lie displayed within his funeral home. It only has a running time of 98 minutes which is part of the reason why it is so successful and enjoyable. I am very much of the opinion that a great deal of horror movies now unnecessarily approach the 120 minute (and beyond) when they could have been infinitely more successful if shortened. There are four stories on show here, each relating to a particular hardship or struggle faced by the African American communities of the early 1990′s. It's important to remember that this was an America which was still sore after the chaos of the LA Riots and the exposure of a crooked police force through the Rodney King videotape leak. Once you see that Spike Lee was drafted in as an executive producer, the social elements of the movie become contextualised to a greater extent. The topics of the cautionary tales cover areas such as police brutality and racism withing law enforcement (Rogue Cop Revelation), domestic abuse against women and children (Boys Do Get Bruised), racism within politics (KKK Comeuppance) and the futility of gang culture and the violence it creates (Hard Core Convert). All are delivered with a supernatural twist which places the movie strongly into the horror genre and making it not only groundbreaking, unique for it's time, but also helps it to maintain a strength when watched today. I was aware of the soundtrack before I was aware of the film itself as it was given to me shortly after its release in 1995, it would be a couple of years before I was able to track down a VHS copy. The OST features some fantastic tracks by Gravediggaz, Wu Tang Clan and a brilliant Ol Dirty Bastard track and is well worth locating a copy of. When one considers the depths to which 'hood' based horror movies became after this ('Snoop Dogg's Hood of Horror' and 'Leprechaun back 2 Da Hood' being just two examples), it is all the more reason to revisit Tales From the Hood. There's something about it which will greatly appeal to a certain horror fan, particularly those fond of the genre output of the early 90′s. I'd tell you to go to your local video store to acquire a copy, but there probably isn't even one left in your town. Get it whatever way you can, you won't regret it. Read more at zombiehamster.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the better horror anthologies
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Matt Kracht (krachtm@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Yes, it's flawed, and it's cheesy, and it's over-the-top. It's equal parts clever satire, straight-up homage, and occasionally even a parody. There are many horror, exploitation, and black humor elements sprinkled throughout the movie. I just can't understand why this movie isn't beloved by more people. Maybe it's because the cast is mostly black, and the stories revolve around inner city, black youth? Well, as a white guy from the suburbs, I absolutely loved this movie. It's flawed, of course, but when it works, it works better than most other movies of this type. If you're not familiar with it, this is a horror anthology highly influenced by Tales from the Crypt, an old 50s horror comic book series that birthed several spin-off movies and an influential TV series. It also takes ample inspiration from the Twilight Zone, Tales from the Dark Side, and Creepshow franchises. If you're a fan of any of these, I'd have to highly recommend Tales from the Hood, especially if you're also into Blaxploitation, from which it also takes some inspiration. In the time honored tradition of horror/exploitation movies everywhere, the guilty are punished with gory deaths and lessons are learned (frequently too late). Is it preachy, didactic social satire? Perhaps, at times. But it's also entertaining as hell. It has a great cast, some really cheesy, over-top-the-top acting, and was produced by Spike Lee. For me, that makes it almost required viewing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    your own private mortality
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A tribute to movies like "Dr. Terror's House of Horrors" and "Tales from the Crypt", "Tales from the Hood" presents some horror vignettes centering on life in the black ghetto. Some drug dealers go to a funeral home to pick up their "s**t", only to have the eccentric owner (Clarence Williams III) tell them about the fates of some recent customers...with a twist at the end. At once a fun horror flick and also warning about getting mixed up with the wrong people, this is a cool one. A particular scene in the fourth vignette appears to be a tribute to "A Clockwork Orange". All in all, a real credit for director Rusty Cundieff and executive producer Spike Lee. Featuring Tom Wright (the hitchhiker in "Creepshow 2"), David Alan Grier, Corbin Bernsen and Rosalind Cash (in her final role).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Rented this for the first time at age 15, own it now, very enjoyable for any horror fan
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tbald1980-1 (tbald1980@aol.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I wrote a review for this on Amazon a couple years ago, I figured I'd do one here as well. The first time I saw this, I expected a comedy, boy! I was dead wrong! To be honest, the first two stories were so freaky, I had my mom turn it off. Obviously, I'm a lot harder to scare now and like it overall, despite the constant language. It's kind of a social commentary with realism and supernatural overtones mixed together. This was my first horror anthology, followed by several others It's got a decent script, even though some will say 'I've seen all this before' but to me, clich&eacute;d doesn't have to mean bad, if the right people are in it/behind and in front of the camera, this was also my first Spike Lee film, so I won't judge it on those merits. I know he didn't direct it, but I've heard about a lot of his movies, some look pretty good. By the way, I'm not black either, but I have a large amount of respect for them. I'm getting off track here, bottom line: if you like horror stories with some semblance of reality, you'll probably enjoy this too, but you'll have to overlook the language.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    you might just want to skip to the last one
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    marymorrissey
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For all but the last vignette this movie seems to be the occasion for lots and lots of gleeful indulgence in pretty disgusting racist profanity and other really offensive material - eg the violence at home chez monster in the closet which was really really over the top and next to nauseating and all the stuff that comes out of "duke's" mouth as he's chased around by the little dolls. there are lots and lots of roles of the sort that black actors really hate to play and constantly complain of being stuck with the 2 exceptions being those in which CW III and Roger GS are cast, both of them being a little too classy to offer any of the other negative-stereotypical central casting black roles that comprise the rest of the film. The white actors in this film, actually, are subjected to that sort of casting that blacks have to put up with lol so that's kind of funny. Poor Corbin Bernsen not that LA Law was such a great height to fall from but still . . . But it's OK ya dig cause it's directed by a black guy and co written by him with a white guy (let's sing together now, "ebony... and ivory..." etc) Well, it all sort of makes sense when you see the producer is spike lee, and so . . . I mean basically it has the same problem as the other spike lee films I've seen in that it's fundamentally separatist and whites and blacks can both enjoy making boogie men of each other in this movie. lucky audience eh? makes very strange viewing. The last story, though, was pretty cool though and sort of a tour de force all around, even if it was a copy of another film it was certainly freshened up. I would like to see its equivalent in Gay Cinema which is so full of us vs them BS. It was really cute how they made use of CWII's gap tooth smile :) This is a really tough one to rate so I'll give it a 7!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rpattz3000
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As Mr.Simms says......ahhh....the s***. I really liked this movie.When I first saw this movie I was 15 yrs old and it scared the crap out of me.Especially the first story where those cops beat up Mr.Moorhouse and drove him to the deck and the cops put him in his car and drove his car into the water after they had over dosed him with drugs and after that he was calling out for Clarence to bring the cops to him and when the police came and that one cop whizzed on Moorhouses grave and he made his other partner whiz on the grave too and Moorhouse grabbed the cop and pulled him in the grave and tore his heart out and they showed Moorehouse standing there holding the cops beating heart and then he went after those other 2 cops.I didn't sleep for 2 weeks.I kept thinking I was gonna see Moorhouse standing over my bed or something when I woke up.I liked the story about the the boy who was being abused by his step dad and he said his step dad was a monster.And the one about the dolls was good too.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A superb mid-90's horror anthology tale with macabre humor and confronting topics
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (Vomitron_G)
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I had to wait more than 10 years to finally see this one. Not one single copy seemed to be available over here in Europe. That was until 2007, when I finally got my hands on a Region 1 DVD copy. If you like anthology movies, then you have no excuse for not seeing this one. One of the best anthology movies of the 90's (it's up there with "Tales From The Dark Side: The Movie" and "Necronomicon", if you ask me). And probably the best horror movie from the hood with a nearly all Afro-American cast ever made (because I can't really say I've ever seen a ghetto-horror flick that was actually any good). Three hood-rats, out to collect some 'shiiit', visit a freaky coroner who tells them 4 terrifying tales of the supernatural. The first tale is about three corrupt white cops who had it coming... Wings Hauser is especially enjoyable in this one. He already evoked my interest at the time after having seen his enjoyable performance in "Night Shadows" (AKA "Mutant"). And by know I simply love the man. Second story is about a boy and his bruises, which are being caused by... a monster supposedly living in his house. Great and fascinating conclusion this one had. The third tale has some killer-puppet action going on in it of which Charles Band could easily be very jealous. Corbin"The Dentist"Bernsen stars in this segment that revolves around voodoo and slavery. The fourth and last segment gives a big nod to Kubrick's "A Clockwork Orange". Enough said about that one. The wrap-around story wraps it all up nicely, and has a very satisfying conclusion. "Tales From The Hood" is actually more than 'just a horror movie'. With Spike Lee being executive producer, you can rightfully expect that this movie will carry important themes & topics like racism, politics, police brutality, guilt, child abuse, brothers killing brothers, etc. The message always comes across, but possible statements & points of view never become too dominant. This film's primary goal is to entertain a horror audience. And it splendidly succeeds in that. The filmmakers also clearly know the rules of the horror-anthology-genre as well as the tricks of the trade, all to great success. Need I even say that the make-up and special effects are darn excellent too? The tales from this hood, are all winners.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A poor rip-off
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    doomchild-635-982234
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/1/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    i watched this movie from start to finish with a few of my friends and i have to say that is a horrible movie. Before anyone says that i am racist i want you to know that i am not. This movie had very poor acting, the stories were very dull, and the ending was a direct rip-off of the ending of the classic Tales From the Crypt. I am sorry but the only thing i could do while i was watching this film was laugh, and not in a good way like with Blood Feast, i was laughing in a way that was saying that it was one of the worst films that i ever saw. I understand that the movie is trying to say some sort of message but come on it is just way to generic. If you want a good film that tells short stories I would recommend Tales From the Crypt, Vault of Horror, Creepshow (both 1 & 2), and Tales From the Darkside,and skip this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A really good movie!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Noakk
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/2/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm not going to add much, since most has been said already. I just wanted to state that I really enjoyed this movie. It not only pays a good homage to the classic EC comics (or at least the adapted early movie versions or series) but it manages to portray profound messages in a very powerful manner. The effects are pretty good as well and there's some nice gore so horror fans should be satisfied. I think that it's really one of the few movies that successfully combine horror and moral. The soundtrack is also very good - This movie was made in 95' - a time where hip hop in my opinion had reached it's highest point. So it's definitely worth a look!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A little racist but the morals are good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    KHayes666
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As a white American, I view this movie a lot differently than its intended audience...lemme tell you why. The movie is basically a Tales From the Crypt like setting with a black cultured twist. It starts off with 3 homeboys checking out "the shyt" from a mortician (played brilliantly by Clarence Williams the 3rd who ironically was in an episode of Tales From the Crypt years earlier). The mortician then tells 4 tales centered around real life issues. Tale 1 is about 3 white cops who murder a black politician while a rookie black cop looks on. A year later the politician rises from the grave to extract revenge. Its your basic police brutality and one of the weaker stories because its not very realistic, which I thought this movie was supposed to be. Tale 2 is the second best in my opinion. A child on the first day of school is examined by his teacher to find bruises all over him, he claims the "monster" at home did it. This one centers around child abuse with the awesome moral that there are monsters in real life, just not in the form everyone thinks. Tale 3 is another weak one but Corbin Bernsen is the man, he absolutely rules so I refuse to hate it no matter how absurd it is. This one's about a former KKK member who's moving into a mansion that was once the sight of a brutal slave massacre back in the civil war days. Once he move in the ghosts of the pasts haunt him and his associate to drive home the fact that someone always pays for the sins of the past. I don't know whether it was a casting goof, but Corbin's associate was a black man so if he was a racist then why would he choose this guy as a partner? The whole dolls come to life idea is another cheesy idea (coming off about 5 Puppet Master and Child's Play movies) and if anyone else was playing the role, I would have hit the fast forward button. Tale 4 is my personal favorite...it involves a young black gangster who will kill everyone and anyone with no remorse or fear. After murdering some homeboy, the cops catch him and throw him in jail. This is where he meets a white supremacist who thanks him for "doing his job for him." which leads to one of the most sickest, eye opening montages in film history. Basically the moral is, what's the difference between white lynch mobs of the 19th and 20th century and gang bangers from today? Gang violence is murder any way you look at it, and it doesn't matter if the parties are black or white, people suffer and die just the same. The film is done incredibly well but it does portray the white race as the bad guys with all the characters being racist (3 cops, politician, prisoner in the cell), but I guess that's payback for all the black characters being petty thugs and thieves in the Dirty Harry series. The tales themselves offer morals that people in every day life deal with, whether it was cheesy or not. Child abuse, crooked cops, corrupt politicians and gang warfare are an unfortunate but very real situations that this movie shines the light on beautifully. I won't give away the ending but Clarence Williams is the man of the hour and the one with the power, too sweet to be sour. I guess the highlight for me was when Corbin Bernsen calls the media "spooky reporters" 7 out of 10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Enjoyable, quirky vignette horror. Worth investigating
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cjmccracken
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Vignette Horror is one of my favourite types, it's not just the accessibility of the format, but the deftness and wit that is required to create a sequence of short stories usually bypasses the problems which certain horror films have in terms of an overstayed welcome. The structure used in Tales From The Hood is the classic one which was perfected by the Amicus and Hammer studios in the 1960′s and 1970′s, only minus Joan Collins. The 'cryptkeeper' in this case is played by Clarence Williams III, who is a drastically underused actor and always a delight to see on screen. He draws the attention of three local gangstas through the promise of a large amount of drugs which have come into his possession. The catch being that they must first listen to him tell several stories relating to the bodies which currently lie displayed within his funeral home. It only has a running time of 98 minutes which is part of the reason why it is so successful and enjoyable. I am very much of the opinion that a great deal of horror movies now unnecessarily approach the 120 minute (and beyond) when they could have been infinitely more successful if shortened. There are four stories on show here, each relating to a particular hardship or struggle faced by the African American communities of the early 1990′s. It's important to remember that this was an America which was still sore after the chaos of the LA Riots and the exposure of a crooked police force through the Rodney King videotape leak. Once you see that Spike Lee was drafted in as an executive producer, the social elements of the movie become contextualised to a greater extent. The topics of the cautionary tales cover areas such as police brutality and racism withing law enforcement (Rogue Cop Revelation), domestic abuse against women and children (Boys Do Get Bruised), racism within politics (KKK Comeuppance) and the futility of gang culture and the violence it creates (Hard Core Convert). All are delivered with a supernatural twist which places the movie strongly into the horror genre and making it not only groundbreaking, unique for it's time, but also helps it to maintain a strength when watched today. I was aware of the soundtrack before I was aware of the film itself as it was given to me shortly after its release in 1995, it would be a couple of years before I was able to track down a VHS copy. The OST features some fantastic tracks by Gravediggaz, Wu Tang Clan and a brilliant Ol Dirty Bastard track and is well worth locating a copy of. When one considers the depths to which 'hood' based horror movies became after this ('Snoop Dogg's Hood of Horror' and 'Leprechaun back 2 Da Hood' being just two examples), it is all the more reason to revisit Tales From the Hood. There's something about it which will greatly appeal to a certain horror fan, particularly those fond of the genre output of the early 90′s. I'd tell you to go to your local video store to acquire a copy, but there probably isn't even one left in your town. Get it whatever way you can, you won't regret it. Read more at zombiehamster.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the better horror anthologies
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Matt Kracht (krachtm@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Yes, it's flawed, and it's cheesy, and it's over-the-top. It's equal parts clever satire, straight-up homage, and occasionally even a parody. There are many horror, exploitation, and black humor elements sprinkled throughout the movie. I just can't understand why this movie isn't beloved by more people. Maybe it's because the cast is mostly black, and the stories revolve around inner city, black youth? Well, as a white guy from the suburbs, I absolutely loved this movie. It's flawed, of course, but when it works, it works better than most other movies of this type. If you're not familiar with it, this is a horror anthology highly influenced by Tales from the Crypt, an old 50s horror comic book series that birthed several spin-off movies and an influential TV series. It also takes ample inspiration from the Twilight Zone, Tales from the Dark Side, and Creepshow franchises. If you're a fan of any of these, I'd have to highly recommend Tales from the Hood, especially if you're also into Blaxploitation, from which it also takes some inspiration. In the time honored tradition of horror/exploitation movies everywhere, the guilty are punished with gory deaths and lessons are learned (frequently too late). Is it preachy, didactic social satire? Perhaps, at times. But it's also entertaining as hell. It has a great cast, some really cheesy, over-top-the-top acting, and was produced by Spike Lee. For me, that makes it almost required viewing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    your own private mortality
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A tribute to movies like "Dr. Terror's House of Horrors" and "Tales from the Crypt", "Tales from the Hood" presents some horror vignettes centering on life in the black ghetto. Some drug dealers go to a funeral home to pick up their "s**t", only to have the eccentric owner (Clarence Williams III) tell them about the fates of some recent customers...with a twist at the end. At once a fun horror flick and also warning about getting mixed up with the wrong people, this is a cool one. A particular scene in the fourth vignette appears to be a tribute to "A Clockwork Orange". All in all, a real credit for director Rusty Cundieff and executive producer Spike Lee. Featuring Tom Wright (the hitchhiker in "Creepshow 2"), David Alan Grier, Corbin Bernsen and Rosalind Cash (in her final role).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Rented this for the first time at age 15, own it now, very enjoyable for any horror fan
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tbald1980-1 (tbald1980@aol.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I wrote a review for this on Amazon a couple years ago, I figured I'd do one here as well. The first time I saw this, I expected a comedy, boy! I was dead wrong! To be honest, the first two stories were so freaky, I had my mom turn it off. Obviously, I'm a lot harder to scare now and like it overall, despite the constant language. It's kind of a social commentary with realism and supernatural overtones mixed together. This was my first horror anthology, followed by several others It's got a decent script, even though some will say 'I've seen all this before' but to me, clich&eacute;d doesn't have to mean bad, if the right people are in it/behind and in front of the camera, this was also my first Spike Lee film, so I won't judge it on those merits. I know he didn't direct it, but I've heard about a lot of his movies, some look pretty good. By the way, I'm not black either, but I have a large amount of respect for them. I'm getting off track here, bottom line: if you like horror stories with some semblance of reality, you'll probably enjoy this too, but you'll have to overlook the language.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    you might just want to skip to the last one
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    marymorrissey
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For all but the last vignette this movie seems to be the occasion for lots and lots of gleeful indulgence in pretty disgusting racist profanity and other really offensive material - eg the violence at home chez monster in the closet which was really really over the top and next to nauseating and all the stuff that comes out of "duke's" mouth as he's chased around by the little dolls. there are lots and lots of roles of the sort that black actors really hate to play and constantly complain of being stuck with the 2 exceptions being those in which CW III and Roger GS are cast, both of them being a little too classy to offer any of the other negative-stereotypical central casting black roles that comprise the rest of the film. The white actors in this film, actually, are subjected to that sort of casting that blacks have to put up with lol so that's kind of funny. Poor Corbin Bernsen not that LA Law was such a great height to fall from but still . . . But it's OK ya dig cause it's directed by a black guy and co written by him with a white guy (let's sing together now, "ebony... and ivory..." etc) Well, it all sort of makes sense when you see the producer is spike lee, and so . . . I mean basically it has the same problem as the other spike lee films I've seen in that it's fundamentally separatist and whites and blacks can both enjoy making boogie men of each other in this movie. lucky audience eh? makes very strange viewing. The last story, though, was pretty cool though and sort of a tour de force all around, even if it was a copy of another film it was certainly freshened up. I would like to see its equivalent in Gay Cinema which is so full of us vs them BS. It was really cute how they made use of CWII's gap tooth smile :) This is a really tough one to rate so I'll give it a 7!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rpattz3000
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As Mr.Simms says......ahhh....the s***. I really liked this movie.When I first saw this movie I was 15 yrs old and it scared the crap out of me.Especially the first story where those cops beat up Mr.Moorhouse and drove him to the deck and the cops put him in his car and drove his car into the water after they had over dosed him with drugs and after that he was calling out for Clarence to bring the cops to him and when the police came and that one cop whizzed on Moorhouses grave and he made his other partner whiz on the grave too and Moorhouse grabbed the cop and pulled him in the grave and tore his heart out and they showed Moorehouse standing there holding the cops beating heart and then he went after those other 2 cops.I didn't sleep for 2 weeks.I kept thinking I was gonna see Moorhouse standing over my bed or something when I woke up.I liked the story about the the boy who was being abused by his step dad and he said his step dad was a monster.And the one about the dolls was good too.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A superb mid-90's horror anthology tale with macabre humor and confronting topics
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (Vomitron_G)
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I had to wait more than 10 years to finally see this one. Not one single copy seemed to be available over here in Europe. That was until 2007, when I finally got my hands on a Region 1 DVD copy. If you like anthology movies, then you have no excuse for not seeing this one. One of the best anthology movies of the 90's (it's up there with "Tales From The Dark Side: The Movie" and "Necronomicon", if you ask me). And probably the best horror movie from the hood with a nearly all Afro-American cast ever made (because I can't really say I've ever seen a ghetto-horror flick that was actually any good). Three hood-rats, out to collect some 'shiiit', visit a freaky coroner who tells them 4 terrifying tales of the supernatural. The first tale is about three corrupt white cops who had it coming... Wings Hauser is especially enjoyable in this one. He already evoked my interest at the time after having seen his enjoyable performance in "Night Shadows" (AKA "Mutant"). And by know I simply love the man. Second story is about a boy and his bruises, which are being caused by... a monster supposedly living in his house. Great and fascinating conclusion this one had. The third tale has some killer-puppet action going on in it of which Charles Band could easily be very jealous. Corbin"The Dentist"Bernsen stars in this segment that revolves around voodoo and slavery. The fourth and last segment gives a big nod to Kubrick's "A Clockwork Orange". Enough said about that one. The wrap-around story wraps it all up nicely, and has a very satisfying conclusion. "Tales From The Hood" is actually more than 'just a horror movie'. With Spike Lee being executive producer, you can rightfully expect that this movie will carry important themes & topics like racism, politics, police brutality, guilt, child abuse, brothers killing brothers, etc. The message always comes across, but possible statements & points of view never become too dominant. This film's primary goal is to entertain a horror audience. And it splendidly succeeds in that. The filmmakers also clearly know the rules of the horror-anthology-genre as well as the tricks of the trade, all to great success. Need I even say that the make-up and special effects are darn excellent too? The tales from this hood, are all winners.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A poor rip-off
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    doomchild-635-982234
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/1/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    i watched this movie from start to finish with a few of my friends and i have to say that is a horrible movie. Before anyone says that i am racist i want you to know that i am not. This movie had very poor acting, the stories were very dull, and the ending was a direct rip-off of the ending of the classic Tales From the Crypt. I am sorry but the only thing i could do while i was watching this film was laugh, and not in a good way like with Blood Feast, i was laughing in a way that was saying that it was one of the worst films that i ever saw. I understand that the movie is trying to say some sort of message but come on it is just way to generic. If you want a good film that tells short stories I would recommend Tales From the Crypt, Vault of Horror, Creepshow (both 1 & 2), and Tales From the Darkside,and skip this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A really good movie!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Noakk
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/2/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm not going to add much, since most has been said already. I just wanted to state that I really enjoyed this movie. It not only pays a good homage to the classic EC comics (or at least the adapted early movie versions or series) but it manages to portray profound messages in a very powerful manner. The effects are pretty good as well and there's some nice gore so horror fans should be satisfied. I think that it's really one of the few movies that successfully combine horror and moral. The soundtrack is also very good - This movie was made in 95' - a time where hip hop in my opinion had reached it's highest point. So it's definitely worth a look!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A little racist but the morals are good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    KHayes666
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As a white American, I view this movie a lot differently than its intended audience...lemme tell you why. The movie is basically a Tales From the Crypt like setting with a black cultured twist. It starts off with 3 homeboys checking out "the shyt" from a mortician (played brilliantly by Clarence Williams the 3rd who ironically was in an episode of Tales From the Crypt years earlier). The mortician then tells 4 tales centered around real life issues. Tale 1 is about 3 white cops who murder a black politician while a rookie black cop looks on. A year later the politician rises from the grave to extract revenge. Its your basic police brutality and one of the weaker stories because its not very realistic, which I thought this movie was supposed to be. Tale 2 is the second best in my opinion. A child on the first day of school is examined by his teacher to find bruises all over him, he claims the "monster" at home did it. This one centers around child abuse with the awesome moral that there are monsters in real life, just not in the form everyone thinks. Tale 3 is another weak one but Corbin Bernsen is the man, he absolutely rules so I refuse to hate it no matter how absurd it is. This one's about a former KKK member who's moving into a mansion that was once the sight of a brutal slave massacre back in the civil war days. Once he move in the ghosts of the pasts haunt him and his associate to drive home the fact that someone always pays for the sins of the past. I don't know whether it was a casting goof, but Corbin's associate was a black man so if he was a racist then why would he choose this guy as a partner? The whole dolls come to life idea is another cheesy idea (coming off about 5 Puppet Master and Child's Play movies) and if anyone else was playing the role, I would have hit the fast forward button. Tale 4 is my personal favorite...it involves a young black gangster who will kill everyone and anyone with no remorse or fear. After murdering some homeboy, the cops catch him and throw him in jail. This is where he meets a white supremacist who thanks him for "doing his job for him." which leads to one of the most sickest, eye opening montages in film history. Basically the moral is, what's the difference between white lynch mobs of the 19th and 20th century and gang bangers from today? Gang violence is murder any way you look at it, and it doesn't matter if the parties are black or white, people suffer and die just the same. The film is done incredibly well but it does portray the white race as the bad guys with all the characters being racist (3 cops, politician, prisoner in the cell), but I guess that's payback for all the black characters being petty thugs and thieves in the Dirty Harry series. The tales themselves offer morals that people in every day life deal with, whether it was cheesy or not. Child abuse, crooked cops, corrupt politicians and gang warfare are an unfortunate but very real situations that this movie shines the light on beautifully. I won't give away the ending but Clarence Williams is the man of the hour and the one with the power, too sweet to be sour. I guess the highlight for me was when Corbin Bernsen calls the media "spooky reporters" 7 out of 10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Enjoyable, quirky vignette horror. Worth investigating
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cjmccracken
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Vignette Horror is one of my favourite types, it's not just the accessibility of the format, but the deftness and wit that is required to create a sequence of short stories usually bypasses the problems which certain horror films have in terms of an overstayed welcome. The structure used in Tales From The Hood is the classic one which was perfected by the Amicus and Hammer studios in the 1960′s and 1970′s, only minus Joan Collins. The 'cryptkeeper' in this case is played by Clarence Williams III, who is a drastically underused actor and always a delight to see on screen. He draws the attention of three local gangstas through the promise of a large amount of drugs which have come into his possession. The catch being that they must first listen to him tell several stories relating to the bodies which currently lie displayed within his funeral home. It only has a running time of 98 minutes which is part of the reason why it is so successful and enjoyable. I am very much of the opinion that a great deal of horror movies now unnecessarily approach the 120 minute (and beyond) when they could have been infinitely more successful if shortened. There are four stories on show here, each relating to a particular hardship or struggle faced by the African American communities of the early 1990′s. It's important to remember that this was an America which was still sore after the chaos of the LA Riots and the exposure of a crooked police force through the Rodney King videotape leak. Once you see that Spike Lee was drafted in as an executive producer, the social elements of the movie become contextualised to a greater extent. The topics of the cautionary tales cover areas such as police brutality and racism withing law enforcement (Rogue Cop Revelation), domestic abuse against women and children (Boys Do Get Bruised), racism within politics (KKK Comeuppance) and the futility of gang culture and the violence it creates (Hard Core Convert). All are delivered with a supernatural twist which places the movie strongly into the horror genre and making it not only groundbreaking, unique for it's time, but also helps it to maintain a strength when watched today. I was aware of the soundtrack before I was aware of the film itself as it was given to me shortly after its release in 1995, it would be a couple of years before I was able to track down a VHS copy. The OST features some fantastic tracks by Gravediggaz, Wu Tang Clan and a brilliant Ol Dirty Bastard track and is well worth locating a copy of. When one considers the depths to which 'hood' based horror movies became after this ('Snoop Dogg's Hood of Horror' and 'Leprechaun back 2 Da Hood' being just two examples), it is all the more reason to revisit Tales From the Hood. There's something about it which will greatly appeal to a certain horror fan, particularly those fond of the genre output of the early 90′s. I'd tell you to go to your local video store to acquire a copy, but there probably isn't even one left in your town. Get it whatever way you can, you won't regret it. Read more at zombiehamster.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the better horror anthologies
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Matt Kracht (krachtm@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Yes, it's flawed, and it's cheesy, and it's over-the-top. It's equal parts clever satire, straight-up homage, and occasionally even a parody. There are many horror, exploitation, and black humor elements sprinkled throughout the movie. I just can't understand why this movie isn't beloved by more people. Maybe it's because the cast is mostly black, and the stories revolve around inner city, black youth? Well, as a white guy from the suburbs, I absolutely loved this movie. It's flawed, of course, but when it works, it works better than most other movies of this type. If you're not familiar with it, this is a horror anthology highly influenced by Tales from the Crypt, an old 50s horror comic book series that birthed several spin-off movies and an influential TV series. It also takes ample inspiration from the Twilight Zone, Tales from the Dark Side, and Creepshow franchises. If you're a fan of any of these, I'd have to highly recommend Tales from the Hood, especially if you're also into Blaxploitation, from which it also takes some inspiration. In the time honored tradition of horror/exploitation movies everywhere, the guilty are punished with gory deaths and lessons are learned (frequently too late). Is it preachy, didactic social satire? Perhaps, at times. But it's also entertaining as hell. It has a great cast, some really cheesy, over-top-the-top acting, and was produced by Spike Lee. For me, that makes it almost required viewing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    your own private mortality
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A tribute to movies like "Dr. Terror's House of Horrors" and "Tales from the Crypt", "Tales from the Hood" presents some horror vignettes centering on life in the black ghetto. Some drug dealers go to a funeral home to pick up their "s**t", only to have the eccentric owner (Clarence Williams III) tell them about the fates of some recent customers...with a twist at the end. At once a fun horror flick and also warning about getting mixed up with the wrong people, this is a cool one. A particular scene in the fourth vignette appears to be a tribute to "A Clockwork Orange". All in all, a real credit for director Rusty Cundieff and executive producer Spike Lee. Featuring Tom Wright (the hitchhiker in "Creepshow 2"), David Alan Grier, Corbin Bernsen and Rosalind Cash (in her final role).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Rented this for the first time at age 15, own it now, very enjoyable for any horror fan
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tbald1980-1 (tbald1980@aol.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I wrote a review for this on Amazon a couple years ago, I figured I'd do one here as well. The first time I saw this, I expected a comedy, boy! I was dead wrong! To be honest, the first two stories were so freaky, I had my mom turn it off. Obviously, I'm a lot harder to scare now and like it overall, despite the constant language. It's kind of a social commentary with realism and supernatural overtones mixed together. This was my first horror anthology, followed by several others It's got a decent script, even though some will say 'I've seen all this before' but to me, clich&eacute;d doesn't have to mean bad, if the right people are in it/behind and in front of the camera, this was also my first Spike Lee film, so I won't judge it on those merits. I know he didn't direct it, but I've heard about a lot of his movies, some look pretty good. By the way, I'm not black either, but I have a large amount of respect for them. I'm getting off track here, bottom line: if you like horror stories with some semblance of reality, you'll probably enjoy this too, but you'll have to overlook the language.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    you might just want to skip to the last one
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    marymorrissey
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For all but the last vignette this movie seems to be the occasion for lots and lots of gleeful indulgence in pretty disgusting racist profanity and other really offensive material - eg the violence at home chez monster in the closet which was really really over the top and next to nauseating and all the stuff that comes out of "duke's" mouth as he's chased around by the little dolls. there are lots and lots of roles of the sort that black actors really hate to play and constantly complain of being stuck with the 2 exceptions being those in which CW III and Roger GS are cast, both of them being a little too classy to offer any of the other negative-stereotypical central casting black roles that comprise the rest of the film. The white actors in this film, actually, are subjected to that sort of casting that blacks have to put up with lol so that's kind of funny. Poor Corbin Bernsen not that LA Law was such a great height to fall from but still . . . But it's OK ya dig cause it's directed by a black guy and co written by him with a white guy (let's sing together now, "ebony... and ivory..." etc) Well, it all sort of makes sense when you see the producer is spike lee, and so . . . I mean basically it has the same problem as the other spike lee films I've seen in that it's fundamentally separatist and whites and blacks can both enjoy making boogie men of each other in this movie. lucky audience eh? makes very strange viewing. The last story, though, was pretty cool though and sort of a tour de force all around, even if it was a copy of another film it was certainly freshened up. I would like to see its equivalent in Gay Cinema which is so full of us vs them BS. It was really cute how they made use of CWII's gap tooth smile :) This is a really tough one to rate so I'll give it a 7!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rpattz3000
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As Mr.Simms says......ahhh....the s***. I really liked this movie.When I first saw this movie I was 15 yrs old and it scared the crap out of me.Especially the first story where those cops beat up Mr.Moorhouse and drove him to the deck and the cops put him in his car and drove his car into the water after they had over dosed him with drugs and after that he was calling out for Clarence to bring the cops to him and when the police came and that one cop whizzed on Moorhouses grave and he made his other partner whiz on the grave too and Moorhouse grabbed the cop and pulled him in the grave and tore his heart out and they showed Moorehouse standing there holding the cops beating heart and then he went after those other 2 cops.I didn't sleep for 2 weeks.I kept thinking I was gonna see Moorhouse standing over my bed or something when I woke up.I liked the story about the the boy who was being abused by his step dad and he said his step dad was a monster.And the one about the dolls was good too.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A superb mid-90's horror anthology tale with macabre humor and confronting topics
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (Vomitron_G)
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I had to wait more than 10 years to finally see this one. Not one single copy seemed to be available over here in Europe. That was until 2007, when I finally got my hands on a Region 1 DVD copy. If you like anthology movies, then you have no excuse for not seeing this one. One of the best anthology movies of the 90's (it's up there with "Tales From The Dark Side: The Movie" and "Necronomicon", if you ask me). And probably the best horror movie from the hood with a nearly all Afro-American cast ever made (because I can't really say I've ever seen a ghetto-horror flick that was actually any good). Three hood-rats, out to collect some 'shiiit', visit a freaky coroner who tells them 4 terrifying tales of the supernatural. The first tale is about three corrupt white cops who had it coming... Wings Hauser is especially enjoyable in this one. He already evoked my interest at the time after having seen his enjoyable performance in "Night Shadows" (AKA "Mutant"). And by know I simply love the man. Second story is about a boy and his bruises, which are being caused by... a monster supposedly living in his house. Great and fascinating conclusion this one had. The third tale has some killer-puppet action going on in it of which Charles Band could easily be very jealous. Corbin"The Dentist"Bernsen stars in this segment that revolves around voodoo and slavery. The fourth and last segment gives a big nod to Kubrick's "A Clockwork Orange". Enough said about that one. The wrap-around story wraps it all up nicely, and has a very satisfying conclusion. "Tales From The Hood" is actually more than 'just a horror movie'. With Spike Lee being executive producer, you can rightfully expect that this movie will carry important themes & topics like racism, politics, police brutality, guilt, child abuse, brothers killing brothers, etc. The message always comes across, but possible statements & points of view never become too dominant. This film's primary goal is to entertain a horror audience. And it splendidly succeeds in that. The filmmakers also clearly know the rules of the horror-anthology-genre as well as the tricks of the trade, all to great success. Need I even say that the make-up and special effects are darn excellent too? The tales from this hood, are all winners.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A poor rip-off
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    doomchild-635-982234
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/1/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    i watched this movie from start to finish with a few of my friends and i have to say that is a horrible movie. Before anyone says that i am racist i want you to know that i am not. This movie had very poor acting, the stories were very dull, and the ending was a direct rip-off of the ending of the classic Tales From the Crypt. I am sorry but the only thing i could do while i was watching this film was laugh, and not in a good way like with Blood Feast, i was laughing in a way that was saying that it was one of the worst films that i ever saw. I understand that the movie is trying to say some sort of message but come on it is just way to generic. If you want a good film that tells short stories I would recommend Tales From the Crypt, Vault of Horror, Creepshow (both 1 & 2), and Tales From the Darkside,and skip this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A really good movie!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Noakk
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/2/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm not going to add much, since most has been said already. I just wanted to state that I really enjoyed this movie. It not only pays a good homage to the classic EC comics (or at least the adapted early movie versions or series) but it manages to portray profound messages in a very powerful manner. The effects are pretty good as well and there's some nice gore so horror fans should be satisfied. I think that it's really one of the few movies that successfully combine horror and moral. The soundtrack is also very good - This movie was made in 95' - a time where hip hop in my opinion had reached it's highest point. So it's definitely worth a look!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A little racist but the morals are good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    KHayes666
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As a white American, I view this movie a lot differently than its intended audience...lemme tell you why. The movie is basically a Tales From the Crypt like setting with a black cultured twist. It starts off with 3 homeboys checking out "the shyt" from a mortician (played brilliantly by Clarence Williams the 3rd who ironically was in an episode of Tales From the Crypt years earlier). The mortician then tells 4 tales centered around real life issues. Tale 1 is about 3 white cops who murder a black politician while a rookie black cop looks on. A year later the politician rises from the grave to extract revenge. Its your basic police brutality and one of the weaker stories because its not very realistic, which I thought this movie was supposed to be. Tale 2 is the second best in my opinion. A child on the first day of school is examined by his teacher to find bruises all over him, he claims the "monster" at home did it. This one centers around child abuse with the awesome moral that there are monsters in real life, just not in the form everyone thinks. Tale 3 is another weak one but Corbin Bernsen is the man, he absolutely rules so I refuse to hate it no matter how absurd it is. This one's about a former KKK member who's moving into a mansion that was once the sight of a brutal slave massacre back in the civil war days. Once he move in the ghosts of the pasts haunt him and his associate to drive home the fact that someone always pays for the sins of the past. I don't know whether it was a casting goof, but Corbin's associate was a black man so if he was a racist then why would he choose this guy as a partner? The whole dolls come to life idea is another cheesy idea (coming off about 5 Puppet Master and Child's Play movies) and if anyone else was playing the role, I would have hit the fast forward button. Tale 4 is my personal favorite...it involves a young black gangster who will kill everyone and anyone with no remorse or fear. After murdering some homeboy, the cops catch him and throw him in jail. This is where he meets a white supremacist who thanks him for "doing his job for him." which leads to one of the most sickest, eye opening montages in film history. Basically the moral is, what's the difference between white lynch mobs of the 19th and 20th century and gang bangers from today? Gang violence is murder any way you look at it, and it doesn't matter if the parties are black or white, people suffer and die just the same. The film is done incredibly well but it does portray the white race as the bad guys with all the characters being racist (3 cops, politician, prisoner in the cell), but I guess that's payback for all the black characters being petty thugs and thieves in the Dirty Harry series. The tales themselves offer morals that people in every day life deal with, whether it was cheesy or not. Child abuse, crooked cops, corrupt politicians and gang warfare are an unfortunate but very real situations that this movie shines the light on beautifully. I won't give away the ending but Clarence Williams is the man of the hour and the one with the power, too sweet to be sour. I guess the highlight for me was when Corbin Bernsen calls the media "spooky reporters" 7 out of 10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Enjoyable, quirky vignette horror. Worth investigating
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cjmccracken
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Vignette Horror is one of my favourite types, it's not just the accessibility of the format, but the deftness and wit that is required to create a sequence of short stories usually bypasses the problems which certain horror films have in terms of an overstayed welcome. The structure used in Tales From The Hood is the classic one which was perfected by the Amicus and Hammer studios in the 1960′s and 1970′s, only minus Joan Collins. The 'cryptkeeper' in this case is played by Clarence Williams III, who is a drastically underused actor and always a delight to see on screen. He draws the attention of three local gangstas through the promise of a large amount of drugs which have come into his possession. The catch being that they must first listen to him tell several stories relating to the bodies which currently lie displayed within his funeral home. It only has a running time of 98 minutes which is part of the reason why it is so successful and enjoyable. I am very much of the opinion that a great deal of horror movies now unnecessarily approach the 120 minute (and beyond) when they could have been infinitely more successful if shortened. There are four stories on show here, each relating to a particular hardship or struggle faced by the African American communities of the early 1990′s. It's important to remember that this was an America which was still sore after the chaos of the LA Riots and the exposure of a crooked police force through the Rodney King videotape leak. Once you see that Spike Lee was drafted in as an executive producer, the social elements of the movie become contextualised to a greater extent. The topics of the cautionary tales cover areas such as police brutality and racism withing law enforcement (Rogue Cop Revelation), domestic abuse against women and children (Boys Do Get Bruised), racism within politics (KKK Comeuppance) and the futility of gang culture and the violence it creates (Hard Core Convert). All are delivered with a supernatural twist which places the movie strongly into the horror genre and making it not only groundbreaking, unique for it's time, but also helps it to maintain a strength when watched today. I was aware of the soundtrack before I was aware of the film itself as it was given to me shortly after its release in 1995, it would be a couple of years before I was able to track down a VHS copy. The OST features some fantastic tracks by Gravediggaz, Wu Tang Clan and a brilliant Ol Dirty Bastard track and is well worth locating a copy of. When one considers the depths to which 'hood' based horror movies became after this ('Snoop Dogg's Hood of Horror' and 'Leprechaun back 2 Da Hood' being just two examples), it is all the more reason to revisit Tales From the Hood. There's something about it which will greatly appeal to a certain horror fan, particularly those fond of the genre output of the early 90′s. I'd tell you to go to your local video store to acquire a copy, but there probably isn't even one left in your town. Get it whatever way you can, you won't regret it. Read more at zombiehamster.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the better horror anthologies
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Matt Kracht (krachtm@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Yes, it's flawed, and it's cheesy, and it's over-the-top. It's equal parts clever satire, straight-up homage, and occasionally even a parody. There are many horror, exploitation, and black humor elements sprinkled throughout the movie. I just can't understand why this movie isn't beloved by more people. Maybe it's because the cast is mostly black, and the stories revolve around inner city, black youth? Well, as a white guy from the suburbs, I absolutely loved this movie. It's flawed, of course, but when it works, it works better than most other movies of this type. If you're not familiar with it, this is a horror anthology highly influenced by Tales from the Crypt, an old 50s horror comic book series that birthed several spin-off movies and an influential TV series. It also takes ample inspiration from the Twilight Zone, Tales from the Dark Side, and Creepshow franchises. If you're a fan of any of these, I'd have to highly recommend Tales from the Hood, especially if you're also into Blaxploitation, from which it also takes some inspiration. In the time honored tradition of horror/exploitation movies everywhere, the guilty are punished with gory deaths and lessons are learned (frequently too late). Is it preachy, didactic social satire? Perhaps, at times. But it's also entertaining as hell. It has a great cast, some really cheesy, over-top-the-top acting, and was produced by Spike Lee. For me, that makes it almost required viewing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    your own private mortality
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A tribute to movies like "Dr. Terror's House of Horrors" and "Tales from the Crypt", "Tales from the Hood" presents some horror vignettes centering on life in the black ghetto. Some drug dealers go to a funeral home to pick up their "s**t", only to have the eccentric owner (Clarence Williams III) tell them about the fates of some recent customers...with a twist at the end. At once a fun horror flick and also warning about getting mixed up with the wrong people, this is a cool one. A particular scene in the fourth vignette appears to be a tribute to "A Clockwork Orange". All in all, a real credit for director Rusty Cundieff and executive producer Spike Lee. Featuring Tom Wright (the hitchhiker in "Creepshow 2"), David Alan Grier, Corbin Bernsen and Rosalind Cash (in her final role).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Rented this for the first time at age 15, own it now, very enjoyable for any horror fan
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tbald1980-1 (tbald1980@aol.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I wrote a review for this on Amazon a couple years ago, I figured I'd do one here as well. The first time I saw this, I expected a comedy, boy! I was dead wrong! To be honest, the first two stories were so freaky, I had my mom turn it off. Obviously, I'm a lot harder to scare now and like it overall, despite the constant language. It's kind of a social commentary with realism and supernatural overtones mixed together. This was my first horror anthology, followed by several others It's got a decent script, even though some will say 'I've seen all this before' but to me, clich&eacute;d doesn't have to mean bad, if the right people are in it/behind and in front of the camera, this was also my first Spike Lee film, so I won't judge it on those merits. I know he didn't direct it, but I've heard about a lot of his movies, some look pretty good. By the way, I'm not black either, but I have a large amount of respect for them. I'm getting off track here, bottom line: if you like horror stories with some semblance of reality, you'll probably enjoy this too, but you'll have to overlook the language.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    you might just want to skip to the last one
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    marymorrissey
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For all but the last vignette this movie seems to be the occasion for lots and lots of gleeful indulgence in pretty disgusting racist profanity and other really offensive material - eg the violence at home chez monster in the closet which was really really over the top and next to nauseating and all the stuff that comes out of "duke's" mouth as he's chased around by the little dolls. there are lots and lots of roles of the sort that black actors really hate to play and constantly complain of being stuck with the 2 exceptions being those in which CW III and Roger GS are cast, both of them being a little too classy to offer any of the other negative-stereotypical central casting black roles that comprise the rest of the film. The white actors in this film, actually, are subjected to that sort of casting that blacks have to put up with lol so that's kind of funny. Poor Corbin Bernsen not that LA Law was such a great height to fall from but still . . . But it's OK ya dig cause it's directed by a black guy and co written by him with a white guy (let's sing together now, "ebony... and ivory..." etc) Well, it all sort of makes sense when you see the producer is spike lee, and so . . . I mean basically it has the same problem as the other spike lee films I've seen in that it's fundamentally separatist and whites and blacks can both enjoy making boogie men of each other in this movie. lucky audience eh? makes very strange viewing. The last story, though, was pretty cool though and sort of a tour de force all around, even if it was a copy of another film it was certainly freshened up. I would like to see its equivalent in Gay Cinema which is so full of us vs them BS. It was really cute how they made use of CWII's gap tooth smile :) This is a really tough one to rate so I'll give it a 7!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rpattz3000
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As Mr.Simms says......ahhh....the s***. I really liked this movie.When I first saw this movie I was 15 yrs old and it scared the crap out of me.Especially the first story where those cops beat up Mr.Moorhouse and drove him to the deck and the cops put him in his car and drove his car into the water after they had over dosed him with drugs and after that he was calling out for Clarence to bring the cops to him and when the police came and that one cop whizzed on Moorhouses grave and he made his other partner whiz on the grave too and Moorhouse grabbed the cop and pulled him in the grave and tore his heart out and they showed Moorehouse standing there holding the cops beating heart and then he went after those other 2 cops.I didn't sleep for 2 weeks.I kept thinking I was gonna see Moorhouse standing over my bed or something when I woke up.I liked the story about the the boy who was being abused by his step dad and he said his step dad was a monster.And the one about the dolls was good too.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A superb mid-90's horror anthology tale with macabre humor and confronting topics
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (Vomitron_G)
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I had to wait more than 10 years to finally see this one. Not one single copy seemed to be available over here in Europe. That was until 2007, when I finally got my hands on a Region 1 DVD copy. If you like anthology movies, then you have no excuse for not seeing this one. One of the best anthology movies of the 90's (it's up there with "Tales From The Dark Side: The Movie" and "Necronomicon", if you ask me). And probably the best horror movie from the hood with a nearly all Afro-American cast ever made (because I can't really say I've ever seen a ghetto-horror flick that was actually any good). Three hood-rats, out to collect some 'shiiit', visit a freaky coroner who tells them 4 terrifying tales of the supernatural. The first tale is about three corrupt white cops who had it coming... Wings Hauser is especially enjoyable in this one. He already evoked my interest at the time after having seen his enjoyable performance in "Night Shadows" (AKA "Mutant"). And by know I simply love the man. Second story is about a boy and his bruises, which are being caused by... a monster supposedly living in his house. Great and fascinating conclusion this one had. The third tale has some killer-puppet action going on in it of which Charles Band could easily be very jealous. Corbin"The Dentist"Bernsen stars in this segment that revolves around voodoo and slavery. The fourth and last segment gives a big nod to Kubrick's "A Clockwork Orange". Enough said about that one. The wrap-around story wraps it all up nicely, and has a very satisfying conclusion. "Tales From The Hood" is actually more than 'just a horror movie'. With Spike Lee being executive producer, you can rightfully expect that this movie will carry important themes & topics like racism, politics, police brutality, guilt, child abuse, brothers killing brothers, etc. The message always comes across, but possible statements & points of view never become too dominant. This film's primary goal is to entertain a horror audience. And it splendidly succeeds in that. The filmmakers also clearly know the rules of the horror-anthology-genre as well as the tricks of the trade, all to great success. Need I even say that the make-up and special effects are darn excellent too? The tales from this hood, are all winners.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A poor rip-off
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    doomchild-635-982234
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/1/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    i watched this movie from start to finish with a few of my friends and i have to say that is a horrible movie. Before anyone says that i am racist i want you to know that i am not. This movie had very poor acting, the stories were very dull, and the ending was a direct rip-off of the ending of the classic Tales From the Crypt. I am sorry but the only thing i could do while i was watching this film was laugh, and not in a good way like with Blood Feast, i was laughing in a way that was saying that it was one of the worst films that i ever saw. I understand that the movie is trying to say some sort of message but come on it is just way to generic. If you want a good film that tells short stories I would recommend Tales From the Crypt, Vault of Horror, Creepshow (both 1 & 2), and Tales From the Darkside,and skip this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A really good movie!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Noakk
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/2/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm not going to add much, since most has been said already. I just wanted to state that I really enjoyed this movie. It not only pays a good homage to the classic EC comics (or at least the adapted early movie versions or series) but it manages to portray profound messages in a very powerful manner. The effects are pretty good as well and there's some nice gore so horror fans should be satisfied. I think that it's really one of the few movies that successfully combine horror and moral. The soundtrack is also very good - This movie was made in 95' - a time where hip hop in my opinion had reached it's highest point. So it's definitely worth a look!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A little racist but the morals are good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    KHayes666
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/5/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As a white American, I view this movie a lot differently than its intended audience...lemme tell you why. The movie is basically a Tales From the Crypt like setting with a black cultured twist. It starts off with 3 homeboys checking out "the shyt" from a mortician (played brilliantly by Clarence Williams the 3rd who ironically was in an episode of Tales From the Crypt years earlier). The mortician then tells 4 tales centered around real life issues. Tale 1 is about 3 white cops who murder a black politician while a rookie black cop looks on. A year later the politician rises from the grave to extract revenge. Its your basic police brutality and one of the weaker stories because its not very realistic, which I thought this movie was supposed to be. Tale 2 is the second best in my opinion. A child on the first day of school is examined by his teacher to find bruises all over him, he claims the "monster" at home did it. This one centers around child abuse with the awesome moral that there are monsters in real life, just not in the form everyone thinks. Tale 3 is another weak one but Corbin Bernsen is the man, he absolutely rules so I refuse to hate it no matter how absurd it is. This one's about a former KKK member who's moving into a mansion that was once the sight of a brutal slave massacre back in the civil war days. Once he move in the ghosts of the pasts haunt him and his associate to drive home the fact that someone always pays for the sins of the past. I don't know whether it was a casting goof, but Corbin's associate was a black man so if he was a racist then why would he choose this guy as a partner? The whole dolls come to life idea is another cheesy idea (coming off about 5 Puppet Master and Child's Play movies) and if anyone else was playing the role, I would have hit the fast forward button. Tale 4 is my personal favorite...it involves a young black gangster who will kill everyone and anyone with no remorse or fear. After murdering some homeboy, the cops catch him and throw him in jail. This is where he meets a white supremacist who thanks him for "doing his job for him." which leads to one of the most sickest, eye opening montages in film history. Basically the moral is, what's the difference between white lynch mobs of the 19th and 20th century and gang bangers from today? Gang violence is murder any way you look at it, and it doesn't matter if the parties are black or white, people suffer and die just the same. The film is done incredibly well but it does portray the white race as the bad guys with all the characters being racist (3 cops, politician, prisoner in the cell), but I guess that's payback for all the black characters being petty thugs and thieves in the Dirty Harry series. The tales themselves offer morals that people in every day life deal with, whether it was cheesy or not. Child abuse, crooked cops, corrupt politicians and gang warfare are an unfortunate but very real situations that this movie shines the light on beautifully. I won't give away the ending but Clarence Williams is the man of the hour and the one with the power, too sweet to be sour. I guess the highlight for me was when Corbin Bernsen calls the media "spooky reporters" 7 out of 10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
