<filme>
 <id>
  565
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0114852
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1995
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  A Cidade dos Amaldi&ccedil;oados
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  5.4
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  A small town's women give birth to unfriendly alien children posing as humans.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  An American village is visited by some unknown life form which leaves the women of the village pregnant. Nine months later, the babies are born, and they all look normal, but it doesn't take the "parents" long to realize that the kids are not human or humane.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Horror
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Sci-Fi
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Thriller
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   children
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   birth
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   small town
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   baby
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   alien
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   John Carpenter
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   John Wyndham
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Stirling Silliphant
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Christopher Reeve
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Kirstie Alley
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Linda Kozlowski
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stick with the original
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This bland rehash of the 1960 original is not without effective moments, but they're all in the first twenty minutes and things get mighty dull from that point on. Once the set-up is out of the way  small village, strange spell, mysterious pregnancies, spooky children  what atmosphere has been established disappears and the film becomes increasingly reliant on cheesy glowing-eye effects and repetitious killings. The characters don't ring true, either; they accept the bizarre events rather easily. On the plus side, there's a solid performance from Christopher Reeve and the score has its moments.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bland remake
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    atinder
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Village of the Damned (1995) Frist of all, I Don't The original was even that good but at least kept in in and moved forward and at more creepy feel to the movie. I did think movie would be better as John Carpenter did this remake, So I looking forward to it but soon as the movie started I knew this movie not going to be good. I didn't really like how they kinda change the story and gave really lame back story to kids being bored, there not one moment did have this kids creepy or scary at all, it was tame from start to end and never feel moved forward as the movie was such their I thought this was going to be a lot more better, so how they about to die, we actually see the death scenes in this movie, seen before and the aftermath but not when happens, it cuts way to the kids was lights in there eyes. The acting was really wooden by some of the main cast, I don't maybe they took make this more main stream movie, I think must worst John carpenter movie but a least movie wasn't boring, it maybe a little intruded how the movie going pan out, even that ending was a load of rubbish. 2 out of 10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Rated R for what?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    utahman1971
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    OK, I saw this in theater when it was release in 1995. I recently saw it again in its original format. I can't see where the rating R is at in this movie. There is hardly any bad language. There is barely any blood. There is a little action. There is nothing to claim it to be rated R. I can name another movie done the same "Dead Silence". I can the ones making the ratings making stupid mistakes, but that stupid is really stupid. Almost about as dumb as having rated PG-13 horror movies, and saying they are horror. I can sit through every single PG-13 wanna be called horror movies, and pretty much fall asleep through them. That is how sad those Directors are. They want to go towards wider range of people. When then call them thrillers, because that is really what they are. Thrillers are for chillers, and horror is for gore. I am sick of good Ole horror movies that have the gore to go with the horror are getting terrible ratings while the lame PG-13 chillers are getting better ratings. I will say it until I die, that those PG-13 so called horror that are really chiller thrillers should never be called horror. Just the claim is dumber than snot. As for the gore, it isn't real blood or guts. Its all fake. So if you can't handle it something is wrong with that person, not the movie. There needs to be more Directors that can make horror a horror movie that is the right rating for the movie, and not the boring wanna be crap.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Enjoyable movie. Forget Carpenter.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    midge56
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is still enjoyable to watch despite Carpenter. In fact, Carpenter had no business entitling this movie as his own since it was not his story or his screenplay in the first place. That was pure, unearned ego on his part as he tries to make his fame by latching onto the brilliant efforts of the original films & writers. Carpenter only added unnecessary, offensive gore to an already great story. The effects on the eyes were good & the extended gov't involvement with more focus on science than paranoia was also a refreshing addition as was the stillborn specimen (but that should have included more details on the lab findings than we got.) The priest character was OK until he became a suicidal gun nut which was ridiculous on too many levels to list. The boiling pot, self evisceration, barbecue, consumption by inferno & "walking tall" gun battle were just intolerable gore which added nothing to the movie. The original movie only had the children harming someone who had caused them harm or perceived as intended. This movie had them killing the innocent for no reason. That seriously degraded the story. The original contained unjustifiable gov't paranoia over acts of self-defense. By the killing of innocents such as the mothers suicides which made no sense whatsoever, it justified the paranoia to kill the children. The original idea was the children were unfairly judged because they were different & had unique abilities; acting only in self defense. I did like the survival ending on the new version. That could make an excellent sequel. It is a mistake to remake popular movies like this film, The Omen & Stepford Wives which were already great to begin with. (& never ridicule a cult classic such as was done with Stepford). Only an idiot would take plot change advice from disgruntled complainers instead of fans. It would be OK to colorize BW films and beef up the special effects & sound improvements on the originals for redistribution as was done for Star Wars & Star Trek. Sequels of great cliffhanger films would be much better ideas to pursue if done in the spirit of the original story. But it is a bad idea to redo an original classic verbatim without offering much more to the story. The desire to see more details & missing parts of the stories is what makes deleted scenes so popular with the public. They don't like to be left hanging in the dark. Hence, the need for a sequel on such movies. Not a remake of the same hanging, unanswered questions which offers nothing extra to fans. It would be better to make follow up sequels on these popular stories rather than trying to duplicate the original verbatim with a completely different cast. There's also nothing worse than an actor doing a popular film remake, who refuses to watch the original or a director who makes changes simply to imprint their ego onto it like a dog marking a hydrant. We might like to see what happens if the children survived & learn the source of their origins; as well as endings where they are successful in survival & goals as well as exceptions to their demeanor like David with multi-layered personalities. Classic films should not be used as a venue for some egomaniacal director to headline his name on the title of a movie he didn't write as Carpenter has been repeatedly guilty of doing. Perhaps he should do something original for a change rather than riding on the coat tails of someone else's ideas & efforts. Don't listen to the opinions of people who get off on gore. They are only happy with chainsaw, saw & serial hacking butcher type Jason films with no appreciation for thrilling & innovative story lines. This classic, one of a kind story has captivated audiences for over 50 years since it was first released. So even a glory stealer like Carpenter can't do too much damage to ruin it. So forget Carpenter. The actors did a good job portraying their roles despite his direction. This new version of the movie is still based on the original classic so it is still enjoyable to watch if you use the fast forward to elude the gore scenes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not As Bad As It's Reputation
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Village of the Damned (1995) ** 1/2 (out of 4) John Carpenter's remake of the 1960 British film took an incredible beating when it was first released and while it's not as good as the original film, there are enough good moments to make it worth sitting through if you're a fan of the director. Basically what we have here is a small town that comes under attack by nine children who were all born on the same night after their mothers became pregnant during a bizarre blackout. Soon the kids are forcing the adults around them to either self mutilate or kill themselves. VILLAGE OF THE DAMNED started off pretty strong but then the screenplay simply ran out of fresh ideas and we're left with just one routine scene after another. As much as I'm against the heated hatred some show this film, there's still no question that it should have been much better considering who was directing it. I think some of the film's faults have to go to Carpenter because the biggest problem is that the children are never scary. Not once did I ever really feel threatened by them and saying Carpenter didn't make something scary is pretty rare. I did like the visual style and look that he gave the film and especially during the early scenes where the blackout occurs. I thought the first portion of the film was the most interesting as it deals with the blackout, the effects of the events and of course the women in the town getting pregnant. The second half of the film pretty much just becomes routine as one adult makes the kids mad after another and they all end up dead. Christopher Reeve does a good job as a doctor trying to help the kids while Kirstie Alley plays the woman who is really trying to help and understand them. While far from a good film, VILLAGE OF THE DAMNED still doesn't deserve the bad rep it's gotten over the years.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bad movie and useless remake
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vostf (vik@noos.fr)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The original Village of the Damned (Wolf Rilla, 1960) was a very good movie. Why remake it? It was very good because every plot point was simple and not overstated, which helped create tension with little. The Carpenter movie only "adds" useless stuff to the basic premise of evil children mysteriously conceived during the blackout of an entire village. More graphic violence, longer discussions about the phenomenon: isn't the tension better if we are left to let the violence grow in our global experience, not just as artifacts of the story? Dozens of cops, soldiers, firemen... and the token government scientist blinded by her outstanding research: this is no longer a small village cut from the world, this is a disaster movie set. I can't understand the urge for Carpenter to shoot such a bad script while the original story and adaptation must have been way better.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "One Of Carpenter's Most Underrated Films!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gwnightscream
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Christopher Reeve, Kirstie Alley and Linda Kozlowski star in John Carpenter's 1995 sci-fi remake of the 1960 film and based on the book, "The Midwich Cuckoos." After a mysterious force invades a town, 8 children are born the same time with alien-like powers. The town of Midwich experiences something strange when an unseen force invades the town and makes the residents pass out for 6 hours. That's not the only thing, a group of women are chosen to give birth to children at the same time who have alien-like powers that become a threat to the people. Reeve plays Alan Chaffee, a doctor who discovers what's happening and that his daughter, Mara is the leader of the children. Alley plays Susan Verner, a scientist who knows the truth about the children and Kozlowski plays Jill McGowan, a woman whose child, David is different than the others. This isn't bad and I think it's one of Carpenter's most underrated films. Reeve was great as usual and I recommend this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Some women give birth various strange children with supernatural power and extraordinary intelligence
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ma-cortes
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Acceptable Carpenter's remake with the premise is still interesting enough to watch it , dealing about several strangely emotionless children all born at the same time in a small village in Midwich . The scene is an American village of Midwich in which rare mist overcomes the idyllic coastal location . At the same moment, every single person and animal in town has passed out just as suddenly; some unknown force has put all the inhabitants of Midwich to sleep. Everybody falls into a deep, mysterious sleep for several hours in the middle of the day. When the army gets involved, they find this force has precise boundaries. A few hours later, this strange force disappears and everyone wakes up. The mystery remains unsolved for weeks, but it has a sequel. Some months later every woman (Linda Kozlowski , Meredith Salenger) capable of child-bearing is pregnant . All Midwich women of childbearing age are unaccountably pregnant. And the glowing-eyed children they have will prove to be worse than what they could have feared. The children that are born out of these pregnancies seem to grow very fast and they all have the same blond hair and strange, penetrating eyes that make people do things they don't want to do ; all of them have telephatic powers . They result to be mind-controlling demons or aliens . Meanwhile the doctor (good performance by Christopher Reeve) along with a scientist (Kirstie Alley in a new role who doesn't appear in the former film and doesn't do much sense) attempt to stop their plans of conquest . This Sci-Fi thriller contains chills , suspense , intrigue and creepy events about some precocious deadly children and their quest of power . However, it suffers from unimaginative account because being a copy from original film (1960) by Wolf Rilla with more violent and explicit scenes and fails to provide the intelligent atmosphere from previous story . Furthermore , it packs better cinematography by Gary Kibbe who photographs colorful scenarios from the village .Suspenseful and thrilling musical score by the same director John Carpenter . Other renditions based on John Wyndham novel titled &uml;The Midwich cuckoos&uml; and well adapted by Stirling Silliphant are the following : The black and white classic (1960) by Wolf Rilla with George Sanders , Michael G. Wynne and Barbara Shelley and followed by &uml;Children of the damned (64)&uml; by Anton Leader with Ian Hendry , Alan Badel and Barbara Ferris . Rating : Acceptable and passable , providing pleasant screams for the viewer . Essential and indispensable seeing for John Carpenter followers .
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not A Disaster But Not Great Either
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Theo Robertson
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    John Carpenter's VILLAGE OF THE DAMNED is considered a rather weak film . With hindsight one would have expected more since his version of THE THING is considered a classic of genre horror . But did you know it isn't a reputation that was instant ? THE THING from 1982 totally bombed at the box office and many critics were turned off by the stomach churning visuals . The reputation grew down to the fact that ET influenced film makers in to making nice family films about cute aliens coming to Earth to be saved from the nasty humans by nice cute kids . Like wise THE THING special effects are indeed special where a crew of effects artists slaved day and night to create something special . By the mid 1990s film makers were getting lazy and relied on CGI . Even some like myself who hated THE THING on its initial release can appreciate it in a nostalgic light Hopes must have been high that Carpenter could weave a similar kind of magic to this remake and surpass the original but tellinglly as the credits come up you'll notice the 1960 screenplay by Stirling Silliphant is namechecked . Silliphant wrote a very faithful adaptation of the original Wyhdham novel and this shouldn't be viewed as a criticism . This means however that if you know the story there's not a lot of surprises to the story . There also seems to be a bit of compromise involved and that is Carpenter includes violent scenes that are in no way gory . I did appreciate the lack of gore such as when Kirsty Alley's spook disembowel's herself but can understand why some people didn't like and would have preferred a bit more blood . Likewise the final shoot out seems to be included to put a bit of action in to a movie that by its very mechanics is a very slow burning type of mystery and does tend to jar with the rest of the story In all VILLAGE OF THE DAMNED is by no means a bad film , certainly not as bad as some people claim it to be but by the same yard stick there's no one claiming it's any way better than the original 1960 British film , probably down to a lack of embellishment and a very much TVM feel to the proceedings
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Where's a flamethrower when you need one?!?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jt1999
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Or an Uzi. Or a shotgun. Or a good old-fashioned Gatling Gun. Doesn't matter... whoever might have managed to get ahold of one would have done what every other friggin' character does in this film: walk up to the platinum blonde kids from hell, and instead firing off a couple of rounds, stand there idiotically for about ten or fifteen seconds. Brilliant! Give those kids plenty of time to kill you, that's what you want to do! Don't shoot, don't bash their brains in -- just wait there a good, long time until their eyes start glowing. This idiotic direction is emblematic of the entire film: it just sits there, doing almost nothing. Could have been directed by a sleepwalker... and that's with all due respect to Mr. Carpenter. Music certainly didn't help either. In fact, it helped ruin the entire film. Sorry, John. Got to put in a little more effort when re-making a classic. Kind of like you did when you re-made "The Thing." Remember those days? No, didn't think so.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stick with the original
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This bland rehash of the 1960 original is not without effective moments, but they're all in the first twenty minutes and things get mighty dull from that point on. Once the set-up is out of the way  small village, strange spell, mysterious pregnancies, spooky children  what atmosphere has been established disappears and the film becomes increasingly reliant on cheesy glowing-eye effects and repetitious killings. The characters don't ring true, either; they accept the bizarre events rather easily. On the plus side, there's a solid performance from Christopher Reeve and the score has its moments.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bland remake
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    atinder
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Village of the Damned (1995) Frist of all, I Don't The original was even that good but at least kept in in and moved forward and at more creepy feel to the movie. I did think movie would be better as John Carpenter did this remake, So I looking forward to it but soon as the movie started I knew this movie not going to be good. I didn't really like how they kinda change the story and gave really lame back story to kids being bored, there not one moment did have this kids creepy or scary at all, it was tame from start to end and never feel moved forward as the movie was such their I thought this was going to be a lot more better, so how they about to die, we actually see the death scenes in this movie, seen before and the aftermath but not when happens, it cuts way to the kids was lights in there eyes. The acting was really wooden by some of the main cast, I don't maybe they took make this more main stream movie, I think must worst John carpenter movie but a least movie wasn't boring, it maybe a little intruded how the movie going pan out, even that ending was a load of rubbish. 2 out of 10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Rated R for what?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    utahman1971
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    OK, I saw this in theater when it was release in 1995. I recently saw it again in its original format. I can't see where the rating R is at in this movie. There is hardly any bad language. There is barely any blood. There is a little action. There is nothing to claim it to be rated R. I can name another movie done the same "Dead Silence". I can the ones making the ratings making stupid mistakes, but that stupid is really stupid. Almost about as dumb as having rated PG-13 horror movies, and saying they are horror. I can sit through every single PG-13 wanna be called horror movies, and pretty much fall asleep through them. That is how sad those Directors are. They want to go towards wider range of people. When then call them thrillers, because that is really what they are. Thrillers are for chillers, and horror is for gore. I am sick of good Ole horror movies that have the gore to go with the horror are getting terrible ratings while the lame PG-13 chillers are getting better ratings. I will say it until I die, that those PG-13 so called horror that are really chiller thrillers should never be called horror. Just the claim is dumber than snot. As for the gore, it isn't real blood or guts. Its all fake. So if you can't handle it something is wrong with that person, not the movie. There needs to be more Directors that can make horror a horror movie that is the right rating for the movie, and not the boring wanna be crap.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Enjoyable movie. Forget Carpenter.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    midge56
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is still enjoyable to watch despite Carpenter. In fact, Carpenter had no business entitling this movie as his own since it was not his story or his screenplay in the first place. That was pure, unearned ego on his part as he tries to make his fame by latching onto the brilliant efforts of the original films & writers. Carpenter only added unnecessary, offensive gore to an already great story. The effects on the eyes were good & the extended gov't involvement with more focus on science than paranoia was also a refreshing addition as was the stillborn specimen (but that should have included more details on the lab findings than we got.) The priest character was OK until he became a suicidal gun nut which was ridiculous on too many levels to list. The boiling pot, self evisceration, barbecue, consumption by inferno & "walking tall" gun battle were just intolerable gore which added nothing to the movie. The original movie only had the children harming someone who had caused them harm or perceived as intended. This movie had them killing the innocent for no reason. That seriously degraded the story. The original contained unjustifiable gov't paranoia over acts of self-defense. By the killing of innocents such as the mothers suicides which made no sense whatsoever, it justified the paranoia to kill the children. The original idea was the children were unfairly judged because they were different & had unique abilities; acting only in self defense. I did like the survival ending on the new version. That could make an excellent sequel. It is a mistake to remake popular movies like this film, The Omen & Stepford Wives which were already great to begin with. (& never ridicule a cult classic such as was done with Stepford). Only an idiot would take plot change advice from disgruntled complainers instead of fans. It would be OK to colorize BW films and beef up the special effects & sound improvements on the originals for redistribution as was done for Star Wars & Star Trek. Sequels of great cliffhanger films would be much better ideas to pursue if done in the spirit of the original story. But it is a bad idea to redo an original classic verbatim without offering much more to the story. The desire to see more details & missing parts of the stories is what makes deleted scenes so popular with the public. They don't like to be left hanging in the dark. Hence, the need for a sequel on such movies. Not a remake of the same hanging, unanswered questions which offers nothing extra to fans. It would be better to make follow up sequels on these popular stories rather than trying to duplicate the original verbatim with a completely different cast. There's also nothing worse than an actor doing a popular film remake, who refuses to watch the original or a director who makes changes simply to imprint their ego onto it like a dog marking a hydrant. We might like to see what happens if the children survived & learn the source of their origins; as well as endings where they are successful in survival & goals as well as exceptions to their demeanor like David with multi-layered personalities. Classic films should not be used as a venue for some egomaniacal director to headline his name on the title of a movie he didn't write as Carpenter has been repeatedly guilty of doing. Perhaps he should do something original for a change rather than riding on the coat tails of someone else's ideas & efforts. Don't listen to the opinions of people who get off on gore. They are only happy with chainsaw, saw & serial hacking butcher type Jason films with no appreciation for thrilling & innovative story lines. This classic, one of a kind story has captivated audiences for over 50 years since it was first released. So even a glory stealer like Carpenter can't do too much damage to ruin it. So forget Carpenter. The actors did a good job portraying their roles despite his direction. This new version of the movie is still based on the original classic so it is still enjoyable to watch if you use the fast forward to elude the gore scenes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not As Bad As It's Reputation
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Village of the Damned (1995) ** 1/2 (out of 4) John Carpenter's remake of the 1960 British film took an incredible beating when it was first released and while it's not as good as the original film, there are enough good moments to make it worth sitting through if you're a fan of the director. Basically what we have here is a small town that comes under attack by nine children who were all born on the same night after their mothers became pregnant during a bizarre blackout. Soon the kids are forcing the adults around them to either self mutilate or kill themselves. VILLAGE OF THE DAMNED started off pretty strong but then the screenplay simply ran out of fresh ideas and we're left with just one routine scene after another. As much as I'm against the heated hatred some show this film, there's still no question that it should have been much better considering who was directing it. I think some of the film's faults have to go to Carpenter because the biggest problem is that the children are never scary. Not once did I ever really feel threatened by them and saying Carpenter didn't make something scary is pretty rare. I did like the visual style and look that he gave the film and especially during the early scenes where the blackout occurs. I thought the first portion of the film was the most interesting as it deals with the blackout, the effects of the events and of course the women in the town getting pregnant. The second half of the film pretty much just becomes routine as one adult makes the kids mad after another and they all end up dead. Christopher Reeve does a good job as a doctor trying to help the kids while Kirstie Alley plays the woman who is really trying to help and understand them. While far from a good film, VILLAGE OF THE DAMNED still doesn't deserve the bad rep it's gotten over the years.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bad movie and useless remake
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vostf (vik@noos.fr)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The original Village of the Damned (Wolf Rilla, 1960) was a very good movie. Why remake it? It was very good because every plot point was simple and not overstated, which helped create tension with little. The Carpenter movie only "adds" useless stuff to the basic premise of evil children mysteriously conceived during the blackout of an entire village. More graphic violence, longer discussions about the phenomenon: isn't the tension better if we are left to let the violence grow in our global experience, not just as artifacts of the story? Dozens of cops, soldiers, firemen... and the token government scientist blinded by her outstanding research: this is no longer a small village cut from the world, this is a disaster movie set. I can't understand the urge for Carpenter to shoot such a bad script while the original story and adaptation must have been way better.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "One Of Carpenter's Most Underrated Films!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gwnightscream
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Christopher Reeve, Kirstie Alley and Linda Kozlowski star in John Carpenter's 1995 sci-fi remake of the 1960 film and based on the book, "The Midwich Cuckoos." After a mysterious force invades a town, 8 children are born the same time with alien-like powers. The town of Midwich experiences something strange when an unseen force invades the town and makes the residents pass out for 6 hours. That's not the only thing, a group of women are chosen to give birth to children at the same time who have alien-like powers that become a threat to the people. Reeve plays Alan Chaffee, a doctor who discovers what's happening and that his daughter, Mara is the leader of the children. Alley plays Susan Verner, a scientist who knows the truth about the children and Kozlowski plays Jill McGowan, a woman whose child, David is different than the others. This isn't bad and I think it's one of Carpenter's most underrated films. Reeve was great as usual and I recommend this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Some women give birth various strange children with supernatural power and extraordinary intelligence
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ma-cortes
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Acceptable Carpenter's remake with the premise is still interesting enough to watch it , dealing about several strangely emotionless children all born at the same time in a small village in Midwich . The scene is an American village of Midwich in which rare mist overcomes the idyllic coastal location . At the same moment, every single person and animal in town has passed out just as suddenly; some unknown force has put all the inhabitants of Midwich to sleep. Everybody falls into a deep, mysterious sleep for several hours in the middle of the day. When the army gets involved, they find this force has precise boundaries. A few hours later, this strange force disappears and everyone wakes up. The mystery remains unsolved for weeks, but it has a sequel. Some months later every woman (Linda Kozlowski , Meredith Salenger) capable of child-bearing is pregnant . All Midwich women of childbearing age are unaccountably pregnant. And the glowing-eyed children they have will prove to be worse than what they could have feared. The children that are born out of these pregnancies seem to grow very fast and they all have the same blond hair and strange, penetrating eyes that make people do things they don't want to do ; all of them have telephatic powers . They result to be mind-controlling demons or aliens . Meanwhile the doctor (good performance by Christopher Reeve) along with a scientist (Kirstie Alley in a new role who doesn't appear in the former film and doesn't do much sense) attempt to stop their plans of conquest . This Sci-Fi thriller contains chills , suspense , intrigue and creepy events about some precocious deadly children and their quest of power . However, it suffers from unimaginative account because being a copy from original film (1960) by Wolf Rilla with more violent and explicit scenes and fails to provide the intelligent atmosphere from previous story . Furthermore , it packs better cinematography by Gary Kibbe who photographs colorful scenarios from the village .Suspenseful and thrilling musical score by the same director John Carpenter . Other renditions based on John Wyndham novel titled &uml;The Midwich cuckoos&uml; and well adapted by Stirling Silliphant are the following : The black and white classic (1960) by Wolf Rilla with George Sanders , Michael G. Wynne and Barbara Shelley and followed by &uml;Children of the damned (64)&uml; by Anton Leader with Ian Hendry , Alan Badel and Barbara Ferris . Rating : Acceptable and passable , providing pleasant screams for the viewer . Essential and indispensable seeing for John Carpenter followers .
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not A Disaster But Not Great Either
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Theo Robertson
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    John Carpenter's VILLAGE OF THE DAMNED is considered a rather weak film . With hindsight one would have expected more since his version of THE THING is considered a classic of genre horror . But did you know it isn't a reputation that was instant ? THE THING from 1982 totally bombed at the box office and many critics were turned off by the stomach churning visuals . The reputation grew down to the fact that ET influenced film makers in to making nice family films about cute aliens coming to Earth to be saved from the nasty humans by nice cute kids . Like wise THE THING special effects are indeed special where a crew of effects artists slaved day and night to create something special . By the mid 1990s film makers were getting lazy and relied on CGI . Even some like myself who hated THE THING on its initial release can appreciate it in a nostalgic light Hopes must have been high that Carpenter could weave a similar kind of magic to this remake and surpass the original but tellinglly as the credits come up you'll notice the 1960 screenplay by Stirling Silliphant is namechecked . Silliphant wrote a very faithful adaptation of the original Wyhdham novel and this shouldn't be viewed as a criticism . This means however that if you know the story there's not a lot of surprises to the story . There also seems to be a bit of compromise involved and that is Carpenter includes violent scenes that are in no way gory . I did appreciate the lack of gore such as when Kirsty Alley's spook disembowel's herself but can understand why some people didn't like and would have preferred a bit more blood . Likewise the final shoot out seems to be included to put a bit of action in to a movie that by its very mechanics is a very slow burning type of mystery and does tend to jar with the rest of the story In all VILLAGE OF THE DAMNED is by no means a bad film , certainly not as bad as some people claim it to be but by the same yard stick there's no one claiming it's any way better than the original 1960 British film , probably down to a lack of embellishment and a very much TVM feel to the proceedings
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Where's a flamethrower when you need one?!?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jt1999
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Or an Uzi. Or a shotgun. Or a good old-fashioned Gatling Gun. Doesn't matter... whoever might have managed to get ahold of one would have done what every other friggin' character does in this film: walk up to the platinum blonde kids from hell, and instead firing off a couple of rounds, stand there idiotically for about ten or fifteen seconds. Brilliant! Give those kids plenty of time to kill you, that's what you want to do! Don't shoot, don't bash their brains in -- just wait there a good, long time until their eyes start glowing. This idiotic direction is emblematic of the entire film: it just sits there, doing almost nothing. Could have been directed by a sleepwalker... and that's with all due respect to Mr. Carpenter. Music certainly didn't help either. In fact, it helped ruin the entire film. Sorry, John. Got to put in a little more effort when re-making a classic. Kind of like you did when you re-made "The Thing." Remember those days? No, didn't think so.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stick with the original
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This bland rehash of the 1960 original is not without effective moments, but they're all in the first twenty minutes and things get mighty dull from that point on. Once the set-up is out of the way  small village, strange spell, mysterious pregnancies, spooky children  what atmosphere has been established disappears and the film becomes increasingly reliant on cheesy glowing-eye effects and repetitious killings. The characters don't ring true, either; they accept the bizarre events rather easily. On the plus side, there's a solid performance from Christopher Reeve and the score has its moments.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bland remake
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    atinder
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Village of the Damned (1995) Frist of all, I Don't The original was even that good but at least kept in in and moved forward and at more creepy feel to the movie. I did think movie would be better as John Carpenter did this remake, So I looking forward to it but soon as the movie started I knew this movie not going to be good. I didn't really like how they kinda change the story and gave really lame back story to kids being bored, there not one moment did have this kids creepy or scary at all, it was tame from start to end and never feel moved forward as the movie was such their I thought this was going to be a lot more better, so how they about to die, we actually see the death scenes in this movie, seen before and the aftermath but not when happens, it cuts way to the kids was lights in there eyes. The acting was really wooden by some of the main cast, I don't maybe they took make this more main stream movie, I think must worst John carpenter movie but a least movie wasn't boring, it maybe a little intruded how the movie going pan out, even that ending was a load of rubbish. 2 out of 10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Rated R for what?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    utahman1971
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    OK, I saw this in theater when it was release in 1995. I recently saw it again in its original format. I can't see where the rating R is at in this movie. There is hardly any bad language. There is barely any blood. There is a little action. There is nothing to claim it to be rated R. I can name another movie done the same "Dead Silence". I can the ones making the ratings making stupid mistakes, but that stupid is really stupid. Almost about as dumb as having rated PG-13 horror movies, and saying they are horror. I can sit through every single PG-13 wanna be called horror movies, and pretty much fall asleep through them. That is how sad those Directors are. They want to go towards wider range of people. When then call them thrillers, because that is really what they are. Thrillers are for chillers, and horror is for gore. I am sick of good Ole horror movies that have the gore to go with the horror are getting terrible ratings while the lame PG-13 chillers are getting better ratings. I will say it until I die, that those PG-13 so called horror that are really chiller thrillers should never be called horror. Just the claim is dumber than snot. As for the gore, it isn't real blood or guts. Its all fake. So if you can't handle it something is wrong with that person, not the movie. There needs to be more Directors that can make horror a horror movie that is the right rating for the movie, and not the boring wanna be crap.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Enjoyable movie. Forget Carpenter.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    midge56
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is still enjoyable to watch despite Carpenter. In fact, Carpenter had no business entitling this movie as his own since it was not his story or his screenplay in the first place. That was pure, unearned ego on his part as he tries to make his fame by latching onto the brilliant efforts of the original films & writers. Carpenter only added unnecessary, offensive gore to an already great story. The effects on the eyes were good & the extended gov't involvement with more focus on science than paranoia was also a refreshing addition as was the stillborn specimen (but that should have included more details on the lab findings than we got.) The priest character was OK until he became a suicidal gun nut which was ridiculous on too many levels to list. The boiling pot, self evisceration, barbecue, consumption by inferno & "walking tall" gun battle were just intolerable gore which added nothing to the movie. The original movie only had the children harming someone who had caused them harm or perceived as intended. This movie had them killing the innocent for no reason. That seriously degraded the story. The original contained unjustifiable gov't paranoia over acts of self-defense. By the killing of innocents such as the mothers suicides which made no sense whatsoever, it justified the paranoia to kill the children. The original idea was the children were unfairly judged because they were different & had unique abilities; acting only in self defense. I did like the survival ending on the new version. That could make an excellent sequel. It is a mistake to remake popular movies like this film, The Omen & Stepford Wives which were already great to begin with. (& never ridicule a cult classic such as was done with Stepford). Only an idiot would take plot change advice from disgruntled complainers instead of fans. It would be OK to colorize BW films and beef up the special effects & sound improvements on the originals for redistribution as was done for Star Wars & Star Trek. Sequels of great cliffhanger films would be much better ideas to pursue if done in the spirit of the original story. But it is a bad idea to redo an original classic verbatim without offering much more to the story. The desire to see more details & missing parts of the stories is what makes deleted scenes so popular with the public. They don't like to be left hanging in the dark. Hence, the need for a sequel on such movies. Not a remake of the same hanging, unanswered questions which offers nothing extra to fans. It would be better to make follow up sequels on these popular stories rather than trying to duplicate the original verbatim with a completely different cast. There's also nothing worse than an actor doing a popular film remake, who refuses to watch the original or a director who makes changes simply to imprint their ego onto it like a dog marking a hydrant. We might like to see what happens if the children survived & learn the source of their origins; as well as endings where they are successful in survival & goals as well as exceptions to their demeanor like David with multi-layered personalities. Classic films should not be used as a venue for some egomaniacal director to headline his name on the title of a movie he didn't write as Carpenter has been repeatedly guilty of doing. Perhaps he should do something original for a change rather than riding on the coat tails of someone else's ideas & efforts. Don't listen to the opinions of people who get off on gore. They are only happy with chainsaw, saw & serial hacking butcher type Jason films with no appreciation for thrilling & innovative story lines. This classic, one of a kind story has captivated audiences for over 50 years since it was first released. So even a glory stealer like Carpenter can't do too much damage to ruin it. So forget Carpenter. The actors did a good job portraying their roles despite his direction. This new version of the movie is still based on the original classic so it is still enjoyable to watch if you use the fast forward to elude the gore scenes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not As Bad As It's Reputation
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Village of the Damned (1995) ** 1/2 (out of 4) John Carpenter's remake of the 1960 British film took an incredible beating when it was first released and while it's not as good as the original film, there are enough good moments to make it worth sitting through if you're a fan of the director. Basically what we have here is a small town that comes under attack by nine children who were all born on the same night after their mothers became pregnant during a bizarre blackout. Soon the kids are forcing the adults around them to either self mutilate or kill themselves. VILLAGE OF THE DAMNED started off pretty strong but then the screenplay simply ran out of fresh ideas and we're left with just one routine scene after another. As much as I'm against the heated hatred some show this film, there's still no question that it should have been much better considering who was directing it. I think some of the film's faults have to go to Carpenter because the biggest problem is that the children are never scary. Not once did I ever really feel threatened by them and saying Carpenter didn't make something scary is pretty rare. I did like the visual style and look that he gave the film and especially during the early scenes where the blackout occurs. I thought the first portion of the film was the most interesting as it deals with the blackout, the effects of the events and of course the women in the town getting pregnant. The second half of the film pretty much just becomes routine as one adult makes the kids mad after another and they all end up dead. Christopher Reeve does a good job as a doctor trying to help the kids while Kirstie Alley plays the woman who is really trying to help and understand them. While far from a good film, VILLAGE OF THE DAMNED still doesn't deserve the bad rep it's gotten over the years.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bad movie and useless remake
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vostf (vik@noos.fr)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The original Village of the Damned (Wolf Rilla, 1960) was a very good movie. Why remake it? It was very good because every plot point was simple and not overstated, which helped create tension with little. The Carpenter movie only "adds" useless stuff to the basic premise of evil children mysteriously conceived during the blackout of an entire village. More graphic violence, longer discussions about the phenomenon: isn't the tension better if we are left to let the violence grow in our global experience, not just as artifacts of the story? Dozens of cops, soldiers, firemen... and the token government scientist blinded by her outstanding research: this is no longer a small village cut from the world, this is a disaster movie set. I can't understand the urge for Carpenter to shoot such a bad script while the original story and adaptation must have been way better.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "One Of Carpenter's Most Underrated Films!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gwnightscream
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Christopher Reeve, Kirstie Alley and Linda Kozlowski star in John Carpenter's 1995 sci-fi remake of the 1960 film and based on the book, "The Midwich Cuckoos." After a mysterious force invades a town, 8 children are born the same time with alien-like powers. The town of Midwich experiences something strange when an unseen force invades the town and makes the residents pass out for 6 hours. That's not the only thing, a group of women are chosen to give birth to children at the same time who have alien-like powers that become a threat to the people. Reeve plays Alan Chaffee, a doctor who discovers what's happening and that his daughter, Mara is the leader of the children. Alley plays Susan Verner, a scientist who knows the truth about the children and Kozlowski plays Jill McGowan, a woman whose child, David is different than the others. This isn't bad and I think it's one of Carpenter's most underrated films. Reeve was great as usual and I recommend this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Some women give birth various strange children with supernatural power and extraordinary intelligence
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ma-cortes
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Acceptable Carpenter's remake with the premise is still interesting enough to watch it , dealing about several strangely emotionless children all born at the same time in a small village in Midwich . The scene is an American village of Midwich in which rare mist overcomes the idyllic coastal location . At the same moment, every single person and animal in town has passed out just as suddenly; some unknown force has put all the inhabitants of Midwich to sleep. Everybody falls into a deep, mysterious sleep for several hours in the middle of the day. When the army gets involved, they find this force has precise boundaries. A few hours later, this strange force disappears and everyone wakes up. The mystery remains unsolved for weeks, but it has a sequel. Some months later every woman (Linda Kozlowski , Meredith Salenger) capable of child-bearing is pregnant . All Midwich women of childbearing age are unaccountably pregnant. And the glowing-eyed children they have will prove to be worse than what they could have feared. The children that are born out of these pregnancies seem to grow very fast and they all have the same blond hair and strange, penetrating eyes that make people do things they don't want to do ; all of them have telephatic powers . They result to be mind-controlling demons or aliens . Meanwhile the doctor (good performance by Christopher Reeve) along with a scientist (Kirstie Alley in a new role who doesn't appear in the former film and doesn't do much sense) attempt to stop their plans of conquest . This Sci-Fi thriller contains chills , suspense , intrigue and creepy events about some precocious deadly children and their quest of power . However, it suffers from unimaginative account because being a copy from original film (1960) by Wolf Rilla with more violent and explicit scenes and fails to provide the intelligent atmosphere from previous story . Furthermore , it packs better cinematography by Gary Kibbe who photographs colorful scenarios from the village .Suspenseful and thrilling musical score by the same director John Carpenter . Other renditions based on John Wyndham novel titled &uml;The Midwich cuckoos&uml; and well adapted by Stirling Silliphant are the following : The black and white classic (1960) by Wolf Rilla with George Sanders , Michael G. Wynne and Barbara Shelley and followed by &uml;Children of the damned (64)&uml; by Anton Leader with Ian Hendry , Alan Badel and Barbara Ferris . Rating : Acceptable and passable , providing pleasant screams for the viewer . Essential and indispensable seeing for John Carpenter followers .
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not A Disaster But Not Great Either
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Theo Robertson
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    John Carpenter's VILLAGE OF THE DAMNED is considered a rather weak film . With hindsight one would have expected more since his version of THE THING is considered a classic of genre horror . But did you know it isn't a reputation that was instant ? THE THING from 1982 totally bombed at the box office and many critics were turned off by the stomach churning visuals . The reputation grew down to the fact that ET influenced film makers in to making nice family films about cute aliens coming to Earth to be saved from the nasty humans by nice cute kids . Like wise THE THING special effects are indeed special where a crew of effects artists slaved day and night to create something special . By the mid 1990s film makers were getting lazy and relied on CGI . Even some like myself who hated THE THING on its initial release can appreciate it in a nostalgic light Hopes must have been high that Carpenter could weave a similar kind of magic to this remake and surpass the original but tellinglly as the credits come up you'll notice the 1960 screenplay by Stirling Silliphant is namechecked . Silliphant wrote a very faithful adaptation of the original Wyhdham novel and this shouldn't be viewed as a criticism . This means however that if you know the story there's not a lot of surprises to the story . There also seems to be a bit of compromise involved and that is Carpenter includes violent scenes that are in no way gory . I did appreciate the lack of gore such as when Kirsty Alley's spook disembowel's herself but can understand why some people didn't like and would have preferred a bit more blood . Likewise the final shoot out seems to be included to put a bit of action in to a movie that by its very mechanics is a very slow burning type of mystery and does tend to jar with the rest of the story In all VILLAGE OF THE DAMNED is by no means a bad film , certainly not as bad as some people claim it to be but by the same yard stick there's no one claiming it's any way better than the original 1960 British film , probably down to a lack of embellishment and a very much TVM feel to the proceedings
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Where's a flamethrower when you need one?!?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jt1999
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Or an Uzi. Or a shotgun. Or a good old-fashioned Gatling Gun. Doesn't matter... whoever might have managed to get ahold of one would have done what every other friggin' character does in this film: walk up to the platinum blonde kids from hell, and instead firing off a couple of rounds, stand there idiotically for about ten or fifteen seconds. Brilliant! Give those kids plenty of time to kill you, that's what you want to do! Don't shoot, don't bash their brains in -- just wait there a good, long time until their eyes start glowing. This idiotic direction is emblematic of the entire film: it just sits there, doing almost nothing. Could have been directed by a sleepwalker... and that's with all due respect to Mr. Carpenter. Music certainly didn't help either. In fact, it helped ruin the entire film. Sorry, John. Got to put in a little more effort when re-making a classic. Kind of like you did when you re-made "The Thing." Remember those days? No, didn't think so.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stick with the original
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This bland rehash of the 1960 original is not without effective moments, but they're all in the first twenty minutes and things get mighty dull from that point on. Once the set-up is out of the way  small village, strange spell, mysterious pregnancies, spooky children  what atmosphere has been established disappears and the film becomes increasingly reliant on cheesy glowing-eye effects and repetitious killings. The characters don't ring true, either; they accept the bizarre events rather easily. On the plus side, there's a solid performance from Christopher Reeve and the score has its moments.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bland remake
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    atinder
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Village of the Damned (1995) Frist of all, I Don't The original was even that good but at least kept in in and moved forward and at more creepy feel to the movie. I did think movie would be better as John Carpenter did this remake, So I looking forward to it but soon as the movie started I knew this movie not going to be good. I didn't really like how they kinda change the story and gave really lame back story to kids being bored, there not one moment did have this kids creepy or scary at all, it was tame from start to end and never feel moved forward as the movie was such their I thought this was going to be a lot more better, so how they about to die, we actually see the death scenes in this movie, seen before and the aftermath but not when happens, it cuts way to the kids was lights in there eyes. The acting was really wooden by some of the main cast, I don't maybe they took make this more main stream movie, I think must worst John carpenter movie but a least movie wasn't boring, it maybe a little intruded how the movie going pan out, even that ending was a load of rubbish. 2 out of 10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Rated R for what?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    utahman1971
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    OK, I saw this in theater when it was release in 1995. I recently saw it again in its original format. I can't see where the rating R is at in this movie. There is hardly any bad language. There is barely any blood. There is a little action. There is nothing to claim it to be rated R. I can name another movie done the same "Dead Silence". I can the ones making the ratings making stupid mistakes, but that stupid is really stupid. Almost about as dumb as having rated PG-13 horror movies, and saying they are horror. I can sit through every single PG-13 wanna be called horror movies, and pretty much fall asleep through them. That is how sad those Directors are. They want to go towards wider range of people. When then call them thrillers, because that is really what they are. Thrillers are for chillers, and horror is for gore. I am sick of good Ole horror movies that have the gore to go with the horror are getting terrible ratings while the lame PG-13 chillers are getting better ratings. I will say it until I die, that those PG-13 so called horror that are really chiller thrillers should never be called horror. Just the claim is dumber than snot. As for the gore, it isn't real blood or guts. Its all fake. So if you can't handle it something is wrong with that person, not the movie. There needs to be more Directors that can make horror a horror movie that is the right rating for the movie, and not the boring wanna be crap.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Enjoyable movie. Forget Carpenter.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    midge56
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is still enjoyable to watch despite Carpenter. In fact, Carpenter had no business entitling this movie as his own since it was not his story or his screenplay in the first place. That was pure, unearned ego on his part as he tries to make his fame by latching onto the brilliant efforts of the original films & writers. Carpenter only added unnecessary, offensive gore to an already great story. The effects on the eyes were good & the extended gov't involvement with more focus on science than paranoia was also a refreshing addition as was the stillborn specimen (but that should have included more details on the lab findings than we got.) The priest character was OK until he became a suicidal gun nut which was ridiculous on too many levels to list. The boiling pot, self evisceration, barbecue, consumption by inferno & "walking tall" gun battle were just intolerable gore which added nothing to the movie. The original movie only had the children harming someone who had caused them harm or perceived as intended. This movie had them killing the innocent for no reason. That seriously degraded the story. The original contained unjustifiable gov't paranoia over acts of self-defense. By the killing of innocents such as the mothers suicides which made no sense whatsoever, it justified the paranoia to kill the children. The original idea was the children were unfairly judged because they were different & had unique abilities; acting only in self defense. I did like the survival ending on the new version. That could make an excellent sequel. It is a mistake to remake popular movies like this film, The Omen & Stepford Wives which were already great to begin with. (& never ridicule a cult classic such as was done with Stepford). Only an idiot would take plot change advice from disgruntled complainers instead of fans. It would be OK to colorize BW films and beef up the special effects & sound improvements on the originals for redistribution as was done for Star Wars & Star Trek. Sequels of great cliffhanger films would be much better ideas to pursue if done in the spirit of the original story. But it is a bad idea to redo an original classic verbatim without offering much more to the story. The desire to see more details & missing parts of the stories is what makes deleted scenes so popular with the public. They don't like to be left hanging in the dark. Hence, the need for a sequel on such movies. Not a remake of the same hanging, unanswered questions which offers nothing extra to fans. It would be better to make follow up sequels on these popular stories rather than trying to duplicate the original verbatim with a completely different cast. There's also nothing worse than an actor doing a popular film remake, who refuses to watch the original or a director who makes changes simply to imprint their ego onto it like a dog marking a hydrant. We might like to see what happens if the children survived & learn the source of their origins; as well as endings where they are successful in survival & goals as well as exceptions to their demeanor like David with multi-layered personalities. Classic films should not be used as a venue for some egomaniacal director to headline his name on the title of a movie he didn't write as Carpenter has been repeatedly guilty of doing. Perhaps he should do something original for a change rather than riding on the coat tails of someone else's ideas & efforts. Don't listen to the opinions of people who get off on gore. They are only happy with chainsaw, saw & serial hacking butcher type Jason films with no appreciation for thrilling & innovative story lines. This classic, one of a kind story has captivated audiences for over 50 years since it was first released. So even a glory stealer like Carpenter can't do too much damage to ruin it. So forget Carpenter. The actors did a good job portraying their roles despite his direction. This new version of the movie is still based on the original classic so it is still enjoyable to watch if you use the fast forward to elude the gore scenes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not As Bad As It's Reputation
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Village of the Damned (1995) ** 1/2 (out of 4) John Carpenter's remake of the 1960 British film took an incredible beating when it was first released and while it's not as good as the original film, there are enough good moments to make it worth sitting through if you're a fan of the director. Basically what we have here is a small town that comes under attack by nine children who were all born on the same night after their mothers became pregnant during a bizarre blackout. Soon the kids are forcing the adults around them to either self mutilate or kill themselves. VILLAGE OF THE DAMNED started off pretty strong but then the screenplay simply ran out of fresh ideas and we're left with just one routine scene after another. As much as I'm against the heated hatred some show this film, there's still no question that it should have been much better considering who was directing it. I think some of the film's faults have to go to Carpenter because the biggest problem is that the children are never scary. Not once did I ever really feel threatened by them and saying Carpenter didn't make something scary is pretty rare. I did like the visual style and look that he gave the film and especially during the early scenes where the blackout occurs. I thought the first portion of the film was the most interesting as it deals with the blackout, the effects of the events and of course the women in the town getting pregnant. The second half of the film pretty much just becomes routine as one adult makes the kids mad after another and they all end up dead. Christopher Reeve does a good job as a doctor trying to help the kids while Kirstie Alley plays the woman who is really trying to help and understand them. While far from a good film, VILLAGE OF THE DAMNED still doesn't deserve the bad rep it's gotten over the years.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bad movie and useless remake
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vostf (vik@noos.fr)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The original Village of the Damned (Wolf Rilla, 1960) was a very good movie. Why remake it? It was very good because every plot point was simple and not overstated, which helped create tension with little. The Carpenter movie only "adds" useless stuff to the basic premise of evil children mysteriously conceived during the blackout of an entire village. More graphic violence, longer discussions about the phenomenon: isn't the tension better if we are left to let the violence grow in our global experience, not just as artifacts of the story? Dozens of cops, soldiers, firemen... and the token government scientist blinded by her outstanding research: this is no longer a small village cut from the world, this is a disaster movie set. I can't understand the urge for Carpenter to shoot such a bad script while the original story and adaptation must have been way better.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "One Of Carpenter's Most Underrated Films!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gwnightscream
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Christopher Reeve, Kirstie Alley and Linda Kozlowski star in John Carpenter's 1995 sci-fi remake of the 1960 film and based on the book, "The Midwich Cuckoos." After a mysterious force invades a town, 8 children are born the same time with alien-like powers. The town of Midwich experiences something strange when an unseen force invades the town and makes the residents pass out for 6 hours. That's not the only thing, a group of women are chosen to give birth to children at the same time who have alien-like powers that become a threat to the people. Reeve plays Alan Chaffee, a doctor who discovers what's happening and that his daughter, Mara is the leader of the children. Alley plays Susan Verner, a scientist who knows the truth about the children and Kozlowski plays Jill McGowan, a woman whose child, David is different than the others. This isn't bad and I think it's one of Carpenter's most underrated films. Reeve was great as usual and I recommend this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Some women give birth various strange children with supernatural power and extraordinary intelligence
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ma-cortes
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Acceptable Carpenter's remake with the premise is still interesting enough to watch it , dealing about several strangely emotionless children all born at the same time in a small village in Midwich . The scene is an American village of Midwich in which rare mist overcomes the idyllic coastal location . At the same moment, every single person and animal in town has passed out just as suddenly; some unknown force has put all the inhabitants of Midwich to sleep. Everybody falls into a deep, mysterious sleep for several hours in the middle of the day. When the army gets involved, they find this force has precise boundaries. A few hours later, this strange force disappears and everyone wakes up. The mystery remains unsolved for weeks, but it has a sequel. Some months later every woman (Linda Kozlowski , Meredith Salenger) capable of child-bearing is pregnant . All Midwich women of childbearing age are unaccountably pregnant. And the glowing-eyed children they have will prove to be worse than what they could have feared. The children that are born out of these pregnancies seem to grow very fast and they all have the same blond hair and strange, penetrating eyes that make people do things they don't want to do ; all of them have telephatic powers . They result to be mind-controlling demons or aliens . Meanwhile the doctor (good performance by Christopher Reeve) along with a scientist (Kirstie Alley in a new role who doesn't appear in the former film and doesn't do much sense) attempt to stop their plans of conquest . This Sci-Fi thriller contains chills , suspense , intrigue and creepy events about some precocious deadly children and their quest of power . However, it suffers from unimaginative account because being a copy from original film (1960) by Wolf Rilla with more violent and explicit scenes and fails to provide the intelligent atmosphere from previous story . Furthermore , it packs better cinematography by Gary Kibbe who photographs colorful scenarios from the village .Suspenseful and thrilling musical score by the same director John Carpenter . Other renditions based on John Wyndham novel titled &uml;The Midwich cuckoos&uml; and well adapted by Stirling Silliphant are the following : The black and white classic (1960) by Wolf Rilla with George Sanders , Michael G. Wynne and Barbara Shelley and followed by &uml;Children of the damned (64)&uml; by Anton Leader with Ian Hendry , Alan Badel and Barbara Ferris . Rating : Acceptable and passable , providing pleasant screams for the viewer . Essential and indispensable seeing for John Carpenter followers .
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not A Disaster But Not Great Either
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Theo Robertson
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    John Carpenter's VILLAGE OF THE DAMNED is considered a rather weak film . With hindsight one would have expected more since his version of THE THING is considered a classic of genre horror . But did you know it isn't a reputation that was instant ? THE THING from 1982 totally bombed at the box office and many critics were turned off by the stomach churning visuals . The reputation grew down to the fact that ET influenced film makers in to making nice family films about cute aliens coming to Earth to be saved from the nasty humans by nice cute kids . Like wise THE THING special effects are indeed special where a crew of effects artists slaved day and night to create something special . By the mid 1990s film makers were getting lazy and relied on CGI . Even some like myself who hated THE THING on its initial release can appreciate it in a nostalgic light Hopes must have been high that Carpenter could weave a similar kind of magic to this remake and surpass the original but tellinglly as the credits come up you'll notice the 1960 screenplay by Stirling Silliphant is namechecked . Silliphant wrote a very faithful adaptation of the original Wyhdham novel and this shouldn't be viewed as a criticism . This means however that if you know the story there's not a lot of surprises to the story . There also seems to be a bit of compromise involved and that is Carpenter includes violent scenes that are in no way gory . I did appreciate the lack of gore such as when Kirsty Alley's spook disembowel's herself but can understand why some people didn't like and would have preferred a bit more blood . Likewise the final shoot out seems to be included to put a bit of action in to a movie that by its very mechanics is a very slow burning type of mystery and does tend to jar with the rest of the story In all VILLAGE OF THE DAMNED is by no means a bad film , certainly not as bad as some people claim it to be but by the same yard stick there's no one claiming it's any way better than the original 1960 British film , probably down to a lack of embellishment and a very much TVM feel to the proceedings
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Where's a flamethrower when you need one?!?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jt1999
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Or an Uzi. Or a shotgun. Or a good old-fashioned Gatling Gun. Doesn't matter... whoever might have managed to get ahold of one would have done what every other friggin' character does in this film: walk up to the platinum blonde kids from hell, and instead firing off a couple of rounds, stand there idiotically for about ten or fifteen seconds. Brilliant! Give those kids plenty of time to kill you, that's what you want to do! Don't shoot, don't bash their brains in -- just wait there a good, long time until their eyes start glowing. This idiotic direction is emblematic of the entire film: it just sits there, doing almost nothing. Could have been directed by a sleepwalker... and that's with all due respect to Mr. Carpenter. Music certainly didn't help either. In fact, it helped ruin the entire film. Sorry, John. Got to put in a little more effort when re-making a classic. Kind of like you did when you re-made "The Thing." Remember those days? No, didn't think so.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stick with the original
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This bland rehash of the 1960 original is not without effective moments, but they're all in the first twenty minutes and things get mighty dull from that point on. Once the set-up is out of the way  small village, strange spell, mysterious pregnancies, spooky children  what atmosphere has been established disappears and the film becomes increasingly reliant on cheesy glowing-eye effects and repetitious killings. The characters don't ring true, either; they accept the bizarre events rather easily. On the plus side, there's a solid performance from Christopher Reeve and the score has its moments.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bland remake
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    atinder
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Village of the Damned (1995) Frist of all, I Don't The original was even that good but at least kept in in and moved forward and at more creepy feel to the movie. I did think movie would be better as John Carpenter did this remake, So I looking forward to it but soon as the movie started I knew this movie not going to be good. I didn't really like how they kinda change the story and gave really lame back story to kids being bored, there not one moment did have this kids creepy or scary at all, it was tame from start to end and never feel moved forward as the movie was such their I thought this was going to be a lot more better, so how they about to die, we actually see the death scenes in this movie, seen before and the aftermath but not when happens, it cuts way to the kids was lights in there eyes. The acting was really wooden by some of the main cast, I don't maybe they took make this more main stream movie, I think must worst John carpenter movie but a least movie wasn't boring, it maybe a little intruded how the movie going pan out, even that ending was a load of rubbish. 2 out of 10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Rated R for what?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    utahman1971
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    OK, I saw this in theater when it was release in 1995. I recently saw it again in its original format. I can't see where the rating R is at in this movie. There is hardly any bad language. There is barely any blood. There is a little action. There is nothing to claim it to be rated R. I can name another movie done the same "Dead Silence". I can the ones making the ratings making stupid mistakes, but that stupid is really stupid. Almost about as dumb as having rated PG-13 horror movies, and saying they are horror. I can sit through every single PG-13 wanna be called horror movies, and pretty much fall asleep through them. That is how sad those Directors are. They want to go towards wider range of people. When then call them thrillers, because that is really what they are. Thrillers are for chillers, and horror is for gore. I am sick of good Ole horror movies that have the gore to go with the horror are getting terrible ratings while the lame PG-13 chillers are getting better ratings. I will say it until I die, that those PG-13 so called horror that are really chiller thrillers should never be called horror. Just the claim is dumber than snot. As for the gore, it isn't real blood or guts. Its all fake. So if you can't handle it something is wrong with that person, not the movie. There needs to be more Directors that can make horror a horror movie that is the right rating for the movie, and not the boring wanna be crap.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Enjoyable movie. Forget Carpenter.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    midge56
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is still enjoyable to watch despite Carpenter. In fact, Carpenter had no business entitling this movie as his own since it was not his story or his screenplay in the first place. That was pure, unearned ego on his part as he tries to make his fame by latching onto the brilliant efforts of the original films & writers. Carpenter only added unnecessary, offensive gore to an already great story. The effects on the eyes were good & the extended gov't involvement with more focus on science than paranoia was also a refreshing addition as was the stillborn specimen (but that should have included more details on the lab findings than we got.) The priest character was OK until he became a suicidal gun nut which was ridiculous on too many levels to list. The boiling pot, self evisceration, barbecue, consumption by inferno & "walking tall" gun battle were just intolerable gore which added nothing to the movie. The original movie only had the children harming someone who had caused them harm or perceived as intended. This movie had them killing the innocent for no reason. That seriously degraded the story. The original contained unjustifiable gov't paranoia over acts of self-defense. By the killing of innocents such as the mothers suicides which made no sense whatsoever, it justified the paranoia to kill the children. The original idea was the children were unfairly judged because they were different & had unique abilities; acting only in self defense. I did like the survival ending on the new version. That could make an excellent sequel. It is a mistake to remake popular movies like this film, The Omen & Stepford Wives which were already great to begin with. (& never ridicule a cult classic such as was done with Stepford). Only an idiot would take plot change advice from disgruntled complainers instead of fans. It would be OK to colorize BW films and beef up the special effects & sound improvements on the originals for redistribution as was done for Star Wars & Star Trek. Sequels of great cliffhanger films would be much better ideas to pursue if done in the spirit of the original story. But it is a bad idea to redo an original classic verbatim without offering much more to the story. The desire to see more details & missing parts of the stories is what makes deleted scenes so popular with the public. They don't like to be left hanging in the dark. Hence, the need for a sequel on such movies. Not a remake of the same hanging, unanswered questions which offers nothing extra to fans. It would be better to make follow up sequels on these popular stories rather than trying to duplicate the original verbatim with a completely different cast. There's also nothing worse than an actor doing a popular film remake, who refuses to watch the original or a director who makes changes simply to imprint their ego onto it like a dog marking a hydrant. We might like to see what happens if the children survived & learn the source of their origins; as well as endings where they are successful in survival & goals as well as exceptions to their demeanor like David with multi-layered personalities. Classic films should not be used as a venue for some egomaniacal director to headline his name on the title of a movie he didn't write as Carpenter has been repeatedly guilty of doing. Perhaps he should do something original for a change rather than riding on the coat tails of someone else's ideas & efforts. Don't listen to the opinions of people who get off on gore. They are only happy with chainsaw, saw & serial hacking butcher type Jason films with no appreciation for thrilling & innovative story lines. This classic, one of a kind story has captivated audiences for over 50 years since it was first released. So even a glory stealer like Carpenter can't do too much damage to ruin it. So forget Carpenter. The actors did a good job portraying their roles despite his direction. This new version of the movie is still based on the original classic so it is still enjoyable to watch if you use the fast forward to elude the gore scenes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not As Bad As It's Reputation
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Village of the Damned (1995) ** 1/2 (out of 4) John Carpenter's remake of the 1960 British film took an incredible beating when it was first released and while it's not as good as the original film, there are enough good moments to make it worth sitting through if you're a fan of the director. Basically what we have here is a small town that comes under attack by nine children who were all born on the same night after their mothers became pregnant during a bizarre blackout. Soon the kids are forcing the adults around them to either self mutilate or kill themselves. VILLAGE OF THE DAMNED started off pretty strong but then the screenplay simply ran out of fresh ideas and we're left with just one routine scene after another. As much as I'm against the heated hatred some show this film, there's still no question that it should have been much better considering who was directing it. I think some of the film's faults have to go to Carpenter because the biggest problem is that the children are never scary. Not once did I ever really feel threatened by them and saying Carpenter didn't make something scary is pretty rare. I did like the visual style and look that he gave the film and especially during the early scenes where the blackout occurs. I thought the first portion of the film was the most interesting as it deals with the blackout, the effects of the events and of course the women in the town getting pregnant. The second half of the film pretty much just becomes routine as one adult makes the kids mad after another and they all end up dead. Christopher Reeve does a good job as a doctor trying to help the kids while Kirstie Alley plays the woman who is really trying to help and understand them. While far from a good film, VILLAGE OF THE DAMNED still doesn't deserve the bad rep it's gotten over the years.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bad movie and useless remake
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vostf (vik@noos.fr)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The original Village of the Damned (Wolf Rilla, 1960) was a very good movie. Why remake it? It was very good because every plot point was simple and not overstated, which helped create tension with little. The Carpenter movie only "adds" useless stuff to the basic premise of evil children mysteriously conceived during the blackout of an entire village. More graphic violence, longer discussions about the phenomenon: isn't the tension better if we are left to let the violence grow in our global experience, not just as artifacts of the story? Dozens of cops, soldiers, firemen... and the token government scientist blinded by her outstanding research: this is no longer a small village cut from the world, this is a disaster movie set. I can't understand the urge for Carpenter to shoot such a bad script while the original story and adaptation must have been way better.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "One Of Carpenter's Most Underrated Films!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gwnightscream
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Christopher Reeve, Kirstie Alley and Linda Kozlowski star in John Carpenter's 1995 sci-fi remake of the 1960 film and based on the book, "The Midwich Cuckoos." After a mysterious force invades a town, 8 children are born the same time with alien-like powers. The town of Midwich experiences something strange when an unseen force invades the town and makes the residents pass out for 6 hours. That's not the only thing, a group of women are chosen to give birth to children at the same time who have alien-like powers that become a threat to the people. Reeve plays Alan Chaffee, a doctor who discovers what's happening and that his daughter, Mara is the leader of the children. Alley plays Susan Verner, a scientist who knows the truth about the children and Kozlowski plays Jill McGowan, a woman whose child, David is different than the others. This isn't bad and I think it's one of Carpenter's most underrated films. Reeve was great as usual and I recommend this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Some women give birth various strange children with supernatural power and extraordinary intelligence
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ma-cortes
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Acceptable Carpenter's remake with the premise is still interesting enough to watch it , dealing about several strangely emotionless children all born at the same time in a small village in Midwich . The scene is an American village of Midwich in which rare mist overcomes the idyllic coastal location . At the same moment, every single person and animal in town has passed out just as suddenly; some unknown force has put all the inhabitants of Midwich to sleep. Everybody falls into a deep, mysterious sleep for several hours in the middle of the day. When the army gets involved, they find this force has precise boundaries. A few hours later, this strange force disappears and everyone wakes up. The mystery remains unsolved for weeks, but it has a sequel. Some months later every woman (Linda Kozlowski , Meredith Salenger) capable of child-bearing is pregnant . All Midwich women of childbearing age are unaccountably pregnant. And the glowing-eyed children they have will prove to be worse than what they could have feared. The children that are born out of these pregnancies seem to grow very fast and they all have the same blond hair and strange, penetrating eyes that make people do things they don't want to do ; all of them have telephatic powers . They result to be mind-controlling demons or aliens . Meanwhile the doctor (good performance by Christopher Reeve) along with a scientist (Kirstie Alley in a new role who doesn't appear in the former film and doesn't do much sense) attempt to stop their plans of conquest . This Sci-Fi thriller contains chills , suspense , intrigue and creepy events about some precocious deadly children and their quest of power . However, it suffers from unimaginative account because being a copy from original film (1960) by Wolf Rilla with more violent and explicit scenes and fails to provide the intelligent atmosphere from previous story . Furthermore , it packs better cinematography by Gary Kibbe who photographs colorful scenarios from the village .Suspenseful and thrilling musical score by the same director John Carpenter . Other renditions based on John Wyndham novel titled &uml;The Midwich cuckoos&uml; and well adapted by Stirling Silliphant are the following : The black and white classic (1960) by Wolf Rilla with George Sanders , Michael G. Wynne and Barbara Shelley and followed by &uml;Children of the damned (64)&uml; by Anton Leader with Ian Hendry , Alan Badel and Barbara Ferris . Rating : Acceptable and passable , providing pleasant screams for the viewer . Essential and indispensable seeing for John Carpenter followers .
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not A Disaster But Not Great Either
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Theo Robertson
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    John Carpenter's VILLAGE OF THE DAMNED is considered a rather weak film . With hindsight one would have expected more since his version of THE THING is considered a classic of genre horror . But did you know it isn't a reputation that was instant ? THE THING from 1982 totally bombed at the box office and many critics were turned off by the stomach churning visuals . The reputation grew down to the fact that ET influenced film makers in to making nice family films about cute aliens coming to Earth to be saved from the nasty humans by nice cute kids . Like wise THE THING special effects are indeed special where a crew of effects artists slaved day and night to create something special . By the mid 1990s film makers were getting lazy and relied on CGI . Even some like myself who hated THE THING on its initial release can appreciate it in a nostalgic light Hopes must have been high that Carpenter could weave a similar kind of magic to this remake and surpass the original but tellinglly as the credits come up you'll notice the 1960 screenplay by Stirling Silliphant is namechecked . Silliphant wrote a very faithful adaptation of the original Wyhdham novel and this shouldn't be viewed as a criticism . This means however that if you know the story there's not a lot of surprises to the story . There also seems to be a bit of compromise involved and that is Carpenter includes violent scenes that are in no way gory . I did appreciate the lack of gore such as when Kirsty Alley's spook disembowel's herself but can understand why some people didn't like and would have preferred a bit more blood . Likewise the final shoot out seems to be included to put a bit of action in to a movie that by its very mechanics is a very slow burning type of mystery and does tend to jar with the rest of the story In all VILLAGE OF THE DAMNED is by no means a bad film , certainly not as bad as some people claim it to be but by the same yard stick there's no one claiming it's any way better than the original 1960 British film , probably down to a lack of embellishment and a very much TVM feel to the proceedings
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Where's a flamethrower when you need one?!?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jt1999
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Or an Uzi. Or a shotgun. Or a good old-fashioned Gatling Gun. Doesn't matter... whoever might have managed to get ahold of one would have done what every other friggin' character does in this film: walk up to the platinum blonde kids from hell, and instead firing off a couple of rounds, stand there idiotically for about ten or fifteen seconds. Brilliant! Give those kids plenty of time to kill you, that's what you want to do! Don't shoot, don't bash their brains in -- just wait there a good, long time until their eyes start glowing. This idiotic direction is emblematic of the entire film: it just sits there, doing almost nothing. Could have been directed by a sleepwalker... and that's with all due respect to Mr. Carpenter. Music certainly didn't help either. In fact, it helped ruin the entire film. Sorry, John. Got to put in a little more effort when re-making a classic. Kind of like you did when you re-made "The Thing." Remember those days? No, didn't think so.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stick with the original
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This bland rehash of the 1960 original is not without effective moments, but they're all in the first twenty minutes and things get mighty dull from that point on. Once the set-up is out of the way  small village, strange spell, mysterious pregnancies, spooky children  what atmosphere has been established disappears and the film becomes increasingly reliant on cheesy glowing-eye effects and repetitious killings. The characters don't ring true, either; they accept the bizarre events rather easily. On the plus side, there's a solid performance from Christopher Reeve and the score has its moments.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bland remake
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    atinder
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Village of the Damned (1995) Frist of all, I Don't The original was even that good but at least kept in in and moved forward and at more creepy feel to the movie. I did think movie would be better as John Carpenter did this remake, So I looking forward to it but soon as the movie started I knew this movie not going to be good. I didn't really like how they kinda change the story and gave really lame back story to kids being bored, there not one moment did have this kids creepy or scary at all, it was tame from start to end and never feel moved forward as the movie was such their I thought this was going to be a lot more better, so how they about to die, we actually see the death scenes in this movie, seen before and the aftermath but not when happens, it cuts way to the kids was lights in there eyes. The acting was really wooden by some of the main cast, I don't maybe they took make this more main stream movie, I think must worst John carpenter movie but a least movie wasn't boring, it maybe a little intruded how the movie going pan out, even that ending was a load of rubbish. 2 out of 10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Rated R for what?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    utahman1971
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    OK, I saw this in theater when it was release in 1995. I recently saw it again in its original format. I can't see where the rating R is at in this movie. There is hardly any bad language. There is barely any blood. There is a little action. There is nothing to claim it to be rated R. I can name another movie done the same "Dead Silence". I can the ones making the ratings making stupid mistakes, but that stupid is really stupid. Almost about as dumb as having rated PG-13 horror movies, and saying they are horror. I can sit through every single PG-13 wanna be called horror movies, and pretty much fall asleep through them. That is how sad those Directors are. They want to go towards wider range of people. When then call them thrillers, because that is really what they are. Thrillers are for chillers, and horror is for gore. I am sick of good Ole horror movies that have the gore to go with the horror are getting terrible ratings while the lame PG-13 chillers are getting better ratings. I will say it until I die, that those PG-13 so called horror that are really chiller thrillers should never be called horror. Just the claim is dumber than snot. As for the gore, it isn't real blood or guts. Its all fake. So if you can't handle it something is wrong with that person, not the movie. There needs to be more Directors that can make horror a horror movie that is the right rating for the movie, and not the boring wanna be crap.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Enjoyable movie. Forget Carpenter.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    midge56
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is still enjoyable to watch despite Carpenter. In fact, Carpenter had no business entitling this movie as his own since it was not his story or his screenplay in the first place. That was pure, unearned ego on his part as he tries to make his fame by latching onto the brilliant efforts of the original films & writers. Carpenter only added unnecessary, offensive gore to an already great story. The effects on the eyes were good & the extended gov't involvement with more focus on science than paranoia was also a refreshing addition as was the stillborn specimen (but that should have included more details on the lab findings than we got.) The priest character was OK until he became a suicidal gun nut which was ridiculous on too many levels to list. The boiling pot, self evisceration, barbecue, consumption by inferno & "walking tall" gun battle were just intolerable gore which added nothing to the movie. The original movie only had the children harming someone who had caused them harm or perceived as intended. This movie had them killing the innocent for no reason. That seriously degraded the story. The original contained unjustifiable gov't paranoia over acts of self-defense. By the killing of innocents such as the mothers suicides which made no sense whatsoever, it justified the paranoia to kill the children. The original idea was the children were unfairly judged because they were different & had unique abilities; acting only in self defense. I did like the survival ending on the new version. That could make an excellent sequel. It is a mistake to remake popular movies like this film, The Omen & Stepford Wives which were already great to begin with. (& never ridicule a cult classic such as was done with Stepford). Only an idiot would take plot change advice from disgruntled complainers instead of fans. It would be OK to colorize BW films and beef up the special effects & sound improvements on the originals for redistribution as was done for Star Wars & Star Trek. Sequels of great cliffhanger films would be much better ideas to pursue if done in the spirit of the original story. But it is a bad idea to redo an original classic verbatim without offering much more to the story. The desire to see more details & missing parts of the stories is what makes deleted scenes so popular with the public. They don't like to be left hanging in the dark. Hence, the need for a sequel on such movies. Not a remake of the same hanging, unanswered questions which offers nothing extra to fans. It would be better to make follow up sequels on these popular stories rather than trying to duplicate the original verbatim with a completely different cast. There's also nothing worse than an actor doing a popular film remake, who refuses to watch the original or a director who makes changes simply to imprint their ego onto it like a dog marking a hydrant. We might like to see what happens if the children survived & learn the source of their origins; as well as endings where they are successful in survival & goals as well as exceptions to their demeanor like David with multi-layered personalities. Classic films should not be used as a venue for some egomaniacal director to headline his name on the title of a movie he didn't write as Carpenter has been repeatedly guilty of doing. Perhaps he should do something original for a change rather than riding on the coat tails of someone else's ideas & efforts. Don't listen to the opinions of people who get off on gore. They are only happy with chainsaw, saw & serial hacking butcher type Jason films with no appreciation for thrilling & innovative story lines. This classic, one of a kind story has captivated audiences for over 50 years since it was first released. So even a glory stealer like Carpenter can't do too much damage to ruin it. So forget Carpenter. The actors did a good job portraying their roles despite his direction. This new version of the movie is still based on the original classic so it is still enjoyable to watch if you use the fast forward to elude the gore scenes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not As Bad As It's Reputation
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Village of the Damned (1995) ** 1/2 (out of 4) John Carpenter's remake of the 1960 British film took an incredible beating when it was first released and while it's not as good as the original film, there are enough good moments to make it worth sitting through if you're a fan of the director. Basically what we have here is a small town that comes under attack by nine children who were all born on the same night after their mothers became pregnant during a bizarre blackout. Soon the kids are forcing the adults around them to either self mutilate or kill themselves. VILLAGE OF THE DAMNED started off pretty strong but then the screenplay simply ran out of fresh ideas and we're left with just one routine scene after another. As much as I'm against the heated hatred some show this film, there's still no question that it should have been much better considering who was directing it. I think some of the film's faults have to go to Carpenter because the biggest problem is that the children are never scary. Not once did I ever really feel threatened by them and saying Carpenter didn't make something scary is pretty rare. I did like the visual style and look that he gave the film and especially during the early scenes where the blackout occurs. I thought the first portion of the film was the most interesting as it deals with the blackout, the effects of the events and of course the women in the town getting pregnant. The second half of the film pretty much just becomes routine as one adult makes the kids mad after another and they all end up dead. Christopher Reeve does a good job as a doctor trying to help the kids while Kirstie Alley plays the woman who is really trying to help and understand them. While far from a good film, VILLAGE OF THE DAMNED still doesn't deserve the bad rep it's gotten over the years.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bad movie and useless remake
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vostf (vik@noos.fr)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The original Village of the Damned (Wolf Rilla, 1960) was a very good movie. Why remake it? It was very good because every plot point was simple and not overstated, which helped create tension with little. The Carpenter movie only "adds" useless stuff to the basic premise of evil children mysteriously conceived during the blackout of an entire village. More graphic violence, longer discussions about the phenomenon: isn't the tension better if we are left to let the violence grow in our global experience, not just as artifacts of the story? Dozens of cops, soldiers, firemen... and the token government scientist blinded by her outstanding research: this is no longer a small village cut from the world, this is a disaster movie set. I can't understand the urge for Carpenter to shoot such a bad script while the original story and adaptation must have been way better.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "One Of Carpenter's Most Underrated Films!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gwnightscream
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Christopher Reeve, Kirstie Alley and Linda Kozlowski star in John Carpenter's 1995 sci-fi remake of the 1960 film and based on the book, "The Midwich Cuckoos." After a mysterious force invades a town, 8 children are born the same time with alien-like powers. The town of Midwich experiences something strange when an unseen force invades the town and makes the residents pass out for 6 hours. That's not the only thing, a group of women are chosen to give birth to children at the same time who have alien-like powers that become a threat to the people. Reeve plays Alan Chaffee, a doctor who discovers what's happening and that his daughter, Mara is the leader of the children. Alley plays Susan Verner, a scientist who knows the truth about the children and Kozlowski plays Jill McGowan, a woman whose child, David is different than the others. This isn't bad and I think it's one of Carpenter's most underrated films. Reeve was great as usual and I recommend this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Some women give birth various strange children with supernatural power and extraordinary intelligence
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ma-cortes
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Acceptable Carpenter's remake with the premise is still interesting enough to watch it , dealing about several strangely emotionless children all born at the same time in a small village in Midwich . The scene is an American village of Midwich in which rare mist overcomes the idyllic coastal location . At the same moment, every single person and animal in town has passed out just as suddenly; some unknown force has put all the inhabitants of Midwich to sleep. Everybody falls into a deep, mysterious sleep for several hours in the middle of the day. When the army gets involved, they find this force has precise boundaries. A few hours later, this strange force disappears and everyone wakes up. The mystery remains unsolved for weeks, but it has a sequel. Some months later every woman (Linda Kozlowski , Meredith Salenger) capable of child-bearing is pregnant . All Midwich women of childbearing age are unaccountably pregnant. And the glowing-eyed children they have will prove to be worse than what they could have feared. The children that are born out of these pregnancies seem to grow very fast and they all have the same blond hair and strange, penetrating eyes that make people do things they don't want to do ; all of them have telephatic powers . They result to be mind-controlling demons or aliens . Meanwhile the doctor (good performance by Christopher Reeve) along with a scientist (Kirstie Alley in a new role who doesn't appear in the former film and doesn't do much sense) attempt to stop their plans of conquest . This Sci-Fi thriller contains chills , suspense , intrigue and creepy events about some precocious deadly children and their quest of power . However, it suffers from unimaginative account because being a copy from original film (1960) by Wolf Rilla with more violent and explicit scenes and fails to provide the intelligent atmosphere from previous story . Furthermore , it packs better cinematography by Gary Kibbe who photographs colorful scenarios from the village .Suspenseful and thrilling musical score by the same director John Carpenter . Other renditions based on John Wyndham novel titled &uml;The Midwich cuckoos&uml; and well adapted by Stirling Silliphant are the following : The black and white classic (1960) by Wolf Rilla with George Sanders , Michael G. Wynne and Barbara Shelley and followed by &uml;Children of the damned (64)&uml; by Anton Leader with Ian Hendry , Alan Badel and Barbara Ferris . Rating : Acceptable and passable , providing pleasant screams for the viewer . Essential and indispensable seeing for John Carpenter followers .
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not A Disaster But Not Great Either
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Theo Robertson
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    John Carpenter's VILLAGE OF THE DAMNED is considered a rather weak film . With hindsight one would have expected more since his version of THE THING is considered a classic of genre horror . But did you know it isn't a reputation that was instant ? THE THING from 1982 totally bombed at the box office and many critics were turned off by the stomach churning visuals . The reputation grew down to the fact that ET influenced film makers in to making nice family films about cute aliens coming to Earth to be saved from the nasty humans by nice cute kids . Like wise THE THING special effects are indeed special where a crew of effects artists slaved day and night to create something special . By the mid 1990s film makers were getting lazy and relied on CGI . Even some like myself who hated THE THING on its initial release can appreciate it in a nostalgic light Hopes must have been high that Carpenter could weave a similar kind of magic to this remake and surpass the original but tellinglly as the credits come up you'll notice the 1960 screenplay by Stirling Silliphant is namechecked . Silliphant wrote a very faithful adaptation of the original Wyhdham novel and this shouldn't be viewed as a criticism . This means however that if you know the story there's not a lot of surprises to the story . There also seems to be a bit of compromise involved and that is Carpenter includes violent scenes that are in no way gory . I did appreciate the lack of gore such as when Kirsty Alley's spook disembowel's herself but can understand why some people didn't like and would have preferred a bit more blood . Likewise the final shoot out seems to be included to put a bit of action in to a movie that by its very mechanics is a very slow burning type of mystery and does tend to jar with the rest of the story In all VILLAGE OF THE DAMNED is by no means a bad film , certainly not as bad as some people claim it to be but by the same yard stick there's no one claiming it's any way better than the original 1960 British film , probably down to a lack of embellishment and a very much TVM feel to the proceedings
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Where's a flamethrower when you need one?!?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jt1999
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Or an Uzi. Or a shotgun. Or a good old-fashioned Gatling Gun. Doesn't matter... whoever might have managed to get ahold of one would have done what every other friggin' character does in this film: walk up to the platinum blonde kids from hell, and instead firing off a couple of rounds, stand there idiotically for about ten or fifteen seconds. Brilliant! Give those kids plenty of time to kill you, that's what you want to do! Don't shoot, don't bash their brains in -- just wait there a good, long time until their eyes start glowing. This idiotic direction is emblematic of the entire film: it just sits there, doing almost nothing. Could have been directed by a sleepwalker... and that's with all due respect to Mr. Carpenter. Music certainly didn't help either. In fact, it helped ruin the entire film. Sorry, John. Got to put in a little more effort when re-making a classic. Kind of like you did when you re-made "The Thing." Remember those days? No, didn't think so.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stick with the original
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This bland rehash of the 1960 original is not without effective moments, but they're all in the first twenty minutes and things get mighty dull from that point on. Once the set-up is out of the way  small village, strange spell, mysterious pregnancies, spooky children  what atmosphere has been established disappears and the film becomes increasingly reliant on cheesy glowing-eye effects and repetitious killings. The characters don't ring true, either; they accept the bizarre events rather easily. On the plus side, there's a solid performance from Christopher Reeve and the score has its moments.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bland remake
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    atinder
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Village of the Damned (1995) Frist of all, I Don't The original was even that good but at least kept in in and moved forward and at more creepy feel to the movie. I did think movie would be better as John Carpenter did this remake, So I looking forward to it but soon as the movie started I knew this movie not going to be good. I didn't really like how they kinda change the story and gave really lame back story to kids being bored, there not one moment did have this kids creepy or scary at all, it was tame from start to end and never feel moved forward as the movie was such their I thought this was going to be a lot more better, so how they about to die, we actually see the death scenes in this movie, seen before and the aftermath but not when happens, it cuts way to the kids was lights in there eyes. The acting was really wooden by some of the main cast, I don't maybe they took make this more main stream movie, I think must worst John carpenter movie but a least movie wasn't boring, it maybe a little intruded how the movie going pan out, even that ending was a load of rubbish. 2 out of 10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Rated R for what?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    utahman1971
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    OK, I saw this in theater when it was release in 1995. I recently saw it again in its original format. I can't see where the rating R is at in this movie. There is hardly any bad language. There is barely any blood. There is a little action. There is nothing to claim it to be rated R. I can name another movie done the same "Dead Silence". I can the ones making the ratings making stupid mistakes, but that stupid is really stupid. Almost about as dumb as having rated PG-13 horror movies, and saying they are horror. I can sit through every single PG-13 wanna be called horror movies, and pretty much fall asleep through them. That is how sad those Directors are. They want to go towards wider range of people. When then call them thrillers, because that is really what they are. Thrillers are for chillers, and horror is for gore. I am sick of good Ole horror movies that have the gore to go with the horror are getting terrible ratings while the lame PG-13 chillers are getting better ratings. I will say it until I die, that those PG-13 so called horror that are really chiller thrillers should never be called horror. Just the claim is dumber than snot. As for the gore, it isn't real blood or guts. Its all fake. So if you can't handle it something is wrong with that person, not the movie. There needs to be more Directors that can make horror a horror movie that is the right rating for the movie, and not the boring wanna be crap.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Enjoyable movie. Forget Carpenter.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    midge56
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is still enjoyable to watch despite Carpenter. In fact, Carpenter had no business entitling this movie as his own since it was not his story or his screenplay in the first place. That was pure, unearned ego on his part as he tries to make his fame by latching onto the brilliant efforts of the original films & writers. Carpenter only added unnecessary, offensive gore to an already great story. The effects on the eyes were good & the extended gov't involvement with more focus on science than paranoia was also a refreshing addition as was the stillborn specimen (but that should have included more details on the lab findings than we got.) The priest character was OK until he became a suicidal gun nut which was ridiculous on too many levels to list. The boiling pot, self evisceration, barbecue, consumption by inferno & "walking tall" gun battle were just intolerable gore which added nothing to the movie. The original movie only had the children harming someone who had caused them harm or perceived as intended. This movie had them killing the innocent for no reason. That seriously degraded the story. The original contained unjustifiable gov't paranoia over acts of self-defense. By the killing of innocents such as the mothers suicides which made no sense whatsoever, it justified the paranoia to kill the children. The original idea was the children were unfairly judged because they were different & had unique abilities; acting only in self defense. I did like the survival ending on the new version. That could make an excellent sequel. It is a mistake to remake popular movies like this film, The Omen & Stepford Wives which were already great to begin with. (& never ridicule a cult classic such as was done with Stepford). Only an idiot would take plot change advice from disgruntled complainers instead of fans. It would be OK to colorize BW films and beef up the special effects & sound improvements on the originals for redistribution as was done for Star Wars & Star Trek. Sequels of great cliffhanger films would be much better ideas to pursue if done in the spirit of the original story. But it is a bad idea to redo an original classic verbatim without offering much more to the story. The desire to see more details & missing parts of the stories is what makes deleted scenes so popular with the public. They don't like to be left hanging in the dark. Hence, the need for a sequel on such movies. Not a remake of the same hanging, unanswered questions which offers nothing extra to fans. It would be better to make follow up sequels on these popular stories rather than trying to duplicate the original verbatim with a completely different cast. There's also nothing worse than an actor doing a popular film remake, who refuses to watch the original or a director who makes changes simply to imprint their ego onto it like a dog marking a hydrant. We might like to see what happens if the children survived & learn the source of their origins; as well as endings where they are successful in survival & goals as well as exceptions to their demeanor like David with multi-layered personalities. Classic films should not be used as a venue for some egomaniacal director to headline his name on the title of a movie he didn't write as Carpenter has been repeatedly guilty of doing. Perhaps he should do something original for a change rather than riding on the coat tails of someone else's ideas & efforts. Don't listen to the opinions of people who get off on gore. They are only happy with chainsaw, saw & serial hacking butcher type Jason films with no appreciation for thrilling & innovative story lines. This classic, one of a kind story has captivated audiences for over 50 years since it was first released. So even a glory stealer like Carpenter can't do too much damage to ruin it. So forget Carpenter. The actors did a good job portraying their roles despite his direction. This new version of the movie is still based on the original classic so it is still enjoyable to watch if you use the fast forward to elude the gore scenes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not As Bad As It's Reputation
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Village of the Damned (1995) ** 1/2 (out of 4) John Carpenter's remake of the 1960 British film took an incredible beating when it was first released and while it's not as good as the original film, there are enough good moments to make it worth sitting through if you're a fan of the director. Basically what we have here is a small town that comes under attack by nine children who were all born on the same night after their mothers became pregnant during a bizarre blackout. Soon the kids are forcing the adults around them to either self mutilate or kill themselves. VILLAGE OF THE DAMNED started off pretty strong but then the screenplay simply ran out of fresh ideas and we're left with just one routine scene after another. As much as I'm against the heated hatred some show this film, there's still no question that it should have been much better considering who was directing it. I think some of the film's faults have to go to Carpenter because the biggest problem is that the children are never scary. Not once did I ever really feel threatened by them and saying Carpenter didn't make something scary is pretty rare. I did like the visual style and look that he gave the film and especially during the early scenes where the blackout occurs. I thought the first portion of the film was the most interesting as it deals with the blackout, the effects of the events and of course the women in the town getting pregnant. The second half of the film pretty much just becomes routine as one adult makes the kids mad after another and they all end up dead. Christopher Reeve does a good job as a doctor trying to help the kids while Kirstie Alley plays the woman who is really trying to help and understand them. While far from a good film, VILLAGE OF THE DAMNED still doesn't deserve the bad rep it's gotten over the years.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bad movie and useless remake
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vostf (vik@noos.fr)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The original Village of the Damned (Wolf Rilla, 1960) was a very good movie. Why remake it? It was very good because every plot point was simple and not overstated, which helped create tension with little. The Carpenter movie only "adds" useless stuff to the basic premise of evil children mysteriously conceived during the blackout of an entire village. More graphic violence, longer discussions about the phenomenon: isn't the tension better if we are left to let the violence grow in our global experience, not just as artifacts of the story? Dozens of cops, soldiers, firemen... and the token government scientist blinded by her outstanding research: this is no longer a small village cut from the world, this is a disaster movie set. I can't understand the urge for Carpenter to shoot such a bad script while the original story and adaptation must have been way better.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "One Of Carpenter's Most Underrated Films!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gwnightscream
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Christopher Reeve, Kirstie Alley and Linda Kozlowski star in John Carpenter's 1995 sci-fi remake of the 1960 film and based on the book, "The Midwich Cuckoos." After a mysterious force invades a town, 8 children are born the same time with alien-like powers. The town of Midwich experiences something strange when an unseen force invades the town and makes the residents pass out for 6 hours. That's not the only thing, a group of women are chosen to give birth to children at the same time who have alien-like powers that become a threat to the people. Reeve plays Alan Chaffee, a doctor who discovers what's happening and that his daughter, Mara is the leader of the children. Alley plays Susan Verner, a scientist who knows the truth about the children and Kozlowski plays Jill McGowan, a woman whose child, David is different than the others. This isn't bad and I think it's one of Carpenter's most underrated films. Reeve was great as usual and I recommend this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Some women give birth various strange children with supernatural power and extraordinary intelligence
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ma-cortes
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Acceptable Carpenter's remake with the premise is still interesting enough to watch it , dealing about several strangely emotionless children all born at the same time in a small village in Midwich . The scene is an American village of Midwich in which rare mist overcomes the idyllic coastal location . At the same moment, every single person and animal in town has passed out just as suddenly; some unknown force has put all the inhabitants of Midwich to sleep. Everybody falls into a deep, mysterious sleep for several hours in the middle of the day. When the army gets involved, they find this force has precise boundaries. A few hours later, this strange force disappears and everyone wakes up. The mystery remains unsolved for weeks, but it has a sequel. Some months later every woman (Linda Kozlowski , Meredith Salenger) capable of child-bearing is pregnant . All Midwich women of childbearing age are unaccountably pregnant. And the glowing-eyed children they have will prove to be worse than what they could have feared. The children that are born out of these pregnancies seem to grow very fast and they all have the same blond hair and strange, penetrating eyes that make people do things they don't want to do ; all of them have telephatic powers . They result to be mind-controlling demons or aliens . Meanwhile the doctor (good performance by Christopher Reeve) along with a scientist (Kirstie Alley in a new role who doesn't appear in the former film and doesn't do much sense) attempt to stop their plans of conquest . This Sci-Fi thriller contains chills , suspense , intrigue and creepy events about some precocious deadly children and their quest of power . However, it suffers from unimaginative account because being a copy from original film (1960) by Wolf Rilla with more violent and explicit scenes and fails to provide the intelligent atmosphere from previous story . Furthermore , it packs better cinematography by Gary Kibbe who photographs colorful scenarios from the village .Suspenseful and thrilling musical score by the same director John Carpenter . Other renditions based on John Wyndham novel titled &uml;The Midwich cuckoos&uml; and well adapted by Stirling Silliphant are the following : The black and white classic (1960) by Wolf Rilla with George Sanders , Michael G. Wynne and Barbara Shelley and followed by &uml;Children of the damned (64)&uml; by Anton Leader with Ian Hendry , Alan Badel and Barbara Ferris . Rating : Acceptable and passable , providing pleasant screams for the viewer . Essential and indispensable seeing for John Carpenter followers .
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not A Disaster But Not Great Either
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Theo Robertson
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    John Carpenter's VILLAGE OF THE DAMNED is considered a rather weak film . With hindsight one would have expected more since his version of THE THING is considered a classic of genre horror . But did you know it isn't a reputation that was instant ? THE THING from 1982 totally bombed at the box office and many critics were turned off by the stomach churning visuals . The reputation grew down to the fact that ET influenced film makers in to making nice family films about cute aliens coming to Earth to be saved from the nasty humans by nice cute kids . Like wise THE THING special effects are indeed special where a crew of effects artists slaved day and night to create something special . By the mid 1990s film makers were getting lazy and relied on CGI . Even some like myself who hated THE THING on its initial release can appreciate it in a nostalgic light Hopes must have been high that Carpenter could weave a similar kind of magic to this remake and surpass the original but tellinglly as the credits come up you'll notice the 1960 screenplay by Stirling Silliphant is namechecked . Silliphant wrote a very faithful adaptation of the original Wyhdham novel and this shouldn't be viewed as a criticism . This means however that if you know the story there's not a lot of surprises to the story . There also seems to be a bit of compromise involved and that is Carpenter includes violent scenes that are in no way gory . I did appreciate the lack of gore such as when Kirsty Alley's spook disembowel's herself but can understand why some people didn't like and would have preferred a bit more blood . Likewise the final shoot out seems to be included to put a bit of action in to a movie that by its very mechanics is a very slow burning type of mystery and does tend to jar with the rest of the story In all VILLAGE OF THE DAMNED is by no means a bad film , certainly not as bad as some people claim it to be but by the same yard stick there's no one claiming it's any way better than the original 1960 British film , probably down to a lack of embellishment and a very much TVM feel to the proceedings
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Where's a flamethrower when you need one?!?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jt1999
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Or an Uzi. Or a shotgun. Or a good old-fashioned Gatling Gun. Doesn't matter... whoever might have managed to get ahold of one would have done what every other friggin' character does in this film: walk up to the platinum blonde kids from hell, and instead firing off a couple of rounds, stand there idiotically for about ten or fifteen seconds. Brilliant! Give those kids plenty of time to kill you, that's what you want to do! Don't shoot, don't bash their brains in -- just wait there a good, long time until their eyes start glowing. This idiotic direction is emblematic of the entire film: it just sits there, doing almost nothing. Could have been directed by a sleepwalker... and that's with all due respect to Mr. Carpenter. Music certainly didn't help either. In fact, it helped ruin the entire film. Sorry, John. Got to put in a little more effort when re-making a classic. Kind of like you did when you re-made "The Thing." Remember those days? No, didn't think so.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stick with the original
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This bland rehash of the 1960 original is not without effective moments, but they're all in the first twenty minutes and things get mighty dull from that point on. Once the set-up is out of the way  small village, strange spell, mysterious pregnancies, spooky children  what atmosphere has been established disappears and the film becomes increasingly reliant on cheesy glowing-eye effects and repetitious killings. The characters don't ring true, either; they accept the bizarre events rather easily. On the plus side, there's a solid performance from Christopher Reeve and the score has its moments.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bland remake
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    atinder
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Village of the Damned (1995) Frist of all, I Don't The original was even that good but at least kept in in and moved forward and at more creepy feel to the movie. I did think movie would be better as John Carpenter did this remake, So I looking forward to it but soon as the movie started I knew this movie not going to be good. I didn't really like how they kinda change the story and gave really lame back story to kids being bored, there not one moment did have this kids creepy or scary at all, it was tame from start to end and never feel moved forward as the movie was such their I thought this was going to be a lot more better, so how they about to die, we actually see the death scenes in this movie, seen before and the aftermath but not when happens, it cuts way to the kids was lights in there eyes. The acting was really wooden by some of the main cast, I don't maybe they took make this more main stream movie, I think must worst John carpenter movie but a least movie wasn't boring, it maybe a little intruded how the movie going pan out, even that ending was a load of rubbish. 2 out of 10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Rated R for what?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    utahman1971
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    OK, I saw this in theater when it was release in 1995. I recently saw it again in its original format. I can't see where the rating R is at in this movie. There is hardly any bad language. There is barely any blood. There is a little action. There is nothing to claim it to be rated R. I can name another movie done the same "Dead Silence". I can the ones making the ratings making stupid mistakes, but that stupid is really stupid. Almost about as dumb as having rated PG-13 horror movies, and saying they are horror. I can sit through every single PG-13 wanna be called horror movies, and pretty much fall asleep through them. That is how sad those Directors are. They want to go towards wider range of people. When then call them thrillers, because that is really what they are. Thrillers are for chillers, and horror is for gore. I am sick of good Ole horror movies that have the gore to go with the horror are getting terrible ratings while the lame PG-13 chillers are getting better ratings. I will say it until I die, that those PG-13 so called horror that are really chiller thrillers should never be called horror. Just the claim is dumber than snot. As for the gore, it isn't real blood or guts. Its all fake. So if you can't handle it something is wrong with that person, not the movie. There needs to be more Directors that can make horror a horror movie that is the right rating for the movie, and not the boring wanna be crap.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Enjoyable movie. Forget Carpenter.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    midge56
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is still enjoyable to watch despite Carpenter. In fact, Carpenter had no business entitling this movie as his own since it was not his story or his screenplay in the first place. That was pure, unearned ego on his part as he tries to make his fame by latching onto the brilliant efforts of the original films & writers. Carpenter only added unnecessary, offensive gore to an already great story. The effects on the eyes were good & the extended gov't involvement with more focus on science than paranoia was also a refreshing addition as was the stillborn specimen (but that should have included more details on the lab findings than we got.) The priest character was OK until he became a suicidal gun nut which was ridiculous on too many levels to list. The boiling pot, self evisceration, barbecue, consumption by inferno & "walking tall" gun battle were just intolerable gore which added nothing to the movie. The original movie only had the children harming someone who had caused them harm or perceived as intended. This movie had them killing the innocent for no reason. That seriously degraded the story. The original contained unjustifiable gov't paranoia over acts of self-defense. By the killing of innocents such as the mothers suicides which made no sense whatsoever, it justified the paranoia to kill the children. The original idea was the children were unfairly judged because they were different & had unique abilities; acting only in self defense. I did like the survival ending on the new version. That could make an excellent sequel. It is a mistake to remake popular movies like this film, The Omen & Stepford Wives which were already great to begin with. (& never ridicule a cult classic such as was done with Stepford). Only an idiot would take plot change advice from disgruntled complainers instead of fans. It would be OK to colorize BW films and beef up the special effects & sound improvements on the originals for redistribution as was done for Star Wars & Star Trek. Sequels of great cliffhanger films would be much better ideas to pursue if done in the spirit of the original story. But it is a bad idea to redo an original classic verbatim without offering much more to the story. The desire to see more details & missing parts of the stories is what makes deleted scenes so popular with the public. They don't like to be left hanging in the dark. Hence, the need for a sequel on such movies. Not a remake of the same hanging, unanswered questions which offers nothing extra to fans. It would be better to make follow up sequels on these popular stories rather than trying to duplicate the original verbatim with a completely different cast. There's also nothing worse than an actor doing a popular film remake, who refuses to watch the original or a director who makes changes simply to imprint their ego onto it like a dog marking a hydrant. We might like to see what happens if the children survived & learn the source of their origins; as well as endings where they are successful in survival & goals as well as exceptions to their demeanor like David with multi-layered personalities. Classic films should not be used as a venue for some egomaniacal director to headline his name on the title of a movie he didn't write as Carpenter has been repeatedly guilty of doing. Perhaps he should do something original for a change rather than riding on the coat tails of someone else's ideas & efforts. Don't listen to the opinions of people who get off on gore. They are only happy with chainsaw, saw & serial hacking butcher type Jason films with no appreciation for thrilling & innovative story lines. This classic, one of a kind story has captivated audiences for over 50 years since it was first released. So even a glory stealer like Carpenter can't do too much damage to ruin it. So forget Carpenter. The actors did a good job portraying their roles despite his direction. This new version of the movie is still based on the original classic so it is still enjoyable to watch if you use the fast forward to elude the gore scenes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not As Bad As It's Reputation
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Village of the Damned (1995) ** 1/2 (out of 4) John Carpenter's remake of the 1960 British film took an incredible beating when it was first released and while it's not as good as the original film, there are enough good moments to make it worth sitting through if you're a fan of the director. Basically what we have here is a small town that comes under attack by nine children who were all born on the same night after their mothers became pregnant during a bizarre blackout. Soon the kids are forcing the adults around them to either self mutilate or kill themselves. VILLAGE OF THE DAMNED started off pretty strong but then the screenplay simply ran out of fresh ideas and we're left with just one routine scene after another. As much as I'm against the heated hatred some show this film, there's still no question that it should have been much better considering who was directing it. I think some of the film's faults have to go to Carpenter because the biggest problem is that the children are never scary. Not once did I ever really feel threatened by them and saying Carpenter didn't make something scary is pretty rare. I did like the visual style and look that he gave the film and especially during the early scenes where the blackout occurs. I thought the first portion of the film was the most interesting as it deals with the blackout, the effects of the events and of course the women in the town getting pregnant. The second half of the film pretty much just becomes routine as one adult makes the kids mad after another and they all end up dead. Christopher Reeve does a good job as a doctor trying to help the kids while Kirstie Alley plays the woman who is really trying to help and understand them. While far from a good film, VILLAGE OF THE DAMNED still doesn't deserve the bad rep it's gotten over the years.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bad movie and useless remake
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vostf (vik@noos.fr)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The original Village of the Damned (Wolf Rilla, 1960) was a very good movie. Why remake it? It was very good because every plot point was simple and not overstated, which helped create tension with little. The Carpenter movie only "adds" useless stuff to the basic premise of evil children mysteriously conceived during the blackout of an entire village. More graphic violence, longer discussions about the phenomenon: isn't the tension better if we are left to let the violence grow in our global experience, not just as artifacts of the story? Dozens of cops, soldiers, firemen... and the token government scientist blinded by her outstanding research: this is no longer a small village cut from the world, this is a disaster movie set. I can't understand the urge for Carpenter to shoot such a bad script while the original story and adaptation must have been way better.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "One Of Carpenter's Most Underrated Films!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gwnightscream
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Christopher Reeve, Kirstie Alley and Linda Kozlowski star in John Carpenter's 1995 sci-fi remake of the 1960 film and based on the book, "The Midwich Cuckoos." After a mysterious force invades a town, 8 children are born the same time with alien-like powers. The town of Midwich experiences something strange when an unseen force invades the town and makes the residents pass out for 6 hours. That's not the only thing, a group of women are chosen to give birth to children at the same time who have alien-like powers that become a threat to the people. Reeve plays Alan Chaffee, a doctor who discovers what's happening and that his daughter, Mara is the leader of the children. Alley plays Susan Verner, a scientist who knows the truth about the children and Kozlowski plays Jill McGowan, a woman whose child, David is different than the others. This isn't bad and I think it's one of Carpenter's most underrated films. Reeve was great as usual and I recommend this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Some women give birth various strange children with supernatural power and extraordinary intelligence
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ma-cortes
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Acceptable Carpenter's remake with the premise is still interesting enough to watch it , dealing about several strangely emotionless children all born at the same time in a small village in Midwich . The scene is an American village of Midwich in which rare mist overcomes the idyllic coastal location . At the same moment, every single person and animal in town has passed out just as suddenly; some unknown force has put all the inhabitants of Midwich to sleep. Everybody falls into a deep, mysterious sleep for several hours in the middle of the day. When the army gets involved, they find this force has precise boundaries. A few hours later, this strange force disappears and everyone wakes up. The mystery remains unsolved for weeks, but it has a sequel. Some months later every woman (Linda Kozlowski , Meredith Salenger) capable of child-bearing is pregnant . All Midwich women of childbearing age are unaccountably pregnant. And the glowing-eyed children they have will prove to be worse than what they could have feared. The children that are born out of these pregnancies seem to grow very fast and they all have the same blond hair and strange, penetrating eyes that make people do things they don't want to do ; all of them have telephatic powers . They result to be mind-controlling demons or aliens . Meanwhile the doctor (good performance by Christopher Reeve) along with a scientist (Kirstie Alley in a new role who doesn't appear in the former film and doesn't do much sense) attempt to stop their plans of conquest . This Sci-Fi thriller contains chills , suspense , intrigue and creepy events about some precocious deadly children and their quest of power . However, it suffers from unimaginative account because being a copy from original film (1960) by Wolf Rilla with more violent and explicit scenes and fails to provide the intelligent atmosphere from previous story . Furthermore , it packs better cinematography by Gary Kibbe who photographs colorful scenarios from the village .Suspenseful and thrilling musical score by the same director John Carpenter . Other renditions based on John Wyndham novel titled &uml;The Midwich cuckoos&uml; and well adapted by Stirling Silliphant are the following : The black and white classic (1960) by Wolf Rilla with George Sanders , Michael G. Wynne and Barbara Shelley and followed by &uml;Children of the damned (64)&uml; by Anton Leader with Ian Hendry , Alan Badel and Barbara Ferris . Rating : Acceptable and passable , providing pleasant screams for the viewer . Essential and indispensable seeing for John Carpenter followers .
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not A Disaster But Not Great Either
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Theo Robertson
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    John Carpenter's VILLAGE OF THE DAMNED is considered a rather weak film . With hindsight one would have expected more since his version of THE THING is considered a classic of genre horror . But did you know it isn't a reputation that was instant ? THE THING from 1982 totally bombed at the box office and many critics were turned off by the stomach churning visuals . The reputation grew down to the fact that ET influenced film makers in to making nice family films about cute aliens coming to Earth to be saved from the nasty humans by nice cute kids . Like wise THE THING special effects are indeed special where a crew of effects artists slaved day and night to create something special . By the mid 1990s film makers were getting lazy and relied on CGI . Even some like myself who hated THE THING on its initial release can appreciate it in a nostalgic light Hopes must have been high that Carpenter could weave a similar kind of magic to this remake and surpass the original but tellinglly as the credits come up you'll notice the 1960 screenplay by Stirling Silliphant is namechecked . Silliphant wrote a very faithful adaptation of the original Wyhdham novel and this shouldn't be viewed as a criticism . This means however that if you know the story there's not a lot of surprises to the story . There also seems to be a bit of compromise involved and that is Carpenter includes violent scenes that are in no way gory . I did appreciate the lack of gore such as when Kirsty Alley's spook disembowel's herself but can understand why some people didn't like and would have preferred a bit more blood . Likewise the final shoot out seems to be included to put a bit of action in to a movie that by its very mechanics is a very slow burning type of mystery and does tend to jar with the rest of the story In all VILLAGE OF THE DAMNED is by no means a bad film , certainly not as bad as some people claim it to be but by the same yard stick there's no one claiming it's any way better than the original 1960 British film , probably down to a lack of embellishment and a very much TVM feel to the proceedings
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Where's a flamethrower when you need one?!?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jt1999
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Or an Uzi. Or a shotgun. Or a good old-fashioned Gatling Gun. Doesn't matter... whoever might have managed to get ahold of one would have done what every other friggin' character does in this film: walk up to the platinum blonde kids from hell, and instead firing off a couple of rounds, stand there idiotically for about ten or fifteen seconds. Brilliant! Give those kids plenty of time to kill you, that's what you want to do! Don't shoot, don't bash their brains in -- just wait there a good, long time until their eyes start glowing. This idiotic direction is emblematic of the entire film: it just sits there, doing almost nothing. Could have been directed by a sleepwalker... and that's with all due respect to Mr. Carpenter. Music certainly didn't help either. In fact, it helped ruin the entire film. Sorry, John. Got to put in a little more effort when re-making a classic. Kind of like you did when you re-made "The Thing." Remember those days? No, didn't think so.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stick with the original
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This bland rehash of the 1960 original is not without effective moments, but they're all in the first twenty minutes and things get mighty dull from that point on. Once the set-up is out of the way  small village, strange spell, mysterious pregnancies, spooky children  what atmosphere has been established disappears and the film becomes increasingly reliant on cheesy glowing-eye effects and repetitious killings. The characters don't ring true, either; they accept the bizarre events rather easily. On the plus side, there's a solid performance from Christopher Reeve and the score has its moments.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bland remake
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    atinder
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Village of the Damned (1995) Frist of all, I Don't The original was even that good but at least kept in in and moved forward and at more creepy feel to the movie. I did think movie would be better as John Carpenter did this remake, So I looking forward to it but soon as the movie started I knew this movie not going to be good. I didn't really like how they kinda change the story and gave really lame back story to kids being bored, there not one moment did have this kids creepy or scary at all, it was tame from start to end and never feel moved forward as the movie was such their I thought this was going to be a lot more better, so how they about to die, we actually see the death scenes in this movie, seen before and the aftermath but not when happens, it cuts way to the kids was lights in there eyes. The acting was really wooden by some of the main cast, I don't maybe they took make this more main stream movie, I think must worst John carpenter movie but a least movie wasn't boring, it maybe a little intruded how the movie going pan out, even that ending was a load of rubbish. 2 out of 10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Rated R for what?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    utahman1971
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    OK, I saw this in theater when it was release in 1995. I recently saw it again in its original format. I can't see where the rating R is at in this movie. There is hardly any bad language. There is barely any blood. There is a little action. There is nothing to claim it to be rated R. I can name another movie done the same "Dead Silence". I can the ones making the ratings making stupid mistakes, but that stupid is really stupid. Almost about as dumb as having rated PG-13 horror movies, and saying they are horror. I can sit through every single PG-13 wanna be called horror movies, and pretty much fall asleep through them. That is how sad those Directors are. They want to go towards wider range of people. When then call them thrillers, because that is really what they are. Thrillers are for chillers, and horror is for gore. I am sick of good Ole horror movies that have the gore to go with the horror are getting terrible ratings while the lame PG-13 chillers are getting better ratings. I will say it until I die, that those PG-13 so called horror that are really chiller thrillers should never be called horror. Just the claim is dumber than snot. As for the gore, it isn't real blood or guts. Its all fake. So if you can't handle it something is wrong with that person, not the movie. There needs to be more Directors that can make horror a horror movie that is the right rating for the movie, and not the boring wanna be crap.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Enjoyable movie. Forget Carpenter.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    midge56
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is still enjoyable to watch despite Carpenter. In fact, Carpenter had no business entitling this movie as his own since it was not his story or his screenplay in the first place. That was pure, unearned ego on his part as he tries to make his fame by latching onto the brilliant efforts of the original films & writers. Carpenter only added unnecessary, offensive gore to an already great story. The effects on the eyes were good & the extended gov't involvement with more focus on science than paranoia was also a refreshing addition as was the stillborn specimen (but that should have included more details on the lab findings than we got.) The priest character was OK until he became a suicidal gun nut which was ridiculous on too many levels to list. The boiling pot, self evisceration, barbecue, consumption by inferno & "walking tall" gun battle were just intolerable gore which added nothing to the movie. The original movie only had the children harming someone who had caused them harm or perceived as intended. This movie had them killing the innocent for no reason. That seriously degraded the story. The original contained unjustifiable gov't paranoia over acts of self-defense. By the killing of innocents such as the mothers suicides which made no sense whatsoever, it justified the paranoia to kill the children. The original idea was the children were unfairly judged because they were different & had unique abilities; acting only in self defense. I did like the survival ending on the new version. That could make an excellent sequel. It is a mistake to remake popular movies like this film, The Omen & Stepford Wives which were already great to begin with. (& never ridicule a cult classic such as was done with Stepford). Only an idiot would take plot change advice from disgruntled complainers instead of fans. It would be OK to colorize BW films and beef up the special effects & sound improvements on the originals for redistribution as was done for Star Wars & Star Trek. Sequels of great cliffhanger films would be much better ideas to pursue if done in the spirit of the original story. But it is a bad idea to redo an original classic verbatim without offering much more to the story. The desire to see more details & missing parts of the stories is what makes deleted scenes so popular with the public. They don't like to be left hanging in the dark. Hence, the need for a sequel on such movies. Not a remake of the same hanging, unanswered questions which offers nothing extra to fans. It would be better to make follow up sequels on these popular stories rather than trying to duplicate the original verbatim with a completely different cast. There's also nothing worse than an actor doing a popular film remake, who refuses to watch the original or a director who makes changes simply to imprint their ego onto it like a dog marking a hydrant. We might like to see what happens if the children survived & learn the source of their origins; as well as endings where they are successful in survival & goals as well as exceptions to their demeanor like David with multi-layered personalities. Classic films should not be used as a venue for some egomaniacal director to headline his name on the title of a movie he didn't write as Carpenter has been repeatedly guilty of doing. Perhaps he should do something original for a change rather than riding on the coat tails of someone else's ideas & efforts. Don't listen to the opinions of people who get off on gore. They are only happy with chainsaw, saw & serial hacking butcher type Jason films with no appreciation for thrilling & innovative story lines. This classic, one of a kind story has captivated audiences for over 50 years since it was first released. So even a glory stealer like Carpenter can't do too much damage to ruin it. So forget Carpenter. The actors did a good job portraying their roles despite his direction. This new version of the movie is still based on the original classic so it is still enjoyable to watch if you use the fast forward to elude the gore scenes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not As Bad As It's Reputation
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Village of the Damned (1995) ** 1/2 (out of 4) John Carpenter's remake of the 1960 British film took an incredible beating when it was first released and while it's not as good as the original film, there are enough good moments to make it worth sitting through if you're a fan of the director. Basically what we have here is a small town that comes under attack by nine children who were all born on the same night after their mothers became pregnant during a bizarre blackout. Soon the kids are forcing the adults around them to either self mutilate or kill themselves. VILLAGE OF THE DAMNED started off pretty strong but then the screenplay simply ran out of fresh ideas and we're left with just one routine scene after another. As much as I'm against the heated hatred some show this film, there's still no question that it should have been much better considering who was directing it. I think some of the film's faults have to go to Carpenter because the biggest problem is that the children are never scary. Not once did I ever really feel threatened by them and saying Carpenter didn't make something scary is pretty rare. I did like the visual style and look that he gave the film and especially during the early scenes where the blackout occurs. I thought the first portion of the film was the most interesting as it deals with the blackout, the effects of the events and of course the women in the town getting pregnant. The second half of the film pretty much just becomes routine as one adult makes the kids mad after another and they all end up dead. Christopher Reeve does a good job as a doctor trying to help the kids while Kirstie Alley plays the woman who is really trying to help and understand them. While far from a good film, VILLAGE OF THE DAMNED still doesn't deserve the bad rep it's gotten over the years.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bad movie and useless remake
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vostf (vik@noos.fr)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The original Village of the Damned (Wolf Rilla, 1960) was a very good movie. Why remake it? It was very good because every plot point was simple and not overstated, which helped create tension with little. The Carpenter movie only "adds" useless stuff to the basic premise of evil children mysteriously conceived during the blackout of an entire village. More graphic violence, longer discussions about the phenomenon: isn't the tension better if we are left to let the violence grow in our global experience, not just as artifacts of the story? Dozens of cops, soldiers, firemen... and the token government scientist blinded by her outstanding research: this is no longer a small village cut from the world, this is a disaster movie set. I can't understand the urge for Carpenter to shoot such a bad script while the original story and adaptation must have been way better.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "One Of Carpenter's Most Underrated Films!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gwnightscream
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Christopher Reeve, Kirstie Alley and Linda Kozlowski star in John Carpenter's 1995 sci-fi remake of the 1960 film and based on the book, "The Midwich Cuckoos." After a mysterious force invades a town, 8 children are born the same time with alien-like powers. The town of Midwich experiences something strange when an unseen force invades the town and makes the residents pass out for 6 hours. That's not the only thing, a group of women are chosen to give birth to children at the same time who have alien-like powers that become a threat to the people. Reeve plays Alan Chaffee, a doctor who discovers what's happening and that his daughter, Mara is the leader of the children. Alley plays Susan Verner, a scientist who knows the truth about the children and Kozlowski plays Jill McGowan, a woman whose child, David is different than the others. This isn't bad and I think it's one of Carpenter's most underrated films. Reeve was great as usual and I recommend this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Some women give birth various strange children with supernatural power and extraordinary intelligence
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ma-cortes
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Acceptable Carpenter's remake with the premise is still interesting enough to watch it , dealing about several strangely emotionless children all born at the same time in a small village in Midwich . The scene is an American village of Midwich in which rare mist overcomes the idyllic coastal location . At the same moment, every single person and animal in town has passed out just as suddenly; some unknown force has put all the inhabitants of Midwich to sleep. Everybody falls into a deep, mysterious sleep for several hours in the middle of the day. When the army gets involved, they find this force has precise boundaries. A few hours later, this strange force disappears and everyone wakes up. The mystery remains unsolved for weeks, but it has a sequel. Some months later every woman (Linda Kozlowski , Meredith Salenger) capable of child-bearing is pregnant . All Midwich women of childbearing age are unaccountably pregnant. And the glowing-eyed children they have will prove to be worse than what they could have feared. The children that are born out of these pregnancies seem to grow very fast and they all have the same blond hair and strange, penetrating eyes that make people do things they don't want to do ; all of them have telephatic powers . They result to be mind-controlling demons or aliens . Meanwhile the doctor (good performance by Christopher Reeve) along with a scientist (Kirstie Alley in a new role who doesn't appear in the former film and doesn't do much sense) attempt to stop their plans of conquest . This Sci-Fi thriller contains chills , suspense , intrigue and creepy events about some precocious deadly children and their quest of power . However, it suffers from unimaginative account because being a copy from original film (1960) by Wolf Rilla with more violent and explicit scenes and fails to provide the intelligent atmosphere from previous story . Furthermore , it packs better cinematography by Gary Kibbe who photographs colorful scenarios from the village .Suspenseful and thrilling musical score by the same director John Carpenter . Other renditions based on John Wyndham novel titled &uml;The Midwich cuckoos&uml; and well adapted by Stirling Silliphant are the following : The black and white classic (1960) by Wolf Rilla with George Sanders , Michael G. Wynne and Barbara Shelley and followed by &uml;Children of the damned (64)&uml; by Anton Leader with Ian Hendry , Alan Badel and Barbara Ferris . Rating : Acceptable and passable , providing pleasant screams for the viewer . Essential and indispensable seeing for John Carpenter followers .
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not A Disaster But Not Great Either
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Theo Robertson
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    John Carpenter's VILLAGE OF THE DAMNED is considered a rather weak film . With hindsight one would have expected more since his version of THE THING is considered a classic of genre horror . But did you know it isn't a reputation that was instant ? THE THING from 1982 totally bombed at the box office and many critics were turned off by the stomach churning visuals . The reputation grew down to the fact that ET influenced film makers in to making nice family films about cute aliens coming to Earth to be saved from the nasty humans by nice cute kids . Like wise THE THING special effects are indeed special where a crew of effects artists slaved day and night to create something special . By the mid 1990s film makers were getting lazy and relied on CGI . Even some like myself who hated THE THING on its initial release can appreciate it in a nostalgic light Hopes must have been high that Carpenter could weave a similar kind of magic to this remake and surpass the original but tellinglly as the credits come up you'll notice the 1960 screenplay by Stirling Silliphant is namechecked . Silliphant wrote a very faithful adaptation of the original Wyhdham novel and this shouldn't be viewed as a criticism . This means however that if you know the story there's not a lot of surprises to the story . There also seems to be a bit of compromise involved and that is Carpenter includes violent scenes that are in no way gory . I did appreciate the lack of gore such as when Kirsty Alley's spook disembowel's herself but can understand why some people didn't like and would have preferred a bit more blood . Likewise the final shoot out seems to be included to put a bit of action in to a movie that by its very mechanics is a very slow burning type of mystery and does tend to jar with the rest of the story In all VILLAGE OF THE DAMNED is by no means a bad film , certainly not as bad as some people claim it to be but by the same yard stick there's no one claiming it's any way better than the original 1960 British film , probably down to a lack of embellishment and a very much TVM feel to the proceedings
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Where's a flamethrower when you need one?!?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jt1999
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Or an Uzi. Or a shotgun. Or a good old-fashioned Gatling Gun. Doesn't matter... whoever might have managed to get ahold of one would have done what every other friggin' character does in this film: walk up to the platinum blonde kids from hell, and instead firing off a couple of rounds, stand there idiotically for about ten or fifteen seconds. Brilliant! Give those kids plenty of time to kill you, that's what you want to do! Don't shoot, don't bash their brains in -- just wait there a good, long time until their eyes start glowing. This idiotic direction is emblematic of the entire film: it just sits there, doing almost nothing. Could have been directed by a sleepwalker... and that's with all due respect to Mr. Carpenter. Music certainly didn't help either. In fact, it helped ruin the entire film. Sorry, John. Got to put in a little more effort when re-making a classic. Kind of like you did when you re-made "The Thing." Remember those days? No, didn't think so.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stick with the original
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This bland rehash of the 1960 original is not without effective moments, but they're all in the first twenty minutes and things get mighty dull from that point on. Once the set-up is out of the way  small village, strange spell, mysterious pregnancies, spooky children  what atmosphere has been established disappears and the film becomes increasingly reliant on cheesy glowing-eye effects and repetitious killings. The characters don't ring true, either; they accept the bizarre events rather easily. On the plus side, there's a solid performance from Christopher Reeve and the score has its moments.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bland remake
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    atinder
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Village of the Damned (1995) Frist of all, I Don't The original was even that good but at least kept in in and moved forward and at more creepy feel to the movie. I did think movie would be better as John Carpenter did this remake, So I looking forward to it but soon as the movie started I knew this movie not going to be good. I didn't really like how they kinda change the story and gave really lame back story to kids being bored, there not one moment did have this kids creepy or scary at all, it was tame from start to end and never feel moved forward as the movie was such their I thought this was going to be a lot more better, so how they about to die, we actually see the death scenes in this movie, seen before and the aftermath but not when happens, it cuts way to the kids was lights in there eyes. The acting was really wooden by some of the main cast, I don't maybe they took make this more main stream movie, I think must worst John carpenter movie but a least movie wasn't boring, it maybe a little intruded how the movie going pan out, even that ending was a load of rubbish. 2 out of 10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Rated R for what?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    utahman1971
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    OK, I saw this in theater when it was release in 1995. I recently saw it again in its original format. I can't see where the rating R is at in this movie. There is hardly any bad language. There is barely any blood. There is a little action. There is nothing to claim it to be rated R. I can name another movie done the same "Dead Silence". I can the ones making the ratings making stupid mistakes, but that stupid is really stupid. Almost about as dumb as having rated PG-13 horror movies, and saying they are horror. I can sit through every single PG-13 wanna be called horror movies, and pretty much fall asleep through them. That is how sad those Directors are. They want to go towards wider range of people. When then call them thrillers, because that is really what they are. Thrillers are for chillers, and horror is for gore. I am sick of good Ole horror movies that have the gore to go with the horror are getting terrible ratings while the lame PG-13 chillers are getting better ratings. I will say it until I die, that those PG-13 so called horror that are really chiller thrillers should never be called horror. Just the claim is dumber than snot. As for the gore, it isn't real blood or guts. Its all fake. So if you can't handle it something is wrong with that person, not the movie. There needs to be more Directors that can make horror a horror movie that is the right rating for the movie, and not the boring wanna be crap.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Enjoyable movie. Forget Carpenter.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    midge56
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is still enjoyable to watch despite Carpenter. In fact, Carpenter had no business entitling this movie as his own since it was not his story or his screenplay in the first place. That was pure, unearned ego on his part as he tries to make his fame by latching onto the brilliant efforts of the original films & writers. Carpenter only added unnecessary, offensive gore to an already great story. The effects on the eyes were good & the extended gov't involvement with more focus on science than paranoia was also a refreshing addition as was the stillborn specimen (but that should have included more details on the lab findings than we got.) The priest character was OK until he became a suicidal gun nut which was ridiculous on too many levels to list. The boiling pot, self evisceration, barbecue, consumption by inferno & "walking tall" gun battle were just intolerable gore which added nothing to the movie. The original movie only had the children harming someone who had caused them harm or perceived as intended. This movie had them killing the innocent for no reason. That seriously degraded the story. The original contained unjustifiable gov't paranoia over acts of self-defense. By the killing of innocents such as the mothers suicides which made no sense whatsoever, it justified the paranoia to kill the children. The original idea was the children were unfairly judged because they were different & had unique abilities; acting only in self defense. I did like the survival ending on the new version. That could make an excellent sequel. It is a mistake to remake popular movies like this film, The Omen & Stepford Wives which were already great to begin with. (& never ridicule a cult classic such as was done with Stepford). Only an idiot would take plot change advice from disgruntled complainers instead of fans. It would be OK to colorize BW films and beef up the special effects & sound improvements on the originals for redistribution as was done for Star Wars & Star Trek. Sequels of great cliffhanger films would be much better ideas to pursue if done in the spirit of the original story. But it is a bad idea to redo an original classic verbatim without offering much more to the story. The desire to see more details & missing parts of the stories is what makes deleted scenes so popular with the public. They don't like to be left hanging in the dark. Hence, the need for a sequel on such movies. Not a remake of the same hanging, unanswered questions which offers nothing extra to fans. It would be better to make follow up sequels on these popular stories rather than trying to duplicate the original verbatim with a completely different cast. There's also nothing worse than an actor doing a popular film remake, who refuses to watch the original or a director who makes changes simply to imprint their ego onto it like a dog marking a hydrant. We might like to see what happens if the children survived & learn the source of their origins; as well as endings where they are successful in survival & goals as well as exceptions to their demeanor like David with multi-layered personalities. Classic films should not be used as a venue for some egomaniacal director to headline his name on the title of a movie he didn't write as Carpenter has been repeatedly guilty of doing. Perhaps he should do something original for a change rather than riding on the coat tails of someone else's ideas & efforts. Don't listen to the opinions of people who get off on gore. They are only happy with chainsaw, saw & serial hacking butcher type Jason films with no appreciation for thrilling & innovative story lines. This classic, one of a kind story has captivated audiences for over 50 years since it was first released. So even a glory stealer like Carpenter can't do too much damage to ruin it. So forget Carpenter. The actors did a good job portraying their roles despite his direction. This new version of the movie is still based on the original classic so it is still enjoyable to watch if you use the fast forward to elude the gore scenes.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not As Bad As It's Reputation
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Village of the Damned (1995) ** 1/2 (out of 4) John Carpenter's remake of the 1960 British film took an incredible beating when it was first released and while it's not as good as the original film, there are enough good moments to make it worth sitting through if you're a fan of the director. Basically what we have here is a small town that comes under attack by nine children who were all born on the same night after their mothers became pregnant during a bizarre blackout. Soon the kids are forcing the adults around them to either self mutilate or kill themselves. VILLAGE OF THE DAMNED started off pretty strong but then the screenplay simply ran out of fresh ideas and we're left with just one routine scene after another. As much as I'm against the heated hatred some show this film, there's still no question that it should have been much better considering who was directing it. I think some of the film's faults have to go to Carpenter because the biggest problem is that the children are never scary. Not once did I ever really feel threatened by them and saying Carpenter didn't make something scary is pretty rare. I did like the visual style and look that he gave the film and especially during the early scenes where the blackout occurs. I thought the first portion of the film was the most interesting as it deals with the blackout, the effects of the events and of course the women in the town getting pregnant. The second half of the film pretty much just becomes routine as one adult makes the kids mad after another and they all end up dead. Christopher Reeve does a good job as a doctor trying to help the kids while Kirstie Alley plays the woman who is really trying to help and understand them. While far from a good film, VILLAGE OF THE DAMNED still doesn't deserve the bad rep it's gotten over the years.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bad movie and useless remake
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vostf (vik@noos.fr)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The original Village of the Damned (Wolf Rilla, 1960) was a very good movie. Why remake it? It was very good because every plot point was simple and not overstated, which helped create tension with little. The Carpenter movie only "adds" useless stuff to the basic premise of evil children mysteriously conceived during the blackout of an entire village. More graphic violence, longer discussions about the phenomenon: isn't the tension better if we are left to let the violence grow in our global experience, not just as artifacts of the story? Dozens of cops, soldiers, firemen... and the token government scientist blinded by her outstanding research: this is no longer a small village cut from the world, this is a disaster movie set. I can't understand the urge for Carpenter to shoot such a bad script while the original story and adaptation must have been way better.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "One Of Carpenter's Most Underrated Films!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gwnightscream
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Christopher Reeve, Kirstie Alley and Linda Kozlowski star in John Carpenter's 1995 sci-fi remake of the 1960 film and based on the book, "The Midwich Cuckoos." After a mysterious force invades a town, 8 children are born the same time with alien-like powers. The town of Midwich experiences something strange when an unseen force invades the town and makes the residents pass out for 6 hours. That's not the only thing, a group of women are chosen to give birth to children at the same time who have alien-like powers that become a threat to the people. Reeve plays Alan Chaffee, a doctor who discovers what's happening and that his daughter, Mara is the leader of the children. Alley plays Susan Verner, a scientist who knows the truth about the children and Kozlowski plays Jill McGowan, a woman whose child, David is different than the others. This isn't bad and I think it's one of Carpenter's most underrated films. Reeve was great as usual and I recommend this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Some women give birth various strange children with supernatural power and extraordinary intelligence
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ma-cortes
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Acceptable Carpenter's remake with the premise is still interesting enough to watch it , dealing about several strangely emotionless children all born at the same time in a small village in Midwich . The scene is an American village of Midwich in which rare mist overcomes the idyllic coastal location . At the same moment, every single person and animal in town has passed out just as suddenly; some unknown force has put all the inhabitants of Midwich to sleep. Everybody falls into a deep, mysterious sleep for several hours in the middle of the day. When the army gets involved, they find this force has precise boundaries. A few hours later, this strange force disappears and everyone wakes up. The mystery remains unsolved for weeks, but it has a sequel. Some months later every woman (Linda Kozlowski , Meredith Salenger) capable of child-bearing is pregnant . All Midwich women of childbearing age are unaccountably pregnant. And the glowing-eyed children they have will prove to be worse than what they could have feared. The children that are born out of these pregnancies seem to grow very fast and they all have the same blond hair and strange, penetrating eyes that make people do things they don't want to do ; all of them have telephatic powers . They result to be mind-controlling demons or aliens . Meanwhile the doctor (good performance by Christopher Reeve) along with a scientist (Kirstie Alley in a new role who doesn't appear in the former film and doesn't do much sense) attempt to stop their plans of conquest . This Sci-Fi thriller contains chills , suspense , intrigue and creepy events about some precocious deadly children and their quest of power . However, it suffers from unimaginative account because being a copy from original film (1960) by Wolf Rilla with more violent and explicit scenes and fails to provide the intelligent atmosphere from previous story . Furthermore , it packs better cinematography by Gary Kibbe who photographs colorful scenarios from the village .Suspenseful and thrilling musical score by the same director John Carpenter . Other renditions based on John Wyndham novel titled &uml;The Midwich cuckoos&uml; and well adapted by Stirling Silliphant are the following : The black and white classic (1960) by Wolf Rilla with George Sanders , Michael G. Wynne and Barbara Shelley and followed by &uml;Children of the damned (64)&uml; by Anton Leader with Ian Hendry , Alan Badel and Barbara Ferris . Rating : Acceptable and passable , providing pleasant screams for the viewer . Essential and indispensable seeing for John Carpenter followers .
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not A Disaster But Not Great Either
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Theo Robertson
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    John Carpenter's VILLAGE OF THE DAMNED is considered a rather weak film . With hindsight one would have expected more since his version of THE THING is considered a classic of genre horror . But did you know it isn't a reputation that was instant ? THE THING from 1982 totally bombed at the box office and many critics were turned off by the stomach churning visuals . The reputation grew down to the fact that ET influenced film makers in to making nice family films about cute aliens coming to Earth to be saved from the nasty humans by nice cute kids . Like wise THE THING special effects are indeed special where a crew of effects artists slaved day and night to create something special . By the mid 1990s film makers were getting lazy and relied on CGI . Even some like myself who hated THE THING on its initial release can appreciate it in a nostalgic light Hopes must have been high that Carpenter could weave a similar kind of magic to this remake and surpass the original but tellinglly as the credits come up you'll notice the 1960 screenplay by Stirling Silliphant is namechecked . Silliphant wrote a very faithful adaptation of the original Wyhdham novel and this shouldn't be viewed as a criticism . This means however that if you know the story there's not a lot of surprises to the story . There also seems to be a bit of compromise involved and that is Carpenter includes violent scenes that are in no way gory . I did appreciate the lack of gore such as when Kirsty Alley's spook disembowel's herself but can understand why some people didn't like and would have preferred a bit more blood . Likewise the final shoot out seems to be included to put a bit of action in to a movie that by its very mechanics is a very slow burning type of mystery and does tend to jar with the rest of the story In all VILLAGE OF THE DAMNED is by no means a bad film , certainly not as bad as some people claim it to be but by the same yard stick there's no one claiming it's any way better than the original 1960 British film , probably down to a lack of embellishment and a very much TVM feel to the proceedings
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Where's a flamethrower when you need one?!?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jt1999
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Or an Uzi. Or a shotgun. Or a good old-fashioned Gatling Gun. Doesn't matter... whoever might have managed to get ahold of one would have done what every other friggin' character does in this film: walk up to the platinum blonde kids from hell, and instead firing off a couple of rounds, stand there idiotically for about ten or fifteen seconds. Brilliant! Give those kids plenty of time to kill you, that's what you want to do! Don't shoot, don't bash their brains in -- just wait there a good, long time until their eyes start glowing. This idiotic direction is emblematic of the entire film: it just sits there, doing almost nothing. Could have been directed by a sleepwalker... and that's with all due respect to Mr. Carpenter. Music certainly didn't help either. In fact, it helped ruin the entire film. Sorry, John. Got to put in a little more effort when re-making a classic. Kind of like you did when you re-made "The Thing." Remember those days? No, didn't think so.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
