<filme>
 <id>
  567
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0111686
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1994
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  O Novo Pesadelo - O Retorno de Freddy Krueger
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.3
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  A demonic force has chosen Freddy Krueger as its portal to the real world. Can Heather play the part of Nancy one last time and trap the evil trying to enter our world?
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  It's nearing the 10th Anniversary of the film 'A Nightmare on Elm Street' and one of the stars, Heather Langenkamp is being scared by a voice on a phone, sounding very similar to the film's villain, Freddy Krueger. When Heather's husband is killed in a car accident and is discovered with slash marks on him, Heather starts to wonder something. Especially when she discovers that Wes Craven is writing another 'Nightmare' film. Soon, she realizes that Freddy has now entered the real world, and the only way to defeat him is to become Nancy Thompson once again.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Horror
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Mystery
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Thriller
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   freddy krueger
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   nightmare
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   elm street
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   car
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   sleep
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Wes Craven
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Wes Craven
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Heather Langenkamp
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Robert Englund
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Jeff Davis
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wes Craven's New Nightmare
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It looked like for some time Freddy's Dead: The Final Nightmare was the final time scary movie fans would see the iconic razor handed "Son of 100 Maniacs", but then original film writer and director Wes Craven (The Hills Have Eyes, Scream) came up with this clever comeback. Basically the tenth anniversary of the movie A Nightmare on Elm Street is coming up, and original star Heather Langenkamp is part of the special events celebrating, along with its director Wes Craven, and of course the man behind killer Freddy Krueger, actor Robert Englund. She has a happy life with husband Chase Porter (David Newsom) and son Dylan (Miko Hughes), but she is being stalked by a nasty voice on the phone, and creepy goings on in her house, and things get worse when her husband is killed in a car crash, and his body has slash marks on it. Dylan is refusing to sleep anymore, because he is scared, like the movie, that Freddy will come in his dream and try to kill him, and dealing with this Heather is also being offered a part in the next Nightmare film Wes is working on, but the script needs work. Heather is finding the behaviour of her son uncontrollable, and she does believe Freddy is haunting her, Wes comes up with the theory that now the Elm Street films are over an ancient spirit must have helped him come out of the fictional world to enter dreams in real life, and his script may be part of this way out. It comes to the point when Dylan may be taken away from Heather due to his psychologically disturbed behaviour, but she is also incarcerated by doctors who believe she is going mad, of course Freddy continues his kills while this is going on. Eventually Heather, like her character, enters a dream to confront Freddy and stop the terror, and she manages to lock him in a furnace to burn to death, and returning to the real world she and her son read the new finished sample script sent by Wes. I like films where actors play a version of themselves, you could see this as semi-documentary considering the concept of how to bring back a character supposedly dead for good, the story has its moments of irritation, especially with the doctors breaking up the mother and son, but the script has clever references and ideas, and there is just enough Freddy and gore for the fans, a not bad horror film. Worth watching!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Langenkamp and Englund go uber real.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    amesmonde
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The lead actors of the original Nightmare on Elm Street, on it's 10th Anniversary, are terrorized by a Freddy Kruger like entity that wants Heather Langenkamp and her son dead. The seemingly outrageous bloody opening is quickly defused as a fitting dream sequence and new ground is broken as we discover the actors are playing themselves. It appears to break the fourth wall with Wes Craven, John Saxon and Robert Englund to name a few playing themselves. Of course this allows Langenkamp to return as herself after her Nancy character's death in the third. This non-conventional approach with a number of uneasy phone calls would become the precursor film within a film which appears in Craven's own Scream series. While you'd expect most of the actors to be able to play themselves they do at times come across as awkward and uncomfortable. Thankfully the leads pull it off with ease - namely Englund and Langenkamp. Faces from the original also cameo as themselves and a photo of Johnny Depp shows up in the background. Some scenes are a blast for fans with Englund playing himself as Freddy on a talk show. Of course Englund also plays Freddy the embodiment of an evil spirit with an expert indifference. This darker, scarier Freddy is probably what fans of the original wanted to see in the handful of sequels. There's irony on irony with producer Rob Shay inviting Langenkamp to come back and play Nancy one last time in a definitive nightmare. Writer/Director Craven delivers another novel idea with a tantalizing hook. There's a nice touch where reality merges with dreams and John Sax returns as his character Lt. Donald Thompson with Langenkamp calling him John and him unawares in turn calling her Nancy. The kill scenes pay homage to the original and even some of the sequels notably the Chase Porter car crash. With a strong supporting cast (mainly those ones who don't play themselves) including Miko Hughes as Dylan Porter Heather's on screen son gives a solid mixture of Poltergeist/Exorcist-like performance. It may have benefited from a more natural looking production, less film- like to emphasis the realness in contrast to the movie world and Nightmare sequences. It's own high production values and Mark Irwin's great cinematography dilute the edginess. Craven's screenplay also injects a part actress character study there is an interesting subtext about fame and it trappings. A New Nightmare has all the kills one would expect with excellent make up and visual effect on display with Craven trying to out do himself with the accompanying music by J. Peter Robinson. The idea of uber Freddy character harassing the real life cast and crew doesn't tire with the entertaining and fitting premise. It's only a movie...or is it?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wes Craven's dream of rebooting Freddy becomes a New Nightmare
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ironhorse_iv
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's hardly a perfect film for Wes Craven, but it's eerie and thought-provoking, something that been lacking in the previous movies that made Freddy Kruger into a goofy wise cracker and cheesy death scenes. It is also the last the last time that Freddy showed any real menace. Wes Craven made this to take back control of his creation and it works as a criticism of what the franchise became with Freddy as a comedian, not to mention a rebuff to the tired argument about violence in films always causing it in the real world. Freddy was far more straightforward with his kills and didn't manifest elaborate scenarios for each death. Pure intimidation. That's what Wes was trying to bring back. New Nightmare is almost in it's own league. New Nightmare had a great story and very original, creative ideas in it but it was still a bit confusing with the plot of the movie! It's the movie without a movie. He would work this angle again, in the 'Scream' series with the "Stab" movies in Scream are movies within a movie! It's work here, it doesn't work there. 'A Nightmare on Elm Street 7: The Ascension' is being film, and Heather Langenkamp playing herself, the actress that play the original heroic star of the original movie is being ask to reprise her role as Nancy Thompson. She notice that her husband Chase, and son Dylan is also being haunted by Freddy Krueger (Robert Englund) outside the filming, and confront the actor Robert Englund about it. She then go to Wes Craven himself, who reveals that Freddy is real, and only she can stop him. There is a interesting theory that comes to front with this. It's probably not Wes Craven's intent, but an audience's interpretation is authorial fallacy to see that there might have been a connection to this movie with that of the 3rd movie Dream Warriors. Heather's character Nancy Thompson's dies in the World of the first three films/four films. Her funeral/gravestone proves this (the gravestone was shown in A Nightmare on Elm Street 4: The Dream Master). The character Kristen from Dream Warrior, somehow, created a new world/new reality and placed Nancy's soul into this world in the end of the film like it stated. It's a dream world, yet Nancy's soul can live a full beautiful life in this beautiful dream world. Nancy's physically dead, yet not spiritually dead. I would think that once she ages and dies in this dream world then she would have truly died. Overall, Nancy has been placed in a matrix type reality so, to her, everyone in this reality is real/important to her. Freddy though, once all event's take place in the "real world" (the world of dream warriors), realizes that Nancy is in this dream world/alternate reality and therefore tries to kill Nancy since he wants to finish her off once and for all. It must take a lot for him to enter this dream world though since earthquakes are occurring constantly. Since Wes Craven wrote 1, 3, and this one... could it be Nancy living as Heather. It's a headache, but it's worth checking out or is the previous films fake and this movie real. Is Heather insane or is Freddy really coming out of the film to kill the actress that kill him in the movie? The movie goes with the realish look to it. Surprising the earthquake footage in the film is real. It was taken from the 1994 Northridge earthquake that happen during filming. The movie seem fresh, and the way in which Freddy talked, walked, and looked really brought a much needed shot of freshness to the character that had seriously been lacking. Freddy has a deeper voice. To correspond with this, the make-up and outfit of the character was different, with one of the most prominent differences being that he now wears a long, black trench coat. In addition, the signature glove was redesigned for a more organic look, with the fingers resembling bones and having muscle textures in between. It really adds to his darker vibe. The problem with the movie was that Freddy was way too soft. He looked better than ever and he was darker than ever, but all he did to the kid and his mom was chase them around, wrestle them, and scare them. Also Freddie's screen time is almost non existent, he rarely in the film, but when he is, he's scary! Heather Langenkamp takes most of the movie time, sadly not great in leading the film anywhere, as she unable to act her way through wet tissue. Even with fails, Wes Craven's New Nightmare was probably created solely for the purpose of Wes wanting to erase 2, 4, 5, and 6, and I believe even 3 because he said in the special documentary for the box set that he essentially believes that only the first film and A New Nightmare are cannon. Essentially Wes Craven threw a bratty fit over the fact there were so many sequels and wanted to basically bury the series with A New Nightmare. The meta-fictional methodology of 'New Nightmare' really gave a unique and terrifying storyline and, in my opinion, one of the best films of the franchise. So while the theory is still interesting and I can see how it would work, I think it takes away from how good 'New Nightmare' is. I'd rather watch this one than a complete hideous garbage 2010 one with Haley is, God I dislike that version.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Christina Aguilera once spoke for him.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RickHarvey
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Freddy is back... well, he's not actually back. Instead, an heinous and satanic Freddy takes over our screens as a his existence forges into reality while his films continue to dwindle in the publics conscious.(With the majority of the films being awful, i can't say that's a bad thing.) I really liked New nightmare: Original, showcasing the same mixture of intelligence with the first NMOES and most importantly, great acting. I was sceptical at first when knowing that a child actor stars - with them mostly being obnoxious and unwittingly annoying in majority of films - but thankfully the character of Dylan paid off. The thought of Freddy becoming closer to reality when the longer he's forgotten is fantastic. With the actors playing themselves, you follow the hysteria that follows Heather while he struggles to cope with a stalker. Freddy's appearance: Long, drab trench coat and feroda hat, is spot on. Despite a change in Freddy, it seems he can't resist on pulling out a one-liner from under his sleeves. Made his enigmatic aura suffer a little. Overall, I'm glad Craven decided to make another NMOES - even if it was just for the money. You sense his input being commanded with every shot. The final act gave lovers of the original NMOES an flash back on their initial experience with Freddy. With both script and camera, Craven didn't do much wrong.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Immensely enjoyable and entertaining
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    GL84
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After a series of nightmares and her son's strange behavior, an actress becomes convinced a famous serial killer from her movie history has come into the real world and targeting her and her family, forcing her to stop him using the tricks from the movies. This here turned out to be a decent if slightly flawed entry. Among the many things that work here is the fact that, by tying into the film series as a whole separate entity away from the reality presented here, it manages to be a lot smarter than it usually would be for this type of film, and that's something to commend by having the actors playing themselves instead of the film roles. That makes the typically-clich&eacute;d is-it-all-a-dream-or-not set-up far more effective than it has any right to be, given even more credence with Freddy's return to being scary again. Dropping any semblance of wise-cracks, puns and lame jokes, reduced screen time and really only appearing to do damage make him a credible, scary force again, and that helps this out tremendously. With some great action in here, a lot of great special effects and a fantastic finale, this has a lot going for it but there's still a few problems here, mainly in the film's continued usage of the annoying child who does nothing but scream and does nothing to the film overall. The low kill count means there's little variety to be found as well, but overall this isn't all too bad. Rated R: Violence, Language, and children in jeopardy
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Worst nightmare come true!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    amethystwings32
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    These movies , are horrific and terrifying to the very core! They are awful , Freddy Krueger made Jason and Mike Myers look like dark angels! He can definitely give someone nightmares, he is grotesque. What he did to his victims , would make any squeamish person want to vomit! That is why I will never get this obsession , anyone who likes these are seriously disturbed! I would hardly call these good, blood and gore doesn't make a movie good! Being terrified to the very core, with it's graphic nightmarish scenes. To the point you want to scream, walk out. Cover your face the whole time , faint or hurl. That is all of the signs that a movie is not worth watching!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Great Nightmare Sequel!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gwnightscream
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Robert Englund, Heather Langenkamp, John Saxon, Wes Craven and Miko Hughes star in Wes Craven's 1994 horror sequel. Freddy Krueger stalks the cast & crew of the original "Nightmare on Elm Street" during it's 10th anniversary. This film takes place in Los Angeles and focuses on Heather (Langenkamp) and her young son, Dylan (Hughes). Robert, John & Wes also play themselves and after mysterious earthquakes occur, Heather notices Dylan is acting strange and learns he's having nightmares abut Freddy Krueger. She gets him cared for at a hospital and decides to talk to Wes. He tells her that Freddy is an ancient evil essence from the films that wants to come into reality and convinces her that the only way to stop him is to make another film where she must play Nancy one last time. I like Freddy's new look and J. Peter Robinson's score is great. Wes re-invented the series with this by making Freddy scary again and bringing back the original stars. I recommend this great nightmare sequel.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It takes a master to re-birth a tired franchise
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert W. (Robert_duder@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    None of the Nightmare On Elm Street sequels were straight-up 'bad' per se. But the series has definitely hit an all time lull with Freddy's Dead. Could anyone breath new life into it? Probably not, other than the creator and horror master himself. Wes Craven comes up with one of the coolest, most unique ideas in a horror franchise. He breaks down the fourth wall and lets Freddy Kreuger into the real real world and brings back some of the iconic original characters. Heather Langenkamp returns as herself who is contemplating returning the Nightmare series as Nancy. Its great to have her back and she brings a certain memorable class to the film. The very talented youngster Miko Hughes (he was stunning in Mercury Rising) plays Heather's young son Dylan. He does a great job! John Saxon also returns playing himself this time around and its good to see him back as he does a great job too. Even Wes Craven plays double duty as himself and it was really cool to have him on the cast. David Newsom is decent as Langenkamp's husband although his role is quite small they have good chemistry. Robert Englund is the star of this movie. That might seem like an obvious statement but he is absolutely phenomenal in New Nightmare playing himself but also the return to the dark twisted killer that is Freddy Kreuger. Englund is a talented actor who has been type casted into horror flicks but this proved he can be versatile and really work with a great script. Its also proof that it was the lack of really depthy scripts that changed Kreuger into a comedic character because he slips back into the dark version of Kreuger flawlessly. It was so much fun to see Englund and Langenkamp together out of character and playing themselves. Ultimately you could watch the first Nightmare On Elm Street movie and then watch this one and not miss anything. This is a direct follow up to Wes Craven's original film and it is a brilliant addition to the series and the perfect way to usher in the tenth anniversary at the time. Generally this is considered by fans to be a great re-birth in the series and rightfully so. This one proves why horror fans like me keep coming back for more because sometimes even upper instalments can surprise you!! 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Again Freddie Krueger with his hideously scarred face and knives terrorizing Heather and family
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ma-cortes
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Modern rendition about the myth Freddy dealing with young people discover they're having the same terrible nightmares . New version about Freddy Krueger killing people in macabre style and boasts some startling , gruesome special effects . A re-imagining of the classic Freddy Krueger, a serial-killer who wields a glove with four blades embedded in the fingers and murders people in their dreams , resulting in their real death in reality . Nowadays, it's nearing the 10th Anniversary of the picture 'A Nightmare on Elm Street' and one of the protagonists , (Heather Langenkamp) starts to be haunted in their nightmares by scar-faced and dream-hunting Freddy Krueger (Robert Englund now fits likes a glove) , a kind of spectre with awful burns , in stripy jumper and large knives. He enters their dreams at will and again kill them. Heather Langenkamp is being scared by a voice on a telephone , sounding very similar to the movie's nasty, Freddy Krueger . When Heather's husband (David Newsom) is killed in a car crash and is discovered with slash marks on him, Heather starts to wonder somethings . Heathe learns that Freddy has now entered the real world . The unsettling Heather plagued by astonishing dreams helps her son (Miko Hughes) to attempt to stop the nasty and demonic Freddy who kill people in macabre ways . Mother and son are having the same bad dream in which a malicious bogeyman is frightening them with knives attached to his fingers and the dream becomes reality . Heather sets out to discover the truth by attempting to draw the bogeyman out of the dream . This is a diverting reworking upon first film's plot by screenwriter Wes Craven based on his characters and dealing with the imaginative premise about a kind of ghost who can enter their dreams at will and intents on taking over both his body and mind . The twisted script dishes up the requisite helping of one-liners and throwaway black humor . This eerie film packs thrills , chills , creepy events and lots of blood and gore . It's a flimsily plotted but visually enjoyable addition to the Krueger endless saga . There are a few genuinely inspired events , notably Freddy's appearances and the extraordinary body-ripping spotlights in the Hospital room . Although it results to be a franchise that we now know was to follow , there are some originally frightening dream sequences. Special and extravagant visual effects are the climax of the movie and the startling make-up on Freddy face , but both of them don't save the story . Young casting and special appearance by John Saxon , the same Wes Craven and Robert Shaye , film's producer . Creepy and imaginatively made musical score fitting to terror movie by J. Peter Robinson . Colorful and atmospheric cinematography by Mark Irwin . The motion picture well produced by the great producer Robert Shaye from New Line Cinema and is professionally directed by Wes Craven , though with no originality and nothing new to show . Wes's sure grasp of the skewed logic of nightmares help to sustain the ambiguity between the dream and real world . Rating : 5,5 , passable sequel . It's all acceptable scary fun . The series initiates itself from original entry title &uml;A Nightmare on Elm Elm Street&uml; directed by Wes Craven with Heather Langenkamp , Johnny Depp , Amanda Wyss and John Saxon . The rest is a series of disjointed but however impressive special effects pieces . As it was followed by a handful of sequels in which horrifying special effects dominate this slasher saga , as &uml;Freddy's revenge&uml; 1985 by Jack Sholder with Kim Myers , Clu Gulager and Hope Lange ; &uml;Dream warrior&uml; 1987 by Chuck Russell with Patricia Arquette , Larry Fishburne and Craig Wasson , it's one of the best sequels from successful original film by Craven , as &uml;Dream master&uml; (1988) by Renny Harlin with Lisa Wilcox , Tuesday Knight and &uml;The dream child&uml; (1989) by Stephen Hopkins with Lisa Wilcox , Erika Anderson . Besides a Television series &uml;The Freddy's nightmares&uml; and this last one &uml; A nightmare on Elm Street&uml;(2010) with Jackie Haley that is a simple copy with little imagination , too many flaws and giving routine treatment .
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Why does this have such a high rating???
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    votesmall
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Okay, first of all, let me say that I am not one of those people who doesn't "get" movies if they aren't "edge of your seat". For example, 2001: A Space Odyssey could have been good, but it just was too boring and had no explanation for the monolith and not enough focus on HAL 9000, the freaky antagonist supercomputer. Basically, most of the movie was shots of space with classical music. And everyone tells me that I didn't "get" it. No, I can't get it because there is no explanation, and it's too boring! BUT, I did love Hellraiser: Inferno, and In the Mouth of Madness. So, what's the problem with New Nightmare??? Okay, first of all is the fact of Freddy. I actually love his new look, the jacket and hand, although the sweater and hat looked kind of funny and I didn't understand why they put the greenish-red rings around his eyes. They went to so much work designing this new, evil looking Freddy and he can't have more than 20 minutes of screen time. Yep, just a little bit more than Freddy's Revenge. And yes, I know that Pinhead had just about as much screen time in Hellraiser: Inferno, but they didn't redesign Pinhead in that one. Okay, I do love psychological thrillers, but this was just BORING! It starts off with an all metal, robotic glove coming to life on the film set of a new Nightmare on Elm Street movie. The glove kills several special effects crew members and is about to kill Heather Langenkamp (Nancy)'s husband. And then she wakes up. Okay, that was awesome! Good, frightening, and all a dream. And the next forty five minutes or so have NOTHING going on for the movie! I will admit, the interview scene and the limousine scene were somewhat interesting, but the rest of it was just boring fluff. And also, we get a few decent shots of Robert Englund in this movie, but we don't see near enough! The entire movie revolves around two characters, that just can't carry the film. The kid is just annoying. He isn't creepy, he's just annoying. Some of the dream sequences are pretty freaky, but other than that, he's just a normal kid talking in a stupid voice. Also, the vomit scene was pretty much stolen from The Exorcist. So, by the end of the movie, all of the characters are referring to Heather as Nancy, but this is never explained. And then there is a showdown at the "boiler room", which looks more like an ancient Greek temple than a power plant mechanical room. Okay, this scene was too tacky. And Freddy actually extends his arm to get the kid, tries to "eat him", and wraps his tongue around Heather before burning to death and turning into, get this, the devil.??? I will admit that I liked how it came to the real world, and we do get some pretty decent shots of Wes Craven and Robert Englund, and even a few other stars, but, like Freddy, they just don't have enough screen time. And some of the dream sequences are pretty creepy. But, I have two HUGE problems with this movie. First off, the fact that Heather has to wait until, like an hour and a half (around three days in the movie) after her kid tries to commit suicide, has seizures, nightmares, and tries to kill her before taking him to the hospital. Also, her kid is terrified of nightmares and she shuts the door so he is in the dark! ??? Worst mother ever! And it also isn't about Freddy on a film set, it's about him stalking Heather and her kid for two hours. This movie was so slow paced that it seemed like Titanic. Not to mention a hilariously low body count, with Freddy having a brand new glove, but breaking someone's neck! ??? Judge for yourself, but I thought it was boring. The kid was annoying, there wasn't enough Freddy, and Heather Langenkamp is just not an interesting character, unlike Nancy Thompson. Overall, this film is just TOO slow. I mean, Wes Craven had a really good idea here. Very original, just like the first Nightmare movie. But he didn't execute it very well. The kid was annoying, Heather Langenkamp looks bored and "worried" throughout the movie. And some of the dialogue is just ridiculous. Like how Wes all of a sudden knows what the new Freddy is is kind of ridiculous, because he couldn't possibly know that. Not to mention that in Never Sleep Again, he showed drawings for a "Freddy mobile" that he was going to put in the movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wes Craven's New Nightmare
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It looked like for some time Freddy's Dead: The Final Nightmare was the final time scary movie fans would see the iconic razor handed "Son of 100 Maniacs", but then original film writer and director Wes Craven (The Hills Have Eyes, Scream) came up with this clever comeback. Basically the tenth anniversary of the movie A Nightmare on Elm Street is coming up, and original star Heather Langenkamp is part of the special events celebrating, along with its director Wes Craven, and of course the man behind killer Freddy Krueger, actor Robert Englund. She has a happy life with husband Chase Porter (David Newsom) and son Dylan (Miko Hughes), but she is being stalked by a nasty voice on the phone, and creepy goings on in her house, and things get worse when her husband is killed in a car crash, and his body has slash marks on it. Dylan is refusing to sleep anymore, because he is scared, like the movie, that Freddy will come in his dream and try to kill him, and dealing with this Heather is also being offered a part in the next Nightmare film Wes is working on, but the script needs work. Heather is finding the behaviour of her son uncontrollable, and she does believe Freddy is haunting her, Wes comes up with the theory that now the Elm Street films are over an ancient spirit must have helped him come out of the fictional world to enter dreams in real life, and his script may be part of this way out. It comes to the point when Dylan may be taken away from Heather due to his psychologically disturbed behaviour, but she is also incarcerated by doctors who believe she is going mad, of course Freddy continues his kills while this is going on. Eventually Heather, like her character, enters a dream to confront Freddy and stop the terror, and she manages to lock him in a furnace to burn to death, and returning to the real world she and her son read the new finished sample script sent by Wes. I like films where actors play a version of themselves, you could see this as semi-documentary considering the concept of how to bring back a character supposedly dead for good, the story has its moments of irritation, especially with the doctors breaking up the mother and son, but the script has clever references and ideas, and there is just enough Freddy and gore for the fans, a not bad horror film. Worth watching!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Langenkamp and Englund go uber real.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    amesmonde
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The lead actors of the original Nightmare on Elm Street, on it's 10th Anniversary, are terrorized by a Freddy Kruger like entity that wants Heather Langenkamp and her son dead. The seemingly outrageous bloody opening is quickly defused as a fitting dream sequence and new ground is broken as we discover the actors are playing themselves. It appears to break the fourth wall with Wes Craven, John Saxon and Robert Englund to name a few playing themselves. Of course this allows Langenkamp to return as herself after her Nancy character's death in the third. This non-conventional approach with a number of uneasy phone calls would become the precursor film within a film which appears in Craven's own Scream series. While you'd expect most of the actors to be able to play themselves they do at times come across as awkward and uncomfortable. Thankfully the leads pull it off with ease - namely Englund and Langenkamp. Faces from the original also cameo as themselves and a photo of Johnny Depp shows up in the background. Some scenes are a blast for fans with Englund playing himself as Freddy on a talk show. Of course Englund also plays Freddy the embodiment of an evil spirit with an expert indifference. This darker, scarier Freddy is probably what fans of the original wanted to see in the handful of sequels. There's irony on irony with producer Rob Shay inviting Langenkamp to come back and play Nancy one last time in a definitive nightmare. Writer/Director Craven delivers another novel idea with a tantalizing hook. There's a nice touch where reality merges with dreams and John Sax returns as his character Lt. Donald Thompson with Langenkamp calling him John and him unawares in turn calling her Nancy. The kill scenes pay homage to the original and even some of the sequels notably the Chase Porter car crash. With a strong supporting cast (mainly those ones who don't play themselves) including Miko Hughes as Dylan Porter Heather's on screen son gives a solid mixture of Poltergeist/Exorcist-like performance. It may have benefited from a more natural looking production, less film- like to emphasis the realness in contrast to the movie world and Nightmare sequences. It's own high production values and Mark Irwin's great cinematography dilute the edginess. Craven's screenplay also injects a part actress character study there is an interesting subtext about fame and it trappings. A New Nightmare has all the kills one would expect with excellent make up and visual effect on display with Craven trying to out do himself with the accompanying music by J. Peter Robinson. The idea of uber Freddy character harassing the real life cast and crew doesn't tire with the entertaining and fitting premise. It's only a movie...or is it?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wes Craven's dream of rebooting Freddy becomes a New Nightmare
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ironhorse_iv
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's hardly a perfect film for Wes Craven, but it's eerie and thought-provoking, something that been lacking in the previous movies that made Freddy Kruger into a goofy wise cracker and cheesy death scenes. It is also the last the last time that Freddy showed any real menace. Wes Craven made this to take back control of his creation and it works as a criticism of what the franchise became with Freddy as a comedian, not to mention a rebuff to the tired argument about violence in films always causing it in the real world. Freddy was far more straightforward with his kills and didn't manifest elaborate scenarios for each death. Pure intimidation. That's what Wes was trying to bring back. New Nightmare is almost in it's own league. New Nightmare had a great story and very original, creative ideas in it but it was still a bit confusing with the plot of the movie! It's the movie without a movie. He would work this angle again, in the 'Scream' series with the "Stab" movies in Scream are movies within a movie! It's work here, it doesn't work there. 'A Nightmare on Elm Street 7: The Ascension' is being film, and Heather Langenkamp playing herself, the actress that play the original heroic star of the original movie is being ask to reprise her role as Nancy Thompson. She notice that her husband Chase, and son Dylan is also being haunted by Freddy Krueger (Robert Englund) outside the filming, and confront the actor Robert Englund about it. She then go to Wes Craven himself, who reveals that Freddy is real, and only she can stop him. There is a interesting theory that comes to front with this. It's probably not Wes Craven's intent, but an audience's interpretation is authorial fallacy to see that there might have been a connection to this movie with that of the 3rd movie Dream Warriors. Heather's character Nancy Thompson's dies in the World of the first three films/four films. Her funeral/gravestone proves this (the gravestone was shown in A Nightmare on Elm Street 4: The Dream Master). The character Kristen from Dream Warrior, somehow, created a new world/new reality and placed Nancy's soul into this world in the end of the film like it stated. It's a dream world, yet Nancy's soul can live a full beautiful life in this beautiful dream world. Nancy's physically dead, yet not spiritually dead. I would think that once she ages and dies in this dream world then she would have truly died. Overall, Nancy has been placed in a matrix type reality so, to her, everyone in this reality is real/important to her. Freddy though, once all event's take place in the "real world" (the world of dream warriors), realizes that Nancy is in this dream world/alternate reality and therefore tries to kill Nancy since he wants to finish her off once and for all. It must take a lot for him to enter this dream world though since earthquakes are occurring constantly. Since Wes Craven wrote 1, 3, and this one... could it be Nancy living as Heather. It's a headache, but it's worth checking out or is the previous films fake and this movie real. Is Heather insane or is Freddy really coming out of the film to kill the actress that kill him in the movie? The movie goes with the realish look to it. Surprising the earthquake footage in the film is real. It was taken from the 1994 Northridge earthquake that happen during filming. The movie seem fresh, and the way in which Freddy talked, walked, and looked really brought a much needed shot of freshness to the character that had seriously been lacking. Freddy has a deeper voice. To correspond with this, the make-up and outfit of the character was different, with one of the most prominent differences being that he now wears a long, black trench coat. In addition, the signature glove was redesigned for a more organic look, with the fingers resembling bones and having muscle textures in between. It really adds to his darker vibe. The problem with the movie was that Freddy was way too soft. He looked better than ever and he was darker than ever, but all he did to the kid and his mom was chase them around, wrestle them, and scare them. Also Freddie's screen time is almost non existent, he rarely in the film, but when he is, he's scary! Heather Langenkamp takes most of the movie time, sadly not great in leading the film anywhere, as she unable to act her way through wet tissue. Even with fails, Wes Craven's New Nightmare was probably created solely for the purpose of Wes wanting to erase 2, 4, 5, and 6, and I believe even 3 because he said in the special documentary for the box set that he essentially believes that only the first film and A New Nightmare are cannon. Essentially Wes Craven threw a bratty fit over the fact there were so many sequels and wanted to basically bury the series with A New Nightmare. The meta-fictional methodology of 'New Nightmare' really gave a unique and terrifying storyline and, in my opinion, one of the best films of the franchise. So while the theory is still interesting and I can see how it would work, I think it takes away from how good 'New Nightmare' is. I'd rather watch this one than a complete hideous garbage 2010 one with Haley is, God I dislike that version.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Christina Aguilera once spoke for him.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RickHarvey
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Freddy is back... well, he's not actually back. Instead, an heinous and satanic Freddy takes over our screens as a his existence forges into reality while his films continue to dwindle in the publics conscious.(With the majority of the films being awful, i can't say that's a bad thing.) I really liked New nightmare: Original, showcasing the same mixture of intelligence with the first NMOES and most importantly, great acting. I was sceptical at first when knowing that a child actor stars - with them mostly being obnoxious and unwittingly annoying in majority of films - but thankfully the character of Dylan paid off. The thought of Freddy becoming closer to reality when the longer he's forgotten is fantastic. With the actors playing themselves, you follow the hysteria that follows Heather while he struggles to cope with a stalker. Freddy's appearance: Long, drab trench coat and feroda hat, is spot on. Despite a change in Freddy, it seems he can't resist on pulling out a one-liner from under his sleeves. Made his enigmatic aura suffer a little. Overall, I'm glad Craven decided to make another NMOES - even if it was just for the money. You sense his input being commanded with every shot. The final act gave lovers of the original NMOES an flash back on their initial experience with Freddy. With both script and camera, Craven didn't do much wrong.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Immensely enjoyable and entertaining
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    GL84
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After a series of nightmares and her son's strange behavior, an actress becomes convinced a famous serial killer from her movie history has come into the real world and targeting her and her family, forcing her to stop him using the tricks from the movies. This here turned out to be a decent if slightly flawed entry. Among the many things that work here is the fact that, by tying into the film series as a whole separate entity away from the reality presented here, it manages to be a lot smarter than it usually would be for this type of film, and that's something to commend by having the actors playing themselves instead of the film roles. That makes the typically-clich&eacute;d is-it-all-a-dream-or-not set-up far more effective than it has any right to be, given even more credence with Freddy's return to being scary again. Dropping any semblance of wise-cracks, puns and lame jokes, reduced screen time and really only appearing to do damage make him a credible, scary force again, and that helps this out tremendously. With some great action in here, a lot of great special effects and a fantastic finale, this has a lot going for it but there's still a few problems here, mainly in the film's continued usage of the annoying child who does nothing but scream and does nothing to the film overall. The low kill count means there's little variety to be found as well, but overall this isn't all too bad. Rated R: Violence, Language, and children in jeopardy
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Worst nightmare come true!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    amethystwings32
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    These movies , are horrific and terrifying to the very core! They are awful , Freddy Krueger made Jason and Mike Myers look like dark angels! He can definitely give someone nightmares, he is grotesque. What he did to his victims , would make any squeamish person want to vomit! That is why I will never get this obsession , anyone who likes these are seriously disturbed! I would hardly call these good, blood and gore doesn't make a movie good! Being terrified to the very core, with it's graphic nightmarish scenes. To the point you want to scream, walk out. Cover your face the whole time , faint or hurl. That is all of the signs that a movie is not worth watching!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Great Nightmare Sequel!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gwnightscream
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Robert Englund, Heather Langenkamp, John Saxon, Wes Craven and Miko Hughes star in Wes Craven's 1994 horror sequel. Freddy Krueger stalks the cast & crew of the original "Nightmare on Elm Street" during it's 10th anniversary. This film takes place in Los Angeles and focuses on Heather (Langenkamp) and her young son, Dylan (Hughes). Robert, John & Wes also play themselves and after mysterious earthquakes occur, Heather notices Dylan is acting strange and learns he's having nightmares abut Freddy Krueger. She gets him cared for at a hospital and decides to talk to Wes. He tells her that Freddy is an ancient evil essence from the films that wants to come into reality and convinces her that the only way to stop him is to make another film where she must play Nancy one last time. I like Freddy's new look and J. Peter Robinson's score is great. Wes re-invented the series with this by making Freddy scary again and bringing back the original stars. I recommend this great nightmare sequel.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It takes a master to re-birth a tired franchise
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert W. (Robert_duder@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    None of the Nightmare On Elm Street sequels were straight-up 'bad' per se. But the series has definitely hit an all time lull with Freddy's Dead. Could anyone breath new life into it? Probably not, other than the creator and horror master himself. Wes Craven comes up with one of the coolest, most unique ideas in a horror franchise. He breaks down the fourth wall and lets Freddy Kreuger into the real real world and brings back some of the iconic original characters. Heather Langenkamp returns as herself who is contemplating returning the Nightmare series as Nancy. Its great to have her back and she brings a certain memorable class to the film. The very talented youngster Miko Hughes (he was stunning in Mercury Rising) plays Heather's young son Dylan. He does a great job! John Saxon also returns playing himself this time around and its good to see him back as he does a great job too. Even Wes Craven plays double duty as himself and it was really cool to have him on the cast. David Newsom is decent as Langenkamp's husband although his role is quite small they have good chemistry. Robert Englund is the star of this movie. That might seem like an obvious statement but he is absolutely phenomenal in New Nightmare playing himself but also the return to the dark twisted killer that is Freddy Kreuger. Englund is a talented actor who has been type casted into horror flicks but this proved he can be versatile and really work with a great script. Its also proof that it was the lack of really depthy scripts that changed Kreuger into a comedic character because he slips back into the dark version of Kreuger flawlessly. It was so much fun to see Englund and Langenkamp together out of character and playing themselves. Ultimately you could watch the first Nightmare On Elm Street movie and then watch this one and not miss anything. This is a direct follow up to Wes Craven's original film and it is a brilliant addition to the series and the perfect way to usher in the tenth anniversary at the time. Generally this is considered by fans to be a great re-birth in the series and rightfully so. This one proves why horror fans like me keep coming back for more because sometimes even upper instalments can surprise you!! 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Again Freddie Krueger with his hideously scarred face and knives terrorizing Heather and family
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ma-cortes
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Modern rendition about the myth Freddy dealing with young people discover they're having the same terrible nightmares . New version about Freddy Krueger killing people in macabre style and boasts some startling , gruesome special effects . A re-imagining of the classic Freddy Krueger, a serial-killer who wields a glove with four blades embedded in the fingers and murders people in their dreams , resulting in their real death in reality . Nowadays, it's nearing the 10th Anniversary of the picture 'A Nightmare on Elm Street' and one of the protagonists , (Heather Langenkamp) starts to be haunted in their nightmares by scar-faced and dream-hunting Freddy Krueger (Robert Englund now fits likes a glove) , a kind of spectre with awful burns , in stripy jumper and large knives. He enters their dreams at will and again kill them. Heather Langenkamp is being scared by a voice on a telephone , sounding very similar to the movie's nasty, Freddy Krueger . When Heather's husband (David Newsom) is killed in a car crash and is discovered with slash marks on him, Heather starts to wonder somethings . Heathe learns that Freddy has now entered the real world . The unsettling Heather plagued by astonishing dreams helps her son (Miko Hughes) to attempt to stop the nasty and demonic Freddy who kill people in macabre ways . Mother and son are having the same bad dream in which a malicious bogeyman is frightening them with knives attached to his fingers and the dream becomes reality . Heather sets out to discover the truth by attempting to draw the bogeyman out of the dream . This is a diverting reworking upon first film's plot by screenwriter Wes Craven based on his characters and dealing with the imaginative premise about a kind of ghost who can enter their dreams at will and intents on taking over both his body and mind . The twisted script dishes up the requisite helping of one-liners and throwaway black humor . This eerie film packs thrills , chills , creepy events and lots of blood and gore . It's a flimsily plotted but visually enjoyable addition to the Krueger endless saga . There are a few genuinely inspired events , notably Freddy's appearances and the extraordinary body-ripping spotlights in the Hospital room . Although it results to be a franchise that we now know was to follow , there are some originally frightening dream sequences. Special and extravagant visual effects are the climax of the movie and the startling make-up on Freddy face , but both of them don't save the story . Young casting and special appearance by John Saxon , the same Wes Craven and Robert Shaye , film's producer . Creepy and imaginatively made musical score fitting to terror movie by J. Peter Robinson . Colorful and atmospheric cinematography by Mark Irwin . The motion picture well produced by the great producer Robert Shaye from New Line Cinema and is professionally directed by Wes Craven , though with no originality and nothing new to show . Wes's sure grasp of the skewed logic of nightmares help to sustain the ambiguity between the dream and real world . Rating : 5,5 , passable sequel . It's all acceptable scary fun . The series initiates itself from original entry title &uml;A Nightmare on Elm Elm Street&uml; directed by Wes Craven with Heather Langenkamp , Johnny Depp , Amanda Wyss and John Saxon . The rest is a series of disjointed but however impressive special effects pieces . As it was followed by a handful of sequels in which horrifying special effects dominate this slasher saga , as &uml;Freddy's revenge&uml; 1985 by Jack Sholder with Kim Myers , Clu Gulager and Hope Lange ; &uml;Dream warrior&uml; 1987 by Chuck Russell with Patricia Arquette , Larry Fishburne and Craig Wasson , it's one of the best sequels from successful original film by Craven , as &uml;Dream master&uml; (1988) by Renny Harlin with Lisa Wilcox , Tuesday Knight and &uml;The dream child&uml; (1989) by Stephen Hopkins with Lisa Wilcox , Erika Anderson . Besides a Television series &uml;The Freddy's nightmares&uml; and this last one &uml; A nightmare on Elm Street&uml;(2010) with Jackie Haley that is a simple copy with little imagination , too many flaws and giving routine treatment .
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Why does this have such a high rating???
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    votesmall
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Okay, first of all, let me say that I am not one of those people who doesn't "get" movies if they aren't "edge of your seat". For example, 2001: A Space Odyssey could have been good, but it just was too boring and had no explanation for the monolith and not enough focus on HAL 9000, the freaky antagonist supercomputer. Basically, most of the movie was shots of space with classical music. And everyone tells me that I didn't "get" it. No, I can't get it because there is no explanation, and it's too boring! BUT, I did love Hellraiser: Inferno, and In the Mouth of Madness. So, what's the problem with New Nightmare??? Okay, first of all is the fact of Freddy. I actually love his new look, the jacket and hand, although the sweater and hat looked kind of funny and I didn't understand why they put the greenish-red rings around his eyes. They went to so much work designing this new, evil looking Freddy and he can't have more than 20 minutes of screen time. Yep, just a little bit more than Freddy's Revenge. And yes, I know that Pinhead had just about as much screen time in Hellraiser: Inferno, but they didn't redesign Pinhead in that one. Okay, I do love psychological thrillers, but this was just BORING! It starts off with an all metal, robotic glove coming to life on the film set of a new Nightmare on Elm Street movie. The glove kills several special effects crew members and is about to kill Heather Langenkamp (Nancy)'s husband. And then she wakes up. Okay, that was awesome! Good, frightening, and all a dream. And the next forty five minutes or so have NOTHING going on for the movie! I will admit, the interview scene and the limousine scene were somewhat interesting, but the rest of it was just boring fluff. And also, we get a few decent shots of Robert Englund in this movie, but we don't see near enough! The entire movie revolves around two characters, that just can't carry the film. The kid is just annoying. He isn't creepy, he's just annoying. Some of the dream sequences are pretty freaky, but other than that, he's just a normal kid talking in a stupid voice. Also, the vomit scene was pretty much stolen from The Exorcist. So, by the end of the movie, all of the characters are referring to Heather as Nancy, but this is never explained. And then there is a showdown at the "boiler room", which looks more like an ancient Greek temple than a power plant mechanical room. Okay, this scene was too tacky. And Freddy actually extends his arm to get the kid, tries to "eat him", and wraps his tongue around Heather before burning to death and turning into, get this, the devil.??? I will admit that I liked how it came to the real world, and we do get some pretty decent shots of Wes Craven and Robert Englund, and even a few other stars, but, like Freddy, they just don't have enough screen time. And some of the dream sequences are pretty creepy. But, I have two HUGE problems with this movie. First off, the fact that Heather has to wait until, like an hour and a half (around three days in the movie) after her kid tries to commit suicide, has seizures, nightmares, and tries to kill her before taking him to the hospital. Also, her kid is terrified of nightmares and she shuts the door so he is in the dark! ??? Worst mother ever! And it also isn't about Freddy on a film set, it's about him stalking Heather and her kid for two hours. This movie was so slow paced that it seemed like Titanic. Not to mention a hilariously low body count, with Freddy having a brand new glove, but breaking someone's neck! ??? Judge for yourself, but I thought it was boring. The kid was annoying, there wasn't enough Freddy, and Heather Langenkamp is just not an interesting character, unlike Nancy Thompson. Overall, this film is just TOO slow. I mean, Wes Craven had a really good idea here. Very original, just like the first Nightmare movie. But he didn't execute it very well. The kid was annoying, Heather Langenkamp looks bored and "worried" throughout the movie. And some of the dialogue is just ridiculous. Like how Wes all of a sudden knows what the new Freddy is is kind of ridiculous, because he couldn't possibly know that. Not to mention that in Never Sleep Again, he showed drawings for a "Freddy mobile" that he was going to put in the movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wes Craven's New Nightmare
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It looked like for some time Freddy's Dead: The Final Nightmare was the final time scary movie fans would see the iconic razor handed "Son of 100 Maniacs", but then original film writer and director Wes Craven (The Hills Have Eyes, Scream) came up with this clever comeback. Basically the tenth anniversary of the movie A Nightmare on Elm Street is coming up, and original star Heather Langenkamp is part of the special events celebrating, along with its director Wes Craven, and of course the man behind killer Freddy Krueger, actor Robert Englund. She has a happy life with husband Chase Porter (David Newsom) and son Dylan (Miko Hughes), but she is being stalked by a nasty voice on the phone, and creepy goings on in her house, and things get worse when her husband is killed in a car crash, and his body has slash marks on it. Dylan is refusing to sleep anymore, because he is scared, like the movie, that Freddy will come in his dream and try to kill him, and dealing with this Heather is also being offered a part in the next Nightmare film Wes is working on, but the script needs work. Heather is finding the behaviour of her son uncontrollable, and she does believe Freddy is haunting her, Wes comes up with the theory that now the Elm Street films are over an ancient spirit must have helped him come out of the fictional world to enter dreams in real life, and his script may be part of this way out. It comes to the point when Dylan may be taken away from Heather due to his psychologically disturbed behaviour, but she is also incarcerated by doctors who believe she is going mad, of course Freddy continues his kills while this is going on. Eventually Heather, like her character, enters a dream to confront Freddy and stop the terror, and she manages to lock him in a furnace to burn to death, and returning to the real world she and her son read the new finished sample script sent by Wes. I like films where actors play a version of themselves, you could see this as semi-documentary considering the concept of how to bring back a character supposedly dead for good, the story has its moments of irritation, especially with the doctors breaking up the mother and son, but the script has clever references and ideas, and there is just enough Freddy and gore for the fans, a not bad horror film. Worth watching!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Langenkamp and Englund go uber real.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    amesmonde
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The lead actors of the original Nightmare on Elm Street, on it's 10th Anniversary, are terrorized by a Freddy Kruger like entity that wants Heather Langenkamp and her son dead. The seemingly outrageous bloody opening is quickly defused as a fitting dream sequence and new ground is broken as we discover the actors are playing themselves. It appears to break the fourth wall with Wes Craven, John Saxon and Robert Englund to name a few playing themselves. Of course this allows Langenkamp to return as herself after her Nancy character's death in the third. This non-conventional approach with a number of uneasy phone calls would become the precursor film within a film which appears in Craven's own Scream series. While you'd expect most of the actors to be able to play themselves they do at times come across as awkward and uncomfortable. Thankfully the leads pull it off with ease - namely Englund and Langenkamp. Faces from the original also cameo as themselves and a photo of Johnny Depp shows up in the background. Some scenes are a blast for fans with Englund playing himself as Freddy on a talk show. Of course Englund also plays Freddy the embodiment of an evil spirit with an expert indifference. This darker, scarier Freddy is probably what fans of the original wanted to see in the handful of sequels. There's irony on irony with producer Rob Shay inviting Langenkamp to come back and play Nancy one last time in a definitive nightmare. Writer/Director Craven delivers another novel idea with a tantalizing hook. There's a nice touch where reality merges with dreams and John Sax returns as his character Lt. Donald Thompson with Langenkamp calling him John and him unawares in turn calling her Nancy. The kill scenes pay homage to the original and even some of the sequels notably the Chase Porter car crash. With a strong supporting cast (mainly those ones who don't play themselves) including Miko Hughes as Dylan Porter Heather's on screen son gives a solid mixture of Poltergeist/Exorcist-like performance. It may have benefited from a more natural looking production, less film- like to emphasis the realness in contrast to the movie world and Nightmare sequences. It's own high production values and Mark Irwin's great cinematography dilute the edginess. Craven's screenplay also injects a part actress character study there is an interesting subtext about fame and it trappings. A New Nightmare has all the kills one would expect with excellent make up and visual effect on display with Craven trying to out do himself with the accompanying music by J. Peter Robinson. The idea of uber Freddy character harassing the real life cast and crew doesn't tire with the entertaining and fitting premise. It's only a movie...or is it?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wes Craven's dream of rebooting Freddy becomes a New Nightmare
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ironhorse_iv
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's hardly a perfect film for Wes Craven, but it's eerie and thought-provoking, something that been lacking in the previous movies that made Freddy Kruger into a goofy wise cracker and cheesy death scenes. It is also the last the last time that Freddy showed any real menace. Wes Craven made this to take back control of his creation and it works as a criticism of what the franchise became with Freddy as a comedian, not to mention a rebuff to the tired argument about violence in films always causing it in the real world. Freddy was far more straightforward with his kills and didn't manifest elaborate scenarios for each death. Pure intimidation. That's what Wes was trying to bring back. New Nightmare is almost in it's own league. New Nightmare had a great story and very original, creative ideas in it but it was still a bit confusing with the plot of the movie! It's the movie without a movie. He would work this angle again, in the 'Scream' series with the "Stab" movies in Scream are movies within a movie! It's work here, it doesn't work there. 'A Nightmare on Elm Street 7: The Ascension' is being film, and Heather Langenkamp playing herself, the actress that play the original heroic star of the original movie is being ask to reprise her role as Nancy Thompson. She notice that her husband Chase, and son Dylan is also being haunted by Freddy Krueger (Robert Englund) outside the filming, and confront the actor Robert Englund about it. She then go to Wes Craven himself, who reveals that Freddy is real, and only she can stop him. There is a interesting theory that comes to front with this. It's probably not Wes Craven's intent, but an audience's interpretation is authorial fallacy to see that there might have been a connection to this movie with that of the 3rd movie Dream Warriors. Heather's character Nancy Thompson's dies in the World of the first three films/four films. Her funeral/gravestone proves this (the gravestone was shown in A Nightmare on Elm Street 4: The Dream Master). The character Kristen from Dream Warrior, somehow, created a new world/new reality and placed Nancy's soul into this world in the end of the film like it stated. It's a dream world, yet Nancy's soul can live a full beautiful life in this beautiful dream world. Nancy's physically dead, yet not spiritually dead. I would think that once she ages and dies in this dream world then she would have truly died. Overall, Nancy has been placed in a matrix type reality so, to her, everyone in this reality is real/important to her. Freddy though, once all event's take place in the "real world" (the world of dream warriors), realizes that Nancy is in this dream world/alternate reality and therefore tries to kill Nancy since he wants to finish her off once and for all. It must take a lot for him to enter this dream world though since earthquakes are occurring constantly. Since Wes Craven wrote 1, 3, and this one... could it be Nancy living as Heather. It's a headache, but it's worth checking out or is the previous films fake and this movie real. Is Heather insane or is Freddy really coming out of the film to kill the actress that kill him in the movie? The movie goes with the realish look to it. Surprising the earthquake footage in the film is real. It was taken from the 1994 Northridge earthquake that happen during filming. The movie seem fresh, and the way in which Freddy talked, walked, and looked really brought a much needed shot of freshness to the character that had seriously been lacking. Freddy has a deeper voice. To correspond with this, the make-up and outfit of the character was different, with one of the most prominent differences being that he now wears a long, black trench coat. In addition, the signature glove was redesigned for a more organic look, with the fingers resembling bones and having muscle textures in between. It really adds to his darker vibe. The problem with the movie was that Freddy was way too soft. He looked better than ever and he was darker than ever, but all he did to the kid and his mom was chase them around, wrestle them, and scare them. Also Freddie's screen time is almost non existent, he rarely in the film, but when he is, he's scary! Heather Langenkamp takes most of the movie time, sadly not great in leading the film anywhere, as she unable to act her way through wet tissue. Even with fails, Wes Craven's New Nightmare was probably created solely for the purpose of Wes wanting to erase 2, 4, 5, and 6, and I believe even 3 because he said in the special documentary for the box set that he essentially believes that only the first film and A New Nightmare are cannon. Essentially Wes Craven threw a bratty fit over the fact there were so many sequels and wanted to basically bury the series with A New Nightmare. The meta-fictional methodology of 'New Nightmare' really gave a unique and terrifying storyline and, in my opinion, one of the best films of the franchise. So while the theory is still interesting and I can see how it would work, I think it takes away from how good 'New Nightmare' is. I'd rather watch this one than a complete hideous garbage 2010 one with Haley is, God I dislike that version.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Christina Aguilera once spoke for him.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RickHarvey
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Freddy is back... well, he's not actually back. Instead, an heinous and satanic Freddy takes over our screens as a his existence forges into reality while his films continue to dwindle in the publics conscious.(With the majority of the films being awful, i can't say that's a bad thing.) I really liked New nightmare: Original, showcasing the same mixture of intelligence with the first NMOES and most importantly, great acting. I was sceptical at first when knowing that a child actor stars - with them mostly being obnoxious and unwittingly annoying in majority of films - but thankfully the character of Dylan paid off. The thought of Freddy becoming closer to reality when the longer he's forgotten is fantastic. With the actors playing themselves, you follow the hysteria that follows Heather while he struggles to cope with a stalker. Freddy's appearance: Long, drab trench coat and feroda hat, is spot on. Despite a change in Freddy, it seems he can't resist on pulling out a one-liner from under his sleeves. Made his enigmatic aura suffer a little. Overall, I'm glad Craven decided to make another NMOES - even if it was just for the money. You sense his input being commanded with every shot. The final act gave lovers of the original NMOES an flash back on their initial experience with Freddy. With both script and camera, Craven didn't do much wrong.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Immensely enjoyable and entertaining
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    GL84
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After a series of nightmares and her son's strange behavior, an actress becomes convinced a famous serial killer from her movie history has come into the real world and targeting her and her family, forcing her to stop him using the tricks from the movies. This here turned out to be a decent if slightly flawed entry. Among the many things that work here is the fact that, by tying into the film series as a whole separate entity away from the reality presented here, it manages to be a lot smarter than it usually would be for this type of film, and that's something to commend by having the actors playing themselves instead of the film roles. That makes the typically-clich&eacute;d is-it-all-a-dream-or-not set-up far more effective than it has any right to be, given even more credence with Freddy's return to being scary again. Dropping any semblance of wise-cracks, puns and lame jokes, reduced screen time and really only appearing to do damage make him a credible, scary force again, and that helps this out tremendously. With some great action in here, a lot of great special effects and a fantastic finale, this has a lot going for it but there's still a few problems here, mainly in the film's continued usage of the annoying child who does nothing but scream and does nothing to the film overall. The low kill count means there's little variety to be found as well, but overall this isn't all too bad. Rated R: Violence, Language, and children in jeopardy
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Worst nightmare come true!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    amethystwings32
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    These movies , are horrific and terrifying to the very core! They are awful , Freddy Krueger made Jason and Mike Myers look like dark angels! He can definitely give someone nightmares, he is grotesque. What he did to his victims , would make any squeamish person want to vomit! That is why I will never get this obsession , anyone who likes these are seriously disturbed! I would hardly call these good, blood and gore doesn't make a movie good! Being terrified to the very core, with it's graphic nightmarish scenes. To the point you want to scream, walk out. Cover your face the whole time , faint or hurl. That is all of the signs that a movie is not worth watching!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Great Nightmare Sequel!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gwnightscream
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Robert Englund, Heather Langenkamp, John Saxon, Wes Craven and Miko Hughes star in Wes Craven's 1994 horror sequel. Freddy Krueger stalks the cast & crew of the original "Nightmare on Elm Street" during it's 10th anniversary. This film takes place in Los Angeles and focuses on Heather (Langenkamp) and her young son, Dylan (Hughes). Robert, John & Wes also play themselves and after mysterious earthquakes occur, Heather notices Dylan is acting strange and learns he's having nightmares abut Freddy Krueger. She gets him cared for at a hospital and decides to talk to Wes. He tells her that Freddy is an ancient evil essence from the films that wants to come into reality and convinces her that the only way to stop him is to make another film where she must play Nancy one last time. I like Freddy's new look and J. Peter Robinson's score is great. Wes re-invented the series with this by making Freddy scary again and bringing back the original stars. I recommend this great nightmare sequel.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It takes a master to re-birth a tired franchise
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert W. (Robert_duder@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    None of the Nightmare On Elm Street sequels were straight-up 'bad' per se. But the series has definitely hit an all time lull with Freddy's Dead. Could anyone breath new life into it? Probably not, other than the creator and horror master himself. Wes Craven comes up with one of the coolest, most unique ideas in a horror franchise. He breaks down the fourth wall and lets Freddy Kreuger into the real real world and brings back some of the iconic original characters. Heather Langenkamp returns as herself who is contemplating returning the Nightmare series as Nancy. Its great to have her back and she brings a certain memorable class to the film. The very talented youngster Miko Hughes (he was stunning in Mercury Rising) plays Heather's young son Dylan. He does a great job! John Saxon also returns playing himself this time around and its good to see him back as he does a great job too. Even Wes Craven plays double duty as himself and it was really cool to have him on the cast. David Newsom is decent as Langenkamp's husband although his role is quite small they have good chemistry. Robert Englund is the star of this movie. That might seem like an obvious statement but he is absolutely phenomenal in New Nightmare playing himself but also the return to the dark twisted killer that is Freddy Kreuger. Englund is a talented actor who has been type casted into horror flicks but this proved he can be versatile and really work with a great script. Its also proof that it was the lack of really depthy scripts that changed Kreuger into a comedic character because he slips back into the dark version of Kreuger flawlessly. It was so much fun to see Englund and Langenkamp together out of character and playing themselves. Ultimately you could watch the first Nightmare On Elm Street movie and then watch this one and not miss anything. This is a direct follow up to Wes Craven's original film and it is a brilliant addition to the series and the perfect way to usher in the tenth anniversary at the time. Generally this is considered by fans to be a great re-birth in the series and rightfully so. This one proves why horror fans like me keep coming back for more because sometimes even upper instalments can surprise you!! 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Again Freddie Krueger with his hideously scarred face and knives terrorizing Heather and family
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ma-cortes
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Modern rendition about the myth Freddy dealing with young people discover they're having the same terrible nightmares . New version about Freddy Krueger killing people in macabre style and boasts some startling , gruesome special effects . A re-imagining of the classic Freddy Krueger, a serial-killer who wields a glove with four blades embedded in the fingers and murders people in their dreams , resulting in their real death in reality . Nowadays, it's nearing the 10th Anniversary of the picture 'A Nightmare on Elm Street' and one of the protagonists , (Heather Langenkamp) starts to be haunted in their nightmares by scar-faced and dream-hunting Freddy Krueger (Robert Englund now fits likes a glove) , a kind of spectre with awful burns , in stripy jumper and large knives. He enters their dreams at will and again kill them. Heather Langenkamp is being scared by a voice on a telephone , sounding very similar to the movie's nasty, Freddy Krueger . When Heather's husband (David Newsom) is killed in a car crash and is discovered with slash marks on him, Heather starts to wonder somethings . Heathe learns that Freddy has now entered the real world . The unsettling Heather plagued by astonishing dreams helps her son (Miko Hughes) to attempt to stop the nasty and demonic Freddy who kill people in macabre ways . Mother and son are having the same bad dream in which a malicious bogeyman is frightening them with knives attached to his fingers and the dream becomes reality . Heather sets out to discover the truth by attempting to draw the bogeyman out of the dream . This is a diverting reworking upon first film's plot by screenwriter Wes Craven based on his characters and dealing with the imaginative premise about a kind of ghost who can enter their dreams at will and intents on taking over both his body and mind . The twisted script dishes up the requisite helping of one-liners and throwaway black humor . This eerie film packs thrills , chills , creepy events and lots of blood and gore . It's a flimsily plotted but visually enjoyable addition to the Krueger endless saga . There are a few genuinely inspired events , notably Freddy's appearances and the extraordinary body-ripping spotlights in the Hospital room . Although it results to be a franchise that we now know was to follow , there are some originally frightening dream sequences. Special and extravagant visual effects are the climax of the movie and the startling make-up on Freddy face , but both of them don't save the story . Young casting and special appearance by John Saxon , the same Wes Craven and Robert Shaye , film's producer . Creepy and imaginatively made musical score fitting to terror movie by J. Peter Robinson . Colorful and atmospheric cinematography by Mark Irwin . The motion picture well produced by the great producer Robert Shaye from New Line Cinema and is professionally directed by Wes Craven , though with no originality and nothing new to show . Wes's sure grasp of the skewed logic of nightmares help to sustain the ambiguity between the dream and real world . Rating : 5,5 , passable sequel . It's all acceptable scary fun . The series initiates itself from original entry title &uml;A Nightmare on Elm Elm Street&uml; directed by Wes Craven with Heather Langenkamp , Johnny Depp , Amanda Wyss and John Saxon . The rest is a series of disjointed but however impressive special effects pieces . As it was followed by a handful of sequels in which horrifying special effects dominate this slasher saga , as &uml;Freddy's revenge&uml; 1985 by Jack Sholder with Kim Myers , Clu Gulager and Hope Lange ; &uml;Dream warrior&uml; 1987 by Chuck Russell with Patricia Arquette , Larry Fishburne and Craig Wasson , it's one of the best sequels from successful original film by Craven , as &uml;Dream master&uml; (1988) by Renny Harlin with Lisa Wilcox , Tuesday Knight and &uml;The dream child&uml; (1989) by Stephen Hopkins with Lisa Wilcox , Erika Anderson . Besides a Television series &uml;The Freddy's nightmares&uml; and this last one &uml; A nightmare on Elm Street&uml;(2010) with Jackie Haley that is a simple copy with little imagination , too many flaws and giving routine treatment .
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Why does this have such a high rating???
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    votesmall
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Okay, first of all, let me say that I am not one of those people who doesn't "get" movies if they aren't "edge of your seat". For example, 2001: A Space Odyssey could have been good, but it just was too boring and had no explanation for the monolith and not enough focus on HAL 9000, the freaky antagonist supercomputer. Basically, most of the movie was shots of space with classical music. And everyone tells me that I didn't "get" it. No, I can't get it because there is no explanation, and it's too boring! BUT, I did love Hellraiser: Inferno, and In the Mouth of Madness. So, what's the problem with New Nightmare??? Okay, first of all is the fact of Freddy. I actually love his new look, the jacket and hand, although the sweater and hat looked kind of funny and I didn't understand why they put the greenish-red rings around his eyes. They went to so much work designing this new, evil looking Freddy and he can't have more than 20 minutes of screen time. Yep, just a little bit more than Freddy's Revenge. And yes, I know that Pinhead had just about as much screen time in Hellraiser: Inferno, but they didn't redesign Pinhead in that one. Okay, I do love psychological thrillers, but this was just BORING! It starts off with an all metal, robotic glove coming to life on the film set of a new Nightmare on Elm Street movie. The glove kills several special effects crew members and is about to kill Heather Langenkamp (Nancy)'s husband. And then she wakes up. Okay, that was awesome! Good, frightening, and all a dream. And the next forty five minutes or so have NOTHING going on for the movie! I will admit, the interview scene and the limousine scene were somewhat interesting, but the rest of it was just boring fluff. And also, we get a few decent shots of Robert Englund in this movie, but we don't see near enough! The entire movie revolves around two characters, that just can't carry the film. The kid is just annoying. He isn't creepy, he's just annoying. Some of the dream sequences are pretty freaky, but other than that, he's just a normal kid talking in a stupid voice. Also, the vomit scene was pretty much stolen from The Exorcist. So, by the end of the movie, all of the characters are referring to Heather as Nancy, but this is never explained. And then there is a showdown at the "boiler room", which looks more like an ancient Greek temple than a power plant mechanical room. Okay, this scene was too tacky. And Freddy actually extends his arm to get the kid, tries to "eat him", and wraps his tongue around Heather before burning to death and turning into, get this, the devil.??? I will admit that I liked how it came to the real world, and we do get some pretty decent shots of Wes Craven and Robert Englund, and even a few other stars, but, like Freddy, they just don't have enough screen time. And some of the dream sequences are pretty creepy. But, I have two HUGE problems with this movie. First off, the fact that Heather has to wait until, like an hour and a half (around three days in the movie) after her kid tries to commit suicide, has seizures, nightmares, and tries to kill her before taking him to the hospital. Also, her kid is terrified of nightmares and she shuts the door so he is in the dark! ??? Worst mother ever! And it also isn't about Freddy on a film set, it's about him stalking Heather and her kid for two hours. This movie was so slow paced that it seemed like Titanic. Not to mention a hilariously low body count, with Freddy having a brand new glove, but breaking someone's neck! ??? Judge for yourself, but I thought it was boring. The kid was annoying, there wasn't enough Freddy, and Heather Langenkamp is just not an interesting character, unlike Nancy Thompson. Overall, this film is just TOO slow. I mean, Wes Craven had a really good idea here. Very original, just like the first Nightmare movie. But he didn't execute it very well. The kid was annoying, Heather Langenkamp looks bored and "worried" throughout the movie. And some of the dialogue is just ridiculous. Like how Wes all of a sudden knows what the new Freddy is is kind of ridiculous, because he couldn't possibly know that. Not to mention that in Never Sleep Again, he showed drawings for a "Freddy mobile" that he was going to put in the movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wes Craven's New Nightmare
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It looked like for some time Freddy's Dead: The Final Nightmare was the final time scary movie fans would see the iconic razor handed "Son of 100 Maniacs", but then original film writer and director Wes Craven (The Hills Have Eyes, Scream) came up with this clever comeback. Basically the tenth anniversary of the movie A Nightmare on Elm Street is coming up, and original star Heather Langenkamp is part of the special events celebrating, along with its director Wes Craven, and of course the man behind killer Freddy Krueger, actor Robert Englund. She has a happy life with husband Chase Porter (David Newsom) and son Dylan (Miko Hughes), but she is being stalked by a nasty voice on the phone, and creepy goings on in her house, and things get worse when her husband is killed in a car crash, and his body has slash marks on it. Dylan is refusing to sleep anymore, because he is scared, like the movie, that Freddy will come in his dream and try to kill him, and dealing with this Heather is also being offered a part in the next Nightmare film Wes is working on, but the script needs work. Heather is finding the behaviour of her son uncontrollable, and she does believe Freddy is haunting her, Wes comes up with the theory that now the Elm Street films are over an ancient spirit must have helped him come out of the fictional world to enter dreams in real life, and his script may be part of this way out. It comes to the point when Dylan may be taken away from Heather due to his psychologically disturbed behaviour, but she is also incarcerated by doctors who believe she is going mad, of course Freddy continues his kills while this is going on. Eventually Heather, like her character, enters a dream to confront Freddy and stop the terror, and she manages to lock him in a furnace to burn to death, and returning to the real world she and her son read the new finished sample script sent by Wes. I like films where actors play a version of themselves, you could see this as semi-documentary considering the concept of how to bring back a character supposedly dead for good, the story has its moments of irritation, especially with the doctors breaking up the mother and son, but the script has clever references and ideas, and there is just enough Freddy and gore for the fans, a not bad horror film. Worth watching!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Langenkamp and Englund go uber real.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    amesmonde
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The lead actors of the original Nightmare on Elm Street, on it's 10th Anniversary, are terrorized by a Freddy Kruger like entity that wants Heather Langenkamp and her son dead. The seemingly outrageous bloody opening is quickly defused as a fitting dream sequence and new ground is broken as we discover the actors are playing themselves. It appears to break the fourth wall with Wes Craven, John Saxon and Robert Englund to name a few playing themselves. Of course this allows Langenkamp to return as herself after her Nancy character's death in the third. This non-conventional approach with a number of uneasy phone calls would become the precursor film within a film which appears in Craven's own Scream series. While you'd expect most of the actors to be able to play themselves they do at times come across as awkward and uncomfortable. Thankfully the leads pull it off with ease - namely Englund and Langenkamp. Faces from the original also cameo as themselves and a photo of Johnny Depp shows up in the background. Some scenes are a blast for fans with Englund playing himself as Freddy on a talk show. Of course Englund also plays Freddy the embodiment of an evil spirit with an expert indifference. This darker, scarier Freddy is probably what fans of the original wanted to see in the handful of sequels. There's irony on irony with producer Rob Shay inviting Langenkamp to come back and play Nancy one last time in a definitive nightmare. Writer/Director Craven delivers another novel idea with a tantalizing hook. There's a nice touch where reality merges with dreams and John Sax returns as his character Lt. Donald Thompson with Langenkamp calling him John and him unawares in turn calling her Nancy. The kill scenes pay homage to the original and even some of the sequels notably the Chase Porter car crash. With a strong supporting cast (mainly those ones who don't play themselves) including Miko Hughes as Dylan Porter Heather's on screen son gives a solid mixture of Poltergeist/Exorcist-like performance. It may have benefited from a more natural looking production, less film- like to emphasis the realness in contrast to the movie world and Nightmare sequences. It's own high production values and Mark Irwin's great cinematography dilute the edginess. Craven's screenplay also injects a part actress character study there is an interesting subtext about fame and it trappings. A New Nightmare has all the kills one would expect with excellent make up and visual effect on display with Craven trying to out do himself with the accompanying music by J. Peter Robinson. The idea of uber Freddy character harassing the real life cast and crew doesn't tire with the entertaining and fitting premise. It's only a movie...or is it?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wes Craven's dream of rebooting Freddy becomes a New Nightmare
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ironhorse_iv
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's hardly a perfect film for Wes Craven, but it's eerie and thought-provoking, something that been lacking in the previous movies that made Freddy Kruger into a goofy wise cracker and cheesy death scenes. It is also the last the last time that Freddy showed any real menace. Wes Craven made this to take back control of his creation and it works as a criticism of what the franchise became with Freddy as a comedian, not to mention a rebuff to the tired argument about violence in films always causing it in the real world. Freddy was far more straightforward with his kills and didn't manifest elaborate scenarios for each death. Pure intimidation. That's what Wes was trying to bring back. New Nightmare is almost in it's own league. New Nightmare had a great story and very original, creative ideas in it but it was still a bit confusing with the plot of the movie! It's the movie without a movie. He would work this angle again, in the 'Scream' series with the "Stab" movies in Scream are movies within a movie! It's work here, it doesn't work there. 'A Nightmare on Elm Street 7: The Ascension' is being film, and Heather Langenkamp playing herself, the actress that play the original heroic star of the original movie is being ask to reprise her role as Nancy Thompson. She notice that her husband Chase, and son Dylan is also being haunted by Freddy Krueger (Robert Englund) outside the filming, and confront the actor Robert Englund about it. She then go to Wes Craven himself, who reveals that Freddy is real, and only she can stop him. There is a interesting theory that comes to front with this. It's probably not Wes Craven's intent, but an audience's interpretation is authorial fallacy to see that there might have been a connection to this movie with that of the 3rd movie Dream Warriors. Heather's character Nancy Thompson's dies in the World of the first three films/four films. Her funeral/gravestone proves this (the gravestone was shown in A Nightmare on Elm Street 4: The Dream Master). The character Kristen from Dream Warrior, somehow, created a new world/new reality and placed Nancy's soul into this world in the end of the film like it stated. It's a dream world, yet Nancy's soul can live a full beautiful life in this beautiful dream world. Nancy's physically dead, yet not spiritually dead. I would think that once she ages and dies in this dream world then she would have truly died. Overall, Nancy has been placed in a matrix type reality so, to her, everyone in this reality is real/important to her. Freddy though, once all event's take place in the "real world" (the world of dream warriors), realizes that Nancy is in this dream world/alternate reality and therefore tries to kill Nancy since he wants to finish her off once and for all. It must take a lot for him to enter this dream world though since earthquakes are occurring constantly. Since Wes Craven wrote 1, 3, and this one... could it be Nancy living as Heather. It's a headache, but it's worth checking out or is the previous films fake and this movie real. Is Heather insane or is Freddy really coming out of the film to kill the actress that kill him in the movie? The movie goes with the realish look to it. Surprising the earthquake footage in the film is real. It was taken from the 1994 Northridge earthquake that happen during filming. The movie seem fresh, and the way in which Freddy talked, walked, and looked really brought a much needed shot of freshness to the character that had seriously been lacking. Freddy has a deeper voice. To correspond with this, the make-up and outfit of the character was different, with one of the most prominent differences being that he now wears a long, black trench coat. In addition, the signature glove was redesigned for a more organic look, with the fingers resembling bones and having muscle textures in between. It really adds to his darker vibe. The problem with the movie was that Freddy was way too soft. He looked better than ever and he was darker than ever, but all he did to the kid and his mom was chase them around, wrestle them, and scare them. Also Freddie's screen time is almost non existent, he rarely in the film, but when he is, he's scary! Heather Langenkamp takes most of the movie time, sadly not great in leading the film anywhere, as she unable to act her way through wet tissue. Even with fails, Wes Craven's New Nightmare was probably created solely for the purpose of Wes wanting to erase 2, 4, 5, and 6, and I believe even 3 because he said in the special documentary for the box set that he essentially believes that only the first film and A New Nightmare are cannon. Essentially Wes Craven threw a bratty fit over the fact there were so many sequels and wanted to basically bury the series with A New Nightmare. The meta-fictional methodology of 'New Nightmare' really gave a unique and terrifying storyline and, in my opinion, one of the best films of the franchise. So while the theory is still interesting and I can see how it would work, I think it takes away from how good 'New Nightmare' is. I'd rather watch this one than a complete hideous garbage 2010 one with Haley is, God I dislike that version.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Christina Aguilera once spoke for him.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RickHarvey
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Freddy is back... well, he's not actually back. Instead, an heinous and satanic Freddy takes over our screens as a his existence forges into reality while his films continue to dwindle in the publics conscious.(With the majority of the films being awful, i can't say that's a bad thing.) I really liked New nightmare: Original, showcasing the same mixture of intelligence with the first NMOES and most importantly, great acting. I was sceptical at first when knowing that a child actor stars - with them mostly being obnoxious and unwittingly annoying in majority of films - but thankfully the character of Dylan paid off. The thought of Freddy becoming closer to reality when the longer he's forgotten is fantastic. With the actors playing themselves, you follow the hysteria that follows Heather while he struggles to cope with a stalker. Freddy's appearance: Long, drab trench coat and feroda hat, is spot on. Despite a change in Freddy, it seems he can't resist on pulling out a one-liner from under his sleeves. Made his enigmatic aura suffer a little. Overall, I'm glad Craven decided to make another NMOES - even if it was just for the money. You sense his input being commanded with every shot. The final act gave lovers of the original NMOES an flash back on their initial experience with Freddy. With both script and camera, Craven didn't do much wrong.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Immensely enjoyable and entertaining
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    GL84
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After a series of nightmares and her son's strange behavior, an actress becomes convinced a famous serial killer from her movie history has come into the real world and targeting her and her family, forcing her to stop him using the tricks from the movies. This here turned out to be a decent if slightly flawed entry. Among the many things that work here is the fact that, by tying into the film series as a whole separate entity away from the reality presented here, it manages to be a lot smarter than it usually would be for this type of film, and that's something to commend by having the actors playing themselves instead of the film roles. That makes the typically-clich&eacute;d is-it-all-a-dream-or-not set-up far more effective than it has any right to be, given even more credence with Freddy's return to being scary again. Dropping any semblance of wise-cracks, puns and lame jokes, reduced screen time and really only appearing to do damage make him a credible, scary force again, and that helps this out tremendously. With some great action in here, a lot of great special effects and a fantastic finale, this has a lot going for it but there's still a few problems here, mainly in the film's continued usage of the annoying child who does nothing but scream and does nothing to the film overall. The low kill count means there's little variety to be found as well, but overall this isn't all too bad. Rated R: Violence, Language, and children in jeopardy
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Worst nightmare come true!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    amethystwings32
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    These movies , are horrific and terrifying to the very core! They are awful , Freddy Krueger made Jason and Mike Myers look like dark angels! He can definitely give someone nightmares, he is grotesque. What he did to his victims , would make any squeamish person want to vomit! That is why I will never get this obsession , anyone who likes these are seriously disturbed! I would hardly call these good, blood and gore doesn't make a movie good! Being terrified to the very core, with it's graphic nightmarish scenes. To the point you want to scream, walk out. Cover your face the whole time , faint or hurl. That is all of the signs that a movie is not worth watching!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Great Nightmare Sequel!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gwnightscream
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Robert Englund, Heather Langenkamp, John Saxon, Wes Craven and Miko Hughes star in Wes Craven's 1994 horror sequel. Freddy Krueger stalks the cast & crew of the original "Nightmare on Elm Street" during it's 10th anniversary. This film takes place in Los Angeles and focuses on Heather (Langenkamp) and her young son, Dylan (Hughes). Robert, John & Wes also play themselves and after mysterious earthquakes occur, Heather notices Dylan is acting strange and learns he's having nightmares abut Freddy Krueger. She gets him cared for at a hospital and decides to talk to Wes. He tells her that Freddy is an ancient evil essence from the films that wants to come into reality and convinces her that the only way to stop him is to make another film where she must play Nancy one last time. I like Freddy's new look and J. Peter Robinson's score is great. Wes re-invented the series with this by making Freddy scary again and bringing back the original stars. I recommend this great nightmare sequel.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It takes a master to re-birth a tired franchise
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert W. (Robert_duder@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    None of the Nightmare On Elm Street sequels were straight-up 'bad' per se. But the series has definitely hit an all time lull with Freddy's Dead. Could anyone breath new life into it? Probably not, other than the creator and horror master himself. Wes Craven comes up with one of the coolest, most unique ideas in a horror franchise. He breaks down the fourth wall and lets Freddy Kreuger into the real real world and brings back some of the iconic original characters. Heather Langenkamp returns as herself who is contemplating returning the Nightmare series as Nancy. Its great to have her back and she brings a certain memorable class to the film. The very talented youngster Miko Hughes (he was stunning in Mercury Rising) plays Heather's young son Dylan. He does a great job! John Saxon also returns playing himself this time around and its good to see him back as he does a great job too. Even Wes Craven plays double duty as himself and it was really cool to have him on the cast. David Newsom is decent as Langenkamp's husband although his role is quite small they have good chemistry. Robert Englund is the star of this movie. That might seem like an obvious statement but he is absolutely phenomenal in New Nightmare playing himself but also the return to the dark twisted killer that is Freddy Kreuger. Englund is a talented actor who has been type casted into horror flicks but this proved he can be versatile and really work with a great script. Its also proof that it was the lack of really depthy scripts that changed Kreuger into a comedic character because he slips back into the dark version of Kreuger flawlessly. It was so much fun to see Englund and Langenkamp together out of character and playing themselves. Ultimately you could watch the first Nightmare On Elm Street movie and then watch this one and not miss anything. This is a direct follow up to Wes Craven's original film and it is a brilliant addition to the series and the perfect way to usher in the tenth anniversary at the time. Generally this is considered by fans to be a great re-birth in the series and rightfully so. This one proves why horror fans like me keep coming back for more because sometimes even upper instalments can surprise you!! 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Again Freddie Krueger with his hideously scarred face and knives terrorizing Heather and family
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ma-cortes
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Modern rendition about the myth Freddy dealing with young people discover they're having the same terrible nightmares . New version about Freddy Krueger killing people in macabre style and boasts some startling , gruesome special effects . A re-imagining of the classic Freddy Krueger, a serial-killer who wields a glove with four blades embedded in the fingers and murders people in their dreams , resulting in their real death in reality . Nowadays, it's nearing the 10th Anniversary of the picture 'A Nightmare on Elm Street' and one of the protagonists , (Heather Langenkamp) starts to be haunted in their nightmares by scar-faced and dream-hunting Freddy Krueger (Robert Englund now fits likes a glove) , a kind of spectre with awful burns , in stripy jumper and large knives. He enters their dreams at will and again kill them. Heather Langenkamp is being scared by a voice on a telephone , sounding very similar to the movie's nasty, Freddy Krueger . When Heather's husband (David Newsom) is killed in a car crash and is discovered with slash marks on him, Heather starts to wonder somethings . Heathe learns that Freddy has now entered the real world . The unsettling Heather plagued by astonishing dreams helps her son (Miko Hughes) to attempt to stop the nasty and demonic Freddy who kill people in macabre ways . Mother and son are having the same bad dream in which a malicious bogeyman is frightening them with knives attached to his fingers and the dream becomes reality . Heather sets out to discover the truth by attempting to draw the bogeyman out of the dream . This is a diverting reworking upon first film's plot by screenwriter Wes Craven based on his characters and dealing with the imaginative premise about a kind of ghost who can enter their dreams at will and intents on taking over both his body and mind . The twisted script dishes up the requisite helping of one-liners and throwaway black humor . This eerie film packs thrills , chills , creepy events and lots of blood and gore . It's a flimsily plotted but visually enjoyable addition to the Krueger endless saga . There are a few genuinely inspired events , notably Freddy's appearances and the extraordinary body-ripping spotlights in the Hospital room . Although it results to be a franchise that we now know was to follow , there are some originally frightening dream sequences. Special and extravagant visual effects are the climax of the movie and the startling make-up on Freddy face , but both of them don't save the story . Young casting and special appearance by John Saxon , the same Wes Craven and Robert Shaye , film's producer . Creepy and imaginatively made musical score fitting to terror movie by J. Peter Robinson . Colorful and atmospheric cinematography by Mark Irwin . The motion picture well produced by the great producer Robert Shaye from New Line Cinema and is professionally directed by Wes Craven , though with no originality and nothing new to show . Wes's sure grasp of the skewed logic of nightmares help to sustain the ambiguity between the dream and real world . Rating : 5,5 , passable sequel . It's all acceptable scary fun . The series initiates itself from original entry title &uml;A Nightmare on Elm Elm Street&uml; directed by Wes Craven with Heather Langenkamp , Johnny Depp , Amanda Wyss and John Saxon . The rest is a series of disjointed but however impressive special effects pieces . As it was followed by a handful of sequels in which horrifying special effects dominate this slasher saga , as &uml;Freddy's revenge&uml; 1985 by Jack Sholder with Kim Myers , Clu Gulager and Hope Lange ; &uml;Dream warrior&uml; 1987 by Chuck Russell with Patricia Arquette , Larry Fishburne and Craig Wasson , it's one of the best sequels from successful original film by Craven , as &uml;Dream master&uml; (1988) by Renny Harlin with Lisa Wilcox , Tuesday Knight and &uml;The dream child&uml; (1989) by Stephen Hopkins with Lisa Wilcox , Erika Anderson . Besides a Television series &uml;The Freddy's nightmares&uml; and this last one &uml; A nightmare on Elm Street&uml;(2010) with Jackie Haley that is a simple copy with little imagination , too many flaws and giving routine treatment .
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Why does this have such a high rating???
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    votesmall
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Okay, first of all, let me say that I am not one of those people who doesn't "get" movies if they aren't "edge of your seat". For example, 2001: A Space Odyssey could have been good, but it just was too boring and had no explanation for the monolith and not enough focus on HAL 9000, the freaky antagonist supercomputer. Basically, most of the movie was shots of space with classical music. And everyone tells me that I didn't "get" it. No, I can't get it because there is no explanation, and it's too boring! BUT, I did love Hellraiser: Inferno, and In the Mouth of Madness. So, what's the problem with New Nightmare??? Okay, first of all is the fact of Freddy. I actually love his new look, the jacket and hand, although the sweater and hat looked kind of funny and I didn't understand why they put the greenish-red rings around his eyes. They went to so much work designing this new, evil looking Freddy and he can't have more than 20 minutes of screen time. Yep, just a little bit more than Freddy's Revenge. And yes, I know that Pinhead had just about as much screen time in Hellraiser: Inferno, but they didn't redesign Pinhead in that one. Okay, I do love psychological thrillers, but this was just BORING! It starts off with an all metal, robotic glove coming to life on the film set of a new Nightmare on Elm Street movie. The glove kills several special effects crew members and is about to kill Heather Langenkamp (Nancy)'s husband. And then she wakes up. Okay, that was awesome! Good, frightening, and all a dream. And the next forty five minutes or so have NOTHING going on for the movie! I will admit, the interview scene and the limousine scene were somewhat interesting, but the rest of it was just boring fluff. And also, we get a few decent shots of Robert Englund in this movie, but we don't see near enough! The entire movie revolves around two characters, that just can't carry the film. The kid is just annoying. He isn't creepy, he's just annoying. Some of the dream sequences are pretty freaky, but other than that, he's just a normal kid talking in a stupid voice. Also, the vomit scene was pretty much stolen from The Exorcist. So, by the end of the movie, all of the characters are referring to Heather as Nancy, but this is never explained. And then there is a showdown at the "boiler room", which looks more like an ancient Greek temple than a power plant mechanical room. Okay, this scene was too tacky. And Freddy actually extends his arm to get the kid, tries to "eat him", and wraps his tongue around Heather before burning to death and turning into, get this, the devil.??? I will admit that I liked how it came to the real world, and we do get some pretty decent shots of Wes Craven and Robert Englund, and even a few other stars, but, like Freddy, they just don't have enough screen time. And some of the dream sequences are pretty creepy. But, I have two HUGE problems with this movie. First off, the fact that Heather has to wait until, like an hour and a half (around three days in the movie) after her kid tries to commit suicide, has seizures, nightmares, and tries to kill her before taking him to the hospital. Also, her kid is terrified of nightmares and she shuts the door so he is in the dark! ??? Worst mother ever! And it also isn't about Freddy on a film set, it's about him stalking Heather and her kid for two hours. This movie was so slow paced that it seemed like Titanic. Not to mention a hilariously low body count, with Freddy having a brand new glove, but breaking someone's neck! ??? Judge for yourself, but I thought it was boring. The kid was annoying, there wasn't enough Freddy, and Heather Langenkamp is just not an interesting character, unlike Nancy Thompson. Overall, this film is just TOO slow. I mean, Wes Craven had a really good idea here. Very original, just like the first Nightmare movie. But he didn't execute it very well. The kid was annoying, Heather Langenkamp looks bored and "worried" throughout the movie. And some of the dialogue is just ridiculous. Like how Wes all of a sudden knows what the new Freddy is is kind of ridiculous, because he couldn't possibly know that. Not to mention that in Never Sleep Again, he showed drawings for a "Freddy mobile" that he was going to put in the movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wes Craven's New Nightmare
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It looked like for some time Freddy's Dead: The Final Nightmare was the final time scary movie fans would see the iconic razor handed "Son of 100 Maniacs", but then original film writer and director Wes Craven (The Hills Have Eyes, Scream) came up with this clever comeback. Basically the tenth anniversary of the movie A Nightmare on Elm Street is coming up, and original star Heather Langenkamp is part of the special events celebrating, along with its director Wes Craven, and of course the man behind killer Freddy Krueger, actor Robert Englund. She has a happy life with husband Chase Porter (David Newsom) and son Dylan (Miko Hughes), but she is being stalked by a nasty voice on the phone, and creepy goings on in her house, and things get worse when her husband is killed in a car crash, and his body has slash marks on it. Dylan is refusing to sleep anymore, because he is scared, like the movie, that Freddy will come in his dream and try to kill him, and dealing with this Heather is also being offered a part in the next Nightmare film Wes is working on, but the script needs work. Heather is finding the behaviour of her son uncontrollable, and she does believe Freddy is haunting her, Wes comes up with the theory that now the Elm Street films are over an ancient spirit must have helped him come out of the fictional world to enter dreams in real life, and his script may be part of this way out. It comes to the point when Dylan may be taken away from Heather due to his psychologically disturbed behaviour, but she is also incarcerated by doctors who believe she is going mad, of course Freddy continues his kills while this is going on. Eventually Heather, like her character, enters a dream to confront Freddy and stop the terror, and she manages to lock him in a furnace to burn to death, and returning to the real world she and her son read the new finished sample script sent by Wes. I like films where actors play a version of themselves, you could see this as semi-documentary considering the concept of how to bring back a character supposedly dead for good, the story has its moments of irritation, especially with the doctors breaking up the mother and son, but the script has clever references and ideas, and there is just enough Freddy and gore for the fans, a not bad horror film. Worth watching!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Langenkamp and Englund go uber real.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    amesmonde
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The lead actors of the original Nightmare on Elm Street, on it's 10th Anniversary, are terrorized by a Freddy Kruger like entity that wants Heather Langenkamp and her son dead. The seemingly outrageous bloody opening is quickly defused as a fitting dream sequence and new ground is broken as we discover the actors are playing themselves. It appears to break the fourth wall with Wes Craven, John Saxon and Robert Englund to name a few playing themselves. Of course this allows Langenkamp to return as herself after her Nancy character's death in the third. This non-conventional approach with a number of uneasy phone calls would become the precursor film within a film which appears in Craven's own Scream series. While you'd expect most of the actors to be able to play themselves they do at times come across as awkward and uncomfortable. Thankfully the leads pull it off with ease - namely Englund and Langenkamp. Faces from the original also cameo as themselves and a photo of Johnny Depp shows up in the background. Some scenes are a blast for fans with Englund playing himself as Freddy on a talk show. Of course Englund also plays Freddy the embodiment of an evil spirit with an expert indifference. This darker, scarier Freddy is probably what fans of the original wanted to see in the handful of sequels. There's irony on irony with producer Rob Shay inviting Langenkamp to come back and play Nancy one last time in a definitive nightmare. Writer/Director Craven delivers another novel idea with a tantalizing hook. There's a nice touch where reality merges with dreams and John Sax returns as his character Lt. Donald Thompson with Langenkamp calling him John and him unawares in turn calling her Nancy. The kill scenes pay homage to the original and even some of the sequels notably the Chase Porter car crash. With a strong supporting cast (mainly those ones who don't play themselves) including Miko Hughes as Dylan Porter Heather's on screen son gives a solid mixture of Poltergeist/Exorcist-like performance. It may have benefited from a more natural looking production, less film- like to emphasis the realness in contrast to the movie world and Nightmare sequences. It's own high production values and Mark Irwin's great cinematography dilute the edginess. Craven's screenplay also injects a part actress character study there is an interesting subtext about fame and it trappings. A New Nightmare has all the kills one would expect with excellent make up and visual effect on display with Craven trying to out do himself with the accompanying music by J. Peter Robinson. The idea of uber Freddy character harassing the real life cast and crew doesn't tire with the entertaining and fitting premise. It's only a movie...or is it?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wes Craven's dream of rebooting Freddy becomes a New Nightmare
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ironhorse_iv
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's hardly a perfect film for Wes Craven, but it's eerie and thought-provoking, something that been lacking in the previous movies that made Freddy Kruger into a goofy wise cracker and cheesy death scenes. It is also the last the last time that Freddy showed any real menace. Wes Craven made this to take back control of his creation and it works as a criticism of what the franchise became with Freddy as a comedian, not to mention a rebuff to the tired argument about violence in films always causing it in the real world. Freddy was far more straightforward with his kills and didn't manifest elaborate scenarios for each death. Pure intimidation. That's what Wes was trying to bring back. New Nightmare is almost in it's own league. New Nightmare had a great story and very original, creative ideas in it but it was still a bit confusing with the plot of the movie! It's the movie without a movie. He would work this angle again, in the 'Scream' series with the "Stab" movies in Scream are movies within a movie! It's work here, it doesn't work there. 'A Nightmare on Elm Street 7: The Ascension' is being film, and Heather Langenkamp playing herself, the actress that play the original heroic star of the original movie is being ask to reprise her role as Nancy Thompson. She notice that her husband Chase, and son Dylan is also being haunted by Freddy Krueger (Robert Englund) outside the filming, and confront the actor Robert Englund about it. She then go to Wes Craven himself, who reveals that Freddy is real, and only she can stop him. There is a interesting theory that comes to front with this. It's probably not Wes Craven's intent, but an audience's interpretation is authorial fallacy to see that there might have been a connection to this movie with that of the 3rd movie Dream Warriors. Heather's character Nancy Thompson's dies in the World of the first three films/four films. Her funeral/gravestone proves this (the gravestone was shown in A Nightmare on Elm Street 4: The Dream Master). The character Kristen from Dream Warrior, somehow, created a new world/new reality and placed Nancy's soul into this world in the end of the film like it stated. It's a dream world, yet Nancy's soul can live a full beautiful life in this beautiful dream world. Nancy's physically dead, yet not spiritually dead. I would think that once she ages and dies in this dream world then she would have truly died. Overall, Nancy has been placed in a matrix type reality so, to her, everyone in this reality is real/important to her. Freddy though, once all event's take place in the "real world" (the world of dream warriors), realizes that Nancy is in this dream world/alternate reality and therefore tries to kill Nancy since he wants to finish her off once and for all. It must take a lot for him to enter this dream world though since earthquakes are occurring constantly. Since Wes Craven wrote 1, 3, and this one... could it be Nancy living as Heather. It's a headache, but it's worth checking out or is the previous films fake and this movie real. Is Heather insane or is Freddy really coming out of the film to kill the actress that kill him in the movie? The movie goes with the realish look to it. Surprising the earthquake footage in the film is real. It was taken from the 1994 Northridge earthquake that happen during filming. The movie seem fresh, and the way in which Freddy talked, walked, and looked really brought a much needed shot of freshness to the character that had seriously been lacking. Freddy has a deeper voice. To correspond with this, the make-up and outfit of the character was different, with one of the most prominent differences being that he now wears a long, black trench coat. In addition, the signature glove was redesigned for a more organic look, with the fingers resembling bones and having muscle textures in between. It really adds to his darker vibe. The problem with the movie was that Freddy was way too soft. He looked better than ever and he was darker than ever, but all he did to the kid and his mom was chase them around, wrestle them, and scare them. Also Freddie's screen time is almost non existent, he rarely in the film, but when he is, he's scary! Heather Langenkamp takes most of the movie time, sadly not great in leading the film anywhere, as she unable to act her way through wet tissue. Even with fails, Wes Craven's New Nightmare was probably created solely for the purpose of Wes wanting to erase 2, 4, 5, and 6, and I believe even 3 because he said in the special documentary for the box set that he essentially believes that only the first film and A New Nightmare are cannon. Essentially Wes Craven threw a bratty fit over the fact there were so many sequels and wanted to basically bury the series with A New Nightmare. The meta-fictional methodology of 'New Nightmare' really gave a unique and terrifying storyline and, in my opinion, one of the best films of the franchise. So while the theory is still interesting and I can see how it would work, I think it takes away from how good 'New Nightmare' is. I'd rather watch this one than a complete hideous garbage 2010 one with Haley is, God I dislike that version.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Christina Aguilera once spoke for him.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RickHarvey
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Freddy is back... well, he's not actually back. Instead, an heinous and satanic Freddy takes over our screens as a his existence forges into reality while his films continue to dwindle in the publics conscious.(With the majority of the films being awful, i can't say that's a bad thing.) I really liked New nightmare: Original, showcasing the same mixture of intelligence with the first NMOES and most importantly, great acting. I was sceptical at first when knowing that a child actor stars - with them mostly being obnoxious and unwittingly annoying in majority of films - but thankfully the character of Dylan paid off. The thought of Freddy becoming closer to reality when the longer he's forgotten is fantastic. With the actors playing themselves, you follow the hysteria that follows Heather while he struggles to cope with a stalker. Freddy's appearance: Long, drab trench coat and feroda hat, is spot on. Despite a change in Freddy, it seems he can't resist on pulling out a one-liner from under his sleeves. Made his enigmatic aura suffer a little. Overall, I'm glad Craven decided to make another NMOES - even if it was just for the money. You sense his input being commanded with every shot. The final act gave lovers of the original NMOES an flash back on their initial experience with Freddy. With both script and camera, Craven didn't do much wrong.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Immensely enjoyable and entertaining
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    GL84
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After a series of nightmares and her son's strange behavior, an actress becomes convinced a famous serial killer from her movie history has come into the real world and targeting her and her family, forcing her to stop him using the tricks from the movies. This here turned out to be a decent if slightly flawed entry. Among the many things that work here is the fact that, by tying into the film series as a whole separate entity away from the reality presented here, it manages to be a lot smarter than it usually would be for this type of film, and that's something to commend by having the actors playing themselves instead of the film roles. That makes the typically-clich&eacute;d is-it-all-a-dream-or-not set-up far more effective than it has any right to be, given even more credence with Freddy's return to being scary again. Dropping any semblance of wise-cracks, puns and lame jokes, reduced screen time and really only appearing to do damage make him a credible, scary force again, and that helps this out tremendously. With some great action in here, a lot of great special effects and a fantastic finale, this has a lot going for it but there's still a few problems here, mainly in the film's continued usage of the annoying child who does nothing but scream and does nothing to the film overall. The low kill count means there's little variety to be found as well, but overall this isn't all too bad. Rated R: Violence, Language, and children in jeopardy
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Worst nightmare come true!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    amethystwings32
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    These movies , are horrific and terrifying to the very core! They are awful , Freddy Krueger made Jason and Mike Myers look like dark angels! He can definitely give someone nightmares, he is grotesque. What he did to his victims , would make any squeamish person want to vomit! That is why I will never get this obsession , anyone who likes these are seriously disturbed! I would hardly call these good, blood and gore doesn't make a movie good! Being terrified to the very core, with it's graphic nightmarish scenes. To the point you want to scream, walk out. Cover your face the whole time , faint or hurl. That is all of the signs that a movie is not worth watching!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Great Nightmare Sequel!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gwnightscream
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Robert Englund, Heather Langenkamp, John Saxon, Wes Craven and Miko Hughes star in Wes Craven's 1994 horror sequel. Freddy Krueger stalks the cast & crew of the original "Nightmare on Elm Street" during it's 10th anniversary. This film takes place in Los Angeles and focuses on Heather (Langenkamp) and her young son, Dylan (Hughes). Robert, John & Wes also play themselves and after mysterious earthquakes occur, Heather notices Dylan is acting strange and learns he's having nightmares abut Freddy Krueger. She gets him cared for at a hospital and decides to talk to Wes. He tells her that Freddy is an ancient evil essence from the films that wants to come into reality and convinces her that the only way to stop him is to make another film where she must play Nancy one last time. I like Freddy's new look and J. Peter Robinson's score is great. Wes re-invented the series with this by making Freddy scary again and bringing back the original stars. I recommend this great nightmare sequel.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It takes a master to re-birth a tired franchise
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert W. (Robert_duder@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    None of the Nightmare On Elm Street sequels were straight-up 'bad' per se. But the series has definitely hit an all time lull with Freddy's Dead. Could anyone breath new life into it? Probably not, other than the creator and horror master himself. Wes Craven comes up with one of the coolest, most unique ideas in a horror franchise. He breaks down the fourth wall and lets Freddy Kreuger into the real real world and brings back some of the iconic original characters. Heather Langenkamp returns as herself who is contemplating returning the Nightmare series as Nancy. Its great to have her back and she brings a certain memorable class to the film. The very talented youngster Miko Hughes (he was stunning in Mercury Rising) plays Heather's young son Dylan. He does a great job! John Saxon also returns playing himself this time around and its good to see him back as he does a great job too. Even Wes Craven plays double duty as himself and it was really cool to have him on the cast. David Newsom is decent as Langenkamp's husband although his role is quite small they have good chemistry. Robert Englund is the star of this movie. That might seem like an obvious statement but he is absolutely phenomenal in New Nightmare playing himself but also the return to the dark twisted killer that is Freddy Kreuger. Englund is a talented actor who has been type casted into horror flicks but this proved he can be versatile and really work with a great script. Its also proof that it was the lack of really depthy scripts that changed Kreuger into a comedic character because he slips back into the dark version of Kreuger flawlessly. It was so much fun to see Englund and Langenkamp together out of character and playing themselves. Ultimately you could watch the first Nightmare On Elm Street movie and then watch this one and not miss anything. This is a direct follow up to Wes Craven's original film and it is a brilliant addition to the series and the perfect way to usher in the tenth anniversary at the time. Generally this is considered by fans to be a great re-birth in the series and rightfully so. This one proves why horror fans like me keep coming back for more because sometimes even upper instalments can surprise you!! 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Again Freddie Krueger with his hideously scarred face and knives terrorizing Heather and family
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ma-cortes
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Modern rendition about the myth Freddy dealing with young people discover they're having the same terrible nightmares . New version about Freddy Krueger killing people in macabre style and boasts some startling , gruesome special effects . A re-imagining of the classic Freddy Krueger, a serial-killer who wields a glove with four blades embedded in the fingers and murders people in their dreams , resulting in their real death in reality . Nowadays, it's nearing the 10th Anniversary of the picture 'A Nightmare on Elm Street' and one of the protagonists , (Heather Langenkamp) starts to be haunted in their nightmares by scar-faced and dream-hunting Freddy Krueger (Robert Englund now fits likes a glove) , a kind of spectre with awful burns , in stripy jumper and large knives. He enters their dreams at will and again kill them. Heather Langenkamp is being scared by a voice on a telephone , sounding very similar to the movie's nasty, Freddy Krueger . When Heather's husband (David Newsom) is killed in a car crash and is discovered with slash marks on him, Heather starts to wonder somethings . Heathe learns that Freddy has now entered the real world . The unsettling Heather plagued by astonishing dreams helps her son (Miko Hughes) to attempt to stop the nasty and demonic Freddy who kill people in macabre ways . Mother and son are having the same bad dream in which a malicious bogeyman is frightening them with knives attached to his fingers and the dream becomes reality . Heather sets out to discover the truth by attempting to draw the bogeyman out of the dream . This is a diverting reworking upon first film's plot by screenwriter Wes Craven based on his characters and dealing with the imaginative premise about a kind of ghost who can enter their dreams at will and intents on taking over both his body and mind . The twisted script dishes up the requisite helping of one-liners and throwaway black humor . This eerie film packs thrills , chills , creepy events and lots of blood and gore . It's a flimsily plotted but visually enjoyable addition to the Krueger endless saga . There are a few genuinely inspired events , notably Freddy's appearances and the extraordinary body-ripping spotlights in the Hospital room . Although it results to be a franchise that we now know was to follow , there are some originally frightening dream sequences. Special and extravagant visual effects are the climax of the movie and the startling make-up on Freddy face , but both of them don't save the story . Young casting and special appearance by John Saxon , the same Wes Craven and Robert Shaye , film's producer . Creepy and imaginatively made musical score fitting to terror movie by J. Peter Robinson . Colorful and atmospheric cinematography by Mark Irwin . The motion picture well produced by the great producer Robert Shaye from New Line Cinema and is professionally directed by Wes Craven , though with no originality and nothing new to show . Wes's sure grasp of the skewed logic of nightmares help to sustain the ambiguity between the dream and real world . Rating : 5,5 , passable sequel . It's all acceptable scary fun . The series initiates itself from original entry title &uml;A Nightmare on Elm Elm Street&uml; directed by Wes Craven with Heather Langenkamp , Johnny Depp , Amanda Wyss and John Saxon . The rest is a series of disjointed but however impressive special effects pieces . As it was followed by a handful of sequels in which horrifying special effects dominate this slasher saga , as &uml;Freddy's revenge&uml; 1985 by Jack Sholder with Kim Myers , Clu Gulager and Hope Lange ; &uml;Dream warrior&uml; 1987 by Chuck Russell with Patricia Arquette , Larry Fishburne and Craig Wasson , it's one of the best sequels from successful original film by Craven , as &uml;Dream master&uml; (1988) by Renny Harlin with Lisa Wilcox , Tuesday Knight and &uml;The dream child&uml; (1989) by Stephen Hopkins with Lisa Wilcox , Erika Anderson . Besides a Television series &uml;The Freddy's nightmares&uml; and this last one &uml; A nightmare on Elm Street&uml;(2010) with Jackie Haley that is a simple copy with little imagination , too many flaws and giving routine treatment .
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Why does this have such a high rating???
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    votesmall
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Okay, first of all, let me say that I am not one of those people who doesn't "get" movies if they aren't "edge of your seat". For example, 2001: A Space Odyssey could have been good, but it just was too boring and had no explanation for the monolith and not enough focus on HAL 9000, the freaky antagonist supercomputer. Basically, most of the movie was shots of space with classical music. And everyone tells me that I didn't "get" it. No, I can't get it because there is no explanation, and it's too boring! BUT, I did love Hellraiser: Inferno, and In the Mouth of Madness. So, what's the problem with New Nightmare??? Okay, first of all is the fact of Freddy. I actually love his new look, the jacket and hand, although the sweater and hat looked kind of funny and I didn't understand why they put the greenish-red rings around his eyes. They went to so much work designing this new, evil looking Freddy and he can't have more than 20 minutes of screen time. Yep, just a little bit more than Freddy's Revenge. And yes, I know that Pinhead had just about as much screen time in Hellraiser: Inferno, but they didn't redesign Pinhead in that one. Okay, I do love psychological thrillers, but this was just BORING! It starts off with an all metal, robotic glove coming to life on the film set of a new Nightmare on Elm Street movie. The glove kills several special effects crew members and is about to kill Heather Langenkamp (Nancy)'s husband. And then she wakes up. Okay, that was awesome! Good, frightening, and all a dream. And the next forty five minutes or so have NOTHING going on for the movie! I will admit, the interview scene and the limousine scene were somewhat interesting, but the rest of it was just boring fluff. And also, we get a few decent shots of Robert Englund in this movie, but we don't see near enough! The entire movie revolves around two characters, that just can't carry the film. The kid is just annoying. He isn't creepy, he's just annoying. Some of the dream sequences are pretty freaky, but other than that, he's just a normal kid talking in a stupid voice. Also, the vomit scene was pretty much stolen from The Exorcist. So, by the end of the movie, all of the characters are referring to Heather as Nancy, but this is never explained. And then there is a showdown at the "boiler room", which looks more like an ancient Greek temple than a power plant mechanical room. Okay, this scene was too tacky. And Freddy actually extends his arm to get the kid, tries to "eat him", and wraps his tongue around Heather before burning to death and turning into, get this, the devil.??? I will admit that I liked how it came to the real world, and we do get some pretty decent shots of Wes Craven and Robert Englund, and even a few other stars, but, like Freddy, they just don't have enough screen time. And some of the dream sequences are pretty creepy. But, I have two HUGE problems with this movie. First off, the fact that Heather has to wait until, like an hour and a half (around three days in the movie) after her kid tries to commit suicide, has seizures, nightmares, and tries to kill her before taking him to the hospital. Also, her kid is terrified of nightmares and she shuts the door so he is in the dark! ??? Worst mother ever! And it also isn't about Freddy on a film set, it's about him stalking Heather and her kid for two hours. This movie was so slow paced that it seemed like Titanic. Not to mention a hilariously low body count, with Freddy having a brand new glove, but breaking someone's neck! ??? Judge for yourself, but I thought it was boring. The kid was annoying, there wasn't enough Freddy, and Heather Langenkamp is just not an interesting character, unlike Nancy Thompson. Overall, this film is just TOO slow. I mean, Wes Craven had a really good idea here. Very original, just like the first Nightmare movie. But he didn't execute it very well. The kid was annoying, Heather Langenkamp looks bored and "worried" throughout the movie. And some of the dialogue is just ridiculous. Like how Wes all of a sudden knows what the new Freddy is is kind of ridiculous, because he couldn't possibly know that. Not to mention that in Never Sleep Again, he showed drawings for a "Freddy mobile" that he was going to put in the movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wes Craven's New Nightmare
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It looked like for some time Freddy's Dead: The Final Nightmare was the final time scary movie fans would see the iconic razor handed "Son of 100 Maniacs", but then original film writer and director Wes Craven (The Hills Have Eyes, Scream) came up with this clever comeback. Basically the tenth anniversary of the movie A Nightmare on Elm Street is coming up, and original star Heather Langenkamp is part of the special events celebrating, along with its director Wes Craven, and of course the man behind killer Freddy Krueger, actor Robert Englund. She has a happy life with husband Chase Porter (David Newsom) and son Dylan (Miko Hughes), but she is being stalked by a nasty voice on the phone, and creepy goings on in her house, and things get worse when her husband is killed in a car crash, and his body has slash marks on it. Dylan is refusing to sleep anymore, because he is scared, like the movie, that Freddy will come in his dream and try to kill him, and dealing with this Heather is also being offered a part in the next Nightmare film Wes is working on, but the script needs work. Heather is finding the behaviour of her son uncontrollable, and she does believe Freddy is haunting her, Wes comes up with the theory that now the Elm Street films are over an ancient spirit must have helped him come out of the fictional world to enter dreams in real life, and his script may be part of this way out. It comes to the point when Dylan may be taken away from Heather due to his psychologically disturbed behaviour, but she is also incarcerated by doctors who believe she is going mad, of course Freddy continues his kills while this is going on. Eventually Heather, like her character, enters a dream to confront Freddy and stop the terror, and she manages to lock him in a furnace to burn to death, and returning to the real world she and her son read the new finished sample script sent by Wes. I like films where actors play a version of themselves, you could see this as semi-documentary considering the concept of how to bring back a character supposedly dead for good, the story has its moments of irritation, especially with the doctors breaking up the mother and son, but the script has clever references and ideas, and there is just enough Freddy and gore for the fans, a not bad horror film. Worth watching!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Langenkamp and Englund go uber real.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    amesmonde
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The lead actors of the original Nightmare on Elm Street, on it's 10th Anniversary, are terrorized by a Freddy Kruger like entity that wants Heather Langenkamp and her son dead. The seemingly outrageous bloody opening is quickly defused as a fitting dream sequence and new ground is broken as we discover the actors are playing themselves. It appears to break the fourth wall with Wes Craven, John Saxon and Robert Englund to name a few playing themselves. Of course this allows Langenkamp to return as herself after her Nancy character's death in the third. This non-conventional approach with a number of uneasy phone calls would become the precursor film within a film which appears in Craven's own Scream series. While you'd expect most of the actors to be able to play themselves they do at times come across as awkward and uncomfortable. Thankfully the leads pull it off with ease - namely Englund and Langenkamp. Faces from the original also cameo as themselves and a photo of Johnny Depp shows up in the background. Some scenes are a blast for fans with Englund playing himself as Freddy on a talk show. Of course Englund also plays Freddy the embodiment of an evil spirit with an expert indifference. This darker, scarier Freddy is probably what fans of the original wanted to see in the handful of sequels. There's irony on irony with producer Rob Shay inviting Langenkamp to come back and play Nancy one last time in a definitive nightmare. Writer/Director Craven delivers another novel idea with a tantalizing hook. There's a nice touch where reality merges with dreams and John Sax returns as his character Lt. Donald Thompson with Langenkamp calling him John and him unawares in turn calling her Nancy. The kill scenes pay homage to the original and even some of the sequels notably the Chase Porter car crash. With a strong supporting cast (mainly those ones who don't play themselves) including Miko Hughes as Dylan Porter Heather's on screen son gives a solid mixture of Poltergeist/Exorcist-like performance. It may have benefited from a more natural looking production, less film- like to emphasis the realness in contrast to the movie world and Nightmare sequences. It's own high production values and Mark Irwin's great cinematography dilute the edginess. Craven's screenplay also injects a part actress character study there is an interesting subtext about fame and it trappings. A New Nightmare has all the kills one would expect with excellent make up and visual effect on display with Craven trying to out do himself with the accompanying music by J. Peter Robinson. The idea of uber Freddy character harassing the real life cast and crew doesn't tire with the entertaining and fitting premise. It's only a movie...or is it?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wes Craven's dream of rebooting Freddy becomes a New Nightmare
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ironhorse_iv
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's hardly a perfect film for Wes Craven, but it's eerie and thought-provoking, something that been lacking in the previous movies that made Freddy Kruger into a goofy wise cracker and cheesy death scenes. It is also the last the last time that Freddy showed any real menace. Wes Craven made this to take back control of his creation and it works as a criticism of what the franchise became with Freddy as a comedian, not to mention a rebuff to the tired argument about violence in films always causing it in the real world. Freddy was far more straightforward with his kills and didn't manifest elaborate scenarios for each death. Pure intimidation. That's what Wes was trying to bring back. New Nightmare is almost in it's own league. New Nightmare had a great story and very original, creative ideas in it but it was still a bit confusing with the plot of the movie! It's the movie without a movie. He would work this angle again, in the 'Scream' series with the "Stab" movies in Scream are movies within a movie! It's work here, it doesn't work there. 'A Nightmare on Elm Street 7: The Ascension' is being film, and Heather Langenkamp playing herself, the actress that play the original heroic star of the original movie is being ask to reprise her role as Nancy Thompson. She notice that her husband Chase, and son Dylan is also being haunted by Freddy Krueger (Robert Englund) outside the filming, and confront the actor Robert Englund about it. She then go to Wes Craven himself, who reveals that Freddy is real, and only she can stop him. There is a interesting theory that comes to front with this. It's probably not Wes Craven's intent, but an audience's interpretation is authorial fallacy to see that there might have been a connection to this movie with that of the 3rd movie Dream Warriors. Heather's character Nancy Thompson's dies in the World of the first three films/four films. Her funeral/gravestone proves this (the gravestone was shown in A Nightmare on Elm Street 4: The Dream Master). The character Kristen from Dream Warrior, somehow, created a new world/new reality and placed Nancy's soul into this world in the end of the film like it stated. It's a dream world, yet Nancy's soul can live a full beautiful life in this beautiful dream world. Nancy's physically dead, yet not spiritually dead. I would think that once she ages and dies in this dream world then she would have truly died. Overall, Nancy has been placed in a matrix type reality so, to her, everyone in this reality is real/important to her. Freddy though, once all event's take place in the "real world" (the world of dream warriors), realizes that Nancy is in this dream world/alternate reality and therefore tries to kill Nancy since he wants to finish her off once and for all. It must take a lot for him to enter this dream world though since earthquakes are occurring constantly. Since Wes Craven wrote 1, 3, and this one... could it be Nancy living as Heather. It's a headache, but it's worth checking out or is the previous films fake and this movie real. Is Heather insane or is Freddy really coming out of the film to kill the actress that kill him in the movie? The movie goes with the realish look to it. Surprising the earthquake footage in the film is real. It was taken from the 1994 Northridge earthquake that happen during filming. The movie seem fresh, and the way in which Freddy talked, walked, and looked really brought a much needed shot of freshness to the character that had seriously been lacking. Freddy has a deeper voice. To correspond with this, the make-up and outfit of the character was different, with one of the most prominent differences being that he now wears a long, black trench coat. In addition, the signature glove was redesigned for a more organic look, with the fingers resembling bones and having muscle textures in between. It really adds to his darker vibe. The problem with the movie was that Freddy was way too soft. He looked better than ever and he was darker than ever, but all he did to the kid and his mom was chase them around, wrestle them, and scare them. Also Freddie's screen time is almost non existent, he rarely in the film, but when he is, he's scary! Heather Langenkamp takes most of the movie time, sadly not great in leading the film anywhere, as she unable to act her way through wet tissue. Even with fails, Wes Craven's New Nightmare was probably created solely for the purpose of Wes wanting to erase 2, 4, 5, and 6, and I believe even 3 because he said in the special documentary for the box set that he essentially believes that only the first film and A New Nightmare are cannon. Essentially Wes Craven threw a bratty fit over the fact there were so many sequels and wanted to basically bury the series with A New Nightmare. The meta-fictional methodology of 'New Nightmare' really gave a unique and terrifying storyline and, in my opinion, one of the best films of the franchise. So while the theory is still interesting and I can see how it would work, I think it takes away from how good 'New Nightmare' is. I'd rather watch this one than a complete hideous garbage 2010 one with Haley is, God I dislike that version.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Christina Aguilera once spoke for him.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RickHarvey
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Freddy is back... well, he's not actually back. Instead, an heinous and satanic Freddy takes over our screens as a his existence forges into reality while his films continue to dwindle in the publics conscious.(With the majority of the films being awful, i can't say that's a bad thing.) I really liked New nightmare: Original, showcasing the same mixture of intelligence with the first NMOES and most importantly, great acting. I was sceptical at first when knowing that a child actor stars - with them mostly being obnoxious and unwittingly annoying in majority of films - but thankfully the character of Dylan paid off. The thought of Freddy becoming closer to reality when the longer he's forgotten is fantastic. With the actors playing themselves, you follow the hysteria that follows Heather while he struggles to cope with a stalker. Freddy's appearance: Long, drab trench coat and feroda hat, is spot on. Despite a change in Freddy, it seems he can't resist on pulling out a one-liner from under his sleeves. Made his enigmatic aura suffer a little. Overall, I'm glad Craven decided to make another NMOES - even if it was just for the money. You sense his input being commanded with every shot. The final act gave lovers of the original NMOES an flash back on their initial experience with Freddy. With both script and camera, Craven didn't do much wrong.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Immensely enjoyable and entertaining
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    GL84
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After a series of nightmares and her son's strange behavior, an actress becomes convinced a famous serial killer from her movie history has come into the real world and targeting her and her family, forcing her to stop him using the tricks from the movies. This here turned out to be a decent if slightly flawed entry. Among the many things that work here is the fact that, by tying into the film series as a whole separate entity away from the reality presented here, it manages to be a lot smarter than it usually would be for this type of film, and that's something to commend by having the actors playing themselves instead of the film roles. That makes the typically-clich&eacute;d is-it-all-a-dream-or-not set-up far more effective than it has any right to be, given even more credence with Freddy's return to being scary again. Dropping any semblance of wise-cracks, puns and lame jokes, reduced screen time and really only appearing to do damage make him a credible, scary force again, and that helps this out tremendously. With some great action in here, a lot of great special effects and a fantastic finale, this has a lot going for it but there's still a few problems here, mainly in the film's continued usage of the annoying child who does nothing but scream and does nothing to the film overall. The low kill count means there's little variety to be found as well, but overall this isn't all too bad. Rated R: Violence, Language, and children in jeopardy
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Worst nightmare come true!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    amethystwings32
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    These movies , are horrific and terrifying to the very core! They are awful , Freddy Krueger made Jason and Mike Myers look like dark angels! He can definitely give someone nightmares, he is grotesque. What he did to his victims , would make any squeamish person want to vomit! That is why I will never get this obsession , anyone who likes these are seriously disturbed! I would hardly call these good, blood and gore doesn't make a movie good! Being terrified to the very core, with it's graphic nightmarish scenes. To the point you want to scream, walk out. Cover your face the whole time , faint or hurl. That is all of the signs that a movie is not worth watching!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Great Nightmare Sequel!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gwnightscream
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Robert Englund, Heather Langenkamp, John Saxon, Wes Craven and Miko Hughes star in Wes Craven's 1994 horror sequel. Freddy Krueger stalks the cast & crew of the original "Nightmare on Elm Street" during it's 10th anniversary. This film takes place in Los Angeles and focuses on Heather (Langenkamp) and her young son, Dylan (Hughes). Robert, John & Wes also play themselves and after mysterious earthquakes occur, Heather notices Dylan is acting strange and learns he's having nightmares abut Freddy Krueger. She gets him cared for at a hospital and decides to talk to Wes. He tells her that Freddy is an ancient evil essence from the films that wants to come into reality and convinces her that the only way to stop him is to make another film where she must play Nancy one last time. I like Freddy's new look and J. Peter Robinson's score is great. Wes re-invented the series with this by making Freddy scary again and bringing back the original stars. I recommend this great nightmare sequel.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It takes a master to re-birth a tired franchise
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert W. (Robert_duder@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    None of the Nightmare On Elm Street sequels were straight-up 'bad' per se. But the series has definitely hit an all time lull with Freddy's Dead. Could anyone breath new life into it? Probably not, other than the creator and horror master himself. Wes Craven comes up with one of the coolest, most unique ideas in a horror franchise. He breaks down the fourth wall and lets Freddy Kreuger into the real real world and brings back some of the iconic original characters. Heather Langenkamp returns as herself who is contemplating returning the Nightmare series as Nancy. Its great to have her back and she brings a certain memorable class to the film. The very talented youngster Miko Hughes (he was stunning in Mercury Rising) plays Heather's young son Dylan. He does a great job! John Saxon also returns playing himself this time around and its good to see him back as he does a great job too. Even Wes Craven plays double duty as himself and it was really cool to have him on the cast. David Newsom is decent as Langenkamp's husband although his role is quite small they have good chemistry. Robert Englund is the star of this movie. That might seem like an obvious statement but he is absolutely phenomenal in New Nightmare playing himself but also the return to the dark twisted killer that is Freddy Kreuger. Englund is a talented actor who has been type casted into horror flicks but this proved he can be versatile and really work with a great script. Its also proof that it was the lack of really depthy scripts that changed Kreuger into a comedic character because he slips back into the dark version of Kreuger flawlessly. It was so much fun to see Englund and Langenkamp together out of character and playing themselves. Ultimately you could watch the first Nightmare On Elm Street movie and then watch this one and not miss anything. This is a direct follow up to Wes Craven's original film and it is a brilliant addition to the series and the perfect way to usher in the tenth anniversary at the time. Generally this is considered by fans to be a great re-birth in the series and rightfully so. This one proves why horror fans like me keep coming back for more because sometimes even upper instalments can surprise you!! 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Again Freddie Krueger with his hideously scarred face and knives terrorizing Heather and family
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ma-cortes
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Modern rendition about the myth Freddy dealing with young people discover they're having the same terrible nightmares . New version about Freddy Krueger killing people in macabre style and boasts some startling , gruesome special effects . A re-imagining of the classic Freddy Krueger, a serial-killer who wields a glove with four blades embedded in the fingers and murders people in their dreams , resulting in their real death in reality . Nowadays, it's nearing the 10th Anniversary of the picture 'A Nightmare on Elm Street' and one of the protagonists , (Heather Langenkamp) starts to be haunted in their nightmares by scar-faced and dream-hunting Freddy Krueger (Robert Englund now fits likes a glove) , a kind of spectre with awful burns , in stripy jumper and large knives. He enters their dreams at will and again kill them. Heather Langenkamp is being scared by a voice on a telephone , sounding very similar to the movie's nasty, Freddy Krueger . When Heather's husband (David Newsom) is killed in a car crash and is discovered with slash marks on him, Heather starts to wonder somethings . Heathe learns that Freddy has now entered the real world . The unsettling Heather plagued by astonishing dreams helps her son (Miko Hughes) to attempt to stop the nasty and demonic Freddy who kill people in macabre ways . Mother and son are having the same bad dream in which a malicious bogeyman is frightening them with knives attached to his fingers and the dream becomes reality . Heather sets out to discover the truth by attempting to draw the bogeyman out of the dream . This is a diverting reworking upon first film's plot by screenwriter Wes Craven based on his characters and dealing with the imaginative premise about a kind of ghost who can enter their dreams at will and intents on taking over both his body and mind . The twisted script dishes up the requisite helping of one-liners and throwaway black humor . This eerie film packs thrills , chills , creepy events and lots of blood and gore . It's a flimsily plotted but visually enjoyable addition to the Krueger endless saga . There are a few genuinely inspired events , notably Freddy's appearances and the extraordinary body-ripping spotlights in the Hospital room . Although it results to be a franchise that we now know was to follow , there are some originally frightening dream sequences. Special and extravagant visual effects are the climax of the movie and the startling make-up on Freddy face , but both of them don't save the story . Young casting and special appearance by John Saxon , the same Wes Craven and Robert Shaye , film's producer . Creepy and imaginatively made musical score fitting to terror movie by J. Peter Robinson . Colorful and atmospheric cinematography by Mark Irwin . The motion picture well produced by the great producer Robert Shaye from New Line Cinema and is professionally directed by Wes Craven , though with no originality and nothing new to show . Wes's sure grasp of the skewed logic of nightmares help to sustain the ambiguity between the dream and real world . Rating : 5,5 , passable sequel . It's all acceptable scary fun . The series initiates itself from original entry title &uml;A Nightmare on Elm Elm Street&uml; directed by Wes Craven with Heather Langenkamp , Johnny Depp , Amanda Wyss and John Saxon . The rest is a series of disjointed but however impressive special effects pieces . As it was followed by a handful of sequels in which horrifying special effects dominate this slasher saga , as &uml;Freddy's revenge&uml; 1985 by Jack Sholder with Kim Myers , Clu Gulager and Hope Lange ; &uml;Dream warrior&uml; 1987 by Chuck Russell with Patricia Arquette , Larry Fishburne and Craig Wasson , it's one of the best sequels from successful original film by Craven , as &uml;Dream master&uml; (1988) by Renny Harlin with Lisa Wilcox , Tuesday Knight and &uml;The dream child&uml; (1989) by Stephen Hopkins with Lisa Wilcox , Erika Anderson . Besides a Television series &uml;The Freddy's nightmares&uml; and this last one &uml; A nightmare on Elm Street&uml;(2010) with Jackie Haley that is a simple copy with little imagination , too many flaws and giving routine treatment .
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Why does this have such a high rating???
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    votesmall
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Okay, first of all, let me say that I am not one of those people who doesn't "get" movies if they aren't "edge of your seat". For example, 2001: A Space Odyssey could have been good, but it just was too boring and had no explanation for the monolith and not enough focus on HAL 9000, the freaky antagonist supercomputer. Basically, most of the movie was shots of space with classical music. And everyone tells me that I didn't "get" it. No, I can't get it because there is no explanation, and it's too boring! BUT, I did love Hellraiser: Inferno, and In the Mouth of Madness. So, what's the problem with New Nightmare??? Okay, first of all is the fact of Freddy. I actually love his new look, the jacket and hand, although the sweater and hat looked kind of funny and I didn't understand why they put the greenish-red rings around his eyes. They went to so much work designing this new, evil looking Freddy and he can't have more than 20 minutes of screen time. Yep, just a little bit more than Freddy's Revenge. And yes, I know that Pinhead had just about as much screen time in Hellraiser: Inferno, but they didn't redesign Pinhead in that one. Okay, I do love psychological thrillers, but this was just BORING! It starts off with an all metal, robotic glove coming to life on the film set of a new Nightmare on Elm Street movie. The glove kills several special effects crew members and is about to kill Heather Langenkamp (Nancy)'s husband. And then she wakes up. Okay, that was awesome! Good, frightening, and all a dream. And the next forty five minutes or so have NOTHING going on for the movie! I will admit, the interview scene and the limousine scene were somewhat interesting, but the rest of it was just boring fluff. And also, we get a few decent shots of Robert Englund in this movie, but we don't see near enough! The entire movie revolves around two characters, that just can't carry the film. The kid is just annoying. He isn't creepy, he's just annoying. Some of the dream sequences are pretty freaky, but other than that, he's just a normal kid talking in a stupid voice. Also, the vomit scene was pretty much stolen from The Exorcist. So, by the end of the movie, all of the characters are referring to Heather as Nancy, but this is never explained. And then there is a showdown at the "boiler room", which looks more like an ancient Greek temple than a power plant mechanical room. Okay, this scene was too tacky. And Freddy actually extends his arm to get the kid, tries to "eat him", and wraps his tongue around Heather before burning to death and turning into, get this, the devil.??? I will admit that I liked how it came to the real world, and we do get some pretty decent shots of Wes Craven and Robert Englund, and even a few other stars, but, like Freddy, they just don't have enough screen time. And some of the dream sequences are pretty creepy. But, I have two HUGE problems with this movie. First off, the fact that Heather has to wait until, like an hour and a half (around three days in the movie) after her kid tries to commit suicide, has seizures, nightmares, and tries to kill her before taking him to the hospital. Also, her kid is terrified of nightmares and she shuts the door so he is in the dark! ??? Worst mother ever! And it also isn't about Freddy on a film set, it's about him stalking Heather and her kid for two hours. This movie was so slow paced that it seemed like Titanic. Not to mention a hilariously low body count, with Freddy having a brand new glove, but breaking someone's neck! ??? Judge for yourself, but I thought it was boring. The kid was annoying, there wasn't enough Freddy, and Heather Langenkamp is just not an interesting character, unlike Nancy Thompson. Overall, this film is just TOO slow. I mean, Wes Craven had a really good idea here. Very original, just like the first Nightmare movie. But he didn't execute it very well. The kid was annoying, Heather Langenkamp looks bored and "worried" throughout the movie. And some of the dialogue is just ridiculous. Like how Wes all of a sudden knows what the new Freddy is is kind of ridiculous, because he couldn't possibly know that. Not to mention that in Never Sleep Again, he showed drawings for a "Freddy mobile" that he was going to put in the movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wes Craven's New Nightmare
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It looked like for some time Freddy's Dead: The Final Nightmare was the final time scary movie fans would see the iconic razor handed "Son of 100 Maniacs", but then original film writer and director Wes Craven (The Hills Have Eyes, Scream) came up with this clever comeback. Basically the tenth anniversary of the movie A Nightmare on Elm Street is coming up, and original star Heather Langenkamp is part of the special events celebrating, along with its director Wes Craven, and of course the man behind killer Freddy Krueger, actor Robert Englund. She has a happy life with husband Chase Porter (David Newsom) and son Dylan (Miko Hughes), but she is being stalked by a nasty voice on the phone, and creepy goings on in her house, and things get worse when her husband is killed in a car crash, and his body has slash marks on it. Dylan is refusing to sleep anymore, because he is scared, like the movie, that Freddy will come in his dream and try to kill him, and dealing with this Heather is also being offered a part in the next Nightmare film Wes is working on, but the script needs work. Heather is finding the behaviour of her son uncontrollable, and she does believe Freddy is haunting her, Wes comes up with the theory that now the Elm Street films are over an ancient spirit must have helped him come out of the fictional world to enter dreams in real life, and his script may be part of this way out. It comes to the point when Dylan may be taken away from Heather due to his psychologically disturbed behaviour, but she is also incarcerated by doctors who believe she is going mad, of course Freddy continues his kills while this is going on. Eventually Heather, like her character, enters a dream to confront Freddy and stop the terror, and she manages to lock him in a furnace to burn to death, and returning to the real world she and her son read the new finished sample script sent by Wes. I like films where actors play a version of themselves, you could see this as semi-documentary considering the concept of how to bring back a character supposedly dead for good, the story has its moments of irritation, especially with the doctors breaking up the mother and son, but the script has clever references and ideas, and there is just enough Freddy and gore for the fans, a not bad horror film. Worth watching!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Langenkamp and Englund go uber real.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    amesmonde
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The lead actors of the original Nightmare on Elm Street, on it's 10th Anniversary, are terrorized by a Freddy Kruger like entity that wants Heather Langenkamp and her son dead. The seemingly outrageous bloody opening is quickly defused as a fitting dream sequence and new ground is broken as we discover the actors are playing themselves. It appears to break the fourth wall with Wes Craven, John Saxon and Robert Englund to name a few playing themselves. Of course this allows Langenkamp to return as herself after her Nancy character's death in the third. This non-conventional approach with a number of uneasy phone calls would become the precursor film within a film which appears in Craven's own Scream series. While you'd expect most of the actors to be able to play themselves they do at times come across as awkward and uncomfortable. Thankfully the leads pull it off with ease - namely Englund and Langenkamp. Faces from the original also cameo as themselves and a photo of Johnny Depp shows up in the background. Some scenes are a blast for fans with Englund playing himself as Freddy on a talk show. Of course Englund also plays Freddy the embodiment of an evil spirit with an expert indifference. This darker, scarier Freddy is probably what fans of the original wanted to see in the handful of sequels. There's irony on irony with producer Rob Shay inviting Langenkamp to come back and play Nancy one last time in a definitive nightmare. Writer/Director Craven delivers another novel idea with a tantalizing hook. There's a nice touch where reality merges with dreams and John Sax returns as his character Lt. Donald Thompson with Langenkamp calling him John and him unawares in turn calling her Nancy. The kill scenes pay homage to the original and even some of the sequels notably the Chase Porter car crash. With a strong supporting cast (mainly those ones who don't play themselves) including Miko Hughes as Dylan Porter Heather's on screen son gives a solid mixture of Poltergeist/Exorcist-like performance. It may have benefited from a more natural looking production, less film- like to emphasis the realness in contrast to the movie world and Nightmare sequences. It's own high production values and Mark Irwin's great cinematography dilute the edginess. Craven's screenplay also injects a part actress character study there is an interesting subtext about fame and it trappings. A New Nightmare has all the kills one would expect with excellent make up and visual effect on display with Craven trying to out do himself with the accompanying music by J. Peter Robinson. The idea of uber Freddy character harassing the real life cast and crew doesn't tire with the entertaining and fitting premise. It's only a movie...or is it?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wes Craven's dream of rebooting Freddy becomes a New Nightmare
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ironhorse_iv
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's hardly a perfect film for Wes Craven, but it's eerie and thought-provoking, something that been lacking in the previous movies that made Freddy Kruger into a goofy wise cracker and cheesy death scenes. It is also the last the last time that Freddy showed any real menace. Wes Craven made this to take back control of his creation and it works as a criticism of what the franchise became with Freddy as a comedian, not to mention a rebuff to the tired argument about violence in films always causing it in the real world. Freddy was far more straightforward with his kills and didn't manifest elaborate scenarios for each death. Pure intimidation. That's what Wes was trying to bring back. New Nightmare is almost in it's own league. New Nightmare had a great story and very original, creative ideas in it but it was still a bit confusing with the plot of the movie! It's the movie without a movie. He would work this angle again, in the 'Scream' series with the "Stab" movies in Scream are movies within a movie! It's work here, it doesn't work there. 'A Nightmare on Elm Street 7: The Ascension' is being film, and Heather Langenkamp playing herself, the actress that play the original heroic star of the original movie is being ask to reprise her role as Nancy Thompson. She notice that her husband Chase, and son Dylan is also being haunted by Freddy Krueger (Robert Englund) outside the filming, and confront the actor Robert Englund about it. She then go to Wes Craven himself, who reveals that Freddy is real, and only she can stop him. There is a interesting theory that comes to front with this. It's probably not Wes Craven's intent, but an audience's interpretation is authorial fallacy to see that there might have been a connection to this movie with that of the 3rd movie Dream Warriors. Heather's character Nancy Thompson's dies in the World of the first three films/four films. Her funeral/gravestone proves this (the gravestone was shown in A Nightmare on Elm Street 4: The Dream Master). The character Kristen from Dream Warrior, somehow, created a new world/new reality and placed Nancy's soul into this world in the end of the film like it stated. It's a dream world, yet Nancy's soul can live a full beautiful life in this beautiful dream world. Nancy's physically dead, yet not spiritually dead. I would think that once she ages and dies in this dream world then she would have truly died. Overall, Nancy has been placed in a matrix type reality so, to her, everyone in this reality is real/important to her. Freddy though, once all event's take place in the "real world" (the world of dream warriors), realizes that Nancy is in this dream world/alternate reality and therefore tries to kill Nancy since he wants to finish her off once and for all. It must take a lot for him to enter this dream world though since earthquakes are occurring constantly. Since Wes Craven wrote 1, 3, and this one... could it be Nancy living as Heather. It's a headache, but it's worth checking out or is the previous films fake and this movie real. Is Heather insane or is Freddy really coming out of the film to kill the actress that kill him in the movie? The movie goes with the realish look to it. Surprising the earthquake footage in the film is real. It was taken from the 1994 Northridge earthquake that happen during filming. The movie seem fresh, and the way in which Freddy talked, walked, and looked really brought a much needed shot of freshness to the character that had seriously been lacking. Freddy has a deeper voice. To correspond with this, the make-up and outfit of the character was different, with one of the most prominent differences being that he now wears a long, black trench coat. In addition, the signature glove was redesigned for a more organic look, with the fingers resembling bones and having muscle textures in between. It really adds to his darker vibe. The problem with the movie was that Freddy was way too soft. He looked better than ever and he was darker than ever, but all he did to the kid and his mom was chase them around, wrestle them, and scare them. Also Freddie's screen time is almost non existent, he rarely in the film, but when he is, he's scary! Heather Langenkamp takes most of the movie time, sadly not great in leading the film anywhere, as she unable to act her way through wet tissue. Even with fails, Wes Craven's New Nightmare was probably created solely for the purpose of Wes wanting to erase 2, 4, 5, and 6, and I believe even 3 because he said in the special documentary for the box set that he essentially believes that only the first film and A New Nightmare are cannon. Essentially Wes Craven threw a bratty fit over the fact there were so many sequels and wanted to basically bury the series with A New Nightmare. The meta-fictional methodology of 'New Nightmare' really gave a unique and terrifying storyline and, in my opinion, one of the best films of the franchise. So while the theory is still interesting and I can see how it would work, I think it takes away from how good 'New Nightmare' is. I'd rather watch this one than a complete hideous garbage 2010 one with Haley is, God I dislike that version.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Christina Aguilera once spoke for him.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RickHarvey
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Freddy is back... well, he's not actually back. Instead, an heinous and satanic Freddy takes over our screens as a his existence forges into reality while his films continue to dwindle in the publics conscious.(With the majority of the films being awful, i can't say that's a bad thing.) I really liked New nightmare: Original, showcasing the same mixture of intelligence with the first NMOES and most importantly, great acting. I was sceptical at first when knowing that a child actor stars - with them mostly being obnoxious and unwittingly annoying in majority of films - but thankfully the character of Dylan paid off. The thought of Freddy becoming closer to reality when the longer he's forgotten is fantastic. With the actors playing themselves, you follow the hysteria that follows Heather while he struggles to cope with a stalker. Freddy's appearance: Long, drab trench coat and feroda hat, is spot on. Despite a change in Freddy, it seems he can't resist on pulling out a one-liner from under his sleeves. Made his enigmatic aura suffer a little. Overall, I'm glad Craven decided to make another NMOES - even if it was just for the money. You sense his input being commanded with every shot. The final act gave lovers of the original NMOES an flash back on their initial experience with Freddy. With both script and camera, Craven didn't do much wrong.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Immensely enjoyable and entertaining
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    GL84
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After a series of nightmares and her son's strange behavior, an actress becomes convinced a famous serial killer from her movie history has come into the real world and targeting her and her family, forcing her to stop him using the tricks from the movies. This here turned out to be a decent if slightly flawed entry. Among the many things that work here is the fact that, by tying into the film series as a whole separate entity away from the reality presented here, it manages to be a lot smarter than it usually would be for this type of film, and that's something to commend by having the actors playing themselves instead of the film roles. That makes the typically-clich&eacute;d is-it-all-a-dream-or-not set-up far more effective than it has any right to be, given even more credence with Freddy's return to being scary again. Dropping any semblance of wise-cracks, puns and lame jokes, reduced screen time and really only appearing to do damage make him a credible, scary force again, and that helps this out tremendously. With some great action in here, a lot of great special effects and a fantastic finale, this has a lot going for it but there's still a few problems here, mainly in the film's continued usage of the annoying child who does nothing but scream and does nothing to the film overall. The low kill count means there's little variety to be found as well, but overall this isn't all too bad. Rated R: Violence, Language, and children in jeopardy
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Worst nightmare come true!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    amethystwings32
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    These movies , are horrific and terrifying to the very core! They are awful , Freddy Krueger made Jason and Mike Myers look like dark angels! He can definitely give someone nightmares, he is grotesque. What he did to his victims , would make any squeamish person want to vomit! That is why I will never get this obsession , anyone who likes these are seriously disturbed! I would hardly call these good, blood and gore doesn't make a movie good! Being terrified to the very core, with it's graphic nightmarish scenes. To the point you want to scream, walk out. Cover your face the whole time , faint or hurl. That is all of the signs that a movie is not worth watching!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Great Nightmare Sequel!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gwnightscream
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Robert Englund, Heather Langenkamp, John Saxon, Wes Craven and Miko Hughes star in Wes Craven's 1994 horror sequel. Freddy Krueger stalks the cast & crew of the original "Nightmare on Elm Street" during it's 10th anniversary. This film takes place in Los Angeles and focuses on Heather (Langenkamp) and her young son, Dylan (Hughes). Robert, John & Wes also play themselves and after mysterious earthquakes occur, Heather notices Dylan is acting strange and learns he's having nightmares abut Freddy Krueger. She gets him cared for at a hospital and decides to talk to Wes. He tells her that Freddy is an ancient evil essence from the films that wants to come into reality and convinces her that the only way to stop him is to make another film where she must play Nancy one last time. I like Freddy's new look and J. Peter Robinson's score is great. Wes re-invented the series with this by making Freddy scary again and bringing back the original stars. I recommend this great nightmare sequel.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It takes a master to re-birth a tired franchise
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert W. (Robert_duder@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    None of the Nightmare On Elm Street sequels were straight-up 'bad' per se. But the series has definitely hit an all time lull with Freddy's Dead. Could anyone breath new life into it? Probably not, other than the creator and horror master himself. Wes Craven comes up with one of the coolest, most unique ideas in a horror franchise. He breaks down the fourth wall and lets Freddy Kreuger into the real real world and brings back some of the iconic original characters. Heather Langenkamp returns as herself who is contemplating returning the Nightmare series as Nancy. Its great to have her back and she brings a certain memorable class to the film. The very talented youngster Miko Hughes (he was stunning in Mercury Rising) plays Heather's young son Dylan. He does a great job! John Saxon also returns playing himself this time around and its good to see him back as he does a great job too. Even Wes Craven plays double duty as himself and it was really cool to have him on the cast. David Newsom is decent as Langenkamp's husband although his role is quite small they have good chemistry. Robert Englund is the star of this movie. That might seem like an obvious statement but he is absolutely phenomenal in New Nightmare playing himself but also the return to the dark twisted killer that is Freddy Kreuger. Englund is a talented actor who has been type casted into horror flicks but this proved he can be versatile and really work with a great script. Its also proof that it was the lack of really depthy scripts that changed Kreuger into a comedic character because he slips back into the dark version of Kreuger flawlessly. It was so much fun to see Englund and Langenkamp together out of character and playing themselves. Ultimately you could watch the first Nightmare On Elm Street movie and then watch this one and not miss anything. This is a direct follow up to Wes Craven's original film and it is a brilliant addition to the series and the perfect way to usher in the tenth anniversary at the time. Generally this is considered by fans to be a great re-birth in the series and rightfully so. This one proves why horror fans like me keep coming back for more because sometimes even upper instalments can surprise you!! 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Again Freddie Krueger with his hideously scarred face and knives terrorizing Heather and family
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ma-cortes
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Modern rendition about the myth Freddy dealing with young people discover they're having the same terrible nightmares . New version about Freddy Krueger killing people in macabre style and boasts some startling , gruesome special effects . A re-imagining of the classic Freddy Krueger, a serial-killer who wields a glove with four blades embedded in the fingers and murders people in their dreams , resulting in their real death in reality . Nowadays, it's nearing the 10th Anniversary of the picture 'A Nightmare on Elm Street' and one of the protagonists , (Heather Langenkamp) starts to be haunted in their nightmares by scar-faced and dream-hunting Freddy Krueger (Robert Englund now fits likes a glove) , a kind of spectre with awful burns , in stripy jumper and large knives. He enters their dreams at will and again kill them. Heather Langenkamp is being scared by a voice on a telephone , sounding very similar to the movie's nasty, Freddy Krueger . When Heather's husband (David Newsom) is killed in a car crash and is discovered with slash marks on him, Heather starts to wonder somethings . Heathe learns that Freddy has now entered the real world . The unsettling Heather plagued by astonishing dreams helps her son (Miko Hughes) to attempt to stop the nasty and demonic Freddy who kill people in macabre ways . Mother and son are having the same bad dream in which a malicious bogeyman is frightening them with knives attached to his fingers and the dream becomes reality . Heather sets out to discover the truth by attempting to draw the bogeyman out of the dream . This is a diverting reworking upon first film's plot by screenwriter Wes Craven based on his characters and dealing with the imaginative premise about a kind of ghost who can enter their dreams at will and intents on taking over both his body and mind . The twisted script dishes up the requisite helping of one-liners and throwaway black humor . This eerie film packs thrills , chills , creepy events and lots of blood and gore . It's a flimsily plotted but visually enjoyable addition to the Krueger endless saga . There are a few genuinely inspired events , notably Freddy's appearances and the extraordinary body-ripping spotlights in the Hospital room . Although it results to be a franchise that we now know was to follow , there are some originally frightening dream sequences. Special and extravagant visual effects are the climax of the movie and the startling make-up on Freddy face , but both of them don't save the story . Young casting and special appearance by John Saxon , the same Wes Craven and Robert Shaye , film's producer . Creepy and imaginatively made musical score fitting to terror movie by J. Peter Robinson . Colorful and atmospheric cinematography by Mark Irwin . The motion picture well produced by the great producer Robert Shaye from New Line Cinema and is professionally directed by Wes Craven , though with no originality and nothing new to show . Wes's sure grasp of the skewed logic of nightmares help to sustain the ambiguity between the dream and real world . Rating : 5,5 , passable sequel . It's all acceptable scary fun . The series initiates itself from original entry title &uml;A Nightmare on Elm Elm Street&uml; directed by Wes Craven with Heather Langenkamp , Johnny Depp , Amanda Wyss and John Saxon . The rest is a series of disjointed but however impressive special effects pieces . As it was followed by a handful of sequels in which horrifying special effects dominate this slasher saga , as &uml;Freddy's revenge&uml; 1985 by Jack Sholder with Kim Myers , Clu Gulager and Hope Lange ; &uml;Dream warrior&uml; 1987 by Chuck Russell with Patricia Arquette , Larry Fishburne and Craig Wasson , it's one of the best sequels from successful original film by Craven , as &uml;Dream master&uml; (1988) by Renny Harlin with Lisa Wilcox , Tuesday Knight and &uml;The dream child&uml; (1989) by Stephen Hopkins with Lisa Wilcox , Erika Anderson . Besides a Television series &uml;The Freddy's nightmares&uml; and this last one &uml; A nightmare on Elm Street&uml;(2010) with Jackie Haley that is a simple copy with little imagination , too many flaws and giving routine treatment .
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Why does this have such a high rating???
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    votesmall
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Okay, first of all, let me say that I am not one of those people who doesn't "get" movies if they aren't "edge of your seat". For example, 2001: A Space Odyssey could have been good, but it just was too boring and had no explanation for the monolith and not enough focus on HAL 9000, the freaky antagonist supercomputer. Basically, most of the movie was shots of space with classical music. And everyone tells me that I didn't "get" it. No, I can't get it because there is no explanation, and it's too boring! BUT, I did love Hellraiser: Inferno, and In the Mouth of Madness. So, what's the problem with New Nightmare??? Okay, first of all is the fact of Freddy. I actually love his new look, the jacket and hand, although the sweater and hat looked kind of funny and I didn't understand why they put the greenish-red rings around his eyes. They went to so much work designing this new, evil looking Freddy and he can't have more than 20 minutes of screen time. Yep, just a little bit more than Freddy's Revenge. And yes, I know that Pinhead had just about as much screen time in Hellraiser: Inferno, but they didn't redesign Pinhead in that one. Okay, I do love psychological thrillers, but this was just BORING! It starts off with an all metal, robotic glove coming to life on the film set of a new Nightmare on Elm Street movie. The glove kills several special effects crew members and is about to kill Heather Langenkamp (Nancy)'s husband. And then she wakes up. Okay, that was awesome! Good, frightening, and all a dream. And the next forty five minutes or so have NOTHING going on for the movie! I will admit, the interview scene and the limousine scene were somewhat interesting, but the rest of it was just boring fluff. And also, we get a few decent shots of Robert Englund in this movie, but we don't see near enough! The entire movie revolves around two characters, that just can't carry the film. The kid is just annoying. He isn't creepy, he's just annoying. Some of the dream sequences are pretty freaky, but other than that, he's just a normal kid talking in a stupid voice. Also, the vomit scene was pretty much stolen from The Exorcist. So, by the end of the movie, all of the characters are referring to Heather as Nancy, but this is never explained. And then there is a showdown at the "boiler room", which looks more like an ancient Greek temple than a power plant mechanical room. Okay, this scene was too tacky. And Freddy actually extends his arm to get the kid, tries to "eat him", and wraps his tongue around Heather before burning to death and turning into, get this, the devil.??? I will admit that I liked how it came to the real world, and we do get some pretty decent shots of Wes Craven and Robert Englund, and even a few other stars, but, like Freddy, they just don't have enough screen time. And some of the dream sequences are pretty creepy. But, I have two HUGE problems with this movie. First off, the fact that Heather has to wait until, like an hour and a half (around three days in the movie) after her kid tries to commit suicide, has seizures, nightmares, and tries to kill her before taking him to the hospital. Also, her kid is terrified of nightmares and she shuts the door so he is in the dark! ??? Worst mother ever! And it also isn't about Freddy on a film set, it's about him stalking Heather and her kid for two hours. This movie was so slow paced that it seemed like Titanic. Not to mention a hilariously low body count, with Freddy having a brand new glove, but breaking someone's neck! ??? Judge for yourself, but I thought it was boring. The kid was annoying, there wasn't enough Freddy, and Heather Langenkamp is just not an interesting character, unlike Nancy Thompson. Overall, this film is just TOO slow. I mean, Wes Craven had a really good idea here. Very original, just like the first Nightmare movie. But he didn't execute it very well. The kid was annoying, Heather Langenkamp looks bored and "worried" throughout the movie. And some of the dialogue is just ridiculous. Like how Wes all of a sudden knows what the new Freddy is is kind of ridiculous, because he couldn't possibly know that. Not to mention that in Never Sleep Again, he showed drawings for a "Freddy mobile" that he was going to put in the movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wes Craven's New Nightmare
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It looked like for some time Freddy's Dead: The Final Nightmare was the final time scary movie fans would see the iconic razor handed "Son of 100 Maniacs", but then original film writer and director Wes Craven (The Hills Have Eyes, Scream) came up with this clever comeback. Basically the tenth anniversary of the movie A Nightmare on Elm Street is coming up, and original star Heather Langenkamp is part of the special events celebrating, along with its director Wes Craven, and of course the man behind killer Freddy Krueger, actor Robert Englund. She has a happy life with husband Chase Porter (David Newsom) and son Dylan (Miko Hughes), but she is being stalked by a nasty voice on the phone, and creepy goings on in her house, and things get worse when her husband is killed in a car crash, and his body has slash marks on it. Dylan is refusing to sleep anymore, because he is scared, like the movie, that Freddy will come in his dream and try to kill him, and dealing with this Heather is also being offered a part in the next Nightmare film Wes is working on, but the script needs work. Heather is finding the behaviour of her son uncontrollable, and she does believe Freddy is haunting her, Wes comes up with the theory that now the Elm Street films are over an ancient spirit must have helped him come out of the fictional world to enter dreams in real life, and his script may be part of this way out. It comes to the point when Dylan may be taken away from Heather due to his psychologically disturbed behaviour, but she is also incarcerated by doctors who believe she is going mad, of course Freddy continues his kills while this is going on. Eventually Heather, like her character, enters a dream to confront Freddy and stop the terror, and she manages to lock him in a furnace to burn to death, and returning to the real world she and her son read the new finished sample script sent by Wes. I like films where actors play a version of themselves, you could see this as semi-documentary considering the concept of how to bring back a character supposedly dead for good, the story has its moments of irritation, especially with the doctors breaking up the mother and son, but the script has clever references and ideas, and there is just enough Freddy and gore for the fans, a not bad horror film. Worth watching!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Langenkamp and Englund go uber real.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    amesmonde
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The lead actors of the original Nightmare on Elm Street, on it's 10th Anniversary, are terrorized by a Freddy Kruger like entity that wants Heather Langenkamp and her son dead. The seemingly outrageous bloody opening is quickly defused as a fitting dream sequence and new ground is broken as we discover the actors are playing themselves. It appears to break the fourth wall with Wes Craven, John Saxon and Robert Englund to name a few playing themselves. Of course this allows Langenkamp to return as herself after her Nancy character's death in the third. This non-conventional approach with a number of uneasy phone calls would become the precursor film within a film which appears in Craven's own Scream series. While you'd expect most of the actors to be able to play themselves they do at times come across as awkward and uncomfortable. Thankfully the leads pull it off with ease - namely Englund and Langenkamp. Faces from the original also cameo as themselves and a photo of Johnny Depp shows up in the background. Some scenes are a blast for fans with Englund playing himself as Freddy on a talk show. Of course Englund also plays Freddy the embodiment of an evil spirit with an expert indifference. This darker, scarier Freddy is probably what fans of the original wanted to see in the handful of sequels. There's irony on irony with producer Rob Shay inviting Langenkamp to come back and play Nancy one last time in a definitive nightmare. Writer/Director Craven delivers another novel idea with a tantalizing hook. There's a nice touch where reality merges with dreams and John Sax returns as his character Lt. Donald Thompson with Langenkamp calling him John and him unawares in turn calling her Nancy. The kill scenes pay homage to the original and even some of the sequels notably the Chase Porter car crash. With a strong supporting cast (mainly those ones who don't play themselves) including Miko Hughes as Dylan Porter Heather's on screen son gives a solid mixture of Poltergeist/Exorcist-like performance. It may have benefited from a more natural looking production, less film- like to emphasis the realness in contrast to the movie world and Nightmare sequences. It's own high production values and Mark Irwin's great cinematography dilute the edginess. Craven's screenplay also injects a part actress character study there is an interesting subtext about fame and it trappings. A New Nightmare has all the kills one would expect with excellent make up and visual effect on display with Craven trying to out do himself with the accompanying music by J. Peter Robinson. The idea of uber Freddy character harassing the real life cast and crew doesn't tire with the entertaining and fitting premise. It's only a movie...or is it?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wes Craven's dream of rebooting Freddy becomes a New Nightmare
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ironhorse_iv
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's hardly a perfect film for Wes Craven, but it's eerie and thought-provoking, something that been lacking in the previous movies that made Freddy Kruger into a goofy wise cracker and cheesy death scenes. It is also the last the last time that Freddy showed any real menace. Wes Craven made this to take back control of his creation and it works as a criticism of what the franchise became with Freddy as a comedian, not to mention a rebuff to the tired argument about violence in films always causing it in the real world. Freddy was far more straightforward with his kills and didn't manifest elaborate scenarios for each death. Pure intimidation. That's what Wes was trying to bring back. New Nightmare is almost in it's own league. New Nightmare had a great story and very original, creative ideas in it but it was still a bit confusing with the plot of the movie! It's the movie without a movie. He would work this angle again, in the 'Scream' series with the "Stab" movies in Scream are movies within a movie! It's work here, it doesn't work there. 'A Nightmare on Elm Street 7: The Ascension' is being film, and Heather Langenkamp playing herself, the actress that play the original heroic star of the original movie is being ask to reprise her role as Nancy Thompson. She notice that her husband Chase, and son Dylan is also being haunted by Freddy Krueger (Robert Englund) outside the filming, and confront the actor Robert Englund about it. She then go to Wes Craven himself, who reveals that Freddy is real, and only she can stop him. There is a interesting theory that comes to front with this. It's probably not Wes Craven's intent, but an audience's interpretation is authorial fallacy to see that there might have been a connection to this movie with that of the 3rd movie Dream Warriors. Heather's character Nancy Thompson's dies in the World of the first three films/four films. Her funeral/gravestone proves this (the gravestone was shown in A Nightmare on Elm Street 4: The Dream Master). The character Kristen from Dream Warrior, somehow, created a new world/new reality and placed Nancy's soul into this world in the end of the film like it stated. It's a dream world, yet Nancy's soul can live a full beautiful life in this beautiful dream world. Nancy's physically dead, yet not spiritually dead. I would think that once she ages and dies in this dream world then she would have truly died. Overall, Nancy has been placed in a matrix type reality so, to her, everyone in this reality is real/important to her. Freddy though, once all event's take place in the "real world" (the world of dream warriors), realizes that Nancy is in this dream world/alternate reality and therefore tries to kill Nancy since he wants to finish her off once and for all. It must take a lot for him to enter this dream world though since earthquakes are occurring constantly. Since Wes Craven wrote 1, 3, and this one... could it be Nancy living as Heather. It's a headache, but it's worth checking out or is the previous films fake and this movie real. Is Heather insane or is Freddy really coming out of the film to kill the actress that kill him in the movie? The movie goes with the realish look to it. Surprising the earthquake footage in the film is real. It was taken from the 1994 Northridge earthquake that happen during filming. The movie seem fresh, and the way in which Freddy talked, walked, and looked really brought a much needed shot of freshness to the character that had seriously been lacking. Freddy has a deeper voice. To correspond with this, the make-up and outfit of the character was different, with one of the most prominent differences being that he now wears a long, black trench coat. In addition, the signature glove was redesigned for a more organic look, with the fingers resembling bones and having muscle textures in between. It really adds to his darker vibe. The problem with the movie was that Freddy was way too soft. He looked better than ever and he was darker than ever, but all he did to the kid and his mom was chase them around, wrestle them, and scare them. Also Freddie's screen time is almost non existent, he rarely in the film, but when he is, he's scary! Heather Langenkamp takes most of the movie time, sadly not great in leading the film anywhere, as she unable to act her way through wet tissue. Even with fails, Wes Craven's New Nightmare was probably created solely for the purpose of Wes wanting to erase 2, 4, 5, and 6, and I believe even 3 because he said in the special documentary for the box set that he essentially believes that only the first film and A New Nightmare are cannon. Essentially Wes Craven threw a bratty fit over the fact there were so many sequels and wanted to basically bury the series with A New Nightmare. The meta-fictional methodology of 'New Nightmare' really gave a unique and terrifying storyline and, in my opinion, one of the best films of the franchise. So while the theory is still interesting and I can see how it would work, I think it takes away from how good 'New Nightmare' is. I'd rather watch this one than a complete hideous garbage 2010 one with Haley is, God I dislike that version.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Christina Aguilera once spoke for him.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RickHarvey
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Freddy is back... well, he's not actually back. Instead, an heinous and satanic Freddy takes over our screens as a his existence forges into reality while his films continue to dwindle in the publics conscious.(With the majority of the films being awful, i can't say that's a bad thing.) I really liked New nightmare: Original, showcasing the same mixture of intelligence with the first NMOES and most importantly, great acting. I was sceptical at first when knowing that a child actor stars - with them mostly being obnoxious and unwittingly annoying in majority of films - but thankfully the character of Dylan paid off. The thought of Freddy becoming closer to reality when the longer he's forgotten is fantastic. With the actors playing themselves, you follow the hysteria that follows Heather while he struggles to cope with a stalker. Freddy's appearance: Long, drab trench coat and feroda hat, is spot on. Despite a change in Freddy, it seems he can't resist on pulling out a one-liner from under his sleeves. Made his enigmatic aura suffer a little. Overall, I'm glad Craven decided to make another NMOES - even if it was just for the money. You sense his input being commanded with every shot. The final act gave lovers of the original NMOES an flash back on their initial experience with Freddy. With both script and camera, Craven didn't do much wrong.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Immensely enjoyable and entertaining
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    GL84
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After a series of nightmares and her son's strange behavior, an actress becomes convinced a famous serial killer from her movie history has come into the real world and targeting her and her family, forcing her to stop him using the tricks from the movies. This here turned out to be a decent if slightly flawed entry. Among the many things that work here is the fact that, by tying into the film series as a whole separate entity away from the reality presented here, it manages to be a lot smarter than it usually would be for this type of film, and that's something to commend by having the actors playing themselves instead of the film roles. That makes the typically-clich&eacute;d is-it-all-a-dream-or-not set-up far more effective than it has any right to be, given even more credence with Freddy's return to being scary again. Dropping any semblance of wise-cracks, puns and lame jokes, reduced screen time and really only appearing to do damage make him a credible, scary force again, and that helps this out tremendously. With some great action in here, a lot of great special effects and a fantastic finale, this has a lot going for it but there's still a few problems here, mainly in the film's continued usage of the annoying child who does nothing but scream and does nothing to the film overall. The low kill count means there's little variety to be found as well, but overall this isn't all too bad. Rated R: Violence, Language, and children in jeopardy
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Worst nightmare come true!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    amethystwings32
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    These movies , are horrific and terrifying to the very core! They are awful , Freddy Krueger made Jason and Mike Myers look like dark angels! He can definitely give someone nightmares, he is grotesque. What he did to his victims , would make any squeamish person want to vomit! That is why I will never get this obsession , anyone who likes these are seriously disturbed! I would hardly call these good, blood and gore doesn't make a movie good! Being terrified to the very core, with it's graphic nightmarish scenes. To the point you want to scream, walk out. Cover your face the whole time , faint or hurl. That is all of the signs that a movie is not worth watching!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Great Nightmare Sequel!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gwnightscream
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Robert Englund, Heather Langenkamp, John Saxon, Wes Craven and Miko Hughes star in Wes Craven's 1994 horror sequel. Freddy Krueger stalks the cast & crew of the original "Nightmare on Elm Street" during it's 10th anniversary. This film takes place in Los Angeles and focuses on Heather (Langenkamp) and her young son, Dylan (Hughes). Robert, John & Wes also play themselves and after mysterious earthquakes occur, Heather notices Dylan is acting strange and learns he's having nightmares abut Freddy Krueger. She gets him cared for at a hospital and decides to talk to Wes. He tells her that Freddy is an ancient evil essence from the films that wants to come into reality and convinces her that the only way to stop him is to make another film where she must play Nancy one last time. I like Freddy's new look and J. Peter Robinson's score is great. Wes re-invented the series with this by making Freddy scary again and bringing back the original stars. I recommend this great nightmare sequel.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It takes a master to re-birth a tired franchise
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert W. (Robert_duder@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    None of the Nightmare On Elm Street sequels were straight-up 'bad' per se. But the series has definitely hit an all time lull with Freddy's Dead. Could anyone breath new life into it? Probably not, other than the creator and horror master himself. Wes Craven comes up with one of the coolest, most unique ideas in a horror franchise. He breaks down the fourth wall and lets Freddy Kreuger into the real real world and brings back some of the iconic original characters. Heather Langenkamp returns as herself who is contemplating returning the Nightmare series as Nancy. Its great to have her back and she brings a certain memorable class to the film. The very talented youngster Miko Hughes (he was stunning in Mercury Rising) plays Heather's young son Dylan. He does a great job! John Saxon also returns playing himself this time around and its good to see him back as he does a great job too. Even Wes Craven plays double duty as himself and it was really cool to have him on the cast. David Newsom is decent as Langenkamp's husband although his role is quite small they have good chemistry. Robert Englund is the star of this movie. That might seem like an obvious statement but he is absolutely phenomenal in New Nightmare playing himself but also the return to the dark twisted killer that is Freddy Kreuger. Englund is a talented actor who has been type casted into horror flicks but this proved he can be versatile and really work with a great script. Its also proof that it was the lack of really depthy scripts that changed Kreuger into a comedic character because he slips back into the dark version of Kreuger flawlessly. It was so much fun to see Englund and Langenkamp together out of character and playing themselves. Ultimately you could watch the first Nightmare On Elm Street movie and then watch this one and not miss anything. This is a direct follow up to Wes Craven's original film and it is a brilliant addition to the series and the perfect way to usher in the tenth anniversary at the time. Generally this is considered by fans to be a great re-birth in the series and rightfully so. This one proves why horror fans like me keep coming back for more because sometimes even upper instalments can surprise you!! 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Again Freddie Krueger with his hideously scarred face and knives terrorizing Heather and family
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ma-cortes
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Modern rendition about the myth Freddy dealing with young people discover they're having the same terrible nightmares . New version about Freddy Krueger killing people in macabre style and boasts some startling , gruesome special effects . A re-imagining of the classic Freddy Krueger, a serial-killer who wields a glove with four blades embedded in the fingers and murders people in their dreams , resulting in their real death in reality . Nowadays, it's nearing the 10th Anniversary of the picture 'A Nightmare on Elm Street' and one of the protagonists , (Heather Langenkamp) starts to be haunted in their nightmares by scar-faced and dream-hunting Freddy Krueger (Robert Englund now fits likes a glove) , a kind of spectre with awful burns , in stripy jumper and large knives. He enters their dreams at will and again kill them. Heather Langenkamp is being scared by a voice on a telephone , sounding very similar to the movie's nasty, Freddy Krueger . When Heather's husband (David Newsom) is killed in a car crash and is discovered with slash marks on him, Heather starts to wonder somethings . Heathe learns that Freddy has now entered the real world . The unsettling Heather plagued by astonishing dreams helps her son (Miko Hughes) to attempt to stop the nasty and demonic Freddy who kill people in macabre ways . Mother and son are having the same bad dream in which a malicious bogeyman is frightening them with knives attached to his fingers and the dream becomes reality . Heather sets out to discover the truth by attempting to draw the bogeyman out of the dream . This is a diverting reworking upon first film's plot by screenwriter Wes Craven based on his characters and dealing with the imaginative premise about a kind of ghost who can enter their dreams at will and intents on taking over both his body and mind . The twisted script dishes up the requisite helping of one-liners and throwaway black humor . This eerie film packs thrills , chills , creepy events and lots of blood and gore . It's a flimsily plotted but visually enjoyable addition to the Krueger endless saga . There are a few genuinely inspired events , notably Freddy's appearances and the extraordinary body-ripping spotlights in the Hospital room . Although it results to be a franchise that we now know was to follow , there are some originally frightening dream sequences. Special and extravagant visual effects are the climax of the movie and the startling make-up on Freddy face , but both of them don't save the story . Young casting and special appearance by John Saxon , the same Wes Craven and Robert Shaye , film's producer . Creepy and imaginatively made musical score fitting to terror movie by J. Peter Robinson . Colorful and atmospheric cinematography by Mark Irwin . The motion picture well produced by the great producer Robert Shaye from New Line Cinema and is professionally directed by Wes Craven , though with no originality and nothing new to show . Wes's sure grasp of the skewed logic of nightmares help to sustain the ambiguity between the dream and real world . Rating : 5,5 , passable sequel . It's all acceptable scary fun . The series initiates itself from original entry title &uml;A Nightmare on Elm Elm Street&uml; directed by Wes Craven with Heather Langenkamp , Johnny Depp , Amanda Wyss and John Saxon . The rest is a series of disjointed but however impressive special effects pieces . As it was followed by a handful of sequels in which horrifying special effects dominate this slasher saga , as &uml;Freddy's revenge&uml; 1985 by Jack Sholder with Kim Myers , Clu Gulager and Hope Lange ; &uml;Dream warrior&uml; 1987 by Chuck Russell with Patricia Arquette , Larry Fishburne and Craig Wasson , it's one of the best sequels from successful original film by Craven , as &uml;Dream master&uml; (1988) by Renny Harlin with Lisa Wilcox , Tuesday Knight and &uml;The dream child&uml; (1989) by Stephen Hopkins with Lisa Wilcox , Erika Anderson . Besides a Television series &uml;The Freddy's nightmares&uml; and this last one &uml; A nightmare on Elm Street&uml;(2010) with Jackie Haley that is a simple copy with little imagination , too many flaws and giving routine treatment .
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Why does this have such a high rating???
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    votesmall
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Okay, first of all, let me say that I am not one of those people who doesn't "get" movies if they aren't "edge of your seat". For example, 2001: A Space Odyssey could have been good, but it just was too boring and had no explanation for the monolith and not enough focus on HAL 9000, the freaky antagonist supercomputer. Basically, most of the movie was shots of space with classical music. And everyone tells me that I didn't "get" it. No, I can't get it because there is no explanation, and it's too boring! BUT, I did love Hellraiser: Inferno, and In the Mouth of Madness. So, what's the problem with New Nightmare??? Okay, first of all is the fact of Freddy. I actually love his new look, the jacket and hand, although the sweater and hat looked kind of funny and I didn't understand why they put the greenish-red rings around his eyes. They went to so much work designing this new, evil looking Freddy and he can't have more than 20 minutes of screen time. Yep, just a little bit more than Freddy's Revenge. And yes, I know that Pinhead had just about as much screen time in Hellraiser: Inferno, but they didn't redesign Pinhead in that one. Okay, I do love psychological thrillers, but this was just BORING! It starts off with an all metal, robotic glove coming to life on the film set of a new Nightmare on Elm Street movie. The glove kills several special effects crew members and is about to kill Heather Langenkamp (Nancy)'s husband. And then she wakes up. Okay, that was awesome! Good, frightening, and all a dream. And the next forty five minutes or so have NOTHING going on for the movie! I will admit, the interview scene and the limousine scene were somewhat interesting, but the rest of it was just boring fluff. And also, we get a few decent shots of Robert Englund in this movie, but we don't see near enough! The entire movie revolves around two characters, that just can't carry the film. The kid is just annoying. He isn't creepy, he's just annoying. Some of the dream sequences are pretty freaky, but other than that, he's just a normal kid talking in a stupid voice. Also, the vomit scene was pretty much stolen from The Exorcist. So, by the end of the movie, all of the characters are referring to Heather as Nancy, but this is never explained. And then there is a showdown at the "boiler room", which looks more like an ancient Greek temple than a power plant mechanical room. Okay, this scene was too tacky. And Freddy actually extends his arm to get the kid, tries to "eat him", and wraps his tongue around Heather before burning to death and turning into, get this, the devil.??? I will admit that I liked how it came to the real world, and we do get some pretty decent shots of Wes Craven and Robert Englund, and even a few other stars, but, like Freddy, they just don't have enough screen time. And some of the dream sequences are pretty creepy. But, I have two HUGE problems with this movie. First off, the fact that Heather has to wait until, like an hour and a half (around three days in the movie) after her kid tries to commit suicide, has seizures, nightmares, and tries to kill her before taking him to the hospital. Also, her kid is terrified of nightmares and she shuts the door so he is in the dark! ??? Worst mother ever! And it also isn't about Freddy on a film set, it's about him stalking Heather and her kid for two hours. This movie was so slow paced that it seemed like Titanic. Not to mention a hilariously low body count, with Freddy having a brand new glove, but breaking someone's neck! ??? Judge for yourself, but I thought it was boring. The kid was annoying, there wasn't enough Freddy, and Heather Langenkamp is just not an interesting character, unlike Nancy Thompson. Overall, this film is just TOO slow. I mean, Wes Craven had a really good idea here. Very original, just like the first Nightmare movie. But he didn't execute it very well. The kid was annoying, Heather Langenkamp looks bored and "worried" throughout the movie. And some of the dialogue is just ridiculous. Like how Wes all of a sudden knows what the new Freddy is is kind of ridiculous, because he couldn't possibly know that. Not to mention that in Never Sleep Again, he showed drawings for a "Freddy mobile" that he was going to put in the movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wes Craven's New Nightmare
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It looked like for some time Freddy's Dead: The Final Nightmare was the final time scary movie fans would see the iconic razor handed "Son of 100 Maniacs", but then original film writer and director Wes Craven (The Hills Have Eyes, Scream) came up with this clever comeback. Basically the tenth anniversary of the movie A Nightmare on Elm Street is coming up, and original star Heather Langenkamp is part of the special events celebrating, along with its director Wes Craven, and of course the man behind killer Freddy Krueger, actor Robert Englund. She has a happy life with husband Chase Porter (David Newsom) and son Dylan (Miko Hughes), but she is being stalked by a nasty voice on the phone, and creepy goings on in her house, and things get worse when her husband is killed in a car crash, and his body has slash marks on it. Dylan is refusing to sleep anymore, because he is scared, like the movie, that Freddy will come in his dream and try to kill him, and dealing with this Heather is also being offered a part in the next Nightmare film Wes is working on, but the script needs work. Heather is finding the behaviour of her son uncontrollable, and she does believe Freddy is haunting her, Wes comes up with the theory that now the Elm Street films are over an ancient spirit must have helped him come out of the fictional world to enter dreams in real life, and his script may be part of this way out. It comes to the point when Dylan may be taken away from Heather due to his psychologically disturbed behaviour, but she is also incarcerated by doctors who believe she is going mad, of course Freddy continues his kills while this is going on. Eventually Heather, like her character, enters a dream to confront Freddy and stop the terror, and she manages to lock him in a furnace to burn to death, and returning to the real world she and her son read the new finished sample script sent by Wes. I like films where actors play a version of themselves, you could see this as semi-documentary considering the concept of how to bring back a character supposedly dead for good, the story has its moments of irritation, especially with the doctors breaking up the mother and son, but the script has clever references and ideas, and there is just enough Freddy and gore for the fans, a not bad horror film. Worth watching!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Langenkamp and Englund go uber real.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    amesmonde
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The lead actors of the original Nightmare on Elm Street, on it's 10th Anniversary, are terrorized by a Freddy Kruger like entity that wants Heather Langenkamp and her son dead. The seemingly outrageous bloody opening is quickly defused as a fitting dream sequence and new ground is broken as we discover the actors are playing themselves. It appears to break the fourth wall with Wes Craven, John Saxon and Robert Englund to name a few playing themselves. Of course this allows Langenkamp to return as herself after her Nancy character's death in the third. This non-conventional approach with a number of uneasy phone calls would become the precursor film within a film which appears in Craven's own Scream series. While you'd expect most of the actors to be able to play themselves they do at times come across as awkward and uncomfortable. Thankfully the leads pull it off with ease - namely Englund and Langenkamp. Faces from the original also cameo as themselves and a photo of Johnny Depp shows up in the background. Some scenes are a blast for fans with Englund playing himself as Freddy on a talk show. Of course Englund also plays Freddy the embodiment of an evil spirit with an expert indifference. This darker, scarier Freddy is probably what fans of the original wanted to see in the handful of sequels. There's irony on irony with producer Rob Shay inviting Langenkamp to come back and play Nancy one last time in a definitive nightmare. Writer/Director Craven delivers another novel idea with a tantalizing hook. There's a nice touch where reality merges with dreams and John Sax returns as his character Lt. Donald Thompson with Langenkamp calling him John and him unawares in turn calling her Nancy. The kill scenes pay homage to the original and even some of the sequels notably the Chase Porter car crash. With a strong supporting cast (mainly those ones who don't play themselves) including Miko Hughes as Dylan Porter Heather's on screen son gives a solid mixture of Poltergeist/Exorcist-like performance. It may have benefited from a more natural looking production, less film- like to emphasis the realness in contrast to the movie world and Nightmare sequences. It's own high production values and Mark Irwin's great cinematography dilute the edginess. Craven's screenplay also injects a part actress character study there is an interesting subtext about fame and it trappings. A New Nightmare has all the kills one would expect with excellent make up and visual effect on display with Craven trying to out do himself with the accompanying music by J. Peter Robinson. The idea of uber Freddy character harassing the real life cast and crew doesn't tire with the entertaining and fitting premise. It's only a movie...or is it?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wes Craven's dream of rebooting Freddy becomes a New Nightmare
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ironhorse_iv
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's hardly a perfect film for Wes Craven, but it's eerie and thought-provoking, something that been lacking in the previous movies that made Freddy Kruger into a goofy wise cracker and cheesy death scenes. It is also the last the last time that Freddy showed any real menace. Wes Craven made this to take back control of his creation and it works as a criticism of what the franchise became with Freddy as a comedian, not to mention a rebuff to the tired argument about violence in films always causing it in the real world. Freddy was far more straightforward with his kills and didn't manifest elaborate scenarios for each death. Pure intimidation. That's what Wes was trying to bring back. New Nightmare is almost in it's own league. New Nightmare had a great story and very original, creative ideas in it but it was still a bit confusing with the plot of the movie! It's the movie without a movie. He would work this angle again, in the 'Scream' series with the "Stab" movies in Scream are movies within a movie! It's work here, it doesn't work there. 'A Nightmare on Elm Street 7: The Ascension' is being film, and Heather Langenkamp playing herself, the actress that play the original heroic star of the original movie is being ask to reprise her role as Nancy Thompson. She notice that her husband Chase, and son Dylan is also being haunted by Freddy Krueger (Robert Englund) outside the filming, and confront the actor Robert Englund about it. She then go to Wes Craven himself, who reveals that Freddy is real, and only she can stop him. There is a interesting theory that comes to front with this. It's probably not Wes Craven's intent, but an audience's interpretation is authorial fallacy to see that there might have been a connection to this movie with that of the 3rd movie Dream Warriors. Heather's character Nancy Thompson's dies in the World of the first three films/four films. Her funeral/gravestone proves this (the gravestone was shown in A Nightmare on Elm Street 4: The Dream Master). The character Kristen from Dream Warrior, somehow, created a new world/new reality and placed Nancy's soul into this world in the end of the film like it stated. It's a dream world, yet Nancy's soul can live a full beautiful life in this beautiful dream world. Nancy's physically dead, yet not spiritually dead. I would think that once she ages and dies in this dream world then she would have truly died. Overall, Nancy has been placed in a matrix type reality so, to her, everyone in this reality is real/important to her. Freddy though, once all event's take place in the "real world" (the world of dream warriors), realizes that Nancy is in this dream world/alternate reality and therefore tries to kill Nancy since he wants to finish her off once and for all. It must take a lot for him to enter this dream world though since earthquakes are occurring constantly. Since Wes Craven wrote 1, 3, and this one... could it be Nancy living as Heather. It's a headache, but it's worth checking out or is the previous films fake and this movie real. Is Heather insane or is Freddy really coming out of the film to kill the actress that kill him in the movie? The movie goes with the realish look to it. Surprising the earthquake footage in the film is real. It was taken from the 1994 Northridge earthquake that happen during filming. The movie seem fresh, and the way in which Freddy talked, walked, and looked really brought a much needed shot of freshness to the character that had seriously been lacking. Freddy has a deeper voice. To correspond with this, the make-up and outfit of the character was different, with one of the most prominent differences being that he now wears a long, black trench coat. In addition, the signature glove was redesigned for a more organic look, with the fingers resembling bones and having muscle textures in between. It really adds to his darker vibe. The problem with the movie was that Freddy was way too soft. He looked better than ever and he was darker than ever, but all he did to the kid and his mom was chase them around, wrestle them, and scare them. Also Freddie's screen time is almost non existent, he rarely in the film, but when he is, he's scary! Heather Langenkamp takes most of the movie time, sadly not great in leading the film anywhere, as she unable to act her way through wet tissue. Even with fails, Wes Craven's New Nightmare was probably created solely for the purpose of Wes wanting to erase 2, 4, 5, and 6, and I believe even 3 because he said in the special documentary for the box set that he essentially believes that only the first film and A New Nightmare are cannon. Essentially Wes Craven threw a bratty fit over the fact there were so many sequels and wanted to basically bury the series with A New Nightmare. The meta-fictional methodology of 'New Nightmare' really gave a unique and terrifying storyline and, in my opinion, one of the best films of the franchise. So while the theory is still interesting and I can see how it would work, I think it takes away from how good 'New Nightmare' is. I'd rather watch this one than a complete hideous garbage 2010 one with Haley is, God I dislike that version.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Christina Aguilera once spoke for him.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RickHarvey
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Freddy is back... well, he's not actually back. Instead, an heinous and satanic Freddy takes over our screens as a his existence forges into reality while his films continue to dwindle in the publics conscious.(With the majority of the films being awful, i can't say that's a bad thing.) I really liked New nightmare: Original, showcasing the same mixture of intelligence with the first NMOES and most importantly, great acting. I was sceptical at first when knowing that a child actor stars - with them mostly being obnoxious and unwittingly annoying in majority of films - but thankfully the character of Dylan paid off. The thought of Freddy becoming closer to reality when the longer he's forgotten is fantastic. With the actors playing themselves, you follow the hysteria that follows Heather while he struggles to cope with a stalker. Freddy's appearance: Long, drab trench coat and feroda hat, is spot on. Despite a change in Freddy, it seems he can't resist on pulling out a one-liner from under his sleeves. Made his enigmatic aura suffer a little. Overall, I'm glad Craven decided to make another NMOES - even if it was just for the money. You sense his input being commanded with every shot. The final act gave lovers of the original NMOES an flash back on their initial experience with Freddy. With both script and camera, Craven didn't do much wrong.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Immensely enjoyable and entertaining
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    GL84
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After a series of nightmares and her son's strange behavior, an actress becomes convinced a famous serial killer from her movie history has come into the real world and targeting her and her family, forcing her to stop him using the tricks from the movies. This here turned out to be a decent if slightly flawed entry. Among the many things that work here is the fact that, by tying into the film series as a whole separate entity away from the reality presented here, it manages to be a lot smarter than it usually would be for this type of film, and that's something to commend by having the actors playing themselves instead of the film roles. That makes the typically-clich&eacute;d is-it-all-a-dream-or-not set-up far more effective than it has any right to be, given even more credence with Freddy's return to being scary again. Dropping any semblance of wise-cracks, puns and lame jokes, reduced screen time and really only appearing to do damage make him a credible, scary force again, and that helps this out tremendously. With some great action in here, a lot of great special effects and a fantastic finale, this has a lot going for it but there's still a few problems here, mainly in the film's continued usage of the annoying child who does nothing but scream and does nothing to the film overall. The low kill count means there's little variety to be found as well, but overall this isn't all too bad. Rated R: Violence, Language, and children in jeopardy
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Worst nightmare come true!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    amethystwings32
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    These movies , are horrific and terrifying to the very core! They are awful , Freddy Krueger made Jason and Mike Myers look like dark angels! He can definitely give someone nightmares, he is grotesque. What he did to his victims , would make any squeamish person want to vomit! That is why I will never get this obsession , anyone who likes these are seriously disturbed! I would hardly call these good, blood and gore doesn't make a movie good! Being terrified to the very core, with it's graphic nightmarish scenes. To the point you want to scream, walk out. Cover your face the whole time , faint or hurl. That is all of the signs that a movie is not worth watching!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Great Nightmare Sequel!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gwnightscream
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Robert Englund, Heather Langenkamp, John Saxon, Wes Craven and Miko Hughes star in Wes Craven's 1994 horror sequel. Freddy Krueger stalks the cast & crew of the original "Nightmare on Elm Street" during it's 10th anniversary. This film takes place in Los Angeles and focuses on Heather (Langenkamp) and her young son, Dylan (Hughes). Robert, John & Wes also play themselves and after mysterious earthquakes occur, Heather notices Dylan is acting strange and learns he's having nightmares abut Freddy Krueger. She gets him cared for at a hospital and decides to talk to Wes. He tells her that Freddy is an ancient evil essence from the films that wants to come into reality and convinces her that the only way to stop him is to make another film where she must play Nancy one last time. I like Freddy's new look and J. Peter Robinson's score is great. Wes re-invented the series with this by making Freddy scary again and bringing back the original stars. I recommend this great nightmare sequel.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It takes a master to re-birth a tired franchise
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert W. (Robert_duder@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    None of the Nightmare On Elm Street sequels were straight-up 'bad' per se. But the series has definitely hit an all time lull with Freddy's Dead. Could anyone breath new life into it? Probably not, other than the creator and horror master himself. Wes Craven comes up with one of the coolest, most unique ideas in a horror franchise. He breaks down the fourth wall and lets Freddy Kreuger into the real real world and brings back some of the iconic original characters. Heather Langenkamp returns as herself who is contemplating returning the Nightmare series as Nancy. Its great to have her back and she brings a certain memorable class to the film. The very talented youngster Miko Hughes (he was stunning in Mercury Rising) plays Heather's young son Dylan. He does a great job! John Saxon also returns playing himself this time around and its good to see him back as he does a great job too. Even Wes Craven plays double duty as himself and it was really cool to have him on the cast. David Newsom is decent as Langenkamp's husband although his role is quite small they have good chemistry. Robert Englund is the star of this movie. That might seem like an obvious statement but he is absolutely phenomenal in New Nightmare playing himself but also the return to the dark twisted killer that is Freddy Kreuger. Englund is a talented actor who has been type casted into horror flicks but this proved he can be versatile and really work with a great script. Its also proof that it was the lack of really depthy scripts that changed Kreuger into a comedic character because he slips back into the dark version of Kreuger flawlessly. It was so much fun to see Englund and Langenkamp together out of character and playing themselves. Ultimately you could watch the first Nightmare On Elm Street movie and then watch this one and not miss anything. This is a direct follow up to Wes Craven's original film and it is a brilliant addition to the series and the perfect way to usher in the tenth anniversary at the time. Generally this is considered by fans to be a great re-birth in the series and rightfully so. This one proves why horror fans like me keep coming back for more because sometimes even upper instalments can surprise you!! 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Again Freddie Krueger with his hideously scarred face and knives terrorizing Heather and family
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ma-cortes
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Modern rendition about the myth Freddy dealing with young people discover they're having the same terrible nightmares . New version about Freddy Krueger killing people in macabre style and boasts some startling , gruesome special effects . A re-imagining of the classic Freddy Krueger, a serial-killer who wields a glove with four blades embedded in the fingers and murders people in their dreams , resulting in their real death in reality . Nowadays, it's nearing the 10th Anniversary of the picture 'A Nightmare on Elm Street' and one of the protagonists , (Heather Langenkamp) starts to be haunted in their nightmares by scar-faced and dream-hunting Freddy Krueger (Robert Englund now fits likes a glove) , a kind of spectre with awful burns , in stripy jumper and large knives. He enters their dreams at will and again kill them. Heather Langenkamp is being scared by a voice on a telephone , sounding very similar to the movie's nasty, Freddy Krueger . When Heather's husband (David Newsom) is killed in a car crash and is discovered with slash marks on him, Heather starts to wonder somethings . Heathe learns that Freddy has now entered the real world . The unsettling Heather plagued by astonishing dreams helps her son (Miko Hughes) to attempt to stop the nasty and demonic Freddy who kill people in macabre ways . Mother and son are having the same bad dream in which a malicious bogeyman is frightening them with knives attached to his fingers and the dream becomes reality . Heather sets out to discover the truth by attempting to draw the bogeyman out of the dream . This is a diverting reworking upon first film's plot by screenwriter Wes Craven based on his characters and dealing with the imaginative premise about a kind of ghost who can enter their dreams at will and intents on taking over both his body and mind . The twisted script dishes up the requisite helping of one-liners and throwaway black humor . This eerie film packs thrills , chills , creepy events and lots of blood and gore . It's a flimsily plotted but visually enjoyable addition to the Krueger endless saga . There are a few genuinely inspired events , notably Freddy's appearances and the extraordinary body-ripping spotlights in the Hospital room . Although it results to be a franchise that we now know was to follow , there are some originally frightening dream sequences. Special and extravagant visual effects are the climax of the movie and the startling make-up on Freddy face , but both of them don't save the story . Young casting and special appearance by John Saxon , the same Wes Craven and Robert Shaye , film's producer . Creepy and imaginatively made musical score fitting to terror movie by J. Peter Robinson . Colorful and atmospheric cinematography by Mark Irwin . The motion picture well produced by the great producer Robert Shaye from New Line Cinema and is professionally directed by Wes Craven , though with no originality and nothing new to show . Wes's sure grasp of the skewed logic of nightmares help to sustain the ambiguity between the dream and real world . Rating : 5,5 , passable sequel . It's all acceptable scary fun . The series initiates itself from original entry title &uml;A Nightmare on Elm Elm Street&uml; directed by Wes Craven with Heather Langenkamp , Johnny Depp , Amanda Wyss and John Saxon . The rest is a series of disjointed but however impressive special effects pieces . As it was followed by a handful of sequels in which horrifying special effects dominate this slasher saga , as &uml;Freddy's revenge&uml; 1985 by Jack Sholder with Kim Myers , Clu Gulager and Hope Lange ; &uml;Dream warrior&uml; 1987 by Chuck Russell with Patricia Arquette , Larry Fishburne and Craig Wasson , it's one of the best sequels from successful original film by Craven , as &uml;Dream master&uml; (1988) by Renny Harlin with Lisa Wilcox , Tuesday Knight and &uml;The dream child&uml; (1989) by Stephen Hopkins with Lisa Wilcox , Erika Anderson . Besides a Television series &uml;The Freddy's nightmares&uml; and this last one &uml; A nightmare on Elm Street&uml;(2010) with Jackie Haley that is a simple copy with little imagination , too many flaws and giving routine treatment .
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Why does this have such a high rating???
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    votesmall
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Okay, first of all, let me say that I am not one of those people who doesn't "get" movies if they aren't "edge of your seat". For example, 2001: A Space Odyssey could have been good, but it just was too boring and had no explanation for the monolith and not enough focus on HAL 9000, the freaky antagonist supercomputer. Basically, most of the movie was shots of space with classical music. And everyone tells me that I didn't "get" it. No, I can't get it because there is no explanation, and it's too boring! BUT, I did love Hellraiser: Inferno, and In the Mouth of Madness. So, what's the problem with New Nightmare??? Okay, first of all is the fact of Freddy. I actually love his new look, the jacket and hand, although the sweater and hat looked kind of funny and I didn't understand why they put the greenish-red rings around his eyes. They went to so much work designing this new, evil looking Freddy and he can't have more than 20 minutes of screen time. Yep, just a little bit more than Freddy's Revenge. And yes, I know that Pinhead had just about as much screen time in Hellraiser: Inferno, but they didn't redesign Pinhead in that one. Okay, I do love psychological thrillers, but this was just BORING! It starts off with an all metal, robotic glove coming to life on the film set of a new Nightmare on Elm Street movie. The glove kills several special effects crew members and is about to kill Heather Langenkamp (Nancy)'s husband. And then she wakes up. Okay, that was awesome! Good, frightening, and all a dream. And the next forty five minutes or so have NOTHING going on for the movie! I will admit, the interview scene and the limousine scene were somewhat interesting, but the rest of it was just boring fluff. And also, we get a few decent shots of Robert Englund in this movie, but we don't see near enough! The entire movie revolves around two characters, that just can't carry the film. The kid is just annoying. He isn't creepy, he's just annoying. Some of the dream sequences are pretty freaky, but other than that, he's just a normal kid talking in a stupid voice. Also, the vomit scene was pretty much stolen from The Exorcist. So, by the end of the movie, all of the characters are referring to Heather as Nancy, but this is never explained. And then there is a showdown at the "boiler room", which looks more like an ancient Greek temple than a power plant mechanical room. Okay, this scene was too tacky. And Freddy actually extends his arm to get the kid, tries to "eat him", and wraps his tongue around Heather before burning to death and turning into, get this, the devil.??? I will admit that I liked how it came to the real world, and we do get some pretty decent shots of Wes Craven and Robert Englund, and even a few other stars, but, like Freddy, they just don't have enough screen time. And some of the dream sequences are pretty creepy. But, I have two HUGE problems with this movie. First off, the fact that Heather has to wait until, like an hour and a half (around three days in the movie) after her kid tries to commit suicide, has seizures, nightmares, and tries to kill her before taking him to the hospital. Also, her kid is terrified of nightmares and she shuts the door so he is in the dark! ??? Worst mother ever! And it also isn't about Freddy on a film set, it's about him stalking Heather and her kid for two hours. This movie was so slow paced that it seemed like Titanic. Not to mention a hilariously low body count, with Freddy having a brand new glove, but breaking someone's neck! ??? Judge for yourself, but I thought it was boring. The kid was annoying, there wasn't enough Freddy, and Heather Langenkamp is just not an interesting character, unlike Nancy Thompson. Overall, this film is just TOO slow. I mean, Wes Craven had a really good idea here. Very original, just like the first Nightmare movie. But he didn't execute it very well. The kid was annoying, Heather Langenkamp looks bored and "worried" throughout the movie. And some of the dialogue is just ridiculous. Like how Wes all of a sudden knows what the new Freddy is is kind of ridiculous, because he couldn't possibly know that. Not to mention that in Never Sleep Again, he showed drawings for a "Freddy mobile" that he was going to put in the movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wes Craven's New Nightmare
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It looked like for some time Freddy's Dead: The Final Nightmare was the final time scary movie fans would see the iconic razor handed "Son of 100 Maniacs", but then original film writer and director Wes Craven (The Hills Have Eyes, Scream) came up with this clever comeback. Basically the tenth anniversary of the movie A Nightmare on Elm Street is coming up, and original star Heather Langenkamp is part of the special events celebrating, along with its director Wes Craven, and of course the man behind killer Freddy Krueger, actor Robert Englund. She has a happy life with husband Chase Porter (David Newsom) and son Dylan (Miko Hughes), but she is being stalked by a nasty voice on the phone, and creepy goings on in her house, and things get worse when her husband is killed in a car crash, and his body has slash marks on it. Dylan is refusing to sleep anymore, because he is scared, like the movie, that Freddy will come in his dream and try to kill him, and dealing with this Heather is also being offered a part in the next Nightmare film Wes is working on, but the script needs work. Heather is finding the behaviour of her son uncontrollable, and she does believe Freddy is haunting her, Wes comes up with the theory that now the Elm Street films are over an ancient spirit must have helped him come out of the fictional world to enter dreams in real life, and his script may be part of this way out. It comes to the point when Dylan may be taken away from Heather due to his psychologically disturbed behaviour, but she is also incarcerated by doctors who believe she is going mad, of course Freddy continues his kills while this is going on. Eventually Heather, like her character, enters a dream to confront Freddy and stop the terror, and she manages to lock him in a furnace to burn to death, and returning to the real world she and her son read the new finished sample script sent by Wes. I like films where actors play a version of themselves, you could see this as semi-documentary considering the concept of how to bring back a character supposedly dead for good, the story has its moments of irritation, especially with the doctors breaking up the mother and son, but the script has clever references and ideas, and there is just enough Freddy and gore for the fans, a not bad horror film. Worth watching!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Langenkamp and Englund go uber real.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    amesmonde
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The lead actors of the original Nightmare on Elm Street, on it's 10th Anniversary, are terrorized by a Freddy Kruger like entity that wants Heather Langenkamp and her son dead. The seemingly outrageous bloody opening is quickly defused as a fitting dream sequence and new ground is broken as we discover the actors are playing themselves. It appears to break the fourth wall with Wes Craven, John Saxon and Robert Englund to name a few playing themselves. Of course this allows Langenkamp to return as herself after her Nancy character's death in the third. This non-conventional approach with a number of uneasy phone calls would become the precursor film within a film which appears in Craven's own Scream series. While you'd expect most of the actors to be able to play themselves they do at times come across as awkward and uncomfortable. Thankfully the leads pull it off with ease - namely Englund and Langenkamp. Faces from the original also cameo as themselves and a photo of Johnny Depp shows up in the background. Some scenes are a blast for fans with Englund playing himself as Freddy on a talk show. Of course Englund also plays Freddy the embodiment of an evil spirit with an expert indifference. This darker, scarier Freddy is probably what fans of the original wanted to see in the handful of sequels. There's irony on irony with producer Rob Shay inviting Langenkamp to come back and play Nancy one last time in a definitive nightmare. Writer/Director Craven delivers another novel idea with a tantalizing hook. There's a nice touch where reality merges with dreams and John Sax returns as his character Lt. Donald Thompson with Langenkamp calling him John and him unawares in turn calling her Nancy. The kill scenes pay homage to the original and even some of the sequels notably the Chase Porter car crash. With a strong supporting cast (mainly those ones who don't play themselves) including Miko Hughes as Dylan Porter Heather's on screen son gives a solid mixture of Poltergeist/Exorcist-like performance. It may have benefited from a more natural looking production, less film- like to emphasis the realness in contrast to the movie world and Nightmare sequences. It's own high production values and Mark Irwin's great cinematography dilute the edginess. Craven's screenplay also injects a part actress character study there is an interesting subtext about fame and it trappings. A New Nightmare has all the kills one would expect with excellent make up and visual effect on display with Craven trying to out do himself with the accompanying music by J. Peter Robinson. The idea of uber Freddy character harassing the real life cast and crew doesn't tire with the entertaining and fitting premise. It's only a movie...or is it?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wes Craven's dream of rebooting Freddy becomes a New Nightmare
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ironhorse_iv
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's hardly a perfect film for Wes Craven, but it's eerie and thought-provoking, something that been lacking in the previous movies that made Freddy Kruger into a goofy wise cracker and cheesy death scenes. It is also the last the last time that Freddy showed any real menace. Wes Craven made this to take back control of his creation and it works as a criticism of what the franchise became with Freddy as a comedian, not to mention a rebuff to the tired argument about violence in films always causing it in the real world. Freddy was far more straightforward with his kills and didn't manifest elaborate scenarios for each death. Pure intimidation. That's what Wes was trying to bring back. New Nightmare is almost in it's own league. New Nightmare had a great story and very original, creative ideas in it but it was still a bit confusing with the plot of the movie! It's the movie without a movie. He would work this angle again, in the 'Scream' series with the "Stab" movies in Scream are movies within a movie! It's work here, it doesn't work there. 'A Nightmare on Elm Street 7: The Ascension' is being film, and Heather Langenkamp playing herself, the actress that play the original heroic star of the original movie is being ask to reprise her role as Nancy Thompson. She notice that her husband Chase, and son Dylan is also being haunted by Freddy Krueger (Robert Englund) outside the filming, and confront the actor Robert Englund about it. She then go to Wes Craven himself, who reveals that Freddy is real, and only she can stop him. There is a interesting theory that comes to front with this. It's probably not Wes Craven's intent, but an audience's interpretation is authorial fallacy to see that there might have been a connection to this movie with that of the 3rd movie Dream Warriors. Heather's character Nancy Thompson's dies in the World of the first three films/four films. Her funeral/gravestone proves this (the gravestone was shown in A Nightmare on Elm Street 4: The Dream Master). The character Kristen from Dream Warrior, somehow, created a new world/new reality and placed Nancy's soul into this world in the end of the film like it stated. It's a dream world, yet Nancy's soul can live a full beautiful life in this beautiful dream world. Nancy's physically dead, yet not spiritually dead. I would think that once she ages and dies in this dream world then she would have truly died. Overall, Nancy has been placed in a matrix type reality so, to her, everyone in this reality is real/important to her. Freddy though, once all event's take place in the "real world" (the world of dream warriors), realizes that Nancy is in this dream world/alternate reality and therefore tries to kill Nancy since he wants to finish her off once and for all. It must take a lot for him to enter this dream world though since earthquakes are occurring constantly. Since Wes Craven wrote 1, 3, and this one... could it be Nancy living as Heather. It's a headache, but it's worth checking out or is the previous films fake and this movie real. Is Heather insane or is Freddy really coming out of the film to kill the actress that kill him in the movie? The movie goes with the realish look to it. Surprising the earthquake footage in the film is real. It was taken from the 1994 Northridge earthquake that happen during filming. The movie seem fresh, and the way in which Freddy talked, walked, and looked really brought a much needed shot of freshness to the character that had seriously been lacking. Freddy has a deeper voice. To correspond with this, the make-up and outfit of the character was different, with one of the most prominent differences being that he now wears a long, black trench coat. In addition, the signature glove was redesigned for a more organic look, with the fingers resembling bones and having muscle textures in between. It really adds to his darker vibe. The problem with the movie was that Freddy was way too soft. He looked better than ever and he was darker than ever, but all he did to the kid and his mom was chase them around, wrestle them, and scare them. Also Freddie's screen time is almost non existent, he rarely in the film, but when he is, he's scary! Heather Langenkamp takes most of the movie time, sadly not great in leading the film anywhere, as she unable to act her way through wet tissue. Even with fails, Wes Craven's New Nightmare was probably created solely for the purpose of Wes wanting to erase 2, 4, 5, and 6, and I believe even 3 because he said in the special documentary for the box set that he essentially believes that only the first film and A New Nightmare are cannon. Essentially Wes Craven threw a bratty fit over the fact there were so many sequels and wanted to basically bury the series with A New Nightmare. The meta-fictional methodology of 'New Nightmare' really gave a unique and terrifying storyline and, in my opinion, one of the best films of the franchise. So while the theory is still interesting and I can see how it would work, I think it takes away from how good 'New Nightmare' is. I'd rather watch this one than a complete hideous garbage 2010 one with Haley is, God I dislike that version.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Christina Aguilera once spoke for him.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RickHarvey
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Freddy is back... well, he's not actually back. Instead, an heinous and satanic Freddy takes over our screens as a his existence forges into reality while his films continue to dwindle in the publics conscious.(With the majority of the films being awful, i can't say that's a bad thing.) I really liked New nightmare: Original, showcasing the same mixture of intelligence with the first NMOES and most importantly, great acting. I was sceptical at first when knowing that a child actor stars - with them mostly being obnoxious and unwittingly annoying in majority of films - but thankfully the character of Dylan paid off. The thought of Freddy becoming closer to reality when the longer he's forgotten is fantastic. With the actors playing themselves, you follow the hysteria that follows Heather while he struggles to cope with a stalker. Freddy's appearance: Long, drab trench coat and feroda hat, is spot on. Despite a change in Freddy, it seems he can't resist on pulling out a one-liner from under his sleeves. Made his enigmatic aura suffer a little. Overall, I'm glad Craven decided to make another NMOES - even if it was just for the money. You sense his input being commanded with every shot. The final act gave lovers of the original NMOES an flash back on their initial experience with Freddy. With both script and camera, Craven didn't do much wrong.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Immensely enjoyable and entertaining
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    GL84
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After a series of nightmares and her son's strange behavior, an actress becomes convinced a famous serial killer from her movie history has come into the real world and targeting her and her family, forcing her to stop him using the tricks from the movies. This here turned out to be a decent if slightly flawed entry. Among the many things that work here is the fact that, by tying into the film series as a whole separate entity away from the reality presented here, it manages to be a lot smarter than it usually would be for this type of film, and that's something to commend by having the actors playing themselves instead of the film roles. That makes the typically-clich&eacute;d is-it-all-a-dream-or-not set-up far more effective than it has any right to be, given even more credence with Freddy's return to being scary again. Dropping any semblance of wise-cracks, puns and lame jokes, reduced screen time and really only appearing to do damage make him a credible, scary force again, and that helps this out tremendously. With some great action in here, a lot of great special effects and a fantastic finale, this has a lot going for it but there's still a few problems here, mainly in the film's continued usage of the annoying child who does nothing but scream and does nothing to the film overall. The low kill count means there's little variety to be found as well, but overall this isn't all too bad. Rated R: Violence, Language, and children in jeopardy
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Worst nightmare come true!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    amethystwings32
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    These movies , are horrific and terrifying to the very core! They are awful , Freddy Krueger made Jason and Mike Myers look like dark angels! He can definitely give someone nightmares, he is grotesque. What he did to his victims , would make any squeamish person want to vomit! That is why I will never get this obsession , anyone who likes these are seriously disturbed! I would hardly call these good, blood and gore doesn't make a movie good! Being terrified to the very core, with it's graphic nightmarish scenes. To the point you want to scream, walk out. Cover your face the whole time , faint or hurl. That is all of the signs that a movie is not worth watching!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Great Nightmare Sequel!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gwnightscream
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Robert Englund, Heather Langenkamp, John Saxon, Wes Craven and Miko Hughes star in Wes Craven's 1994 horror sequel. Freddy Krueger stalks the cast & crew of the original "Nightmare on Elm Street" during it's 10th anniversary. This film takes place in Los Angeles and focuses on Heather (Langenkamp) and her young son, Dylan (Hughes). Robert, John & Wes also play themselves and after mysterious earthquakes occur, Heather notices Dylan is acting strange and learns he's having nightmares abut Freddy Krueger. She gets him cared for at a hospital and decides to talk to Wes. He tells her that Freddy is an ancient evil essence from the films that wants to come into reality and convinces her that the only way to stop him is to make another film where she must play Nancy one last time. I like Freddy's new look and J. Peter Robinson's score is great. Wes re-invented the series with this by making Freddy scary again and bringing back the original stars. I recommend this great nightmare sequel.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It takes a master to re-birth a tired franchise
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert W. (Robert_duder@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    None of the Nightmare On Elm Street sequels were straight-up 'bad' per se. But the series has definitely hit an all time lull with Freddy's Dead. Could anyone breath new life into it? Probably not, other than the creator and horror master himself. Wes Craven comes up with one of the coolest, most unique ideas in a horror franchise. He breaks down the fourth wall and lets Freddy Kreuger into the real real world and brings back some of the iconic original characters. Heather Langenkamp returns as herself who is contemplating returning the Nightmare series as Nancy. Its great to have her back and she brings a certain memorable class to the film. The very talented youngster Miko Hughes (he was stunning in Mercury Rising) plays Heather's young son Dylan. He does a great job! John Saxon also returns playing himself this time around and its good to see him back as he does a great job too. Even Wes Craven plays double duty as himself and it was really cool to have him on the cast. David Newsom is decent as Langenkamp's husband although his role is quite small they have good chemistry. Robert Englund is the star of this movie. That might seem like an obvious statement but he is absolutely phenomenal in New Nightmare playing himself but also the return to the dark twisted killer that is Freddy Kreuger. Englund is a talented actor who has been type casted into horror flicks but this proved he can be versatile and really work with a great script. Its also proof that it was the lack of really depthy scripts that changed Kreuger into a comedic character because he slips back into the dark version of Kreuger flawlessly. It was so much fun to see Englund and Langenkamp together out of character and playing themselves. Ultimately you could watch the first Nightmare On Elm Street movie and then watch this one and not miss anything. This is a direct follow up to Wes Craven's original film and it is a brilliant addition to the series and the perfect way to usher in the tenth anniversary at the time. Generally this is considered by fans to be a great re-birth in the series and rightfully so. This one proves why horror fans like me keep coming back for more because sometimes even upper instalments can surprise you!! 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Again Freddie Krueger with his hideously scarred face and knives terrorizing Heather and family
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ma-cortes
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Modern rendition about the myth Freddy dealing with young people discover they're having the same terrible nightmares . New version about Freddy Krueger killing people in macabre style and boasts some startling , gruesome special effects . A re-imagining of the classic Freddy Krueger, a serial-killer who wields a glove with four blades embedded in the fingers and murders people in their dreams , resulting in their real death in reality . Nowadays, it's nearing the 10th Anniversary of the picture 'A Nightmare on Elm Street' and one of the protagonists , (Heather Langenkamp) starts to be haunted in their nightmares by scar-faced and dream-hunting Freddy Krueger (Robert Englund now fits likes a glove) , a kind of spectre with awful burns , in stripy jumper and large knives. He enters their dreams at will and again kill them. Heather Langenkamp is being scared by a voice on a telephone , sounding very similar to the movie's nasty, Freddy Krueger . When Heather's husband (David Newsom) is killed in a car crash and is discovered with slash marks on him, Heather starts to wonder somethings . Heathe learns that Freddy has now entered the real world . The unsettling Heather plagued by astonishing dreams helps her son (Miko Hughes) to attempt to stop the nasty and demonic Freddy who kill people in macabre ways . Mother and son are having the same bad dream in which a malicious bogeyman is frightening them with knives attached to his fingers and the dream becomes reality . Heather sets out to discover the truth by attempting to draw the bogeyman out of the dream . This is a diverting reworking upon first film's plot by screenwriter Wes Craven based on his characters and dealing with the imaginative premise about a kind of ghost who can enter their dreams at will and intents on taking over both his body and mind . The twisted script dishes up the requisite helping of one-liners and throwaway black humor . This eerie film packs thrills , chills , creepy events and lots of blood and gore . It's a flimsily plotted but visually enjoyable addition to the Krueger endless saga . There are a few genuinely inspired events , notably Freddy's appearances and the extraordinary body-ripping spotlights in the Hospital room . Although it results to be a franchise that we now know was to follow , there are some originally frightening dream sequences. Special and extravagant visual effects are the climax of the movie and the startling make-up on Freddy face , but both of them don't save the story . Young casting and special appearance by John Saxon , the same Wes Craven and Robert Shaye , film's producer . Creepy and imaginatively made musical score fitting to terror movie by J. Peter Robinson . Colorful and atmospheric cinematography by Mark Irwin . The motion picture well produced by the great producer Robert Shaye from New Line Cinema and is professionally directed by Wes Craven , though with no originality and nothing new to show . Wes's sure grasp of the skewed logic of nightmares help to sustain the ambiguity between the dream and real world . Rating : 5,5 , passable sequel . It's all acceptable scary fun . The series initiates itself from original entry title &uml;A Nightmare on Elm Elm Street&uml; directed by Wes Craven with Heather Langenkamp , Johnny Depp , Amanda Wyss and John Saxon . The rest is a series of disjointed but however impressive special effects pieces . As it was followed by a handful of sequels in which horrifying special effects dominate this slasher saga , as &uml;Freddy's revenge&uml; 1985 by Jack Sholder with Kim Myers , Clu Gulager and Hope Lange ; &uml;Dream warrior&uml; 1987 by Chuck Russell with Patricia Arquette , Larry Fishburne and Craig Wasson , it's one of the best sequels from successful original film by Craven , as &uml;Dream master&uml; (1988) by Renny Harlin with Lisa Wilcox , Tuesday Knight and &uml;The dream child&uml; (1989) by Stephen Hopkins with Lisa Wilcox , Erika Anderson . Besides a Television series &uml;The Freddy's nightmares&uml; and this last one &uml; A nightmare on Elm Street&uml;(2010) with Jackie Haley that is a simple copy with little imagination , too many flaws and giving routine treatment .
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Why does this have such a high rating???
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    votesmall
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Okay, first of all, let me say that I am not one of those people who doesn't "get" movies if they aren't "edge of your seat". For example, 2001: A Space Odyssey could have been good, but it just was too boring and had no explanation for the monolith and not enough focus on HAL 9000, the freaky antagonist supercomputer. Basically, most of the movie was shots of space with classical music. And everyone tells me that I didn't "get" it. No, I can't get it because there is no explanation, and it's too boring! BUT, I did love Hellraiser: Inferno, and In the Mouth of Madness. So, what's the problem with New Nightmare??? Okay, first of all is the fact of Freddy. I actually love his new look, the jacket and hand, although the sweater and hat looked kind of funny and I didn't understand why they put the greenish-red rings around his eyes. They went to so much work designing this new, evil looking Freddy and he can't have more than 20 minutes of screen time. Yep, just a little bit more than Freddy's Revenge. And yes, I know that Pinhead had just about as much screen time in Hellraiser: Inferno, but they didn't redesign Pinhead in that one. Okay, I do love psychological thrillers, but this was just BORING! It starts off with an all metal, robotic glove coming to life on the film set of a new Nightmare on Elm Street movie. The glove kills several special effects crew members and is about to kill Heather Langenkamp (Nancy)'s husband. And then she wakes up. Okay, that was awesome! Good, frightening, and all a dream. And the next forty five minutes or so have NOTHING going on for the movie! I will admit, the interview scene and the limousine scene were somewhat interesting, but the rest of it was just boring fluff. And also, we get a few decent shots of Robert Englund in this movie, but we don't see near enough! The entire movie revolves around two characters, that just can't carry the film. The kid is just annoying. He isn't creepy, he's just annoying. Some of the dream sequences are pretty freaky, but other than that, he's just a normal kid talking in a stupid voice. Also, the vomit scene was pretty much stolen from The Exorcist. So, by the end of the movie, all of the characters are referring to Heather as Nancy, but this is never explained. And then there is a showdown at the "boiler room", which looks more like an ancient Greek temple than a power plant mechanical room. Okay, this scene was too tacky. And Freddy actually extends his arm to get the kid, tries to "eat him", and wraps his tongue around Heather before burning to death and turning into, get this, the devil.??? I will admit that I liked how it came to the real world, and we do get some pretty decent shots of Wes Craven and Robert Englund, and even a few other stars, but, like Freddy, they just don't have enough screen time. And some of the dream sequences are pretty creepy. But, I have two HUGE problems with this movie. First off, the fact that Heather has to wait until, like an hour and a half (around three days in the movie) after her kid tries to commit suicide, has seizures, nightmares, and tries to kill her before taking him to the hospital. Also, her kid is terrified of nightmares and she shuts the door so he is in the dark! ??? Worst mother ever! And it also isn't about Freddy on a film set, it's about him stalking Heather and her kid for two hours. This movie was so slow paced that it seemed like Titanic. Not to mention a hilariously low body count, with Freddy having a brand new glove, but breaking someone's neck! ??? Judge for yourself, but I thought it was boring. The kid was annoying, there wasn't enough Freddy, and Heather Langenkamp is just not an interesting character, unlike Nancy Thompson. Overall, this film is just TOO slow. I mean, Wes Craven had a really good idea here. Very original, just like the first Nightmare movie. But he didn't execute it very well. The kid was annoying, Heather Langenkamp looks bored and "worried" throughout the movie. And some of the dialogue is just ridiculous. Like how Wes all of a sudden knows what the new Freddy is is kind of ridiculous, because he couldn't possibly know that. Not to mention that in Never Sleep Again, he showed drawings for a "Freddy mobile" that he was going to put in the movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
