<filme>
 <id>
  572
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0109303
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1994
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Contagem Regressiva
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.0
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  An Irish bomber escapes from prison and targets a member of the Boston bomb squad.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Jimmy Dove works for the bomb squad in Boston and he is always the one who is on the tough jobs. One day he decides to quit the force and to become a teacher for the rookies of the squad. A few days later his former partner is killed by a bomb and Jimmy becomes suspicious that maybe this bomb could have been built by a former friend of himself. He begins to investigate and finds out that his worst nightmare has returned from his past.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Action
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Thriller
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   prison
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   irish
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   ireland
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   flashback
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   revenge
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Stephen Hopkins
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   John Rice
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Joe Batteer
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Jeff Bridges
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Tommy Lee Jones
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Suzy Amis
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Catch you at a bad time?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nickelreviews
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I may never hear the end it from people on why I love this movie so much, but it is one of my favorite Hero/Villain movies ever! It was received very poorly both critically and commercially, but I love it! It goes from Ireland to Boston. There's Guinness drinking, explosions, and at least two songs from U2's Joshua Tree Album, used in parts of the film that fit perfectly. You also have father/son Jeff Bridges/Lloyd Bridges starring together as former IRA members. I don't know what draws me so close to this film. Perhaps my fascination with Ireland, curiosity over the years of conflict there, having done my internship there or what? Maybe that I've just always liked Tommy lee Jones and Jeff Bridges. The pair worked well together in Blown Away. I don't care what the critics said, or how well it did at the box office. Reviewed by AN/NR 11-14-11
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bad Accents
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mfrays
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Blown Away" 1994 movie bout a bomb squads in Boston. Sorry but I just saw it for the first time. Bad casting and really bad voice coaching. Tommy Lee Jones is a fine actor, but his Irish accent was way, way off with his Texas drawl. PLEASE. That was embarrassingly pitiful. Then you've got Jeff Bridges with, I don't know, what was that a combo- Irish and Boston Southie accent. Again  really bad to the point of stinking up the entirety of all Boston zip codes. And I really like Jeff, too. But, here's the real kicker - Forest Whitaker with some kind of lame, overdone Southie brogue mixed in with the inevitable ethnicity blended in. Hell, I was in the Marines with black Bostonians and I never heard the likes of that fiasco  never. And finally, poor old Lloyd Bridges. He actually got the best Irish accent, but he went overboard with it and over-emoted it into almost a caricature. I am no expert and I am no authority, but I can hear and both my ears were offended by the lousy accents, over-emotion and probably bad casting in what could have been a really fine movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great Early 90s Action/Cop Drama Flick
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Thom Sirveaux
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An excellent early 90s action/cop drama flick, it has much of the feel of the Tom Clancy films of similar timeframe. Extremely watchable, with good performances from Bridges, Bridges, and Whitaker. Tommy Lee Jones turns out a very sinister character, and conveys the look of who and what his character is supposed to be surprisingly well. A pretty smart film with good internal consistency, it's well worth watching. One minor negative is that there are actions that police characters take that are distinctly inconsistent with how a real PD would operate - those with EMT/law enforcement backgrounds especially may find it breaks suspension of disbelief. This can be explained away by one of the key elements of a main character's story arc, and doesn't detract from the film very much, but may leave you scratching your head if you think too hard about it. Obviously it's a movie, not a documentary, but analyzing the story arc's impact on judgments allows for many of the actions taken by all of the characters to make perfect sense and maintain that good internal consistency. Being vague enough not to spoil anything - if something seems odd, think about why a character does it. Overall, a very solid, enjoyable film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Everybody loves a hero.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jimmy Dove works for the bomb squad in Boston and he is always the one who is on the tough jobs. One day he decides to quit the force and to become a teacher for the rookies of the squad. A few days later his former partner is killed by a bomb and Jimmy becomes suspicious that maybe this bomb could have been built by a former friend of himself. He begins to investigate and finds out that his worst nightmare has returned from his past..... Lee Jones and Brides were very hot in 1994. Jones had just bagged an Oscar, and Bridges was being praised for his turn in Fearless, what could go wrong? A lot, apparently. Saying that this is a cat and mouse game is a little cynical, as the two leads only make contact twice during the movie, but kudos to them for dealing with such a touchy subject matter which is dealt with in the way only Hollywood could.....glam it up!! Bridges is great as the tortured bomb disposal expert, who has a shady past, hanging around in a hot tub with an old 'Oirish' man and being the all American hero, Bridges is a man you can rely on, when a film isn't that great. Jones on the other hand was in the psycho business at this point in his career (Natural Born Killers, Under Siege), so who better to play the bad guy. And while he's having fun, his accent and the way his culture is stated isn't. It's the worse depiction of the accent I have ever heard, makes Brad Pitt sound like on of the Corrs. And the fact that he dances around to U2 and drinks a funny looking Guinness, just adds insult. But given that, the story is pretty good, and the set pieces are astonishing, especially the destruction of the boat. Take away the bad stuff, the accents, and Lloyd Bridges who plays nothing more than a leprechaun, you have a very tight enjoyable action thriller that doesn't trouble the brain. Consider plausibility, and you will find a stinker of a movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unbelievably dumb and clich&eacute;d
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Major Woody
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We were perusing the On Demand list, and saw this title, with Jeff & Lloyd Bridges, Tommy Lee Jones, and Forest Whitaker, and thought it sounded like a great movie. I should have been forewarned when I didn't recall ever having heard of it before. The opening segment in the prison, where the inmates speak Gaelic ( I believe) and is subtitled, allowed for a bit of confusion when Jones dispatches his cell mate, and says something over his body. Even with repeated viewings, none of us could make out what exactly he says, or even if it's in English. Was the murder done for a reason besides needing a bomb bunker, or was there a back story? Then to watch him assemble his bomb, using all kinds of devices including machine-threaded pipes, explosives, and other unusual items hat would seem to be a bit difficult to accrue in a max security prison, he blows a hole in the wall, and apparently makes his way from that desolate area without any problems, although they don't bother to show how. He next appears in Boston, living in a decrepit, rusty old boat on an abandoned pier, which miraculously not only has electricity, but also has cable TV ( as the orchestra promo mentions that it's on A&E, not an over the air channel). He also has unlimited funds to obtain everything he needs, from explosives, to electronics, to transportation to get around the Boston area. Bridges character, as we soon find out, is also a fugitive IRA guy, wanted by Interpol, yet he apparently had no problem getting past the Boston PD's background check to get hired under his phony identity. He also exhibits almost every Hollywood clich&eacute; about the maverick cop, riding a m/c to a bomb scene while smoking a butt and wearing a Hawaiian shirt to let us know how cool he is. He also ignores basic safety procedures while disarming bombs, even though he is supposedly the one who instructs everyone on EOD protocol. Jones also exhibits the troubling Hollywood syndrome of being able to single handedly surveill multiple people and locate their homes, even their vacation homes, and also gain employment with Boston PD as a janitor ( once again, bypassing the pesky background checks a large agency like BPD conducts even for civilians) with not a care in the world. They also never bothered to explain how Jones was able to get Lloyd Bridges from the bar bathroom out the door, and to the school yard , where he was able to secure him with an unbelievably complex device, without a single person noticing. Then of course there is the TV screen continuously showing Bridges wife in closeup even though she is just one person in the Boston Pops. The story just kept getting more and more ludicrous, and of course there had to be the obligatory Hollywood fight where the bad guy is almost indestructible, no matter what he is hit with. If you come across this, keep on going, it was 2 hours that I'll never get back. I can only imagine that the Dude and the rest were in a slump and needed a quick payday, without regards to the script. The only reason I gave it 2 stars was for the Boston scenery.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Block Buster Sizzler
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    merylmatt
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jeff Bridges was OK in this movie, but Tommy Lee Jones took it way over the top in his role as an IRA terror bomber. It became silly after awhile. The characters were two dimensional, stereotyped and clich&eacute;d. Jeff has a past that haunts him, a job he is addicted to but wants to get out of. Oh, I did not like the nepotism of having Lyold Bridges (Jeff's real life dad) play a cameo. Boston Irish cops drinking, there's a twist. Hollywood block busters or pop corn movies are big on explosions and short on credibility. The rube Goldberg bomb device at the end was beyond disbelief and I have a pretty good suspension of disbelief. And let's add one more clich&eacute; into the mix, just in case you have not had your fill the U-2 songs played as back drops. One star for Jeff Bridges, one for Forrest Whitaker. It's not their fault the script was terrible and predictable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Tommy Lee Jone Gives Oscar Worthy Performance.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vivekmaru45
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For Tommy Lee Jones fans only. This IS the movie that he will be remembered for. I have seen many of his films: The Fugitive, Double Jeopardy, U.S. Marshall's, The Missing, The Hunted, Men In Black 1 & 2, Space Cowboys, Volcano, Batman Forever, Natural Born Killers, In The Valley Of Elah, No Country For Old Man, The Client, Eyes of Laura Mars. *Jones got an Oscar for best supporting actor in The Fugitive. *Jones was also nominated for MTV Movie Awards Best Villain for Blown Away and Batman Forever. The role seems to fit him like a glove. The character he portrays in the film is of an arrogant, dangerous and an untrustworthy person with a one-track mind and a keen eye for revenge. That is the character of Ryan Gaerity, an Irish terrorist imprisoned in Castle Gleigh prison in Northern Ireland. He makes a daring escape to seek vengeance against Liam McGivney, a member of Ryan's original group which also consisted of Ryan's sister who was also Liam's girlfriend. Liam had foiled a plan to bomb some targets chosen be Ryan. As a result he was quickly arrested by the Police and imprisoned for life. Ryan comes to Boston to seek vengeance against Liam, who is semi-retired but working as an instructor with a new identity: Jimmy Dove. Ryan begins taunting his old comrade with threats and his homemade explosives. With his family and friends in danger, he reveals his secret to his wife Kate (Suzy Amis). He returns to action to hunt for Ryan when a former partner of his is killed by one of Ryan's bombs. Fellow officer Anthony Franklin (Forest Whitaker) investigates Jimmy, suspecting a connection between the two. See this superb film directed by Stephen Hopkins (Predator 2, The Ghost And The Darkness) to find out what happens next. Overall the special effects are fantastic, the background music is excellent, script, direction and acting are professionally done. Score 10/10. Flawless film. Buy it on DVD. Similar films: Speed, The Specialist, Executive Decision, The Mechanic, Juggernaut. Email me Vivekmaru45@yahoo.com for info one more movies. Thanks for reading.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the worst Hollywood action thrillers out there.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Paul Andrews (poolandrews@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Blown Away starts at Castle Gleigh Prison in Nothern Ireland as convicted terrorist bomber Ryan Gaerity (Tommy Lee Jones) escapes using his explosive know how. Jumpt to Boston in the US where bomb squad member Jimmy Dove (Jeff Bridges) has decided to retire & new recruit Anthony Franklin (Forest Whitaker) is set to take his place alongside Jimmy's old partner Blanket (Ruben Santiago-Hudson), on their first job Blanket is killed by a booby trapped explosive which forces Jimmy out of retirement. Soon it gets personal for Jimmy as he discovers that his old terrorist mate from Ireland Ryan is behind a series of bombings & he is out for revenge against Jimmy, his family & friends as it was Jimmy who put Ryan behind bars in Ireland all those years ago... Directed by Stephen Hopkins this is actually the second Hopkins directed film I have seen in the past twenty four hours after also seeing The Reaping (2007) yesterday, it wasn't planned & it was a co-incidence & pretty lousy luck as The Reaping was average & this was plain crap. At two hours long Blown Away is very slow going & apart from the last fifteen or so minutes is really dull, lifeless, bland & dare I say it even boring. The melodramatics between Jimmy & his family are unintentionally funny (the scene when his wife jumps in the jacuzzi to shout at Jimmy is pure comedy) while the hero with a dark past role just doesn't suit Bridges, his confrontations with Tommy Lee Jones are awful as it seems to be a contest between the both of them to discover who can do the worst Irish accent. The plot is extremely predictable, routine & by the numbers as the clich&eacute;d tough guy hero with a dark past has to save the day on his own playing by his own rules, any number of better action films use this scenario & add that to a script that offers no surprises (good guy wins in the end, bad guy is stopped) & feels like little or no effort has gone into it. For a big budget action thriller Blown Away is really short on action or thrills, there's a decent explosion at the end, a truck is blown up & there's a speeding jeep & that's it. For a two hour film not enough happens. Footage from Blown Away was edited into two low budget action films called Stealth Fighter (1999) & Agent Red (2000). The Boston locations don't add anything to the film at all to be honest. Apparently the shockwave from the ship explosion at the end shattered 8000 windows in East Boston. If you really want to see an exciting action thriller about bombs then watch Speed (1994) again instead & see how a proper action film should be done. This has decent production values & is well made for what it is but it's still a rubbish film. The acting is poor from a good cast, father & son Jeff & Lloyd Bridges appear here together. Blown Away is a poor action thriller with virtually no action & some poor performances from a decent cast, this is just bad all round really & far too predictable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Totally Blown Away....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Stephen Hopkins 1994 action-packed thriller 'Blown Away' easily ranks amongst the better films from that year. It has a crispy script, fantastic action, superb performances and stylish direction. In short, A winner all the way. 'Blown Away' is a revenge saga about 2 individuals. One believes in violence, while the other keeps away from violence. Hopkins body of work is truly admirable, his direction in here is simply spell-binding. 'Blown Away' has a terrific start, a good middle and an excellent end. This film promises entertainment, and it serves it in abundance. In performances, Jeff Bridges steals the show with a winning performance. He breathes fire in all of his dramatic scenes. Tommy Lee Jones is fantastic as the calculative/conniving villain. He crates a terror in you, without making morbid faces. The Late Lloyd Bridges is lovable. Suzy Amis is very good. In fact, this is her careers best work. Forest Whitaker is excellent from start to end. 'Blown Away' is simply an amazing watch. Two Thumbs Up!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beautifully Showy AND So American !
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ahmed elshikh (ahmed_abd_elreheem@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/10/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's Hollywood. With the good and bad senses of the word. Aside from objection I hold against its standpoint, this is an entertaining movie. In the mid-90s there were many American blockbusters with a plot centers on one bomber and consecutive bombs such as : Speed, The Specialist, Blown Away (all produced in 1994), then Die Hard with a Vengeance (1995). Blown Away stands as one of their best. First it's in the direction. (Stephen Hopkins) is the star of the show. Other work for him like The Ghost and the Darkness (1996), Under Suspicion (2000) got my attention by their clever and charming technique. (Hopkins) here makes every moment thrilling and, thank god, not in a hyped way. The picture was never brighter with an explosion before. Just remember the shot in which the lead takes the bad guy out of the last's cache near the ocean; this "live" piece of action was historically dazzling. In one word : it's showiness as it should be. The script delivers : action, thrill, and hot duel. But nothing is perfect. As I wasn't convinced with matters like a forced nagging (Forest Whitaker); it should have been better as justified enemy turns-into justified friend character. Or how the father (Lloyd Bridges) finds the bad guy (Tommy Lee Jones) plainly and illogically. Plus non-understandable matter like seeing (Jones) crying over killing (Lloyd Bridges) ! (Does he originally love and respect the man? Does he blame himself for killing one of his own people ? Does he hate to murder innocent people ????? I don't know, and I won't know at all !). Let alone the Hollywood clich&eacute;s about the IRA (The Provisional Irish Republican Army) that were so prevalent before the 1998 Belfast agreement. The same you can find in Patriot Games (1992) where the IRA's men are always unmerciful, nearly crazy, assassins. They love to blow up everything and everyone. And their best are the ones whom went to America and stayed there as peaceful citizens ! It could be Hollywood's style of categorizing everyone to only bad guy/good guy, or it's Hollywood's big companies' faith about the IRA, or maybe both ! However you can touch this movie's desire to ignore any political duel by showing the Irish man this time as a maniac who is rejected by the IRA itself, finding a warrant for him to be evil, and turning the whole matter into just another revenge story. Though, why relating him to the IRA from the start ?! It's obvious point of view about anyone who's not American or supporting the American policy, especially when the movie shows information about Palestinians as terrorists the evil man worked with them once. It's sorrowfully typical. Since Hollywood, here, means being illiberal American; namely non-objective (Well, for little instance the Israelis used to kill unarmed men, women and children since ages and I've never seen them as terrorists in one mainstream American movie yet !?). While the 2 leads were cogent and intensive, just casting (Whitaker) was weird. I mean aside from mixed up performance came mainly from weak characterization, he's the last Irish in the world, too heavy to be in a bomb squad, and I don't catch on how they cast him repeatedly as a police officer with the obvious condition of his eye ??! No police officer can make it to be one with that I suppose ! It got madly stimulating Alan Silvestri's soundtrack, unforgettable (Peter Levy)'s cinematography, and masterfully thrilling (Tim Wellburn)'s editing. Enough to remember the climactic sequence in the car. I don't know how this movie wasn't a hit back then. But sure it hits its mark very well. Hollywood movies lately were about abstract explosions and exhausting excitement, with one cliffhanger after another, and non-stop in-the-nick-of-time rescues. (Blown Away) personifies that in iconic way. And even its stereotypes apply to that, since stereotyping became  along the years  part of the show's original formula. The bad, semi-lasting, part.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Catch you at a bad time?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nickelreviews
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I may never hear the end it from people on why I love this movie so much, but it is one of my favorite Hero/Villain movies ever! It was received very poorly both critically and commercially, but I love it! It goes from Ireland to Boston. There's Guinness drinking, explosions, and at least two songs from U2's Joshua Tree Album, used in parts of the film that fit perfectly. You also have father/son Jeff Bridges/Lloyd Bridges starring together as former IRA members. I don't know what draws me so close to this film. Perhaps my fascination with Ireland, curiosity over the years of conflict there, having done my internship there or what? Maybe that I've just always liked Tommy lee Jones and Jeff Bridges. The pair worked well together in Blown Away. I don't care what the critics said, or how well it did at the box office. Reviewed by AN/NR 11-14-11
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bad Accents
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mfrays
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Blown Away" 1994 movie bout a bomb squads in Boston. Sorry but I just saw it for the first time. Bad casting and really bad voice coaching. Tommy Lee Jones is a fine actor, but his Irish accent was way, way off with his Texas drawl. PLEASE. That was embarrassingly pitiful. Then you've got Jeff Bridges with, I don't know, what was that a combo- Irish and Boston Southie accent. Again  really bad to the point of stinking up the entirety of all Boston zip codes. And I really like Jeff, too. But, here's the real kicker - Forest Whitaker with some kind of lame, overdone Southie brogue mixed in with the inevitable ethnicity blended in. Hell, I was in the Marines with black Bostonians and I never heard the likes of that fiasco  never. And finally, poor old Lloyd Bridges. He actually got the best Irish accent, but he went overboard with it and over-emoted it into almost a caricature. I am no expert and I am no authority, but I can hear and both my ears were offended by the lousy accents, over-emotion and probably bad casting in what could have been a really fine movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great Early 90s Action/Cop Drama Flick
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Thom Sirveaux
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An excellent early 90s action/cop drama flick, it has much of the feel of the Tom Clancy films of similar timeframe. Extremely watchable, with good performances from Bridges, Bridges, and Whitaker. Tommy Lee Jones turns out a very sinister character, and conveys the look of who and what his character is supposed to be surprisingly well. A pretty smart film with good internal consistency, it's well worth watching. One minor negative is that there are actions that police characters take that are distinctly inconsistent with how a real PD would operate - those with EMT/law enforcement backgrounds especially may find it breaks suspension of disbelief. This can be explained away by one of the key elements of a main character's story arc, and doesn't detract from the film very much, but may leave you scratching your head if you think too hard about it. Obviously it's a movie, not a documentary, but analyzing the story arc's impact on judgments allows for many of the actions taken by all of the characters to make perfect sense and maintain that good internal consistency. Being vague enough not to spoil anything - if something seems odd, think about why a character does it. Overall, a very solid, enjoyable film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Everybody loves a hero.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jimmy Dove works for the bomb squad in Boston and he is always the one who is on the tough jobs. One day he decides to quit the force and to become a teacher for the rookies of the squad. A few days later his former partner is killed by a bomb and Jimmy becomes suspicious that maybe this bomb could have been built by a former friend of himself. He begins to investigate and finds out that his worst nightmare has returned from his past..... Lee Jones and Brides were very hot in 1994. Jones had just bagged an Oscar, and Bridges was being praised for his turn in Fearless, what could go wrong? A lot, apparently. Saying that this is a cat and mouse game is a little cynical, as the two leads only make contact twice during the movie, but kudos to them for dealing with such a touchy subject matter which is dealt with in the way only Hollywood could.....glam it up!! Bridges is great as the tortured bomb disposal expert, who has a shady past, hanging around in a hot tub with an old 'Oirish' man and being the all American hero, Bridges is a man you can rely on, when a film isn't that great. Jones on the other hand was in the psycho business at this point in his career (Natural Born Killers, Under Siege), so who better to play the bad guy. And while he's having fun, his accent and the way his culture is stated isn't. It's the worse depiction of the accent I have ever heard, makes Brad Pitt sound like on of the Corrs. And the fact that he dances around to U2 and drinks a funny looking Guinness, just adds insult. But given that, the story is pretty good, and the set pieces are astonishing, especially the destruction of the boat. Take away the bad stuff, the accents, and Lloyd Bridges who plays nothing more than a leprechaun, you have a very tight enjoyable action thriller that doesn't trouble the brain. Consider plausibility, and you will find a stinker of a movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unbelievably dumb and clich&eacute;d
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Major Woody
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We were perusing the On Demand list, and saw this title, with Jeff & Lloyd Bridges, Tommy Lee Jones, and Forest Whitaker, and thought it sounded like a great movie. I should have been forewarned when I didn't recall ever having heard of it before. The opening segment in the prison, where the inmates speak Gaelic ( I believe) and is subtitled, allowed for a bit of confusion when Jones dispatches his cell mate, and says something over his body. Even with repeated viewings, none of us could make out what exactly he says, or even if it's in English. Was the murder done for a reason besides needing a bomb bunker, or was there a back story? Then to watch him assemble his bomb, using all kinds of devices including machine-threaded pipes, explosives, and other unusual items hat would seem to be a bit difficult to accrue in a max security prison, he blows a hole in the wall, and apparently makes his way from that desolate area without any problems, although they don't bother to show how. He next appears in Boston, living in a decrepit, rusty old boat on an abandoned pier, which miraculously not only has electricity, but also has cable TV ( as the orchestra promo mentions that it's on A&E, not an over the air channel). He also has unlimited funds to obtain everything he needs, from explosives, to electronics, to transportation to get around the Boston area. Bridges character, as we soon find out, is also a fugitive IRA guy, wanted by Interpol, yet he apparently had no problem getting past the Boston PD's background check to get hired under his phony identity. He also exhibits almost every Hollywood clich&eacute; about the maverick cop, riding a m/c to a bomb scene while smoking a butt and wearing a Hawaiian shirt to let us know how cool he is. He also ignores basic safety procedures while disarming bombs, even though he is supposedly the one who instructs everyone on EOD protocol. Jones also exhibits the troubling Hollywood syndrome of being able to single handedly surveill multiple people and locate their homes, even their vacation homes, and also gain employment with Boston PD as a janitor ( once again, bypassing the pesky background checks a large agency like BPD conducts even for civilians) with not a care in the world. They also never bothered to explain how Jones was able to get Lloyd Bridges from the bar bathroom out the door, and to the school yard , where he was able to secure him with an unbelievably complex device, without a single person noticing. Then of course there is the TV screen continuously showing Bridges wife in closeup even though she is just one person in the Boston Pops. The story just kept getting more and more ludicrous, and of course there had to be the obligatory Hollywood fight where the bad guy is almost indestructible, no matter what he is hit with. If you come across this, keep on going, it was 2 hours that I'll never get back. I can only imagine that the Dude and the rest were in a slump and needed a quick payday, without regards to the script. The only reason I gave it 2 stars was for the Boston scenery.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Block Buster Sizzler
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    merylmatt
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jeff Bridges was OK in this movie, but Tommy Lee Jones took it way over the top in his role as an IRA terror bomber. It became silly after awhile. The characters were two dimensional, stereotyped and clich&eacute;d. Jeff has a past that haunts him, a job he is addicted to but wants to get out of. Oh, I did not like the nepotism of having Lyold Bridges (Jeff's real life dad) play a cameo. Boston Irish cops drinking, there's a twist. Hollywood block busters or pop corn movies are big on explosions and short on credibility. The rube Goldberg bomb device at the end was beyond disbelief and I have a pretty good suspension of disbelief. And let's add one more clich&eacute; into the mix, just in case you have not had your fill the U-2 songs played as back drops. One star for Jeff Bridges, one for Forrest Whitaker. It's not their fault the script was terrible and predictable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Tommy Lee Jone Gives Oscar Worthy Performance.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vivekmaru45
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For Tommy Lee Jones fans only. This IS the movie that he will be remembered for. I have seen many of his films: The Fugitive, Double Jeopardy, U.S. Marshall's, The Missing, The Hunted, Men In Black 1 & 2, Space Cowboys, Volcano, Batman Forever, Natural Born Killers, In The Valley Of Elah, No Country For Old Man, The Client, Eyes of Laura Mars. *Jones got an Oscar for best supporting actor in The Fugitive. *Jones was also nominated for MTV Movie Awards Best Villain for Blown Away and Batman Forever. The role seems to fit him like a glove. The character he portrays in the film is of an arrogant, dangerous and an untrustworthy person with a one-track mind and a keen eye for revenge. That is the character of Ryan Gaerity, an Irish terrorist imprisoned in Castle Gleigh prison in Northern Ireland. He makes a daring escape to seek vengeance against Liam McGivney, a member of Ryan's original group which also consisted of Ryan's sister who was also Liam's girlfriend. Liam had foiled a plan to bomb some targets chosen be Ryan. As a result he was quickly arrested by the Police and imprisoned for life. Ryan comes to Boston to seek vengeance against Liam, who is semi-retired but working as an instructor with a new identity: Jimmy Dove. Ryan begins taunting his old comrade with threats and his homemade explosives. With his family and friends in danger, he reveals his secret to his wife Kate (Suzy Amis). He returns to action to hunt for Ryan when a former partner of his is killed by one of Ryan's bombs. Fellow officer Anthony Franklin (Forest Whitaker) investigates Jimmy, suspecting a connection between the two. See this superb film directed by Stephen Hopkins (Predator 2, The Ghost And The Darkness) to find out what happens next. Overall the special effects are fantastic, the background music is excellent, script, direction and acting are professionally done. Score 10/10. Flawless film. Buy it on DVD. Similar films: Speed, The Specialist, Executive Decision, The Mechanic, Juggernaut. Email me Vivekmaru45@yahoo.com for info one more movies. Thanks for reading.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the worst Hollywood action thrillers out there.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Paul Andrews (poolandrews@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Blown Away starts at Castle Gleigh Prison in Nothern Ireland as convicted terrorist bomber Ryan Gaerity (Tommy Lee Jones) escapes using his explosive know how. Jumpt to Boston in the US where bomb squad member Jimmy Dove (Jeff Bridges) has decided to retire & new recruit Anthony Franklin (Forest Whitaker) is set to take his place alongside Jimmy's old partner Blanket (Ruben Santiago-Hudson), on their first job Blanket is killed by a booby trapped explosive which forces Jimmy out of retirement. Soon it gets personal for Jimmy as he discovers that his old terrorist mate from Ireland Ryan is behind a series of bombings & he is out for revenge against Jimmy, his family & friends as it was Jimmy who put Ryan behind bars in Ireland all those years ago... Directed by Stephen Hopkins this is actually the second Hopkins directed film I have seen in the past twenty four hours after also seeing The Reaping (2007) yesterday, it wasn't planned & it was a co-incidence & pretty lousy luck as The Reaping was average & this was plain crap. At two hours long Blown Away is very slow going & apart from the last fifteen or so minutes is really dull, lifeless, bland & dare I say it even boring. The melodramatics between Jimmy & his family are unintentionally funny (the scene when his wife jumps in the jacuzzi to shout at Jimmy is pure comedy) while the hero with a dark past role just doesn't suit Bridges, his confrontations with Tommy Lee Jones are awful as it seems to be a contest between the both of them to discover who can do the worst Irish accent. The plot is extremely predictable, routine & by the numbers as the clich&eacute;d tough guy hero with a dark past has to save the day on his own playing by his own rules, any number of better action films use this scenario & add that to a script that offers no surprises (good guy wins in the end, bad guy is stopped) & feels like little or no effort has gone into it. For a big budget action thriller Blown Away is really short on action or thrills, there's a decent explosion at the end, a truck is blown up & there's a speeding jeep & that's it. For a two hour film not enough happens. Footage from Blown Away was edited into two low budget action films called Stealth Fighter (1999) & Agent Red (2000). The Boston locations don't add anything to the film at all to be honest. Apparently the shockwave from the ship explosion at the end shattered 8000 windows in East Boston. If you really want to see an exciting action thriller about bombs then watch Speed (1994) again instead & see how a proper action film should be done. This has decent production values & is well made for what it is but it's still a rubbish film. The acting is poor from a good cast, father & son Jeff & Lloyd Bridges appear here together. Blown Away is a poor action thriller with virtually no action & some poor performances from a decent cast, this is just bad all round really & far too predictable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Totally Blown Away....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Stephen Hopkins 1994 action-packed thriller 'Blown Away' easily ranks amongst the better films from that year. It has a crispy script, fantastic action, superb performances and stylish direction. In short, A winner all the way. 'Blown Away' is a revenge saga about 2 individuals. One believes in violence, while the other keeps away from violence. Hopkins body of work is truly admirable, his direction in here is simply spell-binding. 'Blown Away' has a terrific start, a good middle and an excellent end. This film promises entertainment, and it serves it in abundance. In performances, Jeff Bridges steals the show with a winning performance. He breathes fire in all of his dramatic scenes. Tommy Lee Jones is fantastic as the calculative/conniving villain. He crates a terror in you, without making morbid faces. The Late Lloyd Bridges is lovable. Suzy Amis is very good. In fact, this is her careers best work. Forest Whitaker is excellent from start to end. 'Blown Away' is simply an amazing watch. Two Thumbs Up!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beautifully Showy AND So American !
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ahmed elshikh (ahmed_abd_elreheem@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/10/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's Hollywood. With the good and bad senses of the word. Aside from objection I hold against its standpoint, this is an entertaining movie. In the mid-90s there were many American blockbusters with a plot centers on one bomber and consecutive bombs such as : Speed, The Specialist, Blown Away (all produced in 1994), then Die Hard with a Vengeance (1995). Blown Away stands as one of their best. First it's in the direction. (Stephen Hopkins) is the star of the show. Other work for him like The Ghost and the Darkness (1996), Under Suspicion (2000) got my attention by their clever and charming technique. (Hopkins) here makes every moment thrilling and, thank god, not in a hyped way. The picture was never brighter with an explosion before. Just remember the shot in which the lead takes the bad guy out of the last's cache near the ocean; this "live" piece of action was historically dazzling. In one word : it's showiness as it should be. The script delivers : action, thrill, and hot duel. But nothing is perfect. As I wasn't convinced with matters like a forced nagging (Forest Whitaker); it should have been better as justified enemy turns-into justified friend character. Or how the father (Lloyd Bridges) finds the bad guy (Tommy Lee Jones) plainly and illogically. Plus non-understandable matter like seeing (Jones) crying over killing (Lloyd Bridges) ! (Does he originally love and respect the man? Does he blame himself for killing one of his own people ? Does he hate to murder innocent people ????? I don't know, and I won't know at all !). Let alone the Hollywood clich&eacute;s about the IRA (The Provisional Irish Republican Army) that were so prevalent before the 1998 Belfast agreement. The same you can find in Patriot Games (1992) where the IRA's men are always unmerciful, nearly crazy, assassins. They love to blow up everything and everyone. And their best are the ones whom went to America and stayed there as peaceful citizens ! It could be Hollywood's style of categorizing everyone to only bad guy/good guy, or it's Hollywood's big companies' faith about the IRA, or maybe both ! However you can touch this movie's desire to ignore any political duel by showing the Irish man this time as a maniac who is rejected by the IRA itself, finding a warrant for him to be evil, and turning the whole matter into just another revenge story. Though, why relating him to the IRA from the start ?! It's obvious point of view about anyone who's not American or supporting the American policy, especially when the movie shows information about Palestinians as terrorists the evil man worked with them once. It's sorrowfully typical. Since Hollywood, here, means being illiberal American; namely non-objective (Well, for little instance the Israelis used to kill unarmed men, women and children since ages and I've never seen them as terrorists in one mainstream American movie yet !?). While the 2 leads were cogent and intensive, just casting (Whitaker) was weird. I mean aside from mixed up performance came mainly from weak characterization, he's the last Irish in the world, too heavy to be in a bomb squad, and I don't catch on how they cast him repeatedly as a police officer with the obvious condition of his eye ??! No police officer can make it to be one with that I suppose ! It got madly stimulating Alan Silvestri's soundtrack, unforgettable (Peter Levy)'s cinematography, and masterfully thrilling (Tim Wellburn)'s editing. Enough to remember the climactic sequence in the car. I don't know how this movie wasn't a hit back then. But sure it hits its mark very well. Hollywood movies lately were about abstract explosions and exhausting excitement, with one cliffhanger after another, and non-stop in-the-nick-of-time rescues. (Blown Away) personifies that in iconic way. And even its stereotypes apply to that, since stereotyping became  along the years  part of the show's original formula. The bad, semi-lasting, part.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Catch you at a bad time?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nickelreviews
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I may never hear the end it from people on why I love this movie so much, but it is one of my favorite Hero/Villain movies ever! It was received very poorly both critically and commercially, but I love it! It goes from Ireland to Boston. There's Guinness drinking, explosions, and at least two songs from U2's Joshua Tree Album, used in parts of the film that fit perfectly. You also have father/son Jeff Bridges/Lloyd Bridges starring together as former IRA members. I don't know what draws me so close to this film. Perhaps my fascination with Ireland, curiosity over the years of conflict there, having done my internship there or what? Maybe that I've just always liked Tommy lee Jones and Jeff Bridges. The pair worked well together in Blown Away. I don't care what the critics said, or how well it did at the box office. Reviewed by AN/NR 11-14-11
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bad Accents
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mfrays
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Blown Away" 1994 movie bout a bomb squads in Boston. Sorry but I just saw it for the first time. Bad casting and really bad voice coaching. Tommy Lee Jones is a fine actor, but his Irish accent was way, way off with his Texas drawl. PLEASE. That was embarrassingly pitiful. Then you've got Jeff Bridges with, I don't know, what was that a combo- Irish and Boston Southie accent. Again  really bad to the point of stinking up the entirety of all Boston zip codes. And I really like Jeff, too. But, here's the real kicker - Forest Whitaker with some kind of lame, overdone Southie brogue mixed in with the inevitable ethnicity blended in. Hell, I was in the Marines with black Bostonians and I never heard the likes of that fiasco  never. And finally, poor old Lloyd Bridges. He actually got the best Irish accent, but he went overboard with it and over-emoted it into almost a caricature. I am no expert and I am no authority, but I can hear and both my ears were offended by the lousy accents, over-emotion and probably bad casting in what could have been a really fine movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great Early 90s Action/Cop Drama Flick
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Thom Sirveaux
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An excellent early 90s action/cop drama flick, it has much of the feel of the Tom Clancy films of similar timeframe. Extremely watchable, with good performances from Bridges, Bridges, and Whitaker. Tommy Lee Jones turns out a very sinister character, and conveys the look of who and what his character is supposed to be surprisingly well. A pretty smart film with good internal consistency, it's well worth watching. One minor negative is that there are actions that police characters take that are distinctly inconsistent with how a real PD would operate - those with EMT/law enforcement backgrounds especially may find it breaks suspension of disbelief. This can be explained away by one of the key elements of a main character's story arc, and doesn't detract from the film very much, but may leave you scratching your head if you think too hard about it. Obviously it's a movie, not a documentary, but analyzing the story arc's impact on judgments allows for many of the actions taken by all of the characters to make perfect sense and maintain that good internal consistency. Being vague enough not to spoil anything - if something seems odd, think about why a character does it. Overall, a very solid, enjoyable film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Everybody loves a hero.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jimmy Dove works for the bomb squad in Boston and he is always the one who is on the tough jobs. One day he decides to quit the force and to become a teacher for the rookies of the squad. A few days later his former partner is killed by a bomb and Jimmy becomes suspicious that maybe this bomb could have been built by a former friend of himself. He begins to investigate and finds out that his worst nightmare has returned from his past..... Lee Jones and Brides were very hot in 1994. Jones had just bagged an Oscar, and Bridges was being praised for his turn in Fearless, what could go wrong? A lot, apparently. Saying that this is a cat and mouse game is a little cynical, as the two leads only make contact twice during the movie, but kudos to them for dealing with such a touchy subject matter which is dealt with in the way only Hollywood could.....glam it up!! Bridges is great as the tortured bomb disposal expert, who has a shady past, hanging around in a hot tub with an old 'Oirish' man and being the all American hero, Bridges is a man you can rely on, when a film isn't that great. Jones on the other hand was in the psycho business at this point in his career (Natural Born Killers, Under Siege), so who better to play the bad guy. And while he's having fun, his accent and the way his culture is stated isn't. It's the worse depiction of the accent I have ever heard, makes Brad Pitt sound like on of the Corrs. And the fact that he dances around to U2 and drinks a funny looking Guinness, just adds insult. But given that, the story is pretty good, and the set pieces are astonishing, especially the destruction of the boat. Take away the bad stuff, the accents, and Lloyd Bridges who plays nothing more than a leprechaun, you have a very tight enjoyable action thriller that doesn't trouble the brain. Consider plausibility, and you will find a stinker of a movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unbelievably dumb and clich&eacute;d
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Major Woody
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We were perusing the On Demand list, and saw this title, with Jeff & Lloyd Bridges, Tommy Lee Jones, and Forest Whitaker, and thought it sounded like a great movie. I should have been forewarned when I didn't recall ever having heard of it before. The opening segment in the prison, where the inmates speak Gaelic ( I believe) and is subtitled, allowed for a bit of confusion when Jones dispatches his cell mate, and says something over his body. Even with repeated viewings, none of us could make out what exactly he says, or even if it's in English. Was the murder done for a reason besides needing a bomb bunker, or was there a back story? Then to watch him assemble his bomb, using all kinds of devices including machine-threaded pipes, explosives, and other unusual items hat would seem to be a bit difficult to accrue in a max security prison, he blows a hole in the wall, and apparently makes his way from that desolate area without any problems, although they don't bother to show how. He next appears in Boston, living in a decrepit, rusty old boat on an abandoned pier, which miraculously not only has electricity, but also has cable TV ( as the orchestra promo mentions that it's on A&E, not an over the air channel). He also has unlimited funds to obtain everything he needs, from explosives, to electronics, to transportation to get around the Boston area. Bridges character, as we soon find out, is also a fugitive IRA guy, wanted by Interpol, yet he apparently had no problem getting past the Boston PD's background check to get hired under his phony identity. He also exhibits almost every Hollywood clich&eacute; about the maverick cop, riding a m/c to a bomb scene while smoking a butt and wearing a Hawaiian shirt to let us know how cool he is. He also ignores basic safety procedures while disarming bombs, even though he is supposedly the one who instructs everyone on EOD protocol. Jones also exhibits the troubling Hollywood syndrome of being able to single handedly surveill multiple people and locate their homes, even their vacation homes, and also gain employment with Boston PD as a janitor ( once again, bypassing the pesky background checks a large agency like BPD conducts even for civilians) with not a care in the world. They also never bothered to explain how Jones was able to get Lloyd Bridges from the bar bathroom out the door, and to the school yard , where he was able to secure him with an unbelievably complex device, without a single person noticing. Then of course there is the TV screen continuously showing Bridges wife in closeup even though she is just one person in the Boston Pops. The story just kept getting more and more ludicrous, and of course there had to be the obligatory Hollywood fight where the bad guy is almost indestructible, no matter what he is hit with. If you come across this, keep on going, it was 2 hours that I'll never get back. I can only imagine that the Dude and the rest were in a slump and needed a quick payday, without regards to the script. The only reason I gave it 2 stars was for the Boston scenery.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Block Buster Sizzler
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    merylmatt
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jeff Bridges was OK in this movie, but Tommy Lee Jones took it way over the top in his role as an IRA terror bomber. It became silly after awhile. The characters were two dimensional, stereotyped and clich&eacute;d. Jeff has a past that haunts him, a job he is addicted to but wants to get out of. Oh, I did not like the nepotism of having Lyold Bridges (Jeff's real life dad) play a cameo. Boston Irish cops drinking, there's a twist. Hollywood block busters or pop corn movies are big on explosions and short on credibility. The rube Goldberg bomb device at the end was beyond disbelief and I have a pretty good suspension of disbelief. And let's add one more clich&eacute; into the mix, just in case you have not had your fill the U-2 songs played as back drops. One star for Jeff Bridges, one for Forrest Whitaker. It's not their fault the script was terrible and predictable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Tommy Lee Jone Gives Oscar Worthy Performance.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vivekmaru45
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For Tommy Lee Jones fans only. This IS the movie that he will be remembered for. I have seen many of his films: The Fugitive, Double Jeopardy, U.S. Marshall's, The Missing, The Hunted, Men In Black 1 & 2, Space Cowboys, Volcano, Batman Forever, Natural Born Killers, In The Valley Of Elah, No Country For Old Man, The Client, Eyes of Laura Mars. *Jones got an Oscar for best supporting actor in The Fugitive. *Jones was also nominated for MTV Movie Awards Best Villain for Blown Away and Batman Forever. The role seems to fit him like a glove. The character he portrays in the film is of an arrogant, dangerous and an untrustworthy person with a one-track mind and a keen eye for revenge. That is the character of Ryan Gaerity, an Irish terrorist imprisoned in Castle Gleigh prison in Northern Ireland. He makes a daring escape to seek vengeance against Liam McGivney, a member of Ryan's original group which also consisted of Ryan's sister who was also Liam's girlfriend. Liam had foiled a plan to bomb some targets chosen be Ryan. As a result he was quickly arrested by the Police and imprisoned for life. Ryan comes to Boston to seek vengeance against Liam, who is semi-retired but working as an instructor with a new identity: Jimmy Dove. Ryan begins taunting his old comrade with threats and his homemade explosives. With his family and friends in danger, he reveals his secret to his wife Kate (Suzy Amis). He returns to action to hunt for Ryan when a former partner of his is killed by one of Ryan's bombs. Fellow officer Anthony Franklin (Forest Whitaker) investigates Jimmy, suspecting a connection between the two. See this superb film directed by Stephen Hopkins (Predator 2, The Ghost And The Darkness) to find out what happens next. Overall the special effects are fantastic, the background music is excellent, script, direction and acting are professionally done. Score 10/10. Flawless film. Buy it on DVD. Similar films: Speed, The Specialist, Executive Decision, The Mechanic, Juggernaut. Email me Vivekmaru45@yahoo.com for info one more movies. Thanks for reading.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the worst Hollywood action thrillers out there.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Paul Andrews (poolandrews@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Blown Away starts at Castle Gleigh Prison in Nothern Ireland as convicted terrorist bomber Ryan Gaerity (Tommy Lee Jones) escapes using his explosive know how. Jumpt to Boston in the US where bomb squad member Jimmy Dove (Jeff Bridges) has decided to retire & new recruit Anthony Franklin (Forest Whitaker) is set to take his place alongside Jimmy's old partner Blanket (Ruben Santiago-Hudson), on their first job Blanket is killed by a booby trapped explosive which forces Jimmy out of retirement. Soon it gets personal for Jimmy as he discovers that his old terrorist mate from Ireland Ryan is behind a series of bombings & he is out for revenge against Jimmy, his family & friends as it was Jimmy who put Ryan behind bars in Ireland all those years ago... Directed by Stephen Hopkins this is actually the second Hopkins directed film I have seen in the past twenty four hours after also seeing The Reaping (2007) yesterday, it wasn't planned & it was a co-incidence & pretty lousy luck as The Reaping was average & this was plain crap. At two hours long Blown Away is very slow going & apart from the last fifteen or so minutes is really dull, lifeless, bland & dare I say it even boring. The melodramatics between Jimmy & his family are unintentionally funny (the scene when his wife jumps in the jacuzzi to shout at Jimmy is pure comedy) while the hero with a dark past role just doesn't suit Bridges, his confrontations with Tommy Lee Jones are awful as it seems to be a contest between the both of them to discover who can do the worst Irish accent. The plot is extremely predictable, routine & by the numbers as the clich&eacute;d tough guy hero with a dark past has to save the day on his own playing by his own rules, any number of better action films use this scenario & add that to a script that offers no surprises (good guy wins in the end, bad guy is stopped) & feels like little or no effort has gone into it. For a big budget action thriller Blown Away is really short on action or thrills, there's a decent explosion at the end, a truck is blown up & there's a speeding jeep & that's it. For a two hour film not enough happens. Footage from Blown Away was edited into two low budget action films called Stealth Fighter (1999) & Agent Red (2000). The Boston locations don't add anything to the film at all to be honest. Apparently the shockwave from the ship explosion at the end shattered 8000 windows in East Boston. If you really want to see an exciting action thriller about bombs then watch Speed (1994) again instead & see how a proper action film should be done. This has decent production values & is well made for what it is but it's still a rubbish film. The acting is poor from a good cast, father & son Jeff & Lloyd Bridges appear here together. Blown Away is a poor action thriller with virtually no action & some poor performances from a decent cast, this is just bad all round really & far too predictable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Totally Blown Away....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Stephen Hopkins 1994 action-packed thriller 'Blown Away' easily ranks amongst the better films from that year. It has a crispy script, fantastic action, superb performances and stylish direction. In short, A winner all the way. 'Blown Away' is a revenge saga about 2 individuals. One believes in violence, while the other keeps away from violence. Hopkins body of work is truly admirable, his direction in here is simply spell-binding. 'Blown Away' has a terrific start, a good middle and an excellent end. This film promises entertainment, and it serves it in abundance. In performances, Jeff Bridges steals the show with a winning performance. He breathes fire in all of his dramatic scenes. Tommy Lee Jones is fantastic as the calculative/conniving villain. He crates a terror in you, without making morbid faces. The Late Lloyd Bridges is lovable. Suzy Amis is very good. In fact, this is her careers best work. Forest Whitaker is excellent from start to end. 'Blown Away' is simply an amazing watch. Two Thumbs Up!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beautifully Showy AND So American !
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ahmed elshikh (ahmed_abd_elreheem@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/10/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's Hollywood. With the good and bad senses of the word. Aside from objection I hold against its standpoint, this is an entertaining movie. In the mid-90s there were many American blockbusters with a plot centers on one bomber and consecutive bombs such as : Speed, The Specialist, Blown Away (all produced in 1994), then Die Hard with a Vengeance (1995). Blown Away stands as one of their best. First it's in the direction. (Stephen Hopkins) is the star of the show. Other work for him like The Ghost and the Darkness (1996), Under Suspicion (2000) got my attention by their clever and charming technique. (Hopkins) here makes every moment thrilling and, thank god, not in a hyped way. The picture was never brighter with an explosion before. Just remember the shot in which the lead takes the bad guy out of the last's cache near the ocean; this "live" piece of action was historically dazzling. In one word : it's showiness as it should be. The script delivers : action, thrill, and hot duel. But nothing is perfect. As I wasn't convinced with matters like a forced nagging (Forest Whitaker); it should have been better as justified enemy turns-into justified friend character. Or how the father (Lloyd Bridges) finds the bad guy (Tommy Lee Jones) plainly and illogically. Plus non-understandable matter like seeing (Jones) crying over killing (Lloyd Bridges) ! (Does he originally love and respect the man? Does he blame himself for killing one of his own people ? Does he hate to murder innocent people ????? I don't know, and I won't know at all !). Let alone the Hollywood clich&eacute;s about the IRA (The Provisional Irish Republican Army) that were so prevalent before the 1998 Belfast agreement. The same you can find in Patriot Games (1992) where the IRA's men are always unmerciful, nearly crazy, assassins. They love to blow up everything and everyone. And their best are the ones whom went to America and stayed there as peaceful citizens ! It could be Hollywood's style of categorizing everyone to only bad guy/good guy, or it's Hollywood's big companies' faith about the IRA, or maybe both ! However you can touch this movie's desire to ignore any political duel by showing the Irish man this time as a maniac who is rejected by the IRA itself, finding a warrant for him to be evil, and turning the whole matter into just another revenge story. Though, why relating him to the IRA from the start ?! It's obvious point of view about anyone who's not American or supporting the American policy, especially when the movie shows information about Palestinians as terrorists the evil man worked with them once. It's sorrowfully typical. Since Hollywood, here, means being illiberal American; namely non-objective (Well, for little instance the Israelis used to kill unarmed men, women and children since ages and I've never seen them as terrorists in one mainstream American movie yet !?). While the 2 leads were cogent and intensive, just casting (Whitaker) was weird. I mean aside from mixed up performance came mainly from weak characterization, he's the last Irish in the world, too heavy to be in a bomb squad, and I don't catch on how they cast him repeatedly as a police officer with the obvious condition of his eye ??! No police officer can make it to be one with that I suppose ! It got madly stimulating Alan Silvestri's soundtrack, unforgettable (Peter Levy)'s cinematography, and masterfully thrilling (Tim Wellburn)'s editing. Enough to remember the climactic sequence in the car. I don't know how this movie wasn't a hit back then. But sure it hits its mark very well. Hollywood movies lately were about abstract explosions and exhausting excitement, with one cliffhanger after another, and non-stop in-the-nick-of-time rescues. (Blown Away) personifies that in iconic way. And even its stereotypes apply to that, since stereotyping became  along the years  part of the show's original formula. The bad, semi-lasting, part.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Catch you at a bad time?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nickelreviews
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I may never hear the end it from people on why I love this movie so much, but it is one of my favorite Hero/Villain movies ever! It was received very poorly both critically and commercially, but I love it! It goes from Ireland to Boston. There's Guinness drinking, explosions, and at least two songs from U2's Joshua Tree Album, used in parts of the film that fit perfectly. You also have father/son Jeff Bridges/Lloyd Bridges starring together as former IRA members. I don't know what draws me so close to this film. Perhaps my fascination with Ireland, curiosity over the years of conflict there, having done my internship there or what? Maybe that I've just always liked Tommy lee Jones and Jeff Bridges. The pair worked well together in Blown Away. I don't care what the critics said, or how well it did at the box office. Reviewed by AN/NR 11-14-11
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bad Accents
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mfrays
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Blown Away" 1994 movie bout a bomb squads in Boston. Sorry but I just saw it for the first time. Bad casting and really bad voice coaching. Tommy Lee Jones is a fine actor, but his Irish accent was way, way off with his Texas drawl. PLEASE. That was embarrassingly pitiful. Then you've got Jeff Bridges with, I don't know, what was that a combo- Irish and Boston Southie accent. Again  really bad to the point of stinking up the entirety of all Boston zip codes. And I really like Jeff, too. But, here's the real kicker - Forest Whitaker with some kind of lame, overdone Southie brogue mixed in with the inevitable ethnicity blended in. Hell, I was in the Marines with black Bostonians and I never heard the likes of that fiasco  never. And finally, poor old Lloyd Bridges. He actually got the best Irish accent, but he went overboard with it and over-emoted it into almost a caricature. I am no expert and I am no authority, but I can hear and both my ears were offended by the lousy accents, over-emotion and probably bad casting in what could have been a really fine movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great Early 90s Action/Cop Drama Flick
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Thom Sirveaux
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An excellent early 90s action/cop drama flick, it has much of the feel of the Tom Clancy films of similar timeframe. Extremely watchable, with good performances from Bridges, Bridges, and Whitaker. Tommy Lee Jones turns out a very sinister character, and conveys the look of who and what his character is supposed to be surprisingly well. A pretty smart film with good internal consistency, it's well worth watching. One minor negative is that there are actions that police characters take that are distinctly inconsistent with how a real PD would operate - those with EMT/law enforcement backgrounds especially may find it breaks suspension of disbelief. This can be explained away by one of the key elements of a main character's story arc, and doesn't detract from the film very much, but may leave you scratching your head if you think too hard about it. Obviously it's a movie, not a documentary, but analyzing the story arc's impact on judgments allows for many of the actions taken by all of the characters to make perfect sense and maintain that good internal consistency. Being vague enough not to spoil anything - if something seems odd, think about why a character does it. Overall, a very solid, enjoyable film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Everybody loves a hero.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jimmy Dove works for the bomb squad in Boston and he is always the one who is on the tough jobs. One day he decides to quit the force and to become a teacher for the rookies of the squad. A few days later his former partner is killed by a bomb and Jimmy becomes suspicious that maybe this bomb could have been built by a former friend of himself. He begins to investigate and finds out that his worst nightmare has returned from his past..... Lee Jones and Brides were very hot in 1994. Jones had just bagged an Oscar, and Bridges was being praised for his turn in Fearless, what could go wrong? A lot, apparently. Saying that this is a cat and mouse game is a little cynical, as the two leads only make contact twice during the movie, but kudos to them for dealing with such a touchy subject matter which is dealt with in the way only Hollywood could.....glam it up!! Bridges is great as the tortured bomb disposal expert, who has a shady past, hanging around in a hot tub with an old 'Oirish' man and being the all American hero, Bridges is a man you can rely on, when a film isn't that great. Jones on the other hand was in the psycho business at this point in his career (Natural Born Killers, Under Siege), so who better to play the bad guy. And while he's having fun, his accent and the way his culture is stated isn't. It's the worse depiction of the accent I have ever heard, makes Brad Pitt sound like on of the Corrs. And the fact that he dances around to U2 and drinks a funny looking Guinness, just adds insult. But given that, the story is pretty good, and the set pieces are astonishing, especially the destruction of the boat. Take away the bad stuff, the accents, and Lloyd Bridges who plays nothing more than a leprechaun, you have a very tight enjoyable action thriller that doesn't trouble the brain. Consider plausibility, and you will find a stinker of a movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unbelievably dumb and clich&eacute;d
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Major Woody
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We were perusing the On Demand list, and saw this title, with Jeff & Lloyd Bridges, Tommy Lee Jones, and Forest Whitaker, and thought it sounded like a great movie. I should have been forewarned when I didn't recall ever having heard of it before. The opening segment in the prison, where the inmates speak Gaelic ( I believe) and is subtitled, allowed for a bit of confusion when Jones dispatches his cell mate, and says something over his body. Even with repeated viewings, none of us could make out what exactly he says, or even if it's in English. Was the murder done for a reason besides needing a bomb bunker, or was there a back story? Then to watch him assemble his bomb, using all kinds of devices including machine-threaded pipes, explosives, and other unusual items hat would seem to be a bit difficult to accrue in a max security prison, he blows a hole in the wall, and apparently makes his way from that desolate area without any problems, although they don't bother to show how. He next appears in Boston, living in a decrepit, rusty old boat on an abandoned pier, which miraculously not only has electricity, but also has cable TV ( as the orchestra promo mentions that it's on A&E, not an over the air channel). He also has unlimited funds to obtain everything he needs, from explosives, to electronics, to transportation to get around the Boston area. Bridges character, as we soon find out, is also a fugitive IRA guy, wanted by Interpol, yet he apparently had no problem getting past the Boston PD's background check to get hired under his phony identity. He also exhibits almost every Hollywood clich&eacute; about the maverick cop, riding a m/c to a bomb scene while smoking a butt and wearing a Hawaiian shirt to let us know how cool he is. He also ignores basic safety procedures while disarming bombs, even though he is supposedly the one who instructs everyone on EOD protocol. Jones also exhibits the troubling Hollywood syndrome of being able to single handedly surveill multiple people and locate their homes, even their vacation homes, and also gain employment with Boston PD as a janitor ( once again, bypassing the pesky background checks a large agency like BPD conducts even for civilians) with not a care in the world. They also never bothered to explain how Jones was able to get Lloyd Bridges from the bar bathroom out the door, and to the school yard , where he was able to secure him with an unbelievably complex device, without a single person noticing. Then of course there is the TV screen continuously showing Bridges wife in closeup even though she is just one person in the Boston Pops. The story just kept getting more and more ludicrous, and of course there had to be the obligatory Hollywood fight where the bad guy is almost indestructible, no matter what he is hit with. If you come across this, keep on going, it was 2 hours that I'll never get back. I can only imagine that the Dude and the rest were in a slump and needed a quick payday, without regards to the script. The only reason I gave it 2 stars was for the Boston scenery.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Block Buster Sizzler
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    merylmatt
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jeff Bridges was OK in this movie, but Tommy Lee Jones took it way over the top in his role as an IRA terror bomber. It became silly after awhile. The characters were two dimensional, stereotyped and clich&eacute;d. Jeff has a past that haunts him, a job he is addicted to but wants to get out of. Oh, I did not like the nepotism of having Lyold Bridges (Jeff's real life dad) play a cameo. Boston Irish cops drinking, there's a twist. Hollywood block busters or pop corn movies are big on explosions and short on credibility. The rube Goldberg bomb device at the end was beyond disbelief and I have a pretty good suspension of disbelief. And let's add one more clich&eacute; into the mix, just in case you have not had your fill the U-2 songs played as back drops. One star for Jeff Bridges, one for Forrest Whitaker. It's not their fault the script was terrible and predictable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Tommy Lee Jone Gives Oscar Worthy Performance.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vivekmaru45
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For Tommy Lee Jones fans only. This IS the movie that he will be remembered for. I have seen many of his films: The Fugitive, Double Jeopardy, U.S. Marshall's, The Missing, The Hunted, Men In Black 1 & 2, Space Cowboys, Volcano, Batman Forever, Natural Born Killers, In The Valley Of Elah, No Country For Old Man, The Client, Eyes of Laura Mars. *Jones got an Oscar for best supporting actor in The Fugitive. *Jones was also nominated for MTV Movie Awards Best Villain for Blown Away and Batman Forever. The role seems to fit him like a glove. The character he portrays in the film is of an arrogant, dangerous and an untrustworthy person with a one-track mind and a keen eye for revenge. That is the character of Ryan Gaerity, an Irish terrorist imprisoned in Castle Gleigh prison in Northern Ireland. He makes a daring escape to seek vengeance against Liam McGivney, a member of Ryan's original group which also consisted of Ryan's sister who was also Liam's girlfriend. Liam had foiled a plan to bomb some targets chosen be Ryan. As a result he was quickly arrested by the Police and imprisoned for life. Ryan comes to Boston to seek vengeance against Liam, who is semi-retired but working as an instructor with a new identity: Jimmy Dove. Ryan begins taunting his old comrade with threats and his homemade explosives. With his family and friends in danger, he reveals his secret to his wife Kate (Suzy Amis). He returns to action to hunt for Ryan when a former partner of his is killed by one of Ryan's bombs. Fellow officer Anthony Franklin (Forest Whitaker) investigates Jimmy, suspecting a connection between the two. See this superb film directed by Stephen Hopkins (Predator 2, The Ghost And The Darkness) to find out what happens next. Overall the special effects are fantastic, the background music is excellent, script, direction and acting are professionally done. Score 10/10. Flawless film. Buy it on DVD. Similar films: Speed, The Specialist, Executive Decision, The Mechanic, Juggernaut. Email me Vivekmaru45@yahoo.com for info one more movies. Thanks for reading.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the worst Hollywood action thrillers out there.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Paul Andrews (poolandrews@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Blown Away starts at Castle Gleigh Prison in Nothern Ireland as convicted terrorist bomber Ryan Gaerity (Tommy Lee Jones) escapes using his explosive know how. Jumpt to Boston in the US where bomb squad member Jimmy Dove (Jeff Bridges) has decided to retire & new recruit Anthony Franklin (Forest Whitaker) is set to take his place alongside Jimmy's old partner Blanket (Ruben Santiago-Hudson), on their first job Blanket is killed by a booby trapped explosive which forces Jimmy out of retirement. Soon it gets personal for Jimmy as he discovers that his old terrorist mate from Ireland Ryan is behind a series of bombings & he is out for revenge against Jimmy, his family & friends as it was Jimmy who put Ryan behind bars in Ireland all those years ago... Directed by Stephen Hopkins this is actually the second Hopkins directed film I have seen in the past twenty four hours after also seeing The Reaping (2007) yesterday, it wasn't planned & it was a co-incidence & pretty lousy luck as The Reaping was average & this was plain crap. At two hours long Blown Away is very slow going & apart from the last fifteen or so minutes is really dull, lifeless, bland & dare I say it even boring. The melodramatics between Jimmy & his family are unintentionally funny (the scene when his wife jumps in the jacuzzi to shout at Jimmy is pure comedy) while the hero with a dark past role just doesn't suit Bridges, his confrontations with Tommy Lee Jones are awful as it seems to be a contest between the both of them to discover who can do the worst Irish accent. The plot is extremely predictable, routine & by the numbers as the clich&eacute;d tough guy hero with a dark past has to save the day on his own playing by his own rules, any number of better action films use this scenario & add that to a script that offers no surprises (good guy wins in the end, bad guy is stopped) & feels like little or no effort has gone into it. For a big budget action thriller Blown Away is really short on action or thrills, there's a decent explosion at the end, a truck is blown up & there's a speeding jeep & that's it. For a two hour film not enough happens. Footage from Blown Away was edited into two low budget action films called Stealth Fighter (1999) & Agent Red (2000). The Boston locations don't add anything to the film at all to be honest. Apparently the shockwave from the ship explosion at the end shattered 8000 windows in East Boston. If you really want to see an exciting action thriller about bombs then watch Speed (1994) again instead & see how a proper action film should be done. This has decent production values & is well made for what it is but it's still a rubbish film. The acting is poor from a good cast, father & son Jeff & Lloyd Bridges appear here together. Blown Away is a poor action thriller with virtually no action & some poor performances from a decent cast, this is just bad all round really & far too predictable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Totally Blown Away....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Stephen Hopkins 1994 action-packed thriller 'Blown Away' easily ranks amongst the better films from that year. It has a crispy script, fantastic action, superb performances and stylish direction. In short, A winner all the way. 'Blown Away' is a revenge saga about 2 individuals. One believes in violence, while the other keeps away from violence. Hopkins body of work is truly admirable, his direction in here is simply spell-binding. 'Blown Away' has a terrific start, a good middle and an excellent end. This film promises entertainment, and it serves it in abundance. In performances, Jeff Bridges steals the show with a winning performance. He breathes fire in all of his dramatic scenes. Tommy Lee Jones is fantastic as the calculative/conniving villain. He crates a terror in you, without making morbid faces. The Late Lloyd Bridges is lovable. Suzy Amis is very good. In fact, this is her careers best work. Forest Whitaker is excellent from start to end. 'Blown Away' is simply an amazing watch. Two Thumbs Up!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beautifully Showy AND So American !
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ahmed elshikh (ahmed_abd_elreheem@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/10/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's Hollywood. With the good and bad senses of the word. Aside from objection I hold against its standpoint, this is an entertaining movie. In the mid-90s there were many American blockbusters with a plot centers on one bomber and consecutive bombs such as : Speed, The Specialist, Blown Away (all produced in 1994), then Die Hard with a Vengeance (1995). Blown Away stands as one of their best. First it's in the direction. (Stephen Hopkins) is the star of the show. Other work for him like The Ghost and the Darkness (1996), Under Suspicion (2000) got my attention by their clever and charming technique. (Hopkins) here makes every moment thrilling and, thank god, not in a hyped way. The picture was never brighter with an explosion before. Just remember the shot in which the lead takes the bad guy out of the last's cache near the ocean; this "live" piece of action was historically dazzling. In one word : it's showiness as it should be. The script delivers : action, thrill, and hot duel. But nothing is perfect. As I wasn't convinced with matters like a forced nagging (Forest Whitaker); it should have been better as justified enemy turns-into justified friend character. Or how the father (Lloyd Bridges) finds the bad guy (Tommy Lee Jones) plainly and illogically. Plus non-understandable matter like seeing (Jones) crying over killing (Lloyd Bridges) ! (Does he originally love and respect the man? Does he blame himself for killing one of his own people ? Does he hate to murder innocent people ????? I don't know, and I won't know at all !). Let alone the Hollywood clich&eacute;s about the IRA (The Provisional Irish Republican Army) that were so prevalent before the 1998 Belfast agreement. The same you can find in Patriot Games (1992) where the IRA's men are always unmerciful, nearly crazy, assassins. They love to blow up everything and everyone. And their best are the ones whom went to America and stayed there as peaceful citizens ! It could be Hollywood's style of categorizing everyone to only bad guy/good guy, or it's Hollywood's big companies' faith about the IRA, or maybe both ! However you can touch this movie's desire to ignore any political duel by showing the Irish man this time as a maniac who is rejected by the IRA itself, finding a warrant for him to be evil, and turning the whole matter into just another revenge story. Though, why relating him to the IRA from the start ?! It's obvious point of view about anyone who's not American or supporting the American policy, especially when the movie shows information about Palestinians as terrorists the evil man worked with them once. It's sorrowfully typical. Since Hollywood, here, means being illiberal American; namely non-objective (Well, for little instance the Israelis used to kill unarmed men, women and children since ages and I've never seen them as terrorists in one mainstream American movie yet !?). While the 2 leads were cogent and intensive, just casting (Whitaker) was weird. I mean aside from mixed up performance came mainly from weak characterization, he's the last Irish in the world, too heavy to be in a bomb squad, and I don't catch on how they cast him repeatedly as a police officer with the obvious condition of his eye ??! No police officer can make it to be one with that I suppose ! It got madly stimulating Alan Silvestri's soundtrack, unforgettable (Peter Levy)'s cinematography, and masterfully thrilling (Tim Wellburn)'s editing. Enough to remember the climactic sequence in the car. I don't know how this movie wasn't a hit back then. But sure it hits its mark very well. Hollywood movies lately were about abstract explosions and exhausting excitement, with one cliffhanger after another, and non-stop in-the-nick-of-time rescues. (Blown Away) personifies that in iconic way. And even its stereotypes apply to that, since stereotyping became  along the years  part of the show's original formula. The bad, semi-lasting, part.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Catch you at a bad time?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nickelreviews
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I may never hear the end it from people on why I love this movie so much, but it is one of my favorite Hero/Villain movies ever! It was received very poorly both critically and commercially, but I love it! It goes from Ireland to Boston. There's Guinness drinking, explosions, and at least two songs from U2's Joshua Tree Album, used in parts of the film that fit perfectly. You also have father/son Jeff Bridges/Lloyd Bridges starring together as former IRA members. I don't know what draws me so close to this film. Perhaps my fascination with Ireland, curiosity over the years of conflict there, having done my internship there or what? Maybe that I've just always liked Tommy lee Jones and Jeff Bridges. The pair worked well together in Blown Away. I don't care what the critics said, or how well it did at the box office. Reviewed by AN/NR 11-14-11
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bad Accents
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mfrays
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Blown Away" 1994 movie bout a bomb squads in Boston. Sorry but I just saw it for the first time. Bad casting and really bad voice coaching. Tommy Lee Jones is a fine actor, but his Irish accent was way, way off with his Texas drawl. PLEASE. That was embarrassingly pitiful. Then you've got Jeff Bridges with, I don't know, what was that a combo- Irish and Boston Southie accent. Again  really bad to the point of stinking up the entirety of all Boston zip codes. And I really like Jeff, too. But, here's the real kicker - Forest Whitaker with some kind of lame, overdone Southie brogue mixed in with the inevitable ethnicity blended in. Hell, I was in the Marines with black Bostonians and I never heard the likes of that fiasco  never. And finally, poor old Lloyd Bridges. He actually got the best Irish accent, but he went overboard with it and over-emoted it into almost a caricature. I am no expert and I am no authority, but I can hear and both my ears were offended by the lousy accents, over-emotion and probably bad casting in what could have been a really fine movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great Early 90s Action/Cop Drama Flick
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Thom Sirveaux
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An excellent early 90s action/cop drama flick, it has much of the feel of the Tom Clancy films of similar timeframe. Extremely watchable, with good performances from Bridges, Bridges, and Whitaker. Tommy Lee Jones turns out a very sinister character, and conveys the look of who and what his character is supposed to be surprisingly well. A pretty smart film with good internal consistency, it's well worth watching. One minor negative is that there are actions that police characters take that are distinctly inconsistent with how a real PD would operate - those with EMT/law enforcement backgrounds especially may find it breaks suspension of disbelief. This can be explained away by one of the key elements of a main character's story arc, and doesn't detract from the film very much, but may leave you scratching your head if you think too hard about it. Obviously it's a movie, not a documentary, but analyzing the story arc's impact on judgments allows for many of the actions taken by all of the characters to make perfect sense and maintain that good internal consistency. Being vague enough not to spoil anything - if something seems odd, think about why a character does it. Overall, a very solid, enjoyable film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Everybody loves a hero.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jimmy Dove works for the bomb squad in Boston and he is always the one who is on the tough jobs. One day he decides to quit the force and to become a teacher for the rookies of the squad. A few days later his former partner is killed by a bomb and Jimmy becomes suspicious that maybe this bomb could have been built by a former friend of himself. He begins to investigate and finds out that his worst nightmare has returned from his past..... Lee Jones and Brides were very hot in 1994. Jones had just bagged an Oscar, and Bridges was being praised for his turn in Fearless, what could go wrong? A lot, apparently. Saying that this is a cat and mouse game is a little cynical, as the two leads only make contact twice during the movie, but kudos to them for dealing with such a touchy subject matter which is dealt with in the way only Hollywood could.....glam it up!! Bridges is great as the tortured bomb disposal expert, who has a shady past, hanging around in a hot tub with an old 'Oirish' man and being the all American hero, Bridges is a man you can rely on, when a film isn't that great. Jones on the other hand was in the psycho business at this point in his career (Natural Born Killers, Under Siege), so who better to play the bad guy. And while he's having fun, his accent and the way his culture is stated isn't. It's the worse depiction of the accent I have ever heard, makes Brad Pitt sound like on of the Corrs. And the fact that he dances around to U2 and drinks a funny looking Guinness, just adds insult. But given that, the story is pretty good, and the set pieces are astonishing, especially the destruction of the boat. Take away the bad stuff, the accents, and Lloyd Bridges who plays nothing more than a leprechaun, you have a very tight enjoyable action thriller that doesn't trouble the brain. Consider plausibility, and you will find a stinker of a movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unbelievably dumb and clich&eacute;d
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Major Woody
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We were perusing the On Demand list, and saw this title, with Jeff & Lloyd Bridges, Tommy Lee Jones, and Forest Whitaker, and thought it sounded like a great movie. I should have been forewarned when I didn't recall ever having heard of it before. The opening segment in the prison, where the inmates speak Gaelic ( I believe) and is subtitled, allowed for a bit of confusion when Jones dispatches his cell mate, and says something over his body. Even with repeated viewings, none of us could make out what exactly he says, or even if it's in English. Was the murder done for a reason besides needing a bomb bunker, or was there a back story? Then to watch him assemble his bomb, using all kinds of devices including machine-threaded pipes, explosives, and other unusual items hat would seem to be a bit difficult to accrue in a max security prison, he blows a hole in the wall, and apparently makes his way from that desolate area without any problems, although they don't bother to show how. He next appears in Boston, living in a decrepit, rusty old boat on an abandoned pier, which miraculously not only has electricity, but also has cable TV ( as the orchestra promo mentions that it's on A&E, not an over the air channel). He also has unlimited funds to obtain everything he needs, from explosives, to electronics, to transportation to get around the Boston area. Bridges character, as we soon find out, is also a fugitive IRA guy, wanted by Interpol, yet he apparently had no problem getting past the Boston PD's background check to get hired under his phony identity. He also exhibits almost every Hollywood clich&eacute; about the maverick cop, riding a m/c to a bomb scene while smoking a butt and wearing a Hawaiian shirt to let us know how cool he is. He also ignores basic safety procedures while disarming bombs, even though he is supposedly the one who instructs everyone on EOD protocol. Jones also exhibits the troubling Hollywood syndrome of being able to single handedly surveill multiple people and locate their homes, even their vacation homes, and also gain employment with Boston PD as a janitor ( once again, bypassing the pesky background checks a large agency like BPD conducts even for civilians) with not a care in the world. They also never bothered to explain how Jones was able to get Lloyd Bridges from the bar bathroom out the door, and to the school yard , where he was able to secure him with an unbelievably complex device, without a single person noticing. Then of course there is the TV screen continuously showing Bridges wife in closeup even though she is just one person in the Boston Pops. The story just kept getting more and more ludicrous, and of course there had to be the obligatory Hollywood fight where the bad guy is almost indestructible, no matter what he is hit with. If you come across this, keep on going, it was 2 hours that I'll never get back. I can only imagine that the Dude and the rest were in a slump and needed a quick payday, without regards to the script. The only reason I gave it 2 stars was for the Boston scenery.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Block Buster Sizzler
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    merylmatt
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jeff Bridges was OK in this movie, but Tommy Lee Jones took it way over the top in his role as an IRA terror bomber. It became silly after awhile. The characters were two dimensional, stereotyped and clich&eacute;d. Jeff has a past that haunts him, a job he is addicted to but wants to get out of. Oh, I did not like the nepotism of having Lyold Bridges (Jeff's real life dad) play a cameo. Boston Irish cops drinking, there's a twist. Hollywood block busters or pop corn movies are big on explosions and short on credibility. The rube Goldberg bomb device at the end was beyond disbelief and I have a pretty good suspension of disbelief. And let's add one more clich&eacute; into the mix, just in case you have not had your fill the U-2 songs played as back drops. One star for Jeff Bridges, one for Forrest Whitaker. It's not their fault the script was terrible and predictable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Tommy Lee Jone Gives Oscar Worthy Performance.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vivekmaru45
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For Tommy Lee Jones fans only. This IS the movie that he will be remembered for. I have seen many of his films: The Fugitive, Double Jeopardy, U.S. Marshall's, The Missing, The Hunted, Men In Black 1 & 2, Space Cowboys, Volcano, Batman Forever, Natural Born Killers, In The Valley Of Elah, No Country For Old Man, The Client, Eyes of Laura Mars. *Jones got an Oscar for best supporting actor in The Fugitive. *Jones was also nominated for MTV Movie Awards Best Villain for Blown Away and Batman Forever. The role seems to fit him like a glove. The character he portrays in the film is of an arrogant, dangerous and an untrustworthy person with a one-track mind and a keen eye for revenge. That is the character of Ryan Gaerity, an Irish terrorist imprisoned in Castle Gleigh prison in Northern Ireland. He makes a daring escape to seek vengeance against Liam McGivney, a member of Ryan's original group which also consisted of Ryan's sister who was also Liam's girlfriend. Liam had foiled a plan to bomb some targets chosen be Ryan. As a result he was quickly arrested by the Police and imprisoned for life. Ryan comes to Boston to seek vengeance against Liam, who is semi-retired but working as an instructor with a new identity: Jimmy Dove. Ryan begins taunting his old comrade with threats and his homemade explosives. With his family and friends in danger, he reveals his secret to his wife Kate (Suzy Amis). He returns to action to hunt for Ryan when a former partner of his is killed by one of Ryan's bombs. Fellow officer Anthony Franklin (Forest Whitaker) investigates Jimmy, suspecting a connection between the two. See this superb film directed by Stephen Hopkins (Predator 2, The Ghost And The Darkness) to find out what happens next. Overall the special effects are fantastic, the background music is excellent, script, direction and acting are professionally done. Score 10/10. Flawless film. Buy it on DVD. Similar films: Speed, The Specialist, Executive Decision, The Mechanic, Juggernaut. Email me Vivekmaru45@yahoo.com for info one more movies. Thanks for reading.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the worst Hollywood action thrillers out there.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Paul Andrews (poolandrews@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Blown Away starts at Castle Gleigh Prison in Nothern Ireland as convicted terrorist bomber Ryan Gaerity (Tommy Lee Jones) escapes using his explosive know how. Jumpt to Boston in the US where bomb squad member Jimmy Dove (Jeff Bridges) has decided to retire & new recruit Anthony Franklin (Forest Whitaker) is set to take his place alongside Jimmy's old partner Blanket (Ruben Santiago-Hudson), on their first job Blanket is killed by a booby trapped explosive which forces Jimmy out of retirement. Soon it gets personal for Jimmy as he discovers that his old terrorist mate from Ireland Ryan is behind a series of bombings & he is out for revenge against Jimmy, his family & friends as it was Jimmy who put Ryan behind bars in Ireland all those years ago... Directed by Stephen Hopkins this is actually the second Hopkins directed film I have seen in the past twenty four hours after also seeing The Reaping (2007) yesterday, it wasn't planned & it was a co-incidence & pretty lousy luck as The Reaping was average & this was plain crap. At two hours long Blown Away is very slow going & apart from the last fifteen or so minutes is really dull, lifeless, bland & dare I say it even boring. The melodramatics between Jimmy & his family are unintentionally funny (the scene when his wife jumps in the jacuzzi to shout at Jimmy is pure comedy) while the hero with a dark past role just doesn't suit Bridges, his confrontations with Tommy Lee Jones are awful as it seems to be a contest between the both of them to discover who can do the worst Irish accent. The plot is extremely predictable, routine & by the numbers as the clich&eacute;d tough guy hero with a dark past has to save the day on his own playing by his own rules, any number of better action films use this scenario & add that to a script that offers no surprises (good guy wins in the end, bad guy is stopped) & feels like little or no effort has gone into it. For a big budget action thriller Blown Away is really short on action or thrills, there's a decent explosion at the end, a truck is blown up & there's a speeding jeep & that's it. For a two hour film not enough happens. Footage from Blown Away was edited into two low budget action films called Stealth Fighter (1999) & Agent Red (2000). The Boston locations don't add anything to the film at all to be honest. Apparently the shockwave from the ship explosion at the end shattered 8000 windows in East Boston. If you really want to see an exciting action thriller about bombs then watch Speed (1994) again instead & see how a proper action film should be done. This has decent production values & is well made for what it is but it's still a rubbish film. The acting is poor from a good cast, father & son Jeff & Lloyd Bridges appear here together. Blown Away is a poor action thriller with virtually no action & some poor performances from a decent cast, this is just bad all round really & far too predictable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Totally Blown Away....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Stephen Hopkins 1994 action-packed thriller 'Blown Away' easily ranks amongst the better films from that year. It has a crispy script, fantastic action, superb performances and stylish direction. In short, A winner all the way. 'Blown Away' is a revenge saga about 2 individuals. One believes in violence, while the other keeps away from violence. Hopkins body of work is truly admirable, his direction in here is simply spell-binding. 'Blown Away' has a terrific start, a good middle and an excellent end. This film promises entertainment, and it serves it in abundance. In performances, Jeff Bridges steals the show with a winning performance. He breathes fire in all of his dramatic scenes. Tommy Lee Jones is fantastic as the calculative/conniving villain. He crates a terror in you, without making morbid faces. The Late Lloyd Bridges is lovable. Suzy Amis is very good. In fact, this is her careers best work. Forest Whitaker is excellent from start to end. 'Blown Away' is simply an amazing watch. Two Thumbs Up!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beautifully Showy AND So American !
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ahmed elshikh (ahmed_abd_elreheem@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/10/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's Hollywood. With the good and bad senses of the word. Aside from objection I hold against its standpoint, this is an entertaining movie. In the mid-90s there were many American blockbusters with a plot centers on one bomber and consecutive bombs such as : Speed, The Specialist, Blown Away (all produced in 1994), then Die Hard with a Vengeance (1995). Blown Away stands as one of their best. First it's in the direction. (Stephen Hopkins) is the star of the show. Other work for him like The Ghost and the Darkness (1996), Under Suspicion (2000) got my attention by their clever and charming technique. (Hopkins) here makes every moment thrilling and, thank god, not in a hyped way. The picture was never brighter with an explosion before. Just remember the shot in which the lead takes the bad guy out of the last's cache near the ocean; this "live" piece of action was historically dazzling. In one word : it's showiness as it should be. The script delivers : action, thrill, and hot duel. But nothing is perfect. As I wasn't convinced with matters like a forced nagging (Forest Whitaker); it should have been better as justified enemy turns-into justified friend character. Or how the father (Lloyd Bridges) finds the bad guy (Tommy Lee Jones) plainly and illogically. Plus non-understandable matter like seeing (Jones) crying over killing (Lloyd Bridges) ! (Does he originally love and respect the man? Does he blame himself for killing one of his own people ? Does he hate to murder innocent people ????? I don't know, and I won't know at all !). Let alone the Hollywood clich&eacute;s about the IRA (The Provisional Irish Republican Army) that were so prevalent before the 1998 Belfast agreement. The same you can find in Patriot Games (1992) where the IRA's men are always unmerciful, nearly crazy, assassins. They love to blow up everything and everyone. And their best are the ones whom went to America and stayed there as peaceful citizens ! It could be Hollywood's style of categorizing everyone to only bad guy/good guy, or it's Hollywood's big companies' faith about the IRA, or maybe both ! However you can touch this movie's desire to ignore any political duel by showing the Irish man this time as a maniac who is rejected by the IRA itself, finding a warrant for him to be evil, and turning the whole matter into just another revenge story. Though, why relating him to the IRA from the start ?! It's obvious point of view about anyone who's not American or supporting the American policy, especially when the movie shows information about Palestinians as terrorists the evil man worked with them once. It's sorrowfully typical. Since Hollywood, here, means being illiberal American; namely non-objective (Well, for little instance the Israelis used to kill unarmed men, women and children since ages and I've never seen them as terrorists in one mainstream American movie yet !?). While the 2 leads were cogent and intensive, just casting (Whitaker) was weird. I mean aside from mixed up performance came mainly from weak characterization, he's the last Irish in the world, too heavy to be in a bomb squad, and I don't catch on how they cast him repeatedly as a police officer with the obvious condition of his eye ??! No police officer can make it to be one with that I suppose ! It got madly stimulating Alan Silvestri's soundtrack, unforgettable (Peter Levy)'s cinematography, and masterfully thrilling (Tim Wellburn)'s editing. Enough to remember the climactic sequence in the car. I don't know how this movie wasn't a hit back then. But sure it hits its mark very well. Hollywood movies lately were about abstract explosions and exhausting excitement, with one cliffhanger after another, and non-stop in-the-nick-of-time rescues. (Blown Away) personifies that in iconic way. And even its stereotypes apply to that, since stereotyping became  along the years  part of the show's original formula. The bad, semi-lasting, part.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Catch you at a bad time?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nickelreviews
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I may never hear the end it from people on why I love this movie so much, but it is one of my favorite Hero/Villain movies ever! It was received very poorly both critically and commercially, but I love it! It goes from Ireland to Boston. There's Guinness drinking, explosions, and at least two songs from U2's Joshua Tree Album, used in parts of the film that fit perfectly. You also have father/son Jeff Bridges/Lloyd Bridges starring together as former IRA members. I don't know what draws me so close to this film. Perhaps my fascination with Ireland, curiosity over the years of conflict there, having done my internship there or what? Maybe that I've just always liked Tommy lee Jones and Jeff Bridges. The pair worked well together in Blown Away. I don't care what the critics said, or how well it did at the box office. Reviewed by AN/NR 11-14-11
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bad Accents
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mfrays
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Blown Away" 1994 movie bout a bomb squads in Boston. Sorry but I just saw it for the first time. Bad casting and really bad voice coaching. Tommy Lee Jones is a fine actor, but his Irish accent was way, way off with his Texas drawl. PLEASE. That was embarrassingly pitiful. Then you've got Jeff Bridges with, I don't know, what was that a combo- Irish and Boston Southie accent. Again  really bad to the point of stinking up the entirety of all Boston zip codes. And I really like Jeff, too. But, here's the real kicker - Forest Whitaker with some kind of lame, overdone Southie brogue mixed in with the inevitable ethnicity blended in. Hell, I was in the Marines with black Bostonians and I never heard the likes of that fiasco  never. And finally, poor old Lloyd Bridges. He actually got the best Irish accent, but he went overboard with it and over-emoted it into almost a caricature. I am no expert and I am no authority, but I can hear and both my ears were offended by the lousy accents, over-emotion and probably bad casting in what could have been a really fine movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great Early 90s Action/Cop Drama Flick
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Thom Sirveaux
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An excellent early 90s action/cop drama flick, it has much of the feel of the Tom Clancy films of similar timeframe. Extremely watchable, with good performances from Bridges, Bridges, and Whitaker. Tommy Lee Jones turns out a very sinister character, and conveys the look of who and what his character is supposed to be surprisingly well. A pretty smart film with good internal consistency, it's well worth watching. One minor negative is that there are actions that police characters take that are distinctly inconsistent with how a real PD would operate - those with EMT/law enforcement backgrounds especially may find it breaks suspension of disbelief. This can be explained away by one of the key elements of a main character's story arc, and doesn't detract from the film very much, but may leave you scratching your head if you think too hard about it. Obviously it's a movie, not a documentary, but analyzing the story arc's impact on judgments allows for many of the actions taken by all of the characters to make perfect sense and maintain that good internal consistency. Being vague enough not to spoil anything - if something seems odd, think about why a character does it. Overall, a very solid, enjoyable film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Everybody loves a hero.....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jimmy Dove works for the bomb squad in Boston and he is always the one who is on the tough jobs. One day he decides to quit the force and to become a teacher for the rookies of the squad. A few days later his former partner is killed by a bomb and Jimmy becomes suspicious that maybe this bomb could have been built by a former friend of himself. He begins to investigate and finds out that his worst nightmare has returned from his past..... Lee Jones and Brides were very hot in 1994. Jones had just bagged an Oscar, and Bridges was being praised for his turn in Fearless, what could go wrong? A lot, apparently. Saying that this is a cat and mouse game is a little cynical, as the two leads only make contact twice during the movie, but kudos to them for dealing with such a touchy subject matter which is dealt with in the way only Hollywood could.....glam it up!! Bridges is great as the tortured bomb disposal expert, who has a shady past, hanging around in a hot tub with an old 'Oirish' man and being the all American hero, Bridges is a man you can rely on, when a film isn't that great. Jones on the other hand was in the psycho business at this point in his career (Natural Born Killers, Under Siege), so who better to play the bad guy. And while he's having fun, his accent and the way his culture is stated isn't. It's the worse depiction of the accent I have ever heard, makes Brad Pitt sound like on of the Corrs. And the fact that he dances around to U2 and drinks a funny looking Guinness, just adds insult. But given that, the story is pretty good, and the set pieces are astonishing, especially the destruction of the boat. Take away the bad stuff, the accents, and Lloyd Bridges who plays nothing more than a leprechaun, you have a very tight enjoyable action thriller that doesn't trouble the brain. Consider plausibility, and you will find a stinker of a movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unbelievably dumb and clich&eacute;d
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Major Woody
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    We were perusing the On Demand list, and saw this title, with Jeff & Lloyd Bridges, Tommy Lee Jones, and Forest Whitaker, and thought it sounded like a great movie. I should have been forewarned when I didn't recall ever having heard of it before. The opening segment in the prison, where the inmates speak Gaelic ( I believe) and is subtitled, allowed for a bit of confusion when Jones dispatches his cell mate, and says something over his body. Even with repeated viewings, none of us could make out what exactly he says, or even if it's in English. Was the murder done for a reason besides needing a bomb bunker, or was there a back story? Then to watch him assemble his bomb, using all kinds of devices including machine-threaded pipes, explosives, and other unusual items hat would seem to be a bit difficult to accrue in a max security prison, he blows a hole in the wall, and apparently makes his way from that desolate area without any problems, although they don't bother to show how. He next appears in Boston, living in a decrepit, rusty old boat on an abandoned pier, which miraculously not only has electricity, but also has cable TV ( as the orchestra promo mentions that it's on A&E, not an over the air channel). He also has unlimited funds to obtain everything he needs, from explosives, to electronics, to transportation to get around the Boston area. Bridges character, as we soon find out, is also a fugitive IRA guy, wanted by Interpol, yet he apparently had no problem getting past the Boston PD's background check to get hired under his phony identity. He also exhibits almost every Hollywood clich&eacute; about the maverick cop, riding a m/c to a bomb scene while smoking a butt and wearing a Hawaiian shirt to let us know how cool he is. He also ignores basic safety procedures while disarming bombs, even though he is supposedly the one who instructs everyone on EOD protocol. Jones also exhibits the troubling Hollywood syndrome of being able to single handedly surveill multiple people and locate their homes, even their vacation homes, and also gain employment with Boston PD as a janitor ( once again, bypassing the pesky background checks a large agency like BPD conducts even for civilians) with not a care in the world. They also never bothered to explain how Jones was able to get Lloyd Bridges from the bar bathroom out the door, and to the school yard , where he was able to secure him with an unbelievably complex device, without a single person noticing. Then of course there is the TV screen continuously showing Bridges wife in closeup even though she is just one person in the Boston Pops. The story just kept getting more and more ludicrous, and of course there had to be the obligatory Hollywood fight where the bad guy is almost indestructible, no matter what he is hit with. If you come across this, keep on going, it was 2 hours that I'll never get back. I can only imagine that the Dude and the rest were in a slump and needed a quick payday, without regards to the script. The only reason I gave it 2 stars was for the Boston scenery.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Block Buster Sizzler
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    merylmatt
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jeff Bridges was OK in this movie, but Tommy Lee Jones took it way over the top in his role as an IRA terror bomber. It became silly after awhile. The characters were two dimensional, stereotyped and clich&eacute;d. Jeff has a past that haunts him, a job he is addicted to but wants to get out of. Oh, I did not like the nepotism of having Lyold Bridges (Jeff's real life dad) play a cameo. Boston Irish cops drinking, there's a twist. Hollywood block busters or pop corn movies are big on explosions and short on credibility. The rube Goldberg bomb device at the end was beyond disbelief and I have a pretty good suspension of disbelief. And let's add one more clich&eacute; into the mix, just in case you have not had your fill the U-2 songs played as back drops. One star for Jeff Bridges, one for Forrest Whitaker. It's not their fault the script was terrible and predictable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Tommy Lee Jone Gives Oscar Worthy Performance.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vivekmaru45
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For Tommy Lee Jones fans only. This IS the movie that he will be remembered for. I have seen many of his films: The Fugitive, Double Jeopardy, U.S. Marshall's, The Missing, The Hunted, Men In Black 1 & 2, Space Cowboys, Volcano, Batman Forever, Natural Born Killers, In The Valley Of Elah, No Country For Old Man, The Client, Eyes of Laura Mars. *Jones got an Oscar for best supporting actor in The Fugitive. *Jones was also nominated for MTV Movie Awards Best Villain for Blown Away and Batman Forever. The role seems to fit him like a glove. The character he portrays in the film is of an arrogant, dangerous and an untrustworthy person with a one-track mind and a keen eye for revenge. That is the character of Ryan Gaerity, an Irish terrorist imprisoned in Castle Gleigh prison in Northern Ireland. He makes a daring escape to seek vengeance against Liam McGivney, a member of Ryan's original group which also consisted of Ryan's sister who was also Liam's girlfriend. Liam had foiled a plan to bomb some targets chosen be Ryan. As a result he was quickly arrested by the Police and imprisoned for life. Ryan comes to Boston to seek vengeance against Liam, who is semi-retired but working as an instructor with a new identity: Jimmy Dove. Ryan begins taunting his old comrade with threats and his homemade explosives. With his family and friends in danger, he reveals his secret to his wife Kate (Suzy Amis). He returns to action to hunt for Ryan when a former partner of his is killed by one of Ryan's bombs. Fellow officer Anthony Franklin (Forest Whitaker) investigates Jimmy, suspecting a connection between the two. See this superb film directed by Stephen Hopkins (Predator 2, The Ghost And The Darkness) to find out what happens next. Overall the special effects are fantastic, the background music is excellent, script, direction and acting are professionally done. Score 10/10. Flawless film. Buy it on DVD. Similar films: Speed, The Specialist, Executive Decision, The Mechanic, Juggernaut. Email me Vivekmaru45@yahoo.com for info one more movies. Thanks for reading.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the worst Hollywood action thrillers out there.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Paul Andrews (poolandrews@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Blown Away starts at Castle Gleigh Prison in Nothern Ireland as convicted terrorist bomber Ryan Gaerity (Tommy Lee Jones) escapes using his explosive know how. Jumpt to Boston in the US where bomb squad member Jimmy Dove (Jeff Bridges) has decided to retire & new recruit Anthony Franklin (Forest Whitaker) is set to take his place alongside Jimmy's old partner Blanket (Ruben Santiago-Hudson), on their first job Blanket is killed by a booby trapped explosive which forces Jimmy out of retirement. Soon it gets personal for Jimmy as he discovers that his old terrorist mate from Ireland Ryan is behind a series of bombings & he is out for revenge against Jimmy, his family & friends as it was Jimmy who put Ryan behind bars in Ireland all those years ago... Directed by Stephen Hopkins this is actually the second Hopkins directed film I have seen in the past twenty four hours after also seeing The Reaping (2007) yesterday, it wasn't planned & it was a co-incidence & pretty lousy luck as The Reaping was average & this was plain crap. At two hours long Blown Away is very slow going & apart from the last fifteen or so minutes is really dull, lifeless, bland & dare I say it even boring. The melodramatics between Jimmy & his family are unintentionally funny (the scene when his wife jumps in the jacuzzi to shout at Jimmy is pure comedy) while the hero with a dark past role just doesn't suit Bridges, his confrontations with Tommy Lee Jones are awful as it seems to be a contest between the both of them to discover who can do the worst Irish accent. The plot is extremely predictable, routine & by the numbers as the clich&eacute;d tough guy hero with a dark past has to save the day on his own playing by his own rules, any number of better action films use this scenario & add that to a script that offers no surprises (good guy wins in the end, bad guy is stopped) & feels like little or no effort has gone into it. For a big budget action thriller Blown Away is really short on action or thrills, there's a decent explosion at the end, a truck is blown up & there's a speeding jeep & that's it. For a two hour film not enough happens. Footage from Blown Away was edited into two low budget action films called Stealth Fighter (1999) & Agent Red (2000). The Boston locations don't add anything to the film at all to be honest. Apparently the shockwave from the ship explosion at the end shattered 8000 windows in East Boston. If you really want to see an exciting action thriller about bombs then watch Speed (1994) again instead & see how a proper action film should be done. This has decent production values & is well made for what it is but it's still a rubbish film. The acting is poor from a good cast, father & son Jeff & Lloyd Bridges appear here together. Blown Away is a poor action thriller with virtually no action & some poor performances from a decent cast, this is just bad all round really & far too predictable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Totally Blown Away....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Stephen Hopkins 1994 action-packed thriller 'Blown Away' easily ranks amongst the better films from that year. It has a crispy script, fantastic action, superb performances and stylish direction. In short, A winner all the way. 'Blown Away' is a revenge saga about 2 individuals. One believes in violence, while the other keeps away from violence. Hopkins body of work is truly admirable, his direction in here is simply spell-binding. 'Blown Away' has a terrific start, a good middle and an excellent end. This film promises entertainment, and it serves it in abundance. In performances, Jeff Bridges steals the show with a winning performance. He breathes fire in all of his dramatic scenes. Tommy Lee Jones is fantastic as the calculative/conniving villain. He crates a terror in you, without making morbid faces. The Late Lloyd Bridges is lovable. Suzy Amis is very good. In fact, this is her careers best work. Forest Whitaker is excellent from start to end. 'Blown Away' is simply an amazing watch. Two Thumbs Up!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beautifully Showy AND So American !
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ahmed elshikh (ahmed_abd_elreheem@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/10/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's Hollywood. With the good and bad senses of the word. Aside from objection I hold against its standpoint, this is an entertaining movie. In the mid-90s there were many American blockbusters with a plot centers on one bomber and consecutive bombs such as : Speed, The Specialist, Blown Away (all produced in 1994), then Die Hard with a Vengeance (1995). Blown Away stands as one of their best. First it's in the direction. (Stephen Hopkins) is the star of the show. Other work for him like The Ghost and the Darkness (1996), Under Suspicion (2000) got my attention by their clever and charming technique. (Hopkins) here makes every moment thrilling and, thank god, not in a hyped way. The picture was never brighter with an explosion before. Just remember the shot in which the lead takes the bad guy out of the last's cache near the ocean; this "live" piece of action was historically dazzling. In one word : it's showiness as it should be. The script delivers : action, thrill, and hot duel. But nothing is perfect. As I wasn't convinced with matters like a forced nagging (Forest Whitaker); it should have been better as justified enemy turns-into justified friend character. Or how the father (Lloyd Bridges) finds the bad guy (Tommy Lee Jones) plainly and illogically. Plus non-understandable matter like seeing (Jones) crying over killing (Lloyd Bridges) ! (Does he originally love and respect the man? Does he blame himself for killing one of his own people ? Does he hate to murder innocent people ????? I don't know, and I won't know at all !). Let alone the Hollywood clich&eacute;s about the IRA (The Provisional Irish Republican Army) that were so prevalent before the 1998 Belfast agreement. The same you can find in Patriot Games (1992) where the IRA's men are always unmerciful, nearly crazy, assassins. They love to blow up everything and everyone. And their best are the ones whom went to America and stayed there as peaceful citizens ! It could be Hollywood's style of categorizing everyone to only bad guy/good guy, or it's Hollywood's big companies' faith about the IRA, or maybe both ! However you can touch this movie's desire to ignore any political duel by showing the Irish man this time as a maniac who is rejected by the IRA itself, finding a warrant for him to be evil, and turning the whole matter into just another revenge story. Though, why relating him to the IRA from the start ?! It's obvious point of view about anyone who's not American or supporting the American policy, especially when the movie shows information about Palestinians as terrorists the evil man worked with them once. It's sorrowfully typical. Since Hollywood, here, means being illiberal American; namely non-objective (Well, for little instance the Israelis used to kill unarmed men, women and children since ages and I've never seen them as terrorists in one mainstream American movie yet !?). While the 2 leads were cogent and intensive, just casting (Whitaker) was weird. I mean aside from mixed up performance came mainly from weak characterization, he's the last Irish in the world, too heavy to be in a bomb squad, and I don't catch on how they cast him repeatedly as a police officer with the obvious condition of his eye ??! No police officer can make it to be one with that I suppose ! It got madly stimulating Alan Silvestri's soundtrack, unforgettable (Peter Levy)'s cinematography, and masterfully thrilling (Tim Wellburn)'s editing. Enough to remember the climactic sequence in the car. I don't know how this movie wasn't a hit back then. But sure it hits its mark very well. Hollywood movies lately were about abstract explosions and exhausting excitement, with one cliffhanger after another, and non-stop in-the-nick-of-time rescues. (Blown Away) personifies that in iconic way. And even its stereotypes apply to that, since stereotyping became  along the years  part of the show's original formula. The bad, semi-lasting, part.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
