<filme>
 <id>
  579
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0106873
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1993
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Distra&ccedil;&atilde;o Fatal
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  5.3
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  A spoof of the late 80s and early 90s suspense thrillers and murder mysteries, including Basic Instinct, Sleeping With The Enemy, Cape Fear and others. A cop/attorney (yes he's both) is ... &nbsp;&raquo;
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  A spoof of the late 80s and early 90s suspense thrillers and murder mysteries, including Basic Instinct, Sleeping With The Enemy, Cape Fear and others. A cop/attorney (yes he's both) is seduced by a woman while his wife is having an affair with a mechanic. Lots of other sublots and visual gags in the style of Naked Gun. Check the rating !
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Crime
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Thriller
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   gun
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   murder
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   spoof
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   revenge
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   cooking
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Carl Reiner
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   David O'Malley
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Armand Assante
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Sherilyn Fenn
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Kate Nelligan
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An On Target Spoof of the Film Noir Genre
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Gideon24
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    FATAL INSTINCT is a side-split-tingly funny spoof of film noir dramas, in the AIRPLANE/NAKED GUN mode that offers affectionate winks at films like FATAL ATTRACTION, BASIC INSTINCT, THE POSTMAN ALWAYS RINGS TWICE, and CAPE FEAR, offering consistent laughs thanks, in part, to the self- assured direction of comedy icon Carl Reiner. Reiner smartly chose to cast strong actors instead of pure comics whose uncanny ability to play the funny material with completely straight faces is what makes the film so funny. Armand Assante is surprisingly funny as Ned Ravine, a cop and a lawyer who is being cheated on by a scheming wife (Kate Nelligan), being pursued by a sexy client (Sean Young)and being loved from afar by his faithful secretary (Sherilyn Fenn). There are also funny turns from Christopheer McDonald as Nelligan's dim-witted lover, James Remar, in a perfect take off of Max Cady from CAPE FEAR, and Tony Randall as a judge. The gags come fast and furious and most of them work, there's even a very funny cameo by Bob Euker, as a color commentator for a trial. Just sit back, relax, don't think about it too much and there's a lot of fun to be had here.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    As Funny As The Originals.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Nice cast in a sometimes very funny spoof of erotic thrillers that were appearing at the time. Beginning with "Body Heat" in 1981, you could pick one adjective from Column A and one noun from Column B. From Column A: Fatal, Basic, Dangerous, Lethal, or Deadly. From Column B: Affair, Instinct, Liaisons, or Encounters. And then there was the anomalous "Poisonous Panties: The True Story of the Victoria's Secret Murders." This hectic farce rips off scenes and themes from innumerable noirish thrillers with base overtones. I caught "Double Indemnity," "Body Heat," "Sleeping With The Enemy," "The Maltese Falcon," "The Postman Always Rings Twice." I'm not showing off. It's easy. And I'm sure I missed some. The "Airplane" people and those who produced this imitation of imitations -- a kind of meta-imitation -- must have just about run out of gags because there haven't been that many recently. There's no reason to outline the plot. It has something to do with a wife's wanting to kill her husband for insurance but the plot is pulled apart by so many exotic allusions and so much word play, so many quips and monstrous metaphors, so many catachreses and zeugmas and whatnot, that it's often forgotten and just as well. Not that it's a masterpiece of literary play. People are always falling down stairs and doing forward flips for little discernible reason. We're not talking Oscar Wilde, but the dialog is pretty funny. I should have taken notes but, as it is, I can't recall any lines. My short-term memory is getting shoddy. I think my brain is turning to tofu and I may leave it to the American Culinary Institute for analysis. Two observations though. One is that Armand Assante is an excellent comic character. I wouldn't have expected it from him. He put his arrant masculinity to ridiculous use. And Sean Young, for all her off-screen foibles, is a delicious creature, all cream and pearl. I think you'll enjoy this unless you're in an irretrievably dark mood.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Fatally Flawed Comedy That Simply In-Stinks
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    D_Burke
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am well aware of the bad pun I just made in the title of this review. If you didn't think that was funny, all I can tell you is that it is probably funnier than 95% of the gags in this film. I will admit that a couple of the gags here and there elicited a few chuckles out of me, but for the most part, I kept watching this film wondering why a production assistant didn't pull Carl Reiner aside and say, "Sir, this isn't funny. I recommend shutting down production." I'm betting that 1994 must have made for a hell of a family reunion at the Reiner household. Carl Reiner's son, Rob Reiner, ended his hot streak of memorable films when he released "North" (1994), the comedy that almost permanently derailed his career. The elder Reiner, who is also no stranger to funny and often times memorable films ("The Jerk" (1979), "The Man With Two Brains" (1983)), probably felt the same pain as Rob after releasing this forgettable mess of a film. "Fatal Instinct" is a comedy that is a spoof, but is sometimes unsure of just what it is spoofing. It is supposed to be a parody of erotic thrillers that came out in the late '80's and early '90's. Of course, there are many references to scenes in "Fatal Attraction" (1987) and "Basic Instinct" (1992), hence the name of the film. Scenes from other such thrillers like "Sleeping With The Enemy" (1991), "Body Heat" (1981), and "Cape Fear" (1962 or 1991) are also obviously repeated. There are two problems with this films repeating scenes from these movies. First, the key word is "repeat". None of the actors in these scenes even try to reflect the irony of the most memorable moments in these crime thrillers. Sure they reference Sharon Stone's infamous lack of underwear in "Basic Instinct", and Glenn Close's roasting a bunny in a pot in "Fatal Attraction". Simple referencing of such scenes does not make them funny. Second, the film is rated PG-13, which means kids can see it. Because "Basic Instinct" and "Fatal Attraction" were R-rated movies that both came close to being NC-17, kids would not (or should not) have been able to see them. Therefore, any jokes about, or references to, these films, regardless of whether or not they're funny, are going to fly over kids' heads. If you're going to spoof R-rated movies, why not go edgier with the on-screen gags? Kids probably would not want to see the movie anyway, so why did the filmmakers not even think to make this movie R-rated? When the film is not reenacting femme fatale shots from movies adult audience members probably have already seen, it seems as though it inserts infantile gags in an attempt to be "The Naked Gun" (1988). Armand Assante is a good dramatic actor, but in this movie, it seemed as though he tried way too hard to be Leslie Nielsen. Nielsen was funny in the Zucker-Abrahams-Zucker comedies because he said ridiculous things while keeping a straight face. Assante all too often seemed aware of the absurdity of his lines, and his natural comic timing was usually way off. On top of all those errors, there were a lot of really tired running gags. Seeing gum and toilet paper being stuck to Sean Young's high heels wasn't particularly funny the first time, and was even less the fifth time around. The joke about Assante being both a cop and a lawyer was also about as stupid as his closet being full of the same suit. The film was also inundated with really stupid character names (i.e. Max Shady, Judge Skanky), and horrible, obvious puns. Nowhere were these terrible puns more evident than in the courtroom scene. Once the bailiff called for a ten minute recess, guess what happened next? Yep, all the members of the court went outside and played games. Get it? Like it's recess in elementary school!?!?! Ho ho HO!!!!!! Note: By sheer coincidence, there was an equally bad courtroom joke in Rob Reiner's film, "North". When the main character's parents are in comatose during his divorce from them, their attorney says, "I'm afraid the defense rests". Which joke is worse? You decide. So this film was bad. It had very good actors in it that tried way too hard to be funny, and looked stupid as a result. Even worse, there was really no story. The writer of this film seemed to be so busy naming erotic thrillers that the audience never cares about the fate of the characters in THIS movie. The film spins its wheels while managing to go nowhere. Carl Reiner should be thankful to Jason Friedberg and Aaron Seltzer, though. If they hadn't made their awful spoof movies, which are far more guilty of repeating pop culture moments, "Fatal Instinct" would probably be the worst parody film of all time. It is fatal to watch, and you should trust your instinct by not seeing it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An On-Target Spoof of the Film Noir Genre
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Isaac5855
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    FATAL INSTINCT is a side-split-tingly funny spoof of film noir dramas, in the AIRPLANE/NAKED GUN mode that offers affectionate winks at films like FATAL ATTRACTION, BASIC INSTINCT, THE POSTMAN ALWAYS RINGS TWICE, and CAPE FEAR, offering consistent laughs thanks, in part, to the self-assured direction of comedy icon Carl Reiner. Reiner smartly chose to cast strong actors instead of pure comics whose uncanny ability to play the funny material with completely straight faces is what makes the film so funny. Armand Assante is surprisingly funny as Ned Ravine, a cop and a lawyer who is being cheated on by a scheming wife (Kate Nelligan), being pursued by a sexy client (Sean Young)and being loved from afar by his faithful secretary (Sherilyn Fenn). There are also funny turns from Christopheer McDonald as Nelligan's dim-witted lover, James Remar, in a perfect take off of Max Cady from CAPE FEAR, and Tony Randall as a judge. The gags come fast and furious and most of them work, there's even a very funny cameo by Bob Euker, as a color commentator for a trial. Just sit back, relax, don't think about it too much and there's a lot of fun to be had here.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    " On the Count of Monte Christo ? " Not guilty!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thinker1691
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/10/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When a producer selects the actors and actresses for a film, it's usually in his mind what he is looking for. The selection Mr. Carl Reiner made in this film "Fatal Instinct" is nothing short of incredible. Taking a cue from the film parried here ( Fatal Attraction) from the moment it begins, you will begin laughing, so one had better have a good grip on his chair. Whoever selected straight actors or at least actors with a serious streak to do comedy knew they were trolling for gold. What they achieved is memorable in various films, like airplane and Horror Movie. In this hilarious offering, Reiner combines the works of the 1950's black/white films with modern murder venues. Armand Assante is incredible as Ned Ravine, super sleuth and lawyer. Sherilyn Fenn as Laura Lincolnberry, Kate Nelligan is Lana Ravine and Sean Young playing Lola Cain. All take the hero for a mind-bending spin and spoofs and succeed. However, the best selection for real comedy out of his element is none other than James Remar (The Warriors) , who plays, Max Shady. The outcome is fantastic. You've got to see this film for all it's humor. ***
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fatal is right Fatally bad.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Damnthatsgood
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/8/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    With the opening sequence there is a glimmer of hope but roll on a few minutes and it soon becomes clear that this is going to be well short of the mark of decent spoofs like Airplane, Naked Gun and Hot Shots. A good cast does nothing for the poor jokes and bad direction. Some of the cast were totally underused especially John Witherspoon who is extremely funny and might have added that something which was definitely missing from this film. I should have went with my Instinct after the first few minutes and stopped watching, that i'm afraid was my Fatal mistake. Overall if you like the above mentioned spoofs stay well clear of this one.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Spoof comedy with Armand Assante pulling a Leslie Nielsen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moonspinner55
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/7/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Carl Reiner tries his hand at an "Airplane!"-styled spoof of crime-thrillers, such as "Basic Instinct" and "Body Heat", but the results are full of cheap gags and silly smut. Armand Assante is the befuddled cop, Sean Young is the femme fatale, Kate Nelligan is Assante's two-timing spouse, Rosie O'Donnell is...Rosie O'Donnell. Assante, he of the droopy bedroom eyes and self-satisfied smirk, allows himself to be a little ridiculous here, but slapstick buffoonery just isn't in him, and he struggles manfully to have a good time. The movie just doesn't have the correct look of a crime-noir down--and worse, it appears to have been made by a filmmaker with a very standard, square sense of humor. * from ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Why the hell is this rated so low?!?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    craigman
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/5/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I don't understand how a person can watch a very funny and entertaining movie like this and then go on IMDb and give it a low rating! What is wrong with these people?! Do they have no sense of humor? They are probably the same people who didn't see the humor in Airplane! This movie obviously spoofs, or parodies (please forgive me if I don't know the difference!) noir movies and murder thrillers like Basic Instinct and Fatal Attraction, hence the title. Armande Asanti is funnier than most people who are supposed to be funny, like Will Farrell! Also we have the classic beauty Sherilyn Fenn, looking her best as an old fashioned secretary. There are more laugh out loud parts than I can count. They tackle a lot of the clich&eacute;s that have always bugged me, like when the bad person is "killed", they "come to" and try to kill the good person again, and again! The comedic timing is right on the mark, unlike so many unfunny "comedies" that have come out recently. Also, this movie is light on the violence, language and sexual content, so even easily offended people can enjoy it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Shameless spoof of other movies, somewhat funny.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TxMike
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/5/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a parody of such movies as 'Basic Instinct' and 'Fatal Attraction', and others with strained male/female relationships. My neighbor Ron loaned it to me, a budget DVD. Armand Assante is Ned Ravine, cop and lawyer. So he can arrest you, read you your rights (with the help of cue cards), and then defend you in court. Sherilyn Fenn is Laura Lincolnberry, sweet, pretty assistant who secretly is in love with Ned. Kate Nelligan is Ned's wife, Lana Ravine, who is having a torrid affair with Frank, the auto mechanic who never seems to finish the job, played ably by Christopher McDonald (snotty golf professional in 'Happy Gilmore'). The joke is that Ned only sees a drawn out repair job, and is oblivious to the love affair. Tony Randall also does a good turn as Judge Skanky. It would be a mistake to call this a good movie. It has a number of funny moments, but I found it mostly a series of jokes woven into a thin story. However, I found it worthwhile just to see Sherilyn Fenn.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Noir Spoof Worth A Look
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ccthemovieman-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/4/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A wild spoof of suspense and film noirs, I appreciated this silly film a little more than most being a fan of "noirs." As with any comedy, the movie is a combination of genuinely laugh-out-loud gags and sight scenes and genuinely stupid lines. It depends on what makes you laugh. One thing it has for sure: lots of sexual innuendos and just plain overt sexuality. It's yet another one of these PG-13 ratings that is a joke. This is not for kids. Also, this film won't be much for those without a knowledge of classic crime films of the past, from the '40s to the '80s. Many parts of this movie parrot scenes from Fatal Attraction, Body Double, etc. It takes several viewings to catch most of the inside jokes. Armand Assante is the smooth private detective and Sherilyn Fenn is his attractive and loyal secretary. Kate Nelligan, Sean Young and Christopher McDonald add to the fun. To be frank, I enjoyed this more on the first viewing than I did on the second. After watching it twice, I thought the film would have been better had it been cut 10-15 minutes, and it's only 90 minutes. However, I am not knocking it: it's a fun movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An On Target Spoof of the Film Noir Genre
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Gideon24
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    FATAL INSTINCT is a side-split-tingly funny spoof of film noir dramas, in the AIRPLANE/NAKED GUN mode that offers affectionate winks at films like FATAL ATTRACTION, BASIC INSTINCT, THE POSTMAN ALWAYS RINGS TWICE, and CAPE FEAR, offering consistent laughs thanks, in part, to the self- assured direction of comedy icon Carl Reiner. Reiner smartly chose to cast strong actors instead of pure comics whose uncanny ability to play the funny material with completely straight faces is what makes the film so funny. Armand Assante is surprisingly funny as Ned Ravine, a cop and a lawyer who is being cheated on by a scheming wife (Kate Nelligan), being pursued by a sexy client (Sean Young)and being loved from afar by his faithful secretary (Sherilyn Fenn). There are also funny turns from Christopheer McDonald as Nelligan's dim-witted lover, James Remar, in a perfect take off of Max Cady from CAPE FEAR, and Tony Randall as a judge. The gags come fast and furious and most of them work, there's even a very funny cameo by Bob Euker, as a color commentator for a trial. Just sit back, relax, don't think about it too much and there's a lot of fun to be had here.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    As Funny As The Originals.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Nice cast in a sometimes very funny spoof of erotic thrillers that were appearing at the time. Beginning with "Body Heat" in 1981, you could pick one adjective from Column A and one noun from Column B. From Column A: Fatal, Basic, Dangerous, Lethal, or Deadly. From Column B: Affair, Instinct, Liaisons, or Encounters. And then there was the anomalous "Poisonous Panties: The True Story of the Victoria's Secret Murders." This hectic farce rips off scenes and themes from innumerable noirish thrillers with base overtones. I caught "Double Indemnity," "Body Heat," "Sleeping With The Enemy," "The Maltese Falcon," "The Postman Always Rings Twice." I'm not showing off. It's easy. And I'm sure I missed some. The "Airplane" people and those who produced this imitation of imitations -- a kind of meta-imitation -- must have just about run out of gags because there haven't been that many recently. There's no reason to outline the plot. It has something to do with a wife's wanting to kill her husband for insurance but the plot is pulled apart by so many exotic allusions and so much word play, so many quips and monstrous metaphors, so many catachreses and zeugmas and whatnot, that it's often forgotten and just as well. Not that it's a masterpiece of literary play. People are always falling down stairs and doing forward flips for little discernible reason. We're not talking Oscar Wilde, but the dialog is pretty funny. I should have taken notes but, as it is, I can't recall any lines. My short-term memory is getting shoddy. I think my brain is turning to tofu and I may leave it to the American Culinary Institute for analysis. Two observations though. One is that Armand Assante is an excellent comic character. I wouldn't have expected it from him. He put his arrant masculinity to ridiculous use. And Sean Young, for all her off-screen foibles, is a delicious creature, all cream and pearl. I think you'll enjoy this unless you're in an irretrievably dark mood.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Fatally Flawed Comedy That Simply In-Stinks
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    D_Burke
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am well aware of the bad pun I just made in the title of this review. If you didn't think that was funny, all I can tell you is that it is probably funnier than 95% of the gags in this film. I will admit that a couple of the gags here and there elicited a few chuckles out of me, but for the most part, I kept watching this film wondering why a production assistant didn't pull Carl Reiner aside and say, "Sir, this isn't funny. I recommend shutting down production." I'm betting that 1994 must have made for a hell of a family reunion at the Reiner household. Carl Reiner's son, Rob Reiner, ended his hot streak of memorable films when he released "North" (1994), the comedy that almost permanently derailed his career. The elder Reiner, who is also no stranger to funny and often times memorable films ("The Jerk" (1979), "The Man With Two Brains" (1983)), probably felt the same pain as Rob after releasing this forgettable mess of a film. "Fatal Instinct" is a comedy that is a spoof, but is sometimes unsure of just what it is spoofing. It is supposed to be a parody of erotic thrillers that came out in the late '80's and early '90's. Of course, there are many references to scenes in "Fatal Attraction" (1987) and "Basic Instinct" (1992), hence the name of the film. Scenes from other such thrillers like "Sleeping With The Enemy" (1991), "Body Heat" (1981), and "Cape Fear" (1962 or 1991) are also obviously repeated. There are two problems with this films repeating scenes from these movies. First, the key word is "repeat". None of the actors in these scenes even try to reflect the irony of the most memorable moments in these crime thrillers. Sure they reference Sharon Stone's infamous lack of underwear in "Basic Instinct", and Glenn Close's roasting a bunny in a pot in "Fatal Attraction". Simple referencing of such scenes does not make them funny. Second, the film is rated PG-13, which means kids can see it. Because "Basic Instinct" and "Fatal Attraction" were R-rated movies that both came close to being NC-17, kids would not (or should not) have been able to see them. Therefore, any jokes about, or references to, these films, regardless of whether or not they're funny, are going to fly over kids' heads. If you're going to spoof R-rated movies, why not go edgier with the on-screen gags? Kids probably would not want to see the movie anyway, so why did the filmmakers not even think to make this movie R-rated? When the film is not reenacting femme fatale shots from movies adult audience members probably have already seen, it seems as though it inserts infantile gags in an attempt to be "The Naked Gun" (1988). Armand Assante is a good dramatic actor, but in this movie, it seemed as though he tried way too hard to be Leslie Nielsen. Nielsen was funny in the Zucker-Abrahams-Zucker comedies because he said ridiculous things while keeping a straight face. Assante all too often seemed aware of the absurdity of his lines, and his natural comic timing was usually way off. On top of all those errors, there were a lot of really tired running gags. Seeing gum and toilet paper being stuck to Sean Young's high heels wasn't particularly funny the first time, and was even less the fifth time around. The joke about Assante being both a cop and a lawyer was also about as stupid as his closet being full of the same suit. The film was also inundated with really stupid character names (i.e. Max Shady, Judge Skanky), and horrible, obvious puns. Nowhere were these terrible puns more evident than in the courtroom scene. Once the bailiff called for a ten minute recess, guess what happened next? Yep, all the members of the court went outside and played games. Get it? Like it's recess in elementary school!?!?! Ho ho HO!!!!!! Note: By sheer coincidence, there was an equally bad courtroom joke in Rob Reiner's film, "North". When the main character's parents are in comatose during his divorce from them, their attorney says, "I'm afraid the defense rests". Which joke is worse? You decide. So this film was bad. It had very good actors in it that tried way too hard to be funny, and looked stupid as a result. Even worse, there was really no story. The writer of this film seemed to be so busy naming erotic thrillers that the audience never cares about the fate of the characters in THIS movie. The film spins its wheels while managing to go nowhere. Carl Reiner should be thankful to Jason Friedberg and Aaron Seltzer, though. If they hadn't made their awful spoof movies, which are far more guilty of repeating pop culture moments, "Fatal Instinct" would probably be the worst parody film of all time. It is fatal to watch, and you should trust your instinct by not seeing it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An On-Target Spoof of the Film Noir Genre
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Isaac5855
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    FATAL INSTINCT is a side-split-tingly funny spoof of film noir dramas, in the AIRPLANE/NAKED GUN mode that offers affectionate winks at films like FATAL ATTRACTION, BASIC INSTINCT, THE POSTMAN ALWAYS RINGS TWICE, and CAPE FEAR, offering consistent laughs thanks, in part, to the self-assured direction of comedy icon Carl Reiner. Reiner smartly chose to cast strong actors instead of pure comics whose uncanny ability to play the funny material with completely straight faces is what makes the film so funny. Armand Assante is surprisingly funny as Ned Ravine, a cop and a lawyer who is being cheated on by a scheming wife (Kate Nelligan), being pursued by a sexy client (Sean Young)and being loved from afar by his faithful secretary (Sherilyn Fenn). There are also funny turns from Christopheer McDonald as Nelligan's dim-witted lover, James Remar, in a perfect take off of Max Cady from CAPE FEAR, and Tony Randall as a judge. The gags come fast and furious and most of them work, there's even a very funny cameo by Bob Euker, as a color commentator for a trial. Just sit back, relax, don't think about it too much and there's a lot of fun to be had here.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    " On the Count of Monte Christo ? " Not guilty!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thinker1691
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/10/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When a producer selects the actors and actresses for a film, it's usually in his mind what he is looking for. The selection Mr. Carl Reiner made in this film "Fatal Instinct" is nothing short of incredible. Taking a cue from the film parried here ( Fatal Attraction) from the moment it begins, you will begin laughing, so one had better have a good grip on his chair. Whoever selected straight actors or at least actors with a serious streak to do comedy knew they were trolling for gold. What they achieved is memorable in various films, like airplane and Horror Movie. In this hilarious offering, Reiner combines the works of the 1950's black/white films with modern murder venues. Armand Assante is incredible as Ned Ravine, super sleuth and lawyer. Sherilyn Fenn as Laura Lincolnberry, Kate Nelligan is Lana Ravine and Sean Young playing Lola Cain. All take the hero for a mind-bending spin and spoofs and succeed. However, the best selection for real comedy out of his element is none other than James Remar (The Warriors) , who plays, Max Shady. The outcome is fantastic. You've got to see this film for all it's humor. ***
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fatal is right Fatally bad.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Damnthatsgood
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/8/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    With the opening sequence there is a glimmer of hope but roll on a few minutes and it soon becomes clear that this is going to be well short of the mark of decent spoofs like Airplane, Naked Gun and Hot Shots. A good cast does nothing for the poor jokes and bad direction. Some of the cast were totally underused especially John Witherspoon who is extremely funny and might have added that something which was definitely missing from this film. I should have went with my Instinct after the first few minutes and stopped watching, that i'm afraid was my Fatal mistake. Overall if you like the above mentioned spoofs stay well clear of this one.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Spoof comedy with Armand Assante pulling a Leslie Nielsen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moonspinner55
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/7/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Carl Reiner tries his hand at an "Airplane!"-styled spoof of crime-thrillers, such as "Basic Instinct" and "Body Heat", but the results are full of cheap gags and silly smut. Armand Assante is the befuddled cop, Sean Young is the femme fatale, Kate Nelligan is Assante's two-timing spouse, Rosie O'Donnell is...Rosie O'Donnell. Assante, he of the droopy bedroom eyes and self-satisfied smirk, allows himself to be a little ridiculous here, but slapstick buffoonery just isn't in him, and he struggles manfully to have a good time. The movie just doesn't have the correct look of a crime-noir down--and worse, it appears to have been made by a filmmaker with a very standard, square sense of humor. * from ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Why the hell is this rated so low?!?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    craigman
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/5/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I don't understand how a person can watch a very funny and entertaining movie like this and then go on IMDb and give it a low rating! What is wrong with these people?! Do they have no sense of humor? They are probably the same people who didn't see the humor in Airplane! This movie obviously spoofs, or parodies (please forgive me if I don't know the difference!) noir movies and murder thrillers like Basic Instinct and Fatal Attraction, hence the title. Armande Asanti is funnier than most people who are supposed to be funny, like Will Farrell! Also we have the classic beauty Sherilyn Fenn, looking her best as an old fashioned secretary. There are more laugh out loud parts than I can count. They tackle a lot of the clich&eacute;s that have always bugged me, like when the bad person is "killed", they "come to" and try to kill the good person again, and again! The comedic timing is right on the mark, unlike so many unfunny "comedies" that have come out recently. Also, this movie is light on the violence, language and sexual content, so even easily offended people can enjoy it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Shameless spoof of other movies, somewhat funny.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TxMike
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/5/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a parody of such movies as 'Basic Instinct' and 'Fatal Attraction', and others with strained male/female relationships. My neighbor Ron loaned it to me, a budget DVD. Armand Assante is Ned Ravine, cop and lawyer. So he can arrest you, read you your rights (with the help of cue cards), and then defend you in court. Sherilyn Fenn is Laura Lincolnberry, sweet, pretty assistant who secretly is in love with Ned. Kate Nelligan is Ned's wife, Lana Ravine, who is having a torrid affair with Frank, the auto mechanic who never seems to finish the job, played ably by Christopher McDonald (snotty golf professional in 'Happy Gilmore'). The joke is that Ned only sees a drawn out repair job, and is oblivious to the love affair. Tony Randall also does a good turn as Judge Skanky. It would be a mistake to call this a good movie. It has a number of funny moments, but I found it mostly a series of jokes woven into a thin story. However, I found it worthwhile just to see Sherilyn Fenn.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Noir Spoof Worth A Look
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ccthemovieman-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/4/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A wild spoof of suspense and film noirs, I appreciated this silly film a little more than most being a fan of "noirs." As with any comedy, the movie is a combination of genuinely laugh-out-loud gags and sight scenes and genuinely stupid lines. It depends on what makes you laugh. One thing it has for sure: lots of sexual innuendos and just plain overt sexuality. It's yet another one of these PG-13 ratings that is a joke. This is not for kids. Also, this film won't be much for those without a knowledge of classic crime films of the past, from the '40s to the '80s. Many parts of this movie parrot scenes from Fatal Attraction, Body Double, etc. It takes several viewings to catch most of the inside jokes. Armand Assante is the smooth private detective and Sherilyn Fenn is his attractive and loyal secretary. Kate Nelligan, Sean Young and Christopher McDonald add to the fun. To be frank, I enjoyed this more on the first viewing than I did on the second. After watching it twice, I thought the film would have been better had it been cut 10-15 minutes, and it's only 90 minutes. However, I am not knocking it: it's a fun movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An On Target Spoof of the Film Noir Genre
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Gideon24
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    FATAL INSTINCT is a side-split-tingly funny spoof of film noir dramas, in the AIRPLANE/NAKED GUN mode that offers affectionate winks at films like FATAL ATTRACTION, BASIC INSTINCT, THE POSTMAN ALWAYS RINGS TWICE, and CAPE FEAR, offering consistent laughs thanks, in part, to the self- assured direction of comedy icon Carl Reiner. Reiner smartly chose to cast strong actors instead of pure comics whose uncanny ability to play the funny material with completely straight faces is what makes the film so funny. Armand Assante is surprisingly funny as Ned Ravine, a cop and a lawyer who is being cheated on by a scheming wife (Kate Nelligan), being pursued by a sexy client (Sean Young)and being loved from afar by his faithful secretary (Sherilyn Fenn). There are also funny turns from Christopheer McDonald as Nelligan's dim-witted lover, James Remar, in a perfect take off of Max Cady from CAPE FEAR, and Tony Randall as a judge. The gags come fast and furious and most of them work, there's even a very funny cameo by Bob Euker, as a color commentator for a trial. Just sit back, relax, don't think about it too much and there's a lot of fun to be had here.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    As Funny As The Originals.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Nice cast in a sometimes very funny spoof of erotic thrillers that were appearing at the time. Beginning with "Body Heat" in 1981, you could pick one adjective from Column A and one noun from Column B. From Column A: Fatal, Basic, Dangerous, Lethal, or Deadly. From Column B: Affair, Instinct, Liaisons, or Encounters. And then there was the anomalous "Poisonous Panties: The True Story of the Victoria's Secret Murders." This hectic farce rips off scenes and themes from innumerable noirish thrillers with base overtones. I caught "Double Indemnity," "Body Heat," "Sleeping With The Enemy," "The Maltese Falcon," "The Postman Always Rings Twice." I'm not showing off. It's easy. And I'm sure I missed some. The "Airplane" people and those who produced this imitation of imitations -- a kind of meta-imitation -- must have just about run out of gags because there haven't been that many recently. There's no reason to outline the plot. It has something to do with a wife's wanting to kill her husband for insurance but the plot is pulled apart by so many exotic allusions and so much word play, so many quips and monstrous metaphors, so many catachreses and zeugmas and whatnot, that it's often forgotten and just as well. Not that it's a masterpiece of literary play. People are always falling down stairs and doing forward flips for little discernible reason. We're not talking Oscar Wilde, but the dialog is pretty funny. I should have taken notes but, as it is, I can't recall any lines. My short-term memory is getting shoddy. I think my brain is turning to tofu and I may leave it to the American Culinary Institute for analysis. Two observations though. One is that Armand Assante is an excellent comic character. I wouldn't have expected it from him. He put his arrant masculinity to ridiculous use. And Sean Young, for all her off-screen foibles, is a delicious creature, all cream and pearl. I think you'll enjoy this unless you're in an irretrievably dark mood.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Fatally Flawed Comedy That Simply In-Stinks
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    D_Burke
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am well aware of the bad pun I just made in the title of this review. If you didn't think that was funny, all I can tell you is that it is probably funnier than 95% of the gags in this film. I will admit that a couple of the gags here and there elicited a few chuckles out of me, but for the most part, I kept watching this film wondering why a production assistant didn't pull Carl Reiner aside and say, "Sir, this isn't funny. I recommend shutting down production." I'm betting that 1994 must have made for a hell of a family reunion at the Reiner household. Carl Reiner's son, Rob Reiner, ended his hot streak of memorable films when he released "North" (1994), the comedy that almost permanently derailed his career. The elder Reiner, who is also no stranger to funny and often times memorable films ("The Jerk" (1979), "The Man With Two Brains" (1983)), probably felt the same pain as Rob after releasing this forgettable mess of a film. "Fatal Instinct" is a comedy that is a spoof, but is sometimes unsure of just what it is spoofing. It is supposed to be a parody of erotic thrillers that came out in the late '80's and early '90's. Of course, there are many references to scenes in "Fatal Attraction" (1987) and "Basic Instinct" (1992), hence the name of the film. Scenes from other such thrillers like "Sleeping With The Enemy" (1991), "Body Heat" (1981), and "Cape Fear" (1962 or 1991) are also obviously repeated. There are two problems with this films repeating scenes from these movies. First, the key word is "repeat". None of the actors in these scenes even try to reflect the irony of the most memorable moments in these crime thrillers. Sure they reference Sharon Stone's infamous lack of underwear in "Basic Instinct", and Glenn Close's roasting a bunny in a pot in "Fatal Attraction". Simple referencing of such scenes does not make them funny. Second, the film is rated PG-13, which means kids can see it. Because "Basic Instinct" and "Fatal Attraction" were R-rated movies that both came close to being NC-17, kids would not (or should not) have been able to see them. Therefore, any jokes about, or references to, these films, regardless of whether or not they're funny, are going to fly over kids' heads. If you're going to spoof R-rated movies, why not go edgier with the on-screen gags? Kids probably would not want to see the movie anyway, so why did the filmmakers not even think to make this movie R-rated? When the film is not reenacting femme fatale shots from movies adult audience members probably have already seen, it seems as though it inserts infantile gags in an attempt to be "The Naked Gun" (1988). Armand Assante is a good dramatic actor, but in this movie, it seemed as though he tried way too hard to be Leslie Nielsen. Nielsen was funny in the Zucker-Abrahams-Zucker comedies because he said ridiculous things while keeping a straight face. Assante all too often seemed aware of the absurdity of his lines, and his natural comic timing was usually way off. On top of all those errors, there were a lot of really tired running gags. Seeing gum and toilet paper being stuck to Sean Young's high heels wasn't particularly funny the first time, and was even less the fifth time around. The joke about Assante being both a cop and a lawyer was also about as stupid as his closet being full of the same suit. The film was also inundated with really stupid character names (i.e. Max Shady, Judge Skanky), and horrible, obvious puns. Nowhere were these terrible puns more evident than in the courtroom scene. Once the bailiff called for a ten minute recess, guess what happened next? Yep, all the members of the court went outside and played games. Get it? Like it's recess in elementary school!?!?! Ho ho HO!!!!!! Note: By sheer coincidence, there was an equally bad courtroom joke in Rob Reiner's film, "North". When the main character's parents are in comatose during his divorce from them, their attorney says, "I'm afraid the defense rests". Which joke is worse? You decide. So this film was bad. It had very good actors in it that tried way too hard to be funny, and looked stupid as a result. Even worse, there was really no story. The writer of this film seemed to be so busy naming erotic thrillers that the audience never cares about the fate of the characters in THIS movie. The film spins its wheels while managing to go nowhere. Carl Reiner should be thankful to Jason Friedberg and Aaron Seltzer, though. If they hadn't made their awful spoof movies, which are far more guilty of repeating pop culture moments, "Fatal Instinct" would probably be the worst parody film of all time. It is fatal to watch, and you should trust your instinct by not seeing it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An On-Target Spoof of the Film Noir Genre
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Isaac5855
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    FATAL INSTINCT is a side-split-tingly funny spoof of film noir dramas, in the AIRPLANE/NAKED GUN mode that offers affectionate winks at films like FATAL ATTRACTION, BASIC INSTINCT, THE POSTMAN ALWAYS RINGS TWICE, and CAPE FEAR, offering consistent laughs thanks, in part, to the self-assured direction of comedy icon Carl Reiner. Reiner smartly chose to cast strong actors instead of pure comics whose uncanny ability to play the funny material with completely straight faces is what makes the film so funny. Armand Assante is surprisingly funny as Ned Ravine, a cop and a lawyer who is being cheated on by a scheming wife (Kate Nelligan), being pursued by a sexy client (Sean Young)and being loved from afar by his faithful secretary (Sherilyn Fenn). There are also funny turns from Christopheer McDonald as Nelligan's dim-witted lover, James Remar, in a perfect take off of Max Cady from CAPE FEAR, and Tony Randall as a judge. The gags come fast and furious and most of them work, there's even a very funny cameo by Bob Euker, as a color commentator for a trial. Just sit back, relax, don't think about it too much and there's a lot of fun to be had here.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    " On the Count of Monte Christo ? " Not guilty!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thinker1691
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/10/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When a producer selects the actors and actresses for a film, it's usually in his mind what he is looking for. The selection Mr. Carl Reiner made in this film "Fatal Instinct" is nothing short of incredible. Taking a cue from the film parried here ( Fatal Attraction) from the moment it begins, you will begin laughing, so one had better have a good grip on his chair. Whoever selected straight actors or at least actors with a serious streak to do comedy knew they were trolling for gold. What they achieved is memorable in various films, like airplane and Horror Movie. In this hilarious offering, Reiner combines the works of the 1950's black/white films with modern murder venues. Armand Assante is incredible as Ned Ravine, super sleuth and lawyer. Sherilyn Fenn as Laura Lincolnberry, Kate Nelligan is Lana Ravine and Sean Young playing Lola Cain. All take the hero for a mind-bending spin and spoofs and succeed. However, the best selection for real comedy out of his element is none other than James Remar (The Warriors) , who plays, Max Shady. The outcome is fantastic. You've got to see this film for all it's humor. ***
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fatal is right Fatally bad.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Damnthatsgood
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/8/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    With the opening sequence there is a glimmer of hope but roll on a few minutes and it soon becomes clear that this is going to be well short of the mark of decent spoofs like Airplane, Naked Gun and Hot Shots. A good cast does nothing for the poor jokes and bad direction. Some of the cast were totally underused especially John Witherspoon who is extremely funny and might have added that something which was definitely missing from this film. I should have went with my Instinct after the first few minutes and stopped watching, that i'm afraid was my Fatal mistake. Overall if you like the above mentioned spoofs stay well clear of this one.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Spoof comedy with Armand Assante pulling a Leslie Nielsen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moonspinner55
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/7/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Carl Reiner tries his hand at an "Airplane!"-styled spoof of crime-thrillers, such as "Basic Instinct" and "Body Heat", but the results are full of cheap gags and silly smut. Armand Assante is the befuddled cop, Sean Young is the femme fatale, Kate Nelligan is Assante's two-timing spouse, Rosie O'Donnell is...Rosie O'Donnell. Assante, he of the droopy bedroom eyes and self-satisfied smirk, allows himself to be a little ridiculous here, but slapstick buffoonery just isn't in him, and he struggles manfully to have a good time. The movie just doesn't have the correct look of a crime-noir down--and worse, it appears to have been made by a filmmaker with a very standard, square sense of humor. * from ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Why the hell is this rated so low?!?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    craigman
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/5/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I don't understand how a person can watch a very funny and entertaining movie like this and then go on IMDb and give it a low rating! What is wrong with these people?! Do they have no sense of humor? They are probably the same people who didn't see the humor in Airplane! This movie obviously spoofs, or parodies (please forgive me if I don't know the difference!) noir movies and murder thrillers like Basic Instinct and Fatal Attraction, hence the title. Armande Asanti is funnier than most people who are supposed to be funny, like Will Farrell! Also we have the classic beauty Sherilyn Fenn, looking her best as an old fashioned secretary. There are more laugh out loud parts than I can count. They tackle a lot of the clich&eacute;s that have always bugged me, like when the bad person is "killed", they "come to" and try to kill the good person again, and again! The comedic timing is right on the mark, unlike so many unfunny "comedies" that have come out recently. Also, this movie is light on the violence, language and sexual content, so even easily offended people can enjoy it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Shameless spoof of other movies, somewhat funny.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TxMike
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/5/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a parody of such movies as 'Basic Instinct' and 'Fatal Attraction', and others with strained male/female relationships. My neighbor Ron loaned it to me, a budget DVD. Armand Assante is Ned Ravine, cop and lawyer. So he can arrest you, read you your rights (with the help of cue cards), and then defend you in court. Sherilyn Fenn is Laura Lincolnberry, sweet, pretty assistant who secretly is in love with Ned. Kate Nelligan is Ned's wife, Lana Ravine, who is having a torrid affair with Frank, the auto mechanic who never seems to finish the job, played ably by Christopher McDonald (snotty golf professional in 'Happy Gilmore'). The joke is that Ned only sees a drawn out repair job, and is oblivious to the love affair. Tony Randall also does a good turn as Judge Skanky. It would be a mistake to call this a good movie. It has a number of funny moments, but I found it mostly a series of jokes woven into a thin story. However, I found it worthwhile just to see Sherilyn Fenn.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Noir Spoof Worth A Look
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ccthemovieman-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/4/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A wild spoof of suspense and film noirs, I appreciated this silly film a little more than most being a fan of "noirs." As with any comedy, the movie is a combination of genuinely laugh-out-loud gags and sight scenes and genuinely stupid lines. It depends on what makes you laugh. One thing it has for sure: lots of sexual innuendos and just plain overt sexuality. It's yet another one of these PG-13 ratings that is a joke. This is not for kids. Also, this film won't be much for those without a knowledge of classic crime films of the past, from the '40s to the '80s. Many parts of this movie parrot scenes from Fatal Attraction, Body Double, etc. It takes several viewings to catch most of the inside jokes. Armand Assante is the smooth private detective and Sherilyn Fenn is his attractive and loyal secretary. Kate Nelligan, Sean Young and Christopher McDonald add to the fun. To be frank, I enjoyed this more on the first viewing than I did on the second. After watching it twice, I thought the film would have been better had it been cut 10-15 minutes, and it's only 90 minutes. However, I am not knocking it: it's a fun movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An On Target Spoof of the Film Noir Genre
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Gideon24
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    FATAL INSTINCT is a side-split-tingly funny spoof of film noir dramas, in the AIRPLANE/NAKED GUN mode that offers affectionate winks at films like FATAL ATTRACTION, BASIC INSTINCT, THE POSTMAN ALWAYS RINGS TWICE, and CAPE FEAR, offering consistent laughs thanks, in part, to the self- assured direction of comedy icon Carl Reiner. Reiner smartly chose to cast strong actors instead of pure comics whose uncanny ability to play the funny material with completely straight faces is what makes the film so funny. Armand Assante is surprisingly funny as Ned Ravine, a cop and a lawyer who is being cheated on by a scheming wife (Kate Nelligan), being pursued by a sexy client (Sean Young)and being loved from afar by his faithful secretary (Sherilyn Fenn). There are also funny turns from Christopheer McDonald as Nelligan's dim-witted lover, James Remar, in a perfect take off of Max Cady from CAPE FEAR, and Tony Randall as a judge. The gags come fast and furious and most of them work, there's even a very funny cameo by Bob Euker, as a color commentator for a trial. Just sit back, relax, don't think about it too much and there's a lot of fun to be had here.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    As Funny As The Originals.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Nice cast in a sometimes very funny spoof of erotic thrillers that were appearing at the time. Beginning with "Body Heat" in 1981, you could pick one adjective from Column A and one noun from Column B. From Column A: Fatal, Basic, Dangerous, Lethal, or Deadly. From Column B: Affair, Instinct, Liaisons, or Encounters. And then there was the anomalous "Poisonous Panties: The True Story of the Victoria's Secret Murders." This hectic farce rips off scenes and themes from innumerable noirish thrillers with base overtones. I caught "Double Indemnity," "Body Heat," "Sleeping With The Enemy," "The Maltese Falcon," "The Postman Always Rings Twice." I'm not showing off. It's easy. And I'm sure I missed some. The "Airplane" people and those who produced this imitation of imitations -- a kind of meta-imitation -- must have just about run out of gags because there haven't been that many recently. There's no reason to outline the plot. It has something to do with a wife's wanting to kill her husband for insurance but the plot is pulled apart by so many exotic allusions and so much word play, so many quips and monstrous metaphors, so many catachreses and zeugmas and whatnot, that it's often forgotten and just as well. Not that it's a masterpiece of literary play. People are always falling down stairs and doing forward flips for little discernible reason. We're not talking Oscar Wilde, but the dialog is pretty funny. I should have taken notes but, as it is, I can't recall any lines. My short-term memory is getting shoddy. I think my brain is turning to tofu and I may leave it to the American Culinary Institute for analysis. Two observations though. One is that Armand Assante is an excellent comic character. I wouldn't have expected it from him. He put his arrant masculinity to ridiculous use. And Sean Young, for all her off-screen foibles, is a delicious creature, all cream and pearl. I think you'll enjoy this unless you're in an irretrievably dark mood.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Fatally Flawed Comedy That Simply In-Stinks
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    D_Burke
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am well aware of the bad pun I just made in the title of this review. If you didn't think that was funny, all I can tell you is that it is probably funnier than 95% of the gags in this film. I will admit that a couple of the gags here and there elicited a few chuckles out of me, but for the most part, I kept watching this film wondering why a production assistant didn't pull Carl Reiner aside and say, "Sir, this isn't funny. I recommend shutting down production." I'm betting that 1994 must have made for a hell of a family reunion at the Reiner household. Carl Reiner's son, Rob Reiner, ended his hot streak of memorable films when he released "North" (1994), the comedy that almost permanently derailed his career. The elder Reiner, who is also no stranger to funny and often times memorable films ("The Jerk" (1979), "The Man With Two Brains" (1983)), probably felt the same pain as Rob after releasing this forgettable mess of a film. "Fatal Instinct" is a comedy that is a spoof, but is sometimes unsure of just what it is spoofing. It is supposed to be a parody of erotic thrillers that came out in the late '80's and early '90's. Of course, there are many references to scenes in "Fatal Attraction" (1987) and "Basic Instinct" (1992), hence the name of the film. Scenes from other such thrillers like "Sleeping With The Enemy" (1991), "Body Heat" (1981), and "Cape Fear" (1962 or 1991) are also obviously repeated. There are two problems with this films repeating scenes from these movies. First, the key word is "repeat". None of the actors in these scenes even try to reflect the irony of the most memorable moments in these crime thrillers. Sure they reference Sharon Stone's infamous lack of underwear in "Basic Instinct", and Glenn Close's roasting a bunny in a pot in "Fatal Attraction". Simple referencing of such scenes does not make them funny. Second, the film is rated PG-13, which means kids can see it. Because "Basic Instinct" and "Fatal Attraction" were R-rated movies that both came close to being NC-17, kids would not (or should not) have been able to see them. Therefore, any jokes about, or references to, these films, regardless of whether or not they're funny, are going to fly over kids' heads. If you're going to spoof R-rated movies, why not go edgier with the on-screen gags? Kids probably would not want to see the movie anyway, so why did the filmmakers not even think to make this movie R-rated? When the film is not reenacting femme fatale shots from movies adult audience members probably have already seen, it seems as though it inserts infantile gags in an attempt to be "The Naked Gun" (1988). Armand Assante is a good dramatic actor, but in this movie, it seemed as though he tried way too hard to be Leslie Nielsen. Nielsen was funny in the Zucker-Abrahams-Zucker comedies because he said ridiculous things while keeping a straight face. Assante all too often seemed aware of the absurdity of his lines, and his natural comic timing was usually way off. On top of all those errors, there were a lot of really tired running gags. Seeing gum and toilet paper being stuck to Sean Young's high heels wasn't particularly funny the first time, and was even less the fifth time around. The joke about Assante being both a cop and a lawyer was also about as stupid as his closet being full of the same suit. The film was also inundated with really stupid character names (i.e. Max Shady, Judge Skanky), and horrible, obvious puns. Nowhere were these terrible puns more evident than in the courtroom scene. Once the bailiff called for a ten minute recess, guess what happened next? Yep, all the members of the court went outside and played games. Get it? Like it's recess in elementary school!?!?! Ho ho HO!!!!!! Note: By sheer coincidence, there was an equally bad courtroom joke in Rob Reiner's film, "North". When the main character's parents are in comatose during his divorce from them, their attorney says, "I'm afraid the defense rests". Which joke is worse? You decide. So this film was bad. It had very good actors in it that tried way too hard to be funny, and looked stupid as a result. Even worse, there was really no story. The writer of this film seemed to be so busy naming erotic thrillers that the audience never cares about the fate of the characters in THIS movie. The film spins its wheels while managing to go nowhere. Carl Reiner should be thankful to Jason Friedberg and Aaron Seltzer, though. If they hadn't made their awful spoof movies, which are far more guilty of repeating pop culture moments, "Fatal Instinct" would probably be the worst parody film of all time. It is fatal to watch, and you should trust your instinct by not seeing it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An On-Target Spoof of the Film Noir Genre
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Isaac5855
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    FATAL INSTINCT is a side-split-tingly funny spoof of film noir dramas, in the AIRPLANE/NAKED GUN mode that offers affectionate winks at films like FATAL ATTRACTION, BASIC INSTINCT, THE POSTMAN ALWAYS RINGS TWICE, and CAPE FEAR, offering consistent laughs thanks, in part, to the self-assured direction of comedy icon Carl Reiner. Reiner smartly chose to cast strong actors instead of pure comics whose uncanny ability to play the funny material with completely straight faces is what makes the film so funny. Armand Assante is surprisingly funny as Ned Ravine, a cop and a lawyer who is being cheated on by a scheming wife (Kate Nelligan), being pursued by a sexy client (Sean Young)and being loved from afar by his faithful secretary (Sherilyn Fenn). There are also funny turns from Christopheer McDonald as Nelligan's dim-witted lover, James Remar, in a perfect take off of Max Cady from CAPE FEAR, and Tony Randall as a judge. The gags come fast and furious and most of them work, there's even a very funny cameo by Bob Euker, as a color commentator for a trial. Just sit back, relax, don't think about it too much and there's a lot of fun to be had here.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    " On the Count of Monte Christo ? " Not guilty!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thinker1691
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/10/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When a producer selects the actors and actresses for a film, it's usually in his mind what he is looking for. The selection Mr. Carl Reiner made in this film "Fatal Instinct" is nothing short of incredible. Taking a cue from the film parried here ( Fatal Attraction) from the moment it begins, you will begin laughing, so one had better have a good grip on his chair. Whoever selected straight actors or at least actors with a serious streak to do comedy knew they were trolling for gold. What they achieved is memorable in various films, like airplane and Horror Movie. In this hilarious offering, Reiner combines the works of the 1950's black/white films with modern murder venues. Armand Assante is incredible as Ned Ravine, super sleuth and lawyer. Sherilyn Fenn as Laura Lincolnberry, Kate Nelligan is Lana Ravine and Sean Young playing Lola Cain. All take the hero for a mind-bending spin and spoofs and succeed. However, the best selection for real comedy out of his element is none other than James Remar (The Warriors) , who plays, Max Shady. The outcome is fantastic. You've got to see this film for all it's humor. ***
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fatal is right Fatally bad.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Damnthatsgood
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/8/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    With the opening sequence there is a glimmer of hope but roll on a few minutes and it soon becomes clear that this is going to be well short of the mark of decent spoofs like Airplane, Naked Gun and Hot Shots. A good cast does nothing for the poor jokes and bad direction. Some of the cast were totally underused especially John Witherspoon who is extremely funny and might have added that something which was definitely missing from this film. I should have went with my Instinct after the first few minutes and stopped watching, that i'm afraid was my Fatal mistake. Overall if you like the above mentioned spoofs stay well clear of this one.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Spoof comedy with Armand Assante pulling a Leslie Nielsen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moonspinner55
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/7/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Carl Reiner tries his hand at an "Airplane!"-styled spoof of crime-thrillers, such as "Basic Instinct" and "Body Heat", but the results are full of cheap gags and silly smut. Armand Assante is the befuddled cop, Sean Young is the femme fatale, Kate Nelligan is Assante's two-timing spouse, Rosie O'Donnell is...Rosie O'Donnell. Assante, he of the droopy bedroom eyes and self-satisfied smirk, allows himself to be a little ridiculous here, but slapstick buffoonery just isn't in him, and he struggles manfully to have a good time. The movie just doesn't have the correct look of a crime-noir down--and worse, it appears to have been made by a filmmaker with a very standard, square sense of humor. * from ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Why the hell is this rated so low?!?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    craigman
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/5/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I don't understand how a person can watch a very funny and entertaining movie like this and then go on IMDb and give it a low rating! What is wrong with these people?! Do they have no sense of humor? They are probably the same people who didn't see the humor in Airplane! This movie obviously spoofs, or parodies (please forgive me if I don't know the difference!) noir movies and murder thrillers like Basic Instinct and Fatal Attraction, hence the title. Armande Asanti is funnier than most people who are supposed to be funny, like Will Farrell! Also we have the classic beauty Sherilyn Fenn, looking her best as an old fashioned secretary. There are more laugh out loud parts than I can count. They tackle a lot of the clich&eacute;s that have always bugged me, like when the bad person is "killed", they "come to" and try to kill the good person again, and again! The comedic timing is right on the mark, unlike so many unfunny "comedies" that have come out recently. Also, this movie is light on the violence, language and sexual content, so even easily offended people can enjoy it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Shameless spoof of other movies, somewhat funny.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TxMike
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/5/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a parody of such movies as 'Basic Instinct' and 'Fatal Attraction', and others with strained male/female relationships. My neighbor Ron loaned it to me, a budget DVD. Armand Assante is Ned Ravine, cop and lawyer. So he can arrest you, read you your rights (with the help of cue cards), and then defend you in court. Sherilyn Fenn is Laura Lincolnberry, sweet, pretty assistant who secretly is in love with Ned. Kate Nelligan is Ned's wife, Lana Ravine, who is having a torrid affair with Frank, the auto mechanic who never seems to finish the job, played ably by Christopher McDonald (snotty golf professional in 'Happy Gilmore'). The joke is that Ned only sees a drawn out repair job, and is oblivious to the love affair. Tony Randall also does a good turn as Judge Skanky. It would be a mistake to call this a good movie. It has a number of funny moments, but I found it mostly a series of jokes woven into a thin story. However, I found it worthwhile just to see Sherilyn Fenn.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Noir Spoof Worth A Look
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ccthemovieman-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/4/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A wild spoof of suspense and film noirs, I appreciated this silly film a little more than most being a fan of "noirs." As with any comedy, the movie is a combination of genuinely laugh-out-loud gags and sight scenes and genuinely stupid lines. It depends on what makes you laugh. One thing it has for sure: lots of sexual innuendos and just plain overt sexuality. It's yet another one of these PG-13 ratings that is a joke. This is not for kids. Also, this film won't be much for those without a knowledge of classic crime films of the past, from the '40s to the '80s. Many parts of this movie parrot scenes from Fatal Attraction, Body Double, etc. It takes several viewings to catch most of the inside jokes. Armand Assante is the smooth private detective and Sherilyn Fenn is his attractive and loyal secretary. Kate Nelligan, Sean Young and Christopher McDonald add to the fun. To be frank, I enjoyed this more on the first viewing than I did on the second. After watching it twice, I thought the film would have been better had it been cut 10-15 minutes, and it's only 90 minutes. However, I am not knocking it: it's a fun movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An On Target Spoof of the Film Noir Genre
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Gideon24
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    FATAL INSTINCT is a side-split-tingly funny spoof of film noir dramas, in the AIRPLANE/NAKED GUN mode that offers affectionate winks at films like FATAL ATTRACTION, BASIC INSTINCT, THE POSTMAN ALWAYS RINGS TWICE, and CAPE FEAR, offering consistent laughs thanks, in part, to the self- assured direction of comedy icon Carl Reiner. Reiner smartly chose to cast strong actors instead of pure comics whose uncanny ability to play the funny material with completely straight faces is what makes the film so funny. Armand Assante is surprisingly funny as Ned Ravine, a cop and a lawyer who is being cheated on by a scheming wife (Kate Nelligan), being pursued by a sexy client (Sean Young)and being loved from afar by his faithful secretary (Sherilyn Fenn). There are also funny turns from Christopheer McDonald as Nelligan's dim-witted lover, James Remar, in a perfect take off of Max Cady from CAPE FEAR, and Tony Randall as a judge. The gags come fast and furious and most of them work, there's even a very funny cameo by Bob Euker, as a color commentator for a trial. Just sit back, relax, don't think about it too much and there's a lot of fun to be had here.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    As Funny As The Originals.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Nice cast in a sometimes very funny spoof of erotic thrillers that were appearing at the time. Beginning with "Body Heat" in 1981, you could pick one adjective from Column A and one noun from Column B. From Column A: Fatal, Basic, Dangerous, Lethal, or Deadly. From Column B: Affair, Instinct, Liaisons, or Encounters. And then there was the anomalous "Poisonous Panties: The True Story of the Victoria's Secret Murders." This hectic farce rips off scenes and themes from innumerable noirish thrillers with base overtones. I caught "Double Indemnity," "Body Heat," "Sleeping With The Enemy," "The Maltese Falcon," "The Postman Always Rings Twice." I'm not showing off. It's easy. And I'm sure I missed some. The "Airplane" people and those who produced this imitation of imitations -- a kind of meta-imitation -- must have just about run out of gags because there haven't been that many recently. There's no reason to outline the plot. It has something to do with a wife's wanting to kill her husband for insurance but the plot is pulled apart by so many exotic allusions and so much word play, so many quips and monstrous metaphors, so many catachreses and zeugmas and whatnot, that it's often forgotten and just as well. Not that it's a masterpiece of literary play. People are always falling down stairs and doing forward flips for little discernible reason. We're not talking Oscar Wilde, but the dialog is pretty funny. I should have taken notes but, as it is, I can't recall any lines. My short-term memory is getting shoddy. I think my brain is turning to tofu and I may leave it to the American Culinary Institute for analysis. Two observations though. One is that Armand Assante is an excellent comic character. I wouldn't have expected it from him. He put his arrant masculinity to ridiculous use. And Sean Young, for all her off-screen foibles, is a delicious creature, all cream and pearl. I think you'll enjoy this unless you're in an irretrievably dark mood.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Fatally Flawed Comedy That Simply In-Stinks
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    D_Burke
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am well aware of the bad pun I just made in the title of this review. If you didn't think that was funny, all I can tell you is that it is probably funnier than 95% of the gags in this film. I will admit that a couple of the gags here and there elicited a few chuckles out of me, but for the most part, I kept watching this film wondering why a production assistant didn't pull Carl Reiner aside and say, "Sir, this isn't funny. I recommend shutting down production." I'm betting that 1994 must have made for a hell of a family reunion at the Reiner household. Carl Reiner's son, Rob Reiner, ended his hot streak of memorable films when he released "North" (1994), the comedy that almost permanently derailed his career. The elder Reiner, who is also no stranger to funny and often times memorable films ("The Jerk" (1979), "The Man With Two Brains" (1983)), probably felt the same pain as Rob after releasing this forgettable mess of a film. "Fatal Instinct" is a comedy that is a spoof, but is sometimes unsure of just what it is spoofing. It is supposed to be a parody of erotic thrillers that came out in the late '80's and early '90's. Of course, there are many references to scenes in "Fatal Attraction" (1987) and "Basic Instinct" (1992), hence the name of the film. Scenes from other such thrillers like "Sleeping With The Enemy" (1991), "Body Heat" (1981), and "Cape Fear" (1962 or 1991) are also obviously repeated. There are two problems with this films repeating scenes from these movies. First, the key word is "repeat". None of the actors in these scenes even try to reflect the irony of the most memorable moments in these crime thrillers. Sure they reference Sharon Stone's infamous lack of underwear in "Basic Instinct", and Glenn Close's roasting a bunny in a pot in "Fatal Attraction". Simple referencing of such scenes does not make them funny. Second, the film is rated PG-13, which means kids can see it. Because "Basic Instinct" and "Fatal Attraction" were R-rated movies that both came close to being NC-17, kids would not (or should not) have been able to see them. Therefore, any jokes about, or references to, these films, regardless of whether or not they're funny, are going to fly over kids' heads. If you're going to spoof R-rated movies, why not go edgier with the on-screen gags? Kids probably would not want to see the movie anyway, so why did the filmmakers not even think to make this movie R-rated? When the film is not reenacting femme fatale shots from movies adult audience members probably have already seen, it seems as though it inserts infantile gags in an attempt to be "The Naked Gun" (1988). Armand Assante is a good dramatic actor, but in this movie, it seemed as though he tried way too hard to be Leslie Nielsen. Nielsen was funny in the Zucker-Abrahams-Zucker comedies because he said ridiculous things while keeping a straight face. Assante all too often seemed aware of the absurdity of his lines, and his natural comic timing was usually way off. On top of all those errors, there were a lot of really tired running gags. Seeing gum and toilet paper being stuck to Sean Young's high heels wasn't particularly funny the first time, and was even less the fifth time around. The joke about Assante being both a cop and a lawyer was also about as stupid as his closet being full of the same suit. The film was also inundated with really stupid character names (i.e. Max Shady, Judge Skanky), and horrible, obvious puns. Nowhere were these terrible puns more evident than in the courtroom scene. Once the bailiff called for a ten minute recess, guess what happened next? Yep, all the members of the court went outside and played games. Get it? Like it's recess in elementary school!?!?! Ho ho HO!!!!!! Note: By sheer coincidence, there was an equally bad courtroom joke in Rob Reiner's film, "North". When the main character's parents are in comatose during his divorce from them, their attorney says, "I'm afraid the defense rests". Which joke is worse? You decide. So this film was bad. It had very good actors in it that tried way too hard to be funny, and looked stupid as a result. Even worse, there was really no story. The writer of this film seemed to be so busy naming erotic thrillers that the audience never cares about the fate of the characters in THIS movie. The film spins its wheels while managing to go nowhere. Carl Reiner should be thankful to Jason Friedberg and Aaron Seltzer, though. If they hadn't made their awful spoof movies, which are far more guilty of repeating pop culture moments, "Fatal Instinct" would probably be the worst parody film of all time. It is fatal to watch, and you should trust your instinct by not seeing it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An On-Target Spoof of the Film Noir Genre
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Isaac5855
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    FATAL INSTINCT is a side-split-tingly funny spoof of film noir dramas, in the AIRPLANE/NAKED GUN mode that offers affectionate winks at films like FATAL ATTRACTION, BASIC INSTINCT, THE POSTMAN ALWAYS RINGS TWICE, and CAPE FEAR, offering consistent laughs thanks, in part, to the self-assured direction of comedy icon Carl Reiner. Reiner smartly chose to cast strong actors instead of pure comics whose uncanny ability to play the funny material with completely straight faces is what makes the film so funny. Armand Assante is surprisingly funny as Ned Ravine, a cop and a lawyer who is being cheated on by a scheming wife (Kate Nelligan), being pursued by a sexy client (Sean Young)and being loved from afar by his faithful secretary (Sherilyn Fenn). There are also funny turns from Christopheer McDonald as Nelligan's dim-witted lover, James Remar, in a perfect take off of Max Cady from CAPE FEAR, and Tony Randall as a judge. The gags come fast and furious and most of them work, there's even a very funny cameo by Bob Euker, as a color commentator for a trial. Just sit back, relax, don't think about it too much and there's a lot of fun to be had here.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    " On the Count of Monte Christo ? " Not guilty!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thinker1691
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/10/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When a producer selects the actors and actresses for a film, it's usually in his mind what he is looking for. The selection Mr. Carl Reiner made in this film "Fatal Instinct" is nothing short of incredible. Taking a cue from the film parried here ( Fatal Attraction) from the moment it begins, you will begin laughing, so one had better have a good grip on his chair. Whoever selected straight actors or at least actors with a serious streak to do comedy knew they were trolling for gold. What they achieved is memorable in various films, like airplane and Horror Movie. In this hilarious offering, Reiner combines the works of the 1950's black/white films with modern murder venues. Armand Assante is incredible as Ned Ravine, super sleuth and lawyer. Sherilyn Fenn as Laura Lincolnberry, Kate Nelligan is Lana Ravine and Sean Young playing Lola Cain. All take the hero for a mind-bending spin and spoofs and succeed. However, the best selection for real comedy out of his element is none other than James Remar (The Warriors) , who plays, Max Shady. The outcome is fantastic. You've got to see this film for all it's humor. ***
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fatal is right Fatally bad.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Damnthatsgood
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/8/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    With the opening sequence there is a glimmer of hope but roll on a few minutes and it soon becomes clear that this is going to be well short of the mark of decent spoofs like Airplane, Naked Gun and Hot Shots. A good cast does nothing for the poor jokes and bad direction. Some of the cast were totally underused especially John Witherspoon who is extremely funny and might have added that something which was definitely missing from this film. I should have went with my Instinct after the first few minutes and stopped watching, that i'm afraid was my Fatal mistake. Overall if you like the above mentioned spoofs stay well clear of this one.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Spoof comedy with Armand Assante pulling a Leslie Nielsen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moonspinner55
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/7/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Carl Reiner tries his hand at an "Airplane!"-styled spoof of crime-thrillers, such as "Basic Instinct" and "Body Heat", but the results are full of cheap gags and silly smut. Armand Assante is the befuddled cop, Sean Young is the femme fatale, Kate Nelligan is Assante's two-timing spouse, Rosie O'Donnell is...Rosie O'Donnell. Assante, he of the droopy bedroom eyes and self-satisfied smirk, allows himself to be a little ridiculous here, but slapstick buffoonery just isn't in him, and he struggles manfully to have a good time. The movie just doesn't have the correct look of a crime-noir down--and worse, it appears to have been made by a filmmaker with a very standard, square sense of humor. * from ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Why the hell is this rated so low?!?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    craigman
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/5/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I don't understand how a person can watch a very funny and entertaining movie like this and then go on IMDb and give it a low rating! What is wrong with these people?! Do they have no sense of humor? They are probably the same people who didn't see the humor in Airplane! This movie obviously spoofs, or parodies (please forgive me if I don't know the difference!) noir movies and murder thrillers like Basic Instinct and Fatal Attraction, hence the title. Armande Asanti is funnier than most people who are supposed to be funny, like Will Farrell! Also we have the classic beauty Sherilyn Fenn, looking her best as an old fashioned secretary. There are more laugh out loud parts than I can count. They tackle a lot of the clich&eacute;s that have always bugged me, like when the bad person is "killed", they "come to" and try to kill the good person again, and again! The comedic timing is right on the mark, unlike so many unfunny "comedies" that have come out recently. Also, this movie is light on the violence, language and sexual content, so even easily offended people can enjoy it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Shameless spoof of other movies, somewhat funny.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TxMike
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/5/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a parody of such movies as 'Basic Instinct' and 'Fatal Attraction', and others with strained male/female relationships. My neighbor Ron loaned it to me, a budget DVD. Armand Assante is Ned Ravine, cop and lawyer. So he can arrest you, read you your rights (with the help of cue cards), and then defend you in court. Sherilyn Fenn is Laura Lincolnberry, sweet, pretty assistant who secretly is in love with Ned. Kate Nelligan is Ned's wife, Lana Ravine, who is having a torrid affair with Frank, the auto mechanic who never seems to finish the job, played ably by Christopher McDonald (snotty golf professional in 'Happy Gilmore'). The joke is that Ned only sees a drawn out repair job, and is oblivious to the love affair. Tony Randall also does a good turn as Judge Skanky. It would be a mistake to call this a good movie. It has a number of funny moments, but I found it mostly a series of jokes woven into a thin story. However, I found it worthwhile just to see Sherilyn Fenn.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Noir Spoof Worth A Look
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ccthemovieman-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/4/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A wild spoof of suspense and film noirs, I appreciated this silly film a little more than most being a fan of "noirs." As with any comedy, the movie is a combination of genuinely laugh-out-loud gags and sight scenes and genuinely stupid lines. It depends on what makes you laugh. One thing it has for sure: lots of sexual innuendos and just plain overt sexuality. It's yet another one of these PG-13 ratings that is a joke. This is not for kids. Also, this film won't be much for those without a knowledge of classic crime films of the past, from the '40s to the '80s. Many parts of this movie parrot scenes from Fatal Attraction, Body Double, etc. It takes several viewings to catch most of the inside jokes. Armand Assante is the smooth private detective and Sherilyn Fenn is his attractive and loyal secretary. Kate Nelligan, Sean Young and Christopher McDonald add to the fun. To be frank, I enjoyed this more on the first viewing than I did on the second. After watching it twice, I thought the film would have been better had it been cut 10-15 minutes, and it's only 90 minutes. However, I am not knocking it: it's a fun movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
