<filme>
 <id>
  580
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0112966
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1995
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  O Ingl&ecirc;s que Subiu a Colina e Desceu a Montanha
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.4
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  When an English cartographer must tell a Welsh village that their mountain is only a hill, the offended community sets out to change that.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Two English cartographers visit the small South Wales village of Ffynnon Garw, to measure what is claimed to be the "first mountain inside of Wales". It's 1917, and the war in Europe continues. The villagers are very proud of their "mountain", and are understandably disappointed and furious to find that it is in fact a "hill". Not to be outwitted by a rule (and the Englishmen who enforce it), the villagers set out to make their hill into a mountain, but to do so they must keep the English from leaving, before the job is done.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   mountain
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   hill
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   wales
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   welsh
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   1910s
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Christopher Monger
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Ivor Monger
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Christopher Monger
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Hugh Grant
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Tara Fitzgerald
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Colm Meaney
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stop actin' so English!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ben Larson
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am continuing my day of Tara Fitzgerald with an old favorite. That is because I am also a huge Hugh Grant fan, ever since Four Weddings and a Funeral. This is his first film since then. My Tara adventure has taken me to England and Ireland, and now Wales, and a quaint village. The villagers, who are proud to live in the shadow of Ffynnon Garw. the "First Mountain in Wales", are determined to thwart the efforts of the English cartographers to turn it into a "hill." Most of the people in this village, except for the lovely Tara Fitzgerald as Betty, are a bit daft. The local Reverend (Kenneth Griffith) is hilarious, and Colm Meaney is the irreverent Welsh opportunist. Assorted characters like Johnny Shellshocked, Williams the Petroleum, Tommy Twostroke, and the Twp brothers add to the excitement. It is Meaney's plan to employ Tara Fitzgerald as the means to keep Grand and his partner in town until thy can add twenty feet to the mountain that really makes the film worthwhile.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stop actin' so English!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tieman64
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Christopher Monger's "The Englishman Who Went Up a Hill and Came Down A Mountain" is a gentle comedy about a pair of English cartographers (Hugh Grant and Ian McNeice) who travel to the tiny Welsh village of Ffynnon Garw in the year 1917. During their journey they reclassify a mountain as a hill, much to the chagrin of local Welsh folk, who immediately set about increasing the size of their hill so as to reclaim its mountainous status. The film was released the same year as "Braveheart", Mel Gibson's bloody hymn to ye olde Scotland. Monger's film is operating in a similar way, though its far more gentle, poking fun at all things English and exalting all things Welsh. Pitched at tourists, the film's designed to win you over with its lovable locals, quaint tone, funny customs and low key romance between an Englishman and Welsh rose. The film is supposedly based on a true story, or at least a local legend. Regardless, in Monger's hands the hill becomes a means of restoring both the Welsh community's war damaged self esteem within the film, and a means of bolstering Welsh patriotism outside the film. The National Assembly for Wales, which grants Wales the power to pass legislation without having to consult the UK parliament, was formed shortly after the film's release. Meanwhile, the cast's uncertainty as to what makes a hill and what makes a mountain (and when does one become the other?) is used as a means of cross-cultural bridge-building. You may look Welsh, may look English, but gee, you might as well be one of us. 8/10  Worth one viewing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gentle comedy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    potato2
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The year is 1917, and two English mapmakers come to a tiny Welsh village to survey their so-called 'mountain.' With the war taking all the young men and the harsh life in the coal mines, the local folk have little to be proud of except their peak, but cartographer Anson (Hugh Grant) doubts that it reaches the minimum height required to be officially deemed a mountain and may, in fact, be merely a hill. Rallied by their minister, the entire town sets about making sure it's tall enough. This sweet and folksy comedy has a thin plot and moves at a snail's pace, but still succeeds thanks to the coziness of the village, the close bond the locals share, and Hugh Grant's boyish charms. Filmed just after "Four Weddings and a Funeral," but before he was an international star, Grant is bright, likable, and interesting and not-yet affected by his trademark stammering and eyelash-fluttering. Everything about the picturesque village seems authentic and the folksy humor is ingratiating. Enjoyable if you like character-driven films.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I don't want Ffynnon Garw to be on the map because we begged for it.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Englishman Who Went Up a Hill But Came Down a Mountain is directed by Christopher Monger and written by Ivor Monger. It stars Hugh Grant, Ian McNeice, Tara Fitzgerald, Colm Meaney and Kenneth Griffith. Music is by Stephen Endelman and cinematography by Vernon Layton. Set in 1917, plot finds Grant and McNeice as two English cartographers who arrive in the Welsh village of Ffynnon Garw to measure what the locals proudly proclaim to be Wales' first mountain. However, it turns out that the "mountain" is 16 feet below the required 1000 feet requisite so therefore can only be classed as a hill. This news causes disgust amongst the locals, who then set about stopping the cartographers going home whilst they attempt to build atop of the hill to make it over 1000 feet. A film with a big title that is matched by the size of its heart, Monger's film owes much to those fun community based pictures that filed out of Ealing Studios back in the 40s and 50s, Re: Whisky Galore! and The Titfield Thunderbolt. We can also safely place it the whimsy category where something as wonderful as Local Hero sits, while the old British comedy staple that encompasses an obsession with size (The Mouse That Roared) watches over the film like an approving British cinematic angel. Homespun humour marries up with the utterly engaging view of quirky village life to provide us with just under 100 minutes of entertainment. Although clearly simple in plot and structure, to simply dismiss it as such does not do justice to the fine work of the ensemble cast and the writing of Ivor and Chris Monger. With Grant doing what he does best, the amiable nervous fop, picture has a lead actor fully comfortable with the tone and texture of the production, while around him there are a number of fine character actors putting delightful meat on the comedy bones of oddball characters with names such as Morgan the Goat, Johny Shellshock, William the Petroleum and Betty from Cardiff! Best of the bunch is Griffith as Reverend Jones, a grumpy, stubborn eccentric who underpins everything so wonderfully skew-whiff about life in Ffynnon Garw. As for the writing? The screenplay has a wonderful ear for small village dialogue, while in amongst the value of community spirit theme, sits a near sombre observation of the effects of war on such a community. The production design is appealing, with Layton's photography around the Powys locations a visual treat, and Endelman's music has a suitably warming and jaunty feel; even if it starts to get a touch repetitive later in the piece. It doesn't have widespread appeal, it's clearly a film aimed at a small portion of film fans that love those films mentioned earlier. But in an era when film is being smothered by CGI and visual gimmickry, revisiting something like The Englishman Who Went Up a Hill But Came Down a Mountain offers up a most refreshing and diverting experience. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Question Of Identity
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sddavis63 (revsdd@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/4/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A small village in Wales, relatively close to the boundary separating Wales from England, takes its identity from its proximity to what it considers to be its local mountain. All of a sudden, and quite unexpectedly, two English cartographers from the British Army show up to take a measurement of the hill and - to the horror of the town - the "mountain" is found to be 984 feet tall - 16 feet short of the 1000 feet required to be included on the map as a mountain. Set during the First World War, this movie presents an interesting picture of Welsh nationalism. In today's world, nationalism has acquired something of a bad name. It leads to feelings of superiority, racism, violence, terrorism and wars. The nationalism depicted here seemed to me to be of a more positive type. It wasn't about putting anyone down - it was about these villagers finding something about themselves and their land to take pride in without insulting anyone else - although it's clear that they themselves felt insulted by these two Englishmen having the nerve to question whether "their" mountain was really just a hill, and they set out to do something about it! One of the great lines in the movie was "if this isn't a mountain, we might as well be in England." The movie features good, if not overpowering, performances from pretty much everyone. Hugh Grant as the sympathetic Englishman Anson, and Ian McNeice as his less sympathetic partner - who considers the Welsh to be foreigners - do a fine job, and Colm Meaney has a very significant and well-played role as "Morgan the Goat" (there's some great humour here about Welsh names, that add to an overall wonderful, if somewhat low key, sense of humour throughout.) Tara Fitzgerald was also very good as Betty from Cardiff, who eventually becomes Anson's romantic interest, and also worth noting is Kenneth Griffith as Rev. Jones. Overall, this is a very pleasant journey of self-discovery for almost every character in the movie, and it's immensely enjoyable. 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Warm and funny
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andres Salama
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/2/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A pleasant, unusual comedy. Supposedly based on a real story (but probably not) and set in 1917, it tells the story of two English cartographers (Hugh Grant and Ian McNeice) who arrive in a Welsh village in order to take the measure of the nearby mountain, considered the pride of the locals. According to the height (more specifically, if it is higher than 1,000 feet), it will be determined whether it is indeed a mountain or it is just a hill. When the first measure turns out that it is just a few feet under the 1,000 mark, the anxious villagers will take action. In order to makes sure that it is recorded as a mountain, they will transport dirt and soil from the fields, and to the peak, bucket by bucket. At the same time, they will do everything to prevent the two cartographers from leaving town before they can take a second measure. Eventually, Grant, who falls in love with a local girl (Tara Fitzgerald), will help the villagers in their task (the other cartographer is much more meaner and dismissive of the Welsh). This is a small film in every sense, but it is very warm and funny.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Building a mountain out of a molehill has a whole new meaning for me now
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    DAVID SIM
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/9/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Englishman Who Went Up a Hill But Came Down a Mountain is a film that reminds me of The Dish. These are two films that are charming and even modest. Qualities you don't usually find in the Hollywood mainstream nowadays. Another similarity they share is that they both feature monumental events that happen to rural, smalltown folk, and they're directed by natives to they're respective areas. In this film's case, Wales. Set in 1917, in the town of Ffynnon Garw (Welsh names are the worst!), two cartographers Reginald Anson and George Garrad (Hugh Grant and Ian McNeice) pay a visit to survey the land. Their primary interest is to measure the town's local mountain, something the townspeople take great pride in. But they're in for a rude awakening when Anson & Garrad discover they're 'mountain' is not a mountain at all. Just a really large hill. A mountain has to be at least 1000 feet. Ffynnon Garw's hill measures up to 980 feet tops. So its a big hill to be sure. But its still just a hill. The townspeople are devastated to learn this. So they set a plan in motion. Morgan the Goat (Colm Meaney), the town's local barkeep rallies the people together to build an extra mound on top of their hill, and turn it into a mountain. TEWWUAHBCDAM is a film of simple pleasures. But that's where its appeal lies. These people are so incensed by this apparent loss to their culture that they're prepared to bend the rules to restore their former glory. And who wouldn't love the film's idea of transforming a hill into a mountain by just going that little extra distance? The building of the mountain becomes a unifying force for the town and a newfound symbol of hope. Especially since these people have lost a lot of their self-esteem and drive because of WW1. But this new project brings them together and helps them to get back a lot of their faith in themselves. And director Christopher Monger puts these points across without hammering them home. Hugh Grant is not one of my favourite actors in the world. I personally think he's an annoyingly pretentious performer. The only time he's ever watchable is when he's served by an engaging storyline or a witty screenplay. And this film happens to be one of them. He basically falls into his standard, one-note style of acting throughout. In other words, bumbling, foppish and stammering. But at least the intensely likable storytelling allows his character to prevail, despite Grant's shortcomings as an actor. The supporting cast are quite a different kettle of fish. They're all wonderful, and they all have something to add. Colm Meaney's Morgan is my favourite of all the townsfolk. His character is interesting because he swings between ambiguous extremes. Someone who is on the one hand a concerned member of the community, and on the other a self-serving huckster prepared to use the town's dilemma to profit from it. Its a well written part, and well played too by the underrated Colm Meaney. This being a Hugh Grant film, there has to be a love interest for him. And Tara Fitzgerald is superb as Betty from Cardiff. She's not only here as a romantic love interest, but her role is tied into the plot too. She's there to keep Anson distracted while the townsfolk build they're mountain. She'll keep him from leaving town, and when the mountain is ready, he can re-measure it, and put things to rights. Tara Fitzgerald may be a little too modern for a Welsh lass of 1917, but I liked her spirited, twinkly eyed flirtatiousness. Her relationship with Grant is never more than amiable, but she's so appealing in the role, you really are convinced that Anson would be prepared to settle down with her. I know I would! Monger adds the occasional hindrance to increase tension. Such as a torrential downpour that could make short work of the townspeople's hard work. But that all comes with the territory. And the final scene. Where the town vicar passes away on the hill, and his buried earth is used to complete the mountain is clever and moving too. The question of whether or not they'll finish they're mountain is hardly a mystery. But did you really want anything less? Complimented by a lovely lyrical musical score, The Englishman Who Went Up a Hill But Came Down a Mountain is a gently amusing unappreciated treat, and one of the few gracious films to be seen on TV nowadays.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Warm and positive film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Gordon-11
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/8/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is about the villagers in a Welsh village building a mountain from a hill. The determination of the villagers is striking. It touches me that everyone in the village used every imaginable way to heighten the hill to a mountain. The train conductor has to lie, villagers have to do some vandalism, and a woman has to flirt to make the two surveyors stay. It shows that even the hardest task can be achieved through collective effort. It also reminds us not to give up even if there are obstacles that hinder our progress. This film brings such a warm and positive message, which is a rarity nowadays.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Enjoyable, well-acted, funny and uplifting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tonyhu
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/5/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What's the difference between a hill and a mountain? And more importantly, does it matter? Well, it did to the residents of a small Welsh village in 1917 when two English cartographers arrived to tell them that their 'mountain' did not in fact quite make the grade. The devastated locals hatch a plan to put the science right, and therein lies the plot of this very original and charming film. Its plot veers between the insignificant and the faintly ludicrous, but by the time you have realised this you are already enjoying yourself too much to care. Why? It's a delightful and clever combination of whimsical nostalgia and top-rate performances from some truly fine character actors who are clearly having a whale of a time. Most of these performances come as no surprise: Hugh Grant plays his archetypal Hugh Grant character of course - but what critics forget is that he does it very well. Ian McNeice is typically impressive as his pompous but rather stupid superior, as is Ian Hart as the troubled young boy just back from the trenches, and Colm Meaney keeps the standard high as the sly local barman. But for me the show is stolen by Kenneth Griffith as the passionate, ever-trembling, Reverend Jones (watch him in the scene when he scolds Morgan the Goat for selling alcohol at the hill - a tremendously funny and moving characterisation). For me, the film goes off the boil a little when it gets a bogged down in Grant's inevitable fling with local temptress Tara Fitzgerald. But thankfully this doesn't clog the pace of the film too much, and we move to the denouement. It's only after the film has finished that you realise there was much more to it than met the eye. The atmospheric portrayal of early 20th century Wales owes much to meticulous direction and a wonderfully vibrant score. Critics might find some of the locals a bit yokelish, but that would be harsh, I think. This is an affectionate and subtle period piece, with something to say about the human spirit. But even more than that, it's an enjoyable, well-acted, funny and ultimately uplifting film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hugh was brilliant
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lastliberal
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/3/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I know this wasn't a huge success. Grant committed to doing it before his huge hit Four Weddings and a Funeral, but it was fun nonetheless. The conflict between the uptight Englishmen and the Welsh villagers over whether they had a hill or a mountain was extremely funny, and their solution - getting Ian McNeice drunk and keeping Hugh Grant busy with Tara Fitzgerald, who also played Grant's wife in Sirens added to the hilarity. The randy barkeep comes up with the solution to the problem, ostensibly to sell more beer, but it gets the whole town working together and make for an enjoyable film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stop actin' so English!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ben Larson
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am continuing my day of Tara Fitzgerald with an old favorite. That is because I am also a huge Hugh Grant fan, ever since Four Weddings and a Funeral. This is his first film since then. My Tara adventure has taken me to England and Ireland, and now Wales, and a quaint village. The villagers, who are proud to live in the shadow of Ffynnon Garw. the "First Mountain in Wales", are determined to thwart the efforts of the English cartographers to turn it into a "hill." Most of the people in this village, except for the lovely Tara Fitzgerald as Betty, are a bit daft. The local Reverend (Kenneth Griffith) is hilarious, and Colm Meaney is the irreverent Welsh opportunist. Assorted characters like Johnny Shellshocked, Williams the Petroleum, Tommy Twostroke, and the Twp brothers add to the excitement. It is Meaney's plan to employ Tara Fitzgerald as the means to keep Grand and his partner in town until thy can add twenty feet to the mountain that really makes the film worthwhile.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stop actin' so English!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tieman64
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Christopher Monger's "The Englishman Who Went Up a Hill and Came Down A Mountain" is a gentle comedy about a pair of English cartographers (Hugh Grant and Ian McNeice) who travel to the tiny Welsh village of Ffynnon Garw in the year 1917. During their journey they reclassify a mountain as a hill, much to the chagrin of local Welsh folk, who immediately set about increasing the size of their hill so as to reclaim its mountainous status. The film was released the same year as "Braveheart", Mel Gibson's bloody hymn to ye olde Scotland. Monger's film is operating in a similar way, though its far more gentle, poking fun at all things English and exalting all things Welsh. Pitched at tourists, the film's designed to win you over with its lovable locals, quaint tone, funny customs and low key romance between an Englishman and Welsh rose. The film is supposedly based on a true story, or at least a local legend. Regardless, in Monger's hands the hill becomes a means of restoring both the Welsh community's war damaged self esteem within the film, and a means of bolstering Welsh patriotism outside the film. The National Assembly for Wales, which grants Wales the power to pass legislation without having to consult the UK parliament, was formed shortly after the film's release. Meanwhile, the cast's uncertainty as to what makes a hill and what makes a mountain (and when does one become the other?) is used as a means of cross-cultural bridge-building. You may look Welsh, may look English, but gee, you might as well be one of us. 8/10  Worth one viewing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gentle comedy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    potato2
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The year is 1917, and two English mapmakers come to a tiny Welsh village to survey their so-called 'mountain.' With the war taking all the young men and the harsh life in the coal mines, the local folk have little to be proud of except their peak, but cartographer Anson (Hugh Grant) doubts that it reaches the minimum height required to be officially deemed a mountain and may, in fact, be merely a hill. Rallied by their minister, the entire town sets about making sure it's tall enough. This sweet and folksy comedy has a thin plot and moves at a snail's pace, but still succeeds thanks to the coziness of the village, the close bond the locals share, and Hugh Grant's boyish charms. Filmed just after "Four Weddings and a Funeral," but before he was an international star, Grant is bright, likable, and interesting and not-yet affected by his trademark stammering and eyelash-fluttering. Everything about the picturesque village seems authentic and the folksy humor is ingratiating. Enjoyable if you like character-driven films.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I don't want Ffynnon Garw to be on the map because we begged for it.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Englishman Who Went Up a Hill But Came Down a Mountain is directed by Christopher Monger and written by Ivor Monger. It stars Hugh Grant, Ian McNeice, Tara Fitzgerald, Colm Meaney and Kenneth Griffith. Music is by Stephen Endelman and cinematography by Vernon Layton. Set in 1917, plot finds Grant and McNeice as two English cartographers who arrive in the Welsh village of Ffynnon Garw to measure what the locals proudly proclaim to be Wales' first mountain. However, it turns out that the "mountain" is 16 feet below the required 1000 feet requisite so therefore can only be classed as a hill. This news causes disgust amongst the locals, who then set about stopping the cartographers going home whilst they attempt to build atop of the hill to make it over 1000 feet. A film with a big title that is matched by the size of its heart, Monger's film owes much to those fun community based pictures that filed out of Ealing Studios back in the 40s and 50s, Re: Whisky Galore! and The Titfield Thunderbolt. We can also safely place it the whimsy category where something as wonderful as Local Hero sits, while the old British comedy staple that encompasses an obsession with size (The Mouse That Roared) watches over the film like an approving British cinematic angel. Homespun humour marries up with the utterly engaging view of quirky village life to provide us with just under 100 minutes of entertainment. Although clearly simple in plot and structure, to simply dismiss it as such does not do justice to the fine work of the ensemble cast and the writing of Ivor and Chris Monger. With Grant doing what he does best, the amiable nervous fop, picture has a lead actor fully comfortable with the tone and texture of the production, while around him there are a number of fine character actors putting delightful meat on the comedy bones of oddball characters with names such as Morgan the Goat, Johny Shellshock, William the Petroleum and Betty from Cardiff! Best of the bunch is Griffith as Reverend Jones, a grumpy, stubborn eccentric who underpins everything so wonderfully skew-whiff about life in Ffynnon Garw. As for the writing? The screenplay has a wonderful ear for small village dialogue, while in amongst the value of community spirit theme, sits a near sombre observation of the effects of war on such a community. The production design is appealing, with Layton's photography around the Powys locations a visual treat, and Endelman's music has a suitably warming and jaunty feel; even if it starts to get a touch repetitive later in the piece. It doesn't have widespread appeal, it's clearly a film aimed at a small portion of film fans that love those films mentioned earlier. But in an era when film is being smothered by CGI and visual gimmickry, revisiting something like The Englishman Who Went Up a Hill But Came Down a Mountain offers up a most refreshing and diverting experience. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Question Of Identity
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sddavis63 (revsdd@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/4/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A small village in Wales, relatively close to the boundary separating Wales from England, takes its identity from its proximity to what it considers to be its local mountain. All of a sudden, and quite unexpectedly, two English cartographers from the British Army show up to take a measurement of the hill and - to the horror of the town - the "mountain" is found to be 984 feet tall - 16 feet short of the 1000 feet required to be included on the map as a mountain. Set during the First World War, this movie presents an interesting picture of Welsh nationalism. In today's world, nationalism has acquired something of a bad name. It leads to feelings of superiority, racism, violence, terrorism and wars. The nationalism depicted here seemed to me to be of a more positive type. It wasn't about putting anyone down - it was about these villagers finding something about themselves and their land to take pride in without insulting anyone else - although it's clear that they themselves felt insulted by these two Englishmen having the nerve to question whether "their" mountain was really just a hill, and they set out to do something about it! One of the great lines in the movie was "if this isn't a mountain, we might as well be in England." The movie features good, if not overpowering, performances from pretty much everyone. Hugh Grant as the sympathetic Englishman Anson, and Ian McNeice as his less sympathetic partner - who considers the Welsh to be foreigners - do a fine job, and Colm Meaney has a very significant and well-played role as "Morgan the Goat" (there's some great humour here about Welsh names, that add to an overall wonderful, if somewhat low key, sense of humour throughout.) Tara Fitzgerald was also very good as Betty from Cardiff, who eventually becomes Anson's romantic interest, and also worth noting is Kenneth Griffith as Rev. Jones. Overall, this is a very pleasant journey of self-discovery for almost every character in the movie, and it's immensely enjoyable. 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Warm and funny
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andres Salama
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/2/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A pleasant, unusual comedy. Supposedly based on a real story (but probably not) and set in 1917, it tells the story of two English cartographers (Hugh Grant and Ian McNeice) who arrive in a Welsh village in order to take the measure of the nearby mountain, considered the pride of the locals. According to the height (more specifically, if it is higher than 1,000 feet), it will be determined whether it is indeed a mountain or it is just a hill. When the first measure turns out that it is just a few feet under the 1,000 mark, the anxious villagers will take action. In order to makes sure that it is recorded as a mountain, they will transport dirt and soil from the fields, and to the peak, bucket by bucket. At the same time, they will do everything to prevent the two cartographers from leaving town before they can take a second measure. Eventually, Grant, who falls in love with a local girl (Tara Fitzgerald), will help the villagers in their task (the other cartographer is much more meaner and dismissive of the Welsh). This is a small film in every sense, but it is very warm and funny.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Building a mountain out of a molehill has a whole new meaning for me now
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    DAVID SIM
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/9/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Englishman Who Went Up a Hill But Came Down a Mountain is a film that reminds me of The Dish. These are two films that are charming and even modest. Qualities you don't usually find in the Hollywood mainstream nowadays. Another similarity they share is that they both feature monumental events that happen to rural, smalltown folk, and they're directed by natives to they're respective areas. In this film's case, Wales. Set in 1917, in the town of Ffynnon Garw (Welsh names are the worst!), two cartographers Reginald Anson and George Garrad (Hugh Grant and Ian McNeice) pay a visit to survey the land. Their primary interest is to measure the town's local mountain, something the townspeople take great pride in. But they're in for a rude awakening when Anson & Garrad discover they're 'mountain' is not a mountain at all. Just a really large hill. A mountain has to be at least 1000 feet. Ffynnon Garw's hill measures up to 980 feet tops. So its a big hill to be sure. But its still just a hill. The townspeople are devastated to learn this. So they set a plan in motion. Morgan the Goat (Colm Meaney), the town's local barkeep rallies the people together to build an extra mound on top of their hill, and turn it into a mountain. TEWWUAHBCDAM is a film of simple pleasures. But that's where its appeal lies. These people are so incensed by this apparent loss to their culture that they're prepared to bend the rules to restore their former glory. And who wouldn't love the film's idea of transforming a hill into a mountain by just going that little extra distance? The building of the mountain becomes a unifying force for the town and a newfound symbol of hope. Especially since these people have lost a lot of their self-esteem and drive because of WW1. But this new project brings them together and helps them to get back a lot of their faith in themselves. And director Christopher Monger puts these points across without hammering them home. Hugh Grant is not one of my favourite actors in the world. I personally think he's an annoyingly pretentious performer. The only time he's ever watchable is when he's served by an engaging storyline or a witty screenplay. And this film happens to be one of them. He basically falls into his standard, one-note style of acting throughout. In other words, bumbling, foppish and stammering. But at least the intensely likable storytelling allows his character to prevail, despite Grant's shortcomings as an actor. The supporting cast are quite a different kettle of fish. They're all wonderful, and they all have something to add. Colm Meaney's Morgan is my favourite of all the townsfolk. His character is interesting because he swings between ambiguous extremes. Someone who is on the one hand a concerned member of the community, and on the other a self-serving huckster prepared to use the town's dilemma to profit from it. Its a well written part, and well played too by the underrated Colm Meaney. This being a Hugh Grant film, there has to be a love interest for him. And Tara Fitzgerald is superb as Betty from Cardiff. She's not only here as a romantic love interest, but her role is tied into the plot too. She's there to keep Anson distracted while the townsfolk build they're mountain. She'll keep him from leaving town, and when the mountain is ready, he can re-measure it, and put things to rights. Tara Fitzgerald may be a little too modern for a Welsh lass of 1917, but I liked her spirited, twinkly eyed flirtatiousness. Her relationship with Grant is never more than amiable, but she's so appealing in the role, you really are convinced that Anson would be prepared to settle down with her. I know I would! Monger adds the occasional hindrance to increase tension. Such as a torrential downpour that could make short work of the townspeople's hard work. But that all comes with the territory. And the final scene. Where the town vicar passes away on the hill, and his buried earth is used to complete the mountain is clever and moving too. The question of whether or not they'll finish they're mountain is hardly a mystery. But did you really want anything less? Complimented by a lovely lyrical musical score, The Englishman Who Went Up a Hill But Came Down a Mountain is a gently amusing unappreciated treat, and one of the few gracious films to be seen on TV nowadays.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Warm and positive film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Gordon-11
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/8/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is about the villagers in a Welsh village building a mountain from a hill. The determination of the villagers is striking. It touches me that everyone in the village used every imaginable way to heighten the hill to a mountain. The train conductor has to lie, villagers have to do some vandalism, and a woman has to flirt to make the two surveyors stay. It shows that even the hardest task can be achieved through collective effort. It also reminds us not to give up even if there are obstacles that hinder our progress. This film brings such a warm and positive message, which is a rarity nowadays.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Enjoyable, well-acted, funny and uplifting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tonyhu
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/5/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What's the difference between a hill and a mountain? And more importantly, does it matter? Well, it did to the residents of a small Welsh village in 1917 when two English cartographers arrived to tell them that their 'mountain' did not in fact quite make the grade. The devastated locals hatch a plan to put the science right, and therein lies the plot of this very original and charming film. Its plot veers between the insignificant and the faintly ludicrous, but by the time you have realised this you are already enjoying yourself too much to care. Why? It's a delightful and clever combination of whimsical nostalgia and top-rate performances from some truly fine character actors who are clearly having a whale of a time. Most of these performances come as no surprise: Hugh Grant plays his archetypal Hugh Grant character of course - but what critics forget is that he does it very well. Ian McNeice is typically impressive as his pompous but rather stupid superior, as is Ian Hart as the troubled young boy just back from the trenches, and Colm Meaney keeps the standard high as the sly local barman. But for me the show is stolen by Kenneth Griffith as the passionate, ever-trembling, Reverend Jones (watch him in the scene when he scolds Morgan the Goat for selling alcohol at the hill - a tremendously funny and moving characterisation). For me, the film goes off the boil a little when it gets a bogged down in Grant's inevitable fling with local temptress Tara Fitzgerald. But thankfully this doesn't clog the pace of the film too much, and we move to the denouement. It's only after the film has finished that you realise there was much more to it than met the eye. The atmospheric portrayal of early 20th century Wales owes much to meticulous direction and a wonderfully vibrant score. Critics might find some of the locals a bit yokelish, but that would be harsh, I think. This is an affectionate and subtle period piece, with something to say about the human spirit. But even more than that, it's an enjoyable, well-acted, funny and ultimately uplifting film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hugh was brilliant
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lastliberal
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/3/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I know this wasn't a huge success. Grant committed to doing it before his huge hit Four Weddings and a Funeral, but it was fun nonetheless. The conflict between the uptight Englishmen and the Welsh villagers over whether they had a hill or a mountain was extremely funny, and their solution - getting Ian McNeice drunk and keeping Hugh Grant busy with Tara Fitzgerald, who also played Grant's wife in Sirens added to the hilarity. The randy barkeep comes up with the solution to the problem, ostensibly to sell more beer, but it gets the whole town working together and make for an enjoyable film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stop actin' so English!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ben Larson
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am continuing my day of Tara Fitzgerald with an old favorite. That is because I am also a huge Hugh Grant fan, ever since Four Weddings and a Funeral. This is his first film since then. My Tara adventure has taken me to England and Ireland, and now Wales, and a quaint village. The villagers, who are proud to live in the shadow of Ffynnon Garw. the "First Mountain in Wales", are determined to thwart the efforts of the English cartographers to turn it into a "hill." Most of the people in this village, except for the lovely Tara Fitzgerald as Betty, are a bit daft. The local Reverend (Kenneth Griffith) is hilarious, and Colm Meaney is the irreverent Welsh opportunist. Assorted characters like Johnny Shellshocked, Williams the Petroleum, Tommy Twostroke, and the Twp brothers add to the excitement. It is Meaney's plan to employ Tara Fitzgerald as the means to keep Grand and his partner in town until thy can add twenty feet to the mountain that really makes the film worthwhile.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stop actin' so English!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tieman64
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Christopher Monger's "The Englishman Who Went Up a Hill and Came Down A Mountain" is a gentle comedy about a pair of English cartographers (Hugh Grant and Ian McNeice) who travel to the tiny Welsh village of Ffynnon Garw in the year 1917. During their journey they reclassify a mountain as a hill, much to the chagrin of local Welsh folk, who immediately set about increasing the size of their hill so as to reclaim its mountainous status. The film was released the same year as "Braveheart", Mel Gibson's bloody hymn to ye olde Scotland. Monger's film is operating in a similar way, though its far more gentle, poking fun at all things English and exalting all things Welsh. Pitched at tourists, the film's designed to win you over with its lovable locals, quaint tone, funny customs and low key romance between an Englishman and Welsh rose. The film is supposedly based on a true story, or at least a local legend. Regardless, in Monger's hands the hill becomes a means of restoring both the Welsh community's war damaged self esteem within the film, and a means of bolstering Welsh patriotism outside the film. The National Assembly for Wales, which grants Wales the power to pass legislation without having to consult the UK parliament, was formed shortly after the film's release. Meanwhile, the cast's uncertainty as to what makes a hill and what makes a mountain (and when does one become the other?) is used as a means of cross-cultural bridge-building. You may look Welsh, may look English, but gee, you might as well be one of us. 8/10  Worth one viewing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gentle comedy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    potato2
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The year is 1917, and two English mapmakers come to a tiny Welsh village to survey their so-called 'mountain.' With the war taking all the young men and the harsh life in the coal mines, the local folk have little to be proud of except their peak, but cartographer Anson (Hugh Grant) doubts that it reaches the minimum height required to be officially deemed a mountain and may, in fact, be merely a hill. Rallied by their minister, the entire town sets about making sure it's tall enough. This sweet and folksy comedy has a thin plot and moves at a snail's pace, but still succeeds thanks to the coziness of the village, the close bond the locals share, and Hugh Grant's boyish charms. Filmed just after "Four Weddings and a Funeral," but before he was an international star, Grant is bright, likable, and interesting and not-yet affected by his trademark stammering and eyelash-fluttering. Everything about the picturesque village seems authentic and the folksy humor is ingratiating. Enjoyable if you like character-driven films.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I don't want Ffynnon Garw to be on the map because we begged for it.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Englishman Who Went Up a Hill But Came Down a Mountain is directed by Christopher Monger and written by Ivor Monger. It stars Hugh Grant, Ian McNeice, Tara Fitzgerald, Colm Meaney and Kenneth Griffith. Music is by Stephen Endelman and cinematography by Vernon Layton. Set in 1917, plot finds Grant and McNeice as two English cartographers who arrive in the Welsh village of Ffynnon Garw to measure what the locals proudly proclaim to be Wales' first mountain. However, it turns out that the "mountain" is 16 feet below the required 1000 feet requisite so therefore can only be classed as a hill. This news causes disgust amongst the locals, who then set about stopping the cartographers going home whilst they attempt to build atop of the hill to make it over 1000 feet. A film with a big title that is matched by the size of its heart, Monger's film owes much to those fun community based pictures that filed out of Ealing Studios back in the 40s and 50s, Re: Whisky Galore! and The Titfield Thunderbolt. We can also safely place it the whimsy category where something as wonderful as Local Hero sits, while the old British comedy staple that encompasses an obsession with size (The Mouse That Roared) watches over the film like an approving British cinematic angel. Homespun humour marries up with the utterly engaging view of quirky village life to provide us with just under 100 minutes of entertainment. Although clearly simple in plot and structure, to simply dismiss it as such does not do justice to the fine work of the ensemble cast and the writing of Ivor and Chris Monger. With Grant doing what he does best, the amiable nervous fop, picture has a lead actor fully comfortable with the tone and texture of the production, while around him there are a number of fine character actors putting delightful meat on the comedy bones of oddball characters with names such as Morgan the Goat, Johny Shellshock, William the Petroleum and Betty from Cardiff! Best of the bunch is Griffith as Reverend Jones, a grumpy, stubborn eccentric who underpins everything so wonderfully skew-whiff about life in Ffynnon Garw. As for the writing? The screenplay has a wonderful ear for small village dialogue, while in amongst the value of community spirit theme, sits a near sombre observation of the effects of war on such a community. The production design is appealing, with Layton's photography around the Powys locations a visual treat, and Endelman's music has a suitably warming and jaunty feel; even if it starts to get a touch repetitive later in the piece. It doesn't have widespread appeal, it's clearly a film aimed at a small portion of film fans that love those films mentioned earlier. But in an era when film is being smothered by CGI and visual gimmickry, revisiting something like The Englishman Who Went Up a Hill But Came Down a Mountain offers up a most refreshing and diverting experience. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Question Of Identity
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sddavis63 (revsdd@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/4/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A small village in Wales, relatively close to the boundary separating Wales from England, takes its identity from its proximity to what it considers to be its local mountain. All of a sudden, and quite unexpectedly, two English cartographers from the British Army show up to take a measurement of the hill and - to the horror of the town - the "mountain" is found to be 984 feet tall - 16 feet short of the 1000 feet required to be included on the map as a mountain. Set during the First World War, this movie presents an interesting picture of Welsh nationalism. In today's world, nationalism has acquired something of a bad name. It leads to feelings of superiority, racism, violence, terrorism and wars. The nationalism depicted here seemed to me to be of a more positive type. It wasn't about putting anyone down - it was about these villagers finding something about themselves and their land to take pride in without insulting anyone else - although it's clear that they themselves felt insulted by these two Englishmen having the nerve to question whether "their" mountain was really just a hill, and they set out to do something about it! One of the great lines in the movie was "if this isn't a mountain, we might as well be in England." The movie features good, if not overpowering, performances from pretty much everyone. Hugh Grant as the sympathetic Englishman Anson, and Ian McNeice as his less sympathetic partner - who considers the Welsh to be foreigners - do a fine job, and Colm Meaney has a very significant and well-played role as "Morgan the Goat" (there's some great humour here about Welsh names, that add to an overall wonderful, if somewhat low key, sense of humour throughout.) Tara Fitzgerald was also very good as Betty from Cardiff, who eventually becomes Anson's romantic interest, and also worth noting is Kenneth Griffith as Rev. Jones. Overall, this is a very pleasant journey of self-discovery for almost every character in the movie, and it's immensely enjoyable. 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Warm and funny
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andres Salama
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/2/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A pleasant, unusual comedy. Supposedly based on a real story (but probably not) and set in 1917, it tells the story of two English cartographers (Hugh Grant and Ian McNeice) who arrive in a Welsh village in order to take the measure of the nearby mountain, considered the pride of the locals. According to the height (more specifically, if it is higher than 1,000 feet), it will be determined whether it is indeed a mountain or it is just a hill. When the first measure turns out that it is just a few feet under the 1,000 mark, the anxious villagers will take action. In order to makes sure that it is recorded as a mountain, they will transport dirt and soil from the fields, and to the peak, bucket by bucket. At the same time, they will do everything to prevent the two cartographers from leaving town before they can take a second measure. Eventually, Grant, who falls in love with a local girl (Tara Fitzgerald), will help the villagers in their task (the other cartographer is much more meaner and dismissive of the Welsh). This is a small film in every sense, but it is very warm and funny.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Building a mountain out of a molehill has a whole new meaning for me now
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    DAVID SIM
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/9/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Englishman Who Went Up a Hill But Came Down a Mountain is a film that reminds me of The Dish. These are two films that are charming and even modest. Qualities you don't usually find in the Hollywood mainstream nowadays. Another similarity they share is that they both feature monumental events that happen to rural, smalltown folk, and they're directed by natives to they're respective areas. In this film's case, Wales. Set in 1917, in the town of Ffynnon Garw (Welsh names are the worst!), two cartographers Reginald Anson and George Garrad (Hugh Grant and Ian McNeice) pay a visit to survey the land. Their primary interest is to measure the town's local mountain, something the townspeople take great pride in. But they're in for a rude awakening when Anson & Garrad discover they're 'mountain' is not a mountain at all. Just a really large hill. A mountain has to be at least 1000 feet. Ffynnon Garw's hill measures up to 980 feet tops. So its a big hill to be sure. But its still just a hill. The townspeople are devastated to learn this. So they set a plan in motion. Morgan the Goat (Colm Meaney), the town's local barkeep rallies the people together to build an extra mound on top of their hill, and turn it into a mountain. TEWWUAHBCDAM is a film of simple pleasures. But that's where its appeal lies. These people are so incensed by this apparent loss to their culture that they're prepared to bend the rules to restore their former glory. And who wouldn't love the film's idea of transforming a hill into a mountain by just going that little extra distance? The building of the mountain becomes a unifying force for the town and a newfound symbol of hope. Especially since these people have lost a lot of their self-esteem and drive because of WW1. But this new project brings them together and helps them to get back a lot of their faith in themselves. And director Christopher Monger puts these points across without hammering them home. Hugh Grant is not one of my favourite actors in the world. I personally think he's an annoyingly pretentious performer. The only time he's ever watchable is when he's served by an engaging storyline or a witty screenplay. And this film happens to be one of them. He basically falls into his standard, one-note style of acting throughout. In other words, bumbling, foppish and stammering. But at least the intensely likable storytelling allows his character to prevail, despite Grant's shortcomings as an actor. The supporting cast are quite a different kettle of fish. They're all wonderful, and they all have something to add. Colm Meaney's Morgan is my favourite of all the townsfolk. His character is interesting because he swings between ambiguous extremes. Someone who is on the one hand a concerned member of the community, and on the other a self-serving huckster prepared to use the town's dilemma to profit from it. Its a well written part, and well played too by the underrated Colm Meaney. This being a Hugh Grant film, there has to be a love interest for him. And Tara Fitzgerald is superb as Betty from Cardiff. She's not only here as a romantic love interest, but her role is tied into the plot too. She's there to keep Anson distracted while the townsfolk build they're mountain. She'll keep him from leaving town, and when the mountain is ready, he can re-measure it, and put things to rights. Tara Fitzgerald may be a little too modern for a Welsh lass of 1917, but I liked her spirited, twinkly eyed flirtatiousness. Her relationship with Grant is never more than amiable, but she's so appealing in the role, you really are convinced that Anson would be prepared to settle down with her. I know I would! Monger adds the occasional hindrance to increase tension. Such as a torrential downpour that could make short work of the townspeople's hard work. But that all comes with the territory. And the final scene. Where the town vicar passes away on the hill, and his buried earth is used to complete the mountain is clever and moving too. The question of whether or not they'll finish they're mountain is hardly a mystery. But did you really want anything less? Complimented by a lovely lyrical musical score, The Englishman Who Went Up a Hill But Came Down a Mountain is a gently amusing unappreciated treat, and one of the few gracious films to be seen on TV nowadays.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Warm and positive film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Gordon-11
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/8/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is about the villagers in a Welsh village building a mountain from a hill. The determination of the villagers is striking. It touches me that everyone in the village used every imaginable way to heighten the hill to a mountain. The train conductor has to lie, villagers have to do some vandalism, and a woman has to flirt to make the two surveyors stay. It shows that even the hardest task can be achieved through collective effort. It also reminds us not to give up even if there are obstacles that hinder our progress. This film brings such a warm and positive message, which is a rarity nowadays.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Enjoyable, well-acted, funny and uplifting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tonyhu
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/5/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What's the difference between a hill and a mountain? And more importantly, does it matter? Well, it did to the residents of a small Welsh village in 1917 when two English cartographers arrived to tell them that their 'mountain' did not in fact quite make the grade. The devastated locals hatch a plan to put the science right, and therein lies the plot of this very original and charming film. Its plot veers between the insignificant and the faintly ludicrous, but by the time you have realised this you are already enjoying yourself too much to care. Why? It's a delightful and clever combination of whimsical nostalgia and top-rate performances from some truly fine character actors who are clearly having a whale of a time. Most of these performances come as no surprise: Hugh Grant plays his archetypal Hugh Grant character of course - but what critics forget is that he does it very well. Ian McNeice is typically impressive as his pompous but rather stupid superior, as is Ian Hart as the troubled young boy just back from the trenches, and Colm Meaney keeps the standard high as the sly local barman. But for me the show is stolen by Kenneth Griffith as the passionate, ever-trembling, Reverend Jones (watch him in the scene when he scolds Morgan the Goat for selling alcohol at the hill - a tremendously funny and moving characterisation). For me, the film goes off the boil a little when it gets a bogged down in Grant's inevitable fling with local temptress Tara Fitzgerald. But thankfully this doesn't clog the pace of the film too much, and we move to the denouement. It's only after the film has finished that you realise there was much more to it than met the eye. The atmospheric portrayal of early 20th century Wales owes much to meticulous direction and a wonderfully vibrant score. Critics might find some of the locals a bit yokelish, but that would be harsh, I think. This is an affectionate and subtle period piece, with something to say about the human spirit. But even more than that, it's an enjoyable, well-acted, funny and ultimately uplifting film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hugh was brilliant
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lastliberal
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/3/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I know this wasn't a huge success. Grant committed to doing it before his huge hit Four Weddings and a Funeral, but it was fun nonetheless. The conflict between the uptight Englishmen and the Welsh villagers over whether they had a hill or a mountain was extremely funny, and their solution - getting Ian McNeice drunk and keeping Hugh Grant busy with Tara Fitzgerald, who also played Grant's wife in Sirens added to the hilarity. The randy barkeep comes up with the solution to the problem, ostensibly to sell more beer, but it gets the whole town working together and make for an enjoyable film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stop actin' so English!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ben Larson
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am continuing my day of Tara Fitzgerald with an old favorite. That is because I am also a huge Hugh Grant fan, ever since Four Weddings and a Funeral. This is his first film since then. My Tara adventure has taken me to England and Ireland, and now Wales, and a quaint village. The villagers, who are proud to live in the shadow of Ffynnon Garw. the "First Mountain in Wales", are determined to thwart the efforts of the English cartographers to turn it into a "hill." Most of the people in this village, except for the lovely Tara Fitzgerald as Betty, are a bit daft. The local Reverend (Kenneth Griffith) is hilarious, and Colm Meaney is the irreverent Welsh opportunist. Assorted characters like Johnny Shellshocked, Williams the Petroleum, Tommy Twostroke, and the Twp brothers add to the excitement. It is Meaney's plan to employ Tara Fitzgerald as the means to keep Grand and his partner in town until thy can add twenty feet to the mountain that really makes the film worthwhile.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stop actin' so English!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tieman64
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Christopher Monger's "The Englishman Who Went Up a Hill and Came Down A Mountain" is a gentle comedy about a pair of English cartographers (Hugh Grant and Ian McNeice) who travel to the tiny Welsh village of Ffynnon Garw in the year 1917. During their journey they reclassify a mountain as a hill, much to the chagrin of local Welsh folk, who immediately set about increasing the size of their hill so as to reclaim its mountainous status. The film was released the same year as "Braveheart", Mel Gibson's bloody hymn to ye olde Scotland. Monger's film is operating in a similar way, though its far more gentle, poking fun at all things English and exalting all things Welsh. Pitched at tourists, the film's designed to win you over with its lovable locals, quaint tone, funny customs and low key romance between an Englishman and Welsh rose. The film is supposedly based on a true story, or at least a local legend. Regardless, in Monger's hands the hill becomes a means of restoring both the Welsh community's war damaged self esteem within the film, and a means of bolstering Welsh patriotism outside the film. The National Assembly for Wales, which grants Wales the power to pass legislation without having to consult the UK parliament, was formed shortly after the film's release. Meanwhile, the cast's uncertainty as to what makes a hill and what makes a mountain (and when does one become the other?) is used as a means of cross-cultural bridge-building. You may look Welsh, may look English, but gee, you might as well be one of us. 8/10  Worth one viewing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gentle comedy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    potato2
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The year is 1917, and two English mapmakers come to a tiny Welsh village to survey their so-called 'mountain.' With the war taking all the young men and the harsh life in the coal mines, the local folk have little to be proud of except their peak, but cartographer Anson (Hugh Grant) doubts that it reaches the minimum height required to be officially deemed a mountain and may, in fact, be merely a hill. Rallied by their minister, the entire town sets about making sure it's tall enough. This sweet and folksy comedy has a thin plot and moves at a snail's pace, but still succeeds thanks to the coziness of the village, the close bond the locals share, and Hugh Grant's boyish charms. Filmed just after "Four Weddings and a Funeral," but before he was an international star, Grant is bright, likable, and interesting and not-yet affected by his trademark stammering and eyelash-fluttering. Everything about the picturesque village seems authentic and the folksy humor is ingratiating. Enjoyable if you like character-driven films.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I don't want Ffynnon Garw to be on the map because we begged for it.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Englishman Who Went Up a Hill But Came Down a Mountain is directed by Christopher Monger and written by Ivor Monger. It stars Hugh Grant, Ian McNeice, Tara Fitzgerald, Colm Meaney and Kenneth Griffith. Music is by Stephen Endelman and cinematography by Vernon Layton. Set in 1917, plot finds Grant and McNeice as two English cartographers who arrive in the Welsh village of Ffynnon Garw to measure what the locals proudly proclaim to be Wales' first mountain. However, it turns out that the "mountain" is 16 feet below the required 1000 feet requisite so therefore can only be classed as a hill. This news causes disgust amongst the locals, who then set about stopping the cartographers going home whilst they attempt to build atop of the hill to make it over 1000 feet. A film with a big title that is matched by the size of its heart, Monger's film owes much to those fun community based pictures that filed out of Ealing Studios back in the 40s and 50s, Re: Whisky Galore! and The Titfield Thunderbolt. We can also safely place it the whimsy category where something as wonderful as Local Hero sits, while the old British comedy staple that encompasses an obsession with size (The Mouse That Roared) watches over the film like an approving British cinematic angel. Homespun humour marries up with the utterly engaging view of quirky village life to provide us with just under 100 minutes of entertainment. Although clearly simple in plot and structure, to simply dismiss it as such does not do justice to the fine work of the ensemble cast and the writing of Ivor and Chris Monger. With Grant doing what he does best, the amiable nervous fop, picture has a lead actor fully comfortable with the tone and texture of the production, while around him there are a number of fine character actors putting delightful meat on the comedy bones of oddball characters with names such as Morgan the Goat, Johny Shellshock, William the Petroleum and Betty from Cardiff! Best of the bunch is Griffith as Reverend Jones, a grumpy, stubborn eccentric who underpins everything so wonderfully skew-whiff about life in Ffynnon Garw. As for the writing? The screenplay has a wonderful ear for small village dialogue, while in amongst the value of community spirit theme, sits a near sombre observation of the effects of war on such a community. The production design is appealing, with Layton's photography around the Powys locations a visual treat, and Endelman's music has a suitably warming and jaunty feel; even if it starts to get a touch repetitive later in the piece. It doesn't have widespread appeal, it's clearly a film aimed at a small portion of film fans that love those films mentioned earlier. But in an era when film is being smothered by CGI and visual gimmickry, revisiting something like The Englishman Who Went Up a Hill But Came Down a Mountain offers up a most refreshing and diverting experience. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Question Of Identity
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sddavis63 (revsdd@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/4/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A small village in Wales, relatively close to the boundary separating Wales from England, takes its identity from its proximity to what it considers to be its local mountain. All of a sudden, and quite unexpectedly, two English cartographers from the British Army show up to take a measurement of the hill and - to the horror of the town - the "mountain" is found to be 984 feet tall - 16 feet short of the 1000 feet required to be included on the map as a mountain. Set during the First World War, this movie presents an interesting picture of Welsh nationalism. In today's world, nationalism has acquired something of a bad name. It leads to feelings of superiority, racism, violence, terrorism and wars. The nationalism depicted here seemed to me to be of a more positive type. It wasn't about putting anyone down - it was about these villagers finding something about themselves and their land to take pride in without insulting anyone else - although it's clear that they themselves felt insulted by these two Englishmen having the nerve to question whether "their" mountain was really just a hill, and they set out to do something about it! One of the great lines in the movie was "if this isn't a mountain, we might as well be in England." The movie features good, if not overpowering, performances from pretty much everyone. Hugh Grant as the sympathetic Englishman Anson, and Ian McNeice as his less sympathetic partner - who considers the Welsh to be foreigners - do a fine job, and Colm Meaney has a very significant and well-played role as "Morgan the Goat" (there's some great humour here about Welsh names, that add to an overall wonderful, if somewhat low key, sense of humour throughout.) Tara Fitzgerald was also very good as Betty from Cardiff, who eventually becomes Anson's romantic interest, and also worth noting is Kenneth Griffith as Rev. Jones. Overall, this is a very pleasant journey of self-discovery for almost every character in the movie, and it's immensely enjoyable. 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Warm and funny
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andres Salama
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/2/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A pleasant, unusual comedy. Supposedly based on a real story (but probably not) and set in 1917, it tells the story of two English cartographers (Hugh Grant and Ian McNeice) who arrive in a Welsh village in order to take the measure of the nearby mountain, considered the pride of the locals. According to the height (more specifically, if it is higher than 1,000 feet), it will be determined whether it is indeed a mountain or it is just a hill. When the first measure turns out that it is just a few feet under the 1,000 mark, the anxious villagers will take action. In order to makes sure that it is recorded as a mountain, they will transport dirt and soil from the fields, and to the peak, bucket by bucket. At the same time, they will do everything to prevent the two cartographers from leaving town before they can take a second measure. Eventually, Grant, who falls in love with a local girl (Tara Fitzgerald), will help the villagers in their task (the other cartographer is much more meaner and dismissive of the Welsh). This is a small film in every sense, but it is very warm and funny.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Building a mountain out of a molehill has a whole new meaning for me now
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    DAVID SIM
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/9/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Englishman Who Went Up a Hill But Came Down a Mountain is a film that reminds me of The Dish. These are two films that are charming and even modest. Qualities you don't usually find in the Hollywood mainstream nowadays. Another similarity they share is that they both feature monumental events that happen to rural, smalltown folk, and they're directed by natives to they're respective areas. In this film's case, Wales. Set in 1917, in the town of Ffynnon Garw (Welsh names are the worst!), two cartographers Reginald Anson and George Garrad (Hugh Grant and Ian McNeice) pay a visit to survey the land. Their primary interest is to measure the town's local mountain, something the townspeople take great pride in. But they're in for a rude awakening when Anson & Garrad discover they're 'mountain' is not a mountain at all. Just a really large hill. A mountain has to be at least 1000 feet. Ffynnon Garw's hill measures up to 980 feet tops. So its a big hill to be sure. But its still just a hill. The townspeople are devastated to learn this. So they set a plan in motion. Morgan the Goat (Colm Meaney), the town's local barkeep rallies the people together to build an extra mound on top of their hill, and turn it into a mountain. TEWWUAHBCDAM is a film of simple pleasures. But that's where its appeal lies. These people are so incensed by this apparent loss to their culture that they're prepared to bend the rules to restore their former glory. And who wouldn't love the film's idea of transforming a hill into a mountain by just going that little extra distance? The building of the mountain becomes a unifying force for the town and a newfound symbol of hope. Especially since these people have lost a lot of their self-esteem and drive because of WW1. But this new project brings them together and helps them to get back a lot of their faith in themselves. And director Christopher Monger puts these points across without hammering them home. Hugh Grant is not one of my favourite actors in the world. I personally think he's an annoyingly pretentious performer. The only time he's ever watchable is when he's served by an engaging storyline or a witty screenplay. And this film happens to be one of them. He basically falls into his standard, one-note style of acting throughout. In other words, bumbling, foppish and stammering. But at least the intensely likable storytelling allows his character to prevail, despite Grant's shortcomings as an actor. The supporting cast are quite a different kettle of fish. They're all wonderful, and they all have something to add. Colm Meaney's Morgan is my favourite of all the townsfolk. His character is interesting because he swings between ambiguous extremes. Someone who is on the one hand a concerned member of the community, and on the other a self-serving huckster prepared to use the town's dilemma to profit from it. Its a well written part, and well played too by the underrated Colm Meaney. This being a Hugh Grant film, there has to be a love interest for him. And Tara Fitzgerald is superb as Betty from Cardiff. She's not only here as a romantic love interest, but her role is tied into the plot too. She's there to keep Anson distracted while the townsfolk build they're mountain. She'll keep him from leaving town, and when the mountain is ready, he can re-measure it, and put things to rights. Tara Fitzgerald may be a little too modern for a Welsh lass of 1917, but I liked her spirited, twinkly eyed flirtatiousness. Her relationship with Grant is never more than amiable, but she's so appealing in the role, you really are convinced that Anson would be prepared to settle down with her. I know I would! Monger adds the occasional hindrance to increase tension. Such as a torrential downpour that could make short work of the townspeople's hard work. But that all comes with the territory. And the final scene. Where the town vicar passes away on the hill, and his buried earth is used to complete the mountain is clever and moving too. The question of whether or not they'll finish they're mountain is hardly a mystery. But did you really want anything less? Complimented by a lovely lyrical musical score, The Englishman Who Went Up a Hill But Came Down a Mountain is a gently amusing unappreciated treat, and one of the few gracious films to be seen on TV nowadays.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Warm and positive film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Gordon-11
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/8/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is about the villagers in a Welsh village building a mountain from a hill. The determination of the villagers is striking. It touches me that everyone in the village used every imaginable way to heighten the hill to a mountain. The train conductor has to lie, villagers have to do some vandalism, and a woman has to flirt to make the two surveyors stay. It shows that even the hardest task can be achieved through collective effort. It also reminds us not to give up even if there are obstacles that hinder our progress. This film brings such a warm and positive message, which is a rarity nowadays.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Enjoyable, well-acted, funny and uplifting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tonyhu
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/5/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What's the difference between a hill and a mountain? And more importantly, does it matter? Well, it did to the residents of a small Welsh village in 1917 when two English cartographers arrived to tell them that their 'mountain' did not in fact quite make the grade. The devastated locals hatch a plan to put the science right, and therein lies the plot of this very original and charming film. Its plot veers between the insignificant and the faintly ludicrous, but by the time you have realised this you are already enjoying yourself too much to care. Why? It's a delightful and clever combination of whimsical nostalgia and top-rate performances from some truly fine character actors who are clearly having a whale of a time. Most of these performances come as no surprise: Hugh Grant plays his archetypal Hugh Grant character of course - but what critics forget is that he does it very well. Ian McNeice is typically impressive as his pompous but rather stupid superior, as is Ian Hart as the troubled young boy just back from the trenches, and Colm Meaney keeps the standard high as the sly local barman. But for me the show is stolen by Kenneth Griffith as the passionate, ever-trembling, Reverend Jones (watch him in the scene when he scolds Morgan the Goat for selling alcohol at the hill - a tremendously funny and moving characterisation). For me, the film goes off the boil a little when it gets a bogged down in Grant's inevitable fling with local temptress Tara Fitzgerald. But thankfully this doesn't clog the pace of the film too much, and we move to the denouement. It's only after the film has finished that you realise there was much more to it than met the eye. The atmospheric portrayal of early 20th century Wales owes much to meticulous direction and a wonderfully vibrant score. Critics might find some of the locals a bit yokelish, but that would be harsh, I think. This is an affectionate and subtle period piece, with something to say about the human spirit. But even more than that, it's an enjoyable, well-acted, funny and ultimately uplifting film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hugh was brilliant
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lastliberal
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/3/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I know this wasn't a huge success. Grant committed to doing it before his huge hit Four Weddings and a Funeral, but it was fun nonetheless. The conflict between the uptight Englishmen and the Welsh villagers over whether they had a hill or a mountain was extremely funny, and their solution - getting Ian McNeice drunk and keeping Hugh Grant busy with Tara Fitzgerald, who also played Grant's wife in Sirens added to the hilarity. The randy barkeep comes up with the solution to the problem, ostensibly to sell more beer, but it gets the whole town working together and make for an enjoyable film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stop actin' so English!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ben Larson
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am continuing my day of Tara Fitzgerald with an old favorite. That is because I am also a huge Hugh Grant fan, ever since Four Weddings and a Funeral. This is his first film since then. My Tara adventure has taken me to England and Ireland, and now Wales, and a quaint village. The villagers, who are proud to live in the shadow of Ffynnon Garw. the "First Mountain in Wales", are determined to thwart the efforts of the English cartographers to turn it into a "hill." Most of the people in this village, except for the lovely Tara Fitzgerald as Betty, are a bit daft. The local Reverend (Kenneth Griffith) is hilarious, and Colm Meaney is the irreverent Welsh opportunist. Assorted characters like Johnny Shellshocked, Williams the Petroleum, Tommy Twostroke, and the Twp brothers add to the excitement. It is Meaney's plan to employ Tara Fitzgerald as the means to keep Grand and his partner in town until thy can add twenty feet to the mountain that really makes the film worthwhile.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stop actin' so English!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tieman64
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Christopher Monger's "The Englishman Who Went Up a Hill and Came Down A Mountain" is a gentle comedy about a pair of English cartographers (Hugh Grant and Ian McNeice) who travel to the tiny Welsh village of Ffynnon Garw in the year 1917. During their journey they reclassify a mountain as a hill, much to the chagrin of local Welsh folk, who immediately set about increasing the size of their hill so as to reclaim its mountainous status. The film was released the same year as "Braveheart", Mel Gibson's bloody hymn to ye olde Scotland. Monger's film is operating in a similar way, though its far more gentle, poking fun at all things English and exalting all things Welsh. Pitched at tourists, the film's designed to win you over with its lovable locals, quaint tone, funny customs and low key romance between an Englishman and Welsh rose. The film is supposedly based on a true story, or at least a local legend. Regardless, in Monger's hands the hill becomes a means of restoring both the Welsh community's war damaged self esteem within the film, and a means of bolstering Welsh patriotism outside the film. The National Assembly for Wales, which grants Wales the power to pass legislation without having to consult the UK parliament, was formed shortly after the film's release. Meanwhile, the cast's uncertainty as to what makes a hill and what makes a mountain (and when does one become the other?) is used as a means of cross-cultural bridge-building. You may look Welsh, may look English, but gee, you might as well be one of us. 8/10  Worth one viewing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gentle comedy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    potato2
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The year is 1917, and two English mapmakers come to a tiny Welsh village to survey their so-called 'mountain.' With the war taking all the young men and the harsh life in the coal mines, the local folk have little to be proud of except their peak, but cartographer Anson (Hugh Grant) doubts that it reaches the minimum height required to be officially deemed a mountain and may, in fact, be merely a hill. Rallied by their minister, the entire town sets about making sure it's tall enough. This sweet and folksy comedy has a thin plot and moves at a snail's pace, but still succeeds thanks to the coziness of the village, the close bond the locals share, and Hugh Grant's boyish charms. Filmed just after "Four Weddings and a Funeral," but before he was an international star, Grant is bright, likable, and interesting and not-yet affected by his trademark stammering and eyelash-fluttering. Everything about the picturesque village seems authentic and the folksy humor is ingratiating. Enjoyable if you like character-driven films.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I don't want Ffynnon Garw to be on the map because we begged for it.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Englishman Who Went Up a Hill But Came Down a Mountain is directed by Christopher Monger and written by Ivor Monger. It stars Hugh Grant, Ian McNeice, Tara Fitzgerald, Colm Meaney and Kenneth Griffith. Music is by Stephen Endelman and cinematography by Vernon Layton. Set in 1917, plot finds Grant and McNeice as two English cartographers who arrive in the Welsh village of Ffynnon Garw to measure what the locals proudly proclaim to be Wales' first mountain. However, it turns out that the "mountain" is 16 feet below the required 1000 feet requisite so therefore can only be classed as a hill. This news causes disgust amongst the locals, who then set about stopping the cartographers going home whilst they attempt to build atop of the hill to make it over 1000 feet. A film with a big title that is matched by the size of its heart, Monger's film owes much to those fun community based pictures that filed out of Ealing Studios back in the 40s and 50s, Re: Whisky Galore! and The Titfield Thunderbolt. We can also safely place it the whimsy category where something as wonderful as Local Hero sits, while the old British comedy staple that encompasses an obsession with size (The Mouse That Roared) watches over the film like an approving British cinematic angel. Homespun humour marries up with the utterly engaging view of quirky village life to provide us with just under 100 minutes of entertainment. Although clearly simple in plot and structure, to simply dismiss it as such does not do justice to the fine work of the ensemble cast and the writing of Ivor and Chris Monger. With Grant doing what he does best, the amiable nervous fop, picture has a lead actor fully comfortable with the tone and texture of the production, while around him there are a number of fine character actors putting delightful meat on the comedy bones of oddball characters with names such as Morgan the Goat, Johny Shellshock, William the Petroleum and Betty from Cardiff! Best of the bunch is Griffith as Reverend Jones, a grumpy, stubborn eccentric who underpins everything so wonderfully skew-whiff about life in Ffynnon Garw. As for the writing? The screenplay has a wonderful ear for small village dialogue, while in amongst the value of community spirit theme, sits a near sombre observation of the effects of war on such a community. The production design is appealing, with Layton's photography around the Powys locations a visual treat, and Endelman's music has a suitably warming and jaunty feel; even if it starts to get a touch repetitive later in the piece. It doesn't have widespread appeal, it's clearly a film aimed at a small portion of film fans that love those films mentioned earlier. But in an era when film is being smothered by CGI and visual gimmickry, revisiting something like The Englishman Who Went Up a Hill But Came Down a Mountain offers up a most refreshing and diverting experience. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Question Of Identity
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sddavis63 (revsdd@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/4/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A small village in Wales, relatively close to the boundary separating Wales from England, takes its identity from its proximity to what it considers to be its local mountain. All of a sudden, and quite unexpectedly, two English cartographers from the British Army show up to take a measurement of the hill and - to the horror of the town - the "mountain" is found to be 984 feet tall - 16 feet short of the 1000 feet required to be included on the map as a mountain. Set during the First World War, this movie presents an interesting picture of Welsh nationalism. In today's world, nationalism has acquired something of a bad name. It leads to feelings of superiority, racism, violence, terrorism and wars. The nationalism depicted here seemed to me to be of a more positive type. It wasn't about putting anyone down - it was about these villagers finding something about themselves and their land to take pride in without insulting anyone else - although it's clear that they themselves felt insulted by these two Englishmen having the nerve to question whether "their" mountain was really just a hill, and they set out to do something about it! One of the great lines in the movie was "if this isn't a mountain, we might as well be in England." The movie features good, if not overpowering, performances from pretty much everyone. Hugh Grant as the sympathetic Englishman Anson, and Ian McNeice as his less sympathetic partner - who considers the Welsh to be foreigners - do a fine job, and Colm Meaney has a very significant and well-played role as "Morgan the Goat" (there's some great humour here about Welsh names, that add to an overall wonderful, if somewhat low key, sense of humour throughout.) Tara Fitzgerald was also very good as Betty from Cardiff, who eventually becomes Anson's romantic interest, and also worth noting is Kenneth Griffith as Rev. Jones. Overall, this is a very pleasant journey of self-discovery for almost every character in the movie, and it's immensely enjoyable. 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Warm and funny
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andres Salama
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/2/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A pleasant, unusual comedy. Supposedly based on a real story (but probably not) and set in 1917, it tells the story of two English cartographers (Hugh Grant and Ian McNeice) who arrive in a Welsh village in order to take the measure of the nearby mountain, considered the pride of the locals. According to the height (more specifically, if it is higher than 1,000 feet), it will be determined whether it is indeed a mountain or it is just a hill. When the first measure turns out that it is just a few feet under the 1,000 mark, the anxious villagers will take action. In order to makes sure that it is recorded as a mountain, they will transport dirt and soil from the fields, and to the peak, bucket by bucket. At the same time, they will do everything to prevent the two cartographers from leaving town before they can take a second measure. Eventually, Grant, who falls in love with a local girl (Tara Fitzgerald), will help the villagers in their task (the other cartographer is much more meaner and dismissive of the Welsh). This is a small film in every sense, but it is very warm and funny.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Building a mountain out of a molehill has a whole new meaning for me now
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    DAVID SIM
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/9/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Englishman Who Went Up a Hill But Came Down a Mountain is a film that reminds me of The Dish. These are two films that are charming and even modest. Qualities you don't usually find in the Hollywood mainstream nowadays. Another similarity they share is that they both feature monumental events that happen to rural, smalltown folk, and they're directed by natives to they're respective areas. In this film's case, Wales. Set in 1917, in the town of Ffynnon Garw (Welsh names are the worst!), two cartographers Reginald Anson and George Garrad (Hugh Grant and Ian McNeice) pay a visit to survey the land. Their primary interest is to measure the town's local mountain, something the townspeople take great pride in. But they're in for a rude awakening when Anson & Garrad discover they're 'mountain' is not a mountain at all. Just a really large hill. A mountain has to be at least 1000 feet. Ffynnon Garw's hill measures up to 980 feet tops. So its a big hill to be sure. But its still just a hill. The townspeople are devastated to learn this. So they set a plan in motion. Morgan the Goat (Colm Meaney), the town's local barkeep rallies the people together to build an extra mound on top of their hill, and turn it into a mountain. TEWWUAHBCDAM is a film of simple pleasures. But that's where its appeal lies. These people are so incensed by this apparent loss to their culture that they're prepared to bend the rules to restore their former glory. And who wouldn't love the film's idea of transforming a hill into a mountain by just going that little extra distance? The building of the mountain becomes a unifying force for the town and a newfound symbol of hope. Especially since these people have lost a lot of their self-esteem and drive because of WW1. But this new project brings them together and helps them to get back a lot of their faith in themselves. And director Christopher Monger puts these points across without hammering them home. Hugh Grant is not one of my favourite actors in the world. I personally think he's an annoyingly pretentious performer. The only time he's ever watchable is when he's served by an engaging storyline or a witty screenplay. And this film happens to be one of them. He basically falls into his standard, one-note style of acting throughout. In other words, bumbling, foppish and stammering. But at least the intensely likable storytelling allows his character to prevail, despite Grant's shortcomings as an actor. The supporting cast are quite a different kettle of fish. They're all wonderful, and they all have something to add. Colm Meaney's Morgan is my favourite of all the townsfolk. His character is interesting because he swings between ambiguous extremes. Someone who is on the one hand a concerned member of the community, and on the other a self-serving huckster prepared to use the town's dilemma to profit from it. Its a well written part, and well played too by the underrated Colm Meaney. This being a Hugh Grant film, there has to be a love interest for him. And Tara Fitzgerald is superb as Betty from Cardiff. She's not only here as a romantic love interest, but her role is tied into the plot too. She's there to keep Anson distracted while the townsfolk build they're mountain. She'll keep him from leaving town, and when the mountain is ready, he can re-measure it, and put things to rights. Tara Fitzgerald may be a little too modern for a Welsh lass of 1917, but I liked her spirited, twinkly eyed flirtatiousness. Her relationship with Grant is never more than amiable, but she's so appealing in the role, you really are convinced that Anson would be prepared to settle down with her. I know I would! Monger adds the occasional hindrance to increase tension. Such as a torrential downpour that could make short work of the townspeople's hard work. But that all comes with the territory. And the final scene. Where the town vicar passes away on the hill, and his buried earth is used to complete the mountain is clever and moving too. The question of whether or not they'll finish they're mountain is hardly a mystery. But did you really want anything less? Complimented by a lovely lyrical musical score, The Englishman Who Went Up a Hill But Came Down a Mountain is a gently amusing unappreciated treat, and one of the few gracious films to be seen on TV nowadays.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Warm and positive film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Gordon-11
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/8/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is about the villagers in a Welsh village building a mountain from a hill. The determination of the villagers is striking. It touches me that everyone in the village used every imaginable way to heighten the hill to a mountain. The train conductor has to lie, villagers have to do some vandalism, and a woman has to flirt to make the two surveyors stay. It shows that even the hardest task can be achieved through collective effort. It also reminds us not to give up even if there are obstacles that hinder our progress. This film brings such a warm and positive message, which is a rarity nowadays.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Enjoyable, well-acted, funny and uplifting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tonyhu
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/5/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What's the difference between a hill and a mountain? And more importantly, does it matter? Well, it did to the residents of a small Welsh village in 1917 when two English cartographers arrived to tell them that their 'mountain' did not in fact quite make the grade. The devastated locals hatch a plan to put the science right, and therein lies the plot of this very original and charming film. Its plot veers between the insignificant and the faintly ludicrous, but by the time you have realised this you are already enjoying yourself too much to care. Why? It's a delightful and clever combination of whimsical nostalgia and top-rate performances from some truly fine character actors who are clearly having a whale of a time. Most of these performances come as no surprise: Hugh Grant plays his archetypal Hugh Grant character of course - but what critics forget is that he does it very well. Ian McNeice is typically impressive as his pompous but rather stupid superior, as is Ian Hart as the troubled young boy just back from the trenches, and Colm Meaney keeps the standard high as the sly local barman. But for me the show is stolen by Kenneth Griffith as the passionate, ever-trembling, Reverend Jones (watch him in the scene when he scolds Morgan the Goat for selling alcohol at the hill - a tremendously funny and moving characterisation). For me, the film goes off the boil a little when it gets a bogged down in Grant's inevitable fling with local temptress Tara Fitzgerald. But thankfully this doesn't clog the pace of the film too much, and we move to the denouement. It's only after the film has finished that you realise there was much more to it than met the eye. The atmospheric portrayal of early 20th century Wales owes much to meticulous direction and a wonderfully vibrant score. Critics might find some of the locals a bit yokelish, but that would be harsh, I think. This is an affectionate and subtle period piece, with something to say about the human spirit. But even more than that, it's an enjoyable, well-acted, funny and ultimately uplifting film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hugh was brilliant
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lastliberal
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/3/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I know this wasn't a huge success. Grant committed to doing it before his huge hit Four Weddings and a Funeral, but it was fun nonetheless. The conflict between the uptight Englishmen and the Welsh villagers over whether they had a hill or a mountain was extremely funny, and their solution - getting Ian McNeice drunk and keeping Hugh Grant busy with Tara Fitzgerald, who also played Grant's wife in Sirens added to the hilarity. The randy barkeep comes up with the solution to the problem, ostensibly to sell more beer, but it gets the whole town working together and make for an enjoyable film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stop actin' so English!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ben Larson
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am continuing my day of Tara Fitzgerald with an old favorite. That is because I am also a huge Hugh Grant fan, ever since Four Weddings and a Funeral. This is his first film since then. My Tara adventure has taken me to England and Ireland, and now Wales, and a quaint village. The villagers, who are proud to live in the shadow of Ffynnon Garw. the "First Mountain in Wales", are determined to thwart the efforts of the English cartographers to turn it into a "hill." Most of the people in this village, except for the lovely Tara Fitzgerald as Betty, are a bit daft. The local Reverend (Kenneth Griffith) is hilarious, and Colm Meaney is the irreverent Welsh opportunist. Assorted characters like Johnny Shellshocked, Williams the Petroleum, Tommy Twostroke, and the Twp brothers add to the excitement. It is Meaney's plan to employ Tara Fitzgerald as the means to keep Grand and his partner in town until thy can add twenty feet to the mountain that really makes the film worthwhile.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stop actin' so English!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tieman64
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Christopher Monger's "The Englishman Who Went Up a Hill and Came Down A Mountain" is a gentle comedy about a pair of English cartographers (Hugh Grant and Ian McNeice) who travel to the tiny Welsh village of Ffynnon Garw in the year 1917. During their journey they reclassify a mountain as a hill, much to the chagrin of local Welsh folk, who immediately set about increasing the size of their hill so as to reclaim its mountainous status. The film was released the same year as "Braveheart", Mel Gibson's bloody hymn to ye olde Scotland. Monger's film is operating in a similar way, though its far more gentle, poking fun at all things English and exalting all things Welsh. Pitched at tourists, the film's designed to win you over with its lovable locals, quaint tone, funny customs and low key romance between an Englishman and Welsh rose. The film is supposedly based on a true story, or at least a local legend. Regardless, in Monger's hands the hill becomes a means of restoring both the Welsh community's war damaged self esteem within the film, and a means of bolstering Welsh patriotism outside the film. The National Assembly for Wales, which grants Wales the power to pass legislation without having to consult the UK parliament, was formed shortly after the film's release. Meanwhile, the cast's uncertainty as to what makes a hill and what makes a mountain (and when does one become the other?) is used as a means of cross-cultural bridge-building. You may look Welsh, may look English, but gee, you might as well be one of us. 8/10  Worth one viewing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gentle comedy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    potato2
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The year is 1917, and two English mapmakers come to a tiny Welsh village to survey their so-called 'mountain.' With the war taking all the young men and the harsh life in the coal mines, the local folk have little to be proud of except their peak, but cartographer Anson (Hugh Grant) doubts that it reaches the minimum height required to be officially deemed a mountain and may, in fact, be merely a hill. Rallied by their minister, the entire town sets about making sure it's tall enough. This sweet and folksy comedy has a thin plot and moves at a snail's pace, but still succeeds thanks to the coziness of the village, the close bond the locals share, and Hugh Grant's boyish charms. Filmed just after "Four Weddings and a Funeral," but before he was an international star, Grant is bright, likable, and interesting and not-yet affected by his trademark stammering and eyelash-fluttering. Everything about the picturesque village seems authentic and the folksy humor is ingratiating. Enjoyable if you like character-driven films.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I don't want Ffynnon Garw to be on the map because we begged for it.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Englishman Who Went Up a Hill But Came Down a Mountain is directed by Christopher Monger and written by Ivor Monger. It stars Hugh Grant, Ian McNeice, Tara Fitzgerald, Colm Meaney and Kenneth Griffith. Music is by Stephen Endelman and cinematography by Vernon Layton. Set in 1917, plot finds Grant and McNeice as two English cartographers who arrive in the Welsh village of Ffynnon Garw to measure what the locals proudly proclaim to be Wales' first mountain. However, it turns out that the "mountain" is 16 feet below the required 1000 feet requisite so therefore can only be classed as a hill. This news causes disgust amongst the locals, who then set about stopping the cartographers going home whilst they attempt to build atop of the hill to make it over 1000 feet. A film with a big title that is matched by the size of its heart, Monger's film owes much to those fun community based pictures that filed out of Ealing Studios back in the 40s and 50s, Re: Whisky Galore! and The Titfield Thunderbolt. We can also safely place it the whimsy category where something as wonderful as Local Hero sits, while the old British comedy staple that encompasses an obsession with size (The Mouse That Roared) watches over the film like an approving British cinematic angel. Homespun humour marries up with the utterly engaging view of quirky village life to provide us with just under 100 minutes of entertainment. Although clearly simple in plot and structure, to simply dismiss it as such does not do justice to the fine work of the ensemble cast and the writing of Ivor and Chris Monger. With Grant doing what he does best, the amiable nervous fop, picture has a lead actor fully comfortable with the tone and texture of the production, while around him there are a number of fine character actors putting delightful meat on the comedy bones of oddball characters with names such as Morgan the Goat, Johny Shellshock, William the Petroleum and Betty from Cardiff! Best of the bunch is Griffith as Reverend Jones, a grumpy, stubborn eccentric who underpins everything so wonderfully skew-whiff about life in Ffynnon Garw. As for the writing? The screenplay has a wonderful ear for small village dialogue, while in amongst the value of community spirit theme, sits a near sombre observation of the effects of war on such a community. The production design is appealing, with Layton's photography around the Powys locations a visual treat, and Endelman's music has a suitably warming and jaunty feel; even if it starts to get a touch repetitive later in the piece. It doesn't have widespread appeal, it's clearly a film aimed at a small portion of film fans that love those films mentioned earlier. But in an era when film is being smothered by CGI and visual gimmickry, revisiting something like The Englishman Who Went Up a Hill But Came Down a Mountain offers up a most refreshing and diverting experience. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Question Of Identity
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sddavis63 (revsdd@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/4/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A small village in Wales, relatively close to the boundary separating Wales from England, takes its identity from its proximity to what it considers to be its local mountain. All of a sudden, and quite unexpectedly, two English cartographers from the British Army show up to take a measurement of the hill and - to the horror of the town - the "mountain" is found to be 984 feet tall - 16 feet short of the 1000 feet required to be included on the map as a mountain. Set during the First World War, this movie presents an interesting picture of Welsh nationalism. In today's world, nationalism has acquired something of a bad name. It leads to feelings of superiority, racism, violence, terrorism and wars. The nationalism depicted here seemed to me to be of a more positive type. It wasn't about putting anyone down - it was about these villagers finding something about themselves and their land to take pride in without insulting anyone else - although it's clear that they themselves felt insulted by these two Englishmen having the nerve to question whether "their" mountain was really just a hill, and they set out to do something about it! One of the great lines in the movie was "if this isn't a mountain, we might as well be in England." The movie features good, if not overpowering, performances from pretty much everyone. Hugh Grant as the sympathetic Englishman Anson, and Ian McNeice as his less sympathetic partner - who considers the Welsh to be foreigners - do a fine job, and Colm Meaney has a very significant and well-played role as "Morgan the Goat" (there's some great humour here about Welsh names, that add to an overall wonderful, if somewhat low key, sense of humour throughout.) Tara Fitzgerald was also very good as Betty from Cardiff, who eventually becomes Anson's romantic interest, and also worth noting is Kenneth Griffith as Rev. Jones. Overall, this is a very pleasant journey of self-discovery for almost every character in the movie, and it's immensely enjoyable. 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Warm and funny
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andres Salama
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/2/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A pleasant, unusual comedy. Supposedly based on a real story (but probably not) and set in 1917, it tells the story of two English cartographers (Hugh Grant and Ian McNeice) who arrive in a Welsh village in order to take the measure of the nearby mountain, considered the pride of the locals. According to the height (more specifically, if it is higher than 1,000 feet), it will be determined whether it is indeed a mountain or it is just a hill. When the first measure turns out that it is just a few feet under the 1,000 mark, the anxious villagers will take action. In order to makes sure that it is recorded as a mountain, they will transport dirt and soil from the fields, and to the peak, bucket by bucket. At the same time, they will do everything to prevent the two cartographers from leaving town before they can take a second measure. Eventually, Grant, who falls in love with a local girl (Tara Fitzgerald), will help the villagers in their task (the other cartographer is much more meaner and dismissive of the Welsh). This is a small film in every sense, but it is very warm and funny.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Building a mountain out of a molehill has a whole new meaning for me now
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    DAVID SIM
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/9/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Englishman Who Went Up a Hill But Came Down a Mountain is a film that reminds me of The Dish. These are two films that are charming and even modest. Qualities you don't usually find in the Hollywood mainstream nowadays. Another similarity they share is that they both feature monumental events that happen to rural, smalltown folk, and they're directed by natives to they're respective areas. In this film's case, Wales. Set in 1917, in the town of Ffynnon Garw (Welsh names are the worst!), two cartographers Reginald Anson and George Garrad (Hugh Grant and Ian McNeice) pay a visit to survey the land. Their primary interest is to measure the town's local mountain, something the townspeople take great pride in. But they're in for a rude awakening when Anson & Garrad discover they're 'mountain' is not a mountain at all. Just a really large hill. A mountain has to be at least 1000 feet. Ffynnon Garw's hill measures up to 980 feet tops. So its a big hill to be sure. But its still just a hill. The townspeople are devastated to learn this. So they set a plan in motion. Morgan the Goat (Colm Meaney), the town's local barkeep rallies the people together to build an extra mound on top of their hill, and turn it into a mountain. TEWWUAHBCDAM is a film of simple pleasures. But that's where its appeal lies. These people are so incensed by this apparent loss to their culture that they're prepared to bend the rules to restore their former glory. And who wouldn't love the film's idea of transforming a hill into a mountain by just going that little extra distance? The building of the mountain becomes a unifying force for the town and a newfound symbol of hope. Especially since these people have lost a lot of their self-esteem and drive because of WW1. But this new project brings them together and helps them to get back a lot of their faith in themselves. And director Christopher Monger puts these points across without hammering them home. Hugh Grant is not one of my favourite actors in the world. I personally think he's an annoyingly pretentious performer. The only time he's ever watchable is when he's served by an engaging storyline or a witty screenplay. And this film happens to be one of them. He basically falls into his standard, one-note style of acting throughout. In other words, bumbling, foppish and stammering. But at least the intensely likable storytelling allows his character to prevail, despite Grant's shortcomings as an actor. The supporting cast are quite a different kettle of fish. They're all wonderful, and they all have something to add. Colm Meaney's Morgan is my favourite of all the townsfolk. His character is interesting because he swings between ambiguous extremes. Someone who is on the one hand a concerned member of the community, and on the other a self-serving huckster prepared to use the town's dilemma to profit from it. Its a well written part, and well played too by the underrated Colm Meaney. This being a Hugh Grant film, there has to be a love interest for him. And Tara Fitzgerald is superb as Betty from Cardiff. She's not only here as a romantic love interest, but her role is tied into the plot too. She's there to keep Anson distracted while the townsfolk build they're mountain. She'll keep him from leaving town, and when the mountain is ready, he can re-measure it, and put things to rights. Tara Fitzgerald may be a little too modern for a Welsh lass of 1917, but I liked her spirited, twinkly eyed flirtatiousness. Her relationship with Grant is never more than amiable, but she's so appealing in the role, you really are convinced that Anson would be prepared to settle down with her. I know I would! Monger adds the occasional hindrance to increase tension. Such as a torrential downpour that could make short work of the townspeople's hard work. But that all comes with the territory. And the final scene. Where the town vicar passes away on the hill, and his buried earth is used to complete the mountain is clever and moving too. The question of whether or not they'll finish they're mountain is hardly a mystery. But did you really want anything less? Complimented by a lovely lyrical musical score, The Englishman Who Went Up a Hill But Came Down a Mountain is a gently amusing unappreciated treat, and one of the few gracious films to be seen on TV nowadays.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Warm and positive film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Gordon-11
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/8/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is about the villagers in a Welsh village building a mountain from a hill. The determination of the villagers is striking. It touches me that everyone in the village used every imaginable way to heighten the hill to a mountain. The train conductor has to lie, villagers have to do some vandalism, and a woman has to flirt to make the two surveyors stay. It shows that even the hardest task can be achieved through collective effort. It also reminds us not to give up even if there are obstacles that hinder our progress. This film brings such a warm and positive message, which is a rarity nowadays.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Enjoyable, well-acted, funny and uplifting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tonyhu
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/5/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What's the difference between a hill and a mountain? And more importantly, does it matter? Well, it did to the residents of a small Welsh village in 1917 when two English cartographers arrived to tell them that their 'mountain' did not in fact quite make the grade. The devastated locals hatch a plan to put the science right, and therein lies the plot of this very original and charming film. Its plot veers between the insignificant and the faintly ludicrous, but by the time you have realised this you are already enjoying yourself too much to care. Why? It's a delightful and clever combination of whimsical nostalgia and top-rate performances from some truly fine character actors who are clearly having a whale of a time. Most of these performances come as no surprise: Hugh Grant plays his archetypal Hugh Grant character of course - but what critics forget is that he does it very well. Ian McNeice is typically impressive as his pompous but rather stupid superior, as is Ian Hart as the troubled young boy just back from the trenches, and Colm Meaney keeps the standard high as the sly local barman. But for me the show is stolen by Kenneth Griffith as the passionate, ever-trembling, Reverend Jones (watch him in the scene when he scolds Morgan the Goat for selling alcohol at the hill - a tremendously funny and moving characterisation). For me, the film goes off the boil a little when it gets a bogged down in Grant's inevitable fling with local temptress Tara Fitzgerald. But thankfully this doesn't clog the pace of the film too much, and we move to the denouement. It's only after the film has finished that you realise there was much more to it than met the eye. The atmospheric portrayal of early 20th century Wales owes much to meticulous direction and a wonderfully vibrant score. Critics might find some of the locals a bit yokelish, but that would be harsh, I think. This is an affectionate and subtle period piece, with something to say about the human spirit. But even more than that, it's an enjoyable, well-acted, funny and ultimately uplifting film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hugh was brilliant
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lastliberal
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/3/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I know this wasn't a huge success. Grant committed to doing it before his huge hit Four Weddings and a Funeral, but it was fun nonetheless. The conflict between the uptight Englishmen and the Welsh villagers over whether they had a hill or a mountain was extremely funny, and their solution - getting Ian McNeice drunk and keeping Hugh Grant busy with Tara Fitzgerald, who also played Grant's wife in Sirens added to the hilarity. The randy barkeep comes up with the solution to the problem, ostensibly to sell more beer, but it gets the whole town working together and make for an enjoyable film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stop actin' so English!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ben Larson
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am continuing my day of Tara Fitzgerald with an old favorite. That is because I am also a huge Hugh Grant fan, ever since Four Weddings and a Funeral. This is his first film since then. My Tara adventure has taken me to England and Ireland, and now Wales, and a quaint village. The villagers, who are proud to live in the shadow of Ffynnon Garw. the "First Mountain in Wales", are determined to thwart the efforts of the English cartographers to turn it into a "hill." Most of the people in this village, except for the lovely Tara Fitzgerald as Betty, are a bit daft. The local Reverend (Kenneth Griffith) is hilarious, and Colm Meaney is the irreverent Welsh opportunist. Assorted characters like Johnny Shellshocked, Williams the Petroleum, Tommy Twostroke, and the Twp brothers add to the excitement. It is Meaney's plan to employ Tara Fitzgerald as the means to keep Grand and his partner in town until thy can add twenty feet to the mountain that really makes the film worthwhile.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stop actin' so English!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tieman64
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Christopher Monger's "The Englishman Who Went Up a Hill and Came Down A Mountain" is a gentle comedy about a pair of English cartographers (Hugh Grant and Ian McNeice) who travel to the tiny Welsh village of Ffynnon Garw in the year 1917. During their journey they reclassify a mountain as a hill, much to the chagrin of local Welsh folk, who immediately set about increasing the size of their hill so as to reclaim its mountainous status. The film was released the same year as "Braveheart", Mel Gibson's bloody hymn to ye olde Scotland. Monger's film is operating in a similar way, though its far more gentle, poking fun at all things English and exalting all things Welsh. Pitched at tourists, the film's designed to win you over with its lovable locals, quaint tone, funny customs and low key romance between an Englishman and Welsh rose. The film is supposedly based on a true story, or at least a local legend. Regardless, in Monger's hands the hill becomes a means of restoring both the Welsh community's war damaged self esteem within the film, and a means of bolstering Welsh patriotism outside the film. The National Assembly for Wales, which grants Wales the power to pass legislation without having to consult the UK parliament, was formed shortly after the film's release. Meanwhile, the cast's uncertainty as to what makes a hill and what makes a mountain (and when does one become the other?) is used as a means of cross-cultural bridge-building. You may look Welsh, may look English, but gee, you might as well be one of us. 8/10  Worth one viewing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gentle comedy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    potato2
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The year is 1917, and two English mapmakers come to a tiny Welsh village to survey their so-called 'mountain.' With the war taking all the young men and the harsh life in the coal mines, the local folk have little to be proud of except their peak, but cartographer Anson (Hugh Grant) doubts that it reaches the minimum height required to be officially deemed a mountain and may, in fact, be merely a hill. Rallied by their minister, the entire town sets about making sure it's tall enough. This sweet and folksy comedy has a thin plot and moves at a snail's pace, but still succeeds thanks to the coziness of the village, the close bond the locals share, and Hugh Grant's boyish charms. Filmed just after "Four Weddings and a Funeral," but before he was an international star, Grant is bright, likable, and interesting and not-yet affected by his trademark stammering and eyelash-fluttering. Everything about the picturesque village seems authentic and the folksy humor is ingratiating. Enjoyable if you like character-driven films.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I don't want Ffynnon Garw to be on the map because we begged for it.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Englishman Who Went Up a Hill But Came Down a Mountain is directed by Christopher Monger and written by Ivor Monger. It stars Hugh Grant, Ian McNeice, Tara Fitzgerald, Colm Meaney and Kenneth Griffith. Music is by Stephen Endelman and cinematography by Vernon Layton. Set in 1917, plot finds Grant and McNeice as two English cartographers who arrive in the Welsh village of Ffynnon Garw to measure what the locals proudly proclaim to be Wales' first mountain. However, it turns out that the "mountain" is 16 feet below the required 1000 feet requisite so therefore can only be classed as a hill. This news causes disgust amongst the locals, who then set about stopping the cartographers going home whilst they attempt to build atop of the hill to make it over 1000 feet. A film with a big title that is matched by the size of its heart, Monger's film owes much to those fun community based pictures that filed out of Ealing Studios back in the 40s and 50s, Re: Whisky Galore! and The Titfield Thunderbolt. We can also safely place it the whimsy category where something as wonderful as Local Hero sits, while the old British comedy staple that encompasses an obsession with size (The Mouse That Roared) watches over the film like an approving British cinematic angel. Homespun humour marries up with the utterly engaging view of quirky village life to provide us with just under 100 minutes of entertainment. Although clearly simple in plot and structure, to simply dismiss it as such does not do justice to the fine work of the ensemble cast and the writing of Ivor and Chris Monger. With Grant doing what he does best, the amiable nervous fop, picture has a lead actor fully comfortable with the tone and texture of the production, while around him there are a number of fine character actors putting delightful meat on the comedy bones of oddball characters with names such as Morgan the Goat, Johny Shellshock, William the Petroleum and Betty from Cardiff! Best of the bunch is Griffith as Reverend Jones, a grumpy, stubborn eccentric who underpins everything so wonderfully skew-whiff about life in Ffynnon Garw. As for the writing? The screenplay has a wonderful ear for small village dialogue, while in amongst the value of community spirit theme, sits a near sombre observation of the effects of war on such a community. The production design is appealing, with Layton's photography around the Powys locations a visual treat, and Endelman's music has a suitably warming and jaunty feel; even if it starts to get a touch repetitive later in the piece. It doesn't have widespread appeal, it's clearly a film aimed at a small portion of film fans that love those films mentioned earlier. But in an era when film is being smothered by CGI and visual gimmickry, revisiting something like The Englishman Who Went Up a Hill But Came Down a Mountain offers up a most refreshing and diverting experience. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Question Of Identity
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sddavis63 (revsdd@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/4/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A small village in Wales, relatively close to the boundary separating Wales from England, takes its identity from its proximity to what it considers to be its local mountain. All of a sudden, and quite unexpectedly, two English cartographers from the British Army show up to take a measurement of the hill and - to the horror of the town - the "mountain" is found to be 984 feet tall - 16 feet short of the 1000 feet required to be included on the map as a mountain. Set during the First World War, this movie presents an interesting picture of Welsh nationalism. In today's world, nationalism has acquired something of a bad name. It leads to feelings of superiority, racism, violence, terrorism and wars. The nationalism depicted here seemed to me to be of a more positive type. It wasn't about putting anyone down - it was about these villagers finding something about themselves and their land to take pride in without insulting anyone else - although it's clear that they themselves felt insulted by these two Englishmen having the nerve to question whether "their" mountain was really just a hill, and they set out to do something about it! One of the great lines in the movie was "if this isn't a mountain, we might as well be in England." The movie features good, if not overpowering, performances from pretty much everyone. Hugh Grant as the sympathetic Englishman Anson, and Ian McNeice as his less sympathetic partner - who considers the Welsh to be foreigners - do a fine job, and Colm Meaney has a very significant and well-played role as "Morgan the Goat" (there's some great humour here about Welsh names, that add to an overall wonderful, if somewhat low key, sense of humour throughout.) Tara Fitzgerald was also very good as Betty from Cardiff, who eventually becomes Anson's romantic interest, and also worth noting is Kenneth Griffith as Rev. Jones. Overall, this is a very pleasant journey of self-discovery for almost every character in the movie, and it's immensely enjoyable. 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Warm and funny
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andres Salama
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/2/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A pleasant, unusual comedy. Supposedly based on a real story (but probably not) and set in 1917, it tells the story of two English cartographers (Hugh Grant and Ian McNeice) who arrive in a Welsh village in order to take the measure of the nearby mountain, considered the pride of the locals. According to the height (more specifically, if it is higher than 1,000 feet), it will be determined whether it is indeed a mountain or it is just a hill. When the first measure turns out that it is just a few feet under the 1,000 mark, the anxious villagers will take action. In order to makes sure that it is recorded as a mountain, they will transport dirt and soil from the fields, and to the peak, bucket by bucket. At the same time, they will do everything to prevent the two cartographers from leaving town before they can take a second measure. Eventually, Grant, who falls in love with a local girl (Tara Fitzgerald), will help the villagers in their task (the other cartographer is much more meaner and dismissive of the Welsh). This is a small film in every sense, but it is very warm and funny.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Building a mountain out of a molehill has a whole new meaning for me now
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    DAVID SIM
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/9/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Englishman Who Went Up a Hill But Came Down a Mountain is a film that reminds me of The Dish. These are two films that are charming and even modest. Qualities you don't usually find in the Hollywood mainstream nowadays. Another similarity they share is that they both feature monumental events that happen to rural, smalltown folk, and they're directed by natives to they're respective areas. In this film's case, Wales. Set in 1917, in the town of Ffynnon Garw (Welsh names are the worst!), two cartographers Reginald Anson and George Garrad (Hugh Grant and Ian McNeice) pay a visit to survey the land. Their primary interest is to measure the town's local mountain, something the townspeople take great pride in. But they're in for a rude awakening when Anson & Garrad discover they're 'mountain' is not a mountain at all. Just a really large hill. A mountain has to be at least 1000 feet. Ffynnon Garw's hill measures up to 980 feet tops. So its a big hill to be sure. But its still just a hill. The townspeople are devastated to learn this. So they set a plan in motion. Morgan the Goat (Colm Meaney), the town's local barkeep rallies the people together to build an extra mound on top of their hill, and turn it into a mountain. TEWWUAHBCDAM is a film of simple pleasures. But that's where its appeal lies. These people are so incensed by this apparent loss to their culture that they're prepared to bend the rules to restore their former glory. And who wouldn't love the film's idea of transforming a hill into a mountain by just going that little extra distance? The building of the mountain becomes a unifying force for the town and a newfound symbol of hope. Especially since these people have lost a lot of their self-esteem and drive because of WW1. But this new project brings them together and helps them to get back a lot of their faith in themselves. And director Christopher Monger puts these points across without hammering them home. Hugh Grant is not one of my favourite actors in the world. I personally think he's an annoyingly pretentious performer. The only time he's ever watchable is when he's served by an engaging storyline or a witty screenplay. And this film happens to be one of them. He basically falls into his standard, one-note style of acting throughout. In other words, bumbling, foppish and stammering. But at least the intensely likable storytelling allows his character to prevail, despite Grant's shortcomings as an actor. The supporting cast are quite a different kettle of fish. They're all wonderful, and they all have something to add. Colm Meaney's Morgan is my favourite of all the townsfolk. His character is interesting because he swings between ambiguous extremes. Someone who is on the one hand a concerned member of the community, and on the other a self-serving huckster prepared to use the town's dilemma to profit from it. Its a well written part, and well played too by the underrated Colm Meaney. This being a Hugh Grant film, there has to be a love interest for him. And Tara Fitzgerald is superb as Betty from Cardiff. She's not only here as a romantic love interest, but her role is tied into the plot too. She's there to keep Anson distracted while the townsfolk build they're mountain. She'll keep him from leaving town, and when the mountain is ready, he can re-measure it, and put things to rights. Tara Fitzgerald may be a little too modern for a Welsh lass of 1917, but I liked her spirited, twinkly eyed flirtatiousness. Her relationship with Grant is never more than amiable, but she's so appealing in the role, you really are convinced that Anson would be prepared to settle down with her. I know I would! Monger adds the occasional hindrance to increase tension. Such as a torrential downpour that could make short work of the townspeople's hard work. But that all comes with the territory. And the final scene. Where the town vicar passes away on the hill, and his buried earth is used to complete the mountain is clever and moving too. The question of whether or not they'll finish they're mountain is hardly a mystery. But did you really want anything less? Complimented by a lovely lyrical musical score, The Englishman Who Went Up a Hill But Came Down a Mountain is a gently amusing unappreciated treat, and one of the few gracious films to be seen on TV nowadays.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Warm and positive film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Gordon-11
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/8/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is about the villagers in a Welsh village building a mountain from a hill. The determination of the villagers is striking. It touches me that everyone in the village used every imaginable way to heighten the hill to a mountain. The train conductor has to lie, villagers have to do some vandalism, and a woman has to flirt to make the two surveyors stay. It shows that even the hardest task can be achieved through collective effort. It also reminds us not to give up even if there are obstacles that hinder our progress. This film brings such a warm and positive message, which is a rarity nowadays.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Enjoyable, well-acted, funny and uplifting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tonyhu
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/5/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What's the difference between a hill and a mountain? And more importantly, does it matter? Well, it did to the residents of a small Welsh village in 1917 when two English cartographers arrived to tell them that their 'mountain' did not in fact quite make the grade. The devastated locals hatch a plan to put the science right, and therein lies the plot of this very original and charming film. Its plot veers between the insignificant and the faintly ludicrous, but by the time you have realised this you are already enjoying yourself too much to care. Why? It's a delightful and clever combination of whimsical nostalgia and top-rate performances from some truly fine character actors who are clearly having a whale of a time. Most of these performances come as no surprise: Hugh Grant plays his archetypal Hugh Grant character of course - but what critics forget is that he does it very well. Ian McNeice is typically impressive as his pompous but rather stupid superior, as is Ian Hart as the troubled young boy just back from the trenches, and Colm Meaney keeps the standard high as the sly local barman. But for me the show is stolen by Kenneth Griffith as the passionate, ever-trembling, Reverend Jones (watch him in the scene when he scolds Morgan the Goat for selling alcohol at the hill - a tremendously funny and moving characterisation). For me, the film goes off the boil a little when it gets a bogged down in Grant's inevitable fling with local temptress Tara Fitzgerald. But thankfully this doesn't clog the pace of the film too much, and we move to the denouement. It's only after the film has finished that you realise there was much more to it than met the eye. The atmospheric portrayal of early 20th century Wales owes much to meticulous direction and a wonderfully vibrant score. Critics might find some of the locals a bit yokelish, but that would be harsh, I think. This is an affectionate and subtle period piece, with something to say about the human spirit. But even more than that, it's an enjoyable, well-acted, funny and ultimately uplifting film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hugh was brilliant
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lastliberal
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/3/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I know this wasn't a huge success. Grant committed to doing it before his huge hit Four Weddings and a Funeral, but it was fun nonetheless. The conflict between the uptight Englishmen and the Welsh villagers over whether they had a hill or a mountain was extremely funny, and their solution - getting Ian McNeice drunk and keeping Hugh Grant busy with Tara Fitzgerald, who also played Grant's wife in Sirens added to the hilarity. The randy barkeep comes up with the solution to the problem, ostensibly to sell more beer, but it gets the whole town working together and make for an enjoyable film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
