<filme>
 <id>
  581
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0107302
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1993
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Kalifornia - Uma Viagem ao Inferno
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.6
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  A journalist duo go on a tour of serial killer murder sites with two companions, unaware that one of them is a serial killer himself.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Brian Kessler, a journalist researching serial killers, and his photographer girlfriend Carrie set out on a cross-country tour of the sites of the killings. Sharing the ride and their expenses are Early Grayce, a paroled white trash criminal, and his girlfriend Adele. As the trip progresses, Early begins to appear more and more unstable, and Brian and Carrie begin to fear that they may have a real-life killer in the back seat of their car.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Crime
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Thriller
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   killer
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   serial killer
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   journalist
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   cross country
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   murder
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Dominic Sena
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Stephen Levy
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Tim Metcalfe
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Brad Pitt
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Juliette Lewis
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Kathy Larson
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nice showcase for Pitt.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Scott LeBrun (Hey_Sweden)
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What goes on in the mind of a serial killer? What is it, really, that separates "us" from "them"? More importantly, what is with the fascination that so many of us have for true crime stories and deviant individuals? What does it take to change a persons' opinion on the subject? These are questions that this grim, stylish, intelligent drama asks as it plays out. It offers interesting roles to a talented quartet of performers, and is very straightforward with the way it portrays acts of violence. David Duchovny plays Brian Kessler, a writer with a fixation on serial killers who's gotten an advance to write a book about them. With his photographer girlfriend Carrie Laughlin (Michelle Forbes) in tow, he embarks on a road trip of research as he travels across America to visit the sites of various crimes. The two of them get closer to their subject matter than they could have imagined when they hook up with dirt poor trailer trash couple Early Grayce (Brad Pitt) and Adele Corners (Juliette Lewis). Early, you see, is a vicious sociopath who does some awful things without feeling any remorse about them. One major theme of the film is the evolution of the Brian character. He starts out as pretty liberal when it comes to the serial killer topic and is forced to realize the fact that - as he says near the end - that any one of us *is* capable of taking another humans' life if properly motivated. There's not really that much separation, after all. "Kalifornia" is one of those films that works on both the intellectually stimulating and visceral levels. It's fascinating to watch, even as it deliberately paces itself for close to two hours. Pitt is excellent, truly disappearing inside his role and enjoying playing the different aspects to this killer. Lewis is fine as a sweet, simple girl; this part of hers is intriguing when you contrast it to the one she plays in the next years' "Natural Born Killers". Duchovny and Forbes are believable as they do the bulk of the reacting in this film. Hailed by some as a serial killer story for the thinking person, this is a ride well worth taking. Eight out of 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brad Pitt is Simply Outstanding
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is the first movie that I have seen that Erbert has given four stars. He raves about how well this movie was made and how realistic the characters are. I wouldn't give it a score that high, but I do agree that the characters in this movie are really well done. Atlantic Video (my video store, excellent place for cheap videos, and they have a huge selection) labels this as an action, and others say that it is a thriller. I would consider this movie to be a psychological examination of people. It exposes us to the harsh reality of life and is far for falling into the category of mainstream Hollywood. I first heard of this movie when it was advertised in the Mercury Cinema, the old alternative cinema in Adelaide. My gripe is the character of Brian Kessler (David Duchovney). There is nothing wrong with the character itself, but it reminded me a lot of agent Mulder. The twist between Kessler and Mulder is that Kessler considers himself a psychologist but he is not. His ambition is to write a book on serial killers and why the do what they do. Kessler knows that he cannot learn about serial killers by sitting in a library so he decides to go to California with his girlfriend, Carrie Laughlin (Michelle Forbes) and on the way there visit the sights of famous serial killers to try and uncover why serial killers do what they do. Kessler realises at the end of the movie that he has absolutely no idea as to why they do what they do. After his experience with Early he realises that some people do things because they want to. This brings us to Early (Brad Pitt). Brad Pitt's portrayal of Early is brilliant. Upon seeing this one comes to the conclusion that Brad Pitt does know how to act. Beyond this is the character of Early. Kessler does not understand why Early is the way he is but it seems to me that Early just does not perceive anything beyond his own experience. He does not see that there are repercussions for his actions. Erbert says that Early is intelligent, but I disagree. Early does things on the spur of the moment and never plans his actions. He needs money so he kills a man with lots of money. He just doesn't care that he just killed somebody, and this comes from a man who has probably done it a lot before. Adele Corners (Juliette Lewis) is a very well developed character. She is a character that lives in a dream world and believes everything that is told her. She is a child that was thrust into adulthood quite violently. She does not want to grow up so she remains a child at heart. She has a preconceived idea about who Early is and she does not want to believe that he is anything else, even if she is confronted by it. Kalifornia is a movie about reality. It is two couples from different backgrounds who have come together and are influenced by each other. Brian slowly becomes influenced by Early while Adele becomes influenced by Carrie. We notice something when Adele enters the restaurant with her hair cut, and slowly she becomes to look more like Carrie. The only differences are the clothes. Carrie dresses very dark and wears trousers while Adele wear scanty dresses. This is a movie about the way people behave and how some people are just evil.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good psychological thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Wuchak
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Kalifornia" went unnoticed at the box office in 1993, but it's a quality psychological thriller starring David Duchovny and Michelle Forbes as a writer & photographer team who travel to California from Georgia, documenting a book on serial killers along the way. To help with expenses, they take on two have-nots as passengers, played by Brad Pitt and Juliette Lewis. Unfortunately, Pitt's character may be a sinister killer behind his "good ol' boy" mask. The film's presumably spelled "Kalifornia" because Kali is the Hindu goddess of death, which is a creative touch. In any event, this is an effective psychological road movie, shot in Georgia, Illinois and California. Brad Pitt really shows off his acting skills in this one because he is completely convincing as a backcountry psychopath (just as he's convincing as the noble Achilles in "Troy"). Lewis is also effective as his naive and childish girlfriend. As the trip progresses Duchovny's character becomes increasingly intrigued by Pitt's animalistic power while Forbes grows concerned of his dangerous potential. The film's also an interesting look at the differences between the middle class and the poor, the educated and the ignorant. There's not much else to say. If you're in the mood for a serious road flick that examines the nature of the killer instinct and more, be sure to check out "Kalifornia." The film goes on a bit too long at 118 minutes but, other than that, I can't think of anything bad to say. GRADE: B
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stylish, Violent & Fast Moving
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    seymourblack-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Kalifornia" is a violent road movie that features two couples who, for different reasons, want to move to California to make a fresh start. The couples come from different social classes and are worlds apart in terms of education and sophistication. These differences and other tensions that exist between them as individuals, create a consistently strained atmosphere which becomes even more intense as they gradually start to learn more about each other. Brian Kessler (David Duchovny) is a psychology graduate who, having written a well-received magazine article about serial killers is given an advance to write a book on the subject. His girlfriend Carrie Laughlin (Michelle Forbes), who's an aspiring photographer, wants to move to California and so they plan to use their cross-country trip to visit famous murder sites to gather material for Brian's book. As they don't have sufficient funds to pay for their trip, Brian places an advertisement on the bulletin board of the local University for anyone who'd like to make the same journey and share the costs. Brian's ad is answered by Early Grayce (Brad Pitt), an unemployed ex-con who's just killed his landlord because he was demanding payment of rent money that was owed to him. When Brian and Michelle go to pick up Early and his girlfriend Adele (Juliette Lewis), Michelle's first impulse is to pull out of the agreement as Early and Adele look impoverished and common. Brian, however, is anxious to get on with the trip and persuades Michelle to put her concerns to one side. Brian is a man who likes to think the best of everyone and believes that murderers are victims of their backgrounds which have effectively made them into killers. He's absolutely fascinated by murderers and enjoys studying their motivations. During the journey to California, he slowly starts to become aware of the real nature of his travelling companions and things turn extremely violent and scary before he discovers why he has such an intense interest in killing and also has to re-think some of his long-held views. Brad Pitt puts an incredible amount of energy and drive into his role as the embodiment of pure evil and is completely convincing as a psychopath who simply does whatever his instincts dictate. Michelle Forbes does a great deal of frowning and scowling as the cold, pretentious Carrie who's a voyeur and can't help being fascinated by things that she also finds repulsive. She's hard and cynical and even her hairstyle is severe! David Duchovny is good as the naive and gullible Brian who learns more about his specialist subject than he could ever have imagined and Juliette Lewis is amazing as the tragic, undereducated young woman with a traumatic background which has left her so damaged that she sees the manipulative Early as being a well-meaning man who's dedicated to protecting her. "Kalifornia" is stylishly made, fast moving and beautifully photographed but certain passages are also uncomfortable to watch. Its real strength lies in its characters who make it compelling from start to finish.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Worth a watch just for Pitt's performance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ForVirg
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Kalifornia would be just an OK movie, were it not for the performance of pretty-boy Brad Pitt. In this film, he is anything BUT pretty. In fact, he's so convincingly creepy, it makes my skin crawl just to think about this role. Whether or not he took on the role to battle type-casting is unimportant, because he does, in fact, show his acting chops amazingly well as the poor white trash monster. It's rare to see any actor take on the persona of a character so convincingly. The idea of this film is a good one, and executed fairly well, but could have been done better. In particular, Michelle Forbes character, Carrie, is extremely grating. Hers is a character who will fit into L.A. culture very well--bitchy, superior, and judgmental. I know I should sympathize with Carrie's correct assessment of the situation, but I just hate her too much to care. Of course, I could argue that without her bitchy superiority, there wouldn't be a story. On the other hand, Juliette Lewis' character, Adele, is charmingly endearing, and I found myself wishing for Adele and Duchovny's Brian to wind up together. Were it not for the cast, this movie would be unremarkable. But with the performance of the cast, I find myself watching it again and again over the years since its release. That must count for something!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brad gets his kicks on Route 66.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BA_Harrison
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Why the K? I don't know, but then I don't really understand who the intended audience for this film is either. It's not extreme enough to appease fans of disturbing cinema, not cerebral or cool enough for art-house types, nor is it mainstream enough to appeal to the general public; it's there, treading a fine line between all threefrustrating, because Kalifornia has plenty of potential, and if director Dominic Sena had just chosen one definitive route to take, the film might have been a great addition to the serial killer genre instead of an average one. The plot explores several fascinating themesclass divide, the allure of danger and violence, psychotic behaviour and the complexities of the brainbut Sena's indecisive approach means that he only lightly addresses each issue, and often in a trite and predictable manner. A dreary narration from David Duchovny's obnoxious yuppie is intended to make events seem more profound, but only serves to make the film seem highly pretentious. Sena's glossy visuals give an 80s music video vibe (not that surprising given his previous work with Janet Jackson) which seriously jars with the content. Brad Pitt and Juliette Lewis' memorable performances ensure that the film isn't a total waste of time, both actors taking 'poor white trash' to a whole new (and sometimes hilarious) level, and there are one or two effectively shocking outbursts of violence, but this is an ultimately empty experience that says much less about its subject matter than it would have you believe.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dark
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Brad Pitt at his most evil. He is Early, an amoral human being who will destroy anyone for any reason whatsoever. Juliette Lewis is Adele, his companion in their world of woe. Early answers an ad to share a car ride with a journalist, Brian(David Duchovny) who has written a book about serial killers and is traveling to various sites of notorious crimes with his girlfriend,Carrie(Michelle Forbes), a photographer. The law abiding couple have no idea that their driving mates are completely insane. Even before the road trip Early had killed his landlord over a rent dispute and then did away with a gas station attendant during a robbery with his passengers unaware of the events. At one of the stops along the way, Carrie watches a television report about Early as a murder suspect. She and Brian become hostages and witness further mayhem, including a home invasion and police shooting. The four eventually have a violent last stand and the payoff is o.k. as far films of this genre go.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Killer movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Maniac-9
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Interesting movie about a pair of people investigating serial killers but unbeknowest to them they're travelling with their very own serial killer. Brad Pitt totally pulls off the psycho redneck killer persona with Juliette Lewis as his white trash girlfriend and David Duchovny and Michelle Forbes as a pair of yuppies. The movie is definitely a departure for Pitt on his normal leading man roles where he totally transforms himself into a character that is very unBrad Pitt like. The movie is more then just your average serial killer movie with a mix of black comedy and satire. Movie while being a movie about serial killers also has a bit of road trip aspect to it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Terrible And Ugly, Yet For Pure Comedy It Has It's Moments
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dan1863Sickles
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    KALIFORNIA is a movie I wanted to see ever since it first came out. Back in 1993 Brad Pitt and Juliette Lewis were a couple. Both were hot, rising young stars with a hip, punk-rock image. I always assumed this movie would be some sort of cool kids on the run epic, a killing spree set to a great alternative rock sound track, sort of REPO MAN meets POINT BREAK. Alas no, by Jove! Ten minutes in, Brad Pitt walks into a sleazy diner, and shouts, "AW WAWNT A BAOWEL UH CHILLEH," knocking it out of the park with the most uproariously bad Southern accent in the history of film. Right then I knew I was heading for comedy genius. Not since Peter Sellers turned the French accent inside out as Inspector Clouseau has an actor gotten so many laughs out of simple mis-pro-nun-cia-tion. But it doesn't stop with Brad's crucifixion of redneck culture. The moment David Duchovny makes the scene, the John Lennon of Sucky Acting has found his Paul McCartney. The chemistry between the rip-roaring redneck and the geeky nerd with the tape recorder is so amazing -- two forms of bad acting, (macho shouting versus wimpy whining) but blended together with total harmony. The girls in this movie are actually somewhat better than the boys, though that's not saying much. Michelle Forbes, who went on years later to be a standout presence in the HBO series TRUE BLOOD, is at this point totally charisma free, but at least she's inoffensive. What little acting this movie has all comes from Juliette Lewis, who somehow turns the shallowest and most insultingly stereotypical character (the helpless child-woman, the white trash victim) into a completely sympathetic and believable human being. If you want to read a really good book that tells the same story, (wimpy elitist kidnapped/liberated by white trash killer) read DIRTY WHITE BOYS by Stephen Hunter. KALIFORNIA is a terrible movie, but Brad Pitt would have made an awesome Lamar Pye. And David Duchovny would have been a natural as wimpy little Richard Peed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Kalifornia Exhibits Brad Pitt's Acting Talent
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This debut feature film from music video director Dominic Sena is a romp through the world of serial killing, which in its bleakness and moral bankruptcy looks backwards to Terrence Malick's Badlands and forward to Oliver Stone's Natural Born Killers. Kalifornia is a thriller/road film, directed by Sena, features Brad Pitt, Juliette Lewis, David Duchovny, and Michelle Forbes. The story focuses on an aspiring writer and his photographer girlfriend who are traveling cross-country to research serial killers. To help pay for gas, they take along a man and his childlike girlfriend,unaware that the man is a killer himself. Brian Kessler is a graduate student in Psychology and a journalist authoring a book about serial killers. His photographer girlfriend Carrie Laughlin persuades him to move to California; and, when his book project is accepted by a publisher, they decide to drive from Pittsburgh to California and visit infamous murder sites along the way. Short on funds, Brian posts a ride-share ad. Meanwhile, parolee Early Grayce has just lost his job. His Parole Officer learns of this and comes to the trailer park where Early lives with his young girlfriend Adele Corners. Early refuses the officer's offer of a job as a college janitor, saying he wants to leave the state. The officer informs him that, if he doesn't keep the appointment, he will be returned to prison. Early decides to go to the job interview; and, when he's on his way out, he is confronted by the landlord over non-payment of rent. Early grows violent and spins out in his car, chasing the man all over the park. On the road, unknown to his companions, Early murders a man in a gas station bathroom and steals his money. When they arrive at the first hotel, he cuts Adele's hair to match Carrie's. At another hotel, Early invites Brian out to play pool, leaving Adele and Carrie alone together. Adele reveals to Carrie that she is a rape victim and that she views Early as her protector, even though her mother didn't approve because Early had just been released from prison. Carrie is alarmed by Brian's growing fascination with Early and nonchalant response to the news that Early has been in prison. She gives him an ultimatumeither they rid themselves of Early and Adele or she will leave. At the next gas station, Carrie glimpses a newscast with footage of Early and the announcement he is a suspected murderer. Early kills the gas-station attendant and continues the trip with the couple as hostages. They encounter two police officers, whom Early shoots. Early orders Brian to finish off one of the wounded officers, but Brian refuses. They next come to the home of an elderly couple. Early beats the man to death, but Adele allows the woman to flee. As Early rushes to find the woman, Adele confronts him and says she wants nothing more to do with him. Early shoots Adele, strikes Brian on the head, and kidnaps Carrie. Brian regains consciousness, and the elderly woman gives him the keys to her truck. Brian arrives at an abandoned nuclear testing site and surprises Early, hitting him in the head with a shovel. Brian finds Carrie bloodied and handcuffed to a bed. Early, who was only stunned, attacks Brian and they struggle until Carrie hits Early in the head. When Early continues the attack, Brian shoots him dead.The movie ends with Brian and Carrie in a California beach house. It is an absolutely riveting movie that is visually stylish and thematically creepy. The movie begins extremely well before escalating into the inevitable confrontation, when the sensitive-intellectual man discovers that when push comes to shove, we're all brutes and animals.Brad Pitt's performance is excellent and crucial, and he rips into the character with a frightening sense of unhinged egomania, violently subverting the pretty-boy image with which so many wanted to associate him.This definitely made the viewer realize that he indeed is more than a pretty face but a talented actor as well.Watch it for his performance alone.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nice showcase for Pitt.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Scott LeBrun (Hey_Sweden)
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What goes on in the mind of a serial killer? What is it, really, that separates "us" from "them"? More importantly, what is with the fascination that so many of us have for true crime stories and deviant individuals? What does it take to change a persons' opinion on the subject? These are questions that this grim, stylish, intelligent drama asks as it plays out. It offers interesting roles to a talented quartet of performers, and is very straightforward with the way it portrays acts of violence. David Duchovny plays Brian Kessler, a writer with a fixation on serial killers who's gotten an advance to write a book about them. With his photographer girlfriend Carrie Laughlin (Michelle Forbes) in tow, he embarks on a road trip of research as he travels across America to visit the sites of various crimes. The two of them get closer to their subject matter than they could have imagined when they hook up with dirt poor trailer trash couple Early Grayce (Brad Pitt) and Adele Corners (Juliette Lewis). Early, you see, is a vicious sociopath who does some awful things without feeling any remorse about them. One major theme of the film is the evolution of the Brian character. He starts out as pretty liberal when it comes to the serial killer topic and is forced to realize the fact that - as he says near the end - that any one of us *is* capable of taking another humans' life if properly motivated. There's not really that much separation, after all. "Kalifornia" is one of those films that works on both the intellectually stimulating and visceral levels. It's fascinating to watch, even as it deliberately paces itself for close to two hours. Pitt is excellent, truly disappearing inside his role and enjoying playing the different aspects to this killer. Lewis is fine as a sweet, simple girl; this part of hers is intriguing when you contrast it to the one she plays in the next years' "Natural Born Killers". Duchovny and Forbes are believable as they do the bulk of the reacting in this film. Hailed by some as a serial killer story for the thinking person, this is a ride well worth taking. Eight out of 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brad Pitt is Simply Outstanding
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is the first movie that I have seen that Erbert has given four stars. He raves about how well this movie was made and how realistic the characters are. I wouldn't give it a score that high, but I do agree that the characters in this movie are really well done. Atlantic Video (my video store, excellent place for cheap videos, and they have a huge selection) labels this as an action, and others say that it is a thriller. I would consider this movie to be a psychological examination of people. It exposes us to the harsh reality of life and is far for falling into the category of mainstream Hollywood. I first heard of this movie when it was advertised in the Mercury Cinema, the old alternative cinema in Adelaide. My gripe is the character of Brian Kessler (David Duchovney). There is nothing wrong with the character itself, but it reminded me a lot of agent Mulder. The twist between Kessler and Mulder is that Kessler considers himself a psychologist but he is not. His ambition is to write a book on serial killers and why the do what they do. Kessler knows that he cannot learn about serial killers by sitting in a library so he decides to go to California with his girlfriend, Carrie Laughlin (Michelle Forbes) and on the way there visit the sights of famous serial killers to try and uncover why serial killers do what they do. Kessler realises at the end of the movie that he has absolutely no idea as to why they do what they do. After his experience with Early he realises that some people do things because they want to. This brings us to Early (Brad Pitt). Brad Pitt's portrayal of Early is brilliant. Upon seeing this one comes to the conclusion that Brad Pitt does know how to act. Beyond this is the character of Early. Kessler does not understand why Early is the way he is but it seems to me that Early just does not perceive anything beyond his own experience. He does not see that there are repercussions for his actions. Erbert says that Early is intelligent, but I disagree. Early does things on the spur of the moment and never plans his actions. He needs money so he kills a man with lots of money. He just doesn't care that he just killed somebody, and this comes from a man who has probably done it a lot before. Adele Corners (Juliette Lewis) is a very well developed character. She is a character that lives in a dream world and believes everything that is told her. She is a child that was thrust into adulthood quite violently. She does not want to grow up so she remains a child at heart. She has a preconceived idea about who Early is and she does not want to believe that he is anything else, even if she is confronted by it. Kalifornia is a movie about reality. It is two couples from different backgrounds who have come together and are influenced by each other. Brian slowly becomes influenced by Early while Adele becomes influenced by Carrie. We notice something when Adele enters the restaurant with her hair cut, and slowly she becomes to look more like Carrie. The only differences are the clothes. Carrie dresses very dark and wears trousers while Adele wear scanty dresses. This is a movie about the way people behave and how some people are just evil.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good psychological thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Wuchak
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Kalifornia" went unnoticed at the box office in 1993, but it's a quality psychological thriller starring David Duchovny and Michelle Forbes as a writer & photographer team who travel to California from Georgia, documenting a book on serial killers along the way. To help with expenses, they take on two have-nots as passengers, played by Brad Pitt and Juliette Lewis. Unfortunately, Pitt's character may be a sinister killer behind his "good ol' boy" mask. The film's presumably spelled "Kalifornia" because Kali is the Hindu goddess of death, which is a creative touch. In any event, this is an effective psychological road movie, shot in Georgia, Illinois and California. Brad Pitt really shows off his acting skills in this one because he is completely convincing as a backcountry psychopath (just as he's convincing as the noble Achilles in "Troy"). Lewis is also effective as his naive and childish girlfriend. As the trip progresses Duchovny's character becomes increasingly intrigued by Pitt's animalistic power while Forbes grows concerned of his dangerous potential. The film's also an interesting look at the differences between the middle class and the poor, the educated and the ignorant. There's not much else to say. If you're in the mood for a serious road flick that examines the nature of the killer instinct and more, be sure to check out "Kalifornia." The film goes on a bit too long at 118 minutes but, other than that, I can't think of anything bad to say. GRADE: B
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stylish, Violent & Fast Moving
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    seymourblack-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Kalifornia" is a violent road movie that features two couples who, for different reasons, want to move to California to make a fresh start. The couples come from different social classes and are worlds apart in terms of education and sophistication. These differences and other tensions that exist between them as individuals, create a consistently strained atmosphere which becomes even more intense as they gradually start to learn more about each other. Brian Kessler (David Duchovny) is a psychology graduate who, having written a well-received magazine article about serial killers is given an advance to write a book on the subject. His girlfriend Carrie Laughlin (Michelle Forbes), who's an aspiring photographer, wants to move to California and so they plan to use their cross-country trip to visit famous murder sites to gather material for Brian's book. As they don't have sufficient funds to pay for their trip, Brian places an advertisement on the bulletin board of the local University for anyone who'd like to make the same journey and share the costs. Brian's ad is answered by Early Grayce (Brad Pitt), an unemployed ex-con who's just killed his landlord because he was demanding payment of rent money that was owed to him. When Brian and Michelle go to pick up Early and his girlfriend Adele (Juliette Lewis), Michelle's first impulse is to pull out of the agreement as Early and Adele look impoverished and common. Brian, however, is anxious to get on with the trip and persuades Michelle to put her concerns to one side. Brian is a man who likes to think the best of everyone and believes that murderers are victims of their backgrounds which have effectively made them into killers. He's absolutely fascinated by murderers and enjoys studying their motivations. During the journey to California, he slowly starts to become aware of the real nature of his travelling companions and things turn extremely violent and scary before he discovers why he has such an intense interest in killing and also has to re-think some of his long-held views. Brad Pitt puts an incredible amount of energy and drive into his role as the embodiment of pure evil and is completely convincing as a psychopath who simply does whatever his instincts dictate. Michelle Forbes does a great deal of frowning and scowling as the cold, pretentious Carrie who's a voyeur and can't help being fascinated by things that she also finds repulsive. She's hard and cynical and even her hairstyle is severe! David Duchovny is good as the naive and gullible Brian who learns more about his specialist subject than he could ever have imagined and Juliette Lewis is amazing as the tragic, undereducated young woman with a traumatic background which has left her so damaged that she sees the manipulative Early as being a well-meaning man who's dedicated to protecting her. "Kalifornia" is stylishly made, fast moving and beautifully photographed but certain passages are also uncomfortable to watch. Its real strength lies in its characters who make it compelling from start to finish.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Worth a watch just for Pitt's performance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ForVirg
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Kalifornia would be just an OK movie, were it not for the performance of pretty-boy Brad Pitt. In this film, he is anything BUT pretty. In fact, he's so convincingly creepy, it makes my skin crawl just to think about this role. Whether or not he took on the role to battle type-casting is unimportant, because he does, in fact, show his acting chops amazingly well as the poor white trash monster. It's rare to see any actor take on the persona of a character so convincingly. The idea of this film is a good one, and executed fairly well, but could have been done better. In particular, Michelle Forbes character, Carrie, is extremely grating. Hers is a character who will fit into L.A. culture very well--bitchy, superior, and judgmental. I know I should sympathize with Carrie's correct assessment of the situation, but I just hate her too much to care. Of course, I could argue that without her bitchy superiority, there wouldn't be a story. On the other hand, Juliette Lewis' character, Adele, is charmingly endearing, and I found myself wishing for Adele and Duchovny's Brian to wind up together. Were it not for the cast, this movie would be unremarkable. But with the performance of the cast, I find myself watching it again and again over the years since its release. That must count for something!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brad gets his kicks on Route 66.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BA_Harrison
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Why the K? I don't know, but then I don't really understand who the intended audience for this film is either. It's not extreme enough to appease fans of disturbing cinema, not cerebral or cool enough for art-house types, nor is it mainstream enough to appeal to the general public; it's there, treading a fine line between all threefrustrating, because Kalifornia has plenty of potential, and if director Dominic Sena had just chosen one definitive route to take, the film might have been a great addition to the serial killer genre instead of an average one. The plot explores several fascinating themesclass divide, the allure of danger and violence, psychotic behaviour and the complexities of the brainbut Sena's indecisive approach means that he only lightly addresses each issue, and often in a trite and predictable manner. A dreary narration from David Duchovny's obnoxious yuppie is intended to make events seem more profound, but only serves to make the film seem highly pretentious. Sena's glossy visuals give an 80s music video vibe (not that surprising given his previous work with Janet Jackson) which seriously jars with the content. Brad Pitt and Juliette Lewis' memorable performances ensure that the film isn't a total waste of time, both actors taking 'poor white trash' to a whole new (and sometimes hilarious) level, and there are one or two effectively shocking outbursts of violence, but this is an ultimately empty experience that says much less about its subject matter than it would have you believe.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dark
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Brad Pitt at his most evil. He is Early, an amoral human being who will destroy anyone for any reason whatsoever. Juliette Lewis is Adele, his companion in their world of woe. Early answers an ad to share a car ride with a journalist, Brian(David Duchovny) who has written a book about serial killers and is traveling to various sites of notorious crimes with his girlfriend,Carrie(Michelle Forbes), a photographer. The law abiding couple have no idea that their driving mates are completely insane. Even before the road trip Early had killed his landlord over a rent dispute and then did away with a gas station attendant during a robbery with his passengers unaware of the events. At one of the stops along the way, Carrie watches a television report about Early as a murder suspect. She and Brian become hostages and witness further mayhem, including a home invasion and police shooting. The four eventually have a violent last stand and the payoff is o.k. as far films of this genre go.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Killer movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Maniac-9
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Interesting movie about a pair of people investigating serial killers but unbeknowest to them they're travelling with their very own serial killer. Brad Pitt totally pulls off the psycho redneck killer persona with Juliette Lewis as his white trash girlfriend and David Duchovny and Michelle Forbes as a pair of yuppies. The movie is definitely a departure for Pitt on his normal leading man roles where he totally transforms himself into a character that is very unBrad Pitt like. The movie is more then just your average serial killer movie with a mix of black comedy and satire. Movie while being a movie about serial killers also has a bit of road trip aspect to it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Terrible And Ugly, Yet For Pure Comedy It Has It's Moments
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dan1863Sickles
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    KALIFORNIA is a movie I wanted to see ever since it first came out. Back in 1993 Brad Pitt and Juliette Lewis were a couple. Both were hot, rising young stars with a hip, punk-rock image. I always assumed this movie would be some sort of cool kids on the run epic, a killing spree set to a great alternative rock sound track, sort of REPO MAN meets POINT BREAK. Alas no, by Jove! Ten minutes in, Brad Pitt walks into a sleazy diner, and shouts, "AW WAWNT A BAOWEL UH CHILLEH," knocking it out of the park with the most uproariously bad Southern accent in the history of film. Right then I knew I was heading for comedy genius. Not since Peter Sellers turned the French accent inside out as Inspector Clouseau has an actor gotten so many laughs out of simple mis-pro-nun-cia-tion. But it doesn't stop with Brad's crucifixion of redneck culture. The moment David Duchovny makes the scene, the John Lennon of Sucky Acting has found his Paul McCartney. The chemistry between the rip-roaring redneck and the geeky nerd with the tape recorder is so amazing -- two forms of bad acting, (macho shouting versus wimpy whining) but blended together with total harmony. The girls in this movie are actually somewhat better than the boys, though that's not saying much. Michelle Forbes, who went on years later to be a standout presence in the HBO series TRUE BLOOD, is at this point totally charisma free, but at least she's inoffensive. What little acting this movie has all comes from Juliette Lewis, who somehow turns the shallowest and most insultingly stereotypical character (the helpless child-woman, the white trash victim) into a completely sympathetic and believable human being. If you want to read a really good book that tells the same story, (wimpy elitist kidnapped/liberated by white trash killer) read DIRTY WHITE BOYS by Stephen Hunter. KALIFORNIA is a terrible movie, but Brad Pitt would have made an awesome Lamar Pye. And David Duchovny would have been a natural as wimpy little Richard Peed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Kalifornia Exhibits Brad Pitt's Acting Talent
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This debut feature film from music video director Dominic Sena is a romp through the world of serial killing, which in its bleakness and moral bankruptcy looks backwards to Terrence Malick's Badlands and forward to Oliver Stone's Natural Born Killers. Kalifornia is a thriller/road film, directed by Sena, features Brad Pitt, Juliette Lewis, David Duchovny, and Michelle Forbes. The story focuses on an aspiring writer and his photographer girlfriend who are traveling cross-country to research serial killers. To help pay for gas, they take along a man and his childlike girlfriend,unaware that the man is a killer himself. Brian Kessler is a graduate student in Psychology and a journalist authoring a book about serial killers. His photographer girlfriend Carrie Laughlin persuades him to move to California; and, when his book project is accepted by a publisher, they decide to drive from Pittsburgh to California and visit infamous murder sites along the way. Short on funds, Brian posts a ride-share ad. Meanwhile, parolee Early Grayce has just lost his job. His Parole Officer learns of this and comes to the trailer park where Early lives with his young girlfriend Adele Corners. Early refuses the officer's offer of a job as a college janitor, saying he wants to leave the state. The officer informs him that, if he doesn't keep the appointment, he will be returned to prison. Early decides to go to the job interview; and, when he's on his way out, he is confronted by the landlord over non-payment of rent. Early grows violent and spins out in his car, chasing the man all over the park. On the road, unknown to his companions, Early murders a man in a gas station bathroom and steals his money. When they arrive at the first hotel, he cuts Adele's hair to match Carrie's. At another hotel, Early invites Brian out to play pool, leaving Adele and Carrie alone together. Adele reveals to Carrie that she is a rape victim and that she views Early as her protector, even though her mother didn't approve because Early had just been released from prison. Carrie is alarmed by Brian's growing fascination with Early and nonchalant response to the news that Early has been in prison. She gives him an ultimatumeither they rid themselves of Early and Adele or she will leave. At the next gas station, Carrie glimpses a newscast with footage of Early and the announcement he is a suspected murderer. Early kills the gas-station attendant and continues the trip with the couple as hostages. They encounter two police officers, whom Early shoots. Early orders Brian to finish off one of the wounded officers, but Brian refuses. They next come to the home of an elderly couple. Early beats the man to death, but Adele allows the woman to flee. As Early rushes to find the woman, Adele confronts him and says she wants nothing more to do with him. Early shoots Adele, strikes Brian on the head, and kidnaps Carrie. Brian regains consciousness, and the elderly woman gives him the keys to her truck. Brian arrives at an abandoned nuclear testing site and surprises Early, hitting him in the head with a shovel. Brian finds Carrie bloodied and handcuffed to a bed. Early, who was only stunned, attacks Brian and they struggle until Carrie hits Early in the head. When Early continues the attack, Brian shoots him dead.The movie ends with Brian and Carrie in a California beach house. It is an absolutely riveting movie that is visually stylish and thematically creepy. The movie begins extremely well before escalating into the inevitable confrontation, when the sensitive-intellectual man discovers that when push comes to shove, we're all brutes and animals.Brad Pitt's performance is excellent and crucial, and he rips into the character with a frightening sense of unhinged egomania, violently subverting the pretty-boy image with which so many wanted to associate him.This definitely made the viewer realize that he indeed is more than a pretty face but a talented actor as well.Watch it for his performance alone.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nice showcase for Pitt.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Scott LeBrun (Hey_Sweden)
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What goes on in the mind of a serial killer? What is it, really, that separates "us" from "them"? More importantly, what is with the fascination that so many of us have for true crime stories and deviant individuals? What does it take to change a persons' opinion on the subject? These are questions that this grim, stylish, intelligent drama asks as it plays out. It offers interesting roles to a talented quartet of performers, and is very straightforward with the way it portrays acts of violence. David Duchovny plays Brian Kessler, a writer with a fixation on serial killers who's gotten an advance to write a book about them. With his photographer girlfriend Carrie Laughlin (Michelle Forbes) in tow, he embarks on a road trip of research as he travels across America to visit the sites of various crimes. The two of them get closer to their subject matter than they could have imagined when they hook up with dirt poor trailer trash couple Early Grayce (Brad Pitt) and Adele Corners (Juliette Lewis). Early, you see, is a vicious sociopath who does some awful things without feeling any remorse about them. One major theme of the film is the evolution of the Brian character. He starts out as pretty liberal when it comes to the serial killer topic and is forced to realize the fact that - as he says near the end - that any one of us *is* capable of taking another humans' life if properly motivated. There's not really that much separation, after all. "Kalifornia" is one of those films that works on both the intellectually stimulating and visceral levels. It's fascinating to watch, even as it deliberately paces itself for close to two hours. Pitt is excellent, truly disappearing inside his role and enjoying playing the different aspects to this killer. Lewis is fine as a sweet, simple girl; this part of hers is intriguing when you contrast it to the one she plays in the next years' "Natural Born Killers". Duchovny and Forbes are believable as they do the bulk of the reacting in this film. Hailed by some as a serial killer story for the thinking person, this is a ride well worth taking. Eight out of 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brad Pitt is Simply Outstanding
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is the first movie that I have seen that Erbert has given four stars. He raves about how well this movie was made and how realistic the characters are. I wouldn't give it a score that high, but I do agree that the characters in this movie are really well done. Atlantic Video (my video store, excellent place for cheap videos, and they have a huge selection) labels this as an action, and others say that it is a thriller. I would consider this movie to be a psychological examination of people. It exposes us to the harsh reality of life and is far for falling into the category of mainstream Hollywood. I first heard of this movie when it was advertised in the Mercury Cinema, the old alternative cinema in Adelaide. My gripe is the character of Brian Kessler (David Duchovney). There is nothing wrong with the character itself, but it reminded me a lot of agent Mulder. The twist between Kessler and Mulder is that Kessler considers himself a psychologist but he is not. His ambition is to write a book on serial killers and why the do what they do. Kessler knows that he cannot learn about serial killers by sitting in a library so he decides to go to California with his girlfriend, Carrie Laughlin (Michelle Forbes) and on the way there visit the sights of famous serial killers to try and uncover why serial killers do what they do. Kessler realises at the end of the movie that he has absolutely no idea as to why they do what they do. After his experience with Early he realises that some people do things because they want to. This brings us to Early (Brad Pitt). Brad Pitt's portrayal of Early is brilliant. Upon seeing this one comes to the conclusion that Brad Pitt does know how to act. Beyond this is the character of Early. Kessler does not understand why Early is the way he is but it seems to me that Early just does not perceive anything beyond his own experience. He does not see that there are repercussions for his actions. Erbert says that Early is intelligent, but I disagree. Early does things on the spur of the moment and never plans his actions. He needs money so he kills a man with lots of money. He just doesn't care that he just killed somebody, and this comes from a man who has probably done it a lot before. Adele Corners (Juliette Lewis) is a very well developed character. She is a character that lives in a dream world and believes everything that is told her. She is a child that was thrust into adulthood quite violently. She does not want to grow up so she remains a child at heart. She has a preconceived idea about who Early is and she does not want to believe that he is anything else, even if she is confronted by it. Kalifornia is a movie about reality. It is two couples from different backgrounds who have come together and are influenced by each other. Brian slowly becomes influenced by Early while Adele becomes influenced by Carrie. We notice something when Adele enters the restaurant with her hair cut, and slowly she becomes to look more like Carrie. The only differences are the clothes. Carrie dresses very dark and wears trousers while Adele wear scanty dresses. This is a movie about the way people behave and how some people are just evil.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good psychological thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Wuchak
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Kalifornia" went unnoticed at the box office in 1993, but it's a quality psychological thriller starring David Duchovny and Michelle Forbes as a writer & photographer team who travel to California from Georgia, documenting a book on serial killers along the way. To help with expenses, they take on two have-nots as passengers, played by Brad Pitt and Juliette Lewis. Unfortunately, Pitt's character may be a sinister killer behind his "good ol' boy" mask. The film's presumably spelled "Kalifornia" because Kali is the Hindu goddess of death, which is a creative touch. In any event, this is an effective psychological road movie, shot in Georgia, Illinois and California. Brad Pitt really shows off his acting skills in this one because he is completely convincing as a backcountry psychopath (just as he's convincing as the noble Achilles in "Troy"). Lewis is also effective as his naive and childish girlfriend. As the trip progresses Duchovny's character becomes increasingly intrigued by Pitt's animalistic power while Forbes grows concerned of his dangerous potential. The film's also an interesting look at the differences between the middle class and the poor, the educated and the ignorant. There's not much else to say. If you're in the mood for a serious road flick that examines the nature of the killer instinct and more, be sure to check out "Kalifornia." The film goes on a bit too long at 118 minutes but, other than that, I can't think of anything bad to say. GRADE: B
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stylish, Violent & Fast Moving
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    seymourblack-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Kalifornia" is a violent road movie that features two couples who, for different reasons, want to move to California to make a fresh start. The couples come from different social classes and are worlds apart in terms of education and sophistication. These differences and other tensions that exist between them as individuals, create a consistently strained atmosphere which becomes even more intense as they gradually start to learn more about each other. Brian Kessler (David Duchovny) is a psychology graduate who, having written a well-received magazine article about serial killers is given an advance to write a book on the subject. His girlfriend Carrie Laughlin (Michelle Forbes), who's an aspiring photographer, wants to move to California and so they plan to use their cross-country trip to visit famous murder sites to gather material for Brian's book. As they don't have sufficient funds to pay for their trip, Brian places an advertisement on the bulletin board of the local University for anyone who'd like to make the same journey and share the costs. Brian's ad is answered by Early Grayce (Brad Pitt), an unemployed ex-con who's just killed his landlord because he was demanding payment of rent money that was owed to him. When Brian and Michelle go to pick up Early and his girlfriend Adele (Juliette Lewis), Michelle's first impulse is to pull out of the agreement as Early and Adele look impoverished and common. Brian, however, is anxious to get on with the trip and persuades Michelle to put her concerns to one side. Brian is a man who likes to think the best of everyone and believes that murderers are victims of their backgrounds which have effectively made them into killers. He's absolutely fascinated by murderers and enjoys studying their motivations. During the journey to California, he slowly starts to become aware of the real nature of his travelling companions and things turn extremely violent and scary before he discovers why he has such an intense interest in killing and also has to re-think some of his long-held views. Brad Pitt puts an incredible amount of energy and drive into his role as the embodiment of pure evil and is completely convincing as a psychopath who simply does whatever his instincts dictate. Michelle Forbes does a great deal of frowning and scowling as the cold, pretentious Carrie who's a voyeur and can't help being fascinated by things that she also finds repulsive. She's hard and cynical and even her hairstyle is severe! David Duchovny is good as the naive and gullible Brian who learns more about his specialist subject than he could ever have imagined and Juliette Lewis is amazing as the tragic, undereducated young woman with a traumatic background which has left her so damaged that she sees the manipulative Early as being a well-meaning man who's dedicated to protecting her. "Kalifornia" is stylishly made, fast moving and beautifully photographed but certain passages are also uncomfortable to watch. Its real strength lies in its characters who make it compelling from start to finish.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Worth a watch just for Pitt's performance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ForVirg
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Kalifornia would be just an OK movie, were it not for the performance of pretty-boy Brad Pitt. In this film, he is anything BUT pretty. In fact, he's so convincingly creepy, it makes my skin crawl just to think about this role. Whether or not he took on the role to battle type-casting is unimportant, because he does, in fact, show his acting chops amazingly well as the poor white trash monster. It's rare to see any actor take on the persona of a character so convincingly. The idea of this film is a good one, and executed fairly well, but could have been done better. In particular, Michelle Forbes character, Carrie, is extremely grating. Hers is a character who will fit into L.A. culture very well--bitchy, superior, and judgmental. I know I should sympathize with Carrie's correct assessment of the situation, but I just hate her too much to care. Of course, I could argue that without her bitchy superiority, there wouldn't be a story. On the other hand, Juliette Lewis' character, Adele, is charmingly endearing, and I found myself wishing for Adele and Duchovny's Brian to wind up together. Were it not for the cast, this movie would be unremarkable. But with the performance of the cast, I find myself watching it again and again over the years since its release. That must count for something!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brad gets his kicks on Route 66.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BA_Harrison
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Why the K? I don't know, but then I don't really understand who the intended audience for this film is either. It's not extreme enough to appease fans of disturbing cinema, not cerebral or cool enough for art-house types, nor is it mainstream enough to appeal to the general public; it's there, treading a fine line between all threefrustrating, because Kalifornia has plenty of potential, and if director Dominic Sena had just chosen one definitive route to take, the film might have been a great addition to the serial killer genre instead of an average one. The plot explores several fascinating themesclass divide, the allure of danger and violence, psychotic behaviour and the complexities of the brainbut Sena's indecisive approach means that he only lightly addresses each issue, and often in a trite and predictable manner. A dreary narration from David Duchovny's obnoxious yuppie is intended to make events seem more profound, but only serves to make the film seem highly pretentious. Sena's glossy visuals give an 80s music video vibe (not that surprising given his previous work with Janet Jackson) which seriously jars with the content. Brad Pitt and Juliette Lewis' memorable performances ensure that the film isn't a total waste of time, both actors taking 'poor white trash' to a whole new (and sometimes hilarious) level, and there are one or two effectively shocking outbursts of violence, but this is an ultimately empty experience that says much less about its subject matter than it would have you believe.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dark
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Brad Pitt at his most evil. He is Early, an amoral human being who will destroy anyone for any reason whatsoever. Juliette Lewis is Adele, his companion in their world of woe. Early answers an ad to share a car ride with a journalist, Brian(David Duchovny) who has written a book about serial killers and is traveling to various sites of notorious crimes with his girlfriend,Carrie(Michelle Forbes), a photographer. The law abiding couple have no idea that their driving mates are completely insane. Even before the road trip Early had killed his landlord over a rent dispute and then did away with a gas station attendant during a robbery with his passengers unaware of the events. At one of the stops along the way, Carrie watches a television report about Early as a murder suspect. She and Brian become hostages and witness further mayhem, including a home invasion and police shooting. The four eventually have a violent last stand and the payoff is o.k. as far films of this genre go.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Killer movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Maniac-9
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Interesting movie about a pair of people investigating serial killers but unbeknowest to them they're travelling with their very own serial killer. Brad Pitt totally pulls off the psycho redneck killer persona with Juliette Lewis as his white trash girlfriend and David Duchovny and Michelle Forbes as a pair of yuppies. The movie is definitely a departure for Pitt on his normal leading man roles where he totally transforms himself into a character that is very unBrad Pitt like. The movie is more then just your average serial killer movie with a mix of black comedy and satire. Movie while being a movie about serial killers also has a bit of road trip aspect to it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Terrible And Ugly, Yet For Pure Comedy It Has It's Moments
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dan1863Sickles
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    KALIFORNIA is a movie I wanted to see ever since it first came out. Back in 1993 Brad Pitt and Juliette Lewis were a couple. Both were hot, rising young stars with a hip, punk-rock image. I always assumed this movie would be some sort of cool kids on the run epic, a killing spree set to a great alternative rock sound track, sort of REPO MAN meets POINT BREAK. Alas no, by Jove! Ten minutes in, Brad Pitt walks into a sleazy diner, and shouts, "AW WAWNT A BAOWEL UH CHILLEH," knocking it out of the park with the most uproariously bad Southern accent in the history of film. Right then I knew I was heading for comedy genius. Not since Peter Sellers turned the French accent inside out as Inspector Clouseau has an actor gotten so many laughs out of simple mis-pro-nun-cia-tion. But it doesn't stop with Brad's crucifixion of redneck culture. The moment David Duchovny makes the scene, the John Lennon of Sucky Acting has found his Paul McCartney. The chemistry between the rip-roaring redneck and the geeky nerd with the tape recorder is so amazing -- two forms of bad acting, (macho shouting versus wimpy whining) but blended together with total harmony. The girls in this movie are actually somewhat better than the boys, though that's not saying much. Michelle Forbes, who went on years later to be a standout presence in the HBO series TRUE BLOOD, is at this point totally charisma free, but at least she's inoffensive. What little acting this movie has all comes from Juliette Lewis, who somehow turns the shallowest and most insultingly stereotypical character (the helpless child-woman, the white trash victim) into a completely sympathetic and believable human being. If you want to read a really good book that tells the same story, (wimpy elitist kidnapped/liberated by white trash killer) read DIRTY WHITE BOYS by Stephen Hunter. KALIFORNIA is a terrible movie, but Brad Pitt would have made an awesome Lamar Pye. And David Duchovny would have been a natural as wimpy little Richard Peed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Kalifornia Exhibits Brad Pitt's Acting Talent
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This debut feature film from music video director Dominic Sena is a romp through the world of serial killing, which in its bleakness and moral bankruptcy looks backwards to Terrence Malick's Badlands and forward to Oliver Stone's Natural Born Killers. Kalifornia is a thriller/road film, directed by Sena, features Brad Pitt, Juliette Lewis, David Duchovny, and Michelle Forbes. The story focuses on an aspiring writer and his photographer girlfriend who are traveling cross-country to research serial killers. To help pay for gas, they take along a man and his childlike girlfriend,unaware that the man is a killer himself. Brian Kessler is a graduate student in Psychology and a journalist authoring a book about serial killers. His photographer girlfriend Carrie Laughlin persuades him to move to California; and, when his book project is accepted by a publisher, they decide to drive from Pittsburgh to California and visit infamous murder sites along the way. Short on funds, Brian posts a ride-share ad. Meanwhile, parolee Early Grayce has just lost his job. His Parole Officer learns of this and comes to the trailer park where Early lives with his young girlfriend Adele Corners. Early refuses the officer's offer of a job as a college janitor, saying he wants to leave the state. The officer informs him that, if he doesn't keep the appointment, he will be returned to prison. Early decides to go to the job interview; and, when he's on his way out, he is confronted by the landlord over non-payment of rent. Early grows violent and spins out in his car, chasing the man all over the park. On the road, unknown to his companions, Early murders a man in a gas station bathroom and steals his money. When they arrive at the first hotel, he cuts Adele's hair to match Carrie's. At another hotel, Early invites Brian out to play pool, leaving Adele and Carrie alone together. Adele reveals to Carrie that she is a rape victim and that she views Early as her protector, even though her mother didn't approve because Early had just been released from prison. Carrie is alarmed by Brian's growing fascination with Early and nonchalant response to the news that Early has been in prison. She gives him an ultimatumeither they rid themselves of Early and Adele or she will leave. At the next gas station, Carrie glimpses a newscast with footage of Early and the announcement he is a suspected murderer. Early kills the gas-station attendant and continues the trip with the couple as hostages. They encounter two police officers, whom Early shoots. Early orders Brian to finish off one of the wounded officers, but Brian refuses. They next come to the home of an elderly couple. Early beats the man to death, but Adele allows the woman to flee. As Early rushes to find the woman, Adele confronts him and says she wants nothing more to do with him. Early shoots Adele, strikes Brian on the head, and kidnaps Carrie. Brian regains consciousness, and the elderly woman gives him the keys to her truck. Brian arrives at an abandoned nuclear testing site and surprises Early, hitting him in the head with a shovel. Brian finds Carrie bloodied and handcuffed to a bed. Early, who was only stunned, attacks Brian and they struggle until Carrie hits Early in the head. When Early continues the attack, Brian shoots him dead.The movie ends with Brian and Carrie in a California beach house. It is an absolutely riveting movie that is visually stylish and thematically creepy. The movie begins extremely well before escalating into the inevitable confrontation, when the sensitive-intellectual man discovers that when push comes to shove, we're all brutes and animals.Brad Pitt's performance is excellent and crucial, and he rips into the character with a frightening sense of unhinged egomania, violently subverting the pretty-boy image with which so many wanted to associate him.This definitely made the viewer realize that he indeed is more than a pretty face but a talented actor as well.Watch it for his performance alone.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nice showcase for Pitt.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Scott LeBrun (Hey_Sweden)
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What goes on in the mind of a serial killer? What is it, really, that separates "us" from "them"? More importantly, what is with the fascination that so many of us have for true crime stories and deviant individuals? What does it take to change a persons' opinion on the subject? These are questions that this grim, stylish, intelligent drama asks as it plays out. It offers interesting roles to a talented quartet of performers, and is very straightforward with the way it portrays acts of violence. David Duchovny plays Brian Kessler, a writer with a fixation on serial killers who's gotten an advance to write a book about them. With his photographer girlfriend Carrie Laughlin (Michelle Forbes) in tow, he embarks on a road trip of research as he travels across America to visit the sites of various crimes. The two of them get closer to their subject matter than they could have imagined when they hook up with dirt poor trailer trash couple Early Grayce (Brad Pitt) and Adele Corners (Juliette Lewis). Early, you see, is a vicious sociopath who does some awful things without feeling any remorse about them. One major theme of the film is the evolution of the Brian character. He starts out as pretty liberal when it comes to the serial killer topic and is forced to realize the fact that - as he says near the end - that any one of us *is* capable of taking another humans' life if properly motivated. There's not really that much separation, after all. "Kalifornia" is one of those films that works on both the intellectually stimulating and visceral levels. It's fascinating to watch, even as it deliberately paces itself for close to two hours. Pitt is excellent, truly disappearing inside his role and enjoying playing the different aspects to this killer. Lewis is fine as a sweet, simple girl; this part of hers is intriguing when you contrast it to the one she plays in the next years' "Natural Born Killers". Duchovny and Forbes are believable as they do the bulk of the reacting in this film. Hailed by some as a serial killer story for the thinking person, this is a ride well worth taking. Eight out of 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brad Pitt is Simply Outstanding
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is the first movie that I have seen that Erbert has given four stars. He raves about how well this movie was made and how realistic the characters are. I wouldn't give it a score that high, but I do agree that the characters in this movie are really well done. Atlantic Video (my video store, excellent place for cheap videos, and they have a huge selection) labels this as an action, and others say that it is a thriller. I would consider this movie to be a psychological examination of people. It exposes us to the harsh reality of life and is far for falling into the category of mainstream Hollywood. I first heard of this movie when it was advertised in the Mercury Cinema, the old alternative cinema in Adelaide. My gripe is the character of Brian Kessler (David Duchovney). There is nothing wrong with the character itself, but it reminded me a lot of agent Mulder. The twist between Kessler and Mulder is that Kessler considers himself a psychologist but he is not. His ambition is to write a book on serial killers and why the do what they do. Kessler knows that he cannot learn about serial killers by sitting in a library so he decides to go to California with his girlfriend, Carrie Laughlin (Michelle Forbes) and on the way there visit the sights of famous serial killers to try and uncover why serial killers do what they do. Kessler realises at the end of the movie that he has absolutely no idea as to why they do what they do. After his experience with Early he realises that some people do things because they want to. This brings us to Early (Brad Pitt). Brad Pitt's portrayal of Early is brilliant. Upon seeing this one comes to the conclusion that Brad Pitt does know how to act. Beyond this is the character of Early. Kessler does not understand why Early is the way he is but it seems to me that Early just does not perceive anything beyond his own experience. He does not see that there are repercussions for his actions. Erbert says that Early is intelligent, but I disagree. Early does things on the spur of the moment and never plans his actions. He needs money so he kills a man with lots of money. He just doesn't care that he just killed somebody, and this comes from a man who has probably done it a lot before. Adele Corners (Juliette Lewis) is a very well developed character. She is a character that lives in a dream world and believes everything that is told her. She is a child that was thrust into adulthood quite violently. She does not want to grow up so she remains a child at heart. She has a preconceived idea about who Early is and she does not want to believe that he is anything else, even if she is confronted by it. Kalifornia is a movie about reality. It is two couples from different backgrounds who have come together and are influenced by each other. Brian slowly becomes influenced by Early while Adele becomes influenced by Carrie. We notice something when Adele enters the restaurant with her hair cut, and slowly she becomes to look more like Carrie. The only differences are the clothes. Carrie dresses very dark and wears trousers while Adele wear scanty dresses. This is a movie about the way people behave and how some people are just evil.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good psychological thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Wuchak
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Kalifornia" went unnoticed at the box office in 1993, but it's a quality psychological thriller starring David Duchovny and Michelle Forbes as a writer & photographer team who travel to California from Georgia, documenting a book on serial killers along the way. To help with expenses, they take on two have-nots as passengers, played by Brad Pitt and Juliette Lewis. Unfortunately, Pitt's character may be a sinister killer behind his "good ol' boy" mask. The film's presumably spelled "Kalifornia" because Kali is the Hindu goddess of death, which is a creative touch. In any event, this is an effective psychological road movie, shot in Georgia, Illinois and California. Brad Pitt really shows off his acting skills in this one because he is completely convincing as a backcountry psychopath (just as he's convincing as the noble Achilles in "Troy"). Lewis is also effective as his naive and childish girlfriend. As the trip progresses Duchovny's character becomes increasingly intrigued by Pitt's animalistic power while Forbes grows concerned of his dangerous potential. The film's also an interesting look at the differences between the middle class and the poor, the educated and the ignorant. There's not much else to say. If you're in the mood for a serious road flick that examines the nature of the killer instinct and more, be sure to check out "Kalifornia." The film goes on a bit too long at 118 minutes but, other than that, I can't think of anything bad to say. GRADE: B
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stylish, Violent & Fast Moving
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    seymourblack-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Kalifornia" is a violent road movie that features two couples who, for different reasons, want to move to California to make a fresh start. The couples come from different social classes and are worlds apart in terms of education and sophistication. These differences and other tensions that exist between them as individuals, create a consistently strained atmosphere which becomes even more intense as they gradually start to learn more about each other. Brian Kessler (David Duchovny) is a psychology graduate who, having written a well-received magazine article about serial killers is given an advance to write a book on the subject. His girlfriend Carrie Laughlin (Michelle Forbes), who's an aspiring photographer, wants to move to California and so they plan to use their cross-country trip to visit famous murder sites to gather material for Brian's book. As they don't have sufficient funds to pay for their trip, Brian places an advertisement on the bulletin board of the local University for anyone who'd like to make the same journey and share the costs. Brian's ad is answered by Early Grayce (Brad Pitt), an unemployed ex-con who's just killed his landlord because he was demanding payment of rent money that was owed to him. When Brian and Michelle go to pick up Early and his girlfriend Adele (Juliette Lewis), Michelle's first impulse is to pull out of the agreement as Early and Adele look impoverished and common. Brian, however, is anxious to get on with the trip and persuades Michelle to put her concerns to one side. Brian is a man who likes to think the best of everyone and believes that murderers are victims of their backgrounds which have effectively made them into killers. He's absolutely fascinated by murderers and enjoys studying their motivations. During the journey to California, he slowly starts to become aware of the real nature of his travelling companions and things turn extremely violent and scary before he discovers why he has such an intense interest in killing and also has to re-think some of his long-held views. Brad Pitt puts an incredible amount of energy and drive into his role as the embodiment of pure evil and is completely convincing as a psychopath who simply does whatever his instincts dictate. Michelle Forbes does a great deal of frowning and scowling as the cold, pretentious Carrie who's a voyeur and can't help being fascinated by things that she also finds repulsive. She's hard and cynical and even her hairstyle is severe! David Duchovny is good as the naive and gullible Brian who learns more about his specialist subject than he could ever have imagined and Juliette Lewis is amazing as the tragic, undereducated young woman with a traumatic background which has left her so damaged that she sees the manipulative Early as being a well-meaning man who's dedicated to protecting her. "Kalifornia" is stylishly made, fast moving and beautifully photographed but certain passages are also uncomfortable to watch. Its real strength lies in its characters who make it compelling from start to finish.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Worth a watch just for Pitt's performance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ForVirg
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Kalifornia would be just an OK movie, were it not for the performance of pretty-boy Brad Pitt. In this film, he is anything BUT pretty. In fact, he's so convincingly creepy, it makes my skin crawl just to think about this role. Whether or not he took on the role to battle type-casting is unimportant, because he does, in fact, show his acting chops amazingly well as the poor white trash monster. It's rare to see any actor take on the persona of a character so convincingly. The idea of this film is a good one, and executed fairly well, but could have been done better. In particular, Michelle Forbes character, Carrie, is extremely grating. Hers is a character who will fit into L.A. culture very well--bitchy, superior, and judgmental. I know I should sympathize with Carrie's correct assessment of the situation, but I just hate her too much to care. Of course, I could argue that without her bitchy superiority, there wouldn't be a story. On the other hand, Juliette Lewis' character, Adele, is charmingly endearing, and I found myself wishing for Adele and Duchovny's Brian to wind up together. Were it not for the cast, this movie would be unremarkable. But with the performance of the cast, I find myself watching it again and again over the years since its release. That must count for something!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brad gets his kicks on Route 66.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BA_Harrison
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Why the K? I don't know, but then I don't really understand who the intended audience for this film is either. It's not extreme enough to appease fans of disturbing cinema, not cerebral or cool enough for art-house types, nor is it mainstream enough to appeal to the general public; it's there, treading a fine line between all threefrustrating, because Kalifornia has plenty of potential, and if director Dominic Sena had just chosen one definitive route to take, the film might have been a great addition to the serial killer genre instead of an average one. The plot explores several fascinating themesclass divide, the allure of danger and violence, psychotic behaviour and the complexities of the brainbut Sena's indecisive approach means that he only lightly addresses each issue, and often in a trite and predictable manner. A dreary narration from David Duchovny's obnoxious yuppie is intended to make events seem more profound, but only serves to make the film seem highly pretentious. Sena's glossy visuals give an 80s music video vibe (not that surprising given his previous work with Janet Jackson) which seriously jars with the content. Brad Pitt and Juliette Lewis' memorable performances ensure that the film isn't a total waste of time, both actors taking 'poor white trash' to a whole new (and sometimes hilarious) level, and there are one or two effectively shocking outbursts of violence, but this is an ultimately empty experience that says much less about its subject matter than it would have you believe.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dark
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Brad Pitt at his most evil. He is Early, an amoral human being who will destroy anyone for any reason whatsoever. Juliette Lewis is Adele, his companion in their world of woe. Early answers an ad to share a car ride with a journalist, Brian(David Duchovny) who has written a book about serial killers and is traveling to various sites of notorious crimes with his girlfriend,Carrie(Michelle Forbes), a photographer. The law abiding couple have no idea that their driving mates are completely insane. Even before the road trip Early had killed his landlord over a rent dispute and then did away with a gas station attendant during a robbery with his passengers unaware of the events. At one of the stops along the way, Carrie watches a television report about Early as a murder suspect. She and Brian become hostages and witness further mayhem, including a home invasion and police shooting. The four eventually have a violent last stand and the payoff is o.k. as far films of this genre go.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Killer movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Maniac-9
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Interesting movie about a pair of people investigating serial killers but unbeknowest to them they're travelling with their very own serial killer. Brad Pitt totally pulls off the psycho redneck killer persona with Juliette Lewis as his white trash girlfriend and David Duchovny and Michelle Forbes as a pair of yuppies. The movie is definitely a departure for Pitt on his normal leading man roles where he totally transforms himself into a character that is very unBrad Pitt like. The movie is more then just your average serial killer movie with a mix of black comedy and satire. Movie while being a movie about serial killers also has a bit of road trip aspect to it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Terrible And Ugly, Yet For Pure Comedy It Has It's Moments
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dan1863Sickles
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    KALIFORNIA is a movie I wanted to see ever since it first came out. Back in 1993 Brad Pitt and Juliette Lewis were a couple. Both were hot, rising young stars with a hip, punk-rock image. I always assumed this movie would be some sort of cool kids on the run epic, a killing spree set to a great alternative rock sound track, sort of REPO MAN meets POINT BREAK. Alas no, by Jove! Ten minutes in, Brad Pitt walks into a sleazy diner, and shouts, "AW WAWNT A BAOWEL UH CHILLEH," knocking it out of the park with the most uproariously bad Southern accent in the history of film. Right then I knew I was heading for comedy genius. Not since Peter Sellers turned the French accent inside out as Inspector Clouseau has an actor gotten so many laughs out of simple mis-pro-nun-cia-tion. But it doesn't stop with Brad's crucifixion of redneck culture. The moment David Duchovny makes the scene, the John Lennon of Sucky Acting has found his Paul McCartney. The chemistry between the rip-roaring redneck and the geeky nerd with the tape recorder is so amazing -- two forms of bad acting, (macho shouting versus wimpy whining) but blended together with total harmony. The girls in this movie are actually somewhat better than the boys, though that's not saying much. Michelle Forbes, who went on years later to be a standout presence in the HBO series TRUE BLOOD, is at this point totally charisma free, but at least she's inoffensive. What little acting this movie has all comes from Juliette Lewis, who somehow turns the shallowest and most insultingly stereotypical character (the helpless child-woman, the white trash victim) into a completely sympathetic and believable human being. If you want to read a really good book that tells the same story, (wimpy elitist kidnapped/liberated by white trash killer) read DIRTY WHITE BOYS by Stephen Hunter. KALIFORNIA is a terrible movie, but Brad Pitt would have made an awesome Lamar Pye. And David Duchovny would have been a natural as wimpy little Richard Peed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Kalifornia Exhibits Brad Pitt's Acting Talent
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This debut feature film from music video director Dominic Sena is a romp through the world of serial killing, which in its bleakness and moral bankruptcy looks backwards to Terrence Malick's Badlands and forward to Oliver Stone's Natural Born Killers. Kalifornia is a thriller/road film, directed by Sena, features Brad Pitt, Juliette Lewis, David Duchovny, and Michelle Forbes. The story focuses on an aspiring writer and his photographer girlfriend who are traveling cross-country to research serial killers. To help pay for gas, they take along a man and his childlike girlfriend,unaware that the man is a killer himself. Brian Kessler is a graduate student in Psychology and a journalist authoring a book about serial killers. His photographer girlfriend Carrie Laughlin persuades him to move to California; and, when his book project is accepted by a publisher, they decide to drive from Pittsburgh to California and visit infamous murder sites along the way. Short on funds, Brian posts a ride-share ad. Meanwhile, parolee Early Grayce has just lost his job. His Parole Officer learns of this and comes to the trailer park where Early lives with his young girlfriend Adele Corners. Early refuses the officer's offer of a job as a college janitor, saying he wants to leave the state. The officer informs him that, if he doesn't keep the appointment, he will be returned to prison. Early decides to go to the job interview; and, when he's on his way out, he is confronted by the landlord over non-payment of rent. Early grows violent and spins out in his car, chasing the man all over the park. On the road, unknown to his companions, Early murders a man in a gas station bathroom and steals his money. When they arrive at the first hotel, he cuts Adele's hair to match Carrie's. At another hotel, Early invites Brian out to play pool, leaving Adele and Carrie alone together. Adele reveals to Carrie that she is a rape victim and that she views Early as her protector, even though her mother didn't approve because Early had just been released from prison. Carrie is alarmed by Brian's growing fascination with Early and nonchalant response to the news that Early has been in prison. She gives him an ultimatumeither they rid themselves of Early and Adele or she will leave. At the next gas station, Carrie glimpses a newscast with footage of Early and the announcement he is a suspected murderer. Early kills the gas-station attendant and continues the trip with the couple as hostages. They encounter two police officers, whom Early shoots. Early orders Brian to finish off one of the wounded officers, but Brian refuses. They next come to the home of an elderly couple. Early beats the man to death, but Adele allows the woman to flee. As Early rushes to find the woman, Adele confronts him and says she wants nothing more to do with him. Early shoots Adele, strikes Brian on the head, and kidnaps Carrie. Brian regains consciousness, and the elderly woman gives him the keys to her truck. Brian arrives at an abandoned nuclear testing site and surprises Early, hitting him in the head with a shovel. Brian finds Carrie bloodied and handcuffed to a bed. Early, who was only stunned, attacks Brian and they struggle until Carrie hits Early in the head. When Early continues the attack, Brian shoots him dead.The movie ends with Brian and Carrie in a California beach house. It is an absolutely riveting movie that is visually stylish and thematically creepy. The movie begins extremely well before escalating into the inevitable confrontation, when the sensitive-intellectual man discovers that when push comes to shove, we're all brutes and animals.Brad Pitt's performance is excellent and crucial, and he rips into the character with a frightening sense of unhinged egomania, violently subverting the pretty-boy image with which so many wanted to associate him.This definitely made the viewer realize that he indeed is more than a pretty face but a talented actor as well.Watch it for his performance alone.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nice showcase for Pitt.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Scott LeBrun (Hey_Sweden)
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What goes on in the mind of a serial killer? What is it, really, that separates "us" from "them"? More importantly, what is with the fascination that so many of us have for true crime stories and deviant individuals? What does it take to change a persons' opinion on the subject? These are questions that this grim, stylish, intelligent drama asks as it plays out. It offers interesting roles to a talented quartet of performers, and is very straightforward with the way it portrays acts of violence. David Duchovny plays Brian Kessler, a writer with a fixation on serial killers who's gotten an advance to write a book about them. With his photographer girlfriend Carrie Laughlin (Michelle Forbes) in tow, he embarks on a road trip of research as he travels across America to visit the sites of various crimes. The two of them get closer to their subject matter than they could have imagined when they hook up with dirt poor trailer trash couple Early Grayce (Brad Pitt) and Adele Corners (Juliette Lewis). Early, you see, is a vicious sociopath who does some awful things without feeling any remorse about them. One major theme of the film is the evolution of the Brian character. He starts out as pretty liberal when it comes to the serial killer topic and is forced to realize the fact that - as he says near the end - that any one of us *is* capable of taking another humans' life if properly motivated. There's not really that much separation, after all. "Kalifornia" is one of those films that works on both the intellectually stimulating and visceral levels. It's fascinating to watch, even as it deliberately paces itself for close to two hours. Pitt is excellent, truly disappearing inside his role and enjoying playing the different aspects to this killer. Lewis is fine as a sweet, simple girl; this part of hers is intriguing when you contrast it to the one she plays in the next years' "Natural Born Killers". Duchovny and Forbes are believable as they do the bulk of the reacting in this film. Hailed by some as a serial killer story for the thinking person, this is a ride well worth taking. Eight out of 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brad Pitt is Simply Outstanding
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is the first movie that I have seen that Erbert has given four stars. He raves about how well this movie was made and how realistic the characters are. I wouldn't give it a score that high, but I do agree that the characters in this movie are really well done. Atlantic Video (my video store, excellent place for cheap videos, and they have a huge selection) labels this as an action, and others say that it is a thriller. I would consider this movie to be a psychological examination of people. It exposes us to the harsh reality of life and is far for falling into the category of mainstream Hollywood. I first heard of this movie when it was advertised in the Mercury Cinema, the old alternative cinema in Adelaide. My gripe is the character of Brian Kessler (David Duchovney). There is nothing wrong with the character itself, but it reminded me a lot of agent Mulder. The twist between Kessler and Mulder is that Kessler considers himself a psychologist but he is not. His ambition is to write a book on serial killers and why the do what they do. Kessler knows that he cannot learn about serial killers by sitting in a library so he decides to go to California with his girlfriend, Carrie Laughlin (Michelle Forbes) and on the way there visit the sights of famous serial killers to try and uncover why serial killers do what they do. Kessler realises at the end of the movie that he has absolutely no idea as to why they do what they do. After his experience with Early he realises that some people do things because they want to. This brings us to Early (Brad Pitt). Brad Pitt's portrayal of Early is brilliant. Upon seeing this one comes to the conclusion that Brad Pitt does know how to act. Beyond this is the character of Early. Kessler does not understand why Early is the way he is but it seems to me that Early just does not perceive anything beyond his own experience. He does not see that there are repercussions for his actions. Erbert says that Early is intelligent, but I disagree. Early does things on the spur of the moment and never plans his actions. He needs money so he kills a man with lots of money. He just doesn't care that he just killed somebody, and this comes from a man who has probably done it a lot before. Adele Corners (Juliette Lewis) is a very well developed character. She is a character that lives in a dream world and believes everything that is told her. She is a child that was thrust into adulthood quite violently. She does not want to grow up so she remains a child at heart. She has a preconceived idea about who Early is and she does not want to believe that he is anything else, even if she is confronted by it. Kalifornia is a movie about reality. It is two couples from different backgrounds who have come together and are influenced by each other. Brian slowly becomes influenced by Early while Adele becomes influenced by Carrie. We notice something when Adele enters the restaurant with her hair cut, and slowly she becomes to look more like Carrie. The only differences are the clothes. Carrie dresses very dark and wears trousers while Adele wear scanty dresses. This is a movie about the way people behave and how some people are just evil.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good psychological thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Wuchak
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Kalifornia" went unnoticed at the box office in 1993, but it's a quality psychological thriller starring David Duchovny and Michelle Forbes as a writer & photographer team who travel to California from Georgia, documenting a book on serial killers along the way. To help with expenses, they take on two have-nots as passengers, played by Brad Pitt and Juliette Lewis. Unfortunately, Pitt's character may be a sinister killer behind his "good ol' boy" mask. The film's presumably spelled "Kalifornia" because Kali is the Hindu goddess of death, which is a creative touch. In any event, this is an effective psychological road movie, shot in Georgia, Illinois and California. Brad Pitt really shows off his acting skills in this one because he is completely convincing as a backcountry psychopath (just as he's convincing as the noble Achilles in "Troy"). Lewis is also effective as his naive and childish girlfriend. As the trip progresses Duchovny's character becomes increasingly intrigued by Pitt's animalistic power while Forbes grows concerned of his dangerous potential. The film's also an interesting look at the differences between the middle class and the poor, the educated and the ignorant. There's not much else to say. If you're in the mood for a serious road flick that examines the nature of the killer instinct and more, be sure to check out "Kalifornia." The film goes on a bit too long at 118 minutes but, other than that, I can't think of anything bad to say. GRADE: B
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stylish, Violent & Fast Moving
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    seymourblack-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Kalifornia" is a violent road movie that features two couples who, for different reasons, want to move to California to make a fresh start. The couples come from different social classes and are worlds apart in terms of education and sophistication. These differences and other tensions that exist between them as individuals, create a consistently strained atmosphere which becomes even more intense as they gradually start to learn more about each other. Brian Kessler (David Duchovny) is a psychology graduate who, having written a well-received magazine article about serial killers is given an advance to write a book on the subject. His girlfriend Carrie Laughlin (Michelle Forbes), who's an aspiring photographer, wants to move to California and so they plan to use their cross-country trip to visit famous murder sites to gather material for Brian's book. As they don't have sufficient funds to pay for their trip, Brian places an advertisement on the bulletin board of the local University for anyone who'd like to make the same journey and share the costs. Brian's ad is answered by Early Grayce (Brad Pitt), an unemployed ex-con who's just killed his landlord because he was demanding payment of rent money that was owed to him. When Brian and Michelle go to pick up Early and his girlfriend Adele (Juliette Lewis), Michelle's first impulse is to pull out of the agreement as Early and Adele look impoverished and common. Brian, however, is anxious to get on with the trip and persuades Michelle to put her concerns to one side. Brian is a man who likes to think the best of everyone and believes that murderers are victims of their backgrounds which have effectively made them into killers. He's absolutely fascinated by murderers and enjoys studying their motivations. During the journey to California, he slowly starts to become aware of the real nature of his travelling companions and things turn extremely violent and scary before he discovers why he has such an intense interest in killing and also has to re-think some of his long-held views. Brad Pitt puts an incredible amount of energy and drive into his role as the embodiment of pure evil and is completely convincing as a psychopath who simply does whatever his instincts dictate. Michelle Forbes does a great deal of frowning and scowling as the cold, pretentious Carrie who's a voyeur and can't help being fascinated by things that she also finds repulsive. She's hard and cynical and even her hairstyle is severe! David Duchovny is good as the naive and gullible Brian who learns more about his specialist subject than he could ever have imagined and Juliette Lewis is amazing as the tragic, undereducated young woman with a traumatic background which has left her so damaged that she sees the manipulative Early as being a well-meaning man who's dedicated to protecting her. "Kalifornia" is stylishly made, fast moving and beautifully photographed but certain passages are also uncomfortable to watch. Its real strength lies in its characters who make it compelling from start to finish.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Worth a watch just for Pitt's performance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ForVirg
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Kalifornia would be just an OK movie, were it not for the performance of pretty-boy Brad Pitt. In this film, he is anything BUT pretty. In fact, he's so convincingly creepy, it makes my skin crawl just to think about this role. Whether or not he took on the role to battle type-casting is unimportant, because he does, in fact, show his acting chops amazingly well as the poor white trash monster. It's rare to see any actor take on the persona of a character so convincingly. The idea of this film is a good one, and executed fairly well, but could have been done better. In particular, Michelle Forbes character, Carrie, is extremely grating. Hers is a character who will fit into L.A. culture very well--bitchy, superior, and judgmental. I know I should sympathize with Carrie's correct assessment of the situation, but I just hate her too much to care. Of course, I could argue that without her bitchy superiority, there wouldn't be a story. On the other hand, Juliette Lewis' character, Adele, is charmingly endearing, and I found myself wishing for Adele and Duchovny's Brian to wind up together. Were it not for the cast, this movie would be unremarkable. But with the performance of the cast, I find myself watching it again and again over the years since its release. That must count for something!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brad gets his kicks on Route 66.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BA_Harrison
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Why the K? I don't know, but then I don't really understand who the intended audience for this film is either. It's not extreme enough to appease fans of disturbing cinema, not cerebral or cool enough for art-house types, nor is it mainstream enough to appeal to the general public; it's there, treading a fine line between all threefrustrating, because Kalifornia has plenty of potential, and if director Dominic Sena had just chosen one definitive route to take, the film might have been a great addition to the serial killer genre instead of an average one. The plot explores several fascinating themesclass divide, the allure of danger and violence, psychotic behaviour and the complexities of the brainbut Sena's indecisive approach means that he only lightly addresses each issue, and often in a trite and predictable manner. A dreary narration from David Duchovny's obnoxious yuppie is intended to make events seem more profound, but only serves to make the film seem highly pretentious. Sena's glossy visuals give an 80s music video vibe (not that surprising given his previous work with Janet Jackson) which seriously jars with the content. Brad Pitt and Juliette Lewis' memorable performances ensure that the film isn't a total waste of time, both actors taking 'poor white trash' to a whole new (and sometimes hilarious) level, and there are one or two effectively shocking outbursts of violence, but this is an ultimately empty experience that says much less about its subject matter than it would have you believe.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dark
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Brad Pitt at his most evil. He is Early, an amoral human being who will destroy anyone for any reason whatsoever. Juliette Lewis is Adele, his companion in their world of woe. Early answers an ad to share a car ride with a journalist, Brian(David Duchovny) who has written a book about serial killers and is traveling to various sites of notorious crimes with his girlfriend,Carrie(Michelle Forbes), a photographer. The law abiding couple have no idea that their driving mates are completely insane. Even before the road trip Early had killed his landlord over a rent dispute and then did away with a gas station attendant during a robbery with his passengers unaware of the events. At one of the stops along the way, Carrie watches a television report about Early as a murder suspect. She and Brian become hostages and witness further mayhem, including a home invasion and police shooting. The four eventually have a violent last stand and the payoff is o.k. as far films of this genre go.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Killer movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Maniac-9
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Interesting movie about a pair of people investigating serial killers but unbeknowest to them they're travelling with their very own serial killer. Brad Pitt totally pulls off the psycho redneck killer persona with Juliette Lewis as his white trash girlfriend and David Duchovny and Michelle Forbes as a pair of yuppies. The movie is definitely a departure for Pitt on his normal leading man roles where he totally transforms himself into a character that is very unBrad Pitt like. The movie is more then just your average serial killer movie with a mix of black comedy and satire. Movie while being a movie about serial killers also has a bit of road trip aspect to it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Terrible And Ugly, Yet For Pure Comedy It Has It's Moments
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dan1863Sickles
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    KALIFORNIA is a movie I wanted to see ever since it first came out. Back in 1993 Brad Pitt and Juliette Lewis were a couple. Both were hot, rising young stars with a hip, punk-rock image. I always assumed this movie would be some sort of cool kids on the run epic, a killing spree set to a great alternative rock sound track, sort of REPO MAN meets POINT BREAK. Alas no, by Jove! Ten minutes in, Brad Pitt walks into a sleazy diner, and shouts, "AW WAWNT A BAOWEL UH CHILLEH," knocking it out of the park with the most uproariously bad Southern accent in the history of film. Right then I knew I was heading for comedy genius. Not since Peter Sellers turned the French accent inside out as Inspector Clouseau has an actor gotten so many laughs out of simple mis-pro-nun-cia-tion. But it doesn't stop with Brad's crucifixion of redneck culture. The moment David Duchovny makes the scene, the John Lennon of Sucky Acting has found his Paul McCartney. The chemistry between the rip-roaring redneck and the geeky nerd with the tape recorder is so amazing -- two forms of bad acting, (macho shouting versus wimpy whining) but blended together with total harmony. The girls in this movie are actually somewhat better than the boys, though that's not saying much. Michelle Forbes, who went on years later to be a standout presence in the HBO series TRUE BLOOD, is at this point totally charisma free, but at least she's inoffensive. What little acting this movie has all comes from Juliette Lewis, who somehow turns the shallowest and most insultingly stereotypical character (the helpless child-woman, the white trash victim) into a completely sympathetic and believable human being. If you want to read a really good book that tells the same story, (wimpy elitist kidnapped/liberated by white trash killer) read DIRTY WHITE BOYS by Stephen Hunter. KALIFORNIA is a terrible movie, but Brad Pitt would have made an awesome Lamar Pye. And David Duchovny would have been a natural as wimpy little Richard Peed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Kalifornia Exhibits Brad Pitt's Acting Talent
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This debut feature film from music video director Dominic Sena is a romp through the world of serial killing, which in its bleakness and moral bankruptcy looks backwards to Terrence Malick's Badlands and forward to Oliver Stone's Natural Born Killers. Kalifornia is a thriller/road film, directed by Sena, features Brad Pitt, Juliette Lewis, David Duchovny, and Michelle Forbes. The story focuses on an aspiring writer and his photographer girlfriend who are traveling cross-country to research serial killers. To help pay for gas, they take along a man and his childlike girlfriend,unaware that the man is a killer himself. Brian Kessler is a graduate student in Psychology and a journalist authoring a book about serial killers. His photographer girlfriend Carrie Laughlin persuades him to move to California; and, when his book project is accepted by a publisher, they decide to drive from Pittsburgh to California and visit infamous murder sites along the way. Short on funds, Brian posts a ride-share ad. Meanwhile, parolee Early Grayce has just lost his job. His Parole Officer learns of this and comes to the trailer park where Early lives with his young girlfriend Adele Corners. Early refuses the officer's offer of a job as a college janitor, saying he wants to leave the state. The officer informs him that, if he doesn't keep the appointment, he will be returned to prison. Early decides to go to the job interview; and, when he's on his way out, he is confronted by the landlord over non-payment of rent. Early grows violent and spins out in his car, chasing the man all over the park. On the road, unknown to his companions, Early murders a man in a gas station bathroom and steals his money. When they arrive at the first hotel, he cuts Adele's hair to match Carrie's. At another hotel, Early invites Brian out to play pool, leaving Adele and Carrie alone together. Adele reveals to Carrie that she is a rape victim and that she views Early as her protector, even though her mother didn't approve because Early had just been released from prison. Carrie is alarmed by Brian's growing fascination with Early and nonchalant response to the news that Early has been in prison. She gives him an ultimatumeither they rid themselves of Early and Adele or she will leave. At the next gas station, Carrie glimpses a newscast with footage of Early and the announcement he is a suspected murderer. Early kills the gas-station attendant and continues the trip with the couple as hostages. They encounter two police officers, whom Early shoots. Early orders Brian to finish off one of the wounded officers, but Brian refuses. They next come to the home of an elderly couple. Early beats the man to death, but Adele allows the woman to flee. As Early rushes to find the woman, Adele confronts him and says she wants nothing more to do with him. Early shoots Adele, strikes Brian on the head, and kidnaps Carrie. Brian regains consciousness, and the elderly woman gives him the keys to her truck. Brian arrives at an abandoned nuclear testing site and surprises Early, hitting him in the head with a shovel. Brian finds Carrie bloodied and handcuffed to a bed. Early, who was only stunned, attacks Brian and they struggle until Carrie hits Early in the head. When Early continues the attack, Brian shoots him dead.The movie ends with Brian and Carrie in a California beach house. It is an absolutely riveting movie that is visually stylish and thematically creepy. The movie begins extremely well before escalating into the inevitable confrontation, when the sensitive-intellectual man discovers that when push comes to shove, we're all brutes and animals.Brad Pitt's performance is excellent and crucial, and he rips into the character with a frightening sense of unhinged egomania, violently subverting the pretty-boy image with which so many wanted to associate him.This definitely made the viewer realize that he indeed is more than a pretty face but a talented actor as well.Watch it for his performance alone.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nice showcase for Pitt.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Scott LeBrun (Hey_Sweden)
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What goes on in the mind of a serial killer? What is it, really, that separates "us" from "them"? More importantly, what is with the fascination that so many of us have for true crime stories and deviant individuals? What does it take to change a persons' opinion on the subject? These are questions that this grim, stylish, intelligent drama asks as it plays out. It offers interesting roles to a talented quartet of performers, and is very straightforward with the way it portrays acts of violence. David Duchovny plays Brian Kessler, a writer with a fixation on serial killers who's gotten an advance to write a book about them. With his photographer girlfriend Carrie Laughlin (Michelle Forbes) in tow, he embarks on a road trip of research as he travels across America to visit the sites of various crimes. The two of them get closer to their subject matter than they could have imagined when they hook up with dirt poor trailer trash couple Early Grayce (Brad Pitt) and Adele Corners (Juliette Lewis). Early, you see, is a vicious sociopath who does some awful things without feeling any remorse about them. One major theme of the film is the evolution of the Brian character. He starts out as pretty liberal when it comes to the serial killer topic and is forced to realize the fact that - as he says near the end - that any one of us *is* capable of taking another humans' life if properly motivated. There's not really that much separation, after all. "Kalifornia" is one of those films that works on both the intellectually stimulating and visceral levels. It's fascinating to watch, even as it deliberately paces itself for close to two hours. Pitt is excellent, truly disappearing inside his role and enjoying playing the different aspects to this killer. Lewis is fine as a sweet, simple girl; this part of hers is intriguing when you contrast it to the one she plays in the next years' "Natural Born Killers". Duchovny and Forbes are believable as they do the bulk of the reacting in this film. Hailed by some as a serial killer story for the thinking person, this is a ride well worth taking. Eight out of 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brad Pitt is Simply Outstanding
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is the first movie that I have seen that Erbert has given four stars. He raves about how well this movie was made and how realistic the characters are. I wouldn't give it a score that high, but I do agree that the characters in this movie are really well done. Atlantic Video (my video store, excellent place for cheap videos, and they have a huge selection) labels this as an action, and others say that it is a thriller. I would consider this movie to be a psychological examination of people. It exposes us to the harsh reality of life and is far for falling into the category of mainstream Hollywood. I first heard of this movie when it was advertised in the Mercury Cinema, the old alternative cinema in Adelaide. My gripe is the character of Brian Kessler (David Duchovney). There is nothing wrong with the character itself, but it reminded me a lot of agent Mulder. The twist between Kessler and Mulder is that Kessler considers himself a psychologist but he is not. His ambition is to write a book on serial killers and why the do what they do. Kessler knows that he cannot learn about serial killers by sitting in a library so he decides to go to California with his girlfriend, Carrie Laughlin (Michelle Forbes) and on the way there visit the sights of famous serial killers to try and uncover why serial killers do what they do. Kessler realises at the end of the movie that he has absolutely no idea as to why they do what they do. After his experience with Early he realises that some people do things because they want to. This brings us to Early (Brad Pitt). Brad Pitt's portrayal of Early is brilliant. Upon seeing this one comes to the conclusion that Brad Pitt does know how to act. Beyond this is the character of Early. Kessler does not understand why Early is the way he is but it seems to me that Early just does not perceive anything beyond his own experience. He does not see that there are repercussions for his actions. Erbert says that Early is intelligent, but I disagree. Early does things on the spur of the moment and never plans his actions. He needs money so he kills a man with lots of money. He just doesn't care that he just killed somebody, and this comes from a man who has probably done it a lot before. Adele Corners (Juliette Lewis) is a very well developed character. She is a character that lives in a dream world and believes everything that is told her. She is a child that was thrust into adulthood quite violently. She does not want to grow up so she remains a child at heart. She has a preconceived idea about who Early is and she does not want to believe that he is anything else, even if she is confronted by it. Kalifornia is a movie about reality. It is two couples from different backgrounds who have come together and are influenced by each other. Brian slowly becomes influenced by Early while Adele becomes influenced by Carrie. We notice something when Adele enters the restaurant with her hair cut, and slowly she becomes to look more like Carrie. The only differences are the clothes. Carrie dresses very dark and wears trousers while Adele wear scanty dresses. This is a movie about the way people behave and how some people are just evil.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good psychological thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Wuchak
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Kalifornia" went unnoticed at the box office in 1993, but it's a quality psychological thriller starring David Duchovny and Michelle Forbes as a writer & photographer team who travel to California from Georgia, documenting a book on serial killers along the way. To help with expenses, they take on two have-nots as passengers, played by Brad Pitt and Juliette Lewis. Unfortunately, Pitt's character may be a sinister killer behind his "good ol' boy" mask. The film's presumably spelled "Kalifornia" because Kali is the Hindu goddess of death, which is a creative touch. In any event, this is an effective psychological road movie, shot in Georgia, Illinois and California. Brad Pitt really shows off his acting skills in this one because he is completely convincing as a backcountry psychopath (just as he's convincing as the noble Achilles in "Troy"). Lewis is also effective as his naive and childish girlfriend. As the trip progresses Duchovny's character becomes increasingly intrigued by Pitt's animalistic power while Forbes grows concerned of his dangerous potential. The film's also an interesting look at the differences between the middle class and the poor, the educated and the ignorant. There's not much else to say. If you're in the mood for a serious road flick that examines the nature of the killer instinct and more, be sure to check out "Kalifornia." The film goes on a bit too long at 118 minutes but, other than that, I can't think of anything bad to say. GRADE: B
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stylish, Violent & Fast Moving
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    seymourblack-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Kalifornia" is a violent road movie that features two couples who, for different reasons, want to move to California to make a fresh start. The couples come from different social classes and are worlds apart in terms of education and sophistication. These differences and other tensions that exist between them as individuals, create a consistently strained atmosphere which becomes even more intense as they gradually start to learn more about each other. Brian Kessler (David Duchovny) is a psychology graduate who, having written a well-received magazine article about serial killers is given an advance to write a book on the subject. His girlfriend Carrie Laughlin (Michelle Forbes), who's an aspiring photographer, wants to move to California and so they plan to use their cross-country trip to visit famous murder sites to gather material for Brian's book. As they don't have sufficient funds to pay for their trip, Brian places an advertisement on the bulletin board of the local University for anyone who'd like to make the same journey and share the costs. Brian's ad is answered by Early Grayce (Brad Pitt), an unemployed ex-con who's just killed his landlord because he was demanding payment of rent money that was owed to him. When Brian and Michelle go to pick up Early and his girlfriend Adele (Juliette Lewis), Michelle's first impulse is to pull out of the agreement as Early and Adele look impoverished and common. Brian, however, is anxious to get on with the trip and persuades Michelle to put her concerns to one side. Brian is a man who likes to think the best of everyone and believes that murderers are victims of their backgrounds which have effectively made them into killers. He's absolutely fascinated by murderers and enjoys studying their motivations. During the journey to California, he slowly starts to become aware of the real nature of his travelling companions and things turn extremely violent and scary before he discovers why he has such an intense interest in killing and also has to re-think some of his long-held views. Brad Pitt puts an incredible amount of energy and drive into his role as the embodiment of pure evil and is completely convincing as a psychopath who simply does whatever his instincts dictate. Michelle Forbes does a great deal of frowning and scowling as the cold, pretentious Carrie who's a voyeur and can't help being fascinated by things that she also finds repulsive. She's hard and cynical and even her hairstyle is severe! David Duchovny is good as the naive and gullible Brian who learns more about his specialist subject than he could ever have imagined and Juliette Lewis is amazing as the tragic, undereducated young woman with a traumatic background which has left her so damaged that she sees the manipulative Early as being a well-meaning man who's dedicated to protecting her. "Kalifornia" is stylishly made, fast moving and beautifully photographed but certain passages are also uncomfortable to watch. Its real strength lies in its characters who make it compelling from start to finish.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Worth a watch just for Pitt's performance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ForVirg
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Kalifornia would be just an OK movie, were it not for the performance of pretty-boy Brad Pitt. In this film, he is anything BUT pretty. In fact, he's so convincingly creepy, it makes my skin crawl just to think about this role. Whether or not he took on the role to battle type-casting is unimportant, because he does, in fact, show his acting chops amazingly well as the poor white trash monster. It's rare to see any actor take on the persona of a character so convincingly. The idea of this film is a good one, and executed fairly well, but could have been done better. In particular, Michelle Forbes character, Carrie, is extremely grating. Hers is a character who will fit into L.A. culture very well--bitchy, superior, and judgmental. I know I should sympathize with Carrie's correct assessment of the situation, but I just hate her too much to care. Of course, I could argue that without her bitchy superiority, there wouldn't be a story. On the other hand, Juliette Lewis' character, Adele, is charmingly endearing, and I found myself wishing for Adele and Duchovny's Brian to wind up together. Were it not for the cast, this movie would be unremarkable. But with the performance of the cast, I find myself watching it again and again over the years since its release. That must count for something!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brad gets his kicks on Route 66.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BA_Harrison
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Why the K? I don't know, but then I don't really understand who the intended audience for this film is either. It's not extreme enough to appease fans of disturbing cinema, not cerebral or cool enough for art-house types, nor is it mainstream enough to appeal to the general public; it's there, treading a fine line between all threefrustrating, because Kalifornia has plenty of potential, and if director Dominic Sena had just chosen one definitive route to take, the film might have been a great addition to the serial killer genre instead of an average one. The plot explores several fascinating themesclass divide, the allure of danger and violence, psychotic behaviour and the complexities of the brainbut Sena's indecisive approach means that he only lightly addresses each issue, and often in a trite and predictable manner. A dreary narration from David Duchovny's obnoxious yuppie is intended to make events seem more profound, but only serves to make the film seem highly pretentious. Sena's glossy visuals give an 80s music video vibe (not that surprising given his previous work with Janet Jackson) which seriously jars with the content. Brad Pitt and Juliette Lewis' memorable performances ensure that the film isn't a total waste of time, both actors taking 'poor white trash' to a whole new (and sometimes hilarious) level, and there are one or two effectively shocking outbursts of violence, but this is an ultimately empty experience that says much less about its subject matter than it would have you believe.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dark
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Brad Pitt at his most evil. He is Early, an amoral human being who will destroy anyone for any reason whatsoever. Juliette Lewis is Adele, his companion in their world of woe. Early answers an ad to share a car ride with a journalist, Brian(David Duchovny) who has written a book about serial killers and is traveling to various sites of notorious crimes with his girlfriend,Carrie(Michelle Forbes), a photographer. The law abiding couple have no idea that their driving mates are completely insane. Even before the road trip Early had killed his landlord over a rent dispute and then did away with a gas station attendant during a robbery with his passengers unaware of the events. At one of the stops along the way, Carrie watches a television report about Early as a murder suspect. She and Brian become hostages and witness further mayhem, including a home invasion and police shooting. The four eventually have a violent last stand and the payoff is o.k. as far films of this genre go.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Killer movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Maniac-9
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Interesting movie about a pair of people investigating serial killers but unbeknowest to them they're travelling with their very own serial killer. Brad Pitt totally pulls off the psycho redneck killer persona with Juliette Lewis as his white trash girlfriend and David Duchovny and Michelle Forbes as a pair of yuppies. The movie is definitely a departure for Pitt on his normal leading man roles where he totally transforms himself into a character that is very unBrad Pitt like. The movie is more then just your average serial killer movie with a mix of black comedy and satire. Movie while being a movie about serial killers also has a bit of road trip aspect to it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Terrible And Ugly, Yet For Pure Comedy It Has It's Moments
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dan1863Sickles
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    KALIFORNIA is a movie I wanted to see ever since it first came out. Back in 1993 Brad Pitt and Juliette Lewis were a couple. Both were hot, rising young stars with a hip, punk-rock image. I always assumed this movie would be some sort of cool kids on the run epic, a killing spree set to a great alternative rock sound track, sort of REPO MAN meets POINT BREAK. Alas no, by Jove! Ten minutes in, Brad Pitt walks into a sleazy diner, and shouts, "AW WAWNT A BAOWEL UH CHILLEH," knocking it out of the park with the most uproariously bad Southern accent in the history of film. Right then I knew I was heading for comedy genius. Not since Peter Sellers turned the French accent inside out as Inspector Clouseau has an actor gotten so many laughs out of simple mis-pro-nun-cia-tion. But it doesn't stop with Brad's crucifixion of redneck culture. The moment David Duchovny makes the scene, the John Lennon of Sucky Acting has found his Paul McCartney. The chemistry between the rip-roaring redneck and the geeky nerd with the tape recorder is so amazing -- two forms of bad acting, (macho shouting versus wimpy whining) but blended together with total harmony. The girls in this movie are actually somewhat better than the boys, though that's not saying much. Michelle Forbes, who went on years later to be a standout presence in the HBO series TRUE BLOOD, is at this point totally charisma free, but at least she's inoffensive. What little acting this movie has all comes from Juliette Lewis, who somehow turns the shallowest and most insultingly stereotypical character (the helpless child-woman, the white trash victim) into a completely sympathetic and believable human being. If you want to read a really good book that tells the same story, (wimpy elitist kidnapped/liberated by white trash killer) read DIRTY WHITE BOYS by Stephen Hunter. KALIFORNIA is a terrible movie, but Brad Pitt would have made an awesome Lamar Pye. And David Duchovny would have been a natural as wimpy little Richard Peed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Kalifornia Exhibits Brad Pitt's Acting Talent
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This debut feature film from music video director Dominic Sena is a romp through the world of serial killing, which in its bleakness and moral bankruptcy looks backwards to Terrence Malick's Badlands and forward to Oliver Stone's Natural Born Killers. Kalifornia is a thriller/road film, directed by Sena, features Brad Pitt, Juliette Lewis, David Duchovny, and Michelle Forbes. The story focuses on an aspiring writer and his photographer girlfriend who are traveling cross-country to research serial killers. To help pay for gas, they take along a man and his childlike girlfriend,unaware that the man is a killer himself. Brian Kessler is a graduate student in Psychology and a journalist authoring a book about serial killers. His photographer girlfriend Carrie Laughlin persuades him to move to California; and, when his book project is accepted by a publisher, they decide to drive from Pittsburgh to California and visit infamous murder sites along the way. Short on funds, Brian posts a ride-share ad. Meanwhile, parolee Early Grayce has just lost his job. His Parole Officer learns of this and comes to the trailer park where Early lives with his young girlfriend Adele Corners. Early refuses the officer's offer of a job as a college janitor, saying he wants to leave the state. The officer informs him that, if he doesn't keep the appointment, he will be returned to prison. Early decides to go to the job interview; and, when he's on his way out, he is confronted by the landlord over non-payment of rent. Early grows violent and spins out in his car, chasing the man all over the park. On the road, unknown to his companions, Early murders a man in a gas station bathroom and steals his money. When they arrive at the first hotel, he cuts Adele's hair to match Carrie's. At another hotel, Early invites Brian out to play pool, leaving Adele and Carrie alone together. Adele reveals to Carrie that she is a rape victim and that she views Early as her protector, even though her mother didn't approve because Early had just been released from prison. Carrie is alarmed by Brian's growing fascination with Early and nonchalant response to the news that Early has been in prison. She gives him an ultimatumeither they rid themselves of Early and Adele or she will leave. At the next gas station, Carrie glimpses a newscast with footage of Early and the announcement he is a suspected murderer. Early kills the gas-station attendant and continues the trip with the couple as hostages. They encounter two police officers, whom Early shoots. Early orders Brian to finish off one of the wounded officers, but Brian refuses. They next come to the home of an elderly couple. Early beats the man to death, but Adele allows the woman to flee. As Early rushes to find the woman, Adele confronts him and says she wants nothing more to do with him. Early shoots Adele, strikes Brian on the head, and kidnaps Carrie. Brian regains consciousness, and the elderly woman gives him the keys to her truck. Brian arrives at an abandoned nuclear testing site and surprises Early, hitting him in the head with a shovel. Brian finds Carrie bloodied and handcuffed to a bed. Early, who was only stunned, attacks Brian and they struggle until Carrie hits Early in the head. When Early continues the attack, Brian shoots him dead.The movie ends with Brian and Carrie in a California beach house. It is an absolutely riveting movie that is visually stylish and thematically creepy. The movie begins extremely well before escalating into the inevitable confrontation, when the sensitive-intellectual man discovers that when push comes to shove, we're all brutes and animals.Brad Pitt's performance is excellent and crucial, and he rips into the character with a frightening sense of unhinged egomania, violently subverting the pretty-boy image with which so many wanted to associate him.This definitely made the viewer realize that he indeed is more than a pretty face but a talented actor as well.Watch it for his performance alone.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nice showcase for Pitt.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Scott LeBrun (Hey_Sweden)
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What goes on in the mind of a serial killer? What is it, really, that separates "us" from "them"? More importantly, what is with the fascination that so many of us have for true crime stories and deviant individuals? What does it take to change a persons' opinion on the subject? These are questions that this grim, stylish, intelligent drama asks as it plays out. It offers interesting roles to a talented quartet of performers, and is very straightforward with the way it portrays acts of violence. David Duchovny plays Brian Kessler, a writer with a fixation on serial killers who's gotten an advance to write a book about them. With his photographer girlfriend Carrie Laughlin (Michelle Forbes) in tow, he embarks on a road trip of research as he travels across America to visit the sites of various crimes. The two of them get closer to their subject matter than they could have imagined when they hook up with dirt poor trailer trash couple Early Grayce (Brad Pitt) and Adele Corners (Juliette Lewis). Early, you see, is a vicious sociopath who does some awful things without feeling any remorse about them. One major theme of the film is the evolution of the Brian character. He starts out as pretty liberal when it comes to the serial killer topic and is forced to realize the fact that - as he says near the end - that any one of us *is* capable of taking another humans' life if properly motivated. There's not really that much separation, after all. "Kalifornia" is one of those films that works on both the intellectually stimulating and visceral levels. It's fascinating to watch, even as it deliberately paces itself for close to two hours. Pitt is excellent, truly disappearing inside his role and enjoying playing the different aspects to this killer. Lewis is fine as a sweet, simple girl; this part of hers is intriguing when you contrast it to the one she plays in the next years' "Natural Born Killers". Duchovny and Forbes are believable as they do the bulk of the reacting in this film. Hailed by some as a serial killer story for the thinking person, this is a ride well worth taking. Eight out of 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brad Pitt is Simply Outstanding
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is the first movie that I have seen that Erbert has given four stars. He raves about how well this movie was made and how realistic the characters are. I wouldn't give it a score that high, but I do agree that the characters in this movie are really well done. Atlantic Video (my video store, excellent place for cheap videos, and they have a huge selection) labels this as an action, and others say that it is a thriller. I would consider this movie to be a psychological examination of people. It exposes us to the harsh reality of life and is far for falling into the category of mainstream Hollywood. I first heard of this movie when it was advertised in the Mercury Cinema, the old alternative cinema in Adelaide. My gripe is the character of Brian Kessler (David Duchovney). There is nothing wrong with the character itself, but it reminded me a lot of agent Mulder. The twist between Kessler and Mulder is that Kessler considers himself a psychologist but he is not. His ambition is to write a book on serial killers and why the do what they do. Kessler knows that he cannot learn about serial killers by sitting in a library so he decides to go to California with his girlfriend, Carrie Laughlin (Michelle Forbes) and on the way there visit the sights of famous serial killers to try and uncover why serial killers do what they do. Kessler realises at the end of the movie that he has absolutely no idea as to why they do what they do. After his experience with Early he realises that some people do things because they want to. This brings us to Early (Brad Pitt). Brad Pitt's portrayal of Early is brilliant. Upon seeing this one comes to the conclusion that Brad Pitt does know how to act. Beyond this is the character of Early. Kessler does not understand why Early is the way he is but it seems to me that Early just does not perceive anything beyond his own experience. He does not see that there are repercussions for his actions. Erbert says that Early is intelligent, but I disagree. Early does things on the spur of the moment and never plans his actions. He needs money so he kills a man with lots of money. He just doesn't care that he just killed somebody, and this comes from a man who has probably done it a lot before. Adele Corners (Juliette Lewis) is a very well developed character. She is a character that lives in a dream world and believes everything that is told her. She is a child that was thrust into adulthood quite violently. She does not want to grow up so she remains a child at heart. She has a preconceived idea about who Early is and she does not want to believe that he is anything else, even if she is confronted by it. Kalifornia is a movie about reality. It is two couples from different backgrounds who have come together and are influenced by each other. Brian slowly becomes influenced by Early while Adele becomes influenced by Carrie. We notice something when Adele enters the restaurant with her hair cut, and slowly she becomes to look more like Carrie. The only differences are the clothes. Carrie dresses very dark and wears trousers while Adele wear scanty dresses. This is a movie about the way people behave and how some people are just evil.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good psychological thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Wuchak
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Kalifornia" went unnoticed at the box office in 1993, but it's a quality psychological thriller starring David Duchovny and Michelle Forbes as a writer & photographer team who travel to California from Georgia, documenting a book on serial killers along the way. To help with expenses, they take on two have-nots as passengers, played by Brad Pitt and Juliette Lewis. Unfortunately, Pitt's character may be a sinister killer behind his "good ol' boy" mask. The film's presumably spelled "Kalifornia" because Kali is the Hindu goddess of death, which is a creative touch. In any event, this is an effective psychological road movie, shot in Georgia, Illinois and California. Brad Pitt really shows off his acting skills in this one because he is completely convincing as a backcountry psychopath (just as he's convincing as the noble Achilles in "Troy"). Lewis is also effective as his naive and childish girlfriend. As the trip progresses Duchovny's character becomes increasingly intrigued by Pitt's animalistic power while Forbes grows concerned of his dangerous potential. The film's also an interesting look at the differences between the middle class and the poor, the educated and the ignorant. There's not much else to say. If you're in the mood for a serious road flick that examines the nature of the killer instinct and more, be sure to check out "Kalifornia." The film goes on a bit too long at 118 minutes but, other than that, I can't think of anything bad to say. GRADE: B
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stylish, Violent & Fast Moving
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    seymourblack-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Kalifornia" is a violent road movie that features two couples who, for different reasons, want to move to California to make a fresh start. The couples come from different social classes and are worlds apart in terms of education and sophistication. These differences and other tensions that exist between them as individuals, create a consistently strained atmosphere which becomes even more intense as they gradually start to learn more about each other. Brian Kessler (David Duchovny) is a psychology graduate who, having written a well-received magazine article about serial killers is given an advance to write a book on the subject. His girlfriend Carrie Laughlin (Michelle Forbes), who's an aspiring photographer, wants to move to California and so they plan to use their cross-country trip to visit famous murder sites to gather material for Brian's book. As they don't have sufficient funds to pay for their trip, Brian places an advertisement on the bulletin board of the local University for anyone who'd like to make the same journey and share the costs. Brian's ad is answered by Early Grayce (Brad Pitt), an unemployed ex-con who's just killed his landlord because he was demanding payment of rent money that was owed to him. When Brian and Michelle go to pick up Early and his girlfriend Adele (Juliette Lewis), Michelle's first impulse is to pull out of the agreement as Early and Adele look impoverished and common. Brian, however, is anxious to get on with the trip and persuades Michelle to put her concerns to one side. Brian is a man who likes to think the best of everyone and believes that murderers are victims of their backgrounds which have effectively made them into killers. He's absolutely fascinated by murderers and enjoys studying their motivations. During the journey to California, he slowly starts to become aware of the real nature of his travelling companions and things turn extremely violent and scary before he discovers why he has such an intense interest in killing and also has to re-think some of his long-held views. Brad Pitt puts an incredible amount of energy and drive into his role as the embodiment of pure evil and is completely convincing as a psychopath who simply does whatever his instincts dictate. Michelle Forbes does a great deal of frowning and scowling as the cold, pretentious Carrie who's a voyeur and can't help being fascinated by things that she also finds repulsive. She's hard and cynical and even her hairstyle is severe! David Duchovny is good as the naive and gullible Brian who learns more about his specialist subject than he could ever have imagined and Juliette Lewis is amazing as the tragic, undereducated young woman with a traumatic background which has left her so damaged that she sees the manipulative Early as being a well-meaning man who's dedicated to protecting her. "Kalifornia" is stylishly made, fast moving and beautifully photographed but certain passages are also uncomfortable to watch. Its real strength lies in its characters who make it compelling from start to finish.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Worth a watch just for Pitt's performance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ForVirg
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Kalifornia would be just an OK movie, were it not for the performance of pretty-boy Brad Pitt. In this film, he is anything BUT pretty. In fact, he's so convincingly creepy, it makes my skin crawl just to think about this role. Whether or not he took on the role to battle type-casting is unimportant, because he does, in fact, show his acting chops amazingly well as the poor white trash monster. It's rare to see any actor take on the persona of a character so convincingly. The idea of this film is a good one, and executed fairly well, but could have been done better. In particular, Michelle Forbes character, Carrie, is extremely grating. Hers is a character who will fit into L.A. culture very well--bitchy, superior, and judgmental. I know I should sympathize with Carrie's correct assessment of the situation, but I just hate her too much to care. Of course, I could argue that without her bitchy superiority, there wouldn't be a story. On the other hand, Juliette Lewis' character, Adele, is charmingly endearing, and I found myself wishing for Adele and Duchovny's Brian to wind up together. Were it not for the cast, this movie would be unremarkable. But with the performance of the cast, I find myself watching it again and again over the years since its release. That must count for something!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brad gets his kicks on Route 66.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BA_Harrison
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Why the K? I don't know, but then I don't really understand who the intended audience for this film is either. It's not extreme enough to appease fans of disturbing cinema, not cerebral or cool enough for art-house types, nor is it mainstream enough to appeal to the general public; it's there, treading a fine line between all threefrustrating, because Kalifornia has plenty of potential, and if director Dominic Sena had just chosen one definitive route to take, the film might have been a great addition to the serial killer genre instead of an average one. The plot explores several fascinating themesclass divide, the allure of danger and violence, psychotic behaviour and the complexities of the brainbut Sena's indecisive approach means that he only lightly addresses each issue, and often in a trite and predictable manner. A dreary narration from David Duchovny's obnoxious yuppie is intended to make events seem more profound, but only serves to make the film seem highly pretentious. Sena's glossy visuals give an 80s music video vibe (not that surprising given his previous work with Janet Jackson) which seriously jars with the content. Brad Pitt and Juliette Lewis' memorable performances ensure that the film isn't a total waste of time, both actors taking 'poor white trash' to a whole new (and sometimes hilarious) level, and there are one or two effectively shocking outbursts of violence, but this is an ultimately empty experience that says much less about its subject matter than it would have you believe.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dark
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Brad Pitt at his most evil. He is Early, an amoral human being who will destroy anyone for any reason whatsoever. Juliette Lewis is Adele, his companion in their world of woe. Early answers an ad to share a car ride with a journalist, Brian(David Duchovny) who has written a book about serial killers and is traveling to various sites of notorious crimes with his girlfriend,Carrie(Michelle Forbes), a photographer. The law abiding couple have no idea that their driving mates are completely insane. Even before the road trip Early had killed his landlord over a rent dispute and then did away with a gas station attendant during a robbery with his passengers unaware of the events. At one of the stops along the way, Carrie watches a television report about Early as a murder suspect. She and Brian become hostages and witness further mayhem, including a home invasion and police shooting. The four eventually have a violent last stand and the payoff is o.k. as far films of this genre go.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Killer movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Maniac-9
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Interesting movie about a pair of people investigating serial killers but unbeknowest to them they're travelling with their very own serial killer. Brad Pitt totally pulls off the psycho redneck killer persona with Juliette Lewis as his white trash girlfriend and David Duchovny and Michelle Forbes as a pair of yuppies. The movie is definitely a departure for Pitt on his normal leading man roles where he totally transforms himself into a character that is very unBrad Pitt like. The movie is more then just your average serial killer movie with a mix of black comedy and satire. Movie while being a movie about serial killers also has a bit of road trip aspect to it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Terrible And Ugly, Yet For Pure Comedy It Has It's Moments
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dan1863Sickles
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    KALIFORNIA is a movie I wanted to see ever since it first came out. Back in 1993 Brad Pitt and Juliette Lewis were a couple. Both were hot, rising young stars with a hip, punk-rock image. I always assumed this movie would be some sort of cool kids on the run epic, a killing spree set to a great alternative rock sound track, sort of REPO MAN meets POINT BREAK. Alas no, by Jove! Ten minutes in, Brad Pitt walks into a sleazy diner, and shouts, "AW WAWNT A BAOWEL UH CHILLEH," knocking it out of the park with the most uproariously bad Southern accent in the history of film. Right then I knew I was heading for comedy genius. Not since Peter Sellers turned the French accent inside out as Inspector Clouseau has an actor gotten so many laughs out of simple mis-pro-nun-cia-tion. But it doesn't stop with Brad's crucifixion of redneck culture. The moment David Duchovny makes the scene, the John Lennon of Sucky Acting has found his Paul McCartney. The chemistry between the rip-roaring redneck and the geeky nerd with the tape recorder is so amazing -- two forms of bad acting, (macho shouting versus wimpy whining) but blended together with total harmony. The girls in this movie are actually somewhat better than the boys, though that's not saying much. Michelle Forbes, who went on years later to be a standout presence in the HBO series TRUE BLOOD, is at this point totally charisma free, but at least she's inoffensive. What little acting this movie has all comes from Juliette Lewis, who somehow turns the shallowest and most insultingly stereotypical character (the helpless child-woman, the white trash victim) into a completely sympathetic and believable human being. If you want to read a really good book that tells the same story, (wimpy elitist kidnapped/liberated by white trash killer) read DIRTY WHITE BOYS by Stephen Hunter. KALIFORNIA is a terrible movie, but Brad Pitt would have made an awesome Lamar Pye. And David Duchovny would have been a natural as wimpy little Richard Peed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Kalifornia Exhibits Brad Pitt's Acting Talent
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This debut feature film from music video director Dominic Sena is a romp through the world of serial killing, which in its bleakness and moral bankruptcy looks backwards to Terrence Malick's Badlands and forward to Oliver Stone's Natural Born Killers. Kalifornia is a thriller/road film, directed by Sena, features Brad Pitt, Juliette Lewis, David Duchovny, and Michelle Forbes. The story focuses on an aspiring writer and his photographer girlfriend who are traveling cross-country to research serial killers. To help pay for gas, they take along a man and his childlike girlfriend,unaware that the man is a killer himself. Brian Kessler is a graduate student in Psychology and a journalist authoring a book about serial killers. His photographer girlfriend Carrie Laughlin persuades him to move to California; and, when his book project is accepted by a publisher, they decide to drive from Pittsburgh to California and visit infamous murder sites along the way. Short on funds, Brian posts a ride-share ad. Meanwhile, parolee Early Grayce has just lost his job. His Parole Officer learns of this and comes to the trailer park where Early lives with his young girlfriend Adele Corners. Early refuses the officer's offer of a job as a college janitor, saying he wants to leave the state. The officer informs him that, if he doesn't keep the appointment, he will be returned to prison. Early decides to go to the job interview; and, when he's on his way out, he is confronted by the landlord over non-payment of rent. Early grows violent and spins out in his car, chasing the man all over the park. On the road, unknown to his companions, Early murders a man in a gas station bathroom and steals his money. When they arrive at the first hotel, he cuts Adele's hair to match Carrie's. At another hotel, Early invites Brian out to play pool, leaving Adele and Carrie alone together. Adele reveals to Carrie that she is a rape victim and that she views Early as her protector, even though her mother didn't approve because Early had just been released from prison. Carrie is alarmed by Brian's growing fascination with Early and nonchalant response to the news that Early has been in prison. She gives him an ultimatumeither they rid themselves of Early and Adele or she will leave. At the next gas station, Carrie glimpses a newscast with footage of Early and the announcement he is a suspected murderer. Early kills the gas-station attendant and continues the trip with the couple as hostages. They encounter two police officers, whom Early shoots. Early orders Brian to finish off one of the wounded officers, but Brian refuses. They next come to the home of an elderly couple. Early beats the man to death, but Adele allows the woman to flee. As Early rushes to find the woman, Adele confronts him and says she wants nothing more to do with him. Early shoots Adele, strikes Brian on the head, and kidnaps Carrie. Brian regains consciousness, and the elderly woman gives him the keys to her truck. Brian arrives at an abandoned nuclear testing site and surprises Early, hitting him in the head with a shovel. Brian finds Carrie bloodied and handcuffed to a bed. Early, who was only stunned, attacks Brian and they struggle until Carrie hits Early in the head. When Early continues the attack, Brian shoots him dead.The movie ends with Brian and Carrie in a California beach house. It is an absolutely riveting movie that is visually stylish and thematically creepy. The movie begins extremely well before escalating into the inevitable confrontation, when the sensitive-intellectual man discovers that when push comes to shove, we're all brutes and animals.Brad Pitt's performance is excellent and crucial, and he rips into the character with a frightening sense of unhinged egomania, violently subverting the pretty-boy image with which so many wanted to associate him.This definitely made the viewer realize that he indeed is more than a pretty face but a talented actor as well.Watch it for his performance alone.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nice showcase for Pitt.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Scott LeBrun (Hey_Sweden)
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What goes on in the mind of a serial killer? What is it, really, that separates "us" from "them"? More importantly, what is with the fascination that so many of us have for true crime stories and deviant individuals? What does it take to change a persons' opinion on the subject? These are questions that this grim, stylish, intelligent drama asks as it plays out. It offers interesting roles to a talented quartet of performers, and is very straightforward with the way it portrays acts of violence. David Duchovny plays Brian Kessler, a writer with a fixation on serial killers who's gotten an advance to write a book about them. With his photographer girlfriend Carrie Laughlin (Michelle Forbes) in tow, he embarks on a road trip of research as he travels across America to visit the sites of various crimes. The two of them get closer to their subject matter than they could have imagined when they hook up with dirt poor trailer trash couple Early Grayce (Brad Pitt) and Adele Corners (Juliette Lewis). Early, you see, is a vicious sociopath who does some awful things without feeling any remorse about them. One major theme of the film is the evolution of the Brian character. He starts out as pretty liberal when it comes to the serial killer topic and is forced to realize the fact that - as he says near the end - that any one of us *is* capable of taking another humans' life if properly motivated. There's not really that much separation, after all. "Kalifornia" is one of those films that works on both the intellectually stimulating and visceral levels. It's fascinating to watch, even as it deliberately paces itself for close to two hours. Pitt is excellent, truly disappearing inside his role and enjoying playing the different aspects to this killer. Lewis is fine as a sweet, simple girl; this part of hers is intriguing when you contrast it to the one she plays in the next years' "Natural Born Killers". Duchovny and Forbes are believable as they do the bulk of the reacting in this film. Hailed by some as a serial killer story for the thinking person, this is a ride well worth taking. Eight out of 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brad Pitt is Simply Outstanding
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is the first movie that I have seen that Erbert has given four stars. He raves about how well this movie was made and how realistic the characters are. I wouldn't give it a score that high, but I do agree that the characters in this movie are really well done. Atlantic Video (my video store, excellent place for cheap videos, and they have a huge selection) labels this as an action, and others say that it is a thriller. I would consider this movie to be a psychological examination of people. It exposes us to the harsh reality of life and is far for falling into the category of mainstream Hollywood. I first heard of this movie when it was advertised in the Mercury Cinema, the old alternative cinema in Adelaide. My gripe is the character of Brian Kessler (David Duchovney). There is nothing wrong with the character itself, but it reminded me a lot of agent Mulder. The twist between Kessler and Mulder is that Kessler considers himself a psychologist but he is not. His ambition is to write a book on serial killers and why the do what they do. Kessler knows that he cannot learn about serial killers by sitting in a library so he decides to go to California with his girlfriend, Carrie Laughlin (Michelle Forbes) and on the way there visit the sights of famous serial killers to try and uncover why serial killers do what they do. Kessler realises at the end of the movie that he has absolutely no idea as to why they do what they do. After his experience with Early he realises that some people do things because they want to. This brings us to Early (Brad Pitt). Brad Pitt's portrayal of Early is brilliant. Upon seeing this one comes to the conclusion that Brad Pitt does know how to act. Beyond this is the character of Early. Kessler does not understand why Early is the way he is but it seems to me that Early just does not perceive anything beyond his own experience. He does not see that there are repercussions for his actions. Erbert says that Early is intelligent, but I disagree. Early does things on the spur of the moment and never plans his actions. He needs money so he kills a man with lots of money. He just doesn't care that he just killed somebody, and this comes from a man who has probably done it a lot before. Adele Corners (Juliette Lewis) is a very well developed character. She is a character that lives in a dream world and believes everything that is told her. She is a child that was thrust into adulthood quite violently. She does not want to grow up so she remains a child at heart. She has a preconceived idea about who Early is and she does not want to believe that he is anything else, even if she is confronted by it. Kalifornia is a movie about reality. It is two couples from different backgrounds who have come together and are influenced by each other. Brian slowly becomes influenced by Early while Adele becomes influenced by Carrie. We notice something when Adele enters the restaurant with her hair cut, and slowly she becomes to look more like Carrie. The only differences are the clothes. Carrie dresses very dark and wears trousers while Adele wear scanty dresses. This is a movie about the way people behave and how some people are just evil.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good psychological thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Wuchak
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Kalifornia" went unnoticed at the box office in 1993, but it's a quality psychological thriller starring David Duchovny and Michelle Forbes as a writer & photographer team who travel to California from Georgia, documenting a book on serial killers along the way. To help with expenses, they take on two have-nots as passengers, played by Brad Pitt and Juliette Lewis. Unfortunately, Pitt's character may be a sinister killer behind his "good ol' boy" mask. The film's presumably spelled "Kalifornia" because Kali is the Hindu goddess of death, which is a creative touch. In any event, this is an effective psychological road movie, shot in Georgia, Illinois and California. Brad Pitt really shows off his acting skills in this one because he is completely convincing as a backcountry psychopath (just as he's convincing as the noble Achilles in "Troy"). Lewis is also effective as his naive and childish girlfriend. As the trip progresses Duchovny's character becomes increasingly intrigued by Pitt's animalistic power while Forbes grows concerned of his dangerous potential. The film's also an interesting look at the differences between the middle class and the poor, the educated and the ignorant. There's not much else to say. If you're in the mood for a serious road flick that examines the nature of the killer instinct and more, be sure to check out "Kalifornia." The film goes on a bit too long at 118 minutes but, other than that, I can't think of anything bad to say. GRADE: B
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stylish, Violent & Fast Moving
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    seymourblack-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Kalifornia" is a violent road movie that features two couples who, for different reasons, want to move to California to make a fresh start. The couples come from different social classes and are worlds apart in terms of education and sophistication. These differences and other tensions that exist between them as individuals, create a consistently strained atmosphere which becomes even more intense as they gradually start to learn more about each other. Brian Kessler (David Duchovny) is a psychology graduate who, having written a well-received magazine article about serial killers is given an advance to write a book on the subject. His girlfriend Carrie Laughlin (Michelle Forbes), who's an aspiring photographer, wants to move to California and so they plan to use their cross-country trip to visit famous murder sites to gather material for Brian's book. As they don't have sufficient funds to pay for their trip, Brian places an advertisement on the bulletin board of the local University for anyone who'd like to make the same journey and share the costs. Brian's ad is answered by Early Grayce (Brad Pitt), an unemployed ex-con who's just killed his landlord because he was demanding payment of rent money that was owed to him. When Brian and Michelle go to pick up Early and his girlfriend Adele (Juliette Lewis), Michelle's first impulse is to pull out of the agreement as Early and Adele look impoverished and common. Brian, however, is anxious to get on with the trip and persuades Michelle to put her concerns to one side. Brian is a man who likes to think the best of everyone and believes that murderers are victims of their backgrounds which have effectively made them into killers. He's absolutely fascinated by murderers and enjoys studying their motivations. During the journey to California, he slowly starts to become aware of the real nature of his travelling companions and things turn extremely violent and scary before he discovers why he has such an intense interest in killing and also has to re-think some of his long-held views. Brad Pitt puts an incredible amount of energy and drive into his role as the embodiment of pure evil and is completely convincing as a psychopath who simply does whatever his instincts dictate. Michelle Forbes does a great deal of frowning and scowling as the cold, pretentious Carrie who's a voyeur and can't help being fascinated by things that she also finds repulsive. She's hard and cynical and even her hairstyle is severe! David Duchovny is good as the naive and gullible Brian who learns more about his specialist subject than he could ever have imagined and Juliette Lewis is amazing as the tragic, undereducated young woman with a traumatic background which has left her so damaged that she sees the manipulative Early as being a well-meaning man who's dedicated to protecting her. "Kalifornia" is stylishly made, fast moving and beautifully photographed but certain passages are also uncomfortable to watch. Its real strength lies in its characters who make it compelling from start to finish.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Worth a watch just for Pitt's performance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ForVirg
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Kalifornia would be just an OK movie, were it not for the performance of pretty-boy Brad Pitt. In this film, he is anything BUT pretty. In fact, he's so convincingly creepy, it makes my skin crawl just to think about this role. Whether or not he took on the role to battle type-casting is unimportant, because he does, in fact, show his acting chops amazingly well as the poor white trash monster. It's rare to see any actor take on the persona of a character so convincingly. The idea of this film is a good one, and executed fairly well, but could have been done better. In particular, Michelle Forbes character, Carrie, is extremely grating. Hers is a character who will fit into L.A. culture very well--bitchy, superior, and judgmental. I know I should sympathize with Carrie's correct assessment of the situation, but I just hate her too much to care. Of course, I could argue that without her bitchy superiority, there wouldn't be a story. On the other hand, Juliette Lewis' character, Adele, is charmingly endearing, and I found myself wishing for Adele and Duchovny's Brian to wind up together. Were it not for the cast, this movie would be unremarkable. But with the performance of the cast, I find myself watching it again and again over the years since its release. That must count for something!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brad gets his kicks on Route 66.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BA_Harrison
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Why the K? I don't know, but then I don't really understand who the intended audience for this film is either. It's not extreme enough to appease fans of disturbing cinema, not cerebral or cool enough for art-house types, nor is it mainstream enough to appeal to the general public; it's there, treading a fine line between all threefrustrating, because Kalifornia has plenty of potential, and if director Dominic Sena had just chosen one definitive route to take, the film might have been a great addition to the serial killer genre instead of an average one. The plot explores several fascinating themesclass divide, the allure of danger and violence, psychotic behaviour and the complexities of the brainbut Sena's indecisive approach means that he only lightly addresses each issue, and often in a trite and predictable manner. A dreary narration from David Duchovny's obnoxious yuppie is intended to make events seem more profound, but only serves to make the film seem highly pretentious. Sena's glossy visuals give an 80s music video vibe (not that surprising given his previous work with Janet Jackson) which seriously jars with the content. Brad Pitt and Juliette Lewis' memorable performances ensure that the film isn't a total waste of time, both actors taking 'poor white trash' to a whole new (and sometimes hilarious) level, and there are one or two effectively shocking outbursts of violence, but this is an ultimately empty experience that says much less about its subject matter than it would have you believe.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dark
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Brad Pitt at his most evil. He is Early, an amoral human being who will destroy anyone for any reason whatsoever. Juliette Lewis is Adele, his companion in their world of woe. Early answers an ad to share a car ride with a journalist, Brian(David Duchovny) who has written a book about serial killers and is traveling to various sites of notorious crimes with his girlfriend,Carrie(Michelle Forbes), a photographer. The law abiding couple have no idea that their driving mates are completely insane. Even before the road trip Early had killed his landlord over a rent dispute and then did away with a gas station attendant during a robbery with his passengers unaware of the events. At one of the stops along the way, Carrie watches a television report about Early as a murder suspect. She and Brian become hostages and witness further mayhem, including a home invasion and police shooting. The four eventually have a violent last stand and the payoff is o.k. as far films of this genre go.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Killer movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Maniac-9
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Interesting movie about a pair of people investigating serial killers but unbeknowest to them they're travelling with their very own serial killer. Brad Pitt totally pulls off the psycho redneck killer persona with Juliette Lewis as his white trash girlfriend and David Duchovny and Michelle Forbes as a pair of yuppies. The movie is definitely a departure for Pitt on his normal leading man roles where he totally transforms himself into a character that is very unBrad Pitt like. The movie is more then just your average serial killer movie with a mix of black comedy and satire. Movie while being a movie about serial killers also has a bit of road trip aspect to it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Terrible And Ugly, Yet For Pure Comedy It Has It's Moments
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dan1863Sickles
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    KALIFORNIA is a movie I wanted to see ever since it first came out. Back in 1993 Brad Pitt and Juliette Lewis were a couple. Both were hot, rising young stars with a hip, punk-rock image. I always assumed this movie would be some sort of cool kids on the run epic, a killing spree set to a great alternative rock sound track, sort of REPO MAN meets POINT BREAK. Alas no, by Jove! Ten minutes in, Brad Pitt walks into a sleazy diner, and shouts, "AW WAWNT A BAOWEL UH CHILLEH," knocking it out of the park with the most uproariously bad Southern accent in the history of film. Right then I knew I was heading for comedy genius. Not since Peter Sellers turned the French accent inside out as Inspector Clouseau has an actor gotten so many laughs out of simple mis-pro-nun-cia-tion. But it doesn't stop with Brad's crucifixion of redneck culture. The moment David Duchovny makes the scene, the John Lennon of Sucky Acting has found his Paul McCartney. The chemistry between the rip-roaring redneck and the geeky nerd with the tape recorder is so amazing -- two forms of bad acting, (macho shouting versus wimpy whining) but blended together with total harmony. The girls in this movie are actually somewhat better than the boys, though that's not saying much. Michelle Forbes, who went on years later to be a standout presence in the HBO series TRUE BLOOD, is at this point totally charisma free, but at least she's inoffensive. What little acting this movie has all comes from Juliette Lewis, who somehow turns the shallowest and most insultingly stereotypical character (the helpless child-woman, the white trash victim) into a completely sympathetic and believable human being. If you want to read a really good book that tells the same story, (wimpy elitist kidnapped/liberated by white trash killer) read DIRTY WHITE BOYS by Stephen Hunter. KALIFORNIA is a terrible movie, but Brad Pitt would have made an awesome Lamar Pye. And David Duchovny would have been a natural as wimpy little Richard Peed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Kalifornia Exhibits Brad Pitt's Acting Talent
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This debut feature film from music video director Dominic Sena is a romp through the world of serial killing, which in its bleakness and moral bankruptcy looks backwards to Terrence Malick's Badlands and forward to Oliver Stone's Natural Born Killers. Kalifornia is a thriller/road film, directed by Sena, features Brad Pitt, Juliette Lewis, David Duchovny, and Michelle Forbes. The story focuses on an aspiring writer and his photographer girlfriend who are traveling cross-country to research serial killers. To help pay for gas, they take along a man and his childlike girlfriend,unaware that the man is a killer himself. Brian Kessler is a graduate student in Psychology and a journalist authoring a book about serial killers. His photographer girlfriend Carrie Laughlin persuades him to move to California; and, when his book project is accepted by a publisher, they decide to drive from Pittsburgh to California and visit infamous murder sites along the way. Short on funds, Brian posts a ride-share ad. Meanwhile, parolee Early Grayce has just lost his job. His Parole Officer learns of this and comes to the trailer park where Early lives with his young girlfriend Adele Corners. Early refuses the officer's offer of a job as a college janitor, saying he wants to leave the state. The officer informs him that, if he doesn't keep the appointment, he will be returned to prison. Early decides to go to the job interview; and, when he's on his way out, he is confronted by the landlord over non-payment of rent. Early grows violent and spins out in his car, chasing the man all over the park. On the road, unknown to his companions, Early murders a man in a gas station bathroom and steals his money. When they arrive at the first hotel, he cuts Adele's hair to match Carrie's. At another hotel, Early invites Brian out to play pool, leaving Adele and Carrie alone together. Adele reveals to Carrie that she is a rape victim and that she views Early as her protector, even though her mother didn't approve because Early had just been released from prison. Carrie is alarmed by Brian's growing fascination with Early and nonchalant response to the news that Early has been in prison. She gives him an ultimatumeither they rid themselves of Early and Adele or she will leave. At the next gas station, Carrie glimpses a newscast with footage of Early and the announcement he is a suspected murderer. Early kills the gas-station attendant and continues the trip with the couple as hostages. They encounter two police officers, whom Early shoots. Early orders Brian to finish off one of the wounded officers, but Brian refuses. They next come to the home of an elderly couple. Early beats the man to death, but Adele allows the woman to flee. As Early rushes to find the woman, Adele confronts him and says she wants nothing more to do with him. Early shoots Adele, strikes Brian on the head, and kidnaps Carrie. Brian regains consciousness, and the elderly woman gives him the keys to her truck. Brian arrives at an abandoned nuclear testing site and surprises Early, hitting him in the head with a shovel. Brian finds Carrie bloodied and handcuffed to a bed. Early, who was only stunned, attacks Brian and they struggle until Carrie hits Early in the head. When Early continues the attack, Brian shoots him dead.The movie ends with Brian and Carrie in a California beach house. It is an absolutely riveting movie that is visually stylish and thematically creepy. The movie begins extremely well before escalating into the inevitable confrontation, when the sensitive-intellectual man discovers that when push comes to shove, we're all brutes and animals.Brad Pitt's performance is excellent and crucial, and he rips into the character with a frightening sense of unhinged egomania, violently subverting the pretty-boy image with which so many wanted to associate him.This definitely made the viewer realize that he indeed is more than a pretty face but a talented actor as well.Watch it for his performance alone.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nice showcase for Pitt.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Scott LeBrun (Hey_Sweden)
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What goes on in the mind of a serial killer? What is it, really, that separates "us" from "them"? More importantly, what is with the fascination that so many of us have for true crime stories and deviant individuals? What does it take to change a persons' opinion on the subject? These are questions that this grim, stylish, intelligent drama asks as it plays out. It offers interesting roles to a talented quartet of performers, and is very straightforward with the way it portrays acts of violence. David Duchovny plays Brian Kessler, a writer with a fixation on serial killers who's gotten an advance to write a book about them. With his photographer girlfriend Carrie Laughlin (Michelle Forbes) in tow, he embarks on a road trip of research as he travels across America to visit the sites of various crimes. The two of them get closer to their subject matter than they could have imagined when they hook up with dirt poor trailer trash couple Early Grayce (Brad Pitt) and Adele Corners (Juliette Lewis). Early, you see, is a vicious sociopath who does some awful things without feeling any remorse about them. One major theme of the film is the evolution of the Brian character. He starts out as pretty liberal when it comes to the serial killer topic and is forced to realize the fact that - as he says near the end - that any one of us *is* capable of taking another humans' life if properly motivated. There's not really that much separation, after all. "Kalifornia" is one of those films that works on both the intellectually stimulating and visceral levels. It's fascinating to watch, even as it deliberately paces itself for close to two hours. Pitt is excellent, truly disappearing inside his role and enjoying playing the different aspects to this killer. Lewis is fine as a sweet, simple girl; this part of hers is intriguing when you contrast it to the one she plays in the next years' "Natural Born Killers". Duchovny and Forbes are believable as they do the bulk of the reacting in this film. Hailed by some as a serial killer story for the thinking person, this is a ride well worth taking. Eight out of 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brad Pitt is Simply Outstanding
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is the first movie that I have seen that Erbert has given four stars. He raves about how well this movie was made and how realistic the characters are. I wouldn't give it a score that high, but I do agree that the characters in this movie are really well done. Atlantic Video (my video store, excellent place for cheap videos, and they have a huge selection) labels this as an action, and others say that it is a thriller. I would consider this movie to be a psychological examination of people. It exposes us to the harsh reality of life and is far for falling into the category of mainstream Hollywood. I first heard of this movie when it was advertised in the Mercury Cinema, the old alternative cinema in Adelaide. My gripe is the character of Brian Kessler (David Duchovney). There is nothing wrong with the character itself, but it reminded me a lot of agent Mulder. The twist between Kessler and Mulder is that Kessler considers himself a psychologist but he is not. His ambition is to write a book on serial killers and why the do what they do. Kessler knows that he cannot learn about serial killers by sitting in a library so he decides to go to California with his girlfriend, Carrie Laughlin (Michelle Forbes) and on the way there visit the sights of famous serial killers to try and uncover why serial killers do what they do. Kessler realises at the end of the movie that he has absolutely no idea as to why they do what they do. After his experience with Early he realises that some people do things because they want to. This brings us to Early (Brad Pitt). Brad Pitt's portrayal of Early is brilliant. Upon seeing this one comes to the conclusion that Brad Pitt does know how to act. Beyond this is the character of Early. Kessler does not understand why Early is the way he is but it seems to me that Early just does not perceive anything beyond his own experience. He does not see that there are repercussions for his actions. Erbert says that Early is intelligent, but I disagree. Early does things on the spur of the moment and never plans his actions. He needs money so he kills a man with lots of money. He just doesn't care that he just killed somebody, and this comes from a man who has probably done it a lot before. Adele Corners (Juliette Lewis) is a very well developed character. She is a character that lives in a dream world and believes everything that is told her. She is a child that was thrust into adulthood quite violently. She does not want to grow up so she remains a child at heart. She has a preconceived idea about who Early is and she does not want to believe that he is anything else, even if she is confronted by it. Kalifornia is a movie about reality. It is two couples from different backgrounds who have come together and are influenced by each other. Brian slowly becomes influenced by Early while Adele becomes influenced by Carrie. We notice something when Adele enters the restaurant with her hair cut, and slowly she becomes to look more like Carrie. The only differences are the clothes. Carrie dresses very dark and wears trousers while Adele wear scanty dresses. This is a movie about the way people behave and how some people are just evil.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good psychological thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Wuchak
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Kalifornia" went unnoticed at the box office in 1993, but it's a quality psychological thriller starring David Duchovny and Michelle Forbes as a writer & photographer team who travel to California from Georgia, documenting a book on serial killers along the way. To help with expenses, they take on two have-nots as passengers, played by Brad Pitt and Juliette Lewis. Unfortunately, Pitt's character may be a sinister killer behind his "good ol' boy" mask. The film's presumably spelled "Kalifornia" because Kali is the Hindu goddess of death, which is a creative touch. In any event, this is an effective psychological road movie, shot in Georgia, Illinois and California. Brad Pitt really shows off his acting skills in this one because he is completely convincing as a backcountry psychopath (just as he's convincing as the noble Achilles in "Troy"). Lewis is also effective as his naive and childish girlfriend. As the trip progresses Duchovny's character becomes increasingly intrigued by Pitt's animalistic power while Forbes grows concerned of his dangerous potential. The film's also an interesting look at the differences between the middle class and the poor, the educated and the ignorant. There's not much else to say. If you're in the mood for a serious road flick that examines the nature of the killer instinct and more, be sure to check out "Kalifornia." The film goes on a bit too long at 118 minutes but, other than that, I can't think of anything bad to say. GRADE: B
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stylish, Violent & Fast Moving
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    seymourblack-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Kalifornia" is a violent road movie that features two couples who, for different reasons, want to move to California to make a fresh start. The couples come from different social classes and are worlds apart in terms of education and sophistication. These differences and other tensions that exist between them as individuals, create a consistently strained atmosphere which becomes even more intense as they gradually start to learn more about each other. Brian Kessler (David Duchovny) is a psychology graduate who, having written a well-received magazine article about serial killers is given an advance to write a book on the subject. His girlfriend Carrie Laughlin (Michelle Forbes), who's an aspiring photographer, wants to move to California and so they plan to use their cross-country trip to visit famous murder sites to gather material for Brian's book. As they don't have sufficient funds to pay for their trip, Brian places an advertisement on the bulletin board of the local University for anyone who'd like to make the same journey and share the costs. Brian's ad is answered by Early Grayce (Brad Pitt), an unemployed ex-con who's just killed his landlord because he was demanding payment of rent money that was owed to him. When Brian and Michelle go to pick up Early and his girlfriend Adele (Juliette Lewis), Michelle's first impulse is to pull out of the agreement as Early and Adele look impoverished and common. Brian, however, is anxious to get on with the trip and persuades Michelle to put her concerns to one side. Brian is a man who likes to think the best of everyone and believes that murderers are victims of their backgrounds which have effectively made them into killers. He's absolutely fascinated by murderers and enjoys studying their motivations. During the journey to California, he slowly starts to become aware of the real nature of his travelling companions and things turn extremely violent and scary before he discovers why he has such an intense interest in killing and also has to re-think some of his long-held views. Brad Pitt puts an incredible amount of energy and drive into his role as the embodiment of pure evil and is completely convincing as a psychopath who simply does whatever his instincts dictate. Michelle Forbes does a great deal of frowning and scowling as the cold, pretentious Carrie who's a voyeur and can't help being fascinated by things that she also finds repulsive. She's hard and cynical and even her hairstyle is severe! David Duchovny is good as the naive and gullible Brian who learns more about his specialist subject than he could ever have imagined and Juliette Lewis is amazing as the tragic, undereducated young woman with a traumatic background which has left her so damaged that she sees the manipulative Early as being a well-meaning man who's dedicated to protecting her. "Kalifornia" is stylishly made, fast moving and beautifully photographed but certain passages are also uncomfortable to watch. Its real strength lies in its characters who make it compelling from start to finish.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Worth a watch just for Pitt's performance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ForVirg
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Kalifornia would be just an OK movie, were it not for the performance of pretty-boy Brad Pitt. In this film, he is anything BUT pretty. In fact, he's so convincingly creepy, it makes my skin crawl just to think about this role. Whether or not he took on the role to battle type-casting is unimportant, because he does, in fact, show his acting chops amazingly well as the poor white trash monster. It's rare to see any actor take on the persona of a character so convincingly. The idea of this film is a good one, and executed fairly well, but could have been done better. In particular, Michelle Forbes character, Carrie, is extremely grating. Hers is a character who will fit into L.A. culture very well--bitchy, superior, and judgmental. I know I should sympathize with Carrie's correct assessment of the situation, but I just hate her too much to care. Of course, I could argue that without her bitchy superiority, there wouldn't be a story. On the other hand, Juliette Lewis' character, Adele, is charmingly endearing, and I found myself wishing for Adele and Duchovny's Brian to wind up together. Were it not for the cast, this movie would be unremarkable. But with the performance of the cast, I find myself watching it again and again over the years since its release. That must count for something!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brad gets his kicks on Route 66.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BA_Harrison
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Why the K? I don't know, but then I don't really understand who the intended audience for this film is either. It's not extreme enough to appease fans of disturbing cinema, not cerebral or cool enough for art-house types, nor is it mainstream enough to appeal to the general public; it's there, treading a fine line between all threefrustrating, because Kalifornia has plenty of potential, and if director Dominic Sena had just chosen one definitive route to take, the film might have been a great addition to the serial killer genre instead of an average one. The plot explores several fascinating themesclass divide, the allure of danger and violence, psychotic behaviour and the complexities of the brainbut Sena's indecisive approach means that he only lightly addresses each issue, and often in a trite and predictable manner. A dreary narration from David Duchovny's obnoxious yuppie is intended to make events seem more profound, but only serves to make the film seem highly pretentious. Sena's glossy visuals give an 80s music video vibe (not that surprising given his previous work with Janet Jackson) which seriously jars with the content. Brad Pitt and Juliette Lewis' memorable performances ensure that the film isn't a total waste of time, both actors taking 'poor white trash' to a whole new (and sometimes hilarious) level, and there are one or two effectively shocking outbursts of violence, but this is an ultimately empty experience that says much less about its subject matter than it would have you believe.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dark
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Brad Pitt at his most evil. He is Early, an amoral human being who will destroy anyone for any reason whatsoever. Juliette Lewis is Adele, his companion in their world of woe. Early answers an ad to share a car ride with a journalist, Brian(David Duchovny) who has written a book about serial killers and is traveling to various sites of notorious crimes with his girlfriend,Carrie(Michelle Forbes), a photographer. The law abiding couple have no idea that their driving mates are completely insane. Even before the road trip Early had killed his landlord over a rent dispute and then did away with a gas station attendant during a robbery with his passengers unaware of the events. At one of the stops along the way, Carrie watches a television report about Early as a murder suspect. She and Brian become hostages and witness further mayhem, including a home invasion and police shooting. The four eventually have a violent last stand and the payoff is o.k. as far films of this genre go.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Killer movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Maniac-9
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Interesting movie about a pair of people investigating serial killers but unbeknowest to them they're travelling with their very own serial killer. Brad Pitt totally pulls off the psycho redneck killer persona with Juliette Lewis as his white trash girlfriend and David Duchovny and Michelle Forbes as a pair of yuppies. The movie is definitely a departure for Pitt on his normal leading man roles where he totally transforms himself into a character that is very unBrad Pitt like. The movie is more then just your average serial killer movie with a mix of black comedy and satire. Movie while being a movie about serial killers also has a bit of road trip aspect to it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Terrible And Ugly, Yet For Pure Comedy It Has It's Moments
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dan1863Sickles
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    KALIFORNIA is a movie I wanted to see ever since it first came out. Back in 1993 Brad Pitt and Juliette Lewis were a couple. Both were hot, rising young stars with a hip, punk-rock image. I always assumed this movie would be some sort of cool kids on the run epic, a killing spree set to a great alternative rock sound track, sort of REPO MAN meets POINT BREAK. Alas no, by Jove! Ten minutes in, Brad Pitt walks into a sleazy diner, and shouts, "AW WAWNT A BAOWEL UH CHILLEH," knocking it out of the park with the most uproariously bad Southern accent in the history of film. Right then I knew I was heading for comedy genius. Not since Peter Sellers turned the French accent inside out as Inspector Clouseau has an actor gotten so many laughs out of simple mis-pro-nun-cia-tion. But it doesn't stop with Brad's crucifixion of redneck culture. The moment David Duchovny makes the scene, the John Lennon of Sucky Acting has found his Paul McCartney. The chemistry between the rip-roaring redneck and the geeky nerd with the tape recorder is so amazing -- two forms of bad acting, (macho shouting versus wimpy whining) but blended together with total harmony. The girls in this movie are actually somewhat better than the boys, though that's not saying much. Michelle Forbes, who went on years later to be a standout presence in the HBO series TRUE BLOOD, is at this point totally charisma free, but at least she's inoffensive. What little acting this movie has all comes from Juliette Lewis, who somehow turns the shallowest and most insultingly stereotypical character (the helpless child-woman, the white trash victim) into a completely sympathetic and believable human being. If you want to read a really good book that tells the same story, (wimpy elitist kidnapped/liberated by white trash killer) read DIRTY WHITE BOYS by Stephen Hunter. KALIFORNIA is a terrible movie, but Brad Pitt would have made an awesome Lamar Pye. And David Duchovny would have been a natural as wimpy little Richard Peed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Kalifornia Exhibits Brad Pitt's Acting Talent
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This debut feature film from music video director Dominic Sena is a romp through the world of serial killing, which in its bleakness and moral bankruptcy looks backwards to Terrence Malick's Badlands and forward to Oliver Stone's Natural Born Killers. Kalifornia is a thriller/road film, directed by Sena, features Brad Pitt, Juliette Lewis, David Duchovny, and Michelle Forbes. The story focuses on an aspiring writer and his photographer girlfriend who are traveling cross-country to research serial killers. To help pay for gas, they take along a man and his childlike girlfriend,unaware that the man is a killer himself. Brian Kessler is a graduate student in Psychology and a journalist authoring a book about serial killers. His photographer girlfriend Carrie Laughlin persuades him to move to California; and, when his book project is accepted by a publisher, they decide to drive from Pittsburgh to California and visit infamous murder sites along the way. Short on funds, Brian posts a ride-share ad. Meanwhile, parolee Early Grayce has just lost his job. His Parole Officer learns of this and comes to the trailer park where Early lives with his young girlfriend Adele Corners. Early refuses the officer's offer of a job as a college janitor, saying he wants to leave the state. The officer informs him that, if he doesn't keep the appointment, he will be returned to prison. Early decides to go to the job interview; and, when he's on his way out, he is confronted by the landlord over non-payment of rent. Early grows violent and spins out in his car, chasing the man all over the park. On the road, unknown to his companions, Early murders a man in a gas station bathroom and steals his money. When they arrive at the first hotel, he cuts Adele's hair to match Carrie's. At another hotel, Early invites Brian out to play pool, leaving Adele and Carrie alone together. Adele reveals to Carrie that she is a rape victim and that she views Early as her protector, even though her mother didn't approve because Early had just been released from prison. Carrie is alarmed by Brian's growing fascination with Early and nonchalant response to the news that Early has been in prison. She gives him an ultimatumeither they rid themselves of Early and Adele or she will leave. At the next gas station, Carrie glimpses a newscast with footage of Early and the announcement he is a suspected murderer. Early kills the gas-station attendant and continues the trip with the couple as hostages. They encounter two police officers, whom Early shoots. Early orders Brian to finish off one of the wounded officers, but Brian refuses. They next come to the home of an elderly couple. Early beats the man to death, but Adele allows the woman to flee. As Early rushes to find the woman, Adele confronts him and says she wants nothing more to do with him. Early shoots Adele, strikes Brian on the head, and kidnaps Carrie. Brian regains consciousness, and the elderly woman gives him the keys to her truck. Brian arrives at an abandoned nuclear testing site and surprises Early, hitting him in the head with a shovel. Brian finds Carrie bloodied and handcuffed to a bed. Early, who was only stunned, attacks Brian and they struggle until Carrie hits Early in the head. When Early continues the attack, Brian shoots him dead.The movie ends with Brian and Carrie in a California beach house. It is an absolutely riveting movie that is visually stylish and thematically creepy. The movie begins extremely well before escalating into the inevitable confrontation, when the sensitive-intellectual man discovers that when push comes to shove, we're all brutes and animals.Brad Pitt's performance is excellent and crucial, and he rips into the character with a frightening sense of unhinged egomania, violently subverting the pretty-boy image with which so many wanted to associate him.This definitely made the viewer realize that he indeed is more than a pretty face but a talented actor as well.Watch it for his performance alone.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nice showcase for Pitt.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Scott LeBrun (Hey_Sweden)
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What goes on in the mind of a serial killer? What is it, really, that separates "us" from "them"? More importantly, what is with the fascination that so many of us have for true crime stories and deviant individuals? What does it take to change a persons' opinion on the subject? These are questions that this grim, stylish, intelligent drama asks as it plays out. It offers interesting roles to a talented quartet of performers, and is very straightforward with the way it portrays acts of violence. David Duchovny plays Brian Kessler, a writer with a fixation on serial killers who's gotten an advance to write a book about them. With his photographer girlfriend Carrie Laughlin (Michelle Forbes) in tow, he embarks on a road trip of research as he travels across America to visit the sites of various crimes. The two of them get closer to their subject matter than they could have imagined when they hook up with dirt poor trailer trash couple Early Grayce (Brad Pitt) and Adele Corners (Juliette Lewis). Early, you see, is a vicious sociopath who does some awful things without feeling any remorse about them. One major theme of the film is the evolution of the Brian character. He starts out as pretty liberal when it comes to the serial killer topic and is forced to realize the fact that - as he says near the end - that any one of us *is* capable of taking another humans' life if properly motivated. There's not really that much separation, after all. "Kalifornia" is one of those films that works on both the intellectually stimulating and visceral levels. It's fascinating to watch, even as it deliberately paces itself for close to two hours. Pitt is excellent, truly disappearing inside his role and enjoying playing the different aspects to this killer. Lewis is fine as a sweet, simple girl; this part of hers is intriguing when you contrast it to the one she plays in the next years' "Natural Born Killers". Duchovny and Forbes are believable as they do the bulk of the reacting in this film. Hailed by some as a serial killer story for the thinking person, this is a ride well worth taking. Eight out of 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brad Pitt is Simply Outstanding
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is the first movie that I have seen that Erbert has given four stars. He raves about how well this movie was made and how realistic the characters are. I wouldn't give it a score that high, but I do agree that the characters in this movie are really well done. Atlantic Video (my video store, excellent place for cheap videos, and they have a huge selection) labels this as an action, and others say that it is a thriller. I would consider this movie to be a psychological examination of people. It exposes us to the harsh reality of life and is far for falling into the category of mainstream Hollywood. I first heard of this movie when it was advertised in the Mercury Cinema, the old alternative cinema in Adelaide. My gripe is the character of Brian Kessler (David Duchovney). There is nothing wrong with the character itself, but it reminded me a lot of agent Mulder. The twist between Kessler and Mulder is that Kessler considers himself a psychologist but he is not. His ambition is to write a book on serial killers and why the do what they do. Kessler knows that he cannot learn about serial killers by sitting in a library so he decides to go to California with his girlfriend, Carrie Laughlin (Michelle Forbes) and on the way there visit the sights of famous serial killers to try and uncover why serial killers do what they do. Kessler realises at the end of the movie that he has absolutely no idea as to why they do what they do. After his experience with Early he realises that some people do things because they want to. This brings us to Early (Brad Pitt). Brad Pitt's portrayal of Early is brilliant. Upon seeing this one comes to the conclusion that Brad Pitt does know how to act. Beyond this is the character of Early. Kessler does not understand why Early is the way he is but it seems to me that Early just does not perceive anything beyond his own experience. He does not see that there are repercussions for his actions. Erbert says that Early is intelligent, but I disagree. Early does things on the spur of the moment and never plans his actions. He needs money so he kills a man with lots of money. He just doesn't care that he just killed somebody, and this comes from a man who has probably done it a lot before. Adele Corners (Juliette Lewis) is a very well developed character. She is a character that lives in a dream world and believes everything that is told her. She is a child that was thrust into adulthood quite violently. She does not want to grow up so she remains a child at heart. She has a preconceived idea about who Early is and she does not want to believe that he is anything else, even if she is confronted by it. Kalifornia is a movie about reality. It is two couples from different backgrounds who have come together and are influenced by each other. Brian slowly becomes influenced by Early while Adele becomes influenced by Carrie. We notice something when Adele enters the restaurant with her hair cut, and slowly she becomes to look more like Carrie. The only differences are the clothes. Carrie dresses very dark and wears trousers while Adele wear scanty dresses. This is a movie about the way people behave and how some people are just evil.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good psychological thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Wuchak
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Kalifornia" went unnoticed at the box office in 1993, but it's a quality psychological thriller starring David Duchovny and Michelle Forbes as a writer & photographer team who travel to California from Georgia, documenting a book on serial killers along the way. To help with expenses, they take on two have-nots as passengers, played by Brad Pitt and Juliette Lewis. Unfortunately, Pitt's character may be a sinister killer behind his "good ol' boy" mask. The film's presumably spelled "Kalifornia" because Kali is the Hindu goddess of death, which is a creative touch. In any event, this is an effective psychological road movie, shot in Georgia, Illinois and California. Brad Pitt really shows off his acting skills in this one because he is completely convincing as a backcountry psychopath (just as he's convincing as the noble Achilles in "Troy"). Lewis is also effective as his naive and childish girlfriend. As the trip progresses Duchovny's character becomes increasingly intrigued by Pitt's animalistic power while Forbes grows concerned of his dangerous potential. The film's also an interesting look at the differences between the middle class and the poor, the educated and the ignorant. There's not much else to say. If you're in the mood for a serious road flick that examines the nature of the killer instinct and more, be sure to check out "Kalifornia." The film goes on a bit too long at 118 minutes but, other than that, I can't think of anything bad to say. GRADE: B
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stylish, Violent & Fast Moving
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    seymourblack-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Kalifornia" is a violent road movie that features two couples who, for different reasons, want to move to California to make a fresh start. The couples come from different social classes and are worlds apart in terms of education and sophistication. These differences and other tensions that exist between them as individuals, create a consistently strained atmosphere which becomes even more intense as they gradually start to learn more about each other. Brian Kessler (David Duchovny) is a psychology graduate who, having written a well-received magazine article about serial killers is given an advance to write a book on the subject. His girlfriend Carrie Laughlin (Michelle Forbes), who's an aspiring photographer, wants to move to California and so they plan to use their cross-country trip to visit famous murder sites to gather material for Brian's book. As they don't have sufficient funds to pay for their trip, Brian places an advertisement on the bulletin board of the local University for anyone who'd like to make the same journey and share the costs. Brian's ad is answered by Early Grayce (Brad Pitt), an unemployed ex-con who's just killed his landlord because he was demanding payment of rent money that was owed to him. When Brian and Michelle go to pick up Early and his girlfriend Adele (Juliette Lewis), Michelle's first impulse is to pull out of the agreement as Early and Adele look impoverished and common. Brian, however, is anxious to get on with the trip and persuades Michelle to put her concerns to one side. Brian is a man who likes to think the best of everyone and believes that murderers are victims of their backgrounds which have effectively made them into killers. He's absolutely fascinated by murderers and enjoys studying their motivations. During the journey to California, he slowly starts to become aware of the real nature of his travelling companions and things turn extremely violent and scary before he discovers why he has such an intense interest in killing and also has to re-think some of his long-held views. Brad Pitt puts an incredible amount of energy and drive into his role as the embodiment of pure evil and is completely convincing as a psychopath who simply does whatever his instincts dictate. Michelle Forbes does a great deal of frowning and scowling as the cold, pretentious Carrie who's a voyeur and can't help being fascinated by things that she also finds repulsive. She's hard and cynical and even her hairstyle is severe! David Duchovny is good as the naive and gullible Brian who learns more about his specialist subject than he could ever have imagined and Juliette Lewis is amazing as the tragic, undereducated young woman with a traumatic background which has left her so damaged that she sees the manipulative Early as being a well-meaning man who's dedicated to protecting her. "Kalifornia" is stylishly made, fast moving and beautifully photographed but certain passages are also uncomfortable to watch. Its real strength lies in its characters who make it compelling from start to finish.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Worth a watch just for Pitt's performance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ForVirg
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Kalifornia would be just an OK movie, were it not for the performance of pretty-boy Brad Pitt. In this film, he is anything BUT pretty. In fact, he's so convincingly creepy, it makes my skin crawl just to think about this role. Whether or not he took on the role to battle type-casting is unimportant, because he does, in fact, show his acting chops amazingly well as the poor white trash monster. It's rare to see any actor take on the persona of a character so convincingly. The idea of this film is a good one, and executed fairly well, but could have been done better. In particular, Michelle Forbes character, Carrie, is extremely grating. Hers is a character who will fit into L.A. culture very well--bitchy, superior, and judgmental. I know I should sympathize with Carrie's correct assessment of the situation, but I just hate her too much to care. Of course, I could argue that without her bitchy superiority, there wouldn't be a story. On the other hand, Juliette Lewis' character, Adele, is charmingly endearing, and I found myself wishing for Adele and Duchovny's Brian to wind up together. Were it not for the cast, this movie would be unremarkable. But with the performance of the cast, I find myself watching it again and again over the years since its release. That must count for something!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brad gets his kicks on Route 66.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BA_Harrison
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Why the K? I don't know, but then I don't really understand who the intended audience for this film is either. It's not extreme enough to appease fans of disturbing cinema, not cerebral or cool enough for art-house types, nor is it mainstream enough to appeal to the general public; it's there, treading a fine line between all threefrustrating, because Kalifornia has plenty of potential, and if director Dominic Sena had just chosen one definitive route to take, the film might have been a great addition to the serial killer genre instead of an average one. The plot explores several fascinating themesclass divide, the allure of danger and violence, psychotic behaviour and the complexities of the brainbut Sena's indecisive approach means that he only lightly addresses each issue, and often in a trite and predictable manner. A dreary narration from David Duchovny's obnoxious yuppie is intended to make events seem more profound, but only serves to make the film seem highly pretentious. Sena's glossy visuals give an 80s music video vibe (not that surprising given his previous work with Janet Jackson) which seriously jars with the content. Brad Pitt and Juliette Lewis' memorable performances ensure that the film isn't a total waste of time, both actors taking 'poor white trash' to a whole new (and sometimes hilarious) level, and there are one or two effectively shocking outbursts of violence, but this is an ultimately empty experience that says much less about its subject matter than it would have you believe.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dark
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Brad Pitt at his most evil. He is Early, an amoral human being who will destroy anyone for any reason whatsoever. Juliette Lewis is Adele, his companion in their world of woe. Early answers an ad to share a car ride with a journalist, Brian(David Duchovny) who has written a book about serial killers and is traveling to various sites of notorious crimes with his girlfriend,Carrie(Michelle Forbes), a photographer. The law abiding couple have no idea that their driving mates are completely insane. Even before the road trip Early had killed his landlord over a rent dispute and then did away with a gas station attendant during a robbery with his passengers unaware of the events. At one of the stops along the way, Carrie watches a television report about Early as a murder suspect. She and Brian become hostages and witness further mayhem, including a home invasion and police shooting. The four eventually have a violent last stand and the payoff is o.k. as far films of this genre go.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Killer movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Maniac-9
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Interesting movie about a pair of people investigating serial killers but unbeknowest to them they're travelling with their very own serial killer. Brad Pitt totally pulls off the psycho redneck killer persona with Juliette Lewis as his white trash girlfriend and David Duchovny and Michelle Forbes as a pair of yuppies. The movie is definitely a departure for Pitt on his normal leading man roles where he totally transforms himself into a character that is very unBrad Pitt like. The movie is more then just your average serial killer movie with a mix of black comedy and satire. Movie while being a movie about serial killers also has a bit of road trip aspect to it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Terrible And Ugly, Yet For Pure Comedy It Has It's Moments
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dan1863Sickles
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    KALIFORNIA is a movie I wanted to see ever since it first came out. Back in 1993 Brad Pitt and Juliette Lewis were a couple. Both were hot, rising young stars with a hip, punk-rock image. I always assumed this movie would be some sort of cool kids on the run epic, a killing spree set to a great alternative rock sound track, sort of REPO MAN meets POINT BREAK. Alas no, by Jove! Ten minutes in, Brad Pitt walks into a sleazy diner, and shouts, "AW WAWNT A BAOWEL UH CHILLEH," knocking it out of the park with the most uproariously bad Southern accent in the history of film. Right then I knew I was heading for comedy genius. Not since Peter Sellers turned the French accent inside out as Inspector Clouseau has an actor gotten so many laughs out of simple mis-pro-nun-cia-tion. But it doesn't stop with Brad's crucifixion of redneck culture. The moment David Duchovny makes the scene, the John Lennon of Sucky Acting has found his Paul McCartney. The chemistry between the rip-roaring redneck and the geeky nerd with the tape recorder is so amazing -- two forms of bad acting, (macho shouting versus wimpy whining) but blended together with total harmony. The girls in this movie are actually somewhat better than the boys, though that's not saying much. Michelle Forbes, who went on years later to be a standout presence in the HBO series TRUE BLOOD, is at this point totally charisma free, but at least she's inoffensive. What little acting this movie has all comes from Juliette Lewis, who somehow turns the shallowest and most insultingly stereotypical character (the helpless child-woman, the white trash victim) into a completely sympathetic and believable human being. If you want to read a really good book that tells the same story, (wimpy elitist kidnapped/liberated by white trash killer) read DIRTY WHITE BOYS by Stephen Hunter. KALIFORNIA is a terrible movie, but Brad Pitt would have made an awesome Lamar Pye. And David Duchovny would have been a natural as wimpy little Richard Peed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Kalifornia Exhibits Brad Pitt's Acting Talent
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This debut feature film from music video director Dominic Sena is a romp through the world of serial killing, which in its bleakness and moral bankruptcy looks backwards to Terrence Malick's Badlands and forward to Oliver Stone's Natural Born Killers. Kalifornia is a thriller/road film, directed by Sena, features Brad Pitt, Juliette Lewis, David Duchovny, and Michelle Forbes. The story focuses on an aspiring writer and his photographer girlfriend who are traveling cross-country to research serial killers. To help pay for gas, they take along a man and his childlike girlfriend,unaware that the man is a killer himself. Brian Kessler is a graduate student in Psychology and a journalist authoring a book about serial killers. His photographer girlfriend Carrie Laughlin persuades him to move to California; and, when his book project is accepted by a publisher, they decide to drive from Pittsburgh to California and visit infamous murder sites along the way. Short on funds, Brian posts a ride-share ad. Meanwhile, parolee Early Grayce has just lost his job. His Parole Officer learns of this and comes to the trailer park where Early lives with his young girlfriend Adele Corners. Early refuses the officer's offer of a job as a college janitor, saying he wants to leave the state. The officer informs him that, if he doesn't keep the appointment, he will be returned to prison. Early decides to go to the job interview; and, when he's on his way out, he is confronted by the landlord over non-payment of rent. Early grows violent and spins out in his car, chasing the man all over the park. On the road, unknown to his companions, Early murders a man in a gas station bathroom and steals his money. When they arrive at the first hotel, he cuts Adele's hair to match Carrie's. At another hotel, Early invites Brian out to play pool, leaving Adele and Carrie alone together. Adele reveals to Carrie that she is a rape victim and that she views Early as her protector, even though her mother didn't approve because Early had just been released from prison. Carrie is alarmed by Brian's growing fascination with Early and nonchalant response to the news that Early has been in prison. She gives him an ultimatumeither they rid themselves of Early and Adele or she will leave. At the next gas station, Carrie glimpses a newscast with footage of Early and the announcement he is a suspected murderer. Early kills the gas-station attendant and continues the trip with the couple as hostages. They encounter two police officers, whom Early shoots. Early orders Brian to finish off one of the wounded officers, but Brian refuses. They next come to the home of an elderly couple. Early beats the man to death, but Adele allows the woman to flee. As Early rushes to find the woman, Adele confronts him and says she wants nothing more to do with him. Early shoots Adele, strikes Brian on the head, and kidnaps Carrie. Brian regains consciousness, and the elderly woman gives him the keys to her truck. Brian arrives at an abandoned nuclear testing site and surprises Early, hitting him in the head with a shovel. Brian finds Carrie bloodied and handcuffed to a bed. Early, who was only stunned, attacks Brian and they struggle until Carrie hits Early in the head. When Early continues the attack, Brian shoots him dead.The movie ends with Brian and Carrie in a California beach house. It is an absolutely riveting movie that is visually stylish and thematically creepy. The movie begins extremely well before escalating into the inevitable confrontation, when the sensitive-intellectual man discovers that when push comes to shove, we're all brutes and animals.Brad Pitt's performance is excellent and crucial, and he rips into the character with a frightening sense of unhinged egomania, violently subverting the pretty-boy image with which so many wanted to associate him.This definitely made the viewer realize that he indeed is more than a pretty face but a talented actor as well.Watch it for his performance alone.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
