<filme>
 <id>
  588
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0101414
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1991
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  A Bela e a Fera
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  8.0
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Belle, whose father is imprisoned by the Beast, offers herself instead and discovers her captor to be an enchanted prince.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Belle is a girl who is dissatisfied with life in a small provincial French town, constantly trying to fend off the misplaced "affections" of conceited Gaston. The Beast is a prince who was placed under a spell because he could not love. A wrong turn taken by Maurice, Belle's father, causes the two to meet.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Animation
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Family
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Fantasy
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   beast
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   love
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   castle
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   prince
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   village
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Gary Trousdale
  </diretor>
  <diretor>
   Kirk Wise
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Linda Woolverton
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Roger Allers
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Paige O'Hara
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Robby Benson
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Richard White
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gaston is not the villain and Belle's books are important
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    soudkovahana
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of my most beloved Disney movies. I love everything about this movie. Whether it's Belle's opening song, the absence of the villain or Mrs. Potts. Now I know you'll probably tell me that Gaston is the main villain in this story but I don't see him that way. Sure he's pretentious and cocky but that doesn't make him "the villain". Even when he rouse the village to go kill the Beast, yes I know he does it for his own selfish reasons, but he thinks it's just some beast, some animal, and he does not know the true identity of his. I don't want to excuse his actions, he's still very mean and selfish and very much hateful but I just don't see him as the evil villain like Voldemort or Darth Vader. You know what I mean? Anyway the story of the Beauty and the Beast is one of my favorites and it's been remade so many times, in so many versions but the original is only one. There is something about this story that makes me gasp every time I watch it. It's an excellent choice to show your children or grandchildren because it teaches them various of different lessons. Take the main character, Belle, for instance, who likes to read and is called "odd" for that behavior even though she's perfectly normal. You also have here Gaston, who thinks only about himself and who thinks that women should not read or even think. Beast on the other hand is from the very beginning enraptured by Belle's reading and gives her the entire library to read in. I think that Belle's books is an important motive in the movie and should not be alleviated. In other words the story has a lot to tell not only to the children but also to the adults that watch it with them.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The greatest film of the Disney Renaissance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MissSimonetta
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Disney Renaissance (1989-1999) was in many ways the studio's second golden age (the first being from 1937-1942), where experimentation and sublime artistry where the rule rather than the exception. Most of my generation grew up with these movies, so everyone has a favorite. The most popular seems to be The Lion King (1994), but for me the true masterpiece of the era is Beauty and the Beast (1991), arguably the most romantic Disney flick of them all. All the characters are perfect. I think the only cast I like better than this one is from Pinocchio (1940). Belle is an appealing heroine: she has a compassionate and dreamy nature, but she won't let herself be walked over by anyone (notice she doesn't fall for the Beast until he starts acting like a decent person). The Beast has excellent character development, evolving from a selfish brat into a kind, passionate fellow. The enchanted objects are both fun comic relief and interesting characters in their own right. Gaston is one of Disney's best villains, walking the fine line between comic and menacing with ease. BatB boasts the greatest soundtrack of all the Disney canon. Howard Ashman and Alan Mencken outdid themselves here. The choreography is magnificent too, especially the Busby Berkely inspired "Be Our Guest" and the superbly animated "Beauty and the Beast". The incidental music is lush and romantic, a pleasure to listen to in its own right. That's not to say the film doesn't have flaws. The animation on Belle goes off-model at times and the CG in the ballroom sequence is dated. And then there's that plot hole concerning how long Belle was at the castle. None of these issues diminish the greatness of the picture. This is one of the most beautiful and adult love stories ever put put on screen. Absolutely essential.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cookiemonster1234567
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I really like this movie. Its been my favorite movie since I was a little girl. Its a good story about integrity and true character. I mean our world is so messed up these days. Belle didn't care what the beast looked she only cared about his true character which is how all love is supposed to be but sadly its not how life is anymore. Its a beautiful story about what life really should be and what love should really be and mean inside and out. period that's it. People now chose who they 'love' by looks or the way someone is known to be or if that person is a popular person themselves with nobody else's help not one little bit. I really love the movie and I think that you would as well if you watch the movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My favorite
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dannimonai
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I used to watch this movie over and over again when I was little, it was always in the VCR. It was my favorite movie, it still is. I love the music, the animation, the characters and the story line. I identify with Belle the most, I feel as if she and I are one in the same. We love our family and a good book...or two. I have never succumbed to the pressure of society and I always stuck up for myself and others, just like she did. I learned to love people for who they are, not what they look like. This movie always encouraged me to do by best and be the best person I can be. Plus, the library Beast gives her is amazing and I would love it if it were mine!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beauty and the Beast is a 1991 American animated fantasy, romantic, and musical film distributed by Walt Disney Pictures and produced by Walt Disney Feature Animation.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Charith Rajeeva
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Beauty and the Beast Featuring the vocal talents of Robby Benson and Paige O'Hara with Angela Lansbury, David Ogden Stiers, Jerry Orbach and Richard White, the movie displays the story of a prince, whose punishment for his selfish and cruel ways, is turned into a beast and Belle, a woman who willing takes her father's place as prisoner of the castle. To become the prince again, the beast must love Belle and in turn she must love the beast or he will remain as he is forever. The film is directed by Gary Trousdale and Kirk Wise. Gary Trousdale has worked on the story of Oliver and Company( 1998 film), The Little Mermaid(1989 film) as storyboard artist,Aladdin( 1992 film) as pre- production story developer and CGI, The Lion King (1994 film) on the story,The Hunchback of Notre Dame(1996 film) as director, Madagascar(2005 film) as an additional storyboard artist, Flushed Away(2006 film) as an additional story artist, among many more. Meanwhile Kirk Wise also worked on Oliver and Company as an animating assistant and with the story, The Prince and the Pauper as a storyboard artist, The Lion King with additional story material, The Hunchback of Notre Dame as director, Spirited Away as director of the U.S. Production, among others. Paige O'Hara voices the film's main protagonist, Belle. She also portrayed Angela in Enchanted. The setting of the film is somewhere in rural France in the 1700s. Character development was very well done, therefore solid 3-D characters.Another highlight was the computer animation, particularly the ballroom dance scene, which was impressively caricatured. The songs while a bit childish still are very nice. The score was also pleasing to the ears.The sound was very realistic and you could feel like you were actually there. The special effects were outstanding. The movie wasn't slow or fast, it was nearly perfectly well-paced and that's a lot given that the run time is only 84 minutes. It is the best film by Gary Trousdale and Kirk Wise. Quality wise, it's Kirk Wise's Spirited Away was significantly better. The plot was creative and quite unpredictable. The dialogue was also memorable. The movie flowed incredible scene to scene. The lighting and ambiance was superb. The animation was realistic and nothing looked out of the ordinary( in a good way). The costume design was intricate and realistic. It contributed positively towards the movie's overall tone. The set design was exceptional and it added to the movie experience. If the movie was filmed in an actual location, it would have to be well- chosen while there is hardly place where all of that is nearby. The background music was amazing. It worked incredibly well for the film.Ir was wasn't under-used or used in excess. The music was suspenseful and amusing, obviously in the correct places. All in all, the movie was fascinating and interesting, despite not being Disney's finest film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    All time favorite
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kristiscott111
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is an excellent movie for the whole family. I was already in Junior High when this came out but it quickly became one of my favorites. Even now with children of my own I love to pull this movie out and sit down with them to watch it. It starts out with beautiful scenery and wonderful singing. You will follow the life of an ordinary girl named Belle who has a love for reading. She lives alone with her father who is a but odd with his inventions and solitary lifestyle. He goes off to show his invention, he gets lost, finds a castle in the woods and lets himself in. Once inside he meets the enchanted occupants. Then the story really starts. The Beast discovers he has an unannounced visitor and thinks he is there torment him. So the father gets thrown in the tower. Belle has an unwelcoming admirer, the town bully. He tries to woo her, unsuccessfully. She runs out to the field to escape him and finds her fathers riderless horse barreling down on her. She then travels to the woods in search of her father. When she finds him at the castle she trades her life for his and the Beast releases her father and keeps her. Then the story begins.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Middle of Disney's Golden Age
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin6942
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Belle, whose father is imprisoned by the Beast, offers herself instead and discovers her captor to be an enchanted prince. This film was right in the middle of Disney's golden age, sandwiched between "Aladdin" and "Little Mermaid", pushing the boundaries of digital animation (just a few years before Pixar blew Disney out of the water). And the songs... definitely quite memorable. For me, Belle is the best princess Disney has had to date. While not an outright feminist role model like "Brave" was intended to be, she is a woman whose strengths are not in physical beauty, but in her intelligence. I think that was a great decision. Sure, she is not ugly, but the focus was on her being more than just "a prize to be won".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a beautiful young girl who come's in love with a beast.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nimra Rauf
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    the story is about a beautiful young village girl who lives with her old father who's been an inventor. Gaston a brute and rude handsome man on which all the village girls would die for is in love with belle,but after all he is belle would never accept his proposal but Gaston is steadfast to marry belle.one day Belle's father is off to another village to sell one of his invention in auction. but he come's in danger and runs into a castle which is forbidden but he is not known of it.when he gets cozy inside he discovers a scary,huge and rude beast who captures him inside.some how belle come to an awareness about the situation and runs off to help her father.the beast makes a deal with the girl that he would only release him in one condition that belle would be left there.As belle's warm heart agree's the condition her father is set off and belle is kept with the beast. the beast is in love with belle and steady and slow belle also comes in love with him, but the beast is captured in a spell and time is running out..the spell would only be broken only if he gets the KISS OF TRUE LOVE. Gaston comes aware of the situation and prepares an angry mob to attack the beast.later on when the beast is wounded belle kisses him and the spell is broken and the beast turns into a beautiful,young,handsome and charming prince. AND THEY GET MARRIED AND LIVE HAPPILY EVER AFTER!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One Of The Best Films Of The Disney Renaissance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    donuthaters12
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Disney has created a few classic princess fairy tale films in the past, so does Beauty and the Beast still matter? Simply yes. In comparison to the other princess films in the Disney Renaissance, this tops it but overall it isn't my favorite. The Disney Renaissance was film after film executed with brilliance and there are four films that would almost always be chosen either one as the best of the pack; The Little Mermaid, Beauty and the Beast, Aladdin, and The Lion King. I fall in the group that thinks Aladdin is the strongest film but either one are great enough to be number one. The story team for this film, did a great job as they meshed the melodramatic tale ,that is commonly found in the Disney princess films of the past, with modern dialogue and humor that appeals to the newer generation. With Disney animated films, I expect to see funny side characters. The difference between the old Disney and the new Disney is that somehow the most memorable element of the cast is the supporting cast rather than the main star. With Disney's old films, the main characters were the memorable ones for me. The film is an endearing, feel good, romantic story; with hilarious dialogue; that will appeal to all ages. This film was directed by Gary Tousdale and Kirk Wise, and this film was their debut in directing a Disney animated full length feature. What a great way to start, they created a film that is now regarded as a classic and was the first animated feature to be nominated with Best Picture at the Academy Awards. I think they took the best things about The Little Mermaid and added other things that work. Their next directorial efforts for Disney did not achieve close to what they have done for this, although those films did gain a cult following. I felt that The Little Mermaid and The Rescuers Down Under in comparison did not have that beautiful cinematography that Beauty and the Beast shows. It's cinematography is one of the main reasons why so much of this film work, whether it's the beautiful and dramatic lighting or the way the "camera" moves in a particular scene. An example would be the scene where both Belle and the Beast had a romantic dance in the ballroom; the scene was lit gorgeously and the iconic moment when the "camera" starts from the chandelier and glides its way down to them dancing. I felt that this aspect of the film should have been awarded with something. As expected from a Disney film, it is going to contain musical numbers in it. I don't usually mind it as it allows the animators to show off something daring and outrageous. I feel that the songs in this film are much more accessible and beautiful, like 'Be Our Guest' and 'Gaston', rather than something grand and iconic, Lion King, or as fun and daring, Aladdin. Be Our Guest and Gaston are definitely the favorite of mine. Be Our Guest due to it feeling like a Broadway musical and Gaston because it is so ridiculously egotistic that it is entertaining. Also pretty much who has seen the film, would remember the words "Tale as old as time/Song as old as rhyme". The soundtrack is wonderful but I don't feel any of it out trumps Aladdin's 'A Whole New World' or Lion King's 'Circle of Life'. The voices of the film fit well for the characters and certainly gives the characters a bit of personality. The animators did a wonderful job drawing the characters as they look very clean and attractive. The animators pushed hard on this film as large amounts of objects or people move in one shot, and each movement has a personality of its own. Cogsworth and Lumiere are one of the best character duos ever animated on Disney. The film is an icon of its own and definitely ranks in one of the top romance films of all time. Beauty and the Beast is a film that would be competing against films like Casablanca and Gone with the Wind in deciding which melodramatic romance film is the best. If you are looking for a great romantic film or a Disney film that hits all of its marks then this is that film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Tale as Old as Time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thelightbeamrider
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Beauty and the Beast is undoubtedly one of the best animated movies ever created. It is magical, enchanting, and moving in a way only classics are. We learn in the prologue that a selfish and unkind prince was cursed to be a beast. If he can learn to love and be loved in return, he will return to his original form. Belle is a smart, kind, and brave young woman living in a nearby town. She spends her days reading and rejecting advances from the local lout Gaston. When Belle's father gets lost one night, he wanders into the Beast's castle. The Beast accuses him of trespassing and throws him in the dungeon. Belle sets out to save her father and strikes up a deal with the Beast: if he lets her father go, she will stay in his place. The Beast and his servants, who have been turned into household objects, see Belle's arrival as a chance to finally break the spell. However, the Beast must first learn to be a gentleman. It's hard to describe how good this movie is. The songs, story, and characters all come together so perfectly.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gaston is not the villain and Belle's books are important
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    soudkovahana
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of my most beloved Disney movies. I love everything about this movie. Whether it's Belle's opening song, the absence of the villain or Mrs. Potts. Now I know you'll probably tell me that Gaston is the main villain in this story but I don't see him that way. Sure he's pretentious and cocky but that doesn't make him "the villain". Even when he rouse the village to go kill the Beast, yes I know he does it for his own selfish reasons, but he thinks it's just some beast, some animal, and he does not know the true identity of his. I don't want to excuse his actions, he's still very mean and selfish and very much hateful but I just don't see him as the evil villain like Voldemort or Darth Vader. You know what I mean? Anyway the story of the Beauty and the Beast is one of my favorites and it's been remade so many times, in so many versions but the original is only one. There is something about this story that makes me gasp every time I watch it. It's an excellent choice to show your children or grandchildren because it teaches them various of different lessons. Take the main character, Belle, for instance, who likes to read and is called "odd" for that behavior even though she's perfectly normal. You also have here Gaston, who thinks only about himself and who thinks that women should not read or even think. Beast on the other hand is from the very beginning enraptured by Belle's reading and gives her the entire library to read in. I think that Belle's books is an important motive in the movie and should not be alleviated. In other words the story has a lot to tell not only to the children but also to the adults that watch it with them.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The greatest film of the Disney Renaissance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MissSimonetta
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Disney Renaissance (1989-1999) was in many ways the studio's second golden age (the first being from 1937-1942), where experimentation and sublime artistry where the rule rather than the exception. Most of my generation grew up with these movies, so everyone has a favorite. The most popular seems to be The Lion King (1994), but for me the true masterpiece of the era is Beauty and the Beast (1991), arguably the most romantic Disney flick of them all. All the characters are perfect. I think the only cast I like better than this one is from Pinocchio (1940). Belle is an appealing heroine: she has a compassionate and dreamy nature, but she won't let herself be walked over by anyone (notice she doesn't fall for the Beast until he starts acting like a decent person). The Beast has excellent character development, evolving from a selfish brat into a kind, passionate fellow. The enchanted objects are both fun comic relief and interesting characters in their own right. Gaston is one of Disney's best villains, walking the fine line between comic and menacing with ease. BatB boasts the greatest soundtrack of all the Disney canon. Howard Ashman and Alan Mencken outdid themselves here. The choreography is magnificent too, especially the Busby Berkely inspired "Be Our Guest" and the superbly animated "Beauty and the Beast". The incidental music is lush and romantic, a pleasure to listen to in its own right. That's not to say the film doesn't have flaws. The animation on Belle goes off-model at times and the CG in the ballroom sequence is dated. And then there's that plot hole concerning how long Belle was at the castle. None of these issues diminish the greatness of the picture. This is one of the most beautiful and adult love stories ever put put on screen. Absolutely essential.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cookiemonster1234567
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I really like this movie. Its been my favorite movie since I was a little girl. Its a good story about integrity and true character. I mean our world is so messed up these days. Belle didn't care what the beast looked she only cared about his true character which is how all love is supposed to be but sadly its not how life is anymore. Its a beautiful story about what life really should be and what love should really be and mean inside and out. period that's it. People now chose who they 'love' by looks or the way someone is known to be or if that person is a popular person themselves with nobody else's help not one little bit. I really love the movie and I think that you would as well if you watch the movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My favorite
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dannimonai
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I used to watch this movie over and over again when I was little, it was always in the VCR. It was my favorite movie, it still is. I love the music, the animation, the characters and the story line. I identify with Belle the most, I feel as if she and I are one in the same. We love our family and a good book...or two. I have never succumbed to the pressure of society and I always stuck up for myself and others, just like she did. I learned to love people for who they are, not what they look like. This movie always encouraged me to do by best and be the best person I can be. Plus, the library Beast gives her is amazing and I would love it if it were mine!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beauty and the Beast is a 1991 American animated fantasy, romantic, and musical film distributed by Walt Disney Pictures and produced by Walt Disney Feature Animation.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Charith Rajeeva
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Beauty and the Beast Featuring the vocal talents of Robby Benson and Paige O'Hara with Angela Lansbury, David Ogden Stiers, Jerry Orbach and Richard White, the movie displays the story of a prince, whose punishment for his selfish and cruel ways, is turned into a beast and Belle, a woman who willing takes her father's place as prisoner of the castle. To become the prince again, the beast must love Belle and in turn she must love the beast or he will remain as he is forever. The film is directed by Gary Trousdale and Kirk Wise. Gary Trousdale has worked on the story of Oliver and Company( 1998 film), The Little Mermaid(1989 film) as storyboard artist,Aladdin( 1992 film) as pre- production story developer and CGI, The Lion King (1994 film) on the story,The Hunchback of Notre Dame(1996 film) as director, Madagascar(2005 film) as an additional storyboard artist, Flushed Away(2006 film) as an additional story artist, among many more. Meanwhile Kirk Wise also worked on Oliver and Company as an animating assistant and with the story, The Prince and the Pauper as a storyboard artist, The Lion King with additional story material, The Hunchback of Notre Dame as director, Spirited Away as director of the U.S. Production, among others. Paige O'Hara voices the film's main protagonist, Belle. She also portrayed Angela in Enchanted. The setting of the film is somewhere in rural France in the 1700s. Character development was very well done, therefore solid 3-D characters.Another highlight was the computer animation, particularly the ballroom dance scene, which was impressively caricatured. The songs while a bit childish still are very nice. The score was also pleasing to the ears.The sound was very realistic and you could feel like you were actually there. The special effects were outstanding. The movie wasn't slow or fast, it was nearly perfectly well-paced and that's a lot given that the run time is only 84 minutes. It is the best film by Gary Trousdale and Kirk Wise. Quality wise, it's Kirk Wise's Spirited Away was significantly better. The plot was creative and quite unpredictable. The dialogue was also memorable. The movie flowed incredible scene to scene. The lighting and ambiance was superb. The animation was realistic and nothing looked out of the ordinary( in a good way). The costume design was intricate and realistic. It contributed positively towards the movie's overall tone. The set design was exceptional and it added to the movie experience. If the movie was filmed in an actual location, it would have to be well- chosen while there is hardly place where all of that is nearby. The background music was amazing. It worked incredibly well for the film.Ir was wasn't under-used or used in excess. The music was suspenseful and amusing, obviously in the correct places. All in all, the movie was fascinating and interesting, despite not being Disney's finest film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    All time favorite
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kristiscott111
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is an excellent movie for the whole family. I was already in Junior High when this came out but it quickly became one of my favorites. Even now with children of my own I love to pull this movie out and sit down with them to watch it. It starts out with beautiful scenery and wonderful singing. You will follow the life of an ordinary girl named Belle who has a love for reading. She lives alone with her father who is a but odd with his inventions and solitary lifestyle. He goes off to show his invention, he gets lost, finds a castle in the woods and lets himself in. Once inside he meets the enchanted occupants. Then the story really starts. The Beast discovers he has an unannounced visitor and thinks he is there torment him. So the father gets thrown in the tower. Belle has an unwelcoming admirer, the town bully. He tries to woo her, unsuccessfully. She runs out to the field to escape him and finds her fathers riderless horse barreling down on her. She then travels to the woods in search of her father. When she finds him at the castle she trades her life for his and the Beast releases her father and keeps her. Then the story begins.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Middle of Disney's Golden Age
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin6942
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Belle, whose father is imprisoned by the Beast, offers herself instead and discovers her captor to be an enchanted prince. This film was right in the middle of Disney's golden age, sandwiched between "Aladdin" and "Little Mermaid", pushing the boundaries of digital animation (just a few years before Pixar blew Disney out of the water). And the songs... definitely quite memorable. For me, Belle is the best princess Disney has had to date. While not an outright feminist role model like "Brave" was intended to be, she is a woman whose strengths are not in physical beauty, but in her intelligence. I think that was a great decision. Sure, she is not ugly, but the focus was on her being more than just "a prize to be won".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a beautiful young girl who come's in love with a beast.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nimra Rauf
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    the story is about a beautiful young village girl who lives with her old father who's been an inventor. Gaston a brute and rude handsome man on which all the village girls would die for is in love with belle,but after all he is belle would never accept his proposal but Gaston is steadfast to marry belle.one day Belle's father is off to another village to sell one of his invention in auction. but he come's in danger and runs into a castle which is forbidden but he is not known of it.when he gets cozy inside he discovers a scary,huge and rude beast who captures him inside.some how belle come to an awareness about the situation and runs off to help her father.the beast makes a deal with the girl that he would only release him in one condition that belle would be left there.As belle's warm heart agree's the condition her father is set off and belle is kept with the beast. the beast is in love with belle and steady and slow belle also comes in love with him, but the beast is captured in a spell and time is running out..the spell would only be broken only if he gets the KISS OF TRUE LOVE. Gaston comes aware of the situation and prepares an angry mob to attack the beast.later on when the beast is wounded belle kisses him and the spell is broken and the beast turns into a beautiful,young,handsome and charming prince. AND THEY GET MARRIED AND LIVE HAPPILY EVER AFTER!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One Of The Best Films Of The Disney Renaissance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    donuthaters12
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Disney has created a few classic princess fairy tale films in the past, so does Beauty and the Beast still matter? Simply yes. In comparison to the other princess films in the Disney Renaissance, this tops it but overall it isn't my favorite. The Disney Renaissance was film after film executed with brilliance and there are four films that would almost always be chosen either one as the best of the pack; The Little Mermaid, Beauty and the Beast, Aladdin, and The Lion King. I fall in the group that thinks Aladdin is the strongest film but either one are great enough to be number one. The story team for this film, did a great job as they meshed the melodramatic tale ,that is commonly found in the Disney princess films of the past, with modern dialogue and humor that appeals to the newer generation. With Disney animated films, I expect to see funny side characters. The difference between the old Disney and the new Disney is that somehow the most memorable element of the cast is the supporting cast rather than the main star. With Disney's old films, the main characters were the memorable ones for me. The film is an endearing, feel good, romantic story; with hilarious dialogue; that will appeal to all ages. This film was directed by Gary Tousdale and Kirk Wise, and this film was their debut in directing a Disney animated full length feature. What a great way to start, they created a film that is now regarded as a classic and was the first animated feature to be nominated with Best Picture at the Academy Awards. I think they took the best things about The Little Mermaid and added other things that work. Their next directorial efforts for Disney did not achieve close to what they have done for this, although those films did gain a cult following. I felt that The Little Mermaid and The Rescuers Down Under in comparison did not have that beautiful cinematography that Beauty and the Beast shows. It's cinematography is one of the main reasons why so much of this film work, whether it's the beautiful and dramatic lighting or the way the "camera" moves in a particular scene. An example would be the scene where both Belle and the Beast had a romantic dance in the ballroom; the scene was lit gorgeously and the iconic moment when the "camera" starts from the chandelier and glides its way down to them dancing. I felt that this aspect of the film should have been awarded with something. As expected from a Disney film, it is going to contain musical numbers in it. I don't usually mind it as it allows the animators to show off something daring and outrageous. I feel that the songs in this film are much more accessible and beautiful, like 'Be Our Guest' and 'Gaston', rather than something grand and iconic, Lion King, or as fun and daring, Aladdin. Be Our Guest and Gaston are definitely the favorite of mine. Be Our Guest due to it feeling like a Broadway musical and Gaston because it is so ridiculously egotistic that it is entertaining. Also pretty much who has seen the film, would remember the words "Tale as old as time/Song as old as rhyme". The soundtrack is wonderful but I don't feel any of it out trumps Aladdin's 'A Whole New World' or Lion King's 'Circle of Life'. The voices of the film fit well for the characters and certainly gives the characters a bit of personality. The animators did a wonderful job drawing the characters as they look very clean and attractive. The animators pushed hard on this film as large amounts of objects or people move in one shot, and each movement has a personality of its own. Cogsworth and Lumiere are one of the best character duos ever animated on Disney. The film is an icon of its own and definitely ranks in one of the top romance films of all time. Beauty and the Beast is a film that would be competing against films like Casablanca and Gone with the Wind in deciding which melodramatic romance film is the best. If you are looking for a great romantic film or a Disney film that hits all of its marks then this is that film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Tale as Old as Time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thelightbeamrider
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Beauty and the Beast is undoubtedly one of the best animated movies ever created. It is magical, enchanting, and moving in a way only classics are. We learn in the prologue that a selfish and unkind prince was cursed to be a beast. If he can learn to love and be loved in return, he will return to his original form. Belle is a smart, kind, and brave young woman living in a nearby town. She spends her days reading and rejecting advances from the local lout Gaston. When Belle's father gets lost one night, he wanders into the Beast's castle. The Beast accuses him of trespassing and throws him in the dungeon. Belle sets out to save her father and strikes up a deal with the Beast: if he lets her father go, she will stay in his place. The Beast and his servants, who have been turned into household objects, see Belle's arrival as a chance to finally break the spell. However, the Beast must first learn to be a gentleman. It's hard to describe how good this movie is. The songs, story, and characters all come together so perfectly.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gaston is not the villain and Belle's books are important
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    soudkovahana
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of my most beloved Disney movies. I love everything about this movie. Whether it's Belle's opening song, the absence of the villain or Mrs. Potts. Now I know you'll probably tell me that Gaston is the main villain in this story but I don't see him that way. Sure he's pretentious and cocky but that doesn't make him "the villain". Even when he rouse the village to go kill the Beast, yes I know he does it for his own selfish reasons, but he thinks it's just some beast, some animal, and he does not know the true identity of his. I don't want to excuse his actions, he's still very mean and selfish and very much hateful but I just don't see him as the evil villain like Voldemort or Darth Vader. You know what I mean? Anyway the story of the Beauty and the Beast is one of my favorites and it's been remade so many times, in so many versions but the original is only one. There is something about this story that makes me gasp every time I watch it. It's an excellent choice to show your children or grandchildren because it teaches them various of different lessons. Take the main character, Belle, for instance, who likes to read and is called "odd" for that behavior even though she's perfectly normal. You also have here Gaston, who thinks only about himself and who thinks that women should not read or even think. Beast on the other hand is from the very beginning enraptured by Belle's reading and gives her the entire library to read in. I think that Belle's books is an important motive in the movie and should not be alleviated. In other words the story has a lot to tell not only to the children but also to the adults that watch it with them.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The greatest film of the Disney Renaissance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MissSimonetta
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Disney Renaissance (1989-1999) was in many ways the studio's second golden age (the first being from 1937-1942), where experimentation and sublime artistry where the rule rather than the exception. Most of my generation grew up with these movies, so everyone has a favorite. The most popular seems to be The Lion King (1994), but for me the true masterpiece of the era is Beauty and the Beast (1991), arguably the most romantic Disney flick of them all. All the characters are perfect. I think the only cast I like better than this one is from Pinocchio (1940). Belle is an appealing heroine: she has a compassionate and dreamy nature, but she won't let herself be walked over by anyone (notice she doesn't fall for the Beast until he starts acting like a decent person). The Beast has excellent character development, evolving from a selfish brat into a kind, passionate fellow. The enchanted objects are both fun comic relief and interesting characters in their own right. Gaston is one of Disney's best villains, walking the fine line between comic and menacing with ease. BatB boasts the greatest soundtrack of all the Disney canon. Howard Ashman and Alan Mencken outdid themselves here. The choreography is magnificent too, especially the Busby Berkely inspired "Be Our Guest" and the superbly animated "Beauty and the Beast". The incidental music is lush and romantic, a pleasure to listen to in its own right. That's not to say the film doesn't have flaws. The animation on Belle goes off-model at times and the CG in the ballroom sequence is dated. And then there's that plot hole concerning how long Belle was at the castle. None of these issues diminish the greatness of the picture. This is one of the most beautiful and adult love stories ever put put on screen. Absolutely essential.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cookiemonster1234567
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I really like this movie. Its been my favorite movie since I was a little girl. Its a good story about integrity and true character. I mean our world is so messed up these days. Belle didn't care what the beast looked she only cared about his true character which is how all love is supposed to be but sadly its not how life is anymore. Its a beautiful story about what life really should be and what love should really be and mean inside and out. period that's it. People now chose who they 'love' by looks or the way someone is known to be or if that person is a popular person themselves with nobody else's help not one little bit. I really love the movie and I think that you would as well if you watch the movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My favorite
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dannimonai
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I used to watch this movie over and over again when I was little, it was always in the VCR. It was my favorite movie, it still is. I love the music, the animation, the characters and the story line. I identify with Belle the most, I feel as if she and I are one in the same. We love our family and a good book...or two. I have never succumbed to the pressure of society and I always stuck up for myself and others, just like she did. I learned to love people for who they are, not what they look like. This movie always encouraged me to do by best and be the best person I can be. Plus, the library Beast gives her is amazing and I would love it if it were mine!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beauty and the Beast is a 1991 American animated fantasy, romantic, and musical film distributed by Walt Disney Pictures and produced by Walt Disney Feature Animation.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Charith Rajeeva
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Beauty and the Beast Featuring the vocal talents of Robby Benson and Paige O'Hara with Angela Lansbury, David Ogden Stiers, Jerry Orbach and Richard White, the movie displays the story of a prince, whose punishment for his selfish and cruel ways, is turned into a beast and Belle, a woman who willing takes her father's place as prisoner of the castle. To become the prince again, the beast must love Belle and in turn she must love the beast or he will remain as he is forever. The film is directed by Gary Trousdale and Kirk Wise. Gary Trousdale has worked on the story of Oliver and Company( 1998 film), The Little Mermaid(1989 film) as storyboard artist,Aladdin( 1992 film) as pre- production story developer and CGI, The Lion King (1994 film) on the story,The Hunchback of Notre Dame(1996 film) as director, Madagascar(2005 film) as an additional storyboard artist, Flushed Away(2006 film) as an additional story artist, among many more. Meanwhile Kirk Wise also worked on Oliver and Company as an animating assistant and with the story, The Prince and the Pauper as a storyboard artist, The Lion King with additional story material, The Hunchback of Notre Dame as director, Spirited Away as director of the U.S. Production, among others. Paige O'Hara voices the film's main protagonist, Belle. She also portrayed Angela in Enchanted. The setting of the film is somewhere in rural France in the 1700s. Character development was very well done, therefore solid 3-D characters.Another highlight was the computer animation, particularly the ballroom dance scene, which was impressively caricatured. The songs while a bit childish still are very nice. The score was also pleasing to the ears.The sound was very realistic and you could feel like you were actually there. The special effects were outstanding. The movie wasn't slow or fast, it was nearly perfectly well-paced and that's a lot given that the run time is only 84 minutes. It is the best film by Gary Trousdale and Kirk Wise. Quality wise, it's Kirk Wise's Spirited Away was significantly better. The plot was creative and quite unpredictable. The dialogue was also memorable. The movie flowed incredible scene to scene. The lighting and ambiance was superb. The animation was realistic and nothing looked out of the ordinary( in a good way). The costume design was intricate and realistic. It contributed positively towards the movie's overall tone. The set design was exceptional and it added to the movie experience. If the movie was filmed in an actual location, it would have to be well- chosen while there is hardly place where all of that is nearby. The background music was amazing. It worked incredibly well for the film.Ir was wasn't under-used or used in excess. The music was suspenseful and amusing, obviously in the correct places. All in all, the movie was fascinating and interesting, despite not being Disney's finest film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    All time favorite
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kristiscott111
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is an excellent movie for the whole family. I was already in Junior High when this came out but it quickly became one of my favorites. Even now with children of my own I love to pull this movie out and sit down with them to watch it. It starts out with beautiful scenery and wonderful singing. You will follow the life of an ordinary girl named Belle who has a love for reading. She lives alone with her father who is a but odd with his inventions and solitary lifestyle. He goes off to show his invention, he gets lost, finds a castle in the woods and lets himself in. Once inside he meets the enchanted occupants. Then the story really starts. The Beast discovers he has an unannounced visitor and thinks he is there torment him. So the father gets thrown in the tower. Belle has an unwelcoming admirer, the town bully. He tries to woo her, unsuccessfully. She runs out to the field to escape him and finds her fathers riderless horse barreling down on her. She then travels to the woods in search of her father. When she finds him at the castle she trades her life for his and the Beast releases her father and keeps her. Then the story begins.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Middle of Disney's Golden Age
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin6942
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Belle, whose father is imprisoned by the Beast, offers herself instead and discovers her captor to be an enchanted prince. This film was right in the middle of Disney's golden age, sandwiched between "Aladdin" and "Little Mermaid", pushing the boundaries of digital animation (just a few years before Pixar blew Disney out of the water). And the songs... definitely quite memorable. For me, Belle is the best princess Disney has had to date. While not an outright feminist role model like "Brave" was intended to be, she is a woman whose strengths are not in physical beauty, but in her intelligence. I think that was a great decision. Sure, she is not ugly, but the focus was on her being more than just "a prize to be won".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a beautiful young girl who come's in love with a beast.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nimra Rauf
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    the story is about a beautiful young village girl who lives with her old father who's been an inventor. Gaston a brute and rude handsome man on which all the village girls would die for is in love with belle,but after all he is belle would never accept his proposal but Gaston is steadfast to marry belle.one day Belle's father is off to another village to sell one of his invention in auction. but he come's in danger and runs into a castle which is forbidden but he is not known of it.when he gets cozy inside he discovers a scary,huge and rude beast who captures him inside.some how belle come to an awareness about the situation and runs off to help her father.the beast makes a deal with the girl that he would only release him in one condition that belle would be left there.As belle's warm heart agree's the condition her father is set off and belle is kept with the beast. the beast is in love with belle and steady and slow belle also comes in love with him, but the beast is captured in a spell and time is running out..the spell would only be broken only if he gets the KISS OF TRUE LOVE. Gaston comes aware of the situation and prepares an angry mob to attack the beast.later on when the beast is wounded belle kisses him and the spell is broken and the beast turns into a beautiful,young,handsome and charming prince. AND THEY GET MARRIED AND LIVE HAPPILY EVER AFTER!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One Of The Best Films Of The Disney Renaissance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    donuthaters12
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Disney has created a few classic princess fairy tale films in the past, so does Beauty and the Beast still matter? Simply yes. In comparison to the other princess films in the Disney Renaissance, this tops it but overall it isn't my favorite. The Disney Renaissance was film after film executed with brilliance and there are four films that would almost always be chosen either one as the best of the pack; The Little Mermaid, Beauty and the Beast, Aladdin, and The Lion King. I fall in the group that thinks Aladdin is the strongest film but either one are great enough to be number one. The story team for this film, did a great job as they meshed the melodramatic tale ,that is commonly found in the Disney princess films of the past, with modern dialogue and humor that appeals to the newer generation. With Disney animated films, I expect to see funny side characters. The difference between the old Disney and the new Disney is that somehow the most memorable element of the cast is the supporting cast rather than the main star. With Disney's old films, the main characters were the memorable ones for me. The film is an endearing, feel good, romantic story; with hilarious dialogue; that will appeal to all ages. This film was directed by Gary Tousdale and Kirk Wise, and this film was their debut in directing a Disney animated full length feature. What a great way to start, they created a film that is now regarded as a classic and was the first animated feature to be nominated with Best Picture at the Academy Awards. I think they took the best things about The Little Mermaid and added other things that work. Their next directorial efforts for Disney did not achieve close to what they have done for this, although those films did gain a cult following. I felt that The Little Mermaid and The Rescuers Down Under in comparison did not have that beautiful cinematography that Beauty and the Beast shows. It's cinematography is one of the main reasons why so much of this film work, whether it's the beautiful and dramatic lighting or the way the "camera" moves in a particular scene. An example would be the scene where both Belle and the Beast had a romantic dance in the ballroom; the scene was lit gorgeously and the iconic moment when the "camera" starts from the chandelier and glides its way down to them dancing. I felt that this aspect of the film should have been awarded with something. As expected from a Disney film, it is going to contain musical numbers in it. I don't usually mind it as it allows the animators to show off something daring and outrageous. I feel that the songs in this film are much more accessible and beautiful, like 'Be Our Guest' and 'Gaston', rather than something grand and iconic, Lion King, or as fun and daring, Aladdin. Be Our Guest and Gaston are definitely the favorite of mine. Be Our Guest due to it feeling like a Broadway musical and Gaston because it is so ridiculously egotistic that it is entertaining. Also pretty much who has seen the film, would remember the words "Tale as old as time/Song as old as rhyme". The soundtrack is wonderful but I don't feel any of it out trumps Aladdin's 'A Whole New World' or Lion King's 'Circle of Life'. The voices of the film fit well for the characters and certainly gives the characters a bit of personality. The animators did a wonderful job drawing the characters as they look very clean and attractive. The animators pushed hard on this film as large amounts of objects or people move in one shot, and each movement has a personality of its own. Cogsworth and Lumiere are one of the best character duos ever animated on Disney. The film is an icon of its own and definitely ranks in one of the top romance films of all time. Beauty and the Beast is a film that would be competing against films like Casablanca and Gone with the Wind in deciding which melodramatic romance film is the best. If you are looking for a great romantic film or a Disney film that hits all of its marks then this is that film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Tale as Old as Time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thelightbeamrider
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Beauty and the Beast is undoubtedly one of the best animated movies ever created. It is magical, enchanting, and moving in a way only classics are. We learn in the prologue that a selfish and unkind prince was cursed to be a beast. If he can learn to love and be loved in return, he will return to his original form. Belle is a smart, kind, and brave young woman living in a nearby town. She spends her days reading and rejecting advances from the local lout Gaston. When Belle's father gets lost one night, he wanders into the Beast's castle. The Beast accuses him of trespassing and throws him in the dungeon. Belle sets out to save her father and strikes up a deal with the Beast: if he lets her father go, she will stay in his place. The Beast and his servants, who have been turned into household objects, see Belle's arrival as a chance to finally break the spell. However, the Beast must first learn to be a gentleman. It's hard to describe how good this movie is. The songs, story, and characters all come together so perfectly.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gaston is not the villain and Belle's books are important
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    soudkovahana
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of my most beloved Disney movies. I love everything about this movie. Whether it's Belle's opening song, the absence of the villain or Mrs. Potts. Now I know you'll probably tell me that Gaston is the main villain in this story but I don't see him that way. Sure he's pretentious and cocky but that doesn't make him "the villain". Even when he rouse the village to go kill the Beast, yes I know he does it for his own selfish reasons, but he thinks it's just some beast, some animal, and he does not know the true identity of his. I don't want to excuse his actions, he's still very mean and selfish and very much hateful but I just don't see him as the evil villain like Voldemort or Darth Vader. You know what I mean? Anyway the story of the Beauty and the Beast is one of my favorites and it's been remade so many times, in so many versions but the original is only one. There is something about this story that makes me gasp every time I watch it. It's an excellent choice to show your children or grandchildren because it teaches them various of different lessons. Take the main character, Belle, for instance, who likes to read and is called "odd" for that behavior even though she's perfectly normal. You also have here Gaston, who thinks only about himself and who thinks that women should not read or even think. Beast on the other hand is from the very beginning enraptured by Belle's reading and gives her the entire library to read in. I think that Belle's books is an important motive in the movie and should not be alleviated. In other words the story has a lot to tell not only to the children but also to the adults that watch it with them.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The greatest film of the Disney Renaissance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MissSimonetta
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Disney Renaissance (1989-1999) was in many ways the studio's second golden age (the first being from 1937-1942), where experimentation and sublime artistry where the rule rather than the exception. Most of my generation grew up with these movies, so everyone has a favorite. The most popular seems to be The Lion King (1994), but for me the true masterpiece of the era is Beauty and the Beast (1991), arguably the most romantic Disney flick of them all. All the characters are perfect. I think the only cast I like better than this one is from Pinocchio (1940). Belle is an appealing heroine: she has a compassionate and dreamy nature, but she won't let herself be walked over by anyone (notice she doesn't fall for the Beast until he starts acting like a decent person). The Beast has excellent character development, evolving from a selfish brat into a kind, passionate fellow. The enchanted objects are both fun comic relief and interesting characters in their own right. Gaston is one of Disney's best villains, walking the fine line between comic and menacing with ease. BatB boasts the greatest soundtrack of all the Disney canon. Howard Ashman and Alan Mencken outdid themselves here. The choreography is magnificent too, especially the Busby Berkely inspired "Be Our Guest" and the superbly animated "Beauty and the Beast". The incidental music is lush and romantic, a pleasure to listen to in its own right. That's not to say the film doesn't have flaws. The animation on Belle goes off-model at times and the CG in the ballroom sequence is dated. And then there's that plot hole concerning how long Belle was at the castle. None of these issues diminish the greatness of the picture. This is one of the most beautiful and adult love stories ever put put on screen. Absolutely essential.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cookiemonster1234567
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I really like this movie. Its been my favorite movie since I was a little girl. Its a good story about integrity and true character. I mean our world is so messed up these days. Belle didn't care what the beast looked she only cared about his true character which is how all love is supposed to be but sadly its not how life is anymore. Its a beautiful story about what life really should be and what love should really be and mean inside and out. period that's it. People now chose who they 'love' by looks or the way someone is known to be or if that person is a popular person themselves with nobody else's help not one little bit. I really love the movie and I think that you would as well if you watch the movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My favorite
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dannimonai
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I used to watch this movie over and over again when I was little, it was always in the VCR. It was my favorite movie, it still is. I love the music, the animation, the characters and the story line. I identify with Belle the most, I feel as if she and I are one in the same. We love our family and a good book...or two. I have never succumbed to the pressure of society and I always stuck up for myself and others, just like she did. I learned to love people for who they are, not what they look like. This movie always encouraged me to do by best and be the best person I can be. Plus, the library Beast gives her is amazing and I would love it if it were mine!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beauty and the Beast is a 1991 American animated fantasy, romantic, and musical film distributed by Walt Disney Pictures and produced by Walt Disney Feature Animation.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Charith Rajeeva
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Beauty and the Beast Featuring the vocal talents of Robby Benson and Paige O'Hara with Angela Lansbury, David Ogden Stiers, Jerry Orbach and Richard White, the movie displays the story of a prince, whose punishment for his selfish and cruel ways, is turned into a beast and Belle, a woman who willing takes her father's place as prisoner of the castle. To become the prince again, the beast must love Belle and in turn she must love the beast or he will remain as he is forever. The film is directed by Gary Trousdale and Kirk Wise. Gary Trousdale has worked on the story of Oliver and Company( 1998 film), The Little Mermaid(1989 film) as storyboard artist,Aladdin( 1992 film) as pre- production story developer and CGI, The Lion King (1994 film) on the story,The Hunchback of Notre Dame(1996 film) as director, Madagascar(2005 film) as an additional storyboard artist, Flushed Away(2006 film) as an additional story artist, among many more. Meanwhile Kirk Wise also worked on Oliver and Company as an animating assistant and with the story, The Prince and the Pauper as a storyboard artist, The Lion King with additional story material, The Hunchback of Notre Dame as director, Spirited Away as director of the U.S. Production, among others. Paige O'Hara voices the film's main protagonist, Belle. She also portrayed Angela in Enchanted. The setting of the film is somewhere in rural France in the 1700s. Character development was very well done, therefore solid 3-D characters.Another highlight was the computer animation, particularly the ballroom dance scene, which was impressively caricatured. The songs while a bit childish still are very nice. The score was also pleasing to the ears.The sound was very realistic and you could feel like you were actually there. The special effects were outstanding. The movie wasn't slow or fast, it was nearly perfectly well-paced and that's a lot given that the run time is only 84 minutes. It is the best film by Gary Trousdale and Kirk Wise. Quality wise, it's Kirk Wise's Spirited Away was significantly better. The plot was creative and quite unpredictable. The dialogue was also memorable. The movie flowed incredible scene to scene. The lighting and ambiance was superb. The animation was realistic and nothing looked out of the ordinary( in a good way). The costume design was intricate and realistic. It contributed positively towards the movie's overall tone. The set design was exceptional and it added to the movie experience. If the movie was filmed in an actual location, it would have to be well- chosen while there is hardly place where all of that is nearby. The background music was amazing. It worked incredibly well for the film.Ir was wasn't under-used or used in excess. The music was suspenseful and amusing, obviously in the correct places. All in all, the movie was fascinating and interesting, despite not being Disney's finest film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    All time favorite
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kristiscott111
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is an excellent movie for the whole family. I was already in Junior High when this came out but it quickly became one of my favorites. Even now with children of my own I love to pull this movie out and sit down with them to watch it. It starts out with beautiful scenery and wonderful singing. You will follow the life of an ordinary girl named Belle who has a love for reading. She lives alone with her father who is a but odd with his inventions and solitary lifestyle. He goes off to show his invention, he gets lost, finds a castle in the woods and lets himself in. Once inside he meets the enchanted occupants. Then the story really starts. The Beast discovers he has an unannounced visitor and thinks he is there torment him. So the father gets thrown in the tower. Belle has an unwelcoming admirer, the town bully. He tries to woo her, unsuccessfully. She runs out to the field to escape him and finds her fathers riderless horse barreling down on her. She then travels to the woods in search of her father. When she finds him at the castle she trades her life for his and the Beast releases her father and keeps her. Then the story begins.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Middle of Disney's Golden Age
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin6942
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Belle, whose father is imprisoned by the Beast, offers herself instead and discovers her captor to be an enchanted prince. This film was right in the middle of Disney's golden age, sandwiched between "Aladdin" and "Little Mermaid", pushing the boundaries of digital animation (just a few years before Pixar blew Disney out of the water). And the songs... definitely quite memorable. For me, Belle is the best princess Disney has had to date. While not an outright feminist role model like "Brave" was intended to be, she is a woman whose strengths are not in physical beauty, but in her intelligence. I think that was a great decision. Sure, she is not ugly, but the focus was on her being more than just "a prize to be won".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a beautiful young girl who come's in love with a beast.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nimra Rauf
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    the story is about a beautiful young village girl who lives with her old father who's been an inventor. Gaston a brute and rude handsome man on which all the village girls would die for is in love with belle,but after all he is belle would never accept his proposal but Gaston is steadfast to marry belle.one day Belle's father is off to another village to sell one of his invention in auction. but he come's in danger and runs into a castle which is forbidden but he is not known of it.when he gets cozy inside he discovers a scary,huge and rude beast who captures him inside.some how belle come to an awareness about the situation and runs off to help her father.the beast makes a deal with the girl that he would only release him in one condition that belle would be left there.As belle's warm heart agree's the condition her father is set off and belle is kept with the beast. the beast is in love with belle and steady and slow belle also comes in love with him, but the beast is captured in a spell and time is running out..the spell would only be broken only if he gets the KISS OF TRUE LOVE. Gaston comes aware of the situation and prepares an angry mob to attack the beast.later on when the beast is wounded belle kisses him and the spell is broken and the beast turns into a beautiful,young,handsome and charming prince. AND THEY GET MARRIED AND LIVE HAPPILY EVER AFTER!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One Of The Best Films Of The Disney Renaissance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    donuthaters12
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Disney has created a few classic princess fairy tale films in the past, so does Beauty and the Beast still matter? Simply yes. In comparison to the other princess films in the Disney Renaissance, this tops it but overall it isn't my favorite. The Disney Renaissance was film after film executed with brilliance and there are four films that would almost always be chosen either one as the best of the pack; The Little Mermaid, Beauty and the Beast, Aladdin, and The Lion King. I fall in the group that thinks Aladdin is the strongest film but either one are great enough to be number one. The story team for this film, did a great job as they meshed the melodramatic tale ,that is commonly found in the Disney princess films of the past, with modern dialogue and humor that appeals to the newer generation. With Disney animated films, I expect to see funny side characters. The difference between the old Disney and the new Disney is that somehow the most memorable element of the cast is the supporting cast rather than the main star. With Disney's old films, the main characters were the memorable ones for me. The film is an endearing, feel good, romantic story; with hilarious dialogue; that will appeal to all ages. This film was directed by Gary Tousdale and Kirk Wise, and this film was their debut in directing a Disney animated full length feature. What a great way to start, they created a film that is now regarded as a classic and was the first animated feature to be nominated with Best Picture at the Academy Awards. I think they took the best things about The Little Mermaid and added other things that work. Their next directorial efforts for Disney did not achieve close to what they have done for this, although those films did gain a cult following. I felt that The Little Mermaid and The Rescuers Down Under in comparison did not have that beautiful cinematography that Beauty and the Beast shows. It's cinematography is one of the main reasons why so much of this film work, whether it's the beautiful and dramatic lighting or the way the "camera" moves in a particular scene. An example would be the scene where both Belle and the Beast had a romantic dance in the ballroom; the scene was lit gorgeously and the iconic moment when the "camera" starts from the chandelier and glides its way down to them dancing. I felt that this aspect of the film should have been awarded with something. As expected from a Disney film, it is going to contain musical numbers in it. I don't usually mind it as it allows the animators to show off something daring and outrageous. I feel that the songs in this film are much more accessible and beautiful, like 'Be Our Guest' and 'Gaston', rather than something grand and iconic, Lion King, or as fun and daring, Aladdin. Be Our Guest and Gaston are definitely the favorite of mine. Be Our Guest due to it feeling like a Broadway musical and Gaston because it is so ridiculously egotistic that it is entertaining. Also pretty much who has seen the film, would remember the words "Tale as old as time/Song as old as rhyme". The soundtrack is wonderful but I don't feel any of it out trumps Aladdin's 'A Whole New World' or Lion King's 'Circle of Life'. The voices of the film fit well for the characters and certainly gives the characters a bit of personality. The animators did a wonderful job drawing the characters as they look very clean and attractive. The animators pushed hard on this film as large amounts of objects or people move in one shot, and each movement has a personality of its own. Cogsworth and Lumiere are one of the best character duos ever animated on Disney. The film is an icon of its own and definitely ranks in one of the top romance films of all time. Beauty and the Beast is a film that would be competing against films like Casablanca and Gone with the Wind in deciding which melodramatic romance film is the best. If you are looking for a great romantic film or a Disney film that hits all of its marks then this is that film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Tale as Old as Time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thelightbeamrider
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Beauty and the Beast is undoubtedly one of the best animated movies ever created. It is magical, enchanting, and moving in a way only classics are. We learn in the prologue that a selfish and unkind prince was cursed to be a beast. If he can learn to love and be loved in return, he will return to his original form. Belle is a smart, kind, and brave young woman living in a nearby town. She spends her days reading and rejecting advances from the local lout Gaston. When Belle's father gets lost one night, he wanders into the Beast's castle. The Beast accuses him of trespassing and throws him in the dungeon. Belle sets out to save her father and strikes up a deal with the Beast: if he lets her father go, she will stay in his place. The Beast and his servants, who have been turned into household objects, see Belle's arrival as a chance to finally break the spell. However, the Beast must first learn to be a gentleman. It's hard to describe how good this movie is. The songs, story, and characters all come together so perfectly.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gaston is not the villain and Belle's books are important
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    soudkovahana
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of my most beloved Disney movies. I love everything about this movie. Whether it's Belle's opening song, the absence of the villain or Mrs. Potts. Now I know you'll probably tell me that Gaston is the main villain in this story but I don't see him that way. Sure he's pretentious and cocky but that doesn't make him "the villain". Even when he rouse the village to go kill the Beast, yes I know he does it for his own selfish reasons, but he thinks it's just some beast, some animal, and he does not know the true identity of his. I don't want to excuse his actions, he's still very mean and selfish and very much hateful but I just don't see him as the evil villain like Voldemort or Darth Vader. You know what I mean? Anyway the story of the Beauty and the Beast is one of my favorites and it's been remade so many times, in so many versions but the original is only one. There is something about this story that makes me gasp every time I watch it. It's an excellent choice to show your children or grandchildren because it teaches them various of different lessons. Take the main character, Belle, for instance, who likes to read and is called "odd" for that behavior even though she's perfectly normal. You also have here Gaston, who thinks only about himself and who thinks that women should not read or even think. Beast on the other hand is from the very beginning enraptured by Belle's reading and gives her the entire library to read in. I think that Belle's books is an important motive in the movie and should not be alleviated. In other words the story has a lot to tell not only to the children but also to the adults that watch it with them.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The greatest film of the Disney Renaissance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MissSimonetta
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Disney Renaissance (1989-1999) was in many ways the studio's second golden age (the first being from 1937-1942), where experimentation and sublime artistry where the rule rather than the exception. Most of my generation grew up with these movies, so everyone has a favorite. The most popular seems to be The Lion King (1994), but for me the true masterpiece of the era is Beauty and the Beast (1991), arguably the most romantic Disney flick of them all. All the characters are perfect. I think the only cast I like better than this one is from Pinocchio (1940). Belle is an appealing heroine: she has a compassionate and dreamy nature, but she won't let herself be walked over by anyone (notice she doesn't fall for the Beast until he starts acting like a decent person). The Beast has excellent character development, evolving from a selfish brat into a kind, passionate fellow. The enchanted objects are both fun comic relief and interesting characters in their own right. Gaston is one of Disney's best villains, walking the fine line between comic and menacing with ease. BatB boasts the greatest soundtrack of all the Disney canon. Howard Ashman and Alan Mencken outdid themselves here. The choreography is magnificent too, especially the Busby Berkely inspired "Be Our Guest" and the superbly animated "Beauty and the Beast". The incidental music is lush and romantic, a pleasure to listen to in its own right. That's not to say the film doesn't have flaws. The animation on Belle goes off-model at times and the CG in the ballroom sequence is dated. And then there's that plot hole concerning how long Belle was at the castle. None of these issues diminish the greatness of the picture. This is one of the most beautiful and adult love stories ever put put on screen. Absolutely essential.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cookiemonster1234567
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I really like this movie. Its been my favorite movie since I was a little girl. Its a good story about integrity and true character. I mean our world is so messed up these days. Belle didn't care what the beast looked she only cared about his true character which is how all love is supposed to be but sadly its not how life is anymore. Its a beautiful story about what life really should be and what love should really be and mean inside and out. period that's it. People now chose who they 'love' by looks or the way someone is known to be or if that person is a popular person themselves with nobody else's help not one little bit. I really love the movie and I think that you would as well if you watch the movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My favorite
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dannimonai
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I used to watch this movie over and over again when I was little, it was always in the VCR. It was my favorite movie, it still is. I love the music, the animation, the characters and the story line. I identify with Belle the most, I feel as if she and I are one in the same. We love our family and a good book...or two. I have never succumbed to the pressure of society and I always stuck up for myself and others, just like she did. I learned to love people for who they are, not what they look like. This movie always encouraged me to do by best and be the best person I can be. Plus, the library Beast gives her is amazing and I would love it if it were mine!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beauty and the Beast is a 1991 American animated fantasy, romantic, and musical film distributed by Walt Disney Pictures and produced by Walt Disney Feature Animation.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Charith Rajeeva
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Beauty and the Beast Featuring the vocal talents of Robby Benson and Paige O'Hara with Angela Lansbury, David Ogden Stiers, Jerry Orbach and Richard White, the movie displays the story of a prince, whose punishment for his selfish and cruel ways, is turned into a beast and Belle, a woman who willing takes her father's place as prisoner of the castle. To become the prince again, the beast must love Belle and in turn she must love the beast or he will remain as he is forever. The film is directed by Gary Trousdale and Kirk Wise. Gary Trousdale has worked on the story of Oliver and Company( 1998 film), The Little Mermaid(1989 film) as storyboard artist,Aladdin( 1992 film) as pre- production story developer and CGI, The Lion King (1994 film) on the story,The Hunchback of Notre Dame(1996 film) as director, Madagascar(2005 film) as an additional storyboard artist, Flushed Away(2006 film) as an additional story artist, among many more. Meanwhile Kirk Wise also worked on Oliver and Company as an animating assistant and with the story, The Prince and the Pauper as a storyboard artist, The Lion King with additional story material, The Hunchback of Notre Dame as director, Spirited Away as director of the U.S. Production, among others. Paige O'Hara voices the film's main protagonist, Belle. She also portrayed Angela in Enchanted. The setting of the film is somewhere in rural France in the 1700s. Character development was very well done, therefore solid 3-D characters.Another highlight was the computer animation, particularly the ballroom dance scene, which was impressively caricatured. The songs while a bit childish still are very nice. The score was also pleasing to the ears.The sound was very realistic and you could feel like you were actually there. The special effects were outstanding. The movie wasn't slow or fast, it was nearly perfectly well-paced and that's a lot given that the run time is only 84 minutes. It is the best film by Gary Trousdale and Kirk Wise. Quality wise, it's Kirk Wise's Spirited Away was significantly better. The plot was creative and quite unpredictable. The dialogue was also memorable. The movie flowed incredible scene to scene. The lighting and ambiance was superb. The animation was realistic and nothing looked out of the ordinary( in a good way). The costume design was intricate and realistic. It contributed positively towards the movie's overall tone. The set design was exceptional and it added to the movie experience. If the movie was filmed in an actual location, it would have to be well- chosen while there is hardly place where all of that is nearby. The background music was amazing. It worked incredibly well for the film.Ir was wasn't under-used or used in excess. The music was suspenseful and amusing, obviously in the correct places. All in all, the movie was fascinating and interesting, despite not being Disney's finest film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    All time favorite
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kristiscott111
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is an excellent movie for the whole family. I was already in Junior High when this came out but it quickly became one of my favorites. Even now with children of my own I love to pull this movie out and sit down with them to watch it. It starts out with beautiful scenery and wonderful singing. You will follow the life of an ordinary girl named Belle who has a love for reading. She lives alone with her father who is a but odd with his inventions and solitary lifestyle. He goes off to show his invention, he gets lost, finds a castle in the woods and lets himself in. Once inside he meets the enchanted occupants. Then the story really starts. The Beast discovers he has an unannounced visitor and thinks he is there torment him. So the father gets thrown in the tower. Belle has an unwelcoming admirer, the town bully. He tries to woo her, unsuccessfully. She runs out to the field to escape him and finds her fathers riderless horse barreling down on her. She then travels to the woods in search of her father. When she finds him at the castle she trades her life for his and the Beast releases her father and keeps her. Then the story begins.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Middle of Disney's Golden Age
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin6942
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Belle, whose father is imprisoned by the Beast, offers herself instead and discovers her captor to be an enchanted prince. This film was right in the middle of Disney's golden age, sandwiched between "Aladdin" and "Little Mermaid", pushing the boundaries of digital animation (just a few years before Pixar blew Disney out of the water). And the songs... definitely quite memorable. For me, Belle is the best princess Disney has had to date. While not an outright feminist role model like "Brave" was intended to be, she is a woman whose strengths are not in physical beauty, but in her intelligence. I think that was a great decision. Sure, she is not ugly, but the focus was on her being more than just "a prize to be won".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a beautiful young girl who come's in love with a beast.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nimra Rauf
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    the story is about a beautiful young village girl who lives with her old father who's been an inventor. Gaston a brute and rude handsome man on which all the village girls would die for is in love with belle,but after all he is belle would never accept his proposal but Gaston is steadfast to marry belle.one day Belle's father is off to another village to sell one of his invention in auction. but he come's in danger and runs into a castle which is forbidden but he is not known of it.when he gets cozy inside he discovers a scary,huge and rude beast who captures him inside.some how belle come to an awareness about the situation and runs off to help her father.the beast makes a deal with the girl that he would only release him in one condition that belle would be left there.As belle's warm heart agree's the condition her father is set off and belle is kept with the beast. the beast is in love with belle and steady and slow belle also comes in love with him, but the beast is captured in a spell and time is running out..the spell would only be broken only if he gets the KISS OF TRUE LOVE. Gaston comes aware of the situation and prepares an angry mob to attack the beast.later on when the beast is wounded belle kisses him and the spell is broken and the beast turns into a beautiful,young,handsome and charming prince. AND THEY GET MARRIED AND LIVE HAPPILY EVER AFTER!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One Of The Best Films Of The Disney Renaissance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    donuthaters12
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Disney has created a few classic princess fairy tale films in the past, so does Beauty and the Beast still matter? Simply yes. In comparison to the other princess films in the Disney Renaissance, this tops it but overall it isn't my favorite. The Disney Renaissance was film after film executed with brilliance and there are four films that would almost always be chosen either one as the best of the pack; The Little Mermaid, Beauty and the Beast, Aladdin, and The Lion King. I fall in the group that thinks Aladdin is the strongest film but either one are great enough to be number one. The story team for this film, did a great job as they meshed the melodramatic tale ,that is commonly found in the Disney princess films of the past, with modern dialogue and humor that appeals to the newer generation. With Disney animated films, I expect to see funny side characters. The difference between the old Disney and the new Disney is that somehow the most memorable element of the cast is the supporting cast rather than the main star. With Disney's old films, the main characters were the memorable ones for me. The film is an endearing, feel good, romantic story; with hilarious dialogue; that will appeal to all ages. This film was directed by Gary Tousdale and Kirk Wise, and this film was their debut in directing a Disney animated full length feature. What a great way to start, they created a film that is now regarded as a classic and was the first animated feature to be nominated with Best Picture at the Academy Awards. I think they took the best things about The Little Mermaid and added other things that work. Their next directorial efforts for Disney did not achieve close to what they have done for this, although those films did gain a cult following. I felt that The Little Mermaid and The Rescuers Down Under in comparison did not have that beautiful cinematography that Beauty and the Beast shows. It's cinematography is one of the main reasons why so much of this film work, whether it's the beautiful and dramatic lighting or the way the "camera" moves in a particular scene. An example would be the scene where both Belle and the Beast had a romantic dance in the ballroom; the scene was lit gorgeously and the iconic moment when the "camera" starts from the chandelier and glides its way down to them dancing. I felt that this aspect of the film should have been awarded with something. As expected from a Disney film, it is going to contain musical numbers in it. I don't usually mind it as it allows the animators to show off something daring and outrageous. I feel that the songs in this film are much more accessible and beautiful, like 'Be Our Guest' and 'Gaston', rather than something grand and iconic, Lion King, or as fun and daring, Aladdin. Be Our Guest and Gaston are definitely the favorite of mine. Be Our Guest due to it feeling like a Broadway musical and Gaston because it is so ridiculously egotistic that it is entertaining. Also pretty much who has seen the film, would remember the words "Tale as old as time/Song as old as rhyme". The soundtrack is wonderful but I don't feel any of it out trumps Aladdin's 'A Whole New World' or Lion King's 'Circle of Life'. The voices of the film fit well for the characters and certainly gives the characters a bit of personality. The animators did a wonderful job drawing the characters as they look very clean and attractive. The animators pushed hard on this film as large amounts of objects or people move in one shot, and each movement has a personality of its own. Cogsworth and Lumiere are one of the best character duos ever animated on Disney. The film is an icon of its own and definitely ranks in one of the top romance films of all time. Beauty and the Beast is a film that would be competing against films like Casablanca and Gone with the Wind in deciding which melodramatic romance film is the best. If you are looking for a great romantic film or a Disney film that hits all of its marks then this is that film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Tale as Old as Time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thelightbeamrider
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Beauty and the Beast is undoubtedly one of the best animated movies ever created. It is magical, enchanting, and moving in a way only classics are. We learn in the prologue that a selfish and unkind prince was cursed to be a beast. If he can learn to love and be loved in return, he will return to his original form. Belle is a smart, kind, and brave young woman living in a nearby town. She spends her days reading and rejecting advances from the local lout Gaston. When Belle's father gets lost one night, he wanders into the Beast's castle. The Beast accuses him of trespassing and throws him in the dungeon. Belle sets out to save her father and strikes up a deal with the Beast: if he lets her father go, she will stay in his place. The Beast and his servants, who have been turned into household objects, see Belle's arrival as a chance to finally break the spell. However, the Beast must first learn to be a gentleman. It's hard to describe how good this movie is. The songs, story, and characters all come together so perfectly.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gaston is not the villain and Belle's books are important
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    soudkovahana
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of my most beloved Disney movies. I love everything about this movie. Whether it's Belle's opening song, the absence of the villain or Mrs. Potts. Now I know you'll probably tell me that Gaston is the main villain in this story but I don't see him that way. Sure he's pretentious and cocky but that doesn't make him "the villain". Even when he rouse the village to go kill the Beast, yes I know he does it for his own selfish reasons, but he thinks it's just some beast, some animal, and he does not know the true identity of his. I don't want to excuse his actions, he's still very mean and selfish and very much hateful but I just don't see him as the evil villain like Voldemort or Darth Vader. You know what I mean? Anyway the story of the Beauty and the Beast is one of my favorites and it's been remade so many times, in so many versions but the original is only one. There is something about this story that makes me gasp every time I watch it. It's an excellent choice to show your children or grandchildren because it teaches them various of different lessons. Take the main character, Belle, for instance, who likes to read and is called "odd" for that behavior even though she's perfectly normal. You also have here Gaston, who thinks only about himself and who thinks that women should not read or even think. Beast on the other hand is from the very beginning enraptured by Belle's reading and gives her the entire library to read in. I think that Belle's books is an important motive in the movie and should not be alleviated. In other words the story has a lot to tell not only to the children but also to the adults that watch it with them.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The greatest film of the Disney Renaissance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MissSimonetta
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Disney Renaissance (1989-1999) was in many ways the studio's second golden age (the first being from 1937-1942), where experimentation and sublime artistry where the rule rather than the exception. Most of my generation grew up with these movies, so everyone has a favorite. The most popular seems to be The Lion King (1994), but for me the true masterpiece of the era is Beauty and the Beast (1991), arguably the most romantic Disney flick of them all. All the characters are perfect. I think the only cast I like better than this one is from Pinocchio (1940). Belle is an appealing heroine: she has a compassionate and dreamy nature, but she won't let herself be walked over by anyone (notice she doesn't fall for the Beast until he starts acting like a decent person). The Beast has excellent character development, evolving from a selfish brat into a kind, passionate fellow. The enchanted objects are both fun comic relief and interesting characters in their own right. Gaston is one of Disney's best villains, walking the fine line between comic and menacing with ease. BatB boasts the greatest soundtrack of all the Disney canon. Howard Ashman and Alan Mencken outdid themselves here. The choreography is magnificent too, especially the Busby Berkely inspired "Be Our Guest" and the superbly animated "Beauty and the Beast". The incidental music is lush and romantic, a pleasure to listen to in its own right. That's not to say the film doesn't have flaws. The animation on Belle goes off-model at times and the CG in the ballroom sequence is dated. And then there's that plot hole concerning how long Belle was at the castle. None of these issues diminish the greatness of the picture. This is one of the most beautiful and adult love stories ever put put on screen. Absolutely essential.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cookiemonster1234567
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I really like this movie. Its been my favorite movie since I was a little girl. Its a good story about integrity and true character. I mean our world is so messed up these days. Belle didn't care what the beast looked she only cared about his true character which is how all love is supposed to be but sadly its not how life is anymore. Its a beautiful story about what life really should be and what love should really be and mean inside and out. period that's it. People now chose who they 'love' by looks or the way someone is known to be or if that person is a popular person themselves with nobody else's help not one little bit. I really love the movie and I think that you would as well if you watch the movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My favorite
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dannimonai
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I used to watch this movie over and over again when I was little, it was always in the VCR. It was my favorite movie, it still is. I love the music, the animation, the characters and the story line. I identify with Belle the most, I feel as if she and I are one in the same. We love our family and a good book...or two. I have never succumbed to the pressure of society and I always stuck up for myself and others, just like she did. I learned to love people for who they are, not what they look like. This movie always encouraged me to do by best and be the best person I can be. Plus, the library Beast gives her is amazing and I would love it if it were mine!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beauty and the Beast is a 1991 American animated fantasy, romantic, and musical film distributed by Walt Disney Pictures and produced by Walt Disney Feature Animation.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Charith Rajeeva
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Beauty and the Beast Featuring the vocal talents of Robby Benson and Paige O'Hara with Angela Lansbury, David Ogden Stiers, Jerry Orbach and Richard White, the movie displays the story of a prince, whose punishment for his selfish and cruel ways, is turned into a beast and Belle, a woman who willing takes her father's place as prisoner of the castle. To become the prince again, the beast must love Belle and in turn she must love the beast or he will remain as he is forever. The film is directed by Gary Trousdale and Kirk Wise. Gary Trousdale has worked on the story of Oliver and Company( 1998 film), The Little Mermaid(1989 film) as storyboard artist,Aladdin( 1992 film) as pre- production story developer and CGI, The Lion King (1994 film) on the story,The Hunchback of Notre Dame(1996 film) as director, Madagascar(2005 film) as an additional storyboard artist, Flushed Away(2006 film) as an additional story artist, among many more. Meanwhile Kirk Wise also worked on Oliver and Company as an animating assistant and with the story, The Prince and the Pauper as a storyboard artist, The Lion King with additional story material, The Hunchback of Notre Dame as director, Spirited Away as director of the U.S. Production, among others. Paige O'Hara voices the film's main protagonist, Belle. She also portrayed Angela in Enchanted. The setting of the film is somewhere in rural France in the 1700s. Character development was very well done, therefore solid 3-D characters.Another highlight was the computer animation, particularly the ballroom dance scene, which was impressively caricatured. The songs while a bit childish still are very nice. The score was also pleasing to the ears.The sound was very realistic and you could feel like you were actually there. The special effects were outstanding. The movie wasn't slow or fast, it was nearly perfectly well-paced and that's a lot given that the run time is only 84 minutes. It is the best film by Gary Trousdale and Kirk Wise. Quality wise, it's Kirk Wise's Spirited Away was significantly better. The plot was creative and quite unpredictable. The dialogue was also memorable. The movie flowed incredible scene to scene. The lighting and ambiance was superb. The animation was realistic and nothing looked out of the ordinary( in a good way). The costume design was intricate and realistic. It contributed positively towards the movie's overall tone. The set design was exceptional and it added to the movie experience. If the movie was filmed in an actual location, it would have to be well- chosen while there is hardly place where all of that is nearby. The background music was amazing. It worked incredibly well for the film.Ir was wasn't under-used or used in excess. The music was suspenseful and amusing, obviously in the correct places. All in all, the movie was fascinating and interesting, despite not being Disney's finest film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    All time favorite
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kristiscott111
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is an excellent movie for the whole family. I was already in Junior High when this came out but it quickly became one of my favorites. Even now with children of my own I love to pull this movie out and sit down with them to watch it. It starts out with beautiful scenery and wonderful singing. You will follow the life of an ordinary girl named Belle who has a love for reading. She lives alone with her father who is a but odd with his inventions and solitary lifestyle. He goes off to show his invention, he gets lost, finds a castle in the woods and lets himself in. Once inside he meets the enchanted occupants. Then the story really starts. The Beast discovers he has an unannounced visitor and thinks he is there torment him. So the father gets thrown in the tower. Belle has an unwelcoming admirer, the town bully. He tries to woo her, unsuccessfully. She runs out to the field to escape him and finds her fathers riderless horse barreling down on her. She then travels to the woods in search of her father. When she finds him at the castle she trades her life for his and the Beast releases her father and keeps her. Then the story begins.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Middle of Disney's Golden Age
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin6942
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Belle, whose father is imprisoned by the Beast, offers herself instead and discovers her captor to be an enchanted prince. This film was right in the middle of Disney's golden age, sandwiched between "Aladdin" and "Little Mermaid", pushing the boundaries of digital animation (just a few years before Pixar blew Disney out of the water). And the songs... definitely quite memorable. For me, Belle is the best princess Disney has had to date. While not an outright feminist role model like "Brave" was intended to be, she is a woman whose strengths are not in physical beauty, but in her intelligence. I think that was a great decision. Sure, she is not ugly, but the focus was on her being more than just "a prize to be won".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a beautiful young girl who come's in love with a beast.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nimra Rauf
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    the story is about a beautiful young village girl who lives with her old father who's been an inventor. Gaston a brute and rude handsome man on which all the village girls would die for is in love with belle,but after all he is belle would never accept his proposal but Gaston is steadfast to marry belle.one day Belle's father is off to another village to sell one of his invention in auction. but he come's in danger and runs into a castle which is forbidden but he is not known of it.when he gets cozy inside he discovers a scary,huge and rude beast who captures him inside.some how belle come to an awareness about the situation and runs off to help her father.the beast makes a deal with the girl that he would only release him in one condition that belle would be left there.As belle's warm heart agree's the condition her father is set off and belle is kept with the beast. the beast is in love with belle and steady and slow belle also comes in love with him, but the beast is captured in a spell and time is running out..the spell would only be broken only if he gets the KISS OF TRUE LOVE. Gaston comes aware of the situation and prepares an angry mob to attack the beast.later on when the beast is wounded belle kisses him and the spell is broken and the beast turns into a beautiful,young,handsome and charming prince. AND THEY GET MARRIED AND LIVE HAPPILY EVER AFTER!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One Of The Best Films Of The Disney Renaissance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    donuthaters12
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Disney has created a few classic princess fairy tale films in the past, so does Beauty and the Beast still matter? Simply yes. In comparison to the other princess films in the Disney Renaissance, this tops it but overall it isn't my favorite. The Disney Renaissance was film after film executed with brilliance and there are four films that would almost always be chosen either one as the best of the pack; The Little Mermaid, Beauty and the Beast, Aladdin, and The Lion King. I fall in the group that thinks Aladdin is the strongest film but either one are great enough to be number one. The story team for this film, did a great job as they meshed the melodramatic tale ,that is commonly found in the Disney princess films of the past, with modern dialogue and humor that appeals to the newer generation. With Disney animated films, I expect to see funny side characters. The difference between the old Disney and the new Disney is that somehow the most memorable element of the cast is the supporting cast rather than the main star. With Disney's old films, the main characters were the memorable ones for me. The film is an endearing, feel good, romantic story; with hilarious dialogue; that will appeal to all ages. This film was directed by Gary Tousdale and Kirk Wise, and this film was their debut in directing a Disney animated full length feature. What a great way to start, they created a film that is now regarded as a classic and was the first animated feature to be nominated with Best Picture at the Academy Awards. I think they took the best things about The Little Mermaid and added other things that work. Their next directorial efforts for Disney did not achieve close to what they have done for this, although those films did gain a cult following. I felt that The Little Mermaid and The Rescuers Down Under in comparison did not have that beautiful cinematography that Beauty and the Beast shows. It's cinematography is one of the main reasons why so much of this film work, whether it's the beautiful and dramatic lighting or the way the "camera" moves in a particular scene. An example would be the scene where both Belle and the Beast had a romantic dance in the ballroom; the scene was lit gorgeously and the iconic moment when the "camera" starts from the chandelier and glides its way down to them dancing. I felt that this aspect of the film should have been awarded with something. As expected from a Disney film, it is going to contain musical numbers in it. I don't usually mind it as it allows the animators to show off something daring and outrageous. I feel that the songs in this film are much more accessible and beautiful, like 'Be Our Guest' and 'Gaston', rather than something grand and iconic, Lion King, or as fun and daring, Aladdin. Be Our Guest and Gaston are definitely the favorite of mine. Be Our Guest due to it feeling like a Broadway musical and Gaston because it is so ridiculously egotistic that it is entertaining. Also pretty much who has seen the film, would remember the words "Tale as old as time/Song as old as rhyme". The soundtrack is wonderful but I don't feel any of it out trumps Aladdin's 'A Whole New World' or Lion King's 'Circle of Life'. The voices of the film fit well for the characters and certainly gives the characters a bit of personality. The animators did a wonderful job drawing the characters as they look very clean and attractive. The animators pushed hard on this film as large amounts of objects or people move in one shot, and each movement has a personality of its own. Cogsworth and Lumiere are one of the best character duos ever animated on Disney. The film is an icon of its own and definitely ranks in one of the top romance films of all time. Beauty and the Beast is a film that would be competing against films like Casablanca and Gone with the Wind in deciding which melodramatic romance film is the best. If you are looking for a great romantic film or a Disney film that hits all of its marks then this is that film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Tale as Old as Time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thelightbeamrider
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Beauty and the Beast is undoubtedly one of the best animated movies ever created. It is magical, enchanting, and moving in a way only classics are. We learn in the prologue that a selfish and unkind prince was cursed to be a beast. If he can learn to love and be loved in return, he will return to his original form. Belle is a smart, kind, and brave young woman living in a nearby town. She spends her days reading and rejecting advances from the local lout Gaston. When Belle's father gets lost one night, he wanders into the Beast's castle. The Beast accuses him of trespassing and throws him in the dungeon. Belle sets out to save her father and strikes up a deal with the Beast: if he lets her father go, she will stay in his place. The Beast and his servants, who have been turned into household objects, see Belle's arrival as a chance to finally break the spell. However, the Beast must first learn to be a gentleman. It's hard to describe how good this movie is. The songs, story, and characters all come together so perfectly.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gaston is not the villain and Belle's books are important
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    soudkovahana
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of my most beloved Disney movies. I love everything about this movie. Whether it's Belle's opening song, the absence of the villain or Mrs. Potts. Now I know you'll probably tell me that Gaston is the main villain in this story but I don't see him that way. Sure he's pretentious and cocky but that doesn't make him "the villain". Even when he rouse the village to go kill the Beast, yes I know he does it for his own selfish reasons, but he thinks it's just some beast, some animal, and he does not know the true identity of his. I don't want to excuse his actions, he's still very mean and selfish and very much hateful but I just don't see him as the evil villain like Voldemort or Darth Vader. You know what I mean? Anyway the story of the Beauty and the Beast is one of my favorites and it's been remade so many times, in so many versions but the original is only one. There is something about this story that makes me gasp every time I watch it. It's an excellent choice to show your children or grandchildren because it teaches them various of different lessons. Take the main character, Belle, for instance, who likes to read and is called "odd" for that behavior even though she's perfectly normal. You also have here Gaston, who thinks only about himself and who thinks that women should not read or even think. Beast on the other hand is from the very beginning enraptured by Belle's reading and gives her the entire library to read in. I think that Belle's books is an important motive in the movie and should not be alleviated. In other words the story has a lot to tell not only to the children but also to the adults that watch it with them.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The greatest film of the Disney Renaissance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MissSimonetta
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Disney Renaissance (1989-1999) was in many ways the studio's second golden age (the first being from 1937-1942), where experimentation and sublime artistry where the rule rather than the exception. Most of my generation grew up with these movies, so everyone has a favorite. The most popular seems to be The Lion King (1994), but for me the true masterpiece of the era is Beauty and the Beast (1991), arguably the most romantic Disney flick of them all. All the characters are perfect. I think the only cast I like better than this one is from Pinocchio (1940). Belle is an appealing heroine: she has a compassionate and dreamy nature, but she won't let herself be walked over by anyone (notice she doesn't fall for the Beast until he starts acting like a decent person). The Beast has excellent character development, evolving from a selfish brat into a kind, passionate fellow. The enchanted objects are both fun comic relief and interesting characters in their own right. Gaston is one of Disney's best villains, walking the fine line between comic and menacing with ease. BatB boasts the greatest soundtrack of all the Disney canon. Howard Ashman and Alan Mencken outdid themselves here. The choreography is magnificent too, especially the Busby Berkely inspired "Be Our Guest" and the superbly animated "Beauty and the Beast". The incidental music is lush and romantic, a pleasure to listen to in its own right. That's not to say the film doesn't have flaws. The animation on Belle goes off-model at times and the CG in the ballroom sequence is dated. And then there's that plot hole concerning how long Belle was at the castle. None of these issues diminish the greatness of the picture. This is one of the most beautiful and adult love stories ever put put on screen. Absolutely essential.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cookiemonster1234567
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I really like this movie. Its been my favorite movie since I was a little girl. Its a good story about integrity and true character. I mean our world is so messed up these days. Belle didn't care what the beast looked she only cared about his true character which is how all love is supposed to be but sadly its not how life is anymore. Its a beautiful story about what life really should be and what love should really be and mean inside and out. period that's it. People now chose who they 'love' by looks or the way someone is known to be or if that person is a popular person themselves with nobody else's help not one little bit. I really love the movie and I think that you would as well if you watch the movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My favorite
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dannimonai
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I used to watch this movie over and over again when I was little, it was always in the VCR. It was my favorite movie, it still is. I love the music, the animation, the characters and the story line. I identify with Belle the most, I feel as if she and I are one in the same. We love our family and a good book...or two. I have never succumbed to the pressure of society and I always stuck up for myself and others, just like she did. I learned to love people for who they are, not what they look like. This movie always encouraged me to do by best and be the best person I can be. Plus, the library Beast gives her is amazing and I would love it if it were mine!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beauty and the Beast is a 1991 American animated fantasy, romantic, and musical film distributed by Walt Disney Pictures and produced by Walt Disney Feature Animation.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Charith Rajeeva
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Beauty and the Beast Featuring the vocal talents of Robby Benson and Paige O'Hara with Angela Lansbury, David Ogden Stiers, Jerry Orbach and Richard White, the movie displays the story of a prince, whose punishment for his selfish and cruel ways, is turned into a beast and Belle, a woman who willing takes her father's place as prisoner of the castle. To become the prince again, the beast must love Belle and in turn she must love the beast or he will remain as he is forever. The film is directed by Gary Trousdale and Kirk Wise. Gary Trousdale has worked on the story of Oliver and Company( 1998 film), The Little Mermaid(1989 film) as storyboard artist,Aladdin( 1992 film) as pre- production story developer and CGI, The Lion King (1994 film) on the story,The Hunchback of Notre Dame(1996 film) as director, Madagascar(2005 film) as an additional storyboard artist, Flushed Away(2006 film) as an additional story artist, among many more. Meanwhile Kirk Wise also worked on Oliver and Company as an animating assistant and with the story, The Prince and the Pauper as a storyboard artist, The Lion King with additional story material, The Hunchback of Notre Dame as director, Spirited Away as director of the U.S. Production, among others. Paige O'Hara voices the film's main protagonist, Belle. She also portrayed Angela in Enchanted. The setting of the film is somewhere in rural France in the 1700s. Character development was very well done, therefore solid 3-D characters.Another highlight was the computer animation, particularly the ballroom dance scene, which was impressively caricatured. The songs while a bit childish still are very nice. The score was also pleasing to the ears.The sound was very realistic and you could feel like you were actually there. The special effects were outstanding. The movie wasn't slow or fast, it was nearly perfectly well-paced and that's a lot given that the run time is only 84 minutes. It is the best film by Gary Trousdale and Kirk Wise. Quality wise, it's Kirk Wise's Spirited Away was significantly better. The plot was creative and quite unpredictable. The dialogue was also memorable. The movie flowed incredible scene to scene. The lighting and ambiance was superb. The animation was realistic and nothing looked out of the ordinary( in a good way). The costume design was intricate and realistic. It contributed positively towards the movie's overall tone. The set design was exceptional and it added to the movie experience. If the movie was filmed in an actual location, it would have to be well- chosen while there is hardly place where all of that is nearby. The background music was amazing. It worked incredibly well for the film.Ir was wasn't under-used or used in excess. The music was suspenseful and amusing, obviously in the correct places. All in all, the movie was fascinating and interesting, despite not being Disney's finest film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    All time favorite
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kristiscott111
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is an excellent movie for the whole family. I was already in Junior High when this came out but it quickly became one of my favorites. Even now with children of my own I love to pull this movie out and sit down with them to watch it. It starts out with beautiful scenery and wonderful singing. You will follow the life of an ordinary girl named Belle who has a love for reading. She lives alone with her father who is a but odd with his inventions and solitary lifestyle. He goes off to show his invention, he gets lost, finds a castle in the woods and lets himself in. Once inside he meets the enchanted occupants. Then the story really starts. The Beast discovers he has an unannounced visitor and thinks he is there torment him. So the father gets thrown in the tower. Belle has an unwelcoming admirer, the town bully. He tries to woo her, unsuccessfully. She runs out to the field to escape him and finds her fathers riderless horse barreling down on her. She then travels to the woods in search of her father. When she finds him at the castle she trades her life for his and the Beast releases her father and keeps her. Then the story begins.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Middle of Disney's Golden Age
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin6942
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Belle, whose father is imprisoned by the Beast, offers herself instead and discovers her captor to be an enchanted prince. This film was right in the middle of Disney's golden age, sandwiched between "Aladdin" and "Little Mermaid", pushing the boundaries of digital animation (just a few years before Pixar blew Disney out of the water). And the songs... definitely quite memorable. For me, Belle is the best princess Disney has had to date. While not an outright feminist role model like "Brave" was intended to be, she is a woman whose strengths are not in physical beauty, but in her intelligence. I think that was a great decision. Sure, she is not ugly, but the focus was on her being more than just "a prize to be won".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a beautiful young girl who come's in love with a beast.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nimra Rauf
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    the story is about a beautiful young village girl who lives with her old father who's been an inventor. Gaston a brute and rude handsome man on which all the village girls would die for is in love with belle,but after all he is belle would never accept his proposal but Gaston is steadfast to marry belle.one day Belle's father is off to another village to sell one of his invention in auction. but he come's in danger and runs into a castle which is forbidden but he is not known of it.when he gets cozy inside he discovers a scary,huge and rude beast who captures him inside.some how belle come to an awareness about the situation and runs off to help her father.the beast makes a deal with the girl that he would only release him in one condition that belle would be left there.As belle's warm heart agree's the condition her father is set off and belle is kept with the beast. the beast is in love with belle and steady and slow belle also comes in love with him, but the beast is captured in a spell and time is running out..the spell would only be broken only if he gets the KISS OF TRUE LOVE. Gaston comes aware of the situation and prepares an angry mob to attack the beast.later on when the beast is wounded belle kisses him and the spell is broken and the beast turns into a beautiful,young,handsome and charming prince. AND THEY GET MARRIED AND LIVE HAPPILY EVER AFTER!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One Of The Best Films Of The Disney Renaissance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    donuthaters12
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Disney has created a few classic princess fairy tale films in the past, so does Beauty and the Beast still matter? Simply yes. In comparison to the other princess films in the Disney Renaissance, this tops it but overall it isn't my favorite. The Disney Renaissance was film after film executed with brilliance and there are four films that would almost always be chosen either one as the best of the pack; The Little Mermaid, Beauty and the Beast, Aladdin, and The Lion King. I fall in the group that thinks Aladdin is the strongest film but either one are great enough to be number one. The story team for this film, did a great job as they meshed the melodramatic tale ,that is commonly found in the Disney princess films of the past, with modern dialogue and humor that appeals to the newer generation. With Disney animated films, I expect to see funny side characters. The difference between the old Disney and the new Disney is that somehow the most memorable element of the cast is the supporting cast rather than the main star. With Disney's old films, the main characters were the memorable ones for me. The film is an endearing, feel good, romantic story; with hilarious dialogue; that will appeal to all ages. This film was directed by Gary Tousdale and Kirk Wise, and this film was their debut in directing a Disney animated full length feature. What a great way to start, they created a film that is now regarded as a classic and was the first animated feature to be nominated with Best Picture at the Academy Awards. I think they took the best things about The Little Mermaid and added other things that work. Their next directorial efforts for Disney did not achieve close to what they have done for this, although those films did gain a cult following. I felt that The Little Mermaid and The Rescuers Down Under in comparison did not have that beautiful cinematography that Beauty and the Beast shows. It's cinematography is one of the main reasons why so much of this film work, whether it's the beautiful and dramatic lighting or the way the "camera" moves in a particular scene. An example would be the scene where both Belle and the Beast had a romantic dance in the ballroom; the scene was lit gorgeously and the iconic moment when the "camera" starts from the chandelier and glides its way down to them dancing. I felt that this aspect of the film should have been awarded with something. As expected from a Disney film, it is going to contain musical numbers in it. I don't usually mind it as it allows the animators to show off something daring and outrageous. I feel that the songs in this film are much more accessible and beautiful, like 'Be Our Guest' and 'Gaston', rather than something grand and iconic, Lion King, or as fun and daring, Aladdin. Be Our Guest and Gaston are definitely the favorite of mine. Be Our Guest due to it feeling like a Broadway musical and Gaston because it is so ridiculously egotistic that it is entertaining. Also pretty much who has seen the film, would remember the words "Tale as old as time/Song as old as rhyme". The soundtrack is wonderful but I don't feel any of it out trumps Aladdin's 'A Whole New World' or Lion King's 'Circle of Life'. The voices of the film fit well for the characters and certainly gives the characters a bit of personality. The animators did a wonderful job drawing the characters as they look very clean and attractive. The animators pushed hard on this film as large amounts of objects or people move in one shot, and each movement has a personality of its own. Cogsworth and Lumiere are one of the best character duos ever animated on Disney. The film is an icon of its own and definitely ranks in one of the top romance films of all time. Beauty and the Beast is a film that would be competing against films like Casablanca and Gone with the Wind in deciding which melodramatic romance film is the best. If you are looking for a great romantic film or a Disney film that hits all of its marks then this is that film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Tale as Old as Time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thelightbeamrider
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Beauty and the Beast is undoubtedly one of the best animated movies ever created. It is magical, enchanting, and moving in a way only classics are. We learn in the prologue that a selfish and unkind prince was cursed to be a beast. If he can learn to love and be loved in return, he will return to his original form. Belle is a smart, kind, and brave young woman living in a nearby town. She spends her days reading and rejecting advances from the local lout Gaston. When Belle's father gets lost one night, he wanders into the Beast's castle. The Beast accuses him of trespassing and throws him in the dungeon. Belle sets out to save her father and strikes up a deal with the Beast: if he lets her father go, she will stay in his place. The Beast and his servants, who have been turned into household objects, see Belle's arrival as a chance to finally break the spell. However, the Beast must first learn to be a gentleman. It's hard to describe how good this movie is. The songs, story, and characters all come together so perfectly.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gaston is not the villain and Belle's books are important
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    soudkovahana
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of my most beloved Disney movies. I love everything about this movie. Whether it's Belle's opening song, the absence of the villain or Mrs. Potts. Now I know you'll probably tell me that Gaston is the main villain in this story but I don't see him that way. Sure he's pretentious and cocky but that doesn't make him "the villain". Even when he rouse the village to go kill the Beast, yes I know he does it for his own selfish reasons, but he thinks it's just some beast, some animal, and he does not know the true identity of his. I don't want to excuse his actions, he's still very mean and selfish and very much hateful but I just don't see him as the evil villain like Voldemort or Darth Vader. You know what I mean? Anyway the story of the Beauty and the Beast is one of my favorites and it's been remade so many times, in so many versions but the original is only one. There is something about this story that makes me gasp every time I watch it. It's an excellent choice to show your children or grandchildren because it teaches them various of different lessons. Take the main character, Belle, for instance, who likes to read and is called "odd" for that behavior even though she's perfectly normal. You also have here Gaston, who thinks only about himself and who thinks that women should not read or even think. Beast on the other hand is from the very beginning enraptured by Belle's reading and gives her the entire library to read in. I think that Belle's books is an important motive in the movie and should not be alleviated. In other words the story has a lot to tell not only to the children but also to the adults that watch it with them.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The greatest film of the Disney Renaissance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MissSimonetta
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Disney Renaissance (1989-1999) was in many ways the studio's second golden age (the first being from 1937-1942), where experimentation and sublime artistry where the rule rather than the exception. Most of my generation grew up with these movies, so everyone has a favorite. The most popular seems to be The Lion King (1994), but for me the true masterpiece of the era is Beauty and the Beast (1991), arguably the most romantic Disney flick of them all. All the characters are perfect. I think the only cast I like better than this one is from Pinocchio (1940). Belle is an appealing heroine: she has a compassionate and dreamy nature, but she won't let herself be walked over by anyone (notice she doesn't fall for the Beast until he starts acting like a decent person). The Beast has excellent character development, evolving from a selfish brat into a kind, passionate fellow. The enchanted objects are both fun comic relief and interesting characters in their own right. Gaston is one of Disney's best villains, walking the fine line between comic and menacing with ease. BatB boasts the greatest soundtrack of all the Disney canon. Howard Ashman and Alan Mencken outdid themselves here. The choreography is magnificent too, especially the Busby Berkely inspired "Be Our Guest" and the superbly animated "Beauty and the Beast". The incidental music is lush and romantic, a pleasure to listen to in its own right. That's not to say the film doesn't have flaws. The animation on Belle goes off-model at times and the CG in the ballroom sequence is dated. And then there's that plot hole concerning how long Belle was at the castle. None of these issues diminish the greatness of the picture. This is one of the most beautiful and adult love stories ever put put on screen. Absolutely essential.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cookiemonster1234567
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I really like this movie. Its been my favorite movie since I was a little girl. Its a good story about integrity and true character. I mean our world is so messed up these days. Belle didn't care what the beast looked she only cared about his true character which is how all love is supposed to be but sadly its not how life is anymore. Its a beautiful story about what life really should be and what love should really be and mean inside and out. period that's it. People now chose who they 'love' by looks or the way someone is known to be or if that person is a popular person themselves with nobody else's help not one little bit. I really love the movie and I think that you would as well if you watch the movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My favorite
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dannimonai
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I used to watch this movie over and over again when I was little, it was always in the VCR. It was my favorite movie, it still is. I love the music, the animation, the characters and the story line. I identify with Belle the most, I feel as if she and I are one in the same. We love our family and a good book...or two. I have never succumbed to the pressure of society and I always stuck up for myself and others, just like she did. I learned to love people for who they are, not what they look like. This movie always encouraged me to do by best and be the best person I can be. Plus, the library Beast gives her is amazing and I would love it if it were mine!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beauty and the Beast is a 1991 American animated fantasy, romantic, and musical film distributed by Walt Disney Pictures and produced by Walt Disney Feature Animation.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Charith Rajeeva
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Beauty and the Beast Featuring the vocal talents of Robby Benson and Paige O'Hara with Angela Lansbury, David Ogden Stiers, Jerry Orbach and Richard White, the movie displays the story of a prince, whose punishment for his selfish and cruel ways, is turned into a beast and Belle, a woman who willing takes her father's place as prisoner of the castle. To become the prince again, the beast must love Belle and in turn she must love the beast or he will remain as he is forever. The film is directed by Gary Trousdale and Kirk Wise. Gary Trousdale has worked on the story of Oliver and Company( 1998 film), The Little Mermaid(1989 film) as storyboard artist,Aladdin( 1992 film) as pre- production story developer and CGI, The Lion King (1994 film) on the story,The Hunchback of Notre Dame(1996 film) as director, Madagascar(2005 film) as an additional storyboard artist, Flushed Away(2006 film) as an additional story artist, among many more. Meanwhile Kirk Wise also worked on Oliver and Company as an animating assistant and with the story, The Prince and the Pauper as a storyboard artist, The Lion King with additional story material, The Hunchback of Notre Dame as director, Spirited Away as director of the U.S. Production, among others. Paige O'Hara voices the film's main protagonist, Belle. She also portrayed Angela in Enchanted. The setting of the film is somewhere in rural France in the 1700s. Character development was very well done, therefore solid 3-D characters.Another highlight was the computer animation, particularly the ballroom dance scene, which was impressively caricatured. The songs while a bit childish still are very nice. The score was also pleasing to the ears.The sound was very realistic and you could feel like you were actually there. The special effects were outstanding. The movie wasn't slow or fast, it was nearly perfectly well-paced and that's a lot given that the run time is only 84 minutes. It is the best film by Gary Trousdale and Kirk Wise. Quality wise, it's Kirk Wise's Spirited Away was significantly better. The plot was creative and quite unpredictable. The dialogue was also memorable. The movie flowed incredible scene to scene. The lighting and ambiance was superb. The animation was realistic and nothing looked out of the ordinary( in a good way). The costume design was intricate and realistic. It contributed positively towards the movie's overall tone. The set design was exceptional and it added to the movie experience. If the movie was filmed in an actual location, it would have to be well- chosen while there is hardly place where all of that is nearby. The background music was amazing. It worked incredibly well for the film.Ir was wasn't under-used or used in excess. The music was suspenseful and amusing, obviously in the correct places. All in all, the movie was fascinating and interesting, despite not being Disney's finest film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    All time favorite
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kristiscott111
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is an excellent movie for the whole family. I was already in Junior High when this came out but it quickly became one of my favorites. Even now with children of my own I love to pull this movie out and sit down with them to watch it. It starts out with beautiful scenery and wonderful singing. You will follow the life of an ordinary girl named Belle who has a love for reading. She lives alone with her father who is a but odd with his inventions and solitary lifestyle. He goes off to show his invention, he gets lost, finds a castle in the woods and lets himself in. Once inside he meets the enchanted occupants. Then the story really starts. The Beast discovers he has an unannounced visitor and thinks he is there torment him. So the father gets thrown in the tower. Belle has an unwelcoming admirer, the town bully. He tries to woo her, unsuccessfully. She runs out to the field to escape him and finds her fathers riderless horse barreling down on her. She then travels to the woods in search of her father. When she finds him at the castle she trades her life for his and the Beast releases her father and keeps her. Then the story begins.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Middle of Disney's Golden Age
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin6942
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Belle, whose father is imprisoned by the Beast, offers herself instead and discovers her captor to be an enchanted prince. This film was right in the middle of Disney's golden age, sandwiched between "Aladdin" and "Little Mermaid", pushing the boundaries of digital animation (just a few years before Pixar blew Disney out of the water). And the songs... definitely quite memorable. For me, Belle is the best princess Disney has had to date. While not an outright feminist role model like "Brave" was intended to be, she is a woman whose strengths are not in physical beauty, but in her intelligence. I think that was a great decision. Sure, she is not ugly, but the focus was on her being more than just "a prize to be won".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a beautiful young girl who come's in love with a beast.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nimra Rauf
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    the story is about a beautiful young village girl who lives with her old father who's been an inventor. Gaston a brute and rude handsome man on which all the village girls would die for is in love with belle,but after all he is belle would never accept his proposal but Gaston is steadfast to marry belle.one day Belle's father is off to another village to sell one of his invention in auction. but he come's in danger and runs into a castle which is forbidden but he is not known of it.when he gets cozy inside he discovers a scary,huge and rude beast who captures him inside.some how belle come to an awareness about the situation and runs off to help her father.the beast makes a deal with the girl that he would only release him in one condition that belle would be left there.As belle's warm heart agree's the condition her father is set off and belle is kept with the beast. the beast is in love with belle and steady and slow belle also comes in love with him, but the beast is captured in a spell and time is running out..the spell would only be broken only if he gets the KISS OF TRUE LOVE. Gaston comes aware of the situation and prepares an angry mob to attack the beast.later on when the beast is wounded belle kisses him and the spell is broken and the beast turns into a beautiful,young,handsome and charming prince. AND THEY GET MARRIED AND LIVE HAPPILY EVER AFTER!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One Of The Best Films Of The Disney Renaissance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    donuthaters12
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Disney has created a few classic princess fairy tale films in the past, so does Beauty and the Beast still matter? Simply yes. In comparison to the other princess films in the Disney Renaissance, this tops it but overall it isn't my favorite. The Disney Renaissance was film after film executed with brilliance and there are four films that would almost always be chosen either one as the best of the pack; The Little Mermaid, Beauty and the Beast, Aladdin, and The Lion King. I fall in the group that thinks Aladdin is the strongest film but either one are great enough to be number one. The story team for this film, did a great job as they meshed the melodramatic tale ,that is commonly found in the Disney princess films of the past, with modern dialogue and humor that appeals to the newer generation. With Disney animated films, I expect to see funny side characters. The difference between the old Disney and the new Disney is that somehow the most memorable element of the cast is the supporting cast rather than the main star. With Disney's old films, the main characters were the memorable ones for me. The film is an endearing, feel good, romantic story; with hilarious dialogue; that will appeal to all ages. This film was directed by Gary Tousdale and Kirk Wise, and this film was their debut in directing a Disney animated full length feature. What a great way to start, they created a film that is now regarded as a classic and was the first animated feature to be nominated with Best Picture at the Academy Awards. I think they took the best things about The Little Mermaid and added other things that work. Their next directorial efforts for Disney did not achieve close to what they have done for this, although those films did gain a cult following. I felt that The Little Mermaid and The Rescuers Down Under in comparison did not have that beautiful cinematography that Beauty and the Beast shows. It's cinematography is one of the main reasons why so much of this film work, whether it's the beautiful and dramatic lighting or the way the "camera" moves in a particular scene. An example would be the scene where both Belle and the Beast had a romantic dance in the ballroom; the scene was lit gorgeously and the iconic moment when the "camera" starts from the chandelier and glides its way down to them dancing. I felt that this aspect of the film should have been awarded with something. As expected from a Disney film, it is going to contain musical numbers in it. I don't usually mind it as it allows the animators to show off something daring and outrageous. I feel that the songs in this film are much more accessible and beautiful, like 'Be Our Guest' and 'Gaston', rather than something grand and iconic, Lion King, or as fun and daring, Aladdin. Be Our Guest and Gaston are definitely the favorite of mine. Be Our Guest due to it feeling like a Broadway musical and Gaston because it is so ridiculously egotistic that it is entertaining. Also pretty much who has seen the film, would remember the words "Tale as old as time/Song as old as rhyme". The soundtrack is wonderful but I don't feel any of it out trumps Aladdin's 'A Whole New World' or Lion King's 'Circle of Life'. The voices of the film fit well for the characters and certainly gives the characters a bit of personality. The animators did a wonderful job drawing the characters as they look very clean and attractive. The animators pushed hard on this film as large amounts of objects or people move in one shot, and each movement has a personality of its own. Cogsworth and Lumiere are one of the best character duos ever animated on Disney. The film is an icon of its own and definitely ranks in one of the top romance films of all time. Beauty and the Beast is a film that would be competing against films like Casablanca and Gone with the Wind in deciding which melodramatic romance film is the best. If you are looking for a great romantic film or a Disney film that hits all of its marks then this is that film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Tale as Old as Time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thelightbeamrider
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Beauty and the Beast is undoubtedly one of the best animated movies ever created. It is magical, enchanting, and moving in a way only classics are. We learn in the prologue that a selfish and unkind prince was cursed to be a beast. If he can learn to love and be loved in return, he will return to his original form. Belle is a smart, kind, and brave young woman living in a nearby town. She spends her days reading and rejecting advances from the local lout Gaston. When Belle's father gets lost one night, he wanders into the Beast's castle. The Beast accuses him of trespassing and throws him in the dungeon. Belle sets out to save her father and strikes up a deal with the Beast: if he lets her father go, she will stay in his place. The Beast and his servants, who have been turned into household objects, see Belle's arrival as a chance to finally break the spell. However, the Beast must first learn to be a gentleman. It's hard to describe how good this movie is. The songs, story, and characters all come together so perfectly.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gaston is not the villain and Belle's books are important
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    soudkovahana
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of my most beloved Disney movies. I love everything about this movie. Whether it's Belle's opening song, the absence of the villain or Mrs. Potts. Now I know you'll probably tell me that Gaston is the main villain in this story but I don't see him that way. Sure he's pretentious and cocky but that doesn't make him "the villain". Even when he rouse the village to go kill the Beast, yes I know he does it for his own selfish reasons, but he thinks it's just some beast, some animal, and he does not know the true identity of his. I don't want to excuse his actions, he's still very mean and selfish and very much hateful but I just don't see him as the evil villain like Voldemort or Darth Vader. You know what I mean? Anyway the story of the Beauty and the Beast is one of my favorites and it's been remade so many times, in so many versions but the original is only one. There is something about this story that makes me gasp every time I watch it. It's an excellent choice to show your children or grandchildren because it teaches them various of different lessons. Take the main character, Belle, for instance, who likes to read and is called "odd" for that behavior even though she's perfectly normal. You also have here Gaston, who thinks only about himself and who thinks that women should not read or even think. Beast on the other hand is from the very beginning enraptured by Belle's reading and gives her the entire library to read in. I think that Belle's books is an important motive in the movie and should not be alleviated. In other words the story has a lot to tell not only to the children but also to the adults that watch it with them.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The greatest film of the Disney Renaissance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MissSimonetta
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Disney Renaissance (1989-1999) was in many ways the studio's second golden age (the first being from 1937-1942), where experimentation and sublime artistry where the rule rather than the exception. Most of my generation grew up with these movies, so everyone has a favorite. The most popular seems to be The Lion King (1994), but for me the true masterpiece of the era is Beauty and the Beast (1991), arguably the most romantic Disney flick of them all. All the characters are perfect. I think the only cast I like better than this one is from Pinocchio (1940). Belle is an appealing heroine: she has a compassionate and dreamy nature, but she won't let herself be walked over by anyone (notice she doesn't fall for the Beast until he starts acting like a decent person). The Beast has excellent character development, evolving from a selfish brat into a kind, passionate fellow. The enchanted objects are both fun comic relief and interesting characters in their own right. Gaston is one of Disney's best villains, walking the fine line between comic and menacing with ease. BatB boasts the greatest soundtrack of all the Disney canon. Howard Ashman and Alan Mencken outdid themselves here. The choreography is magnificent too, especially the Busby Berkely inspired "Be Our Guest" and the superbly animated "Beauty and the Beast". The incidental music is lush and romantic, a pleasure to listen to in its own right. That's not to say the film doesn't have flaws. The animation on Belle goes off-model at times and the CG in the ballroom sequence is dated. And then there's that plot hole concerning how long Belle was at the castle. None of these issues diminish the greatness of the picture. This is one of the most beautiful and adult love stories ever put put on screen. Absolutely essential.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cookiemonster1234567
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I really like this movie. Its been my favorite movie since I was a little girl. Its a good story about integrity and true character. I mean our world is so messed up these days. Belle didn't care what the beast looked she only cared about his true character which is how all love is supposed to be but sadly its not how life is anymore. Its a beautiful story about what life really should be and what love should really be and mean inside and out. period that's it. People now chose who they 'love' by looks or the way someone is known to be or if that person is a popular person themselves with nobody else's help not one little bit. I really love the movie and I think that you would as well if you watch the movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My favorite
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dannimonai
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I used to watch this movie over and over again when I was little, it was always in the VCR. It was my favorite movie, it still is. I love the music, the animation, the characters and the story line. I identify with Belle the most, I feel as if she and I are one in the same. We love our family and a good book...or two. I have never succumbed to the pressure of society and I always stuck up for myself and others, just like she did. I learned to love people for who they are, not what they look like. This movie always encouraged me to do by best and be the best person I can be. Plus, the library Beast gives her is amazing and I would love it if it were mine!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beauty and the Beast is a 1991 American animated fantasy, romantic, and musical film distributed by Walt Disney Pictures and produced by Walt Disney Feature Animation.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Charith Rajeeva
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Beauty and the Beast Featuring the vocal talents of Robby Benson and Paige O'Hara with Angela Lansbury, David Ogden Stiers, Jerry Orbach and Richard White, the movie displays the story of a prince, whose punishment for his selfish and cruel ways, is turned into a beast and Belle, a woman who willing takes her father's place as prisoner of the castle. To become the prince again, the beast must love Belle and in turn she must love the beast or he will remain as he is forever. The film is directed by Gary Trousdale and Kirk Wise. Gary Trousdale has worked on the story of Oliver and Company( 1998 film), The Little Mermaid(1989 film) as storyboard artist,Aladdin( 1992 film) as pre- production story developer and CGI, The Lion King (1994 film) on the story,The Hunchback of Notre Dame(1996 film) as director, Madagascar(2005 film) as an additional storyboard artist, Flushed Away(2006 film) as an additional story artist, among many more. Meanwhile Kirk Wise also worked on Oliver and Company as an animating assistant and with the story, The Prince and the Pauper as a storyboard artist, The Lion King with additional story material, The Hunchback of Notre Dame as director, Spirited Away as director of the U.S. Production, among others. Paige O'Hara voices the film's main protagonist, Belle. She also portrayed Angela in Enchanted. The setting of the film is somewhere in rural France in the 1700s. Character development was very well done, therefore solid 3-D characters.Another highlight was the computer animation, particularly the ballroom dance scene, which was impressively caricatured. The songs while a bit childish still are very nice. The score was also pleasing to the ears.The sound was very realistic and you could feel like you were actually there. The special effects were outstanding. The movie wasn't slow or fast, it was nearly perfectly well-paced and that's a lot given that the run time is only 84 minutes. It is the best film by Gary Trousdale and Kirk Wise. Quality wise, it's Kirk Wise's Spirited Away was significantly better. The plot was creative and quite unpredictable. The dialogue was also memorable. The movie flowed incredible scene to scene. The lighting and ambiance was superb. The animation was realistic and nothing looked out of the ordinary( in a good way). The costume design was intricate and realistic. It contributed positively towards the movie's overall tone. The set design was exceptional and it added to the movie experience. If the movie was filmed in an actual location, it would have to be well- chosen while there is hardly place where all of that is nearby. The background music was amazing. It worked incredibly well for the film.Ir was wasn't under-used or used in excess. The music was suspenseful and amusing, obviously in the correct places. All in all, the movie was fascinating and interesting, despite not being Disney's finest film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    All time favorite
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kristiscott111
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is an excellent movie for the whole family. I was already in Junior High when this came out but it quickly became one of my favorites. Even now with children of my own I love to pull this movie out and sit down with them to watch it. It starts out with beautiful scenery and wonderful singing. You will follow the life of an ordinary girl named Belle who has a love for reading. She lives alone with her father who is a but odd with his inventions and solitary lifestyle. He goes off to show his invention, he gets lost, finds a castle in the woods and lets himself in. Once inside he meets the enchanted occupants. Then the story really starts. The Beast discovers he has an unannounced visitor and thinks he is there torment him. So the father gets thrown in the tower. Belle has an unwelcoming admirer, the town bully. He tries to woo her, unsuccessfully. She runs out to the field to escape him and finds her fathers riderless horse barreling down on her. She then travels to the woods in search of her father. When she finds him at the castle she trades her life for his and the Beast releases her father and keeps her. Then the story begins.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Middle of Disney's Golden Age
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin6942
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Belle, whose father is imprisoned by the Beast, offers herself instead and discovers her captor to be an enchanted prince. This film was right in the middle of Disney's golden age, sandwiched between "Aladdin" and "Little Mermaid", pushing the boundaries of digital animation (just a few years before Pixar blew Disney out of the water). And the songs... definitely quite memorable. For me, Belle is the best princess Disney has had to date. While not an outright feminist role model like "Brave" was intended to be, she is a woman whose strengths are not in physical beauty, but in her intelligence. I think that was a great decision. Sure, she is not ugly, but the focus was on her being more than just "a prize to be won".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a beautiful young girl who come's in love with a beast.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nimra Rauf
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    the story is about a beautiful young village girl who lives with her old father who's been an inventor. Gaston a brute and rude handsome man on which all the village girls would die for is in love with belle,but after all he is belle would never accept his proposal but Gaston is steadfast to marry belle.one day Belle's father is off to another village to sell one of his invention in auction. but he come's in danger and runs into a castle which is forbidden but he is not known of it.when he gets cozy inside he discovers a scary,huge and rude beast who captures him inside.some how belle come to an awareness about the situation and runs off to help her father.the beast makes a deal with the girl that he would only release him in one condition that belle would be left there.As belle's warm heart agree's the condition her father is set off and belle is kept with the beast. the beast is in love with belle and steady and slow belle also comes in love with him, but the beast is captured in a spell and time is running out..the spell would only be broken only if he gets the KISS OF TRUE LOVE. Gaston comes aware of the situation and prepares an angry mob to attack the beast.later on when the beast is wounded belle kisses him and the spell is broken and the beast turns into a beautiful,young,handsome and charming prince. AND THEY GET MARRIED AND LIVE HAPPILY EVER AFTER!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One Of The Best Films Of The Disney Renaissance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    donuthaters12
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Disney has created a few classic princess fairy tale films in the past, so does Beauty and the Beast still matter? Simply yes. In comparison to the other princess films in the Disney Renaissance, this tops it but overall it isn't my favorite. The Disney Renaissance was film after film executed with brilliance and there are four films that would almost always be chosen either one as the best of the pack; The Little Mermaid, Beauty and the Beast, Aladdin, and The Lion King. I fall in the group that thinks Aladdin is the strongest film but either one are great enough to be number one. The story team for this film, did a great job as they meshed the melodramatic tale ,that is commonly found in the Disney princess films of the past, with modern dialogue and humor that appeals to the newer generation. With Disney animated films, I expect to see funny side characters. The difference between the old Disney and the new Disney is that somehow the most memorable element of the cast is the supporting cast rather than the main star. With Disney's old films, the main characters were the memorable ones for me. The film is an endearing, feel good, romantic story; with hilarious dialogue; that will appeal to all ages. This film was directed by Gary Tousdale and Kirk Wise, and this film was their debut in directing a Disney animated full length feature. What a great way to start, they created a film that is now regarded as a classic and was the first animated feature to be nominated with Best Picture at the Academy Awards. I think they took the best things about The Little Mermaid and added other things that work. Their next directorial efforts for Disney did not achieve close to what they have done for this, although those films did gain a cult following. I felt that The Little Mermaid and The Rescuers Down Under in comparison did not have that beautiful cinematography that Beauty and the Beast shows. It's cinematography is one of the main reasons why so much of this film work, whether it's the beautiful and dramatic lighting or the way the "camera" moves in a particular scene. An example would be the scene where both Belle and the Beast had a romantic dance in the ballroom; the scene was lit gorgeously and the iconic moment when the "camera" starts from the chandelier and glides its way down to them dancing. I felt that this aspect of the film should have been awarded with something. As expected from a Disney film, it is going to contain musical numbers in it. I don't usually mind it as it allows the animators to show off something daring and outrageous. I feel that the songs in this film are much more accessible and beautiful, like 'Be Our Guest' and 'Gaston', rather than something grand and iconic, Lion King, or as fun and daring, Aladdin. Be Our Guest and Gaston are definitely the favorite of mine. Be Our Guest due to it feeling like a Broadway musical and Gaston because it is so ridiculously egotistic that it is entertaining. Also pretty much who has seen the film, would remember the words "Tale as old as time/Song as old as rhyme". The soundtrack is wonderful but I don't feel any of it out trumps Aladdin's 'A Whole New World' or Lion King's 'Circle of Life'. The voices of the film fit well for the characters and certainly gives the characters a bit of personality. The animators did a wonderful job drawing the characters as they look very clean and attractive. The animators pushed hard on this film as large amounts of objects or people move in one shot, and each movement has a personality of its own. Cogsworth and Lumiere are one of the best character duos ever animated on Disney. The film is an icon of its own and definitely ranks in one of the top romance films of all time. Beauty and the Beast is a film that would be competing against films like Casablanca and Gone with the Wind in deciding which melodramatic romance film is the best. If you are looking for a great romantic film or a Disney film that hits all of its marks then this is that film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Tale as Old as Time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thelightbeamrider
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Beauty and the Beast is undoubtedly one of the best animated movies ever created. It is magical, enchanting, and moving in a way only classics are. We learn in the prologue that a selfish and unkind prince was cursed to be a beast. If he can learn to love and be loved in return, he will return to his original form. Belle is a smart, kind, and brave young woman living in a nearby town. She spends her days reading and rejecting advances from the local lout Gaston. When Belle's father gets lost one night, he wanders into the Beast's castle. The Beast accuses him of trespassing and throws him in the dungeon. Belle sets out to save her father and strikes up a deal with the Beast: if he lets her father go, she will stay in his place. The Beast and his servants, who have been turned into household objects, see Belle's arrival as a chance to finally break the spell. However, the Beast must first learn to be a gentleman. It's hard to describe how good this movie is. The songs, story, and characters all come together so perfectly.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gaston is not the villain and Belle's books are important
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    soudkovahana
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of my most beloved Disney movies. I love everything about this movie. Whether it's Belle's opening song, the absence of the villain or Mrs. Potts. Now I know you'll probably tell me that Gaston is the main villain in this story but I don't see him that way. Sure he's pretentious and cocky but that doesn't make him "the villain". Even when he rouse the village to go kill the Beast, yes I know he does it for his own selfish reasons, but he thinks it's just some beast, some animal, and he does not know the true identity of his. I don't want to excuse his actions, he's still very mean and selfish and very much hateful but I just don't see him as the evil villain like Voldemort or Darth Vader. You know what I mean? Anyway the story of the Beauty and the Beast is one of my favorites and it's been remade so many times, in so many versions but the original is only one. There is something about this story that makes me gasp every time I watch it. It's an excellent choice to show your children or grandchildren because it teaches them various of different lessons. Take the main character, Belle, for instance, who likes to read and is called "odd" for that behavior even though she's perfectly normal. You also have here Gaston, who thinks only about himself and who thinks that women should not read or even think. Beast on the other hand is from the very beginning enraptured by Belle's reading and gives her the entire library to read in. I think that Belle's books is an important motive in the movie and should not be alleviated. In other words the story has a lot to tell not only to the children but also to the adults that watch it with them.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The greatest film of the Disney Renaissance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MissSimonetta
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Disney Renaissance (1989-1999) was in many ways the studio's second golden age (the first being from 1937-1942), where experimentation and sublime artistry where the rule rather than the exception. Most of my generation grew up with these movies, so everyone has a favorite. The most popular seems to be The Lion King (1994), but for me the true masterpiece of the era is Beauty and the Beast (1991), arguably the most romantic Disney flick of them all. All the characters are perfect. I think the only cast I like better than this one is from Pinocchio (1940). Belle is an appealing heroine: she has a compassionate and dreamy nature, but she won't let herself be walked over by anyone (notice she doesn't fall for the Beast until he starts acting like a decent person). The Beast has excellent character development, evolving from a selfish brat into a kind, passionate fellow. The enchanted objects are both fun comic relief and interesting characters in their own right. Gaston is one of Disney's best villains, walking the fine line between comic and menacing with ease. BatB boasts the greatest soundtrack of all the Disney canon. Howard Ashman and Alan Mencken outdid themselves here. The choreography is magnificent too, especially the Busby Berkely inspired "Be Our Guest" and the superbly animated "Beauty and the Beast". The incidental music is lush and romantic, a pleasure to listen to in its own right. That's not to say the film doesn't have flaws. The animation on Belle goes off-model at times and the CG in the ballroom sequence is dated. And then there's that plot hole concerning how long Belle was at the castle. None of these issues diminish the greatness of the picture. This is one of the most beautiful and adult love stories ever put put on screen. Absolutely essential.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cookiemonster1234567
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I really like this movie. Its been my favorite movie since I was a little girl. Its a good story about integrity and true character. I mean our world is so messed up these days. Belle didn't care what the beast looked she only cared about his true character which is how all love is supposed to be but sadly its not how life is anymore. Its a beautiful story about what life really should be and what love should really be and mean inside and out. period that's it. People now chose who they 'love' by looks or the way someone is known to be or if that person is a popular person themselves with nobody else's help not one little bit. I really love the movie and I think that you would as well if you watch the movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My favorite
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dannimonai
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I used to watch this movie over and over again when I was little, it was always in the VCR. It was my favorite movie, it still is. I love the music, the animation, the characters and the story line. I identify with Belle the most, I feel as if she and I are one in the same. We love our family and a good book...or two. I have never succumbed to the pressure of society and I always stuck up for myself and others, just like she did. I learned to love people for who they are, not what they look like. This movie always encouraged me to do by best and be the best person I can be. Plus, the library Beast gives her is amazing and I would love it if it were mine!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Beauty and the Beast is a 1991 American animated fantasy, romantic, and musical film distributed by Walt Disney Pictures and produced by Walt Disney Feature Animation.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Charith Rajeeva
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Beauty and the Beast Featuring the vocal talents of Robby Benson and Paige O'Hara with Angela Lansbury, David Ogden Stiers, Jerry Orbach and Richard White, the movie displays the story of a prince, whose punishment for his selfish and cruel ways, is turned into a beast and Belle, a woman who willing takes her father's place as prisoner of the castle. To become the prince again, the beast must love Belle and in turn she must love the beast or he will remain as he is forever. The film is directed by Gary Trousdale and Kirk Wise. Gary Trousdale has worked on the story of Oliver and Company( 1998 film), The Little Mermaid(1989 film) as storyboard artist,Aladdin( 1992 film) as pre- production story developer and CGI, The Lion King (1994 film) on the story,The Hunchback of Notre Dame(1996 film) as director, Madagascar(2005 film) as an additional storyboard artist, Flushed Away(2006 film) as an additional story artist, among many more. Meanwhile Kirk Wise also worked on Oliver and Company as an animating assistant and with the story, The Prince and the Pauper as a storyboard artist, The Lion King with additional story material, The Hunchback of Notre Dame as director, Spirited Away as director of the U.S. Production, among others. Paige O'Hara voices the film's main protagonist, Belle. She also portrayed Angela in Enchanted. The setting of the film is somewhere in rural France in the 1700s. Character development was very well done, therefore solid 3-D characters.Another highlight was the computer animation, particularly the ballroom dance scene, which was impressively caricatured. The songs while a bit childish still are very nice. The score was also pleasing to the ears.The sound was very realistic and you could feel like you were actually there. The special effects were outstanding. The movie wasn't slow or fast, it was nearly perfectly well-paced and that's a lot given that the run time is only 84 minutes. It is the best film by Gary Trousdale and Kirk Wise. Quality wise, it's Kirk Wise's Spirited Away was significantly better. The plot was creative and quite unpredictable. The dialogue was also memorable. The movie flowed incredible scene to scene. The lighting and ambiance was superb. The animation was realistic and nothing looked out of the ordinary( in a good way). The costume design was intricate and realistic. It contributed positively towards the movie's overall tone. The set design was exceptional and it added to the movie experience. If the movie was filmed in an actual location, it would have to be well- chosen while there is hardly place where all of that is nearby. The background music was amazing. It worked incredibly well for the film.Ir was wasn't under-used or used in excess. The music was suspenseful and amusing, obviously in the correct places. All in all, the movie was fascinating and interesting, despite not being Disney's finest film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    All time favorite
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kristiscott111
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is an excellent movie for the whole family. I was already in Junior High when this came out but it quickly became one of my favorites. Even now with children of my own I love to pull this movie out and sit down with them to watch it. It starts out with beautiful scenery and wonderful singing. You will follow the life of an ordinary girl named Belle who has a love for reading. She lives alone with her father who is a but odd with his inventions and solitary lifestyle. He goes off to show his invention, he gets lost, finds a castle in the woods and lets himself in. Once inside he meets the enchanted occupants. Then the story really starts. The Beast discovers he has an unannounced visitor and thinks he is there torment him. So the father gets thrown in the tower. Belle has an unwelcoming admirer, the town bully. He tries to woo her, unsuccessfully. She runs out to the field to escape him and finds her fathers riderless horse barreling down on her. She then travels to the woods in search of her father. When she finds him at the castle she trades her life for his and the Beast releases her father and keeps her. Then the story begins.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Middle of Disney's Golden Age
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin6942
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Belle, whose father is imprisoned by the Beast, offers herself instead and discovers her captor to be an enchanted prince. This film was right in the middle of Disney's golden age, sandwiched between "Aladdin" and "Little Mermaid", pushing the boundaries of digital animation (just a few years before Pixar blew Disney out of the water). And the songs... definitely quite memorable. For me, Belle is the best princess Disney has had to date. While not an outright feminist role model like "Brave" was intended to be, she is a woman whose strengths are not in physical beauty, but in her intelligence. I think that was a great decision. Sure, she is not ugly, but the focus was on her being more than just "a prize to be won".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a beautiful young girl who come's in love with a beast.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nimra Rauf
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    the story is about a beautiful young village girl who lives with her old father who's been an inventor. Gaston a brute and rude handsome man on which all the village girls would die for is in love with belle,but after all he is belle would never accept his proposal but Gaston is steadfast to marry belle.one day Belle's father is off to another village to sell one of his invention in auction. but he come's in danger and runs into a castle which is forbidden but he is not known of it.when he gets cozy inside he discovers a scary,huge and rude beast who captures him inside.some how belle come to an awareness about the situation and runs off to help her father.the beast makes a deal with the girl that he would only release him in one condition that belle would be left there.As belle's warm heart agree's the condition her father is set off and belle is kept with the beast. the beast is in love with belle and steady and slow belle also comes in love with him, but the beast is captured in a spell and time is running out..the spell would only be broken only if he gets the KISS OF TRUE LOVE. Gaston comes aware of the situation and prepares an angry mob to attack the beast.later on when the beast is wounded belle kisses him and the spell is broken and the beast turns into a beautiful,young,handsome and charming prince. AND THEY GET MARRIED AND LIVE HAPPILY EVER AFTER!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One Of The Best Films Of The Disney Renaissance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    donuthaters12
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Disney has created a few classic princess fairy tale films in the past, so does Beauty and the Beast still matter? Simply yes. In comparison to the other princess films in the Disney Renaissance, this tops it but overall it isn't my favorite. The Disney Renaissance was film after film executed with brilliance and there are four films that would almost always be chosen either one as the best of the pack; The Little Mermaid, Beauty and the Beast, Aladdin, and The Lion King. I fall in the group that thinks Aladdin is the strongest film but either one are great enough to be number one. The story team for this film, did a great job as they meshed the melodramatic tale ,that is commonly found in the Disney princess films of the past, with modern dialogue and humor that appeals to the newer generation. With Disney animated films, I expect to see funny side characters. The difference between the old Disney and the new Disney is that somehow the most memorable element of the cast is the supporting cast rather than the main star. With Disney's old films, the main characters were the memorable ones for me. The film is an endearing, feel good, romantic story; with hilarious dialogue; that will appeal to all ages. This film was directed by Gary Tousdale and Kirk Wise, and this film was their debut in directing a Disney animated full length feature. What a great way to start, they created a film that is now regarded as a classic and was the first animated feature to be nominated with Best Picture at the Academy Awards. I think they took the best things about The Little Mermaid and added other things that work. Their next directorial efforts for Disney did not achieve close to what they have done for this, although those films did gain a cult following. I felt that The Little Mermaid and The Rescuers Down Under in comparison did not have that beautiful cinematography that Beauty and the Beast shows. It's cinematography is one of the main reasons why so much of this film work, whether it's the beautiful and dramatic lighting or the way the "camera" moves in a particular scene. An example would be the scene where both Belle and the Beast had a romantic dance in the ballroom; the scene was lit gorgeously and the iconic moment when the "camera" starts from the chandelier and glides its way down to them dancing. I felt that this aspect of the film should have been awarded with something. As expected from a Disney film, it is going to contain musical numbers in it. I don't usually mind it as it allows the animators to show off something daring and outrageous. I feel that the songs in this film are much more accessible and beautiful, like 'Be Our Guest' and 'Gaston', rather than something grand and iconic, Lion King, or as fun and daring, Aladdin. Be Our Guest and Gaston are definitely the favorite of mine. Be Our Guest due to it feeling like a Broadway musical and Gaston because it is so ridiculously egotistic that it is entertaining. Also pretty much who has seen the film, would remember the words "Tale as old as time/Song as old as rhyme". The soundtrack is wonderful but I don't feel any of it out trumps Aladdin's 'A Whole New World' or Lion King's 'Circle of Life'. The voices of the film fit well for the characters and certainly gives the characters a bit of personality. The animators did a wonderful job drawing the characters as they look very clean and attractive. The animators pushed hard on this film as large amounts of objects or people move in one shot, and each movement has a personality of its own. Cogsworth and Lumiere are one of the best character duos ever animated on Disney. The film is an icon of its own and definitely ranks in one of the top romance films of all time. Beauty and the Beast is a film that would be competing against films like Casablanca and Gone with the Wind in deciding which melodramatic romance film is the best. If you are looking for a great romantic film or a Disney film that hits all of its marks then this is that film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Tale as Old as Time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thelightbeamrider
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Beauty and the Beast is undoubtedly one of the best animated movies ever created. It is magical, enchanting, and moving in a way only classics are. We learn in the prologue that a selfish and unkind prince was cursed to be a beast. If he can learn to love and be loved in return, he will return to his original form. Belle is a smart, kind, and brave young woman living in a nearby town. She spends her days reading and rejecting advances from the local lout Gaston. When Belle's father gets lost one night, he wanders into the Beast's castle. The Beast accuses him of trespassing and throws him in the dungeon. Belle sets out to save her father and strikes up a deal with the Beast: if he lets her father go, she will stay in his place. The Beast and his servants, who have been turned into household objects, see Belle's arrival as a chance to finally break the spell. However, the Beast must first learn to be a gentleman. It's hard to describe how good this movie is. The songs, story, and characters all come together so perfectly.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
