<filme>
 <id>
  589
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0065214
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1969
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Meu &Oacute;dio Ser&aacute; Sua Heran&ccedil;a
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  8.1
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  An aging group of outlaws look for one last big score as the "traditional" American West is disappearing around them.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  In the Wild Bunch the movie opens with a group of aging outlaw's final score, a bank robbery. The event concludes with a violent and overtly bloody shootout that would generally mark the finale of a movie. This is correct in that it marks the finale of an era, for the characters and the world they live in. They simply can no longer keep up, the times are changing, technology advancing, and they're style of life is getting left behind in the dust that they spent so long galloping through. They abandon their careers for the simpler life of retirement. They enjoy this time, they live their fantasies. During this time the law is always on their tracks, bounty hunters. The further into their fantasy they get, the closer their demise seems to get. When one of their own is captured they are faced with the choice of escape or what is certainly a suicide mission to attempt and free their fallen behind comrade. For them it is not a choice. They all die in what can only be described as a ...
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Western
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   outlaw
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   bounty
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   mexico
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   texas
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   mexican
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Sam Peckinpah
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Walon Green
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Sam Peckinpah
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   William Holden
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Ernest Borgnine
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Robert Ryan
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What to Expect: The Wild Bunch
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Film Watchin Fool
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Why You Might Like It: If you are a fan of Westerns, then you will likely enjoy this movie. It is a bit different than your traditional Western as it is action-packed at times and has an over the top shoot em up fill to it. The acting is great and the directing by Peckinpah is very fresh to this genre of movies and makes for a fun watch. Why You Might Not Like It: As most Westerns do, it has its slow spots that will make some lose interest. Also, this film is rated very high, so many will go into it with lofty expectations that it may or may not live up to. Acting/Casting: 8* - There is no shortage of great acting and cast members in this film. I am a huge fan of both William Holden and Robert Ryan in particular. Directing/Cinematography/Technical: 8* - Peckinpah does a fantastic job and many of the gun fight scenes are something to marvel for the film being made in 1969. Plot/Characters: 7* - The story has many layers and is pretty impressive. It starts out with a robbery, progresses into bounty hunting, and ends up being about loyalty. Entertainment Value: 7* - I really enjoyed this movie and was extremely impressed by the gun fight scenes, which are the highlight of the movie in my opinion. I would recommend this to fans of Western films and will likely watch again some time down the road. My Score: 8+8+7+7 = 30/4 = 7.5 Email your thoughts to filmwatchinfool@gmail.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Glossy, outdated violence and not much else
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Conrad
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sam Peckinpah wants you to know that Hollywood is at last free of its self-imposed Hays Code. He sets out to create the most violent Western to date, and he succeeds. The body count here is higher than in some wars. Every death is captured in slow-motion and augmented with jets of blood. Perhaps these novel visuals were thrilling and shocking to moviegoers in the late 1960s, but decades later desensitization has long since set in. The violence in "The Wild Bunch" has not aged well, and there is little else of interest in the film. A thin storyline links one scene of carnage to the next, but the movie doesn't know what to do with its characters between the action. A sentimental musical score plays to the point of distraction throughout the film but should fool nobody into caring about any of the people on screen. It is, however, nice to see the underrated Robert Ryan in a starring role.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An unsparing vision of the dream of innocence, and of human failure. . . .
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    malcolmi
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You can ride with a gang that seems to share a rough code of honour, but you'll be pursued by a former friend who's betraying you to stay out of prison. You can try to earn an easy score through the bloody hard work of robbing a bank, or a railroad, and cross the river into the freedom of a country where no law applies to you, but once you've crossed the river you'll be consumed by the chaos that always flourishes in the absence of law. You can try to rescue a friend, but your gesture will be rendered useless by a knife blade's flash. Then, when there's no more running, and nowhere to run to, when you've given your word and found that no one values it, when you've played out your string right to the end, what will you do? The Wild Bunch is Sam Peckinpah's exploration of that question. An artist who knew and loved life on the land, who knew well, and hated, the corruptions of 'civilization', and was compelled to cross the border into lawless territory, to seek a freedom which his own knowledge could never let him inhabit, Peckinpah made this marvellous film. It's set in a physical and spiritual landscape that any thinking middle-aged man is appallingly familiar with - the world of turning a blind eye to one's own cruelty, of watching one's hopes trashed by malevolence and stupidity, of being betrayed by friends, of fantasizing about the stroke of good luck that will let a man walk away from his compromises and failures. And Peckinpah's refusal to accept false sentiment reflects a middle-aged man's knowledge that self-interest and cruelty tempt even the very young, that even the powerful dream of being a child again is an illusion promising no peace. The children dream of being as brave and powerful as the adults whose violent actions are so seductively exciting. In the film's penultimate cathartic moment, it's a child who pulls the rifle's trigger. So, in the face of the disintegration of his world, and the impossibility of returning to innocence, what must a man do? No, the characters in this film are not honourable. But they dream of honourable actions - helping one's countrymen, one's village, one's friends. Yes, the idea of the frontier as an escape, and a new beginning, dies, in a welter of bullets after a man is dragged by technology across the abrasive landscape of his failure to see the consequences of his own actions. But the freedom of the frontier is its uncompromising offer of a chance to assess what's really true about existence. Sam Peckinpah knew that the assessment was the important thing. Death will happen. . . the important thing is to be ready to face death honestly, and so be able to live truly. The Wild Bunch isn't a young person's film, but for people who are ready to live in the minute details of existence faced honestly, ready to face the inevitable truth of death, The Wild Bunch is the necessary film. Peckinpah's clear vision cost him his happiness, and his health, finally, but left the rest of us a tough, miraculous, work of art.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The wages of sin is...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Wuchak
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ...death. That's the moral of Sam Peckinpah's classic 1969 Western about a group of aging and meandering outlaws who ride into Mexico in 1913 to flee a posse led by a former member, Deke Thornton (Robert Ryan). The outlaws, led by Pike Bishop (William Holden), eventually take refuge with a Mexican "general" and his hundreds of soldiers. When the Mexican member of the gang, Angel, is taken captive by the general for his revolutionary interests the rest of the gang have to decide whether to ignore it or make a bold stand. The Director's Cut of "The Wild Bunch" (1969) runs 145 minutes and features a great opening shootout and an outstanding closing shootout, a catharsis of blood; in the middle is a compelling train robbery. The material in between these three sequences isn't all that engrossing due to the fact that the characters aren't noble, likable or even redeemable, which is the film's weakness. I get the pessimistic message, but it doesn't change the fact that practically every character is an immoral or amoral dirtbag. Speaking of which, Deke Thornton has the audacity to repeatedly call the members of his posse "gutter trash" and the like. Well, what is he? A freed-on-condition prisoner who was once a member of the outlaw scum. At least the posse members -- lowlifes that they are -- are on the right side of the law. What hypocrisy. As noted above, a lot of dialogue and drama is devoted to character development, but who cares about a bunch of criminal scumbags? How can you devote "character development" to people who have no character? That's the problem with the film. That said, if you can accept the de-glorification of the Old West and the unlikable characters, "The Wild Bunch" is a solid Western with three thrilling sequences, including the unforgettable ending. There's a good message about the boldness of taking a stand and sticking by one's comrades, but that's the extent of the depth. GRADE: C+ or B-
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One Of The Best Westerns Ever Released
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Wild Bunch is a Western directed by Sam Peckinpah about an aging outlaw gang on the Texas-Mexico border, trying to exist in the changing modern world of 1913. The film was controversial because of its graphic violence and its portrayal of crude men attempting to survive by any available means.It features William Holden, Robert Ryan, Ernest Borgnine, Ben Johnson and Warren Oates. The screenplay was by Peckinpah and Walon Green.It is noted for intricate, multi-angle editing, using normal and slow motion images, a revolutionary cinema technique during its time of release in 1969. After a failed payroll robbery, the outlaw Bunch, led by aging Pike Bishop and including Dutch, Angel, and Lyle and Tector Gorch, heads for Mexico pursued by the gang of Pike's friend-turned-nemesis Deke Thornton.Ultimately caught between the corruption of railroad fat cat Harrigan and Federal general Mapache, and without a frontier for escape, the Bunch opts for a final Pyrrhic victory, striding purposefully to confront Mapache and avenge their friend Angel. "If they move, kill 'em!" Beginning and ending with two of the bloodiest battles in screen history, Sam Peckinpah's classic revisionist Western ruthlessly takes apart the myths of the West. Released in the late '60s discord over Vietnam, in the wake of the controversial Bonnie and Clyde nihilism of the times, while the other reviled it as depraved. But nevertheless, it takes the basic elements of the Western movie myth, which once defined a simple, morally comprehensible world, and by bending them turns them into symbols of futility and aimless corruption. Also,credit Peckinpah's success in setting the scenes and the sketches of a dozen vividly individualized characters, and choreographs one of the most realistic, influential, brilliantly photographed shootouts under the pitiless sun. The cast is superb, the dialog crackling, the bitterly ambiguous moral of the story hard-earned.One of the best Westerns ever released on screen.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not wild about this bunch
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brefane
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Stunningly photographed by Lucien Ballard, The Wild Bunch is a gorgeous looking and stunningly directed bore, yes, bore. Pacing is sorely lacking, and the direction, accomplished as it is, is sometimes undercut by the splintered editing. Despite the hyperactive editing, the film drags, and talk, most of it insignificant, fills the time between scenes of abstract violence. I didn't really care for or about the characters as I did in Kurosawa's The Seven Samurai or Pechnipah's Ride the High Country hence 21/2 hrs with them was too much. Sure the set pieces are terrific and worth watching, but pieces do not translate into a satisfactory whole. The acting is good, particularly Borgnine, Ryan, and Holden talented actors relegated to forgettable films during the 60's so The Wild Bunch was a last hurrah for them as well. The supporting cast has a convincing look and feel as does the film. Released the same year as the far more traditional Oscar-winning westerns Butch Cassidy and the Sundance Kid and True Grit, The Wild Bunch was nominated for 2 Oscars, for Original Screenplay and Score, though it's the direction, editing and cinematography that are outstanding.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The End Of A Golden Age
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nick-leonardi
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A group of aging outlaws, after a bloody and violent battle taking place in a small town, decide they want to accomplish one last hit before retiring: a train heist to get weapons, to give them to a Mexican general who promises them good money. The Bunch meanwhile is chased by Deke Thornton (a man who used to be in the Bunch), who's pressured by the risk of going back to Yuma if he fails to capture the old comrades. Sam Peckinpah's fifth film as a director has all of the qualities of a magnum opus: epic narrative structure, a vast, varied and always gorgeous array of sceneries, memorable and likable protagonists (William Holden, Ernest Borgnine, Warren Oates, Ben Johnson, Jamie Sanchez), masterful and innovative directing: the battle scenes are full of repeated slow motion shots and fast and complex editing choices. The Revisionist Western film par excellence: the beloved world of the West is portrayed as an ugly, dangerous, savage place, in which everyone is selfish, greedy, and cynical; but this world is also seen at its twilight, at the closing of the frontier, as the East brings in more and more modernization. Nominated for 2 Oscars.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Makes Rambo Look Like a Sissy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin6942
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An aging group of outlaws look for one last big score as the "traditional" American West is disappearing around them. The film starts off with a group of children watching a scorpion in an anthill. I knew this had to be symbolic, but I did not fully grasp how until the film was over. Seeing it now, it really tied the film together with a nice bookend and foreshadowing. Wow. The story is a good one, full of a moral morass. The "good guys" are as despicable as the outlaws, perhaps even more. Who do we cheer for? And the body count... wow (again). I can only imagine how many squibs were used for this movie, because blood and bullets were busting out everywhere. A good story, plenty of action, and Ernest Borgnine...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sam Peckinpah's Grand Slam
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    georgep53
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw a Director's Cut of "The Wild Bunch" on the big screen a couple of nights ago and although 43 years have passed it's still one helluva kick in the gut. I could tell how deeply this film has touched people by the reactions from the audience and obviously with so many IMDb reviews "The Wild Bunch" has made a lasting impression. There's so much to praise from the great performances of William Holden, Ernest Borgnine, Robert Ryan, Ben Johnson, Warren Oates and Edmond O'Brien to the great work of cinematographer Lucien Ballard and editor Lou Lombardo; the intricate screenplay by Peckinpah and Walon Green and Sam Peckinpah's bold, uncompromising direction. "The Wild Bunch" belongs to a group of films like "Butch Cassidy and the Sundance Kid" and "Lonely Are the Brave" that depict the cowboy/gunslinger as an anachronism in the face of a rapidly advancing modernity. They know their time is running out but the lure of one last job; the bonds between them and their adversaries' commitment to bringing them to justice lock them in a life and death struggle. The machine gun that figures so prominently in the conclusion is a great symbol of the mechanized slaughter that would come to dominate the 20th century. I loved the allegorical imagery of the scorpions and the ants locked in a battle to the death under the eager, enthusiastic eyes of children and by extension, us. William Holden gives one of his best performances in the role of Bishop Pike, aging leader of the Bunch. Robert Ryan is memorable as Deke Thornton, his former partner and current pursuer. Thornton feels disdain for the greedy, incompetent, railroad bosses who hate Pike. They have even less concern for human life than the outlaws.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A classic in every way.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Scott LeBrun (Hey_Sweden)
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sam Peckinpah's masterful movie is an incredible piece of work; much as its main characters realize that the way of the Old West are changing, so too does his movie acknowledge the evolution of the whole Western genre. No longer were ideas of "good" and "bad" so clearly defined. No longer did people merely clutch themselves and fall over when fatally shot; here we see bloody bullet penetration in all of its Technicolor glory. And there is one constant and admirable theme running throughout, that of a man's need to stand by his fellow men. Loyalty means a lot to ageing outlaw Pike Bishop (William Holden, in a fantastic change of pace performance). He and his fellow outlaws - Dutch (Ernest Borgnine), the Gorch brothers (Warren Oates and Ben Johnson), and Angel (Jaime Sanchez) can see that things are changing all around them, as they are witness to the marvel of automobiles and even the variety of "car" that can fly. As they look to make one last big score before they pack it in, they're trailed by Pike's old comrade Deke Thornton (Robert Ryan), not terribly happy to be pursuing his former friend, but having very little choice in the matter. The characters are all quite colourful and interesting, and each actor gets a chance to shine as the intricate, well written (by Peckinpah and Walon Green, based on Green's and Roy N. Sickner's story) plot plays itself out. And this is a true "man's" movie, one in which the female characters don't fare too well, so this may not be to all tastes, but it's hard to deny the punch that this movie packs. It's extremely tense and exciting, with excellently staged action scenes, and plenty of squibs going off. Technically, this movie is a marvel, scored (by Jerry Fielding), lit (by Lucien Ballard), and edited (by Lou Lombardo) to perfection. It's a very rich looking experience that makes full use of its Panavision aspect ratio. The opening robbery scene is wonderfully intense (and features that memorable line, "If they move, kill them."); it will have you on the edge of your seat. Many fine sequences, with the robbery of guns and ammo from a train and the climactic shootout definite standouts. In addition to those actors already mentioned, solid contributions are made by a number of great character players: Edmond O'Brien, Strother Martin, L.Q. Jones (those last two making for a priceless comedy relief duo), Albert Dekker, Bo Hopkins, Dub Taylor, Emilio Fernandez, and Alfonso Arau. Poignant moments are mixed with some sharp dialogue, some good laughs, thrilling moments, and a high fun factor to make this well worth watching for any film fan, not just Western aficionados. As it reaches its conclusion, it would be too hard not to cheer seeing four of our main characters march side by side, guns at the ready, as they prepare to meet their destiny. The result of all of this is something truly unforgettable. 10 out of 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What to Expect: The Wild Bunch
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Film Watchin Fool
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Why You Might Like It: If you are a fan of Westerns, then you will likely enjoy this movie. It is a bit different than your traditional Western as it is action-packed at times and has an over the top shoot em up fill to it. The acting is great and the directing by Peckinpah is very fresh to this genre of movies and makes for a fun watch. Why You Might Not Like It: As most Westerns do, it has its slow spots that will make some lose interest. Also, this film is rated very high, so many will go into it with lofty expectations that it may or may not live up to. Acting/Casting: 8* - There is no shortage of great acting and cast members in this film. I am a huge fan of both William Holden and Robert Ryan in particular. Directing/Cinematography/Technical: 8* - Peckinpah does a fantastic job and many of the gun fight scenes are something to marvel for the film being made in 1969. Plot/Characters: 7* - The story has many layers and is pretty impressive. It starts out with a robbery, progresses into bounty hunting, and ends up being about loyalty. Entertainment Value: 7* - I really enjoyed this movie and was extremely impressed by the gun fight scenes, which are the highlight of the movie in my opinion. I would recommend this to fans of Western films and will likely watch again some time down the road. My Score: 8+8+7+7 = 30/4 = 7.5 Email your thoughts to filmwatchinfool@gmail.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Glossy, outdated violence and not much else
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Conrad
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sam Peckinpah wants you to know that Hollywood is at last free of its self-imposed Hays Code. He sets out to create the most violent Western to date, and he succeeds. The body count here is higher than in some wars. Every death is captured in slow-motion and augmented with jets of blood. Perhaps these novel visuals were thrilling and shocking to moviegoers in the late 1960s, but decades later desensitization has long since set in. The violence in "The Wild Bunch" has not aged well, and there is little else of interest in the film. A thin storyline links one scene of carnage to the next, but the movie doesn't know what to do with its characters between the action. A sentimental musical score plays to the point of distraction throughout the film but should fool nobody into caring about any of the people on screen. It is, however, nice to see the underrated Robert Ryan in a starring role.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An unsparing vision of the dream of innocence, and of human failure. . . .
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    malcolmi
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You can ride with a gang that seems to share a rough code of honour, but you'll be pursued by a former friend who's betraying you to stay out of prison. You can try to earn an easy score through the bloody hard work of robbing a bank, or a railroad, and cross the river into the freedom of a country where no law applies to you, but once you've crossed the river you'll be consumed by the chaos that always flourishes in the absence of law. You can try to rescue a friend, but your gesture will be rendered useless by a knife blade's flash. Then, when there's no more running, and nowhere to run to, when you've given your word and found that no one values it, when you've played out your string right to the end, what will you do? The Wild Bunch is Sam Peckinpah's exploration of that question. An artist who knew and loved life on the land, who knew well, and hated, the corruptions of 'civilization', and was compelled to cross the border into lawless territory, to seek a freedom which his own knowledge could never let him inhabit, Peckinpah made this marvellous film. It's set in a physical and spiritual landscape that any thinking middle-aged man is appallingly familiar with - the world of turning a blind eye to one's own cruelty, of watching one's hopes trashed by malevolence and stupidity, of being betrayed by friends, of fantasizing about the stroke of good luck that will let a man walk away from his compromises and failures. And Peckinpah's refusal to accept false sentiment reflects a middle-aged man's knowledge that self-interest and cruelty tempt even the very young, that even the powerful dream of being a child again is an illusion promising no peace. The children dream of being as brave and powerful as the adults whose violent actions are so seductively exciting. In the film's penultimate cathartic moment, it's a child who pulls the rifle's trigger. So, in the face of the disintegration of his world, and the impossibility of returning to innocence, what must a man do? No, the characters in this film are not honourable. But they dream of honourable actions - helping one's countrymen, one's village, one's friends. Yes, the idea of the frontier as an escape, and a new beginning, dies, in a welter of bullets after a man is dragged by technology across the abrasive landscape of his failure to see the consequences of his own actions. But the freedom of the frontier is its uncompromising offer of a chance to assess what's really true about existence. Sam Peckinpah knew that the assessment was the important thing. Death will happen. . . the important thing is to be ready to face death honestly, and so be able to live truly. The Wild Bunch isn't a young person's film, but for people who are ready to live in the minute details of existence faced honestly, ready to face the inevitable truth of death, The Wild Bunch is the necessary film. Peckinpah's clear vision cost him his happiness, and his health, finally, but left the rest of us a tough, miraculous, work of art.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The wages of sin is...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Wuchak
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ...death. That's the moral of Sam Peckinpah's classic 1969 Western about a group of aging and meandering outlaws who ride into Mexico in 1913 to flee a posse led by a former member, Deke Thornton (Robert Ryan). The outlaws, led by Pike Bishop (William Holden), eventually take refuge with a Mexican "general" and his hundreds of soldiers. When the Mexican member of the gang, Angel, is taken captive by the general for his revolutionary interests the rest of the gang have to decide whether to ignore it or make a bold stand. The Director's Cut of "The Wild Bunch" (1969) runs 145 minutes and features a great opening shootout and an outstanding closing shootout, a catharsis of blood; in the middle is a compelling train robbery. The material in between these three sequences isn't all that engrossing due to the fact that the characters aren't noble, likable or even redeemable, which is the film's weakness. I get the pessimistic message, but it doesn't change the fact that practically every character is an immoral or amoral dirtbag. Speaking of which, Deke Thornton has the audacity to repeatedly call the members of his posse "gutter trash" and the like. Well, what is he? A freed-on-condition prisoner who was once a member of the outlaw scum. At least the posse members -- lowlifes that they are -- are on the right side of the law. What hypocrisy. As noted above, a lot of dialogue and drama is devoted to character development, but who cares about a bunch of criminal scumbags? How can you devote "character development" to people who have no character? That's the problem with the film. That said, if you can accept the de-glorification of the Old West and the unlikable characters, "The Wild Bunch" is a solid Western with three thrilling sequences, including the unforgettable ending. There's a good message about the boldness of taking a stand and sticking by one's comrades, but that's the extent of the depth. GRADE: C+ or B-
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One Of The Best Westerns Ever Released
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Wild Bunch is a Western directed by Sam Peckinpah about an aging outlaw gang on the Texas-Mexico border, trying to exist in the changing modern world of 1913. The film was controversial because of its graphic violence and its portrayal of crude men attempting to survive by any available means.It features William Holden, Robert Ryan, Ernest Borgnine, Ben Johnson and Warren Oates. The screenplay was by Peckinpah and Walon Green.It is noted for intricate, multi-angle editing, using normal and slow motion images, a revolutionary cinema technique during its time of release in 1969. After a failed payroll robbery, the outlaw Bunch, led by aging Pike Bishop and including Dutch, Angel, and Lyle and Tector Gorch, heads for Mexico pursued by the gang of Pike's friend-turned-nemesis Deke Thornton.Ultimately caught between the corruption of railroad fat cat Harrigan and Federal general Mapache, and without a frontier for escape, the Bunch opts for a final Pyrrhic victory, striding purposefully to confront Mapache and avenge their friend Angel. "If they move, kill 'em!" Beginning and ending with two of the bloodiest battles in screen history, Sam Peckinpah's classic revisionist Western ruthlessly takes apart the myths of the West. Released in the late '60s discord over Vietnam, in the wake of the controversial Bonnie and Clyde nihilism of the times, while the other reviled it as depraved. But nevertheless, it takes the basic elements of the Western movie myth, which once defined a simple, morally comprehensible world, and by bending them turns them into symbols of futility and aimless corruption. Also,credit Peckinpah's success in setting the scenes and the sketches of a dozen vividly individualized characters, and choreographs one of the most realistic, influential, brilliantly photographed shootouts under the pitiless sun. The cast is superb, the dialog crackling, the bitterly ambiguous moral of the story hard-earned.One of the best Westerns ever released on screen.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not wild about this bunch
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brefane
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Stunningly photographed by Lucien Ballard, The Wild Bunch is a gorgeous looking and stunningly directed bore, yes, bore. Pacing is sorely lacking, and the direction, accomplished as it is, is sometimes undercut by the splintered editing. Despite the hyperactive editing, the film drags, and talk, most of it insignificant, fills the time between scenes of abstract violence. I didn't really care for or about the characters as I did in Kurosawa's The Seven Samurai or Pechnipah's Ride the High Country hence 21/2 hrs with them was too much. Sure the set pieces are terrific and worth watching, but pieces do not translate into a satisfactory whole. The acting is good, particularly Borgnine, Ryan, and Holden talented actors relegated to forgettable films during the 60's so The Wild Bunch was a last hurrah for them as well. The supporting cast has a convincing look and feel as does the film. Released the same year as the far more traditional Oscar-winning westerns Butch Cassidy and the Sundance Kid and True Grit, The Wild Bunch was nominated for 2 Oscars, for Original Screenplay and Score, though it's the direction, editing and cinematography that are outstanding.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The End Of A Golden Age
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nick-leonardi
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A group of aging outlaws, after a bloody and violent battle taking place in a small town, decide they want to accomplish one last hit before retiring: a train heist to get weapons, to give them to a Mexican general who promises them good money. The Bunch meanwhile is chased by Deke Thornton (a man who used to be in the Bunch), who's pressured by the risk of going back to Yuma if he fails to capture the old comrades. Sam Peckinpah's fifth film as a director has all of the qualities of a magnum opus: epic narrative structure, a vast, varied and always gorgeous array of sceneries, memorable and likable protagonists (William Holden, Ernest Borgnine, Warren Oates, Ben Johnson, Jamie Sanchez), masterful and innovative directing: the battle scenes are full of repeated slow motion shots and fast and complex editing choices. The Revisionist Western film par excellence: the beloved world of the West is portrayed as an ugly, dangerous, savage place, in which everyone is selfish, greedy, and cynical; but this world is also seen at its twilight, at the closing of the frontier, as the East brings in more and more modernization. Nominated for 2 Oscars.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Makes Rambo Look Like a Sissy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin6942
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An aging group of outlaws look for one last big score as the "traditional" American West is disappearing around them. The film starts off with a group of children watching a scorpion in an anthill. I knew this had to be symbolic, but I did not fully grasp how until the film was over. Seeing it now, it really tied the film together with a nice bookend and foreshadowing. Wow. The story is a good one, full of a moral morass. The "good guys" are as despicable as the outlaws, perhaps even more. Who do we cheer for? And the body count... wow (again). I can only imagine how many squibs were used for this movie, because blood and bullets were busting out everywhere. A good story, plenty of action, and Ernest Borgnine...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sam Peckinpah's Grand Slam
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    georgep53
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw a Director's Cut of "The Wild Bunch" on the big screen a couple of nights ago and although 43 years have passed it's still one helluva kick in the gut. I could tell how deeply this film has touched people by the reactions from the audience and obviously with so many IMDb reviews "The Wild Bunch" has made a lasting impression. There's so much to praise from the great performances of William Holden, Ernest Borgnine, Robert Ryan, Ben Johnson, Warren Oates and Edmond O'Brien to the great work of cinematographer Lucien Ballard and editor Lou Lombardo; the intricate screenplay by Peckinpah and Walon Green and Sam Peckinpah's bold, uncompromising direction. "The Wild Bunch" belongs to a group of films like "Butch Cassidy and the Sundance Kid" and "Lonely Are the Brave" that depict the cowboy/gunslinger as an anachronism in the face of a rapidly advancing modernity. They know their time is running out but the lure of one last job; the bonds between them and their adversaries' commitment to bringing them to justice lock them in a life and death struggle. The machine gun that figures so prominently in the conclusion is a great symbol of the mechanized slaughter that would come to dominate the 20th century. I loved the allegorical imagery of the scorpions and the ants locked in a battle to the death under the eager, enthusiastic eyes of children and by extension, us. William Holden gives one of his best performances in the role of Bishop Pike, aging leader of the Bunch. Robert Ryan is memorable as Deke Thornton, his former partner and current pursuer. Thornton feels disdain for the greedy, incompetent, railroad bosses who hate Pike. They have even less concern for human life than the outlaws.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A classic in every way.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Scott LeBrun (Hey_Sweden)
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sam Peckinpah's masterful movie is an incredible piece of work; much as its main characters realize that the way of the Old West are changing, so too does his movie acknowledge the evolution of the whole Western genre. No longer were ideas of "good" and "bad" so clearly defined. No longer did people merely clutch themselves and fall over when fatally shot; here we see bloody bullet penetration in all of its Technicolor glory. And there is one constant and admirable theme running throughout, that of a man's need to stand by his fellow men. Loyalty means a lot to ageing outlaw Pike Bishop (William Holden, in a fantastic change of pace performance). He and his fellow outlaws - Dutch (Ernest Borgnine), the Gorch brothers (Warren Oates and Ben Johnson), and Angel (Jaime Sanchez) can see that things are changing all around them, as they are witness to the marvel of automobiles and even the variety of "car" that can fly. As they look to make one last big score before they pack it in, they're trailed by Pike's old comrade Deke Thornton (Robert Ryan), not terribly happy to be pursuing his former friend, but having very little choice in the matter. The characters are all quite colourful and interesting, and each actor gets a chance to shine as the intricate, well written (by Peckinpah and Walon Green, based on Green's and Roy N. Sickner's story) plot plays itself out. And this is a true "man's" movie, one in which the female characters don't fare too well, so this may not be to all tastes, but it's hard to deny the punch that this movie packs. It's extremely tense and exciting, with excellently staged action scenes, and plenty of squibs going off. Technically, this movie is a marvel, scored (by Jerry Fielding), lit (by Lucien Ballard), and edited (by Lou Lombardo) to perfection. It's a very rich looking experience that makes full use of its Panavision aspect ratio. The opening robbery scene is wonderfully intense (and features that memorable line, "If they move, kill them."); it will have you on the edge of your seat. Many fine sequences, with the robbery of guns and ammo from a train and the climactic shootout definite standouts. In addition to those actors already mentioned, solid contributions are made by a number of great character players: Edmond O'Brien, Strother Martin, L.Q. Jones (those last two making for a priceless comedy relief duo), Albert Dekker, Bo Hopkins, Dub Taylor, Emilio Fernandez, and Alfonso Arau. Poignant moments are mixed with some sharp dialogue, some good laughs, thrilling moments, and a high fun factor to make this well worth watching for any film fan, not just Western aficionados. As it reaches its conclusion, it would be too hard not to cheer seeing four of our main characters march side by side, guns at the ready, as they prepare to meet their destiny. The result of all of this is something truly unforgettable. 10 out of 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What to Expect: The Wild Bunch
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Film Watchin Fool
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Why You Might Like It: If you are a fan of Westerns, then you will likely enjoy this movie. It is a bit different than your traditional Western as it is action-packed at times and has an over the top shoot em up fill to it. The acting is great and the directing by Peckinpah is very fresh to this genre of movies and makes for a fun watch. Why You Might Not Like It: As most Westerns do, it has its slow spots that will make some lose interest. Also, this film is rated very high, so many will go into it with lofty expectations that it may or may not live up to. Acting/Casting: 8* - There is no shortage of great acting and cast members in this film. I am a huge fan of both William Holden and Robert Ryan in particular. Directing/Cinematography/Technical: 8* - Peckinpah does a fantastic job and many of the gun fight scenes are something to marvel for the film being made in 1969. Plot/Characters: 7* - The story has many layers and is pretty impressive. It starts out with a robbery, progresses into bounty hunting, and ends up being about loyalty. Entertainment Value: 7* - I really enjoyed this movie and was extremely impressed by the gun fight scenes, which are the highlight of the movie in my opinion. I would recommend this to fans of Western films and will likely watch again some time down the road. My Score: 8+8+7+7 = 30/4 = 7.5 Email your thoughts to filmwatchinfool@gmail.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Glossy, outdated violence and not much else
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Conrad
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sam Peckinpah wants you to know that Hollywood is at last free of its self-imposed Hays Code. He sets out to create the most violent Western to date, and he succeeds. The body count here is higher than in some wars. Every death is captured in slow-motion and augmented with jets of blood. Perhaps these novel visuals were thrilling and shocking to moviegoers in the late 1960s, but decades later desensitization has long since set in. The violence in "The Wild Bunch" has not aged well, and there is little else of interest in the film. A thin storyline links one scene of carnage to the next, but the movie doesn't know what to do with its characters between the action. A sentimental musical score plays to the point of distraction throughout the film but should fool nobody into caring about any of the people on screen. It is, however, nice to see the underrated Robert Ryan in a starring role.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An unsparing vision of the dream of innocence, and of human failure. . . .
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    malcolmi
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You can ride with a gang that seems to share a rough code of honour, but you'll be pursued by a former friend who's betraying you to stay out of prison. You can try to earn an easy score through the bloody hard work of robbing a bank, or a railroad, and cross the river into the freedom of a country where no law applies to you, but once you've crossed the river you'll be consumed by the chaos that always flourishes in the absence of law. You can try to rescue a friend, but your gesture will be rendered useless by a knife blade's flash. Then, when there's no more running, and nowhere to run to, when you've given your word and found that no one values it, when you've played out your string right to the end, what will you do? The Wild Bunch is Sam Peckinpah's exploration of that question. An artist who knew and loved life on the land, who knew well, and hated, the corruptions of 'civilization', and was compelled to cross the border into lawless territory, to seek a freedom which his own knowledge could never let him inhabit, Peckinpah made this marvellous film. It's set in a physical and spiritual landscape that any thinking middle-aged man is appallingly familiar with - the world of turning a blind eye to one's own cruelty, of watching one's hopes trashed by malevolence and stupidity, of being betrayed by friends, of fantasizing about the stroke of good luck that will let a man walk away from his compromises and failures. And Peckinpah's refusal to accept false sentiment reflects a middle-aged man's knowledge that self-interest and cruelty tempt even the very young, that even the powerful dream of being a child again is an illusion promising no peace. The children dream of being as brave and powerful as the adults whose violent actions are so seductively exciting. In the film's penultimate cathartic moment, it's a child who pulls the rifle's trigger. So, in the face of the disintegration of his world, and the impossibility of returning to innocence, what must a man do? No, the characters in this film are not honourable. But they dream of honourable actions - helping one's countrymen, one's village, one's friends. Yes, the idea of the frontier as an escape, and a new beginning, dies, in a welter of bullets after a man is dragged by technology across the abrasive landscape of his failure to see the consequences of his own actions. But the freedom of the frontier is its uncompromising offer of a chance to assess what's really true about existence. Sam Peckinpah knew that the assessment was the important thing. Death will happen. . . the important thing is to be ready to face death honestly, and so be able to live truly. The Wild Bunch isn't a young person's film, but for people who are ready to live in the minute details of existence faced honestly, ready to face the inevitable truth of death, The Wild Bunch is the necessary film. Peckinpah's clear vision cost him his happiness, and his health, finally, but left the rest of us a tough, miraculous, work of art.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The wages of sin is...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Wuchak
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ...death. That's the moral of Sam Peckinpah's classic 1969 Western about a group of aging and meandering outlaws who ride into Mexico in 1913 to flee a posse led by a former member, Deke Thornton (Robert Ryan). The outlaws, led by Pike Bishop (William Holden), eventually take refuge with a Mexican "general" and his hundreds of soldiers. When the Mexican member of the gang, Angel, is taken captive by the general for his revolutionary interests the rest of the gang have to decide whether to ignore it or make a bold stand. The Director's Cut of "The Wild Bunch" (1969) runs 145 minutes and features a great opening shootout and an outstanding closing shootout, a catharsis of blood; in the middle is a compelling train robbery. The material in between these three sequences isn't all that engrossing due to the fact that the characters aren't noble, likable or even redeemable, which is the film's weakness. I get the pessimistic message, but it doesn't change the fact that practically every character is an immoral or amoral dirtbag. Speaking of which, Deke Thornton has the audacity to repeatedly call the members of his posse "gutter trash" and the like. Well, what is he? A freed-on-condition prisoner who was once a member of the outlaw scum. At least the posse members -- lowlifes that they are -- are on the right side of the law. What hypocrisy. As noted above, a lot of dialogue and drama is devoted to character development, but who cares about a bunch of criminal scumbags? How can you devote "character development" to people who have no character? That's the problem with the film. That said, if you can accept the de-glorification of the Old West and the unlikable characters, "The Wild Bunch" is a solid Western with three thrilling sequences, including the unforgettable ending. There's a good message about the boldness of taking a stand and sticking by one's comrades, but that's the extent of the depth. GRADE: C+ or B-
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One Of The Best Westerns Ever Released
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Wild Bunch is a Western directed by Sam Peckinpah about an aging outlaw gang on the Texas-Mexico border, trying to exist in the changing modern world of 1913. The film was controversial because of its graphic violence and its portrayal of crude men attempting to survive by any available means.It features William Holden, Robert Ryan, Ernest Borgnine, Ben Johnson and Warren Oates. The screenplay was by Peckinpah and Walon Green.It is noted for intricate, multi-angle editing, using normal and slow motion images, a revolutionary cinema technique during its time of release in 1969. After a failed payroll robbery, the outlaw Bunch, led by aging Pike Bishop and including Dutch, Angel, and Lyle and Tector Gorch, heads for Mexico pursued by the gang of Pike's friend-turned-nemesis Deke Thornton.Ultimately caught between the corruption of railroad fat cat Harrigan and Federal general Mapache, and without a frontier for escape, the Bunch opts for a final Pyrrhic victory, striding purposefully to confront Mapache and avenge their friend Angel. "If they move, kill 'em!" Beginning and ending with two of the bloodiest battles in screen history, Sam Peckinpah's classic revisionist Western ruthlessly takes apart the myths of the West. Released in the late '60s discord over Vietnam, in the wake of the controversial Bonnie and Clyde nihilism of the times, while the other reviled it as depraved. But nevertheless, it takes the basic elements of the Western movie myth, which once defined a simple, morally comprehensible world, and by bending them turns them into symbols of futility and aimless corruption. Also,credit Peckinpah's success in setting the scenes and the sketches of a dozen vividly individualized characters, and choreographs one of the most realistic, influential, brilliantly photographed shootouts under the pitiless sun. The cast is superb, the dialog crackling, the bitterly ambiguous moral of the story hard-earned.One of the best Westerns ever released on screen.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not wild about this bunch
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brefane
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Stunningly photographed by Lucien Ballard, The Wild Bunch is a gorgeous looking and stunningly directed bore, yes, bore. Pacing is sorely lacking, and the direction, accomplished as it is, is sometimes undercut by the splintered editing. Despite the hyperactive editing, the film drags, and talk, most of it insignificant, fills the time between scenes of abstract violence. I didn't really care for or about the characters as I did in Kurosawa's The Seven Samurai or Pechnipah's Ride the High Country hence 21/2 hrs with them was too much. Sure the set pieces are terrific and worth watching, but pieces do not translate into a satisfactory whole. The acting is good, particularly Borgnine, Ryan, and Holden talented actors relegated to forgettable films during the 60's so The Wild Bunch was a last hurrah for them as well. The supporting cast has a convincing look and feel as does the film. Released the same year as the far more traditional Oscar-winning westerns Butch Cassidy and the Sundance Kid and True Grit, The Wild Bunch was nominated for 2 Oscars, for Original Screenplay and Score, though it's the direction, editing and cinematography that are outstanding.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The End Of A Golden Age
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nick-leonardi
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A group of aging outlaws, after a bloody and violent battle taking place in a small town, decide they want to accomplish one last hit before retiring: a train heist to get weapons, to give them to a Mexican general who promises them good money. The Bunch meanwhile is chased by Deke Thornton (a man who used to be in the Bunch), who's pressured by the risk of going back to Yuma if he fails to capture the old comrades. Sam Peckinpah's fifth film as a director has all of the qualities of a magnum opus: epic narrative structure, a vast, varied and always gorgeous array of sceneries, memorable and likable protagonists (William Holden, Ernest Borgnine, Warren Oates, Ben Johnson, Jamie Sanchez), masterful and innovative directing: the battle scenes are full of repeated slow motion shots and fast and complex editing choices. The Revisionist Western film par excellence: the beloved world of the West is portrayed as an ugly, dangerous, savage place, in which everyone is selfish, greedy, and cynical; but this world is also seen at its twilight, at the closing of the frontier, as the East brings in more and more modernization. Nominated for 2 Oscars.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Makes Rambo Look Like a Sissy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin6942
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An aging group of outlaws look for one last big score as the "traditional" American West is disappearing around them. The film starts off with a group of children watching a scorpion in an anthill. I knew this had to be symbolic, but I did not fully grasp how until the film was over. Seeing it now, it really tied the film together with a nice bookend and foreshadowing. Wow. The story is a good one, full of a moral morass. The "good guys" are as despicable as the outlaws, perhaps even more. Who do we cheer for? And the body count... wow (again). I can only imagine how many squibs were used for this movie, because blood and bullets were busting out everywhere. A good story, plenty of action, and Ernest Borgnine...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sam Peckinpah's Grand Slam
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    georgep53
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw a Director's Cut of "The Wild Bunch" on the big screen a couple of nights ago and although 43 years have passed it's still one helluva kick in the gut. I could tell how deeply this film has touched people by the reactions from the audience and obviously with so many IMDb reviews "The Wild Bunch" has made a lasting impression. There's so much to praise from the great performances of William Holden, Ernest Borgnine, Robert Ryan, Ben Johnson, Warren Oates and Edmond O'Brien to the great work of cinematographer Lucien Ballard and editor Lou Lombardo; the intricate screenplay by Peckinpah and Walon Green and Sam Peckinpah's bold, uncompromising direction. "The Wild Bunch" belongs to a group of films like "Butch Cassidy and the Sundance Kid" and "Lonely Are the Brave" that depict the cowboy/gunslinger as an anachronism in the face of a rapidly advancing modernity. They know their time is running out but the lure of one last job; the bonds between them and their adversaries' commitment to bringing them to justice lock them in a life and death struggle. The machine gun that figures so prominently in the conclusion is a great symbol of the mechanized slaughter that would come to dominate the 20th century. I loved the allegorical imagery of the scorpions and the ants locked in a battle to the death under the eager, enthusiastic eyes of children and by extension, us. William Holden gives one of his best performances in the role of Bishop Pike, aging leader of the Bunch. Robert Ryan is memorable as Deke Thornton, his former partner and current pursuer. Thornton feels disdain for the greedy, incompetent, railroad bosses who hate Pike. They have even less concern for human life than the outlaws.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A classic in every way.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Scott LeBrun (Hey_Sweden)
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sam Peckinpah's masterful movie is an incredible piece of work; much as its main characters realize that the way of the Old West are changing, so too does his movie acknowledge the evolution of the whole Western genre. No longer were ideas of "good" and "bad" so clearly defined. No longer did people merely clutch themselves and fall over when fatally shot; here we see bloody bullet penetration in all of its Technicolor glory. And there is one constant and admirable theme running throughout, that of a man's need to stand by his fellow men. Loyalty means a lot to ageing outlaw Pike Bishop (William Holden, in a fantastic change of pace performance). He and his fellow outlaws - Dutch (Ernest Borgnine), the Gorch brothers (Warren Oates and Ben Johnson), and Angel (Jaime Sanchez) can see that things are changing all around them, as they are witness to the marvel of automobiles and even the variety of "car" that can fly. As they look to make one last big score before they pack it in, they're trailed by Pike's old comrade Deke Thornton (Robert Ryan), not terribly happy to be pursuing his former friend, but having very little choice in the matter. The characters are all quite colourful and interesting, and each actor gets a chance to shine as the intricate, well written (by Peckinpah and Walon Green, based on Green's and Roy N. Sickner's story) plot plays itself out. And this is a true "man's" movie, one in which the female characters don't fare too well, so this may not be to all tastes, but it's hard to deny the punch that this movie packs. It's extremely tense and exciting, with excellently staged action scenes, and plenty of squibs going off. Technically, this movie is a marvel, scored (by Jerry Fielding), lit (by Lucien Ballard), and edited (by Lou Lombardo) to perfection. It's a very rich looking experience that makes full use of its Panavision aspect ratio. The opening robbery scene is wonderfully intense (and features that memorable line, "If they move, kill them."); it will have you on the edge of your seat. Many fine sequences, with the robbery of guns and ammo from a train and the climactic shootout definite standouts. In addition to those actors already mentioned, solid contributions are made by a number of great character players: Edmond O'Brien, Strother Martin, L.Q. Jones (those last two making for a priceless comedy relief duo), Albert Dekker, Bo Hopkins, Dub Taylor, Emilio Fernandez, and Alfonso Arau. Poignant moments are mixed with some sharp dialogue, some good laughs, thrilling moments, and a high fun factor to make this well worth watching for any film fan, not just Western aficionados. As it reaches its conclusion, it would be too hard not to cheer seeing four of our main characters march side by side, guns at the ready, as they prepare to meet their destiny. The result of all of this is something truly unforgettable. 10 out of 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What to Expect: The Wild Bunch
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Film Watchin Fool
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Why You Might Like It: If you are a fan of Westerns, then you will likely enjoy this movie. It is a bit different than your traditional Western as it is action-packed at times and has an over the top shoot em up fill to it. The acting is great and the directing by Peckinpah is very fresh to this genre of movies and makes for a fun watch. Why You Might Not Like It: As most Westerns do, it has its slow spots that will make some lose interest. Also, this film is rated very high, so many will go into it with lofty expectations that it may or may not live up to. Acting/Casting: 8* - There is no shortage of great acting and cast members in this film. I am a huge fan of both William Holden and Robert Ryan in particular. Directing/Cinematography/Technical: 8* - Peckinpah does a fantastic job and many of the gun fight scenes are something to marvel for the film being made in 1969. Plot/Characters: 7* - The story has many layers and is pretty impressive. It starts out with a robbery, progresses into bounty hunting, and ends up being about loyalty. Entertainment Value: 7* - I really enjoyed this movie and was extremely impressed by the gun fight scenes, which are the highlight of the movie in my opinion. I would recommend this to fans of Western films and will likely watch again some time down the road. My Score: 8+8+7+7 = 30/4 = 7.5 Email your thoughts to filmwatchinfool@gmail.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Glossy, outdated violence and not much else
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Conrad
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sam Peckinpah wants you to know that Hollywood is at last free of its self-imposed Hays Code. He sets out to create the most violent Western to date, and he succeeds. The body count here is higher than in some wars. Every death is captured in slow-motion and augmented with jets of blood. Perhaps these novel visuals were thrilling and shocking to moviegoers in the late 1960s, but decades later desensitization has long since set in. The violence in "The Wild Bunch" has not aged well, and there is little else of interest in the film. A thin storyline links one scene of carnage to the next, but the movie doesn't know what to do with its characters between the action. A sentimental musical score plays to the point of distraction throughout the film but should fool nobody into caring about any of the people on screen. It is, however, nice to see the underrated Robert Ryan in a starring role.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An unsparing vision of the dream of innocence, and of human failure. . . .
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    malcolmi
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You can ride with a gang that seems to share a rough code of honour, but you'll be pursued by a former friend who's betraying you to stay out of prison. You can try to earn an easy score through the bloody hard work of robbing a bank, or a railroad, and cross the river into the freedom of a country where no law applies to you, but once you've crossed the river you'll be consumed by the chaos that always flourishes in the absence of law. You can try to rescue a friend, but your gesture will be rendered useless by a knife blade's flash. Then, when there's no more running, and nowhere to run to, when you've given your word and found that no one values it, when you've played out your string right to the end, what will you do? The Wild Bunch is Sam Peckinpah's exploration of that question. An artist who knew and loved life on the land, who knew well, and hated, the corruptions of 'civilization', and was compelled to cross the border into lawless territory, to seek a freedom which his own knowledge could never let him inhabit, Peckinpah made this marvellous film. It's set in a physical and spiritual landscape that any thinking middle-aged man is appallingly familiar with - the world of turning a blind eye to one's own cruelty, of watching one's hopes trashed by malevolence and stupidity, of being betrayed by friends, of fantasizing about the stroke of good luck that will let a man walk away from his compromises and failures. And Peckinpah's refusal to accept false sentiment reflects a middle-aged man's knowledge that self-interest and cruelty tempt even the very young, that even the powerful dream of being a child again is an illusion promising no peace. The children dream of being as brave and powerful as the adults whose violent actions are so seductively exciting. In the film's penultimate cathartic moment, it's a child who pulls the rifle's trigger. So, in the face of the disintegration of his world, and the impossibility of returning to innocence, what must a man do? No, the characters in this film are not honourable. But they dream of honourable actions - helping one's countrymen, one's village, one's friends. Yes, the idea of the frontier as an escape, and a new beginning, dies, in a welter of bullets after a man is dragged by technology across the abrasive landscape of his failure to see the consequences of his own actions. But the freedom of the frontier is its uncompromising offer of a chance to assess what's really true about existence. Sam Peckinpah knew that the assessment was the important thing. Death will happen. . . the important thing is to be ready to face death honestly, and so be able to live truly. The Wild Bunch isn't a young person's film, but for people who are ready to live in the minute details of existence faced honestly, ready to face the inevitable truth of death, The Wild Bunch is the necessary film. Peckinpah's clear vision cost him his happiness, and his health, finally, but left the rest of us a tough, miraculous, work of art.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The wages of sin is...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Wuchak
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ...death. That's the moral of Sam Peckinpah's classic 1969 Western about a group of aging and meandering outlaws who ride into Mexico in 1913 to flee a posse led by a former member, Deke Thornton (Robert Ryan). The outlaws, led by Pike Bishop (William Holden), eventually take refuge with a Mexican "general" and his hundreds of soldiers. When the Mexican member of the gang, Angel, is taken captive by the general for his revolutionary interests the rest of the gang have to decide whether to ignore it or make a bold stand. The Director's Cut of "The Wild Bunch" (1969) runs 145 minutes and features a great opening shootout and an outstanding closing shootout, a catharsis of blood; in the middle is a compelling train robbery. The material in between these three sequences isn't all that engrossing due to the fact that the characters aren't noble, likable or even redeemable, which is the film's weakness. I get the pessimistic message, but it doesn't change the fact that practically every character is an immoral or amoral dirtbag. Speaking of which, Deke Thornton has the audacity to repeatedly call the members of his posse "gutter trash" and the like. Well, what is he? A freed-on-condition prisoner who was once a member of the outlaw scum. At least the posse members -- lowlifes that they are -- are on the right side of the law. What hypocrisy. As noted above, a lot of dialogue and drama is devoted to character development, but who cares about a bunch of criminal scumbags? How can you devote "character development" to people who have no character? That's the problem with the film. That said, if you can accept the de-glorification of the Old West and the unlikable characters, "The Wild Bunch" is a solid Western with three thrilling sequences, including the unforgettable ending. There's a good message about the boldness of taking a stand and sticking by one's comrades, but that's the extent of the depth. GRADE: C+ or B-
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One Of The Best Westerns Ever Released
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Wild Bunch is a Western directed by Sam Peckinpah about an aging outlaw gang on the Texas-Mexico border, trying to exist in the changing modern world of 1913. The film was controversial because of its graphic violence and its portrayal of crude men attempting to survive by any available means.It features William Holden, Robert Ryan, Ernest Borgnine, Ben Johnson and Warren Oates. The screenplay was by Peckinpah and Walon Green.It is noted for intricate, multi-angle editing, using normal and slow motion images, a revolutionary cinema technique during its time of release in 1969. After a failed payroll robbery, the outlaw Bunch, led by aging Pike Bishop and including Dutch, Angel, and Lyle and Tector Gorch, heads for Mexico pursued by the gang of Pike's friend-turned-nemesis Deke Thornton.Ultimately caught between the corruption of railroad fat cat Harrigan and Federal general Mapache, and without a frontier for escape, the Bunch opts for a final Pyrrhic victory, striding purposefully to confront Mapache and avenge their friend Angel. "If they move, kill 'em!" Beginning and ending with two of the bloodiest battles in screen history, Sam Peckinpah's classic revisionist Western ruthlessly takes apart the myths of the West. Released in the late '60s discord over Vietnam, in the wake of the controversial Bonnie and Clyde nihilism of the times, while the other reviled it as depraved. But nevertheless, it takes the basic elements of the Western movie myth, which once defined a simple, morally comprehensible world, and by bending them turns them into symbols of futility and aimless corruption. Also,credit Peckinpah's success in setting the scenes and the sketches of a dozen vividly individualized characters, and choreographs one of the most realistic, influential, brilliantly photographed shootouts under the pitiless sun. The cast is superb, the dialog crackling, the bitterly ambiguous moral of the story hard-earned.One of the best Westerns ever released on screen.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not wild about this bunch
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brefane
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Stunningly photographed by Lucien Ballard, The Wild Bunch is a gorgeous looking and stunningly directed bore, yes, bore. Pacing is sorely lacking, and the direction, accomplished as it is, is sometimes undercut by the splintered editing. Despite the hyperactive editing, the film drags, and talk, most of it insignificant, fills the time between scenes of abstract violence. I didn't really care for or about the characters as I did in Kurosawa's The Seven Samurai or Pechnipah's Ride the High Country hence 21/2 hrs with them was too much. Sure the set pieces are terrific and worth watching, but pieces do not translate into a satisfactory whole. The acting is good, particularly Borgnine, Ryan, and Holden talented actors relegated to forgettable films during the 60's so The Wild Bunch was a last hurrah for them as well. The supporting cast has a convincing look and feel as does the film. Released the same year as the far more traditional Oscar-winning westerns Butch Cassidy and the Sundance Kid and True Grit, The Wild Bunch was nominated for 2 Oscars, for Original Screenplay and Score, though it's the direction, editing and cinematography that are outstanding.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The End Of A Golden Age
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nick-leonardi
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A group of aging outlaws, after a bloody and violent battle taking place in a small town, decide they want to accomplish one last hit before retiring: a train heist to get weapons, to give them to a Mexican general who promises them good money. The Bunch meanwhile is chased by Deke Thornton (a man who used to be in the Bunch), who's pressured by the risk of going back to Yuma if he fails to capture the old comrades. Sam Peckinpah's fifth film as a director has all of the qualities of a magnum opus: epic narrative structure, a vast, varied and always gorgeous array of sceneries, memorable and likable protagonists (William Holden, Ernest Borgnine, Warren Oates, Ben Johnson, Jamie Sanchez), masterful and innovative directing: the battle scenes are full of repeated slow motion shots and fast and complex editing choices. The Revisionist Western film par excellence: the beloved world of the West is portrayed as an ugly, dangerous, savage place, in which everyone is selfish, greedy, and cynical; but this world is also seen at its twilight, at the closing of the frontier, as the East brings in more and more modernization. Nominated for 2 Oscars.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Makes Rambo Look Like a Sissy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin6942
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An aging group of outlaws look for one last big score as the "traditional" American West is disappearing around them. The film starts off with a group of children watching a scorpion in an anthill. I knew this had to be symbolic, but I did not fully grasp how until the film was over. Seeing it now, it really tied the film together with a nice bookend and foreshadowing. Wow. The story is a good one, full of a moral morass. The "good guys" are as despicable as the outlaws, perhaps even more. Who do we cheer for? And the body count... wow (again). I can only imagine how many squibs were used for this movie, because blood and bullets were busting out everywhere. A good story, plenty of action, and Ernest Borgnine...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sam Peckinpah's Grand Slam
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    georgep53
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw a Director's Cut of "The Wild Bunch" on the big screen a couple of nights ago and although 43 years have passed it's still one helluva kick in the gut. I could tell how deeply this film has touched people by the reactions from the audience and obviously with so many IMDb reviews "The Wild Bunch" has made a lasting impression. There's so much to praise from the great performances of William Holden, Ernest Borgnine, Robert Ryan, Ben Johnson, Warren Oates and Edmond O'Brien to the great work of cinematographer Lucien Ballard and editor Lou Lombardo; the intricate screenplay by Peckinpah and Walon Green and Sam Peckinpah's bold, uncompromising direction. "The Wild Bunch" belongs to a group of films like "Butch Cassidy and the Sundance Kid" and "Lonely Are the Brave" that depict the cowboy/gunslinger as an anachronism in the face of a rapidly advancing modernity. They know their time is running out but the lure of one last job; the bonds between them and their adversaries' commitment to bringing them to justice lock them in a life and death struggle. The machine gun that figures so prominently in the conclusion is a great symbol of the mechanized slaughter that would come to dominate the 20th century. I loved the allegorical imagery of the scorpions and the ants locked in a battle to the death under the eager, enthusiastic eyes of children and by extension, us. William Holden gives one of his best performances in the role of Bishop Pike, aging leader of the Bunch. Robert Ryan is memorable as Deke Thornton, his former partner and current pursuer. Thornton feels disdain for the greedy, incompetent, railroad bosses who hate Pike. They have even less concern for human life than the outlaws.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A classic in every way.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Scott LeBrun (Hey_Sweden)
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sam Peckinpah's masterful movie is an incredible piece of work; much as its main characters realize that the way of the Old West are changing, so too does his movie acknowledge the evolution of the whole Western genre. No longer were ideas of "good" and "bad" so clearly defined. No longer did people merely clutch themselves and fall over when fatally shot; here we see bloody bullet penetration in all of its Technicolor glory. And there is one constant and admirable theme running throughout, that of a man's need to stand by his fellow men. Loyalty means a lot to ageing outlaw Pike Bishop (William Holden, in a fantastic change of pace performance). He and his fellow outlaws - Dutch (Ernest Borgnine), the Gorch brothers (Warren Oates and Ben Johnson), and Angel (Jaime Sanchez) can see that things are changing all around them, as they are witness to the marvel of automobiles and even the variety of "car" that can fly. As they look to make one last big score before they pack it in, they're trailed by Pike's old comrade Deke Thornton (Robert Ryan), not terribly happy to be pursuing his former friend, but having very little choice in the matter. The characters are all quite colourful and interesting, and each actor gets a chance to shine as the intricate, well written (by Peckinpah and Walon Green, based on Green's and Roy N. Sickner's story) plot plays itself out. And this is a true "man's" movie, one in which the female characters don't fare too well, so this may not be to all tastes, but it's hard to deny the punch that this movie packs. It's extremely tense and exciting, with excellently staged action scenes, and plenty of squibs going off. Technically, this movie is a marvel, scored (by Jerry Fielding), lit (by Lucien Ballard), and edited (by Lou Lombardo) to perfection. It's a very rich looking experience that makes full use of its Panavision aspect ratio. The opening robbery scene is wonderfully intense (and features that memorable line, "If they move, kill them."); it will have you on the edge of your seat. Many fine sequences, with the robbery of guns and ammo from a train and the climactic shootout definite standouts. In addition to those actors already mentioned, solid contributions are made by a number of great character players: Edmond O'Brien, Strother Martin, L.Q. Jones (those last two making for a priceless comedy relief duo), Albert Dekker, Bo Hopkins, Dub Taylor, Emilio Fernandez, and Alfonso Arau. Poignant moments are mixed with some sharp dialogue, some good laughs, thrilling moments, and a high fun factor to make this well worth watching for any film fan, not just Western aficionados. As it reaches its conclusion, it would be too hard not to cheer seeing four of our main characters march side by side, guns at the ready, as they prepare to meet their destiny. The result of all of this is something truly unforgettable. 10 out of 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What to Expect: The Wild Bunch
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Film Watchin Fool
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Why You Might Like It: If you are a fan of Westerns, then you will likely enjoy this movie. It is a bit different than your traditional Western as it is action-packed at times and has an over the top shoot em up fill to it. The acting is great and the directing by Peckinpah is very fresh to this genre of movies and makes for a fun watch. Why You Might Not Like It: As most Westerns do, it has its slow spots that will make some lose interest. Also, this film is rated very high, so many will go into it with lofty expectations that it may or may not live up to. Acting/Casting: 8* - There is no shortage of great acting and cast members in this film. I am a huge fan of both William Holden and Robert Ryan in particular. Directing/Cinematography/Technical: 8* - Peckinpah does a fantastic job and many of the gun fight scenes are something to marvel for the film being made in 1969. Plot/Characters: 7* - The story has many layers and is pretty impressive. It starts out with a robbery, progresses into bounty hunting, and ends up being about loyalty. Entertainment Value: 7* - I really enjoyed this movie and was extremely impressed by the gun fight scenes, which are the highlight of the movie in my opinion. I would recommend this to fans of Western films and will likely watch again some time down the road. My Score: 8+8+7+7 = 30/4 = 7.5 Email your thoughts to filmwatchinfool@gmail.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Glossy, outdated violence and not much else
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Conrad
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sam Peckinpah wants you to know that Hollywood is at last free of its self-imposed Hays Code. He sets out to create the most violent Western to date, and he succeeds. The body count here is higher than in some wars. Every death is captured in slow-motion and augmented with jets of blood. Perhaps these novel visuals were thrilling and shocking to moviegoers in the late 1960s, but decades later desensitization has long since set in. The violence in "The Wild Bunch" has not aged well, and there is little else of interest in the film. A thin storyline links one scene of carnage to the next, but the movie doesn't know what to do with its characters between the action. A sentimental musical score plays to the point of distraction throughout the film but should fool nobody into caring about any of the people on screen. It is, however, nice to see the underrated Robert Ryan in a starring role.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An unsparing vision of the dream of innocence, and of human failure. . . .
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    malcolmi
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You can ride with a gang that seems to share a rough code of honour, but you'll be pursued by a former friend who's betraying you to stay out of prison. You can try to earn an easy score through the bloody hard work of robbing a bank, or a railroad, and cross the river into the freedom of a country where no law applies to you, but once you've crossed the river you'll be consumed by the chaos that always flourishes in the absence of law. You can try to rescue a friend, but your gesture will be rendered useless by a knife blade's flash. Then, when there's no more running, and nowhere to run to, when you've given your word and found that no one values it, when you've played out your string right to the end, what will you do? The Wild Bunch is Sam Peckinpah's exploration of that question. An artist who knew and loved life on the land, who knew well, and hated, the corruptions of 'civilization', and was compelled to cross the border into lawless territory, to seek a freedom which his own knowledge could never let him inhabit, Peckinpah made this marvellous film. It's set in a physical and spiritual landscape that any thinking middle-aged man is appallingly familiar with - the world of turning a blind eye to one's own cruelty, of watching one's hopes trashed by malevolence and stupidity, of being betrayed by friends, of fantasizing about the stroke of good luck that will let a man walk away from his compromises and failures. And Peckinpah's refusal to accept false sentiment reflects a middle-aged man's knowledge that self-interest and cruelty tempt even the very young, that even the powerful dream of being a child again is an illusion promising no peace. The children dream of being as brave and powerful as the adults whose violent actions are so seductively exciting. In the film's penultimate cathartic moment, it's a child who pulls the rifle's trigger. So, in the face of the disintegration of his world, and the impossibility of returning to innocence, what must a man do? No, the characters in this film are not honourable. But they dream of honourable actions - helping one's countrymen, one's village, one's friends. Yes, the idea of the frontier as an escape, and a new beginning, dies, in a welter of bullets after a man is dragged by technology across the abrasive landscape of his failure to see the consequences of his own actions. But the freedom of the frontier is its uncompromising offer of a chance to assess what's really true about existence. Sam Peckinpah knew that the assessment was the important thing. Death will happen. . . the important thing is to be ready to face death honestly, and so be able to live truly. The Wild Bunch isn't a young person's film, but for people who are ready to live in the minute details of existence faced honestly, ready to face the inevitable truth of death, The Wild Bunch is the necessary film. Peckinpah's clear vision cost him his happiness, and his health, finally, but left the rest of us a tough, miraculous, work of art.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The wages of sin is...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Wuchak
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ...death. That's the moral of Sam Peckinpah's classic 1969 Western about a group of aging and meandering outlaws who ride into Mexico in 1913 to flee a posse led by a former member, Deke Thornton (Robert Ryan). The outlaws, led by Pike Bishop (William Holden), eventually take refuge with a Mexican "general" and his hundreds of soldiers. When the Mexican member of the gang, Angel, is taken captive by the general for his revolutionary interests the rest of the gang have to decide whether to ignore it or make a bold stand. The Director's Cut of "The Wild Bunch" (1969) runs 145 minutes and features a great opening shootout and an outstanding closing shootout, a catharsis of blood; in the middle is a compelling train robbery. The material in between these three sequences isn't all that engrossing due to the fact that the characters aren't noble, likable or even redeemable, which is the film's weakness. I get the pessimistic message, but it doesn't change the fact that practically every character is an immoral or amoral dirtbag. Speaking of which, Deke Thornton has the audacity to repeatedly call the members of his posse "gutter trash" and the like. Well, what is he? A freed-on-condition prisoner who was once a member of the outlaw scum. At least the posse members -- lowlifes that they are -- are on the right side of the law. What hypocrisy. As noted above, a lot of dialogue and drama is devoted to character development, but who cares about a bunch of criminal scumbags? How can you devote "character development" to people who have no character? That's the problem with the film. That said, if you can accept the de-glorification of the Old West and the unlikable characters, "The Wild Bunch" is a solid Western with three thrilling sequences, including the unforgettable ending. There's a good message about the boldness of taking a stand and sticking by one's comrades, but that's the extent of the depth. GRADE: C+ or B-
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One Of The Best Westerns Ever Released
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Wild Bunch is a Western directed by Sam Peckinpah about an aging outlaw gang on the Texas-Mexico border, trying to exist in the changing modern world of 1913. The film was controversial because of its graphic violence and its portrayal of crude men attempting to survive by any available means.It features William Holden, Robert Ryan, Ernest Borgnine, Ben Johnson and Warren Oates. The screenplay was by Peckinpah and Walon Green.It is noted for intricate, multi-angle editing, using normal and slow motion images, a revolutionary cinema technique during its time of release in 1969. After a failed payroll robbery, the outlaw Bunch, led by aging Pike Bishop and including Dutch, Angel, and Lyle and Tector Gorch, heads for Mexico pursued by the gang of Pike's friend-turned-nemesis Deke Thornton.Ultimately caught between the corruption of railroad fat cat Harrigan and Federal general Mapache, and without a frontier for escape, the Bunch opts for a final Pyrrhic victory, striding purposefully to confront Mapache and avenge their friend Angel. "If they move, kill 'em!" Beginning and ending with two of the bloodiest battles in screen history, Sam Peckinpah's classic revisionist Western ruthlessly takes apart the myths of the West. Released in the late '60s discord over Vietnam, in the wake of the controversial Bonnie and Clyde nihilism of the times, while the other reviled it as depraved. But nevertheless, it takes the basic elements of the Western movie myth, which once defined a simple, morally comprehensible world, and by bending them turns them into symbols of futility and aimless corruption. Also,credit Peckinpah's success in setting the scenes and the sketches of a dozen vividly individualized characters, and choreographs one of the most realistic, influential, brilliantly photographed shootouts under the pitiless sun. The cast is superb, the dialog crackling, the bitterly ambiguous moral of the story hard-earned.One of the best Westerns ever released on screen.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not wild about this bunch
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brefane
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Stunningly photographed by Lucien Ballard, The Wild Bunch is a gorgeous looking and stunningly directed bore, yes, bore. Pacing is sorely lacking, and the direction, accomplished as it is, is sometimes undercut by the splintered editing. Despite the hyperactive editing, the film drags, and talk, most of it insignificant, fills the time between scenes of abstract violence. I didn't really care for or about the characters as I did in Kurosawa's The Seven Samurai or Pechnipah's Ride the High Country hence 21/2 hrs with them was too much. Sure the set pieces are terrific and worth watching, but pieces do not translate into a satisfactory whole. The acting is good, particularly Borgnine, Ryan, and Holden talented actors relegated to forgettable films during the 60's so The Wild Bunch was a last hurrah for them as well. The supporting cast has a convincing look and feel as does the film. Released the same year as the far more traditional Oscar-winning westerns Butch Cassidy and the Sundance Kid and True Grit, The Wild Bunch was nominated for 2 Oscars, for Original Screenplay and Score, though it's the direction, editing and cinematography that are outstanding.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The End Of A Golden Age
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nick-leonardi
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A group of aging outlaws, after a bloody and violent battle taking place in a small town, decide they want to accomplish one last hit before retiring: a train heist to get weapons, to give them to a Mexican general who promises them good money. The Bunch meanwhile is chased by Deke Thornton (a man who used to be in the Bunch), who's pressured by the risk of going back to Yuma if he fails to capture the old comrades. Sam Peckinpah's fifth film as a director has all of the qualities of a magnum opus: epic narrative structure, a vast, varied and always gorgeous array of sceneries, memorable and likable protagonists (William Holden, Ernest Borgnine, Warren Oates, Ben Johnson, Jamie Sanchez), masterful and innovative directing: the battle scenes are full of repeated slow motion shots and fast and complex editing choices. The Revisionist Western film par excellence: the beloved world of the West is portrayed as an ugly, dangerous, savage place, in which everyone is selfish, greedy, and cynical; but this world is also seen at its twilight, at the closing of the frontier, as the East brings in more and more modernization. Nominated for 2 Oscars.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Makes Rambo Look Like a Sissy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin6942
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An aging group of outlaws look for one last big score as the "traditional" American West is disappearing around them. The film starts off with a group of children watching a scorpion in an anthill. I knew this had to be symbolic, but I did not fully grasp how until the film was over. Seeing it now, it really tied the film together with a nice bookend and foreshadowing. Wow. The story is a good one, full of a moral morass. The "good guys" are as despicable as the outlaws, perhaps even more. Who do we cheer for? And the body count... wow (again). I can only imagine how many squibs were used for this movie, because blood and bullets were busting out everywhere. A good story, plenty of action, and Ernest Borgnine...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sam Peckinpah's Grand Slam
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    georgep53
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw a Director's Cut of "The Wild Bunch" on the big screen a couple of nights ago and although 43 years have passed it's still one helluva kick in the gut. I could tell how deeply this film has touched people by the reactions from the audience and obviously with so many IMDb reviews "The Wild Bunch" has made a lasting impression. There's so much to praise from the great performances of William Holden, Ernest Borgnine, Robert Ryan, Ben Johnson, Warren Oates and Edmond O'Brien to the great work of cinematographer Lucien Ballard and editor Lou Lombardo; the intricate screenplay by Peckinpah and Walon Green and Sam Peckinpah's bold, uncompromising direction. "The Wild Bunch" belongs to a group of films like "Butch Cassidy and the Sundance Kid" and "Lonely Are the Brave" that depict the cowboy/gunslinger as an anachronism in the face of a rapidly advancing modernity. They know their time is running out but the lure of one last job; the bonds between them and their adversaries' commitment to bringing them to justice lock them in a life and death struggle. The machine gun that figures so prominently in the conclusion is a great symbol of the mechanized slaughter that would come to dominate the 20th century. I loved the allegorical imagery of the scorpions and the ants locked in a battle to the death under the eager, enthusiastic eyes of children and by extension, us. William Holden gives one of his best performances in the role of Bishop Pike, aging leader of the Bunch. Robert Ryan is memorable as Deke Thornton, his former partner and current pursuer. Thornton feels disdain for the greedy, incompetent, railroad bosses who hate Pike. They have even less concern for human life than the outlaws.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A classic in every way.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Scott LeBrun (Hey_Sweden)
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sam Peckinpah's masterful movie is an incredible piece of work; much as its main characters realize that the way of the Old West are changing, so too does his movie acknowledge the evolution of the whole Western genre. No longer were ideas of "good" and "bad" so clearly defined. No longer did people merely clutch themselves and fall over when fatally shot; here we see bloody bullet penetration in all of its Technicolor glory. And there is one constant and admirable theme running throughout, that of a man's need to stand by his fellow men. Loyalty means a lot to ageing outlaw Pike Bishop (William Holden, in a fantastic change of pace performance). He and his fellow outlaws - Dutch (Ernest Borgnine), the Gorch brothers (Warren Oates and Ben Johnson), and Angel (Jaime Sanchez) can see that things are changing all around them, as they are witness to the marvel of automobiles and even the variety of "car" that can fly. As they look to make one last big score before they pack it in, they're trailed by Pike's old comrade Deke Thornton (Robert Ryan), not terribly happy to be pursuing his former friend, but having very little choice in the matter. The characters are all quite colourful and interesting, and each actor gets a chance to shine as the intricate, well written (by Peckinpah and Walon Green, based on Green's and Roy N. Sickner's story) plot plays itself out. And this is a true "man's" movie, one in which the female characters don't fare too well, so this may not be to all tastes, but it's hard to deny the punch that this movie packs. It's extremely tense and exciting, with excellently staged action scenes, and plenty of squibs going off. Technically, this movie is a marvel, scored (by Jerry Fielding), lit (by Lucien Ballard), and edited (by Lou Lombardo) to perfection. It's a very rich looking experience that makes full use of its Panavision aspect ratio. The opening robbery scene is wonderfully intense (and features that memorable line, "If they move, kill them."); it will have you on the edge of your seat. Many fine sequences, with the robbery of guns and ammo from a train and the climactic shootout definite standouts. In addition to those actors already mentioned, solid contributions are made by a number of great character players: Edmond O'Brien, Strother Martin, L.Q. Jones (those last two making for a priceless comedy relief duo), Albert Dekker, Bo Hopkins, Dub Taylor, Emilio Fernandez, and Alfonso Arau. Poignant moments are mixed with some sharp dialogue, some good laughs, thrilling moments, and a high fun factor to make this well worth watching for any film fan, not just Western aficionados. As it reaches its conclusion, it would be too hard not to cheer seeing four of our main characters march side by side, guns at the ready, as they prepare to meet their destiny. The result of all of this is something truly unforgettable. 10 out of 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What to Expect: The Wild Bunch
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Film Watchin Fool
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Why You Might Like It: If you are a fan of Westerns, then you will likely enjoy this movie. It is a bit different than your traditional Western as it is action-packed at times and has an over the top shoot em up fill to it. The acting is great and the directing by Peckinpah is very fresh to this genre of movies and makes for a fun watch. Why You Might Not Like It: As most Westerns do, it has its slow spots that will make some lose interest. Also, this film is rated very high, so many will go into it with lofty expectations that it may or may not live up to. Acting/Casting: 8* - There is no shortage of great acting and cast members in this film. I am a huge fan of both William Holden and Robert Ryan in particular. Directing/Cinematography/Technical: 8* - Peckinpah does a fantastic job and many of the gun fight scenes are something to marvel for the film being made in 1969. Plot/Characters: 7* - The story has many layers and is pretty impressive. It starts out with a robbery, progresses into bounty hunting, and ends up being about loyalty. Entertainment Value: 7* - I really enjoyed this movie and was extremely impressed by the gun fight scenes, which are the highlight of the movie in my opinion. I would recommend this to fans of Western films and will likely watch again some time down the road. My Score: 8+8+7+7 = 30/4 = 7.5 Email your thoughts to filmwatchinfool@gmail.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Glossy, outdated violence and not much else
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Conrad
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sam Peckinpah wants you to know that Hollywood is at last free of its self-imposed Hays Code. He sets out to create the most violent Western to date, and he succeeds. The body count here is higher than in some wars. Every death is captured in slow-motion and augmented with jets of blood. Perhaps these novel visuals were thrilling and shocking to moviegoers in the late 1960s, but decades later desensitization has long since set in. The violence in "The Wild Bunch" has not aged well, and there is little else of interest in the film. A thin storyline links one scene of carnage to the next, but the movie doesn't know what to do with its characters between the action. A sentimental musical score plays to the point of distraction throughout the film but should fool nobody into caring about any of the people on screen. It is, however, nice to see the underrated Robert Ryan in a starring role.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An unsparing vision of the dream of innocence, and of human failure. . . .
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    malcolmi
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You can ride with a gang that seems to share a rough code of honour, but you'll be pursued by a former friend who's betraying you to stay out of prison. You can try to earn an easy score through the bloody hard work of robbing a bank, or a railroad, and cross the river into the freedom of a country where no law applies to you, but once you've crossed the river you'll be consumed by the chaos that always flourishes in the absence of law. You can try to rescue a friend, but your gesture will be rendered useless by a knife blade's flash. Then, when there's no more running, and nowhere to run to, when you've given your word and found that no one values it, when you've played out your string right to the end, what will you do? The Wild Bunch is Sam Peckinpah's exploration of that question. An artist who knew and loved life on the land, who knew well, and hated, the corruptions of 'civilization', and was compelled to cross the border into lawless territory, to seek a freedom which his own knowledge could never let him inhabit, Peckinpah made this marvellous film. It's set in a physical and spiritual landscape that any thinking middle-aged man is appallingly familiar with - the world of turning a blind eye to one's own cruelty, of watching one's hopes trashed by malevolence and stupidity, of being betrayed by friends, of fantasizing about the stroke of good luck that will let a man walk away from his compromises and failures. And Peckinpah's refusal to accept false sentiment reflects a middle-aged man's knowledge that self-interest and cruelty tempt even the very young, that even the powerful dream of being a child again is an illusion promising no peace. The children dream of being as brave and powerful as the adults whose violent actions are so seductively exciting. In the film's penultimate cathartic moment, it's a child who pulls the rifle's trigger. So, in the face of the disintegration of his world, and the impossibility of returning to innocence, what must a man do? No, the characters in this film are not honourable. But they dream of honourable actions - helping one's countrymen, one's village, one's friends. Yes, the idea of the frontier as an escape, and a new beginning, dies, in a welter of bullets after a man is dragged by technology across the abrasive landscape of his failure to see the consequences of his own actions. But the freedom of the frontier is its uncompromising offer of a chance to assess what's really true about existence. Sam Peckinpah knew that the assessment was the important thing. Death will happen. . . the important thing is to be ready to face death honestly, and so be able to live truly. The Wild Bunch isn't a young person's film, but for people who are ready to live in the minute details of existence faced honestly, ready to face the inevitable truth of death, The Wild Bunch is the necessary film. Peckinpah's clear vision cost him his happiness, and his health, finally, but left the rest of us a tough, miraculous, work of art.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The wages of sin is...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Wuchak
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ...death. That's the moral of Sam Peckinpah's classic 1969 Western about a group of aging and meandering outlaws who ride into Mexico in 1913 to flee a posse led by a former member, Deke Thornton (Robert Ryan). The outlaws, led by Pike Bishop (William Holden), eventually take refuge with a Mexican "general" and his hundreds of soldiers. When the Mexican member of the gang, Angel, is taken captive by the general for his revolutionary interests the rest of the gang have to decide whether to ignore it or make a bold stand. The Director's Cut of "The Wild Bunch" (1969) runs 145 minutes and features a great opening shootout and an outstanding closing shootout, a catharsis of blood; in the middle is a compelling train robbery. The material in between these three sequences isn't all that engrossing due to the fact that the characters aren't noble, likable or even redeemable, which is the film's weakness. I get the pessimistic message, but it doesn't change the fact that practically every character is an immoral or amoral dirtbag. Speaking of which, Deke Thornton has the audacity to repeatedly call the members of his posse "gutter trash" and the like. Well, what is he? A freed-on-condition prisoner who was once a member of the outlaw scum. At least the posse members -- lowlifes that they are -- are on the right side of the law. What hypocrisy. As noted above, a lot of dialogue and drama is devoted to character development, but who cares about a bunch of criminal scumbags? How can you devote "character development" to people who have no character? That's the problem with the film. That said, if you can accept the de-glorification of the Old West and the unlikable characters, "The Wild Bunch" is a solid Western with three thrilling sequences, including the unforgettable ending. There's a good message about the boldness of taking a stand and sticking by one's comrades, but that's the extent of the depth. GRADE: C+ or B-
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One Of The Best Westerns Ever Released
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Wild Bunch is a Western directed by Sam Peckinpah about an aging outlaw gang on the Texas-Mexico border, trying to exist in the changing modern world of 1913. The film was controversial because of its graphic violence and its portrayal of crude men attempting to survive by any available means.It features William Holden, Robert Ryan, Ernest Borgnine, Ben Johnson and Warren Oates. The screenplay was by Peckinpah and Walon Green.It is noted for intricate, multi-angle editing, using normal and slow motion images, a revolutionary cinema technique during its time of release in 1969. After a failed payroll robbery, the outlaw Bunch, led by aging Pike Bishop and including Dutch, Angel, and Lyle and Tector Gorch, heads for Mexico pursued by the gang of Pike's friend-turned-nemesis Deke Thornton.Ultimately caught between the corruption of railroad fat cat Harrigan and Federal general Mapache, and without a frontier for escape, the Bunch opts for a final Pyrrhic victory, striding purposefully to confront Mapache and avenge their friend Angel. "If they move, kill 'em!" Beginning and ending with two of the bloodiest battles in screen history, Sam Peckinpah's classic revisionist Western ruthlessly takes apart the myths of the West. Released in the late '60s discord over Vietnam, in the wake of the controversial Bonnie and Clyde nihilism of the times, while the other reviled it as depraved. But nevertheless, it takes the basic elements of the Western movie myth, which once defined a simple, morally comprehensible world, and by bending them turns them into symbols of futility and aimless corruption. Also,credit Peckinpah's success in setting the scenes and the sketches of a dozen vividly individualized characters, and choreographs one of the most realistic, influential, brilliantly photographed shootouts under the pitiless sun. The cast is superb, the dialog crackling, the bitterly ambiguous moral of the story hard-earned.One of the best Westerns ever released on screen.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not wild about this bunch
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brefane
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Stunningly photographed by Lucien Ballard, The Wild Bunch is a gorgeous looking and stunningly directed bore, yes, bore. Pacing is sorely lacking, and the direction, accomplished as it is, is sometimes undercut by the splintered editing. Despite the hyperactive editing, the film drags, and talk, most of it insignificant, fills the time between scenes of abstract violence. I didn't really care for or about the characters as I did in Kurosawa's The Seven Samurai or Pechnipah's Ride the High Country hence 21/2 hrs with them was too much. Sure the set pieces are terrific and worth watching, but pieces do not translate into a satisfactory whole. The acting is good, particularly Borgnine, Ryan, and Holden talented actors relegated to forgettable films during the 60's so The Wild Bunch was a last hurrah for them as well. The supporting cast has a convincing look and feel as does the film. Released the same year as the far more traditional Oscar-winning westerns Butch Cassidy and the Sundance Kid and True Grit, The Wild Bunch was nominated for 2 Oscars, for Original Screenplay and Score, though it's the direction, editing and cinematography that are outstanding.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The End Of A Golden Age
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nick-leonardi
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A group of aging outlaws, after a bloody and violent battle taking place in a small town, decide they want to accomplish one last hit before retiring: a train heist to get weapons, to give them to a Mexican general who promises them good money. The Bunch meanwhile is chased by Deke Thornton (a man who used to be in the Bunch), who's pressured by the risk of going back to Yuma if he fails to capture the old comrades. Sam Peckinpah's fifth film as a director has all of the qualities of a magnum opus: epic narrative structure, a vast, varied and always gorgeous array of sceneries, memorable and likable protagonists (William Holden, Ernest Borgnine, Warren Oates, Ben Johnson, Jamie Sanchez), masterful and innovative directing: the battle scenes are full of repeated slow motion shots and fast and complex editing choices. The Revisionist Western film par excellence: the beloved world of the West is portrayed as an ugly, dangerous, savage place, in which everyone is selfish, greedy, and cynical; but this world is also seen at its twilight, at the closing of the frontier, as the East brings in more and more modernization. Nominated for 2 Oscars.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Makes Rambo Look Like a Sissy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin6942
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An aging group of outlaws look for one last big score as the "traditional" American West is disappearing around them. The film starts off with a group of children watching a scorpion in an anthill. I knew this had to be symbolic, but I did not fully grasp how until the film was over. Seeing it now, it really tied the film together with a nice bookend and foreshadowing. Wow. The story is a good one, full of a moral morass. The "good guys" are as despicable as the outlaws, perhaps even more. Who do we cheer for? And the body count... wow (again). I can only imagine how many squibs were used for this movie, because blood and bullets were busting out everywhere. A good story, plenty of action, and Ernest Borgnine...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sam Peckinpah's Grand Slam
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    georgep53
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw a Director's Cut of "The Wild Bunch" on the big screen a couple of nights ago and although 43 years have passed it's still one helluva kick in the gut. I could tell how deeply this film has touched people by the reactions from the audience and obviously with so many IMDb reviews "The Wild Bunch" has made a lasting impression. There's so much to praise from the great performances of William Holden, Ernest Borgnine, Robert Ryan, Ben Johnson, Warren Oates and Edmond O'Brien to the great work of cinematographer Lucien Ballard and editor Lou Lombardo; the intricate screenplay by Peckinpah and Walon Green and Sam Peckinpah's bold, uncompromising direction. "The Wild Bunch" belongs to a group of films like "Butch Cassidy and the Sundance Kid" and "Lonely Are the Brave" that depict the cowboy/gunslinger as an anachronism in the face of a rapidly advancing modernity. They know their time is running out but the lure of one last job; the bonds between them and their adversaries' commitment to bringing them to justice lock them in a life and death struggle. The machine gun that figures so prominently in the conclusion is a great symbol of the mechanized slaughter that would come to dominate the 20th century. I loved the allegorical imagery of the scorpions and the ants locked in a battle to the death under the eager, enthusiastic eyes of children and by extension, us. William Holden gives one of his best performances in the role of Bishop Pike, aging leader of the Bunch. Robert Ryan is memorable as Deke Thornton, his former partner and current pursuer. Thornton feels disdain for the greedy, incompetent, railroad bosses who hate Pike. They have even less concern for human life than the outlaws.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A classic in every way.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Scott LeBrun (Hey_Sweden)
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sam Peckinpah's masterful movie is an incredible piece of work; much as its main characters realize that the way of the Old West are changing, so too does his movie acknowledge the evolution of the whole Western genre. No longer were ideas of "good" and "bad" so clearly defined. No longer did people merely clutch themselves and fall over when fatally shot; here we see bloody bullet penetration in all of its Technicolor glory. And there is one constant and admirable theme running throughout, that of a man's need to stand by his fellow men. Loyalty means a lot to ageing outlaw Pike Bishop (William Holden, in a fantastic change of pace performance). He and his fellow outlaws - Dutch (Ernest Borgnine), the Gorch brothers (Warren Oates and Ben Johnson), and Angel (Jaime Sanchez) can see that things are changing all around them, as they are witness to the marvel of automobiles and even the variety of "car" that can fly. As they look to make one last big score before they pack it in, they're trailed by Pike's old comrade Deke Thornton (Robert Ryan), not terribly happy to be pursuing his former friend, but having very little choice in the matter. The characters are all quite colourful and interesting, and each actor gets a chance to shine as the intricate, well written (by Peckinpah and Walon Green, based on Green's and Roy N. Sickner's story) plot plays itself out. And this is a true "man's" movie, one in which the female characters don't fare too well, so this may not be to all tastes, but it's hard to deny the punch that this movie packs. It's extremely tense and exciting, with excellently staged action scenes, and plenty of squibs going off. Technically, this movie is a marvel, scored (by Jerry Fielding), lit (by Lucien Ballard), and edited (by Lou Lombardo) to perfection. It's a very rich looking experience that makes full use of its Panavision aspect ratio. The opening robbery scene is wonderfully intense (and features that memorable line, "If they move, kill them."); it will have you on the edge of your seat. Many fine sequences, with the robbery of guns and ammo from a train and the climactic shootout definite standouts. In addition to those actors already mentioned, solid contributions are made by a number of great character players: Edmond O'Brien, Strother Martin, L.Q. Jones (those last two making for a priceless comedy relief duo), Albert Dekker, Bo Hopkins, Dub Taylor, Emilio Fernandez, and Alfonso Arau. Poignant moments are mixed with some sharp dialogue, some good laughs, thrilling moments, and a high fun factor to make this well worth watching for any film fan, not just Western aficionados. As it reaches its conclusion, it would be too hard not to cheer seeing four of our main characters march side by side, guns at the ready, as they prepare to meet their destiny. The result of all of this is something truly unforgettable. 10 out of 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What to Expect: The Wild Bunch
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Film Watchin Fool
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Why You Might Like It: If you are a fan of Westerns, then you will likely enjoy this movie. It is a bit different than your traditional Western as it is action-packed at times and has an over the top shoot em up fill to it. The acting is great and the directing by Peckinpah is very fresh to this genre of movies and makes for a fun watch. Why You Might Not Like It: As most Westerns do, it has its slow spots that will make some lose interest. Also, this film is rated very high, so many will go into it with lofty expectations that it may or may not live up to. Acting/Casting: 8* - There is no shortage of great acting and cast members in this film. I am a huge fan of both William Holden and Robert Ryan in particular. Directing/Cinematography/Technical: 8* - Peckinpah does a fantastic job and many of the gun fight scenes are something to marvel for the film being made in 1969. Plot/Characters: 7* - The story has many layers and is pretty impressive. It starts out with a robbery, progresses into bounty hunting, and ends up being about loyalty. Entertainment Value: 7* - I really enjoyed this movie and was extremely impressed by the gun fight scenes, which are the highlight of the movie in my opinion. I would recommend this to fans of Western films and will likely watch again some time down the road. My Score: 8+8+7+7 = 30/4 = 7.5 Email your thoughts to filmwatchinfool@gmail.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Glossy, outdated violence and not much else
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Conrad
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sam Peckinpah wants you to know that Hollywood is at last free of its self-imposed Hays Code. He sets out to create the most violent Western to date, and he succeeds. The body count here is higher than in some wars. Every death is captured in slow-motion and augmented with jets of blood. Perhaps these novel visuals were thrilling and shocking to moviegoers in the late 1960s, but decades later desensitization has long since set in. The violence in "The Wild Bunch" has not aged well, and there is little else of interest in the film. A thin storyline links one scene of carnage to the next, but the movie doesn't know what to do with its characters between the action. A sentimental musical score plays to the point of distraction throughout the film but should fool nobody into caring about any of the people on screen. It is, however, nice to see the underrated Robert Ryan in a starring role.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An unsparing vision of the dream of innocence, and of human failure. . . .
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    malcolmi
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You can ride with a gang that seems to share a rough code of honour, but you'll be pursued by a former friend who's betraying you to stay out of prison. You can try to earn an easy score through the bloody hard work of robbing a bank, or a railroad, and cross the river into the freedom of a country where no law applies to you, but once you've crossed the river you'll be consumed by the chaos that always flourishes in the absence of law. You can try to rescue a friend, but your gesture will be rendered useless by a knife blade's flash. Then, when there's no more running, and nowhere to run to, when you've given your word and found that no one values it, when you've played out your string right to the end, what will you do? The Wild Bunch is Sam Peckinpah's exploration of that question. An artist who knew and loved life on the land, who knew well, and hated, the corruptions of 'civilization', and was compelled to cross the border into lawless territory, to seek a freedom which his own knowledge could never let him inhabit, Peckinpah made this marvellous film. It's set in a physical and spiritual landscape that any thinking middle-aged man is appallingly familiar with - the world of turning a blind eye to one's own cruelty, of watching one's hopes trashed by malevolence and stupidity, of being betrayed by friends, of fantasizing about the stroke of good luck that will let a man walk away from his compromises and failures. And Peckinpah's refusal to accept false sentiment reflects a middle-aged man's knowledge that self-interest and cruelty tempt even the very young, that even the powerful dream of being a child again is an illusion promising no peace. The children dream of being as brave and powerful as the adults whose violent actions are so seductively exciting. In the film's penultimate cathartic moment, it's a child who pulls the rifle's trigger. So, in the face of the disintegration of his world, and the impossibility of returning to innocence, what must a man do? No, the characters in this film are not honourable. But they dream of honourable actions - helping one's countrymen, one's village, one's friends. Yes, the idea of the frontier as an escape, and a new beginning, dies, in a welter of bullets after a man is dragged by technology across the abrasive landscape of his failure to see the consequences of his own actions. But the freedom of the frontier is its uncompromising offer of a chance to assess what's really true about existence. Sam Peckinpah knew that the assessment was the important thing. Death will happen. . . the important thing is to be ready to face death honestly, and so be able to live truly. The Wild Bunch isn't a young person's film, but for people who are ready to live in the minute details of existence faced honestly, ready to face the inevitable truth of death, The Wild Bunch is the necessary film. Peckinpah's clear vision cost him his happiness, and his health, finally, but left the rest of us a tough, miraculous, work of art.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The wages of sin is...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Wuchak
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ...death. That's the moral of Sam Peckinpah's classic 1969 Western about a group of aging and meandering outlaws who ride into Mexico in 1913 to flee a posse led by a former member, Deke Thornton (Robert Ryan). The outlaws, led by Pike Bishop (William Holden), eventually take refuge with a Mexican "general" and his hundreds of soldiers. When the Mexican member of the gang, Angel, is taken captive by the general for his revolutionary interests the rest of the gang have to decide whether to ignore it or make a bold stand. The Director's Cut of "The Wild Bunch" (1969) runs 145 minutes and features a great opening shootout and an outstanding closing shootout, a catharsis of blood; in the middle is a compelling train robbery. The material in between these three sequences isn't all that engrossing due to the fact that the characters aren't noble, likable or even redeemable, which is the film's weakness. I get the pessimistic message, but it doesn't change the fact that practically every character is an immoral or amoral dirtbag. Speaking of which, Deke Thornton has the audacity to repeatedly call the members of his posse "gutter trash" and the like. Well, what is he? A freed-on-condition prisoner who was once a member of the outlaw scum. At least the posse members -- lowlifes that they are -- are on the right side of the law. What hypocrisy. As noted above, a lot of dialogue and drama is devoted to character development, but who cares about a bunch of criminal scumbags? How can you devote "character development" to people who have no character? That's the problem with the film. That said, if you can accept the de-glorification of the Old West and the unlikable characters, "The Wild Bunch" is a solid Western with three thrilling sequences, including the unforgettable ending. There's a good message about the boldness of taking a stand and sticking by one's comrades, but that's the extent of the depth. GRADE: C+ or B-
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One Of The Best Westerns Ever Released
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Wild Bunch is a Western directed by Sam Peckinpah about an aging outlaw gang on the Texas-Mexico border, trying to exist in the changing modern world of 1913. The film was controversial because of its graphic violence and its portrayal of crude men attempting to survive by any available means.It features William Holden, Robert Ryan, Ernest Borgnine, Ben Johnson and Warren Oates. The screenplay was by Peckinpah and Walon Green.It is noted for intricate, multi-angle editing, using normal and slow motion images, a revolutionary cinema technique during its time of release in 1969. After a failed payroll robbery, the outlaw Bunch, led by aging Pike Bishop and including Dutch, Angel, and Lyle and Tector Gorch, heads for Mexico pursued by the gang of Pike's friend-turned-nemesis Deke Thornton.Ultimately caught between the corruption of railroad fat cat Harrigan and Federal general Mapache, and without a frontier for escape, the Bunch opts for a final Pyrrhic victory, striding purposefully to confront Mapache and avenge their friend Angel. "If they move, kill 'em!" Beginning and ending with two of the bloodiest battles in screen history, Sam Peckinpah's classic revisionist Western ruthlessly takes apart the myths of the West. Released in the late '60s discord over Vietnam, in the wake of the controversial Bonnie and Clyde nihilism of the times, while the other reviled it as depraved. But nevertheless, it takes the basic elements of the Western movie myth, which once defined a simple, morally comprehensible world, and by bending them turns them into symbols of futility and aimless corruption. Also,credit Peckinpah's success in setting the scenes and the sketches of a dozen vividly individualized characters, and choreographs one of the most realistic, influential, brilliantly photographed shootouts under the pitiless sun. The cast is superb, the dialog crackling, the bitterly ambiguous moral of the story hard-earned.One of the best Westerns ever released on screen.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not wild about this bunch
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brefane
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Stunningly photographed by Lucien Ballard, The Wild Bunch is a gorgeous looking and stunningly directed bore, yes, bore. Pacing is sorely lacking, and the direction, accomplished as it is, is sometimes undercut by the splintered editing. Despite the hyperactive editing, the film drags, and talk, most of it insignificant, fills the time between scenes of abstract violence. I didn't really care for or about the characters as I did in Kurosawa's The Seven Samurai or Pechnipah's Ride the High Country hence 21/2 hrs with them was too much. Sure the set pieces are terrific and worth watching, but pieces do not translate into a satisfactory whole. The acting is good, particularly Borgnine, Ryan, and Holden talented actors relegated to forgettable films during the 60's so The Wild Bunch was a last hurrah for them as well. The supporting cast has a convincing look and feel as does the film. Released the same year as the far more traditional Oscar-winning westerns Butch Cassidy and the Sundance Kid and True Grit, The Wild Bunch was nominated for 2 Oscars, for Original Screenplay and Score, though it's the direction, editing and cinematography that are outstanding.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The End Of A Golden Age
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nick-leonardi
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A group of aging outlaws, after a bloody and violent battle taking place in a small town, decide they want to accomplish one last hit before retiring: a train heist to get weapons, to give them to a Mexican general who promises them good money. The Bunch meanwhile is chased by Deke Thornton (a man who used to be in the Bunch), who's pressured by the risk of going back to Yuma if he fails to capture the old comrades. Sam Peckinpah's fifth film as a director has all of the qualities of a magnum opus: epic narrative structure, a vast, varied and always gorgeous array of sceneries, memorable and likable protagonists (William Holden, Ernest Borgnine, Warren Oates, Ben Johnson, Jamie Sanchez), masterful and innovative directing: the battle scenes are full of repeated slow motion shots and fast and complex editing choices. The Revisionist Western film par excellence: the beloved world of the West is portrayed as an ugly, dangerous, savage place, in which everyone is selfish, greedy, and cynical; but this world is also seen at its twilight, at the closing of the frontier, as the East brings in more and more modernization. Nominated for 2 Oscars.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Makes Rambo Look Like a Sissy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin6942
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An aging group of outlaws look for one last big score as the "traditional" American West is disappearing around them. The film starts off with a group of children watching a scorpion in an anthill. I knew this had to be symbolic, but I did not fully grasp how until the film was over. Seeing it now, it really tied the film together with a nice bookend and foreshadowing. Wow. The story is a good one, full of a moral morass. The "good guys" are as despicable as the outlaws, perhaps even more. Who do we cheer for? And the body count... wow (again). I can only imagine how many squibs were used for this movie, because blood and bullets were busting out everywhere. A good story, plenty of action, and Ernest Borgnine...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sam Peckinpah's Grand Slam
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    georgep53
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw a Director's Cut of "The Wild Bunch" on the big screen a couple of nights ago and although 43 years have passed it's still one helluva kick in the gut. I could tell how deeply this film has touched people by the reactions from the audience and obviously with so many IMDb reviews "The Wild Bunch" has made a lasting impression. There's so much to praise from the great performances of William Holden, Ernest Borgnine, Robert Ryan, Ben Johnson, Warren Oates and Edmond O'Brien to the great work of cinematographer Lucien Ballard and editor Lou Lombardo; the intricate screenplay by Peckinpah and Walon Green and Sam Peckinpah's bold, uncompromising direction. "The Wild Bunch" belongs to a group of films like "Butch Cassidy and the Sundance Kid" and "Lonely Are the Brave" that depict the cowboy/gunslinger as an anachronism in the face of a rapidly advancing modernity. They know their time is running out but the lure of one last job; the bonds between them and their adversaries' commitment to bringing them to justice lock them in a life and death struggle. The machine gun that figures so prominently in the conclusion is a great symbol of the mechanized slaughter that would come to dominate the 20th century. I loved the allegorical imagery of the scorpions and the ants locked in a battle to the death under the eager, enthusiastic eyes of children and by extension, us. William Holden gives one of his best performances in the role of Bishop Pike, aging leader of the Bunch. Robert Ryan is memorable as Deke Thornton, his former partner and current pursuer. Thornton feels disdain for the greedy, incompetent, railroad bosses who hate Pike. They have even less concern for human life than the outlaws.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A classic in every way.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Scott LeBrun (Hey_Sweden)
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sam Peckinpah's masterful movie is an incredible piece of work; much as its main characters realize that the way of the Old West are changing, so too does his movie acknowledge the evolution of the whole Western genre. No longer were ideas of "good" and "bad" so clearly defined. No longer did people merely clutch themselves and fall over when fatally shot; here we see bloody bullet penetration in all of its Technicolor glory. And there is one constant and admirable theme running throughout, that of a man's need to stand by his fellow men. Loyalty means a lot to ageing outlaw Pike Bishop (William Holden, in a fantastic change of pace performance). He and his fellow outlaws - Dutch (Ernest Borgnine), the Gorch brothers (Warren Oates and Ben Johnson), and Angel (Jaime Sanchez) can see that things are changing all around them, as they are witness to the marvel of automobiles and even the variety of "car" that can fly. As they look to make one last big score before they pack it in, they're trailed by Pike's old comrade Deke Thornton (Robert Ryan), not terribly happy to be pursuing his former friend, but having very little choice in the matter. The characters are all quite colourful and interesting, and each actor gets a chance to shine as the intricate, well written (by Peckinpah and Walon Green, based on Green's and Roy N. Sickner's story) plot plays itself out. And this is a true "man's" movie, one in which the female characters don't fare too well, so this may not be to all tastes, but it's hard to deny the punch that this movie packs. It's extremely tense and exciting, with excellently staged action scenes, and plenty of squibs going off. Technically, this movie is a marvel, scored (by Jerry Fielding), lit (by Lucien Ballard), and edited (by Lou Lombardo) to perfection. It's a very rich looking experience that makes full use of its Panavision aspect ratio. The opening robbery scene is wonderfully intense (and features that memorable line, "If they move, kill them."); it will have you on the edge of your seat. Many fine sequences, with the robbery of guns and ammo from a train and the climactic shootout definite standouts. In addition to those actors already mentioned, solid contributions are made by a number of great character players: Edmond O'Brien, Strother Martin, L.Q. Jones (those last two making for a priceless comedy relief duo), Albert Dekker, Bo Hopkins, Dub Taylor, Emilio Fernandez, and Alfonso Arau. Poignant moments are mixed with some sharp dialogue, some good laughs, thrilling moments, and a high fun factor to make this well worth watching for any film fan, not just Western aficionados. As it reaches its conclusion, it would be too hard not to cheer seeing four of our main characters march side by side, guns at the ready, as they prepare to meet their destiny. The result of all of this is something truly unforgettable. 10 out of 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What to Expect: The Wild Bunch
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Film Watchin Fool
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Why You Might Like It: If you are a fan of Westerns, then you will likely enjoy this movie. It is a bit different than your traditional Western as it is action-packed at times and has an over the top shoot em up fill to it. The acting is great and the directing by Peckinpah is very fresh to this genre of movies and makes for a fun watch. Why You Might Not Like It: As most Westerns do, it has its slow spots that will make some lose interest. Also, this film is rated very high, so many will go into it with lofty expectations that it may or may not live up to. Acting/Casting: 8* - There is no shortage of great acting and cast members in this film. I am a huge fan of both William Holden and Robert Ryan in particular. Directing/Cinematography/Technical: 8* - Peckinpah does a fantastic job and many of the gun fight scenes are something to marvel for the film being made in 1969. Plot/Characters: 7* - The story has many layers and is pretty impressive. It starts out with a robbery, progresses into bounty hunting, and ends up being about loyalty. Entertainment Value: 7* - I really enjoyed this movie and was extremely impressed by the gun fight scenes, which are the highlight of the movie in my opinion. I would recommend this to fans of Western films and will likely watch again some time down the road. My Score: 8+8+7+7 = 30/4 = 7.5 Email your thoughts to filmwatchinfool@gmail.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Glossy, outdated violence and not much else
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Conrad
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sam Peckinpah wants you to know that Hollywood is at last free of its self-imposed Hays Code. He sets out to create the most violent Western to date, and he succeeds. The body count here is higher than in some wars. Every death is captured in slow-motion and augmented with jets of blood. Perhaps these novel visuals were thrilling and shocking to moviegoers in the late 1960s, but decades later desensitization has long since set in. The violence in "The Wild Bunch" has not aged well, and there is little else of interest in the film. A thin storyline links one scene of carnage to the next, but the movie doesn't know what to do with its characters between the action. A sentimental musical score plays to the point of distraction throughout the film but should fool nobody into caring about any of the people on screen. It is, however, nice to see the underrated Robert Ryan in a starring role.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An unsparing vision of the dream of innocence, and of human failure. . . .
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    malcolmi
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You can ride with a gang that seems to share a rough code of honour, but you'll be pursued by a former friend who's betraying you to stay out of prison. You can try to earn an easy score through the bloody hard work of robbing a bank, or a railroad, and cross the river into the freedom of a country where no law applies to you, but once you've crossed the river you'll be consumed by the chaos that always flourishes in the absence of law. You can try to rescue a friend, but your gesture will be rendered useless by a knife blade's flash. Then, when there's no more running, and nowhere to run to, when you've given your word and found that no one values it, when you've played out your string right to the end, what will you do? The Wild Bunch is Sam Peckinpah's exploration of that question. An artist who knew and loved life on the land, who knew well, and hated, the corruptions of 'civilization', and was compelled to cross the border into lawless territory, to seek a freedom which his own knowledge could never let him inhabit, Peckinpah made this marvellous film. It's set in a physical and spiritual landscape that any thinking middle-aged man is appallingly familiar with - the world of turning a blind eye to one's own cruelty, of watching one's hopes trashed by malevolence and stupidity, of being betrayed by friends, of fantasizing about the stroke of good luck that will let a man walk away from his compromises and failures. And Peckinpah's refusal to accept false sentiment reflects a middle-aged man's knowledge that self-interest and cruelty tempt even the very young, that even the powerful dream of being a child again is an illusion promising no peace. The children dream of being as brave and powerful as the adults whose violent actions are so seductively exciting. In the film's penultimate cathartic moment, it's a child who pulls the rifle's trigger. So, in the face of the disintegration of his world, and the impossibility of returning to innocence, what must a man do? No, the characters in this film are not honourable. But they dream of honourable actions - helping one's countrymen, one's village, one's friends. Yes, the idea of the frontier as an escape, and a new beginning, dies, in a welter of bullets after a man is dragged by technology across the abrasive landscape of his failure to see the consequences of his own actions. But the freedom of the frontier is its uncompromising offer of a chance to assess what's really true about existence. Sam Peckinpah knew that the assessment was the important thing. Death will happen. . . the important thing is to be ready to face death honestly, and so be able to live truly. The Wild Bunch isn't a young person's film, but for people who are ready to live in the minute details of existence faced honestly, ready to face the inevitable truth of death, The Wild Bunch is the necessary film. Peckinpah's clear vision cost him his happiness, and his health, finally, but left the rest of us a tough, miraculous, work of art.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The wages of sin is...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Wuchak
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ...death. That's the moral of Sam Peckinpah's classic 1969 Western about a group of aging and meandering outlaws who ride into Mexico in 1913 to flee a posse led by a former member, Deke Thornton (Robert Ryan). The outlaws, led by Pike Bishop (William Holden), eventually take refuge with a Mexican "general" and his hundreds of soldiers. When the Mexican member of the gang, Angel, is taken captive by the general for his revolutionary interests the rest of the gang have to decide whether to ignore it or make a bold stand. The Director's Cut of "The Wild Bunch" (1969) runs 145 minutes and features a great opening shootout and an outstanding closing shootout, a catharsis of blood; in the middle is a compelling train robbery. The material in between these three sequences isn't all that engrossing due to the fact that the characters aren't noble, likable or even redeemable, which is the film's weakness. I get the pessimistic message, but it doesn't change the fact that practically every character is an immoral or amoral dirtbag. Speaking of which, Deke Thornton has the audacity to repeatedly call the members of his posse "gutter trash" and the like. Well, what is he? A freed-on-condition prisoner who was once a member of the outlaw scum. At least the posse members -- lowlifes that they are -- are on the right side of the law. What hypocrisy. As noted above, a lot of dialogue and drama is devoted to character development, but who cares about a bunch of criminal scumbags? How can you devote "character development" to people who have no character? That's the problem with the film. That said, if you can accept the de-glorification of the Old West and the unlikable characters, "The Wild Bunch" is a solid Western with three thrilling sequences, including the unforgettable ending. There's a good message about the boldness of taking a stand and sticking by one's comrades, but that's the extent of the depth. GRADE: C+ or B-
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One Of The Best Westerns Ever Released
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Wild Bunch is a Western directed by Sam Peckinpah about an aging outlaw gang on the Texas-Mexico border, trying to exist in the changing modern world of 1913. The film was controversial because of its graphic violence and its portrayal of crude men attempting to survive by any available means.It features William Holden, Robert Ryan, Ernest Borgnine, Ben Johnson and Warren Oates. The screenplay was by Peckinpah and Walon Green.It is noted for intricate, multi-angle editing, using normal and slow motion images, a revolutionary cinema technique during its time of release in 1969. After a failed payroll robbery, the outlaw Bunch, led by aging Pike Bishop and including Dutch, Angel, and Lyle and Tector Gorch, heads for Mexico pursued by the gang of Pike's friend-turned-nemesis Deke Thornton.Ultimately caught between the corruption of railroad fat cat Harrigan and Federal general Mapache, and without a frontier for escape, the Bunch opts for a final Pyrrhic victory, striding purposefully to confront Mapache and avenge their friend Angel. "If they move, kill 'em!" Beginning and ending with two of the bloodiest battles in screen history, Sam Peckinpah's classic revisionist Western ruthlessly takes apart the myths of the West. Released in the late '60s discord over Vietnam, in the wake of the controversial Bonnie and Clyde nihilism of the times, while the other reviled it as depraved. But nevertheless, it takes the basic elements of the Western movie myth, which once defined a simple, morally comprehensible world, and by bending them turns them into symbols of futility and aimless corruption. Also,credit Peckinpah's success in setting the scenes and the sketches of a dozen vividly individualized characters, and choreographs one of the most realistic, influential, brilliantly photographed shootouts under the pitiless sun. The cast is superb, the dialog crackling, the bitterly ambiguous moral of the story hard-earned.One of the best Westerns ever released on screen.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not wild about this bunch
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brefane
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Stunningly photographed by Lucien Ballard, The Wild Bunch is a gorgeous looking and stunningly directed bore, yes, bore. Pacing is sorely lacking, and the direction, accomplished as it is, is sometimes undercut by the splintered editing. Despite the hyperactive editing, the film drags, and talk, most of it insignificant, fills the time between scenes of abstract violence. I didn't really care for or about the characters as I did in Kurosawa's The Seven Samurai or Pechnipah's Ride the High Country hence 21/2 hrs with them was too much. Sure the set pieces are terrific and worth watching, but pieces do not translate into a satisfactory whole. The acting is good, particularly Borgnine, Ryan, and Holden talented actors relegated to forgettable films during the 60's so The Wild Bunch was a last hurrah for them as well. The supporting cast has a convincing look and feel as does the film. Released the same year as the far more traditional Oscar-winning westerns Butch Cassidy and the Sundance Kid and True Grit, The Wild Bunch was nominated for 2 Oscars, for Original Screenplay and Score, though it's the direction, editing and cinematography that are outstanding.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The End Of A Golden Age
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nick-leonardi
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A group of aging outlaws, after a bloody and violent battle taking place in a small town, decide they want to accomplish one last hit before retiring: a train heist to get weapons, to give them to a Mexican general who promises them good money. The Bunch meanwhile is chased by Deke Thornton (a man who used to be in the Bunch), who's pressured by the risk of going back to Yuma if he fails to capture the old comrades. Sam Peckinpah's fifth film as a director has all of the qualities of a magnum opus: epic narrative structure, a vast, varied and always gorgeous array of sceneries, memorable and likable protagonists (William Holden, Ernest Borgnine, Warren Oates, Ben Johnson, Jamie Sanchez), masterful and innovative directing: the battle scenes are full of repeated slow motion shots and fast and complex editing choices. The Revisionist Western film par excellence: the beloved world of the West is portrayed as an ugly, dangerous, savage place, in which everyone is selfish, greedy, and cynical; but this world is also seen at its twilight, at the closing of the frontier, as the East brings in more and more modernization. Nominated for 2 Oscars.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Makes Rambo Look Like a Sissy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin6942
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An aging group of outlaws look for one last big score as the "traditional" American West is disappearing around them. The film starts off with a group of children watching a scorpion in an anthill. I knew this had to be symbolic, but I did not fully grasp how until the film was over. Seeing it now, it really tied the film together with a nice bookend and foreshadowing. Wow. The story is a good one, full of a moral morass. The "good guys" are as despicable as the outlaws, perhaps even more. Who do we cheer for? And the body count... wow (again). I can only imagine how many squibs were used for this movie, because blood and bullets were busting out everywhere. A good story, plenty of action, and Ernest Borgnine...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sam Peckinpah's Grand Slam
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    georgep53
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw a Director's Cut of "The Wild Bunch" on the big screen a couple of nights ago and although 43 years have passed it's still one helluva kick in the gut. I could tell how deeply this film has touched people by the reactions from the audience and obviously with so many IMDb reviews "The Wild Bunch" has made a lasting impression. There's so much to praise from the great performances of William Holden, Ernest Borgnine, Robert Ryan, Ben Johnson, Warren Oates and Edmond O'Brien to the great work of cinematographer Lucien Ballard and editor Lou Lombardo; the intricate screenplay by Peckinpah and Walon Green and Sam Peckinpah's bold, uncompromising direction. "The Wild Bunch" belongs to a group of films like "Butch Cassidy and the Sundance Kid" and "Lonely Are the Brave" that depict the cowboy/gunslinger as an anachronism in the face of a rapidly advancing modernity. They know their time is running out but the lure of one last job; the bonds between them and their adversaries' commitment to bringing them to justice lock them in a life and death struggle. The machine gun that figures so prominently in the conclusion is a great symbol of the mechanized slaughter that would come to dominate the 20th century. I loved the allegorical imagery of the scorpions and the ants locked in a battle to the death under the eager, enthusiastic eyes of children and by extension, us. William Holden gives one of his best performances in the role of Bishop Pike, aging leader of the Bunch. Robert Ryan is memorable as Deke Thornton, his former partner and current pursuer. Thornton feels disdain for the greedy, incompetent, railroad bosses who hate Pike. They have even less concern for human life than the outlaws.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A classic in every way.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Scott LeBrun (Hey_Sweden)
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sam Peckinpah's masterful movie is an incredible piece of work; much as its main characters realize that the way of the Old West are changing, so too does his movie acknowledge the evolution of the whole Western genre. No longer were ideas of "good" and "bad" so clearly defined. No longer did people merely clutch themselves and fall over when fatally shot; here we see bloody bullet penetration in all of its Technicolor glory. And there is one constant and admirable theme running throughout, that of a man's need to stand by his fellow men. Loyalty means a lot to ageing outlaw Pike Bishop (William Holden, in a fantastic change of pace performance). He and his fellow outlaws - Dutch (Ernest Borgnine), the Gorch brothers (Warren Oates and Ben Johnson), and Angel (Jaime Sanchez) can see that things are changing all around them, as they are witness to the marvel of automobiles and even the variety of "car" that can fly. As they look to make one last big score before they pack it in, they're trailed by Pike's old comrade Deke Thornton (Robert Ryan), not terribly happy to be pursuing his former friend, but having very little choice in the matter. The characters are all quite colourful and interesting, and each actor gets a chance to shine as the intricate, well written (by Peckinpah and Walon Green, based on Green's and Roy N. Sickner's story) plot plays itself out. And this is a true "man's" movie, one in which the female characters don't fare too well, so this may not be to all tastes, but it's hard to deny the punch that this movie packs. It's extremely tense and exciting, with excellently staged action scenes, and plenty of squibs going off. Technically, this movie is a marvel, scored (by Jerry Fielding), lit (by Lucien Ballard), and edited (by Lou Lombardo) to perfection. It's a very rich looking experience that makes full use of its Panavision aspect ratio. The opening robbery scene is wonderfully intense (and features that memorable line, "If they move, kill them."); it will have you on the edge of your seat. Many fine sequences, with the robbery of guns and ammo from a train and the climactic shootout definite standouts. In addition to those actors already mentioned, solid contributions are made by a number of great character players: Edmond O'Brien, Strother Martin, L.Q. Jones (those last two making for a priceless comedy relief duo), Albert Dekker, Bo Hopkins, Dub Taylor, Emilio Fernandez, and Alfonso Arau. Poignant moments are mixed with some sharp dialogue, some good laughs, thrilling moments, and a high fun factor to make this well worth watching for any film fan, not just Western aficionados. As it reaches its conclusion, it would be too hard not to cheer seeing four of our main characters march side by side, guns at the ready, as they prepare to meet their destiny. The result of all of this is something truly unforgettable. 10 out of 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What to Expect: The Wild Bunch
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Film Watchin Fool
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Why You Might Like It: If you are a fan of Westerns, then you will likely enjoy this movie. It is a bit different than your traditional Western as it is action-packed at times and has an over the top shoot em up fill to it. The acting is great and the directing by Peckinpah is very fresh to this genre of movies and makes for a fun watch. Why You Might Not Like It: As most Westerns do, it has its slow spots that will make some lose interest. Also, this film is rated very high, so many will go into it with lofty expectations that it may or may not live up to. Acting/Casting: 8* - There is no shortage of great acting and cast members in this film. I am a huge fan of both William Holden and Robert Ryan in particular. Directing/Cinematography/Technical: 8* - Peckinpah does a fantastic job and many of the gun fight scenes are something to marvel for the film being made in 1969. Plot/Characters: 7* - The story has many layers and is pretty impressive. It starts out with a robbery, progresses into bounty hunting, and ends up being about loyalty. Entertainment Value: 7* - I really enjoyed this movie and was extremely impressed by the gun fight scenes, which are the highlight of the movie in my opinion. I would recommend this to fans of Western films and will likely watch again some time down the road. My Score: 8+8+7+7 = 30/4 = 7.5 Email your thoughts to filmwatchinfool@gmail.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Glossy, outdated violence and not much else
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Conrad
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sam Peckinpah wants you to know that Hollywood is at last free of its self-imposed Hays Code. He sets out to create the most violent Western to date, and he succeeds. The body count here is higher than in some wars. Every death is captured in slow-motion and augmented with jets of blood. Perhaps these novel visuals were thrilling and shocking to moviegoers in the late 1960s, but decades later desensitization has long since set in. The violence in "The Wild Bunch" has not aged well, and there is little else of interest in the film. A thin storyline links one scene of carnage to the next, but the movie doesn't know what to do with its characters between the action. A sentimental musical score plays to the point of distraction throughout the film but should fool nobody into caring about any of the people on screen. It is, however, nice to see the underrated Robert Ryan in a starring role.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An unsparing vision of the dream of innocence, and of human failure. . . .
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    malcolmi
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You can ride with a gang that seems to share a rough code of honour, but you'll be pursued by a former friend who's betraying you to stay out of prison. You can try to earn an easy score through the bloody hard work of robbing a bank, or a railroad, and cross the river into the freedom of a country where no law applies to you, but once you've crossed the river you'll be consumed by the chaos that always flourishes in the absence of law. You can try to rescue a friend, but your gesture will be rendered useless by a knife blade's flash. Then, when there's no more running, and nowhere to run to, when you've given your word and found that no one values it, when you've played out your string right to the end, what will you do? The Wild Bunch is Sam Peckinpah's exploration of that question. An artist who knew and loved life on the land, who knew well, and hated, the corruptions of 'civilization', and was compelled to cross the border into lawless territory, to seek a freedom which his own knowledge could never let him inhabit, Peckinpah made this marvellous film. It's set in a physical and spiritual landscape that any thinking middle-aged man is appallingly familiar with - the world of turning a blind eye to one's own cruelty, of watching one's hopes trashed by malevolence and stupidity, of being betrayed by friends, of fantasizing about the stroke of good luck that will let a man walk away from his compromises and failures. And Peckinpah's refusal to accept false sentiment reflects a middle-aged man's knowledge that self-interest and cruelty tempt even the very young, that even the powerful dream of being a child again is an illusion promising no peace. The children dream of being as brave and powerful as the adults whose violent actions are so seductively exciting. In the film's penultimate cathartic moment, it's a child who pulls the rifle's trigger. So, in the face of the disintegration of his world, and the impossibility of returning to innocence, what must a man do? No, the characters in this film are not honourable. But they dream of honourable actions - helping one's countrymen, one's village, one's friends. Yes, the idea of the frontier as an escape, and a new beginning, dies, in a welter of bullets after a man is dragged by technology across the abrasive landscape of his failure to see the consequences of his own actions. But the freedom of the frontier is its uncompromising offer of a chance to assess what's really true about existence. Sam Peckinpah knew that the assessment was the important thing. Death will happen. . . the important thing is to be ready to face death honestly, and so be able to live truly. The Wild Bunch isn't a young person's film, but for people who are ready to live in the minute details of existence faced honestly, ready to face the inevitable truth of death, The Wild Bunch is the necessary film. Peckinpah's clear vision cost him his happiness, and his health, finally, but left the rest of us a tough, miraculous, work of art.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The wages of sin is...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Wuchak
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ...death. That's the moral of Sam Peckinpah's classic 1969 Western about a group of aging and meandering outlaws who ride into Mexico in 1913 to flee a posse led by a former member, Deke Thornton (Robert Ryan). The outlaws, led by Pike Bishop (William Holden), eventually take refuge with a Mexican "general" and his hundreds of soldiers. When the Mexican member of the gang, Angel, is taken captive by the general for his revolutionary interests the rest of the gang have to decide whether to ignore it or make a bold stand. The Director's Cut of "The Wild Bunch" (1969) runs 145 minutes and features a great opening shootout and an outstanding closing shootout, a catharsis of blood; in the middle is a compelling train robbery. The material in between these three sequences isn't all that engrossing due to the fact that the characters aren't noble, likable or even redeemable, which is the film's weakness. I get the pessimistic message, but it doesn't change the fact that practically every character is an immoral or amoral dirtbag. Speaking of which, Deke Thornton has the audacity to repeatedly call the members of his posse "gutter trash" and the like. Well, what is he? A freed-on-condition prisoner who was once a member of the outlaw scum. At least the posse members -- lowlifes that they are -- are on the right side of the law. What hypocrisy. As noted above, a lot of dialogue and drama is devoted to character development, but who cares about a bunch of criminal scumbags? How can you devote "character development" to people who have no character? That's the problem with the film. That said, if you can accept the de-glorification of the Old West and the unlikable characters, "The Wild Bunch" is a solid Western with three thrilling sequences, including the unforgettable ending. There's a good message about the boldness of taking a stand and sticking by one's comrades, but that's the extent of the depth. GRADE: C+ or B-
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One Of The Best Westerns Ever Released
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Wild Bunch is a Western directed by Sam Peckinpah about an aging outlaw gang on the Texas-Mexico border, trying to exist in the changing modern world of 1913. The film was controversial because of its graphic violence and its portrayal of crude men attempting to survive by any available means.It features William Holden, Robert Ryan, Ernest Borgnine, Ben Johnson and Warren Oates. The screenplay was by Peckinpah and Walon Green.It is noted for intricate, multi-angle editing, using normal and slow motion images, a revolutionary cinema technique during its time of release in 1969. After a failed payroll robbery, the outlaw Bunch, led by aging Pike Bishop and including Dutch, Angel, and Lyle and Tector Gorch, heads for Mexico pursued by the gang of Pike's friend-turned-nemesis Deke Thornton.Ultimately caught between the corruption of railroad fat cat Harrigan and Federal general Mapache, and without a frontier for escape, the Bunch opts for a final Pyrrhic victory, striding purposefully to confront Mapache and avenge their friend Angel. "If they move, kill 'em!" Beginning and ending with two of the bloodiest battles in screen history, Sam Peckinpah's classic revisionist Western ruthlessly takes apart the myths of the West. Released in the late '60s discord over Vietnam, in the wake of the controversial Bonnie and Clyde nihilism of the times, while the other reviled it as depraved. But nevertheless, it takes the basic elements of the Western movie myth, which once defined a simple, morally comprehensible world, and by bending them turns them into symbols of futility and aimless corruption. Also,credit Peckinpah's success in setting the scenes and the sketches of a dozen vividly individualized characters, and choreographs one of the most realistic, influential, brilliantly photographed shootouts under the pitiless sun. The cast is superb, the dialog crackling, the bitterly ambiguous moral of the story hard-earned.One of the best Westerns ever released on screen.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not wild about this bunch
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brefane
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Stunningly photographed by Lucien Ballard, The Wild Bunch is a gorgeous looking and stunningly directed bore, yes, bore. Pacing is sorely lacking, and the direction, accomplished as it is, is sometimes undercut by the splintered editing. Despite the hyperactive editing, the film drags, and talk, most of it insignificant, fills the time between scenes of abstract violence. I didn't really care for or about the characters as I did in Kurosawa's The Seven Samurai or Pechnipah's Ride the High Country hence 21/2 hrs with them was too much. Sure the set pieces are terrific and worth watching, but pieces do not translate into a satisfactory whole. The acting is good, particularly Borgnine, Ryan, and Holden talented actors relegated to forgettable films during the 60's so The Wild Bunch was a last hurrah for them as well. The supporting cast has a convincing look and feel as does the film. Released the same year as the far more traditional Oscar-winning westerns Butch Cassidy and the Sundance Kid and True Grit, The Wild Bunch was nominated for 2 Oscars, for Original Screenplay and Score, though it's the direction, editing and cinematography that are outstanding.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The End Of A Golden Age
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nick-leonardi
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A group of aging outlaws, after a bloody and violent battle taking place in a small town, decide they want to accomplish one last hit before retiring: a train heist to get weapons, to give them to a Mexican general who promises them good money. The Bunch meanwhile is chased by Deke Thornton (a man who used to be in the Bunch), who's pressured by the risk of going back to Yuma if he fails to capture the old comrades. Sam Peckinpah's fifth film as a director has all of the qualities of a magnum opus: epic narrative structure, a vast, varied and always gorgeous array of sceneries, memorable and likable protagonists (William Holden, Ernest Borgnine, Warren Oates, Ben Johnson, Jamie Sanchez), masterful and innovative directing: the battle scenes are full of repeated slow motion shots and fast and complex editing choices. The Revisionist Western film par excellence: the beloved world of the West is portrayed as an ugly, dangerous, savage place, in which everyone is selfish, greedy, and cynical; but this world is also seen at its twilight, at the closing of the frontier, as the East brings in more and more modernization. Nominated for 2 Oscars.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Makes Rambo Look Like a Sissy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin6942
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An aging group of outlaws look for one last big score as the "traditional" American West is disappearing around them. The film starts off with a group of children watching a scorpion in an anthill. I knew this had to be symbolic, but I did not fully grasp how until the film was over. Seeing it now, it really tied the film together with a nice bookend and foreshadowing. Wow. The story is a good one, full of a moral morass. The "good guys" are as despicable as the outlaws, perhaps even more. Who do we cheer for? And the body count... wow (again). I can only imagine how many squibs were used for this movie, because blood and bullets were busting out everywhere. A good story, plenty of action, and Ernest Borgnine...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sam Peckinpah's Grand Slam
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    georgep53
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw a Director's Cut of "The Wild Bunch" on the big screen a couple of nights ago and although 43 years have passed it's still one helluva kick in the gut. I could tell how deeply this film has touched people by the reactions from the audience and obviously with so many IMDb reviews "The Wild Bunch" has made a lasting impression. There's so much to praise from the great performances of William Holden, Ernest Borgnine, Robert Ryan, Ben Johnson, Warren Oates and Edmond O'Brien to the great work of cinematographer Lucien Ballard and editor Lou Lombardo; the intricate screenplay by Peckinpah and Walon Green and Sam Peckinpah's bold, uncompromising direction. "The Wild Bunch" belongs to a group of films like "Butch Cassidy and the Sundance Kid" and "Lonely Are the Brave" that depict the cowboy/gunslinger as an anachronism in the face of a rapidly advancing modernity. They know their time is running out but the lure of one last job; the bonds between them and their adversaries' commitment to bringing them to justice lock them in a life and death struggle. The machine gun that figures so prominently in the conclusion is a great symbol of the mechanized slaughter that would come to dominate the 20th century. I loved the allegorical imagery of the scorpions and the ants locked in a battle to the death under the eager, enthusiastic eyes of children and by extension, us. William Holden gives one of his best performances in the role of Bishop Pike, aging leader of the Bunch. Robert Ryan is memorable as Deke Thornton, his former partner and current pursuer. Thornton feels disdain for the greedy, incompetent, railroad bosses who hate Pike. They have even less concern for human life than the outlaws.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A classic in every way.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Scott LeBrun (Hey_Sweden)
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sam Peckinpah's masterful movie is an incredible piece of work; much as its main characters realize that the way of the Old West are changing, so too does his movie acknowledge the evolution of the whole Western genre. No longer were ideas of "good" and "bad" so clearly defined. No longer did people merely clutch themselves and fall over when fatally shot; here we see bloody bullet penetration in all of its Technicolor glory. And there is one constant and admirable theme running throughout, that of a man's need to stand by his fellow men. Loyalty means a lot to ageing outlaw Pike Bishop (William Holden, in a fantastic change of pace performance). He and his fellow outlaws - Dutch (Ernest Borgnine), the Gorch brothers (Warren Oates and Ben Johnson), and Angel (Jaime Sanchez) can see that things are changing all around them, as they are witness to the marvel of automobiles and even the variety of "car" that can fly. As they look to make one last big score before they pack it in, they're trailed by Pike's old comrade Deke Thornton (Robert Ryan), not terribly happy to be pursuing his former friend, but having very little choice in the matter. The characters are all quite colourful and interesting, and each actor gets a chance to shine as the intricate, well written (by Peckinpah and Walon Green, based on Green's and Roy N. Sickner's story) plot plays itself out. And this is a true "man's" movie, one in which the female characters don't fare too well, so this may not be to all tastes, but it's hard to deny the punch that this movie packs. It's extremely tense and exciting, with excellently staged action scenes, and plenty of squibs going off. Technically, this movie is a marvel, scored (by Jerry Fielding), lit (by Lucien Ballard), and edited (by Lou Lombardo) to perfection. It's a very rich looking experience that makes full use of its Panavision aspect ratio. The opening robbery scene is wonderfully intense (and features that memorable line, "If they move, kill them."); it will have you on the edge of your seat. Many fine sequences, with the robbery of guns and ammo from a train and the climactic shootout definite standouts. In addition to those actors already mentioned, solid contributions are made by a number of great character players: Edmond O'Brien, Strother Martin, L.Q. Jones (those last two making for a priceless comedy relief duo), Albert Dekker, Bo Hopkins, Dub Taylor, Emilio Fernandez, and Alfonso Arau. Poignant moments are mixed with some sharp dialogue, some good laughs, thrilling moments, and a high fun factor to make this well worth watching for any film fan, not just Western aficionados. As it reaches its conclusion, it would be too hard not to cheer seeing four of our main characters march side by side, guns at the ready, as they prepare to meet their destiny. The result of all of this is something truly unforgettable. 10 out of 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What to Expect: The Wild Bunch
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Film Watchin Fool
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Why You Might Like It: If you are a fan of Westerns, then you will likely enjoy this movie. It is a bit different than your traditional Western as it is action-packed at times and has an over the top shoot em up fill to it. The acting is great and the directing by Peckinpah is very fresh to this genre of movies and makes for a fun watch. Why You Might Not Like It: As most Westerns do, it has its slow spots that will make some lose interest. Also, this film is rated very high, so many will go into it with lofty expectations that it may or may not live up to. Acting/Casting: 8* - There is no shortage of great acting and cast members in this film. I am a huge fan of both William Holden and Robert Ryan in particular. Directing/Cinematography/Technical: 8* - Peckinpah does a fantastic job and many of the gun fight scenes are something to marvel for the film being made in 1969. Plot/Characters: 7* - The story has many layers and is pretty impressive. It starts out with a robbery, progresses into bounty hunting, and ends up being about loyalty. Entertainment Value: 7* - I really enjoyed this movie and was extremely impressed by the gun fight scenes, which are the highlight of the movie in my opinion. I would recommend this to fans of Western films and will likely watch again some time down the road. My Score: 8+8+7+7 = 30/4 = 7.5 Email your thoughts to filmwatchinfool@gmail.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Glossy, outdated violence and not much else
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Conrad
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sam Peckinpah wants you to know that Hollywood is at last free of its self-imposed Hays Code. He sets out to create the most violent Western to date, and he succeeds. The body count here is higher than in some wars. Every death is captured in slow-motion and augmented with jets of blood. Perhaps these novel visuals were thrilling and shocking to moviegoers in the late 1960s, but decades later desensitization has long since set in. The violence in "The Wild Bunch" has not aged well, and there is little else of interest in the film. A thin storyline links one scene of carnage to the next, but the movie doesn't know what to do with its characters between the action. A sentimental musical score plays to the point of distraction throughout the film but should fool nobody into caring about any of the people on screen. It is, however, nice to see the underrated Robert Ryan in a starring role.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An unsparing vision of the dream of innocence, and of human failure. . . .
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    malcolmi
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You can ride with a gang that seems to share a rough code of honour, but you'll be pursued by a former friend who's betraying you to stay out of prison. You can try to earn an easy score through the bloody hard work of robbing a bank, or a railroad, and cross the river into the freedom of a country where no law applies to you, but once you've crossed the river you'll be consumed by the chaos that always flourishes in the absence of law. You can try to rescue a friend, but your gesture will be rendered useless by a knife blade's flash. Then, when there's no more running, and nowhere to run to, when you've given your word and found that no one values it, when you've played out your string right to the end, what will you do? The Wild Bunch is Sam Peckinpah's exploration of that question. An artist who knew and loved life on the land, who knew well, and hated, the corruptions of 'civilization', and was compelled to cross the border into lawless territory, to seek a freedom which his own knowledge could never let him inhabit, Peckinpah made this marvellous film. It's set in a physical and spiritual landscape that any thinking middle-aged man is appallingly familiar with - the world of turning a blind eye to one's own cruelty, of watching one's hopes trashed by malevolence and stupidity, of being betrayed by friends, of fantasizing about the stroke of good luck that will let a man walk away from his compromises and failures. And Peckinpah's refusal to accept false sentiment reflects a middle-aged man's knowledge that self-interest and cruelty tempt even the very young, that even the powerful dream of being a child again is an illusion promising no peace. The children dream of being as brave and powerful as the adults whose violent actions are so seductively exciting. In the film's penultimate cathartic moment, it's a child who pulls the rifle's trigger. So, in the face of the disintegration of his world, and the impossibility of returning to innocence, what must a man do? No, the characters in this film are not honourable. But they dream of honourable actions - helping one's countrymen, one's village, one's friends. Yes, the idea of the frontier as an escape, and a new beginning, dies, in a welter of bullets after a man is dragged by technology across the abrasive landscape of his failure to see the consequences of his own actions. But the freedom of the frontier is its uncompromising offer of a chance to assess what's really true about existence. Sam Peckinpah knew that the assessment was the important thing. Death will happen. . . the important thing is to be ready to face death honestly, and so be able to live truly. The Wild Bunch isn't a young person's film, but for people who are ready to live in the minute details of existence faced honestly, ready to face the inevitable truth of death, The Wild Bunch is the necessary film. Peckinpah's clear vision cost him his happiness, and his health, finally, but left the rest of us a tough, miraculous, work of art.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The wages of sin is...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Wuchak
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ...death. That's the moral of Sam Peckinpah's classic 1969 Western about a group of aging and meandering outlaws who ride into Mexico in 1913 to flee a posse led by a former member, Deke Thornton (Robert Ryan). The outlaws, led by Pike Bishop (William Holden), eventually take refuge with a Mexican "general" and his hundreds of soldiers. When the Mexican member of the gang, Angel, is taken captive by the general for his revolutionary interests the rest of the gang have to decide whether to ignore it or make a bold stand. The Director's Cut of "The Wild Bunch" (1969) runs 145 minutes and features a great opening shootout and an outstanding closing shootout, a catharsis of blood; in the middle is a compelling train robbery. The material in between these three sequences isn't all that engrossing due to the fact that the characters aren't noble, likable or even redeemable, which is the film's weakness. I get the pessimistic message, but it doesn't change the fact that practically every character is an immoral or amoral dirtbag. Speaking of which, Deke Thornton has the audacity to repeatedly call the members of his posse "gutter trash" and the like. Well, what is he? A freed-on-condition prisoner who was once a member of the outlaw scum. At least the posse members -- lowlifes that they are -- are on the right side of the law. What hypocrisy. As noted above, a lot of dialogue and drama is devoted to character development, but who cares about a bunch of criminal scumbags? How can you devote "character development" to people who have no character? That's the problem with the film. That said, if you can accept the de-glorification of the Old West and the unlikable characters, "The Wild Bunch" is a solid Western with three thrilling sequences, including the unforgettable ending. There's a good message about the boldness of taking a stand and sticking by one's comrades, but that's the extent of the depth. GRADE: C+ or B-
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One Of The Best Westerns Ever Released
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Wild Bunch is a Western directed by Sam Peckinpah about an aging outlaw gang on the Texas-Mexico border, trying to exist in the changing modern world of 1913. The film was controversial because of its graphic violence and its portrayal of crude men attempting to survive by any available means.It features William Holden, Robert Ryan, Ernest Borgnine, Ben Johnson and Warren Oates. The screenplay was by Peckinpah and Walon Green.It is noted for intricate, multi-angle editing, using normal and slow motion images, a revolutionary cinema technique during its time of release in 1969. After a failed payroll robbery, the outlaw Bunch, led by aging Pike Bishop and including Dutch, Angel, and Lyle and Tector Gorch, heads for Mexico pursued by the gang of Pike's friend-turned-nemesis Deke Thornton.Ultimately caught between the corruption of railroad fat cat Harrigan and Federal general Mapache, and without a frontier for escape, the Bunch opts for a final Pyrrhic victory, striding purposefully to confront Mapache and avenge their friend Angel. "If they move, kill 'em!" Beginning and ending with two of the bloodiest battles in screen history, Sam Peckinpah's classic revisionist Western ruthlessly takes apart the myths of the West. Released in the late '60s discord over Vietnam, in the wake of the controversial Bonnie and Clyde nihilism of the times, while the other reviled it as depraved. But nevertheless, it takes the basic elements of the Western movie myth, which once defined a simple, morally comprehensible world, and by bending them turns them into symbols of futility and aimless corruption. Also,credit Peckinpah's success in setting the scenes and the sketches of a dozen vividly individualized characters, and choreographs one of the most realistic, influential, brilliantly photographed shootouts under the pitiless sun. The cast is superb, the dialog crackling, the bitterly ambiguous moral of the story hard-earned.One of the best Westerns ever released on screen.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not wild about this bunch
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brefane
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Stunningly photographed by Lucien Ballard, The Wild Bunch is a gorgeous looking and stunningly directed bore, yes, bore. Pacing is sorely lacking, and the direction, accomplished as it is, is sometimes undercut by the splintered editing. Despite the hyperactive editing, the film drags, and talk, most of it insignificant, fills the time between scenes of abstract violence. I didn't really care for or about the characters as I did in Kurosawa's The Seven Samurai or Pechnipah's Ride the High Country hence 21/2 hrs with them was too much. Sure the set pieces are terrific and worth watching, but pieces do not translate into a satisfactory whole. The acting is good, particularly Borgnine, Ryan, and Holden talented actors relegated to forgettable films during the 60's so The Wild Bunch was a last hurrah for them as well. The supporting cast has a convincing look and feel as does the film. Released the same year as the far more traditional Oscar-winning westerns Butch Cassidy and the Sundance Kid and True Grit, The Wild Bunch was nominated for 2 Oscars, for Original Screenplay and Score, though it's the direction, editing and cinematography that are outstanding.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The End Of A Golden Age
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nick-leonardi
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A group of aging outlaws, after a bloody and violent battle taking place in a small town, decide they want to accomplish one last hit before retiring: a train heist to get weapons, to give them to a Mexican general who promises them good money. The Bunch meanwhile is chased by Deke Thornton (a man who used to be in the Bunch), who's pressured by the risk of going back to Yuma if he fails to capture the old comrades. Sam Peckinpah's fifth film as a director has all of the qualities of a magnum opus: epic narrative structure, a vast, varied and always gorgeous array of sceneries, memorable and likable protagonists (William Holden, Ernest Borgnine, Warren Oates, Ben Johnson, Jamie Sanchez), masterful and innovative directing: the battle scenes are full of repeated slow motion shots and fast and complex editing choices. The Revisionist Western film par excellence: the beloved world of the West is portrayed as an ugly, dangerous, savage place, in which everyone is selfish, greedy, and cynical; but this world is also seen at its twilight, at the closing of the frontier, as the East brings in more and more modernization. Nominated for 2 Oscars.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Makes Rambo Look Like a Sissy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin6942
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An aging group of outlaws look for one last big score as the "traditional" American West is disappearing around them. The film starts off with a group of children watching a scorpion in an anthill. I knew this had to be symbolic, but I did not fully grasp how until the film was over. Seeing it now, it really tied the film together with a nice bookend and foreshadowing. Wow. The story is a good one, full of a moral morass. The "good guys" are as despicable as the outlaws, perhaps even more. Who do we cheer for? And the body count... wow (again). I can only imagine how many squibs were used for this movie, because blood and bullets were busting out everywhere. A good story, plenty of action, and Ernest Borgnine...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sam Peckinpah's Grand Slam
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    georgep53
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw a Director's Cut of "The Wild Bunch" on the big screen a couple of nights ago and although 43 years have passed it's still one helluva kick in the gut. I could tell how deeply this film has touched people by the reactions from the audience and obviously with so many IMDb reviews "The Wild Bunch" has made a lasting impression. There's so much to praise from the great performances of William Holden, Ernest Borgnine, Robert Ryan, Ben Johnson, Warren Oates and Edmond O'Brien to the great work of cinematographer Lucien Ballard and editor Lou Lombardo; the intricate screenplay by Peckinpah and Walon Green and Sam Peckinpah's bold, uncompromising direction. "The Wild Bunch" belongs to a group of films like "Butch Cassidy and the Sundance Kid" and "Lonely Are the Brave" that depict the cowboy/gunslinger as an anachronism in the face of a rapidly advancing modernity. They know their time is running out but the lure of one last job; the bonds between them and their adversaries' commitment to bringing them to justice lock them in a life and death struggle. The machine gun that figures so prominently in the conclusion is a great symbol of the mechanized slaughter that would come to dominate the 20th century. I loved the allegorical imagery of the scorpions and the ants locked in a battle to the death under the eager, enthusiastic eyes of children and by extension, us. William Holden gives one of his best performances in the role of Bishop Pike, aging leader of the Bunch. Robert Ryan is memorable as Deke Thornton, his former partner and current pursuer. Thornton feels disdain for the greedy, incompetent, railroad bosses who hate Pike. They have even less concern for human life than the outlaws.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A classic in every way.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Scott LeBrun (Hey_Sweden)
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sam Peckinpah's masterful movie is an incredible piece of work; much as its main characters realize that the way of the Old West are changing, so too does his movie acknowledge the evolution of the whole Western genre. No longer were ideas of "good" and "bad" so clearly defined. No longer did people merely clutch themselves and fall over when fatally shot; here we see bloody bullet penetration in all of its Technicolor glory. And there is one constant and admirable theme running throughout, that of a man's need to stand by his fellow men. Loyalty means a lot to ageing outlaw Pike Bishop (William Holden, in a fantastic change of pace performance). He and his fellow outlaws - Dutch (Ernest Borgnine), the Gorch brothers (Warren Oates and Ben Johnson), and Angel (Jaime Sanchez) can see that things are changing all around them, as they are witness to the marvel of automobiles and even the variety of "car" that can fly. As they look to make one last big score before they pack it in, they're trailed by Pike's old comrade Deke Thornton (Robert Ryan), not terribly happy to be pursuing his former friend, but having very little choice in the matter. The characters are all quite colourful and interesting, and each actor gets a chance to shine as the intricate, well written (by Peckinpah and Walon Green, based on Green's and Roy N. Sickner's story) plot plays itself out. And this is a true "man's" movie, one in which the female characters don't fare too well, so this may not be to all tastes, but it's hard to deny the punch that this movie packs. It's extremely tense and exciting, with excellently staged action scenes, and plenty of squibs going off. Technically, this movie is a marvel, scored (by Jerry Fielding), lit (by Lucien Ballard), and edited (by Lou Lombardo) to perfection. It's a very rich looking experience that makes full use of its Panavision aspect ratio. The opening robbery scene is wonderfully intense (and features that memorable line, "If they move, kill them."); it will have you on the edge of your seat. Many fine sequences, with the robbery of guns and ammo from a train and the climactic shootout definite standouts. In addition to those actors already mentioned, solid contributions are made by a number of great character players: Edmond O'Brien, Strother Martin, L.Q. Jones (those last two making for a priceless comedy relief duo), Albert Dekker, Bo Hopkins, Dub Taylor, Emilio Fernandez, and Alfonso Arau. Poignant moments are mixed with some sharp dialogue, some good laughs, thrilling moments, and a high fun factor to make this well worth watching for any film fan, not just Western aficionados. As it reaches its conclusion, it would be too hard not to cheer seeing four of our main characters march side by side, guns at the ready, as they prepare to meet their destiny. The result of all of this is something truly unforgettable. 10 out of 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
