<filme>
 <id>
  590
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0116514
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1996
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Hellraiser IV - Heran&ccedil;a Maldita
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  4.7
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  In the 22nd century, a scientist attempts to right the wrong his ancestor created: the puzzle box that opens the gates of Hell and unleashes Pinhead and his Cenobite legions.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  It's the year 2127. Pinhead, the evil cenobite of the series, has found himself on board a space station in outer space, run by scientist Dr.Merchant. Dr. Merchant's mission is to close the gates to hell forever. Because his ancestor, a toymaker in the 18th century, built the evil puzzlebox that opens the gates to hell. And through the generations, the family of the bloodline has tried to stop it. But now, Dr.Merchant has built the reverse box. The box that will close the gates to hell instead of opening it.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Horror
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Sci-Fi
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   hell
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   pinhead
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   22nd century
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   18th century
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   puzzle box
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Kevin Yagher
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Peter Atkins
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Bruce Ramsay
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Valentina Vargas
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Doug Bradley
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's better than the second one anyway
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There's a lot of ketchup but not a lot of narrative sense in this supposedly explanatory third sequel, which piles on the crummy visuals to no effect. Good old Alan Smithee directed this one, in which various members of the same family (all played, poorly, by Bruce Ramsay) are terrorised by Pinhead (Doug Bradley, wheeled out of mothballs for the umpteenth time). Peter Atkins tries to imbue his script with poetic touches but doesn't seem to realise that his dialogue is as deep and meaningful as a plate of vomit. The incoherent plot fails to adequately fill the movie's meagre running time, although this may have more to do with studio interference than anything the filmmakers intended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    In CGI Space - Nobody Can Hear Your Boredom...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Josh Morgan
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Pinhead in space! Hey - it worked for the Leprechaun. You know you're in trouble when a once reputable horror franchise throws a "katching" sound effect at you before the opening titles. The plot, dealing with the history of those responsible for the notorious puzzle box, is sadly done in relatively cheap flashbacks (with limited sets). Most of the (surprisingly minimal) gore is unnecessary (such as the autopsy of a body for no apparent reason), and the now cut-rate CGI box looks incredibly lame. Also, the conclusion - where a space station folds into a giant puzzle box - left my forehead bruised, as I smacked it in disgust. The worst of the theatrical entries. You may just want to skip ahead to Hellraiser: Inferno, as it's a pretty decent little thriller. Directed by everyone's favorite pseudonym, Alan Smithee.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hellraiser IV: Bloodline
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The first film was good, the second film was disappointing, the third film was okay, and this next sequel I expected to be pretty much exactly the same standard as the last one, and it would be the last played in the cinemas. Basically it is the year 2127 on the Space Station Mionos, and the man who built the station Dr. Paul Merchant (Bruce Ramsay) has built a robot that can solve the Lament Configuration, i.e. the puzzle box, but the robot is destroyed and he is captured, and he tells his kidnapper Rimmer (Christine Harnos) the story of his bloodline. The story flashbacks 400 years earlier, where French toymaker Philip L'Merchant (Ramsay again) creates the Lament Configuration, he believes it will be just a simple puzzle box for wealthy aristocrat Duc De L'Isle (Mickey Cottrell), but he has black magic in mind and uses it to release Cenobite slave Angelique (Valentina Vargas) from the dark regions. The toymaker also invented the Elysium Configuration which he uses to destroy the demons, the Duc's apprentice Jacques (Adam Scott) informs him that his bloodline are cursed until time ends because of his creation. Two hundred year pass, and the next in the bloodline John Merchant (also Ramsay) is the architect who built the building seen at the end of Hellraiser III, where the puzzle box was placed in the wet cement, and after Jacques is killed by Angelique she travels to America and tries to seduce John, the puzzle box is taken from the ground, and a man solves it and as a result releases Pinhead (Doug Bradley). The Cenobite leader wants the Elysium Configuration to be be used to open the gates of Hell and allow him and his dark forces to do anything he pleases, and he knows the best way to force John to do it is by threatening his child Jack (Courtland Mead). The Elysium Configuration is forced to be used, but it does not work, so Merchant is killed, while his wife Bobbi (Kim Myers) is the one who sends Pinhead, Angelique and the other Cenobites created back to Hell. Back in the future 2127 on the space station the Cenobites are freed once again, Rimmer realises the danger they are all in and releases Paul so that he can destroy the demons, using the main purpose the Minos was built for. Pinhead is distracted while Paul and Rimmer escape in a shuttle, and the combination of powerful lasers and mirrors create a blast of light, and the space station is transformed into a giant version of the puzzle box to trap the Cenobites within, and it self destructs as well, and destroying the connection between Hell and Earth as well. Bradley still keeps you watching as Pinhead with his philosophical like dialogue and his malevolent love for torture and death on humans, I will be honest though I don't fully agree with the critics giving it an average review, I think it is nearly the most ridiculous of the films in the series, going to the future and into space is a daft idea, only the origins of the puzzle box and the bloody effects is what kept me interested, apart from that it was a slightly disappointing horror. Okay!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    He back, and this time he in space.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    atinder
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This my first watch of this movie, , I loved first 2 move in the series and I enjoyed the third one, i thought it okay sequel However this one, i did not like as much as the other sequels, I just could not get into this story at all, I really bored for most of the time in them movie. I did not care for any one in this movie, the acting was not great but it still worth watching i say There were some decent gory scenes in this movie but I didn't find anything scary or creepy about this what so ever. I found this very dull and boring with bloody parts in here and there, Over I give 4 out of 10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Do I look like someone who cares what God thinks?!?"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Scott LeBrun (Hey_Sweden)
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watchable entry in the "Hellraiser" series at least does its best to establish a mythology. It focuses on the puzzle box itself, otherwise known as the Lament Configuration, that caused all of the trouble in the first place. It was created centuries ago by a toy maker who knew not what he was doing, as nefarious types were out to use it to unleash demons such as Pinhead upon the world. The back stories are framed by sequences set in the future where the latest descendant of that long ago toy maker is attempting to make things right again with a puzzle box of his own. Now, it almost certainly would have been better had director Kevin Yagher, a top makeup and special effects designer, been able to stick with his own vision, as extensive re-shoots were ordered, re-shoots that didn't involve him, and as a result he took his own name off the picture in favour of the notorious pseudonym Alan Smithee. And the story does indeed feel thin, not fully realized, and too rushed. Overall this is a hard movie to really get interested in, as too many of the characters and actors on hand are of the nondescript kind. Doug Bradley as Pinhead, of course, is an exception, and is magnetic as always, sinking his teeth into his literate dialogue. And Valentina Vargas is mildly amusing and definitely sexy as his ironically named cohort Angelique. There's just not much "oomph" to this thing, no standout set pieces, and no real sense of overwhelming doom or menace. In fact, it's tiresome at times. The gore and designs are a highlight (although one can tell this was done on a budget), with Pinhead provided with an effective "canine" companion. There are interesting ideas here, and hints of what could have been, but from start to finish this is purely on the routine side. Five out of 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Geez, these people need to stay away from that box! Grab a friggin' Rubic's Cube!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Kristine (kristinedrama14@msn.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When we think about what famous horror films like A Nightmare on Elm Street, Halloween and Friday the 13th, what do they have in common? They all have a million sequels. The series that seems to be the underdog that most people forget about but know it's main villain is Hellraiser which has a decent amount of sequels. However the sad part is, after the first three movies, every sequel that came out was a direct to video so I don't think the series had much of a chance to stand up to the big boys on the block of the horror genre. Hellraiser was the series that was not only darker but more serious when it came to horror and wasn't afraid to show off the gory side of torture. Think about it, I don't think we could have films like Saw and Hostel which owe a little thanks to Hellraiser for giving us the blood and guts. Also it gave us an extremely dark villain, Pinhead who feels no mercy and enjoys the pleasure of putting pain into your body and pulling your flesh every way possible with chains and hooks. But where did the puzzle box come from? Well Bloodline takes us into the story of the origin of the cenobites. In the year 2127, Paul Merchant, has a robot solve the puzzle box that holds Pinhead. However, several guards led by Rimmer capture Paul. Paul tells Rimmer the story of his bloodline. Philip L'Merchant, a French toymaker, makes the puzzle box for a wealthy aristocrat, who is obsessed with dark magic. He and his apprentice kill a woman and use her to summon the Cenobite slave Angelique. However, Angelique betrays and kills the aristocrat. L'Merchant, in the process of inventing a design to destroy the demons, attempts to steal back the box but is discovered. Jacques, Angelique's master, callously informs the toymaker that he and his bloodline are cursed until the end of time because of the box he created, before ordering Angelique to kill him. However, his wife survives and gives birth to his son, thus continuing the bloodline and to the future where Paul is trying to destroy Pinhead and Angelique once and for all. So I really did enjoy the story of Bloodline, it was a great idea that deserved more time and money. The film does well with what it was given, but since you can tell they were not given such great finances, the film falls short in the acting and shortness of the film. It feels like a made for TV film at times that was just more bloody than others. I couldn't really get into Valentina Vargas as Angelique nor did I find her incredibly evil like Pinhead, she didn't send any chills down my spine. But the last fight with Pinhead was cool and there are some great one liners. Pinhead screaming how he couldn't die is classic considering how many more sequels there are, but this was meant to take place in the future so who knows? Maybe Pinhead really does die in the future. I was a bit disappointed that we didn't have any more Elliot Spencer who is also a very interesting character. But this story was more about how the box was created and the family and their curse to fight the cenobites forever. Over all, it's worth the look, I think this was the last good sequel before it started getting weird and that's odd to say considering this is the Hellraiser series. 5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very well done! C'mon, have you actually SEEN most other 'Horror' films...?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lathe-of-heaven
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Okay, I wasn't going to bother writing a review for this one and I rarely take the time to write reviews here, BUT... Seeing this undeservedly LOW score here made me feel that I really had to 'say' something. First off, YES, I am indeed a BIG fan of the first three films; before these just recently came out on glorious Blu-ray, years ago, I even sprang for the UK Puzzle Box set of the first three films (mainly because at the time UNCUT versions were not available here in the states and also for the full commentaries and the bonus DVD that came with it : ) Now, I know it is hard to believe, but I just NOW for the very first time saw this one, part 4; the reason being is that from casual stuff I had read I was under the impression that pretty much all the other 'HELLRAISER' films were not made very well. Well... Let me tell you, I was extremely surprised (again, as my title above mentions) compared to all the REALLY AWFUL Horror films that are excruciatingly badly made, and that is most of them, I really was truly surprised that this one was made quite well. Okay, so a lot of the fans are sort of put off because it is really different from the other films. Fine... Isn't the POINT to try to come up with different angles and new approaches rather than just remaking the same film again and again...? I thought it was genuinely very creative and kept my attention very much so throughout the film. Sure, okay, it starts in space and your thinking 'LEPRECHAUN 3'; well, it works; it really does. Obviously a LOT of thought was put into the timeline and the mythology of the box, etc., not to mention the follow through at the end. Sure, it wrapped it up rather quickly and left it kind of ambiguous, but so what?! Yes, of COURSE it doesn't have the intensity of the original or even the complexity of the next two films, but to me I was mainly impressed by not only coming up with the new idea to show the origins, etc., but also I honestly felt that everything that made up the film was done very well considering that it is a damn 'HORROR' movie! : ) I gave it a good, strong '8' which it fully deserves considering the context and type of film. I think that people get SO jaded and expect SO dang much from sequels. Hey, like I say... I mean, C'mon, compared to what, 'WITCHBOARD' I-9 or whatever the hell it is, this here is pure art! Heh, if THIS one threw you, just wait until you see part 5! I just this minute finished watching that one for the very first time also a few minutes ago and that is a WILD departure from the early films. However, it was made even much better than this one; the director was actually very, very good!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    FINALLY a decent Hellrasier movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steven Smith
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In my honest opinion, I think the Hellrasier franchise is extremely overrated in the horror genre. I didn't like Hellraiser 1 at all. I thought it was poorly acted and directed. Hellrasier 2 was an OK movie but certainly not a classic at all. Hellrasier 3 was just awful and ridiculous. So I decided to watch 'Bloodline' last night expecting to see another poor Hellrasier movie. I was completely surprised. It was actually a good movie! Unlike the other Hellrasier movies, 'Bloodline' focuses more on important story elements but it certainly doesn't shy away from the nasty death scenes which have become synonymous with Hellrasier. People will either hate the direction this film takes or will enjoy it. I personally enjoy it and think it's superior to the other Hellrasier films. That probably sounds stupid as Hellraiser 1 & 2 are often touted as "horror classics" - I've never understood why they get so much praise as classics, whatever... 'Bloodline' has both story and gore - the perfect combination for a horror flick in my opinion. People who found Hellrasier 1,2 and 3 lame might just find 'Bloodline' a decent horror movie. Watch it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Surprisingly Complete Package But With Timidity
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tabuno
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Three stories are wrapped up in this version of Hellraiser and the storyline has a nicely cyclical completion from beginning to end. The irony with this version that it seems to have toned down the very nature of hell and pain and in a timid move edited out some of the more horrifying potential elements. Not as elegant as THE CELL (2000) and variations of THE HOUSE ON HAUNTED HILL (1999), is the storyline that keeps this movie's momentum up to the end. There are elements of ALIEN but the monsters are not that spectacular and the script seems unable to capture the emotive richness available in the storyline, the temptations, the conflicting loyalty and lust associated with real life. Nevertheless, this complete package has its qualitative, if not quantitative horrifying elements.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Poorly executed and as empty as the 22nd century space setting.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    amesmonde
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This instalment of Hellraiser, IV follows the bloodline of the creator of the puzzle box the 'Toy Maker' and his plan to summon and to destroy Pinhead forever. Despite a theatrical release, bloodline looks and feels TV movie-like and the acting is below average, possibly due to the script. That said, Doug Bradley is fine as Pinhead and Valentina Vargas is note-worthy as the demon Angelique. The story's concept is quite good, and includes (one assumes) the building in the 3rd and the history of the box. It is told in flash-backs by Dr. Paul Merchant in the year 2127 and follows his descendants Phillip L'Merchant in the 18th century and John Merchant in 1996. Sadly, it's just poorly executed and let down by an uneven screenplay, bland direction and sub-par sets. The effects are a mixed bag, some are well done while others are less-convincing and tame. It appears to have a troubled shooting history as there were two directors Alan Smithee (under an alias Kevin Yagher) and Joe Chappelle (uncredited). This maybe one cause and result of such an less than satisfying fourth. Overall, producers didn't give such a bankable character as Pinhead the attention he deserved leaving the viewer as empty as the 22nd century space setting.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's better than the second one anyway
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There's a lot of ketchup but not a lot of narrative sense in this supposedly explanatory third sequel, which piles on the crummy visuals to no effect. Good old Alan Smithee directed this one, in which various members of the same family (all played, poorly, by Bruce Ramsay) are terrorised by Pinhead (Doug Bradley, wheeled out of mothballs for the umpteenth time). Peter Atkins tries to imbue his script with poetic touches but doesn't seem to realise that his dialogue is as deep and meaningful as a plate of vomit. The incoherent plot fails to adequately fill the movie's meagre running time, although this may have more to do with studio interference than anything the filmmakers intended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    In CGI Space - Nobody Can Hear Your Boredom...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Josh Morgan
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Pinhead in space! Hey - it worked for the Leprechaun. You know you're in trouble when a once reputable horror franchise throws a "katching" sound effect at you before the opening titles. The plot, dealing with the history of those responsible for the notorious puzzle box, is sadly done in relatively cheap flashbacks (with limited sets). Most of the (surprisingly minimal) gore is unnecessary (such as the autopsy of a body for no apparent reason), and the now cut-rate CGI box looks incredibly lame. Also, the conclusion - where a space station folds into a giant puzzle box - left my forehead bruised, as I smacked it in disgust. The worst of the theatrical entries. You may just want to skip ahead to Hellraiser: Inferno, as it's a pretty decent little thriller. Directed by everyone's favorite pseudonym, Alan Smithee.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hellraiser IV: Bloodline
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The first film was good, the second film was disappointing, the third film was okay, and this next sequel I expected to be pretty much exactly the same standard as the last one, and it would be the last played in the cinemas. Basically it is the year 2127 on the Space Station Mionos, and the man who built the station Dr. Paul Merchant (Bruce Ramsay) has built a robot that can solve the Lament Configuration, i.e. the puzzle box, but the robot is destroyed and he is captured, and he tells his kidnapper Rimmer (Christine Harnos) the story of his bloodline. The story flashbacks 400 years earlier, where French toymaker Philip L'Merchant (Ramsay again) creates the Lament Configuration, he believes it will be just a simple puzzle box for wealthy aristocrat Duc De L'Isle (Mickey Cottrell), but he has black magic in mind and uses it to release Cenobite slave Angelique (Valentina Vargas) from the dark regions. The toymaker also invented the Elysium Configuration which he uses to destroy the demons, the Duc's apprentice Jacques (Adam Scott) informs him that his bloodline are cursed until time ends because of his creation. Two hundred year pass, and the next in the bloodline John Merchant (also Ramsay) is the architect who built the building seen at the end of Hellraiser III, where the puzzle box was placed in the wet cement, and after Jacques is killed by Angelique she travels to America and tries to seduce John, the puzzle box is taken from the ground, and a man solves it and as a result releases Pinhead (Doug Bradley). The Cenobite leader wants the Elysium Configuration to be be used to open the gates of Hell and allow him and his dark forces to do anything he pleases, and he knows the best way to force John to do it is by threatening his child Jack (Courtland Mead). The Elysium Configuration is forced to be used, but it does not work, so Merchant is killed, while his wife Bobbi (Kim Myers) is the one who sends Pinhead, Angelique and the other Cenobites created back to Hell. Back in the future 2127 on the space station the Cenobites are freed once again, Rimmer realises the danger they are all in and releases Paul so that he can destroy the demons, using the main purpose the Minos was built for. Pinhead is distracted while Paul and Rimmer escape in a shuttle, and the combination of powerful lasers and mirrors create a blast of light, and the space station is transformed into a giant version of the puzzle box to trap the Cenobites within, and it self destructs as well, and destroying the connection between Hell and Earth as well. Bradley still keeps you watching as Pinhead with his philosophical like dialogue and his malevolent love for torture and death on humans, I will be honest though I don't fully agree with the critics giving it an average review, I think it is nearly the most ridiculous of the films in the series, going to the future and into space is a daft idea, only the origins of the puzzle box and the bloody effects is what kept me interested, apart from that it was a slightly disappointing horror. Okay!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    He back, and this time he in space.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    atinder
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This my first watch of this movie, , I loved first 2 move in the series and I enjoyed the third one, i thought it okay sequel However this one, i did not like as much as the other sequels, I just could not get into this story at all, I really bored for most of the time in them movie. I did not care for any one in this movie, the acting was not great but it still worth watching i say There were some decent gory scenes in this movie but I didn't find anything scary or creepy about this what so ever. I found this very dull and boring with bloody parts in here and there, Over I give 4 out of 10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Do I look like someone who cares what God thinks?!?"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Scott LeBrun (Hey_Sweden)
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watchable entry in the "Hellraiser" series at least does its best to establish a mythology. It focuses on the puzzle box itself, otherwise known as the Lament Configuration, that caused all of the trouble in the first place. It was created centuries ago by a toy maker who knew not what he was doing, as nefarious types were out to use it to unleash demons such as Pinhead upon the world. The back stories are framed by sequences set in the future where the latest descendant of that long ago toy maker is attempting to make things right again with a puzzle box of his own. Now, it almost certainly would have been better had director Kevin Yagher, a top makeup and special effects designer, been able to stick with his own vision, as extensive re-shoots were ordered, re-shoots that didn't involve him, and as a result he took his own name off the picture in favour of the notorious pseudonym Alan Smithee. And the story does indeed feel thin, not fully realized, and too rushed. Overall this is a hard movie to really get interested in, as too many of the characters and actors on hand are of the nondescript kind. Doug Bradley as Pinhead, of course, is an exception, and is magnetic as always, sinking his teeth into his literate dialogue. And Valentina Vargas is mildly amusing and definitely sexy as his ironically named cohort Angelique. There's just not much "oomph" to this thing, no standout set pieces, and no real sense of overwhelming doom or menace. In fact, it's tiresome at times. The gore and designs are a highlight (although one can tell this was done on a budget), with Pinhead provided with an effective "canine" companion. There are interesting ideas here, and hints of what could have been, but from start to finish this is purely on the routine side. Five out of 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Geez, these people need to stay away from that box! Grab a friggin' Rubic's Cube!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Kristine (kristinedrama14@msn.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When we think about what famous horror films like A Nightmare on Elm Street, Halloween and Friday the 13th, what do they have in common? They all have a million sequels. The series that seems to be the underdog that most people forget about but know it's main villain is Hellraiser which has a decent amount of sequels. However the sad part is, after the first three movies, every sequel that came out was a direct to video so I don't think the series had much of a chance to stand up to the big boys on the block of the horror genre. Hellraiser was the series that was not only darker but more serious when it came to horror and wasn't afraid to show off the gory side of torture. Think about it, I don't think we could have films like Saw and Hostel which owe a little thanks to Hellraiser for giving us the blood and guts. Also it gave us an extremely dark villain, Pinhead who feels no mercy and enjoys the pleasure of putting pain into your body and pulling your flesh every way possible with chains and hooks. But where did the puzzle box come from? Well Bloodline takes us into the story of the origin of the cenobites. In the year 2127, Paul Merchant, has a robot solve the puzzle box that holds Pinhead. However, several guards led by Rimmer capture Paul. Paul tells Rimmer the story of his bloodline. Philip L'Merchant, a French toymaker, makes the puzzle box for a wealthy aristocrat, who is obsessed with dark magic. He and his apprentice kill a woman and use her to summon the Cenobite slave Angelique. However, Angelique betrays and kills the aristocrat. L'Merchant, in the process of inventing a design to destroy the demons, attempts to steal back the box but is discovered. Jacques, Angelique's master, callously informs the toymaker that he and his bloodline are cursed until the end of time because of the box he created, before ordering Angelique to kill him. However, his wife survives and gives birth to his son, thus continuing the bloodline and to the future where Paul is trying to destroy Pinhead and Angelique once and for all. So I really did enjoy the story of Bloodline, it was a great idea that deserved more time and money. The film does well with what it was given, but since you can tell they were not given such great finances, the film falls short in the acting and shortness of the film. It feels like a made for TV film at times that was just more bloody than others. I couldn't really get into Valentina Vargas as Angelique nor did I find her incredibly evil like Pinhead, she didn't send any chills down my spine. But the last fight with Pinhead was cool and there are some great one liners. Pinhead screaming how he couldn't die is classic considering how many more sequels there are, but this was meant to take place in the future so who knows? Maybe Pinhead really does die in the future. I was a bit disappointed that we didn't have any more Elliot Spencer who is also a very interesting character. But this story was more about how the box was created and the family and their curse to fight the cenobites forever. Over all, it's worth the look, I think this was the last good sequel before it started getting weird and that's odd to say considering this is the Hellraiser series. 5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very well done! C'mon, have you actually SEEN most other 'Horror' films...?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lathe-of-heaven
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Okay, I wasn't going to bother writing a review for this one and I rarely take the time to write reviews here, BUT... Seeing this undeservedly LOW score here made me feel that I really had to 'say' something. First off, YES, I am indeed a BIG fan of the first three films; before these just recently came out on glorious Blu-ray, years ago, I even sprang for the UK Puzzle Box set of the first three films (mainly because at the time UNCUT versions were not available here in the states and also for the full commentaries and the bonus DVD that came with it : ) Now, I know it is hard to believe, but I just NOW for the very first time saw this one, part 4; the reason being is that from casual stuff I had read I was under the impression that pretty much all the other 'HELLRAISER' films were not made very well. Well... Let me tell you, I was extremely surprised (again, as my title above mentions) compared to all the REALLY AWFUL Horror films that are excruciatingly badly made, and that is most of them, I really was truly surprised that this one was made quite well. Okay, so a lot of the fans are sort of put off because it is really different from the other films. Fine... Isn't the POINT to try to come up with different angles and new approaches rather than just remaking the same film again and again...? I thought it was genuinely very creative and kept my attention very much so throughout the film. Sure, okay, it starts in space and your thinking 'LEPRECHAUN 3'; well, it works; it really does. Obviously a LOT of thought was put into the timeline and the mythology of the box, etc., not to mention the follow through at the end. Sure, it wrapped it up rather quickly and left it kind of ambiguous, but so what?! Yes, of COURSE it doesn't have the intensity of the original or even the complexity of the next two films, but to me I was mainly impressed by not only coming up with the new idea to show the origins, etc., but also I honestly felt that everything that made up the film was done very well considering that it is a damn 'HORROR' movie! : ) I gave it a good, strong '8' which it fully deserves considering the context and type of film. I think that people get SO jaded and expect SO dang much from sequels. Hey, like I say... I mean, C'mon, compared to what, 'WITCHBOARD' I-9 or whatever the hell it is, this here is pure art! Heh, if THIS one threw you, just wait until you see part 5! I just this minute finished watching that one for the very first time also a few minutes ago and that is a WILD departure from the early films. However, it was made even much better than this one; the director was actually very, very good!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    FINALLY a decent Hellrasier movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steven Smith
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In my honest opinion, I think the Hellrasier franchise is extremely overrated in the horror genre. I didn't like Hellraiser 1 at all. I thought it was poorly acted and directed. Hellrasier 2 was an OK movie but certainly not a classic at all. Hellrasier 3 was just awful and ridiculous. So I decided to watch 'Bloodline' last night expecting to see another poor Hellrasier movie. I was completely surprised. It was actually a good movie! Unlike the other Hellrasier movies, 'Bloodline' focuses more on important story elements but it certainly doesn't shy away from the nasty death scenes which have become synonymous with Hellrasier. People will either hate the direction this film takes or will enjoy it. I personally enjoy it and think it's superior to the other Hellrasier films. That probably sounds stupid as Hellraiser 1 & 2 are often touted as "horror classics" - I've never understood why they get so much praise as classics, whatever... 'Bloodline' has both story and gore - the perfect combination for a horror flick in my opinion. People who found Hellrasier 1,2 and 3 lame might just find 'Bloodline' a decent horror movie. Watch it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Surprisingly Complete Package But With Timidity
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tabuno
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Three stories are wrapped up in this version of Hellraiser and the storyline has a nicely cyclical completion from beginning to end. The irony with this version that it seems to have toned down the very nature of hell and pain and in a timid move edited out some of the more horrifying potential elements. Not as elegant as THE CELL (2000) and variations of THE HOUSE ON HAUNTED HILL (1999), is the storyline that keeps this movie's momentum up to the end. There are elements of ALIEN but the monsters are not that spectacular and the script seems unable to capture the emotive richness available in the storyline, the temptations, the conflicting loyalty and lust associated with real life. Nevertheless, this complete package has its qualitative, if not quantitative horrifying elements.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Poorly executed and as empty as the 22nd century space setting.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    amesmonde
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This instalment of Hellraiser, IV follows the bloodline of the creator of the puzzle box the 'Toy Maker' and his plan to summon and to destroy Pinhead forever. Despite a theatrical release, bloodline looks and feels TV movie-like and the acting is below average, possibly due to the script. That said, Doug Bradley is fine as Pinhead and Valentina Vargas is note-worthy as the demon Angelique. The story's concept is quite good, and includes (one assumes) the building in the 3rd and the history of the box. It is told in flash-backs by Dr. Paul Merchant in the year 2127 and follows his descendants Phillip L'Merchant in the 18th century and John Merchant in 1996. Sadly, it's just poorly executed and let down by an uneven screenplay, bland direction and sub-par sets. The effects are a mixed bag, some are well done while others are less-convincing and tame. It appears to have a troubled shooting history as there were two directors Alan Smithee (under an alias Kevin Yagher) and Joe Chappelle (uncredited). This maybe one cause and result of such an less than satisfying fourth. Overall, producers didn't give such a bankable character as Pinhead the attention he deserved leaving the viewer as empty as the 22nd century space setting.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's better than the second one anyway
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There's a lot of ketchup but not a lot of narrative sense in this supposedly explanatory third sequel, which piles on the crummy visuals to no effect. Good old Alan Smithee directed this one, in which various members of the same family (all played, poorly, by Bruce Ramsay) are terrorised by Pinhead (Doug Bradley, wheeled out of mothballs for the umpteenth time). Peter Atkins tries to imbue his script with poetic touches but doesn't seem to realise that his dialogue is as deep and meaningful as a plate of vomit. The incoherent plot fails to adequately fill the movie's meagre running time, although this may have more to do with studio interference than anything the filmmakers intended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    In CGI Space - Nobody Can Hear Your Boredom...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Josh Morgan
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Pinhead in space! Hey - it worked for the Leprechaun. You know you're in trouble when a once reputable horror franchise throws a "katching" sound effect at you before the opening titles. The plot, dealing with the history of those responsible for the notorious puzzle box, is sadly done in relatively cheap flashbacks (with limited sets). Most of the (surprisingly minimal) gore is unnecessary (such as the autopsy of a body for no apparent reason), and the now cut-rate CGI box looks incredibly lame. Also, the conclusion - where a space station folds into a giant puzzle box - left my forehead bruised, as I smacked it in disgust. The worst of the theatrical entries. You may just want to skip ahead to Hellraiser: Inferno, as it's a pretty decent little thriller. Directed by everyone's favorite pseudonym, Alan Smithee.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hellraiser IV: Bloodline
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The first film was good, the second film was disappointing, the third film was okay, and this next sequel I expected to be pretty much exactly the same standard as the last one, and it would be the last played in the cinemas. Basically it is the year 2127 on the Space Station Mionos, and the man who built the station Dr. Paul Merchant (Bruce Ramsay) has built a robot that can solve the Lament Configuration, i.e. the puzzle box, but the robot is destroyed and he is captured, and he tells his kidnapper Rimmer (Christine Harnos) the story of his bloodline. The story flashbacks 400 years earlier, where French toymaker Philip L'Merchant (Ramsay again) creates the Lament Configuration, he believes it will be just a simple puzzle box for wealthy aristocrat Duc De L'Isle (Mickey Cottrell), but he has black magic in mind and uses it to release Cenobite slave Angelique (Valentina Vargas) from the dark regions. The toymaker also invented the Elysium Configuration which he uses to destroy the demons, the Duc's apprentice Jacques (Adam Scott) informs him that his bloodline are cursed until time ends because of his creation. Two hundred year pass, and the next in the bloodline John Merchant (also Ramsay) is the architect who built the building seen at the end of Hellraiser III, where the puzzle box was placed in the wet cement, and after Jacques is killed by Angelique she travels to America and tries to seduce John, the puzzle box is taken from the ground, and a man solves it and as a result releases Pinhead (Doug Bradley). The Cenobite leader wants the Elysium Configuration to be be used to open the gates of Hell and allow him and his dark forces to do anything he pleases, and he knows the best way to force John to do it is by threatening his child Jack (Courtland Mead). The Elysium Configuration is forced to be used, but it does not work, so Merchant is killed, while his wife Bobbi (Kim Myers) is the one who sends Pinhead, Angelique and the other Cenobites created back to Hell. Back in the future 2127 on the space station the Cenobites are freed once again, Rimmer realises the danger they are all in and releases Paul so that he can destroy the demons, using the main purpose the Minos was built for. Pinhead is distracted while Paul and Rimmer escape in a shuttle, and the combination of powerful lasers and mirrors create a blast of light, and the space station is transformed into a giant version of the puzzle box to trap the Cenobites within, and it self destructs as well, and destroying the connection between Hell and Earth as well. Bradley still keeps you watching as Pinhead with his philosophical like dialogue and his malevolent love for torture and death on humans, I will be honest though I don't fully agree with the critics giving it an average review, I think it is nearly the most ridiculous of the films in the series, going to the future and into space is a daft idea, only the origins of the puzzle box and the bloody effects is what kept me interested, apart from that it was a slightly disappointing horror. Okay!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    He back, and this time he in space.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    atinder
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This my first watch of this movie, , I loved first 2 move in the series and I enjoyed the third one, i thought it okay sequel However this one, i did not like as much as the other sequels, I just could not get into this story at all, I really bored for most of the time in them movie. I did not care for any one in this movie, the acting was not great but it still worth watching i say There were some decent gory scenes in this movie but I didn't find anything scary or creepy about this what so ever. I found this very dull and boring with bloody parts in here and there, Over I give 4 out of 10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Do I look like someone who cares what God thinks?!?"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Scott LeBrun (Hey_Sweden)
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watchable entry in the "Hellraiser" series at least does its best to establish a mythology. It focuses on the puzzle box itself, otherwise known as the Lament Configuration, that caused all of the trouble in the first place. It was created centuries ago by a toy maker who knew not what he was doing, as nefarious types were out to use it to unleash demons such as Pinhead upon the world. The back stories are framed by sequences set in the future where the latest descendant of that long ago toy maker is attempting to make things right again with a puzzle box of his own. Now, it almost certainly would have been better had director Kevin Yagher, a top makeup and special effects designer, been able to stick with his own vision, as extensive re-shoots were ordered, re-shoots that didn't involve him, and as a result he took his own name off the picture in favour of the notorious pseudonym Alan Smithee. And the story does indeed feel thin, not fully realized, and too rushed. Overall this is a hard movie to really get interested in, as too many of the characters and actors on hand are of the nondescript kind. Doug Bradley as Pinhead, of course, is an exception, and is magnetic as always, sinking his teeth into his literate dialogue. And Valentina Vargas is mildly amusing and definitely sexy as his ironically named cohort Angelique. There's just not much "oomph" to this thing, no standout set pieces, and no real sense of overwhelming doom or menace. In fact, it's tiresome at times. The gore and designs are a highlight (although one can tell this was done on a budget), with Pinhead provided with an effective "canine" companion. There are interesting ideas here, and hints of what could have been, but from start to finish this is purely on the routine side. Five out of 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Geez, these people need to stay away from that box! Grab a friggin' Rubic's Cube!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Kristine (kristinedrama14@msn.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When we think about what famous horror films like A Nightmare on Elm Street, Halloween and Friday the 13th, what do they have in common? They all have a million sequels. The series that seems to be the underdog that most people forget about but know it's main villain is Hellraiser which has a decent amount of sequels. However the sad part is, after the first three movies, every sequel that came out was a direct to video so I don't think the series had much of a chance to stand up to the big boys on the block of the horror genre. Hellraiser was the series that was not only darker but more serious when it came to horror and wasn't afraid to show off the gory side of torture. Think about it, I don't think we could have films like Saw and Hostel which owe a little thanks to Hellraiser for giving us the blood and guts. Also it gave us an extremely dark villain, Pinhead who feels no mercy and enjoys the pleasure of putting pain into your body and pulling your flesh every way possible with chains and hooks. But where did the puzzle box come from? Well Bloodline takes us into the story of the origin of the cenobites. In the year 2127, Paul Merchant, has a robot solve the puzzle box that holds Pinhead. However, several guards led by Rimmer capture Paul. Paul tells Rimmer the story of his bloodline. Philip L'Merchant, a French toymaker, makes the puzzle box for a wealthy aristocrat, who is obsessed with dark magic. He and his apprentice kill a woman and use her to summon the Cenobite slave Angelique. However, Angelique betrays and kills the aristocrat. L'Merchant, in the process of inventing a design to destroy the demons, attempts to steal back the box but is discovered. Jacques, Angelique's master, callously informs the toymaker that he and his bloodline are cursed until the end of time because of the box he created, before ordering Angelique to kill him. However, his wife survives and gives birth to his son, thus continuing the bloodline and to the future where Paul is trying to destroy Pinhead and Angelique once and for all. So I really did enjoy the story of Bloodline, it was a great idea that deserved more time and money. The film does well with what it was given, but since you can tell they were not given such great finances, the film falls short in the acting and shortness of the film. It feels like a made for TV film at times that was just more bloody than others. I couldn't really get into Valentina Vargas as Angelique nor did I find her incredibly evil like Pinhead, she didn't send any chills down my spine. But the last fight with Pinhead was cool and there are some great one liners. Pinhead screaming how he couldn't die is classic considering how many more sequels there are, but this was meant to take place in the future so who knows? Maybe Pinhead really does die in the future. I was a bit disappointed that we didn't have any more Elliot Spencer who is also a very interesting character. But this story was more about how the box was created and the family and their curse to fight the cenobites forever. Over all, it's worth the look, I think this was the last good sequel before it started getting weird and that's odd to say considering this is the Hellraiser series. 5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very well done! C'mon, have you actually SEEN most other 'Horror' films...?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lathe-of-heaven
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Okay, I wasn't going to bother writing a review for this one and I rarely take the time to write reviews here, BUT... Seeing this undeservedly LOW score here made me feel that I really had to 'say' something. First off, YES, I am indeed a BIG fan of the first three films; before these just recently came out on glorious Blu-ray, years ago, I even sprang for the UK Puzzle Box set of the first three films (mainly because at the time UNCUT versions were not available here in the states and also for the full commentaries and the bonus DVD that came with it : ) Now, I know it is hard to believe, but I just NOW for the very first time saw this one, part 4; the reason being is that from casual stuff I had read I was under the impression that pretty much all the other 'HELLRAISER' films were not made very well. Well... Let me tell you, I was extremely surprised (again, as my title above mentions) compared to all the REALLY AWFUL Horror films that are excruciatingly badly made, and that is most of them, I really was truly surprised that this one was made quite well. Okay, so a lot of the fans are sort of put off because it is really different from the other films. Fine... Isn't the POINT to try to come up with different angles and new approaches rather than just remaking the same film again and again...? I thought it was genuinely very creative and kept my attention very much so throughout the film. Sure, okay, it starts in space and your thinking 'LEPRECHAUN 3'; well, it works; it really does. Obviously a LOT of thought was put into the timeline and the mythology of the box, etc., not to mention the follow through at the end. Sure, it wrapped it up rather quickly and left it kind of ambiguous, but so what?! Yes, of COURSE it doesn't have the intensity of the original or even the complexity of the next two films, but to me I was mainly impressed by not only coming up with the new idea to show the origins, etc., but also I honestly felt that everything that made up the film was done very well considering that it is a damn 'HORROR' movie! : ) I gave it a good, strong '8' which it fully deserves considering the context and type of film. I think that people get SO jaded and expect SO dang much from sequels. Hey, like I say... I mean, C'mon, compared to what, 'WITCHBOARD' I-9 or whatever the hell it is, this here is pure art! Heh, if THIS one threw you, just wait until you see part 5! I just this minute finished watching that one for the very first time also a few minutes ago and that is a WILD departure from the early films. However, it was made even much better than this one; the director was actually very, very good!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    FINALLY a decent Hellrasier movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steven Smith
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In my honest opinion, I think the Hellrasier franchise is extremely overrated in the horror genre. I didn't like Hellraiser 1 at all. I thought it was poorly acted and directed. Hellrasier 2 was an OK movie but certainly not a classic at all. Hellrasier 3 was just awful and ridiculous. So I decided to watch 'Bloodline' last night expecting to see another poor Hellrasier movie. I was completely surprised. It was actually a good movie! Unlike the other Hellrasier movies, 'Bloodline' focuses more on important story elements but it certainly doesn't shy away from the nasty death scenes which have become synonymous with Hellrasier. People will either hate the direction this film takes or will enjoy it. I personally enjoy it and think it's superior to the other Hellrasier films. That probably sounds stupid as Hellraiser 1 & 2 are often touted as "horror classics" - I've never understood why they get so much praise as classics, whatever... 'Bloodline' has both story and gore - the perfect combination for a horror flick in my opinion. People who found Hellrasier 1,2 and 3 lame might just find 'Bloodline' a decent horror movie. Watch it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Surprisingly Complete Package But With Timidity
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tabuno
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Three stories are wrapped up in this version of Hellraiser and the storyline has a nicely cyclical completion from beginning to end. The irony with this version that it seems to have toned down the very nature of hell and pain and in a timid move edited out some of the more horrifying potential elements. Not as elegant as THE CELL (2000) and variations of THE HOUSE ON HAUNTED HILL (1999), is the storyline that keeps this movie's momentum up to the end. There are elements of ALIEN but the monsters are not that spectacular and the script seems unable to capture the emotive richness available in the storyline, the temptations, the conflicting loyalty and lust associated with real life. Nevertheless, this complete package has its qualitative, if not quantitative horrifying elements.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Poorly executed and as empty as the 22nd century space setting.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    amesmonde
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This instalment of Hellraiser, IV follows the bloodline of the creator of the puzzle box the 'Toy Maker' and his plan to summon and to destroy Pinhead forever. Despite a theatrical release, bloodline looks and feels TV movie-like and the acting is below average, possibly due to the script. That said, Doug Bradley is fine as Pinhead and Valentina Vargas is note-worthy as the demon Angelique. The story's concept is quite good, and includes (one assumes) the building in the 3rd and the history of the box. It is told in flash-backs by Dr. Paul Merchant in the year 2127 and follows his descendants Phillip L'Merchant in the 18th century and John Merchant in 1996. Sadly, it's just poorly executed and let down by an uneven screenplay, bland direction and sub-par sets. The effects are a mixed bag, some are well done while others are less-convincing and tame. It appears to have a troubled shooting history as there were two directors Alan Smithee (under an alias Kevin Yagher) and Joe Chappelle (uncredited). This maybe one cause and result of such an less than satisfying fourth. Overall, producers didn't give such a bankable character as Pinhead the attention he deserved leaving the viewer as empty as the 22nd century space setting.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's better than the second one anyway
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There's a lot of ketchup but not a lot of narrative sense in this supposedly explanatory third sequel, which piles on the crummy visuals to no effect. Good old Alan Smithee directed this one, in which various members of the same family (all played, poorly, by Bruce Ramsay) are terrorised by Pinhead (Doug Bradley, wheeled out of mothballs for the umpteenth time). Peter Atkins tries to imbue his script with poetic touches but doesn't seem to realise that his dialogue is as deep and meaningful as a plate of vomit. The incoherent plot fails to adequately fill the movie's meagre running time, although this may have more to do with studio interference than anything the filmmakers intended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    In CGI Space - Nobody Can Hear Your Boredom...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Josh Morgan
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Pinhead in space! Hey - it worked for the Leprechaun. You know you're in trouble when a once reputable horror franchise throws a "katching" sound effect at you before the opening titles. The plot, dealing with the history of those responsible for the notorious puzzle box, is sadly done in relatively cheap flashbacks (with limited sets). Most of the (surprisingly minimal) gore is unnecessary (such as the autopsy of a body for no apparent reason), and the now cut-rate CGI box looks incredibly lame. Also, the conclusion - where a space station folds into a giant puzzle box - left my forehead bruised, as I smacked it in disgust. The worst of the theatrical entries. You may just want to skip ahead to Hellraiser: Inferno, as it's a pretty decent little thriller. Directed by everyone's favorite pseudonym, Alan Smithee.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hellraiser IV: Bloodline
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The first film was good, the second film was disappointing, the third film was okay, and this next sequel I expected to be pretty much exactly the same standard as the last one, and it would be the last played in the cinemas. Basically it is the year 2127 on the Space Station Mionos, and the man who built the station Dr. Paul Merchant (Bruce Ramsay) has built a robot that can solve the Lament Configuration, i.e. the puzzle box, but the robot is destroyed and he is captured, and he tells his kidnapper Rimmer (Christine Harnos) the story of his bloodline. The story flashbacks 400 years earlier, where French toymaker Philip L'Merchant (Ramsay again) creates the Lament Configuration, he believes it will be just a simple puzzle box for wealthy aristocrat Duc De L'Isle (Mickey Cottrell), but he has black magic in mind and uses it to release Cenobite slave Angelique (Valentina Vargas) from the dark regions. The toymaker also invented the Elysium Configuration which he uses to destroy the demons, the Duc's apprentice Jacques (Adam Scott) informs him that his bloodline are cursed until time ends because of his creation. Two hundred year pass, and the next in the bloodline John Merchant (also Ramsay) is the architect who built the building seen at the end of Hellraiser III, where the puzzle box was placed in the wet cement, and after Jacques is killed by Angelique she travels to America and tries to seduce John, the puzzle box is taken from the ground, and a man solves it and as a result releases Pinhead (Doug Bradley). The Cenobite leader wants the Elysium Configuration to be be used to open the gates of Hell and allow him and his dark forces to do anything he pleases, and he knows the best way to force John to do it is by threatening his child Jack (Courtland Mead). The Elysium Configuration is forced to be used, but it does not work, so Merchant is killed, while his wife Bobbi (Kim Myers) is the one who sends Pinhead, Angelique and the other Cenobites created back to Hell. Back in the future 2127 on the space station the Cenobites are freed once again, Rimmer realises the danger they are all in and releases Paul so that he can destroy the demons, using the main purpose the Minos was built for. Pinhead is distracted while Paul and Rimmer escape in a shuttle, and the combination of powerful lasers and mirrors create a blast of light, and the space station is transformed into a giant version of the puzzle box to trap the Cenobites within, and it self destructs as well, and destroying the connection between Hell and Earth as well. Bradley still keeps you watching as Pinhead with his philosophical like dialogue and his malevolent love for torture and death on humans, I will be honest though I don't fully agree with the critics giving it an average review, I think it is nearly the most ridiculous of the films in the series, going to the future and into space is a daft idea, only the origins of the puzzle box and the bloody effects is what kept me interested, apart from that it was a slightly disappointing horror. Okay!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    He back, and this time he in space.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    atinder
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This my first watch of this movie, , I loved first 2 move in the series and I enjoyed the third one, i thought it okay sequel However this one, i did not like as much as the other sequels, I just could not get into this story at all, I really bored for most of the time in them movie. I did not care for any one in this movie, the acting was not great but it still worth watching i say There were some decent gory scenes in this movie but I didn't find anything scary or creepy about this what so ever. I found this very dull and boring with bloody parts in here and there, Over I give 4 out of 10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Do I look like someone who cares what God thinks?!?"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Scott LeBrun (Hey_Sweden)
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watchable entry in the "Hellraiser" series at least does its best to establish a mythology. It focuses on the puzzle box itself, otherwise known as the Lament Configuration, that caused all of the trouble in the first place. It was created centuries ago by a toy maker who knew not what he was doing, as nefarious types were out to use it to unleash demons such as Pinhead upon the world. The back stories are framed by sequences set in the future where the latest descendant of that long ago toy maker is attempting to make things right again with a puzzle box of his own. Now, it almost certainly would have been better had director Kevin Yagher, a top makeup and special effects designer, been able to stick with his own vision, as extensive re-shoots were ordered, re-shoots that didn't involve him, and as a result he took his own name off the picture in favour of the notorious pseudonym Alan Smithee. And the story does indeed feel thin, not fully realized, and too rushed. Overall this is a hard movie to really get interested in, as too many of the characters and actors on hand are of the nondescript kind. Doug Bradley as Pinhead, of course, is an exception, and is magnetic as always, sinking his teeth into his literate dialogue. And Valentina Vargas is mildly amusing and definitely sexy as his ironically named cohort Angelique. There's just not much "oomph" to this thing, no standout set pieces, and no real sense of overwhelming doom or menace. In fact, it's tiresome at times. The gore and designs are a highlight (although one can tell this was done on a budget), with Pinhead provided with an effective "canine" companion. There are interesting ideas here, and hints of what could have been, but from start to finish this is purely on the routine side. Five out of 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Geez, these people need to stay away from that box! Grab a friggin' Rubic's Cube!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Kristine (kristinedrama14@msn.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When we think about what famous horror films like A Nightmare on Elm Street, Halloween and Friday the 13th, what do they have in common? They all have a million sequels. The series that seems to be the underdog that most people forget about but know it's main villain is Hellraiser which has a decent amount of sequels. However the sad part is, after the first three movies, every sequel that came out was a direct to video so I don't think the series had much of a chance to stand up to the big boys on the block of the horror genre. Hellraiser was the series that was not only darker but more serious when it came to horror and wasn't afraid to show off the gory side of torture. Think about it, I don't think we could have films like Saw and Hostel which owe a little thanks to Hellraiser for giving us the blood and guts. Also it gave us an extremely dark villain, Pinhead who feels no mercy and enjoys the pleasure of putting pain into your body and pulling your flesh every way possible with chains and hooks. But where did the puzzle box come from? Well Bloodline takes us into the story of the origin of the cenobites. In the year 2127, Paul Merchant, has a robot solve the puzzle box that holds Pinhead. However, several guards led by Rimmer capture Paul. Paul tells Rimmer the story of his bloodline. Philip L'Merchant, a French toymaker, makes the puzzle box for a wealthy aristocrat, who is obsessed with dark magic. He and his apprentice kill a woman and use her to summon the Cenobite slave Angelique. However, Angelique betrays and kills the aristocrat. L'Merchant, in the process of inventing a design to destroy the demons, attempts to steal back the box but is discovered. Jacques, Angelique's master, callously informs the toymaker that he and his bloodline are cursed until the end of time because of the box he created, before ordering Angelique to kill him. However, his wife survives and gives birth to his son, thus continuing the bloodline and to the future where Paul is trying to destroy Pinhead and Angelique once and for all. So I really did enjoy the story of Bloodline, it was a great idea that deserved more time and money. The film does well with what it was given, but since you can tell they were not given such great finances, the film falls short in the acting and shortness of the film. It feels like a made for TV film at times that was just more bloody than others. I couldn't really get into Valentina Vargas as Angelique nor did I find her incredibly evil like Pinhead, she didn't send any chills down my spine. But the last fight with Pinhead was cool and there are some great one liners. Pinhead screaming how he couldn't die is classic considering how many more sequels there are, but this was meant to take place in the future so who knows? Maybe Pinhead really does die in the future. I was a bit disappointed that we didn't have any more Elliot Spencer who is also a very interesting character. But this story was more about how the box was created and the family and their curse to fight the cenobites forever. Over all, it's worth the look, I think this was the last good sequel before it started getting weird and that's odd to say considering this is the Hellraiser series. 5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very well done! C'mon, have you actually SEEN most other 'Horror' films...?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lathe-of-heaven
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Okay, I wasn't going to bother writing a review for this one and I rarely take the time to write reviews here, BUT... Seeing this undeservedly LOW score here made me feel that I really had to 'say' something. First off, YES, I am indeed a BIG fan of the first three films; before these just recently came out on glorious Blu-ray, years ago, I even sprang for the UK Puzzle Box set of the first three films (mainly because at the time UNCUT versions were not available here in the states and also for the full commentaries and the bonus DVD that came with it : ) Now, I know it is hard to believe, but I just NOW for the very first time saw this one, part 4; the reason being is that from casual stuff I had read I was under the impression that pretty much all the other 'HELLRAISER' films were not made very well. Well... Let me tell you, I was extremely surprised (again, as my title above mentions) compared to all the REALLY AWFUL Horror films that are excruciatingly badly made, and that is most of them, I really was truly surprised that this one was made quite well. Okay, so a lot of the fans are sort of put off because it is really different from the other films. Fine... Isn't the POINT to try to come up with different angles and new approaches rather than just remaking the same film again and again...? I thought it was genuinely very creative and kept my attention very much so throughout the film. Sure, okay, it starts in space and your thinking 'LEPRECHAUN 3'; well, it works; it really does. Obviously a LOT of thought was put into the timeline and the mythology of the box, etc., not to mention the follow through at the end. Sure, it wrapped it up rather quickly and left it kind of ambiguous, but so what?! Yes, of COURSE it doesn't have the intensity of the original or even the complexity of the next two films, but to me I was mainly impressed by not only coming up with the new idea to show the origins, etc., but also I honestly felt that everything that made up the film was done very well considering that it is a damn 'HORROR' movie! : ) I gave it a good, strong '8' which it fully deserves considering the context and type of film. I think that people get SO jaded and expect SO dang much from sequels. Hey, like I say... I mean, C'mon, compared to what, 'WITCHBOARD' I-9 or whatever the hell it is, this here is pure art! Heh, if THIS one threw you, just wait until you see part 5! I just this minute finished watching that one for the very first time also a few minutes ago and that is a WILD departure from the early films. However, it was made even much better than this one; the director was actually very, very good!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    FINALLY a decent Hellrasier movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steven Smith
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In my honest opinion, I think the Hellrasier franchise is extremely overrated in the horror genre. I didn't like Hellraiser 1 at all. I thought it was poorly acted and directed. Hellrasier 2 was an OK movie but certainly not a classic at all. Hellrasier 3 was just awful and ridiculous. So I decided to watch 'Bloodline' last night expecting to see another poor Hellrasier movie. I was completely surprised. It was actually a good movie! Unlike the other Hellrasier movies, 'Bloodline' focuses more on important story elements but it certainly doesn't shy away from the nasty death scenes which have become synonymous with Hellrasier. People will either hate the direction this film takes or will enjoy it. I personally enjoy it and think it's superior to the other Hellrasier films. That probably sounds stupid as Hellraiser 1 & 2 are often touted as "horror classics" - I've never understood why they get so much praise as classics, whatever... 'Bloodline' has both story and gore - the perfect combination for a horror flick in my opinion. People who found Hellrasier 1,2 and 3 lame might just find 'Bloodline' a decent horror movie. Watch it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Surprisingly Complete Package But With Timidity
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tabuno
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Three stories are wrapped up in this version of Hellraiser and the storyline has a nicely cyclical completion from beginning to end. The irony with this version that it seems to have toned down the very nature of hell and pain and in a timid move edited out some of the more horrifying potential elements. Not as elegant as THE CELL (2000) and variations of THE HOUSE ON HAUNTED HILL (1999), is the storyline that keeps this movie's momentum up to the end. There are elements of ALIEN but the monsters are not that spectacular and the script seems unable to capture the emotive richness available in the storyline, the temptations, the conflicting loyalty and lust associated with real life. Nevertheless, this complete package has its qualitative, if not quantitative horrifying elements.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Poorly executed and as empty as the 22nd century space setting.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    amesmonde
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This instalment of Hellraiser, IV follows the bloodline of the creator of the puzzle box the 'Toy Maker' and his plan to summon and to destroy Pinhead forever. Despite a theatrical release, bloodline looks and feels TV movie-like and the acting is below average, possibly due to the script. That said, Doug Bradley is fine as Pinhead and Valentina Vargas is note-worthy as the demon Angelique. The story's concept is quite good, and includes (one assumes) the building in the 3rd and the history of the box. It is told in flash-backs by Dr. Paul Merchant in the year 2127 and follows his descendants Phillip L'Merchant in the 18th century and John Merchant in 1996. Sadly, it's just poorly executed and let down by an uneven screenplay, bland direction and sub-par sets. The effects are a mixed bag, some are well done while others are less-convincing and tame. It appears to have a troubled shooting history as there were two directors Alan Smithee (under an alias Kevin Yagher) and Joe Chappelle (uncredited). This maybe one cause and result of such an less than satisfying fourth. Overall, producers didn't give such a bankable character as Pinhead the attention he deserved leaving the viewer as empty as the 22nd century space setting.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's better than the second one anyway
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There's a lot of ketchup but not a lot of narrative sense in this supposedly explanatory third sequel, which piles on the crummy visuals to no effect. Good old Alan Smithee directed this one, in which various members of the same family (all played, poorly, by Bruce Ramsay) are terrorised by Pinhead (Doug Bradley, wheeled out of mothballs for the umpteenth time). Peter Atkins tries to imbue his script with poetic touches but doesn't seem to realise that his dialogue is as deep and meaningful as a plate of vomit. The incoherent plot fails to adequately fill the movie's meagre running time, although this may have more to do with studio interference than anything the filmmakers intended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    In CGI Space - Nobody Can Hear Your Boredom...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Josh Morgan
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Pinhead in space! Hey - it worked for the Leprechaun. You know you're in trouble when a once reputable horror franchise throws a "katching" sound effect at you before the opening titles. The plot, dealing with the history of those responsible for the notorious puzzle box, is sadly done in relatively cheap flashbacks (with limited sets). Most of the (surprisingly minimal) gore is unnecessary (such as the autopsy of a body for no apparent reason), and the now cut-rate CGI box looks incredibly lame. Also, the conclusion - where a space station folds into a giant puzzle box - left my forehead bruised, as I smacked it in disgust. The worst of the theatrical entries. You may just want to skip ahead to Hellraiser: Inferno, as it's a pretty decent little thriller. Directed by everyone's favorite pseudonym, Alan Smithee.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hellraiser IV: Bloodline
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The first film was good, the second film was disappointing, the third film was okay, and this next sequel I expected to be pretty much exactly the same standard as the last one, and it would be the last played in the cinemas. Basically it is the year 2127 on the Space Station Mionos, and the man who built the station Dr. Paul Merchant (Bruce Ramsay) has built a robot that can solve the Lament Configuration, i.e. the puzzle box, but the robot is destroyed and he is captured, and he tells his kidnapper Rimmer (Christine Harnos) the story of his bloodline. The story flashbacks 400 years earlier, where French toymaker Philip L'Merchant (Ramsay again) creates the Lament Configuration, he believes it will be just a simple puzzle box for wealthy aristocrat Duc De L'Isle (Mickey Cottrell), but he has black magic in mind and uses it to release Cenobite slave Angelique (Valentina Vargas) from the dark regions. The toymaker also invented the Elysium Configuration which he uses to destroy the demons, the Duc's apprentice Jacques (Adam Scott) informs him that his bloodline are cursed until time ends because of his creation. Two hundred year pass, and the next in the bloodline John Merchant (also Ramsay) is the architect who built the building seen at the end of Hellraiser III, where the puzzle box was placed in the wet cement, and after Jacques is killed by Angelique she travels to America and tries to seduce John, the puzzle box is taken from the ground, and a man solves it and as a result releases Pinhead (Doug Bradley). The Cenobite leader wants the Elysium Configuration to be be used to open the gates of Hell and allow him and his dark forces to do anything he pleases, and he knows the best way to force John to do it is by threatening his child Jack (Courtland Mead). The Elysium Configuration is forced to be used, but it does not work, so Merchant is killed, while his wife Bobbi (Kim Myers) is the one who sends Pinhead, Angelique and the other Cenobites created back to Hell. Back in the future 2127 on the space station the Cenobites are freed once again, Rimmer realises the danger they are all in and releases Paul so that he can destroy the demons, using the main purpose the Minos was built for. Pinhead is distracted while Paul and Rimmer escape in a shuttle, and the combination of powerful lasers and mirrors create a blast of light, and the space station is transformed into a giant version of the puzzle box to trap the Cenobites within, and it self destructs as well, and destroying the connection between Hell and Earth as well. Bradley still keeps you watching as Pinhead with his philosophical like dialogue and his malevolent love for torture and death on humans, I will be honest though I don't fully agree with the critics giving it an average review, I think it is nearly the most ridiculous of the films in the series, going to the future and into space is a daft idea, only the origins of the puzzle box and the bloody effects is what kept me interested, apart from that it was a slightly disappointing horror. Okay!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    He back, and this time he in space.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    atinder
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This my first watch of this movie, , I loved first 2 move in the series and I enjoyed the third one, i thought it okay sequel However this one, i did not like as much as the other sequels, I just could not get into this story at all, I really bored for most of the time in them movie. I did not care for any one in this movie, the acting was not great but it still worth watching i say There were some decent gory scenes in this movie but I didn't find anything scary or creepy about this what so ever. I found this very dull and boring with bloody parts in here and there, Over I give 4 out of 10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Do I look like someone who cares what God thinks?!?"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Scott LeBrun (Hey_Sweden)
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watchable entry in the "Hellraiser" series at least does its best to establish a mythology. It focuses on the puzzle box itself, otherwise known as the Lament Configuration, that caused all of the trouble in the first place. It was created centuries ago by a toy maker who knew not what he was doing, as nefarious types were out to use it to unleash demons such as Pinhead upon the world. The back stories are framed by sequences set in the future where the latest descendant of that long ago toy maker is attempting to make things right again with a puzzle box of his own. Now, it almost certainly would have been better had director Kevin Yagher, a top makeup and special effects designer, been able to stick with his own vision, as extensive re-shoots were ordered, re-shoots that didn't involve him, and as a result he took his own name off the picture in favour of the notorious pseudonym Alan Smithee. And the story does indeed feel thin, not fully realized, and too rushed. Overall this is a hard movie to really get interested in, as too many of the characters and actors on hand are of the nondescript kind. Doug Bradley as Pinhead, of course, is an exception, and is magnetic as always, sinking his teeth into his literate dialogue. And Valentina Vargas is mildly amusing and definitely sexy as his ironically named cohort Angelique. There's just not much "oomph" to this thing, no standout set pieces, and no real sense of overwhelming doom or menace. In fact, it's tiresome at times. The gore and designs are a highlight (although one can tell this was done on a budget), with Pinhead provided with an effective "canine" companion. There are interesting ideas here, and hints of what could have been, but from start to finish this is purely on the routine side. Five out of 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Geez, these people need to stay away from that box! Grab a friggin' Rubic's Cube!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Kristine (kristinedrama14@msn.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When we think about what famous horror films like A Nightmare on Elm Street, Halloween and Friday the 13th, what do they have in common? They all have a million sequels. The series that seems to be the underdog that most people forget about but know it's main villain is Hellraiser which has a decent amount of sequels. However the sad part is, after the first three movies, every sequel that came out was a direct to video so I don't think the series had much of a chance to stand up to the big boys on the block of the horror genre. Hellraiser was the series that was not only darker but more serious when it came to horror and wasn't afraid to show off the gory side of torture. Think about it, I don't think we could have films like Saw and Hostel which owe a little thanks to Hellraiser for giving us the blood and guts. Also it gave us an extremely dark villain, Pinhead who feels no mercy and enjoys the pleasure of putting pain into your body and pulling your flesh every way possible with chains and hooks. But where did the puzzle box come from? Well Bloodline takes us into the story of the origin of the cenobites. In the year 2127, Paul Merchant, has a robot solve the puzzle box that holds Pinhead. However, several guards led by Rimmer capture Paul. Paul tells Rimmer the story of his bloodline. Philip L'Merchant, a French toymaker, makes the puzzle box for a wealthy aristocrat, who is obsessed with dark magic. He and his apprentice kill a woman and use her to summon the Cenobite slave Angelique. However, Angelique betrays and kills the aristocrat. L'Merchant, in the process of inventing a design to destroy the demons, attempts to steal back the box but is discovered. Jacques, Angelique's master, callously informs the toymaker that he and his bloodline are cursed until the end of time because of the box he created, before ordering Angelique to kill him. However, his wife survives and gives birth to his son, thus continuing the bloodline and to the future where Paul is trying to destroy Pinhead and Angelique once and for all. So I really did enjoy the story of Bloodline, it was a great idea that deserved more time and money. The film does well with what it was given, but since you can tell they were not given such great finances, the film falls short in the acting and shortness of the film. It feels like a made for TV film at times that was just more bloody than others. I couldn't really get into Valentina Vargas as Angelique nor did I find her incredibly evil like Pinhead, she didn't send any chills down my spine. But the last fight with Pinhead was cool and there are some great one liners. Pinhead screaming how he couldn't die is classic considering how many more sequels there are, but this was meant to take place in the future so who knows? Maybe Pinhead really does die in the future. I was a bit disappointed that we didn't have any more Elliot Spencer who is also a very interesting character. But this story was more about how the box was created and the family and their curse to fight the cenobites forever. Over all, it's worth the look, I think this was the last good sequel before it started getting weird and that's odd to say considering this is the Hellraiser series. 5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very well done! C'mon, have you actually SEEN most other 'Horror' films...?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lathe-of-heaven
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Okay, I wasn't going to bother writing a review for this one and I rarely take the time to write reviews here, BUT... Seeing this undeservedly LOW score here made me feel that I really had to 'say' something. First off, YES, I am indeed a BIG fan of the first three films; before these just recently came out on glorious Blu-ray, years ago, I even sprang for the UK Puzzle Box set of the first three films (mainly because at the time UNCUT versions were not available here in the states and also for the full commentaries and the bonus DVD that came with it : ) Now, I know it is hard to believe, but I just NOW for the very first time saw this one, part 4; the reason being is that from casual stuff I had read I was under the impression that pretty much all the other 'HELLRAISER' films were not made very well. Well... Let me tell you, I was extremely surprised (again, as my title above mentions) compared to all the REALLY AWFUL Horror films that are excruciatingly badly made, and that is most of them, I really was truly surprised that this one was made quite well. Okay, so a lot of the fans are sort of put off because it is really different from the other films. Fine... Isn't the POINT to try to come up with different angles and new approaches rather than just remaking the same film again and again...? I thought it was genuinely very creative and kept my attention very much so throughout the film. Sure, okay, it starts in space and your thinking 'LEPRECHAUN 3'; well, it works; it really does. Obviously a LOT of thought was put into the timeline and the mythology of the box, etc., not to mention the follow through at the end. Sure, it wrapped it up rather quickly and left it kind of ambiguous, but so what?! Yes, of COURSE it doesn't have the intensity of the original or even the complexity of the next two films, but to me I was mainly impressed by not only coming up with the new idea to show the origins, etc., but also I honestly felt that everything that made up the film was done very well considering that it is a damn 'HORROR' movie! : ) I gave it a good, strong '8' which it fully deserves considering the context and type of film. I think that people get SO jaded and expect SO dang much from sequels. Hey, like I say... I mean, C'mon, compared to what, 'WITCHBOARD' I-9 or whatever the hell it is, this here is pure art! Heh, if THIS one threw you, just wait until you see part 5! I just this minute finished watching that one for the very first time also a few minutes ago and that is a WILD departure from the early films. However, it was made even much better than this one; the director was actually very, very good!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    FINALLY a decent Hellrasier movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steven Smith
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In my honest opinion, I think the Hellrasier franchise is extremely overrated in the horror genre. I didn't like Hellraiser 1 at all. I thought it was poorly acted and directed. Hellrasier 2 was an OK movie but certainly not a classic at all. Hellrasier 3 was just awful and ridiculous. So I decided to watch 'Bloodline' last night expecting to see another poor Hellrasier movie. I was completely surprised. It was actually a good movie! Unlike the other Hellrasier movies, 'Bloodline' focuses more on important story elements but it certainly doesn't shy away from the nasty death scenes which have become synonymous with Hellrasier. People will either hate the direction this film takes or will enjoy it. I personally enjoy it and think it's superior to the other Hellrasier films. That probably sounds stupid as Hellraiser 1 & 2 are often touted as "horror classics" - I've never understood why they get so much praise as classics, whatever... 'Bloodline' has both story and gore - the perfect combination for a horror flick in my opinion. People who found Hellrasier 1,2 and 3 lame might just find 'Bloodline' a decent horror movie. Watch it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Surprisingly Complete Package But With Timidity
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tabuno
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Three stories are wrapped up in this version of Hellraiser and the storyline has a nicely cyclical completion from beginning to end. The irony with this version that it seems to have toned down the very nature of hell and pain and in a timid move edited out some of the more horrifying potential elements. Not as elegant as THE CELL (2000) and variations of THE HOUSE ON HAUNTED HILL (1999), is the storyline that keeps this movie's momentum up to the end. There are elements of ALIEN but the monsters are not that spectacular and the script seems unable to capture the emotive richness available in the storyline, the temptations, the conflicting loyalty and lust associated with real life. Nevertheless, this complete package has its qualitative, if not quantitative horrifying elements.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Poorly executed and as empty as the 22nd century space setting.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    amesmonde
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This instalment of Hellraiser, IV follows the bloodline of the creator of the puzzle box the 'Toy Maker' and his plan to summon and to destroy Pinhead forever. Despite a theatrical release, bloodline looks and feels TV movie-like and the acting is below average, possibly due to the script. That said, Doug Bradley is fine as Pinhead and Valentina Vargas is note-worthy as the demon Angelique. The story's concept is quite good, and includes (one assumes) the building in the 3rd and the history of the box. It is told in flash-backs by Dr. Paul Merchant in the year 2127 and follows his descendants Phillip L'Merchant in the 18th century and John Merchant in 1996. Sadly, it's just poorly executed and let down by an uneven screenplay, bland direction and sub-par sets. The effects are a mixed bag, some are well done while others are less-convincing and tame. It appears to have a troubled shooting history as there were two directors Alan Smithee (under an alias Kevin Yagher) and Joe Chappelle (uncredited). This maybe one cause and result of such an less than satisfying fourth. Overall, producers didn't give such a bankable character as Pinhead the attention he deserved leaving the viewer as empty as the 22nd century space setting.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's better than the second one anyway
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There's a lot of ketchup but not a lot of narrative sense in this supposedly explanatory third sequel, which piles on the crummy visuals to no effect. Good old Alan Smithee directed this one, in which various members of the same family (all played, poorly, by Bruce Ramsay) are terrorised by Pinhead (Doug Bradley, wheeled out of mothballs for the umpteenth time). Peter Atkins tries to imbue his script with poetic touches but doesn't seem to realise that his dialogue is as deep and meaningful as a plate of vomit. The incoherent plot fails to adequately fill the movie's meagre running time, although this may have more to do with studio interference than anything the filmmakers intended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    In CGI Space - Nobody Can Hear Your Boredom...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Josh Morgan
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Pinhead in space! Hey - it worked for the Leprechaun. You know you're in trouble when a once reputable horror franchise throws a "katching" sound effect at you before the opening titles. The plot, dealing with the history of those responsible for the notorious puzzle box, is sadly done in relatively cheap flashbacks (with limited sets). Most of the (surprisingly minimal) gore is unnecessary (such as the autopsy of a body for no apparent reason), and the now cut-rate CGI box looks incredibly lame. Also, the conclusion - where a space station folds into a giant puzzle box - left my forehead bruised, as I smacked it in disgust. The worst of the theatrical entries. You may just want to skip ahead to Hellraiser: Inferno, as it's a pretty decent little thriller. Directed by everyone's favorite pseudonym, Alan Smithee.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hellraiser IV: Bloodline
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The first film was good, the second film was disappointing, the third film was okay, and this next sequel I expected to be pretty much exactly the same standard as the last one, and it would be the last played in the cinemas. Basically it is the year 2127 on the Space Station Mionos, and the man who built the station Dr. Paul Merchant (Bruce Ramsay) has built a robot that can solve the Lament Configuration, i.e. the puzzle box, but the robot is destroyed and he is captured, and he tells his kidnapper Rimmer (Christine Harnos) the story of his bloodline. The story flashbacks 400 years earlier, where French toymaker Philip L'Merchant (Ramsay again) creates the Lament Configuration, he believes it will be just a simple puzzle box for wealthy aristocrat Duc De L'Isle (Mickey Cottrell), but he has black magic in mind and uses it to release Cenobite slave Angelique (Valentina Vargas) from the dark regions. The toymaker also invented the Elysium Configuration which he uses to destroy the demons, the Duc's apprentice Jacques (Adam Scott) informs him that his bloodline are cursed until time ends because of his creation. Two hundred year pass, and the next in the bloodline John Merchant (also Ramsay) is the architect who built the building seen at the end of Hellraiser III, where the puzzle box was placed in the wet cement, and after Jacques is killed by Angelique she travels to America and tries to seduce John, the puzzle box is taken from the ground, and a man solves it and as a result releases Pinhead (Doug Bradley). The Cenobite leader wants the Elysium Configuration to be be used to open the gates of Hell and allow him and his dark forces to do anything he pleases, and he knows the best way to force John to do it is by threatening his child Jack (Courtland Mead). The Elysium Configuration is forced to be used, but it does not work, so Merchant is killed, while his wife Bobbi (Kim Myers) is the one who sends Pinhead, Angelique and the other Cenobites created back to Hell. Back in the future 2127 on the space station the Cenobites are freed once again, Rimmer realises the danger they are all in and releases Paul so that he can destroy the demons, using the main purpose the Minos was built for. Pinhead is distracted while Paul and Rimmer escape in a shuttle, and the combination of powerful lasers and mirrors create a blast of light, and the space station is transformed into a giant version of the puzzle box to trap the Cenobites within, and it self destructs as well, and destroying the connection between Hell and Earth as well. Bradley still keeps you watching as Pinhead with his philosophical like dialogue and his malevolent love for torture and death on humans, I will be honest though I don't fully agree with the critics giving it an average review, I think it is nearly the most ridiculous of the films in the series, going to the future and into space is a daft idea, only the origins of the puzzle box and the bloody effects is what kept me interested, apart from that it was a slightly disappointing horror. Okay!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    He back, and this time he in space.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    atinder
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This my first watch of this movie, , I loved first 2 move in the series and I enjoyed the third one, i thought it okay sequel However this one, i did not like as much as the other sequels, I just could not get into this story at all, I really bored for most of the time in them movie. I did not care for any one in this movie, the acting was not great but it still worth watching i say There were some decent gory scenes in this movie but I didn't find anything scary or creepy about this what so ever. I found this very dull and boring with bloody parts in here and there, Over I give 4 out of 10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Do I look like someone who cares what God thinks?!?"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Scott LeBrun (Hey_Sweden)
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watchable entry in the "Hellraiser" series at least does its best to establish a mythology. It focuses on the puzzle box itself, otherwise known as the Lament Configuration, that caused all of the trouble in the first place. It was created centuries ago by a toy maker who knew not what he was doing, as nefarious types were out to use it to unleash demons such as Pinhead upon the world. The back stories are framed by sequences set in the future where the latest descendant of that long ago toy maker is attempting to make things right again with a puzzle box of his own. Now, it almost certainly would have been better had director Kevin Yagher, a top makeup and special effects designer, been able to stick with his own vision, as extensive re-shoots were ordered, re-shoots that didn't involve him, and as a result he took his own name off the picture in favour of the notorious pseudonym Alan Smithee. And the story does indeed feel thin, not fully realized, and too rushed. Overall this is a hard movie to really get interested in, as too many of the characters and actors on hand are of the nondescript kind. Doug Bradley as Pinhead, of course, is an exception, and is magnetic as always, sinking his teeth into his literate dialogue. And Valentina Vargas is mildly amusing and definitely sexy as his ironically named cohort Angelique. There's just not much "oomph" to this thing, no standout set pieces, and no real sense of overwhelming doom or menace. In fact, it's tiresome at times. The gore and designs are a highlight (although one can tell this was done on a budget), with Pinhead provided with an effective "canine" companion. There are interesting ideas here, and hints of what could have been, but from start to finish this is purely on the routine side. Five out of 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Geez, these people need to stay away from that box! Grab a friggin' Rubic's Cube!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Kristine (kristinedrama14@msn.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When we think about what famous horror films like A Nightmare on Elm Street, Halloween and Friday the 13th, what do they have in common? They all have a million sequels. The series that seems to be the underdog that most people forget about but know it's main villain is Hellraiser which has a decent amount of sequels. However the sad part is, after the first three movies, every sequel that came out was a direct to video so I don't think the series had much of a chance to stand up to the big boys on the block of the horror genre. Hellraiser was the series that was not only darker but more serious when it came to horror and wasn't afraid to show off the gory side of torture. Think about it, I don't think we could have films like Saw and Hostel which owe a little thanks to Hellraiser for giving us the blood and guts. Also it gave us an extremely dark villain, Pinhead who feels no mercy and enjoys the pleasure of putting pain into your body and pulling your flesh every way possible with chains and hooks. But where did the puzzle box come from? Well Bloodline takes us into the story of the origin of the cenobites. In the year 2127, Paul Merchant, has a robot solve the puzzle box that holds Pinhead. However, several guards led by Rimmer capture Paul. Paul tells Rimmer the story of his bloodline. Philip L'Merchant, a French toymaker, makes the puzzle box for a wealthy aristocrat, who is obsessed with dark magic. He and his apprentice kill a woman and use her to summon the Cenobite slave Angelique. However, Angelique betrays and kills the aristocrat. L'Merchant, in the process of inventing a design to destroy the demons, attempts to steal back the box but is discovered. Jacques, Angelique's master, callously informs the toymaker that he and his bloodline are cursed until the end of time because of the box he created, before ordering Angelique to kill him. However, his wife survives and gives birth to his son, thus continuing the bloodline and to the future where Paul is trying to destroy Pinhead and Angelique once and for all. So I really did enjoy the story of Bloodline, it was a great idea that deserved more time and money. The film does well with what it was given, but since you can tell they were not given such great finances, the film falls short in the acting and shortness of the film. It feels like a made for TV film at times that was just more bloody than others. I couldn't really get into Valentina Vargas as Angelique nor did I find her incredibly evil like Pinhead, she didn't send any chills down my spine. But the last fight with Pinhead was cool and there are some great one liners. Pinhead screaming how he couldn't die is classic considering how many more sequels there are, but this was meant to take place in the future so who knows? Maybe Pinhead really does die in the future. I was a bit disappointed that we didn't have any more Elliot Spencer who is also a very interesting character. But this story was more about how the box was created and the family and their curse to fight the cenobites forever. Over all, it's worth the look, I think this was the last good sequel before it started getting weird and that's odd to say considering this is the Hellraiser series. 5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very well done! C'mon, have you actually SEEN most other 'Horror' films...?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lathe-of-heaven
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Okay, I wasn't going to bother writing a review for this one and I rarely take the time to write reviews here, BUT... Seeing this undeservedly LOW score here made me feel that I really had to 'say' something. First off, YES, I am indeed a BIG fan of the first three films; before these just recently came out on glorious Blu-ray, years ago, I even sprang for the UK Puzzle Box set of the first three films (mainly because at the time UNCUT versions were not available here in the states and also for the full commentaries and the bonus DVD that came with it : ) Now, I know it is hard to believe, but I just NOW for the very first time saw this one, part 4; the reason being is that from casual stuff I had read I was under the impression that pretty much all the other 'HELLRAISER' films were not made very well. Well... Let me tell you, I was extremely surprised (again, as my title above mentions) compared to all the REALLY AWFUL Horror films that are excruciatingly badly made, and that is most of them, I really was truly surprised that this one was made quite well. Okay, so a lot of the fans are sort of put off because it is really different from the other films. Fine... Isn't the POINT to try to come up with different angles and new approaches rather than just remaking the same film again and again...? I thought it was genuinely very creative and kept my attention very much so throughout the film. Sure, okay, it starts in space and your thinking 'LEPRECHAUN 3'; well, it works; it really does. Obviously a LOT of thought was put into the timeline and the mythology of the box, etc., not to mention the follow through at the end. Sure, it wrapped it up rather quickly and left it kind of ambiguous, but so what?! Yes, of COURSE it doesn't have the intensity of the original or even the complexity of the next two films, but to me I was mainly impressed by not only coming up with the new idea to show the origins, etc., but also I honestly felt that everything that made up the film was done very well considering that it is a damn 'HORROR' movie! : ) I gave it a good, strong '8' which it fully deserves considering the context and type of film. I think that people get SO jaded and expect SO dang much from sequels. Hey, like I say... I mean, C'mon, compared to what, 'WITCHBOARD' I-9 or whatever the hell it is, this here is pure art! Heh, if THIS one threw you, just wait until you see part 5! I just this minute finished watching that one for the very first time also a few minutes ago and that is a WILD departure from the early films. However, it was made even much better than this one; the director was actually very, very good!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    FINALLY a decent Hellrasier movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steven Smith
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In my honest opinion, I think the Hellrasier franchise is extremely overrated in the horror genre. I didn't like Hellraiser 1 at all. I thought it was poorly acted and directed. Hellrasier 2 was an OK movie but certainly not a classic at all. Hellrasier 3 was just awful and ridiculous. So I decided to watch 'Bloodline' last night expecting to see another poor Hellrasier movie. I was completely surprised. It was actually a good movie! Unlike the other Hellrasier movies, 'Bloodline' focuses more on important story elements but it certainly doesn't shy away from the nasty death scenes which have become synonymous with Hellrasier. People will either hate the direction this film takes or will enjoy it. I personally enjoy it and think it's superior to the other Hellrasier films. That probably sounds stupid as Hellraiser 1 & 2 are often touted as "horror classics" - I've never understood why they get so much praise as classics, whatever... 'Bloodline' has both story and gore - the perfect combination for a horror flick in my opinion. People who found Hellrasier 1,2 and 3 lame might just find 'Bloodline' a decent horror movie. Watch it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Surprisingly Complete Package But With Timidity
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tabuno
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Three stories are wrapped up in this version of Hellraiser and the storyline has a nicely cyclical completion from beginning to end. The irony with this version that it seems to have toned down the very nature of hell and pain and in a timid move edited out some of the more horrifying potential elements. Not as elegant as THE CELL (2000) and variations of THE HOUSE ON HAUNTED HILL (1999), is the storyline that keeps this movie's momentum up to the end. There are elements of ALIEN but the monsters are not that spectacular and the script seems unable to capture the emotive richness available in the storyline, the temptations, the conflicting loyalty and lust associated with real life. Nevertheless, this complete package has its qualitative, if not quantitative horrifying elements.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Poorly executed and as empty as the 22nd century space setting.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    amesmonde
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This instalment of Hellraiser, IV follows the bloodline of the creator of the puzzle box the 'Toy Maker' and his plan to summon and to destroy Pinhead forever. Despite a theatrical release, bloodline looks and feels TV movie-like and the acting is below average, possibly due to the script. That said, Doug Bradley is fine as Pinhead and Valentina Vargas is note-worthy as the demon Angelique. The story's concept is quite good, and includes (one assumes) the building in the 3rd and the history of the box. It is told in flash-backs by Dr. Paul Merchant in the year 2127 and follows his descendants Phillip L'Merchant in the 18th century and John Merchant in 1996. Sadly, it's just poorly executed and let down by an uneven screenplay, bland direction and sub-par sets. The effects are a mixed bag, some are well done while others are less-convincing and tame. It appears to have a troubled shooting history as there were two directors Alan Smithee (under an alias Kevin Yagher) and Joe Chappelle (uncredited). This maybe one cause and result of such an less than satisfying fourth. Overall, producers didn't give such a bankable character as Pinhead the attention he deserved leaving the viewer as empty as the 22nd century space setting.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's better than the second one anyway
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There's a lot of ketchup but not a lot of narrative sense in this supposedly explanatory third sequel, which piles on the crummy visuals to no effect. Good old Alan Smithee directed this one, in which various members of the same family (all played, poorly, by Bruce Ramsay) are terrorised by Pinhead (Doug Bradley, wheeled out of mothballs for the umpteenth time). Peter Atkins tries to imbue his script with poetic touches but doesn't seem to realise that his dialogue is as deep and meaningful as a plate of vomit. The incoherent plot fails to adequately fill the movie's meagre running time, although this may have more to do with studio interference than anything the filmmakers intended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    In CGI Space - Nobody Can Hear Your Boredom...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Josh Morgan
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Pinhead in space! Hey - it worked for the Leprechaun. You know you're in trouble when a once reputable horror franchise throws a "katching" sound effect at you before the opening titles. The plot, dealing with the history of those responsible for the notorious puzzle box, is sadly done in relatively cheap flashbacks (with limited sets). Most of the (surprisingly minimal) gore is unnecessary (such as the autopsy of a body for no apparent reason), and the now cut-rate CGI box looks incredibly lame. Also, the conclusion - where a space station folds into a giant puzzle box - left my forehead bruised, as I smacked it in disgust. The worst of the theatrical entries. You may just want to skip ahead to Hellraiser: Inferno, as it's a pretty decent little thriller. Directed by everyone's favorite pseudonym, Alan Smithee.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hellraiser IV: Bloodline
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The first film was good, the second film was disappointing, the third film was okay, and this next sequel I expected to be pretty much exactly the same standard as the last one, and it would be the last played in the cinemas. Basically it is the year 2127 on the Space Station Mionos, and the man who built the station Dr. Paul Merchant (Bruce Ramsay) has built a robot that can solve the Lament Configuration, i.e. the puzzle box, but the robot is destroyed and he is captured, and he tells his kidnapper Rimmer (Christine Harnos) the story of his bloodline. The story flashbacks 400 years earlier, where French toymaker Philip L'Merchant (Ramsay again) creates the Lament Configuration, he believes it will be just a simple puzzle box for wealthy aristocrat Duc De L'Isle (Mickey Cottrell), but he has black magic in mind and uses it to release Cenobite slave Angelique (Valentina Vargas) from the dark regions. The toymaker also invented the Elysium Configuration which he uses to destroy the demons, the Duc's apprentice Jacques (Adam Scott) informs him that his bloodline are cursed until time ends because of his creation. Two hundred year pass, and the next in the bloodline John Merchant (also Ramsay) is the architect who built the building seen at the end of Hellraiser III, where the puzzle box was placed in the wet cement, and after Jacques is killed by Angelique she travels to America and tries to seduce John, the puzzle box is taken from the ground, and a man solves it and as a result releases Pinhead (Doug Bradley). The Cenobite leader wants the Elysium Configuration to be be used to open the gates of Hell and allow him and his dark forces to do anything he pleases, and he knows the best way to force John to do it is by threatening his child Jack (Courtland Mead). The Elysium Configuration is forced to be used, but it does not work, so Merchant is killed, while his wife Bobbi (Kim Myers) is the one who sends Pinhead, Angelique and the other Cenobites created back to Hell. Back in the future 2127 on the space station the Cenobites are freed once again, Rimmer realises the danger they are all in and releases Paul so that he can destroy the demons, using the main purpose the Minos was built for. Pinhead is distracted while Paul and Rimmer escape in a shuttle, and the combination of powerful lasers and mirrors create a blast of light, and the space station is transformed into a giant version of the puzzle box to trap the Cenobites within, and it self destructs as well, and destroying the connection between Hell and Earth as well. Bradley still keeps you watching as Pinhead with his philosophical like dialogue and his malevolent love for torture and death on humans, I will be honest though I don't fully agree with the critics giving it an average review, I think it is nearly the most ridiculous of the films in the series, going to the future and into space is a daft idea, only the origins of the puzzle box and the bloody effects is what kept me interested, apart from that it was a slightly disappointing horror. Okay!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    He back, and this time he in space.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    atinder
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This my first watch of this movie, , I loved first 2 move in the series and I enjoyed the third one, i thought it okay sequel However this one, i did not like as much as the other sequels, I just could not get into this story at all, I really bored for most of the time in them movie. I did not care for any one in this movie, the acting was not great but it still worth watching i say There were some decent gory scenes in this movie but I didn't find anything scary or creepy about this what so ever. I found this very dull and boring with bloody parts in here and there, Over I give 4 out of 10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Do I look like someone who cares what God thinks?!?"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Scott LeBrun (Hey_Sweden)
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watchable entry in the "Hellraiser" series at least does its best to establish a mythology. It focuses on the puzzle box itself, otherwise known as the Lament Configuration, that caused all of the trouble in the first place. It was created centuries ago by a toy maker who knew not what he was doing, as nefarious types were out to use it to unleash demons such as Pinhead upon the world. The back stories are framed by sequences set in the future where the latest descendant of that long ago toy maker is attempting to make things right again with a puzzle box of his own. Now, it almost certainly would have been better had director Kevin Yagher, a top makeup and special effects designer, been able to stick with his own vision, as extensive re-shoots were ordered, re-shoots that didn't involve him, and as a result he took his own name off the picture in favour of the notorious pseudonym Alan Smithee. And the story does indeed feel thin, not fully realized, and too rushed. Overall this is a hard movie to really get interested in, as too many of the characters and actors on hand are of the nondescript kind. Doug Bradley as Pinhead, of course, is an exception, and is magnetic as always, sinking his teeth into his literate dialogue. And Valentina Vargas is mildly amusing and definitely sexy as his ironically named cohort Angelique. There's just not much "oomph" to this thing, no standout set pieces, and no real sense of overwhelming doom or menace. In fact, it's tiresome at times. The gore and designs are a highlight (although one can tell this was done on a budget), with Pinhead provided with an effective "canine" companion. There are interesting ideas here, and hints of what could have been, but from start to finish this is purely on the routine side. Five out of 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Geez, these people need to stay away from that box! Grab a friggin' Rubic's Cube!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Kristine (kristinedrama14@msn.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When we think about what famous horror films like A Nightmare on Elm Street, Halloween and Friday the 13th, what do they have in common? They all have a million sequels. The series that seems to be the underdog that most people forget about but know it's main villain is Hellraiser which has a decent amount of sequels. However the sad part is, after the first three movies, every sequel that came out was a direct to video so I don't think the series had much of a chance to stand up to the big boys on the block of the horror genre. Hellraiser was the series that was not only darker but more serious when it came to horror and wasn't afraid to show off the gory side of torture. Think about it, I don't think we could have films like Saw and Hostel which owe a little thanks to Hellraiser for giving us the blood and guts. Also it gave us an extremely dark villain, Pinhead who feels no mercy and enjoys the pleasure of putting pain into your body and pulling your flesh every way possible with chains and hooks. But where did the puzzle box come from? Well Bloodline takes us into the story of the origin of the cenobites. In the year 2127, Paul Merchant, has a robot solve the puzzle box that holds Pinhead. However, several guards led by Rimmer capture Paul. Paul tells Rimmer the story of his bloodline. Philip L'Merchant, a French toymaker, makes the puzzle box for a wealthy aristocrat, who is obsessed with dark magic. He and his apprentice kill a woman and use her to summon the Cenobite slave Angelique. However, Angelique betrays and kills the aristocrat. L'Merchant, in the process of inventing a design to destroy the demons, attempts to steal back the box but is discovered. Jacques, Angelique's master, callously informs the toymaker that he and his bloodline are cursed until the end of time because of the box he created, before ordering Angelique to kill him. However, his wife survives and gives birth to his son, thus continuing the bloodline and to the future where Paul is trying to destroy Pinhead and Angelique once and for all. So I really did enjoy the story of Bloodline, it was a great idea that deserved more time and money. The film does well with what it was given, but since you can tell they were not given such great finances, the film falls short in the acting and shortness of the film. It feels like a made for TV film at times that was just more bloody than others. I couldn't really get into Valentina Vargas as Angelique nor did I find her incredibly evil like Pinhead, she didn't send any chills down my spine. But the last fight with Pinhead was cool and there are some great one liners. Pinhead screaming how he couldn't die is classic considering how many more sequels there are, but this was meant to take place in the future so who knows? Maybe Pinhead really does die in the future. I was a bit disappointed that we didn't have any more Elliot Spencer who is also a very interesting character. But this story was more about how the box was created and the family and their curse to fight the cenobites forever. Over all, it's worth the look, I think this was the last good sequel before it started getting weird and that's odd to say considering this is the Hellraiser series. 5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very well done! C'mon, have you actually SEEN most other 'Horror' films...?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lathe-of-heaven
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Okay, I wasn't going to bother writing a review for this one and I rarely take the time to write reviews here, BUT... Seeing this undeservedly LOW score here made me feel that I really had to 'say' something. First off, YES, I am indeed a BIG fan of the first three films; before these just recently came out on glorious Blu-ray, years ago, I even sprang for the UK Puzzle Box set of the first three films (mainly because at the time UNCUT versions were not available here in the states and also for the full commentaries and the bonus DVD that came with it : ) Now, I know it is hard to believe, but I just NOW for the very first time saw this one, part 4; the reason being is that from casual stuff I had read I was under the impression that pretty much all the other 'HELLRAISER' films were not made very well. Well... Let me tell you, I was extremely surprised (again, as my title above mentions) compared to all the REALLY AWFUL Horror films that are excruciatingly badly made, and that is most of them, I really was truly surprised that this one was made quite well. Okay, so a lot of the fans are sort of put off because it is really different from the other films. Fine... Isn't the POINT to try to come up with different angles and new approaches rather than just remaking the same film again and again...? I thought it was genuinely very creative and kept my attention very much so throughout the film. Sure, okay, it starts in space and your thinking 'LEPRECHAUN 3'; well, it works; it really does. Obviously a LOT of thought was put into the timeline and the mythology of the box, etc., not to mention the follow through at the end. Sure, it wrapped it up rather quickly and left it kind of ambiguous, but so what?! Yes, of COURSE it doesn't have the intensity of the original or even the complexity of the next two films, but to me I was mainly impressed by not only coming up with the new idea to show the origins, etc., but also I honestly felt that everything that made up the film was done very well considering that it is a damn 'HORROR' movie! : ) I gave it a good, strong '8' which it fully deserves considering the context and type of film. I think that people get SO jaded and expect SO dang much from sequels. Hey, like I say... I mean, C'mon, compared to what, 'WITCHBOARD' I-9 or whatever the hell it is, this here is pure art! Heh, if THIS one threw you, just wait until you see part 5! I just this minute finished watching that one for the very first time also a few minutes ago and that is a WILD departure from the early films. However, it was made even much better than this one; the director was actually very, very good!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    FINALLY a decent Hellrasier movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steven Smith
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In my honest opinion, I think the Hellrasier franchise is extremely overrated in the horror genre. I didn't like Hellraiser 1 at all. I thought it was poorly acted and directed. Hellrasier 2 was an OK movie but certainly not a classic at all. Hellrasier 3 was just awful and ridiculous. So I decided to watch 'Bloodline' last night expecting to see another poor Hellrasier movie. I was completely surprised. It was actually a good movie! Unlike the other Hellrasier movies, 'Bloodline' focuses more on important story elements but it certainly doesn't shy away from the nasty death scenes which have become synonymous with Hellrasier. People will either hate the direction this film takes or will enjoy it. I personally enjoy it and think it's superior to the other Hellrasier films. That probably sounds stupid as Hellraiser 1 & 2 are often touted as "horror classics" - I've never understood why they get so much praise as classics, whatever... 'Bloodline' has both story and gore - the perfect combination for a horror flick in my opinion. People who found Hellrasier 1,2 and 3 lame might just find 'Bloodline' a decent horror movie. Watch it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Surprisingly Complete Package But With Timidity
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tabuno
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Three stories are wrapped up in this version of Hellraiser and the storyline has a nicely cyclical completion from beginning to end. The irony with this version that it seems to have toned down the very nature of hell and pain and in a timid move edited out some of the more horrifying potential elements. Not as elegant as THE CELL (2000) and variations of THE HOUSE ON HAUNTED HILL (1999), is the storyline that keeps this movie's momentum up to the end. There are elements of ALIEN but the monsters are not that spectacular and the script seems unable to capture the emotive richness available in the storyline, the temptations, the conflicting loyalty and lust associated with real life. Nevertheless, this complete package has its qualitative, if not quantitative horrifying elements.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Poorly executed and as empty as the 22nd century space setting.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    amesmonde
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This instalment of Hellraiser, IV follows the bloodline of the creator of the puzzle box the 'Toy Maker' and his plan to summon and to destroy Pinhead forever. Despite a theatrical release, bloodline looks and feels TV movie-like and the acting is below average, possibly due to the script. That said, Doug Bradley is fine as Pinhead and Valentina Vargas is note-worthy as the demon Angelique. The story's concept is quite good, and includes (one assumes) the building in the 3rd and the history of the box. It is told in flash-backs by Dr. Paul Merchant in the year 2127 and follows his descendants Phillip L'Merchant in the 18th century and John Merchant in 1996. Sadly, it's just poorly executed and let down by an uneven screenplay, bland direction and sub-par sets. The effects are a mixed bag, some are well done while others are less-convincing and tame. It appears to have a troubled shooting history as there were two directors Alan Smithee (under an alias Kevin Yagher) and Joe Chappelle (uncredited). This maybe one cause and result of such an less than satisfying fourth. Overall, producers didn't give such a bankable character as Pinhead the attention he deserved leaving the viewer as empty as the 22nd century space setting.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's better than the second one anyway
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There's a lot of ketchup but not a lot of narrative sense in this supposedly explanatory third sequel, which piles on the crummy visuals to no effect. Good old Alan Smithee directed this one, in which various members of the same family (all played, poorly, by Bruce Ramsay) are terrorised by Pinhead (Doug Bradley, wheeled out of mothballs for the umpteenth time). Peter Atkins tries to imbue his script with poetic touches but doesn't seem to realise that his dialogue is as deep and meaningful as a plate of vomit. The incoherent plot fails to adequately fill the movie's meagre running time, although this may have more to do with studio interference than anything the filmmakers intended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    In CGI Space - Nobody Can Hear Your Boredom...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Josh Morgan
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Pinhead in space! Hey - it worked for the Leprechaun. You know you're in trouble when a once reputable horror franchise throws a "katching" sound effect at you before the opening titles. The plot, dealing with the history of those responsible for the notorious puzzle box, is sadly done in relatively cheap flashbacks (with limited sets). Most of the (surprisingly minimal) gore is unnecessary (such as the autopsy of a body for no apparent reason), and the now cut-rate CGI box looks incredibly lame. Also, the conclusion - where a space station folds into a giant puzzle box - left my forehead bruised, as I smacked it in disgust. The worst of the theatrical entries. You may just want to skip ahead to Hellraiser: Inferno, as it's a pretty decent little thriller. Directed by everyone's favorite pseudonym, Alan Smithee.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hellraiser IV: Bloodline
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The first film was good, the second film was disappointing, the third film was okay, and this next sequel I expected to be pretty much exactly the same standard as the last one, and it would be the last played in the cinemas. Basically it is the year 2127 on the Space Station Mionos, and the man who built the station Dr. Paul Merchant (Bruce Ramsay) has built a robot that can solve the Lament Configuration, i.e. the puzzle box, but the robot is destroyed and he is captured, and he tells his kidnapper Rimmer (Christine Harnos) the story of his bloodline. The story flashbacks 400 years earlier, where French toymaker Philip L'Merchant (Ramsay again) creates the Lament Configuration, he believes it will be just a simple puzzle box for wealthy aristocrat Duc De L'Isle (Mickey Cottrell), but he has black magic in mind and uses it to release Cenobite slave Angelique (Valentina Vargas) from the dark regions. The toymaker also invented the Elysium Configuration which he uses to destroy the demons, the Duc's apprentice Jacques (Adam Scott) informs him that his bloodline are cursed until time ends because of his creation. Two hundred year pass, and the next in the bloodline John Merchant (also Ramsay) is the architect who built the building seen at the end of Hellraiser III, where the puzzle box was placed in the wet cement, and after Jacques is killed by Angelique she travels to America and tries to seduce John, the puzzle box is taken from the ground, and a man solves it and as a result releases Pinhead (Doug Bradley). The Cenobite leader wants the Elysium Configuration to be be used to open the gates of Hell and allow him and his dark forces to do anything he pleases, and he knows the best way to force John to do it is by threatening his child Jack (Courtland Mead). The Elysium Configuration is forced to be used, but it does not work, so Merchant is killed, while his wife Bobbi (Kim Myers) is the one who sends Pinhead, Angelique and the other Cenobites created back to Hell. Back in the future 2127 on the space station the Cenobites are freed once again, Rimmer realises the danger they are all in and releases Paul so that he can destroy the demons, using the main purpose the Minos was built for. Pinhead is distracted while Paul and Rimmer escape in a shuttle, and the combination of powerful lasers and mirrors create a blast of light, and the space station is transformed into a giant version of the puzzle box to trap the Cenobites within, and it self destructs as well, and destroying the connection between Hell and Earth as well. Bradley still keeps you watching as Pinhead with his philosophical like dialogue and his malevolent love for torture and death on humans, I will be honest though I don't fully agree with the critics giving it an average review, I think it is nearly the most ridiculous of the films in the series, going to the future and into space is a daft idea, only the origins of the puzzle box and the bloody effects is what kept me interested, apart from that it was a slightly disappointing horror. Okay!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    He back, and this time he in space.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    atinder
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This my first watch of this movie, , I loved first 2 move in the series and I enjoyed the third one, i thought it okay sequel However this one, i did not like as much as the other sequels, I just could not get into this story at all, I really bored for most of the time in them movie. I did not care for any one in this movie, the acting was not great but it still worth watching i say There were some decent gory scenes in this movie but I didn't find anything scary or creepy about this what so ever. I found this very dull and boring with bloody parts in here and there, Over I give 4 out of 10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Do I look like someone who cares what God thinks?!?"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Scott LeBrun (Hey_Sweden)
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watchable entry in the "Hellraiser" series at least does its best to establish a mythology. It focuses on the puzzle box itself, otherwise known as the Lament Configuration, that caused all of the trouble in the first place. It was created centuries ago by a toy maker who knew not what he was doing, as nefarious types were out to use it to unleash demons such as Pinhead upon the world. The back stories are framed by sequences set in the future where the latest descendant of that long ago toy maker is attempting to make things right again with a puzzle box of his own. Now, it almost certainly would have been better had director Kevin Yagher, a top makeup and special effects designer, been able to stick with his own vision, as extensive re-shoots were ordered, re-shoots that didn't involve him, and as a result he took his own name off the picture in favour of the notorious pseudonym Alan Smithee. And the story does indeed feel thin, not fully realized, and too rushed. Overall this is a hard movie to really get interested in, as too many of the characters and actors on hand are of the nondescript kind. Doug Bradley as Pinhead, of course, is an exception, and is magnetic as always, sinking his teeth into his literate dialogue. And Valentina Vargas is mildly amusing and definitely sexy as his ironically named cohort Angelique. There's just not much "oomph" to this thing, no standout set pieces, and no real sense of overwhelming doom or menace. In fact, it's tiresome at times. The gore and designs are a highlight (although one can tell this was done on a budget), with Pinhead provided with an effective "canine" companion. There are interesting ideas here, and hints of what could have been, but from start to finish this is purely on the routine side. Five out of 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Geez, these people need to stay away from that box! Grab a friggin' Rubic's Cube!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Kristine (kristinedrama14@msn.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When we think about what famous horror films like A Nightmare on Elm Street, Halloween and Friday the 13th, what do they have in common? They all have a million sequels. The series that seems to be the underdog that most people forget about but know it's main villain is Hellraiser which has a decent amount of sequels. However the sad part is, after the first three movies, every sequel that came out was a direct to video so I don't think the series had much of a chance to stand up to the big boys on the block of the horror genre. Hellraiser was the series that was not only darker but more serious when it came to horror and wasn't afraid to show off the gory side of torture. Think about it, I don't think we could have films like Saw and Hostel which owe a little thanks to Hellraiser for giving us the blood and guts. Also it gave us an extremely dark villain, Pinhead who feels no mercy and enjoys the pleasure of putting pain into your body and pulling your flesh every way possible with chains and hooks. But where did the puzzle box come from? Well Bloodline takes us into the story of the origin of the cenobites. In the year 2127, Paul Merchant, has a robot solve the puzzle box that holds Pinhead. However, several guards led by Rimmer capture Paul. Paul tells Rimmer the story of his bloodline. Philip L'Merchant, a French toymaker, makes the puzzle box for a wealthy aristocrat, who is obsessed with dark magic. He and his apprentice kill a woman and use her to summon the Cenobite slave Angelique. However, Angelique betrays and kills the aristocrat. L'Merchant, in the process of inventing a design to destroy the demons, attempts to steal back the box but is discovered. Jacques, Angelique's master, callously informs the toymaker that he and his bloodline are cursed until the end of time because of the box he created, before ordering Angelique to kill him. However, his wife survives and gives birth to his son, thus continuing the bloodline and to the future where Paul is trying to destroy Pinhead and Angelique once and for all. So I really did enjoy the story of Bloodline, it was a great idea that deserved more time and money. The film does well with what it was given, but since you can tell they were not given such great finances, the film falls short in the acting and shortness of the film. It feels like a made for TV film at times that was just more bloody than others. I couldn't really get into Valentina Vargas as Angelique nor did I find her incredibly evil like Pinhead, she didn't send any chills down my spine. But the last fight with Pinhead was cool and there are some great one liners. Pinhead screaming how he couldn't die is classic considering how many more sequels there are, but this was meant to take place in the future so who knows? Maybe Pinhead really does die in the future. I was a bit disappointed that we didn't have any more Elliot Spencer who is also a very interesting character. But this story was more about how the box was created and the family and their curse to fight the cenobites forever. Over all, it's worth the look, I think this was the last good sequel before it started getting weird and that's odd to say considering this is the Hellraiser series. 5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very well done! C'mon, have you actually SEEN most other 'Horror' films...?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lathe-of-heaven
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Okay, I wasn't going to bother writing a review for this one and I rarely take the time to write reviews here, BUT... Seeing this undeservedly LOW score here made me feel that I really had to 'say' something. First off, YES, I am indeed a BIG fan of the first three films; before these just recently came out on glorious Blu-ray, years ago, I even sprang for the UK Puzzle Box set of the first three films (mainly because at the time UNCUT versions were not available here in the states and also for the full commentaries and the bonus DVD that came with it : ) Now, I know it is hard to believe, but I just NOW for the very first time saw this one, part 4; the reason being is that from casual stuff I had read I was under the impression that pretty much all the other 'HELLRAISER' films were not made very well. Well... Let me tell you, I was extremely surprised (again, as my title above mentions) compared to all the REALLY AWFUL Horror films that are excruciatingly badly made, and that is most of them, I really was truly surprised that this one was made quite well. Okay, so a lot of the fans are sort of put off because it is really different from the other films. Fine... Isn't the POINT to try to come up with different angles and new approaches rather than just remaking the same film again and again...? I thought it was genuinely very creative and kept my attention very much so throughout the film. Sure, okay, it starts in space and your thinking 'LEPRECHAUN 3'; well, it works; it really does. Obviously a LOT of thought was put into the timeline and the mythology of the box, etc., not to mention the follow through at the end. Sure, it wrapped it up rather quickly and left it kind of ambiguous, but so what?! Yes, of COURSE it doesn't have the intensity of the original or even the complexity of the next two films, but to me I was mainly impressed by not only coming up with the new idea to show the origins, etc., but also I honestly felt that everything that made up the film was done very well considering that it is a damn 'HORROR' movie! : ) I gave it a good, strong '8' which it fully deserves considering the context and type of film. I think that people get SO jaded and expect SO dang much from sequels. Hey, like I say... I mean, C'mon, compared to what, 'WITCHBOARD' I-9 or whatever the hell it is, this here is pure art! Heh, if THIS one threw you, just wait until you see part 5! I just this minute finished watching that one for the very first time also a few minutes ago and that is a WILD departure from the early films. However, it was made even much better than this one; the director was actually very, very good!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    FINALLY a decent Hellrasier movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steven Smith
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In my honest opinion, I think the Hellrasier franchise is extremely overrated in the horror genre. I didn't like Hellraiser 1 at all. I thought it was poorly acted and directed. Hellrasier 2 was an OK movie but certainly not a classic at all. Hellrasier 3 was just awful and ridiculous. So I decided to watch 'Bloodline' last night expecting to see another poor Hellrasier movie. I was completely surprised. It was actually a good movie! Unlike the other Hellrasier movies, 'Bloodline' focuses more on important story elements but it certainly doesn't shy away from the nasty death scenes which have become synonymous with Hellrasier. People will either hate the direction this film takes or will enjoy it. I personally enjoy it and think it's superior to the other Hellrasier films. That probably sounds stupid as Hellraiser 1 & 2 are often touted as "horror classics" - I've never understood why they get so much praise as classics, whatever... 'Bloodline' has both story and gore - the perfect combination for a horror flick in my opinion. People who found Hellrasier 1,2 and 3 lame might just find 'Bloodline' a decent horror movie. Watch it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Surprisingly Complete Package But With Timidity
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tabuno
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Three stories are wrapped up in this version of Hellraiser and the storyline has a nicely cyclical completion from beginning to end. The irony with this version that it seems to have toned down the very nature of hell and pain and in a timid move edited out some of the more horrifying potential elements. Not as elegant as THE CELL (2000) and variations of THE HOUSE ON HAUNTED HILL (1999), is the storyline that keeps this movie's momentum up to the end. There are elements of ALIEN but the monsters are not that spectacular and the script seems unable to capture the emotive richness available in the storyline, the temptations, the conflicting loyalty and lust associated with real life. Nevertheless, this complete package has its qualitative, if not quantitative horrifying elements.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Poorly executed and as empty as the 22nd century space setting.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    amesmonde
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This instalment of Hellraiser, IV follows the bloodline of the creator of the puzzle box the 'Toy Maker' and his plan to summon and to destroy Pinhead forever. Despite a theatrical release, bloodline looks and feels TV movie-like and the acting is below average, possibly due to the script. That said, Doug Bradley is fine as Pinhead and Valentina Vargas is note-worthy as the demon Angelique. The story's concept is quite good, and includes (one assumes) the building in the 3rd and the history of the box. It is told in flash-backs by Dr. Paul Merchant in the year 2127 and follows his descendants Phillip L'Merchant in the 18th century and John Merchant in 1996. Sadly, it's just poorly executed and let down by an uneven screenplay, bland direction and sub-par sets. The effects are a mixed bag, some are well done while others are less-convincing and tame. It appears to have a troubled shooting history as there were two directors Alan Smithee (under an alias Kevin Yagher) and Joe Chappelle (uncredited). This maybe one cause and result of such an less than satisfying fourth. Overall, producers didn't give such a bankable character as Pinhead the attention he deserved leaving the viewer as empty as the 22nd century space setting.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's better than the second one anyway
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There's a lot of ketchup but not a lot of narrative sense in this supposedly explanatory third sequel, which piles on the crummy visuals to no effect. Good old Alan Smithee directed this one, in which various members of the same family (all played, poorly, by Bruce Ramsay) are terrorised by Pinhead (Doug Bradley, wheeled out of mothballs for the umpteenth time). Peter Atkins tries to imbue his script with poetic touches but doesn't seem to realise that his dialogue is as deep and meaningful as a plate of vomit. The incoherent plot fails to adequately fill the movie's meagre running time, although this may have more to do with studio interference than anything the filmmakers intended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    In CGI Space - Nobody Can Hear Your Boredom...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Josh Morgan
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Pinhead in space! Hey - it worked for the Leprechaun. You know you're in trouble when a once reputable horror franchise throws a "katching" sound effect at you before the opening titles. The plot, dealing with the history of those responsible for the notorious puzzle box, is sadly done in relatively cheap flashbacks (with limited sets). Most of the (surprisingly minimal) gore is unnecessary (such as the autopsy of a body for no apparent reason), and the now cut-rate CGI box looks incredibly lame. Also, the conclusion - where a space station folds into a giant puzzle box - left my forehead bruised, as I smacked it in disgust. The worst of the theatrical entries. You may just want to skip ahead to Hellraiser: Inferno, as it's a pretty decent little thriller. Directed by everyone's favorite pseudonym, Alan Smithee.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hellraiser IV: Bloodline
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The first film was good, the second film was disappointing, the third film was okay, and this next sequel I expected to be pretty much exactly the same standard as the last one, and it would be the last played in the cinemas. Basically it is the year 2127 on the Space Station Mionos, and the man who built the station Dr. Paul Merchant (Bruce Ramsay) has built a robot that can solve the Lament Configuration, i.e. the puzzle box, but the robot is destroyed and he is captured, and he tells his kidnapper Rimmer (Christine Harnos) the story of his bloodline. The story flashbacks 400 years earlier, where French toymaker Philip L'Merchant (Ramsay again) creates the Lament Configuration, he believes it will be just a simple puzzle box for wealthy aristocrat Duc De L'Isle (Mickey Cottrell), but he has black magic in mind and uses it to release Cenobite slave Angelique (Valentina Vargas) from the dark regions. The toymaker also invented the Elysium Configuration which he uses to destroy the demons, the Duc's apprentice Jacques (Adam Scott) informs him that his bloodline are cursed until time ends because of his creation. Two hundred year pass, and the next in the bloodline John Merchant (also Ramsay) is the architect who built the building seen at the end of Hellraiser III, where the puzzle box was placed in the wet cement, and after Jacques is killed by Angelique she travels to America and tries to seduce John, the puzzle box is taken from the ground, and a man solves it and as a result releases Pinhead (Doug Bradley). The Cenobite leader wants the Elysium Configuration to be be used to open the gates of Hell and allow him and his dark forces to do anything he pleases, and he knows the best way to force John to do it is by threatening his child Jack (Courtland Mead). The Elysium Configuration is forced to be used, but it does not work, so Merchant is killed, while his wife Bobbi (Kim Myers) is the one who sends Pinhead, Angelique and the other Cenobites created back to Hell. Back in the future 2127 on the space station the Cenobites are freed once again, Rimmer realises the danger they are all in and releases Paul so that he can destroy the demons, using the main purpose the Minos was built for. Pinhead is distracted while Paul and Rimmer escape in a shuttle, and the combination of powerful lasers and mirrors create a blast of light, and the space station is transformed into a giant version of the puzzle box to trap the Cenobites within, and it self destructs as well, and destroying the connection between Hell and Earth as well. Bradley still keeps you watching as Pinhead with his philosophical like dialogue and his malevolent love for torture and death on humans, I will be honest though I don't fully agree with the critics giving it an average review, I think it is nearly the most ridiculous of the films in the series, going to the future and into space is a daft idea, only the origins of the puzzle box and the bloody effects is what kept me interested, apart from that it was a slightly disappointing horror. Okay!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    He back, and this time he in space.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    atinder
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This my first watch of this movie, , I loved first 2 move in the series and I enjoyed the third one, i thought it okay sequel However this one, i did not like as much as the other sequels, I just could not get into this story at all, I really bored for most of the time in them movie. I did not care for any one in this movie, the acting was not great but it still worth watching i say There were some decent gory scenes in this movie but I didn't find anything scary or creepy about this what so ever. I found this very dull and boring with bloody parts in here and there, Over I give 4 out of 10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Do I look like someone who cares what God thinks?!?"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Scott LeBrun (Hey_Sweden)
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watchable entry in the "Hellraiser" series at least does its best to establish a mythology. It focuses on the puzzle box itself, otherwise known as the Lament Configuration, that caused all of the trouble in the first place. It was created centuries ago by a toy maker who knew not what he was doing, as nefarious types were out to use it to unleash demons such as Pinhead upon the world. The back stories are framed by sequences set in the future where the latest descendant of that long ago toy maker is attempting to make things right again with a puzzle box of his own. Now, it almost certainly would have been better had director Kevin Yagher, a top makeup and special effects designer, been able to stick with his own vision, as extensive re-shoots were ordered, re-shoots that didn't involve him, and as a result he took his own name off the picture in favour of the notorious pseudonym Alan Smithee. And the story does indeed feel thin, not fully realized, and too rushed. Overall this is a hard movie to really get interested in, as too many of the characters and actors on hand are of the nondescript kind. Doug Bradley as Pinhead, of course, is an exception, and is magnetic as always, sinking his teeth into his literate dialogue. And Valentina Vargas is mildly amusing and definitely sexy as his ironically named cohort Angelique. There's just not much "oomph" to this thing, no standout set pieces, and no real sense of overwhelming doom or menace. In fact, it's tiresome at times. The gore and designs are a highlight (although one can tell this was done on a budget), with Pinhead provided with an effective "canine" companion. There are interesting ideas here, and hints of what could have been, but from start to finish this is purely on the routine side. Five out of 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Geez, these people need to stay away from that box! Grab a friggin' Rubic's Cube!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Kristine (kristinedrama14@msn.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When we think about what famous horror films like A Nightmare on Elm Street, Halloween and Friday the 13th, what do they have in common? They all have a million sequels. The series that seems to be the underdog that most people forget about but know it's main villain is Hellraiser which has a decent amount of sequels. However the sad part is, after the first three movies, every sequel that came out was a direct to video so I don't think the series had much of a chance to stand up to the big boys on the block of the horror genre. Hellraiser was the series that was not only darker but more serious when it came to horror and wasn't afraid to show off the gory side of torture. Think about it, I don't think we could have films like Saw and Hostel which owe a little thanks to Hellraiser for giving us the blood and guts. Also it gave us an extremely dark villain, Pinhead who feels no mercy and enjoys the pleasure of putting pain into your body and pulling your flesh every way possible with chains and hooks. But where did the puzzle box come from? Well Bloodline takes us into the story of the origin of the cenobites. In the year 2127, Paul Merchant, has a robot solve the puzzle box that holds Pinhead. However, several guards led by Rimmer capture Paul. Paul tells Rimmer the story of his bloodline. Philip L'Merchant, a French toymaker, makes the puzzle box for a wealthy aristocrat, who is obsessed with dark magic. He and his apprentice kill a woman and use her to summon the Cenobite slave Angelique. However, Angelique betrays and kills the aristocrat. L'Merchant, in the process of inventing a design to destroy the demons, attempts to steal back the box but is discovered. Jacques, Angelique's master, callously informs the toymaker that he and his bloodline are cursed until the end of time because of the box he created, before ordering Angelique to kill him. However, his wife survives and gives birth to his son, thus continuing the bloodline and to the future where Paul is trying to destroy Pinhead and Angelique once and for all. So I really did enjoy the story of Bloodline, it was a great idea that deserved more time and money. The film does well with what it was given, but since you can tell they were not given such great finances, the film falls short in the acting and shortness of the film. It feels like a made for TV film at times that was just more bloody than others. I couldn't really get into Valentina Vargas as Angelique nor did I find her incredibly evil like Pinhead, she didn't send any chills down my spine. But the last fight with Pinhead was cool and there are some great one liners. Pinhead screaming how he couldn't die is classic considering how many more sequels there are, but this was meant to take place in the future so who knows? Maybe Pinhead really does die in the future. I was a bit disappointed that we didn't have any more Elliot Spencer who is also a very interesting character. But this story was more about how the box was created and the family and their curse to fight the cenobites forever. Over all, it's worth the look, I think this was the last good sequel before it started getting weird and that's odd to say considering this is the Hellraiser series. 5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very well done! C'mon, have you actually SEEN most other 'Horror' films...?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lathe-of-heaven
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Okay, I wasn't going to bother writing a review for this one and I rarely take the time to write reviews here, BUT... Seeing this undeservedly LOW score here made me feel that I really had to 'say' something. First off, YES, I am indeed a BIG fan of the first three films; before these just recently came out on glorious Blu-ray, years ago, I even sprang for the UK Puzzle Box set of the first three films (mainly because at the time UNCUT versions were not available here in the states and also for the full commentaries and the bonus DVD that came with it : ) Now, I know it is hard to believe, but I just NOW for the very first time saw this one, part 4; the reason being is that from casual stuff I had read I was under the impression that pretty much all the other 'HELLRAISER' films were not made very well. Well... Let me tell you, I was extremely surprised (again, as my title above mentions) compared to all the REALLY AWFUL Horror films that are excruciatingly badly made, and that is most of them, I really was truly surprised that this one was made quite well. Okay, so a lot of the fans are sort of put off because it is really different from the other films. Fine... Isn't the POINT to try to come up with different angles and new approaches rather than just remaking the same film again and again...? I thought it was genuinely very creative and kept my attention very much so throughout the film. Sure, okay, it starts in space and your thinking 'LEPRECHAUN 3'; well, it works; it really does. Obviously a LOT of thought was put into the timeline and the mythology of the box, etc., not to mention the follow through at the end. Sure, it wrapped it up rather quickly and left it kind of ambiguous, but so what?! Yes, of COURSE it doesn't have the intensity of the original or even the complexity of the next two films, but to me I was mainly impressed by not only coming up with the new idea to show the origins, etc., but also I honestly felt that everything that made up the film was done very well considering that it is a damn 'HORROR' movie! : ) I gave it a good, strong '8' which it fully deserves considering the context and type of film. I think that people get SO jaded and expect SO dang much from sequels. Hey, like I say... I mean, C'mon, compared to what, 'WITCHBOARD' I-9 or whatever the hell it is, this here is pure art! Heh, if THIS one threw you, just wait until you see part 5! I just this minute finished watching that one for the very first time also a few minutes ago and that is a WILD departure from the early films. However, it was made even much better than this one; the director was actually very, very good!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    FINALLY a decent Hellrasier movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steven Smith
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In my honest opinion, I think the Hellrasier franchise is extremely overrated in the horror genre. I didn't like Hellraiser 1 at all. I thought it was poorly acted and directed. Hellrasier 2 was an OK movie but certainly not a classic at all. Hellrasier 3 was just awful and ridiculous. So I decided to watch 'Bloodline' last night expecting to see another poor Hellrasier movie. I was completely surprised. It was actually a good movie! Unlike the other Hellrasier movies, 'Bloodline' focuses more on important story elements but it certainly doesn't shy away from the nasty death scenes which have become synonymous with Hellrasier. People will either hate the direction this film takes or will enjoy it. I personally enjoy it and think it's superior to the other Hellrasier films. That probably sounds stupid as Hellraiser 1 & 2 are often touted as "horror classics" - I've never understood why they get so much praise as classics, whatever... 'Bloodline' has both story and gore - the perfect combination for a horror flick in my opinion. People who found Hellrasier 1,2 and 3 lame might just find 'Bloodline' a decent horror movie. Watch it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Surprisingly Complete Package But With Timidity
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tabuno
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Three stories are wrapped up in this version of Hellraiser and the storyline has a nicely cyclical completion from beginning to end. The irony with this version that it seems to have toned down the very nature of hell and pain and in a timid move edited out some of the more horrifying potential elements. Not as elegant as THE CELL (2000) and variations of THE HOUSE ON HAUNTED HILL (1999), is the storyline that keeps this movie's momentum up to the end. There are elements of ALIEN but the monsters are not that spectacular and the script seems unable to capture the emotive richness available in the storyline, the temptations, the conflicting loyalty and lust associated with real life. Nevertheless, this complete package has its qualitative, if not quantitative horrifying elements.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Poorly executed and as empty as the 22nd century space setting.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    amesmonde
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This instalment of Hellraiser, IV follows the bloodline of the creator of the puzzle box the 'Toy Maker' and his plan to summon and to destroy Pinhead forever. Despite a theatrical release, bloodline looks and feels TV movie-like and the acting is below average, possibly due to the script. That said, Doug Bradley is fine as Pinhead and Valentina Vargas is note-worthy as the demon Angelique. The story's concept is quite good, and includes (one assumes) the building in the 3rd and the history of the box. It is told in flash-backs by Dr. Paul Merchant in the year 2127 and follows his descendants Phillip L'Merchant in the 18th century and John Merchant in 1996. Sadly, it's just poorly executed and let down by an uneven screenplay, bland direction and sub-par sets. The effects are a mixed bag, some are well done while others are less-convincing and tame. It appears to have a troubled shooting history as there were two directors Alan Smithee (under an alias Kevin Yagher) and Joe Chappelle (uncredited). This maybe one cause and result of such an less than satisfying fourth. Overall, producers didn't give such a bankable character as Pinhead the attention he deserved leaving the viewer as empty as the 22nd century space setting.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's better than the second one anyway
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There's a lot of ketchup but not a lot of narrative sense in this supposedly explanatory third sequel, which piles on the crummy visuals to no effect. Good old Alan Smithee directed this one, in which various members of the same family (all played, poorly, by Bruce Ramsay) are terrorised by Pinhead (Doug Bradley, wheeled out of mothballs for the umpteenth time). Peter Atkins tries to imbue his script with poetic touches but doesn't seem to realise that his dialogue is as deep and meaningful as a plate of vomit. The incoherent plot fails to adequately fill the movie's meagre running time, although this may have more to do with studio interference than anything the filmmakers intended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    In CGI Space - Nobody Can Hear Your Boredom...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Josh Morgan
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Pinhead in space! Hey - it worked for the Leprechaun. You know you're in trouble when a once reputable horror franchise throws a "katching" sound effect at you before the opening titles. The plot, dealing with the history of those responsible for the notorious puzzle box, is sadly done in relatively cheap flashbacks (with limited sets). Most of the (surprisingly minimal) gore is unnecessary (such as the autopsy of a body for no apparent reason), and the now cut-rate CGI box looks incredibly lame. Also, the conclusion - where a space station folds into a giant puzzle box - left my forehead bruised, as I smacked it in disgust. The worst of the theatrical entries. You may just want to skip ahead to Hellraiser: Inferno, as it's a pretty decent little thriller. Directed by everyone's favorite pseudonym, Alan Smithee.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hellraiser IV: Bloodline
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The first film was good, the second film was disappointing, the third film was okay, and this next sequel I expected to be pretty much exactly the same standard as the last one, and it would be the last played in the cinemas. Basically it is the year 2127 on the Space Station Mionos, and the man who built the station Dr. Paul Merchant (Bruce Ramsay) has built a robot that can solve the Lament Configuration, i.e. the puzzle box, but the robot is destroyed and he is captured, and he tells his kidnapper Rimmer (Christine Harnos) the story of his bloodline. The story flashbacks 400 years earlier, where French toymaker Philip L'Merchant (Ramsay again) creates the Lament Configuration, he believes it will be just a simple puzzle box for wealthy aristocrat Duc De L'Isle (Mickey Cottrell), but he has black magic in mind and uses it to release Cenobite slave Angelique (Valentina Vargas) from the dark regions. The toymaker also invented the Elysium Configuration which he uses to destroy the demons, the Duc's apprentice Jacques (Adam Scott) informs him that his bloodline are cursed until time ends because of his creation. Two hundred year pass, and the next in the bloodline John Merchant (also Ramsay) is the architect who built the building seen at the end of Hellraiser III, where the puzzle box was placed in the wet cement, and after Jacques is killed by Angelique she travels to America and tries to seduce John, the puzzle box is taken from the ground, and a man solves it and as a result releases Pinhead (Doug Bradley). The Cenobite leader wants the Elysium Configuration to be be used to open the gates of Hell and allow him and his dark forces to do anything he pleases, and he knows the best way to force John to do it is by threatening his child Jack (Courtland Mead). The Elysium Configuration is forced to be used, but it does not work, so Merchant is killed, while his wife Bobbi (Kim Myers) is the one who sends Pinhead, Angelique and the other Cenobites created back to Hell. Back in the future 2127 on the space station the Cenobites are freed once again, Rimmer realises the danger they are all in and releases Paul so that he can destroy the demons, using the main purpose the Minos was built for. Pinhead is distracted while Paul and Rimmer escape in a shuttle, and the combination of powerful lasers and mirrors create a blast of light, and the space station is transformed into a giant version of the puzzle box to trap the Cenobites within, and it self destructs as well, and destroying the connection between Hell and Earth as well. Bradley still keeps you watching as Pinhead with his philosophical like dialogue and his malevolent love for torture and death on humans, I will be honest though I don't fully agree with the critics giving it an average review, I think it is nearly the most ridiculous of the films in the series, going to the future and into space is a daft idea, only the origins of the puzzle box and the bloody effects is what kept me interested, apart from that it was a slightly disappointing horror. Okay!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    He back, and this time he in space.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    atinder
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This my first watch of this movie, , I loved first 2 move in the series and I enjoyed the third one, i thought it okay sequel However this one, i did not like as much as the other sequels, I just could not get into this story at all, I really bored for most of the time in them movie. I did not care for any one in this movie, the acting was not great but it still worth watching i say There were some decent gory scenes in this movie but I didn't find anything scary or creepy about this what so ever. I found this very dull and boring with bloody parts in here and there, Over I give 4 out of 10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Do I look like someone who cares what God thinks?!?"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Scott LeBrun (Hey_Sweden)
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watchable entry in the "Hellraiser" series at least does its best to establish a mythology. It focuses on the puzzle box itself, otherwise known as the Lament Configuration, that caused all of the trouble in the first place. It was created centuries ago by a toy maker who knew not what he was doing, as nefarious types were out to use it to unleash demons such as Pinhead upon the world. The back stories are framed by sequences set in the future where the latest descendant of that long ago toy maker is attempting to make things right again with a puzzle box of his own. Now, it almost certainly would have been better had director Kevin Yagher, a top makeup and special effects designer, been able to stick with his own vision, as extensive re-shoots were ordered, re-shoots that didn't involve him, and as a result he took his own name off the picture in favour of the notorious pseudonym Alan Smithee. And the story does indeed feel thin, not fully realized, and too rushed. Overall this is a hard movie to really get interested in, as too many of the characters and actors on hand are of the nondescript kind. Doug Bradley as Pinhead, of course, is an exception, and is magnetic as always, sinking his teeth into his literate dialogue. And Valentina Vargas is mildly amusing and definitely sexy as his ironically named cohort Angelique. There's just not much "oomph" to this thing, no standout set pieces, and no real sense of overwhelming doom or menace. In fact, it's tiresome at times. The gore and designs are a highlight (although one can tell this was done on a budget), with Pinhead provided with an effective "canine" companion. There are interesting ideas here, and hints of what could have been, but from start to finish this is purely on the routine side. Five out of 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Geez, these people need to stay away from that box! Grab a friggin' Rubic's Cube!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Kristine (kristinedrama14@msn.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When we think about what famous horror films like A Nightmare on Elm Street, Halloween and Friday the 13th, what do they have in common? They all have a million sequels. The series that seems to be the underdog that most people forget about but know it's main villain is Hellraiser which has a decent amount of sequels. However the sad part is, after the first three movies, every sequel that came out was a direct to video so I don't think the series had much of a chance to stand up to the big boys on the block of the horror genre. Hellraiser was the series that was not only darker but more serious when it came to horror and wasn't afraid to show off the gory side of torture. Think about it, I don't think we could have films like Saw and Hostel which owe a little thanks to Hellraiser for giving us the blood and guts. Also it gave us an extremely dark villain, Pinhead who feels no mercy and enjoys the pleasure of putting pain into your body and pulling your flesh every way possible with chains and hooks. But where did the puzzle box come from? Well Bloodline takes us into the story of the origin of the cenobites. In the year 2127, Paul Merchant, has a robot solve the puzzle box that holds Pinhead. However, several guards led by Rimmer capture Paul. Paul tells Rimmer the story of his bloodline. Philip L'Merchant, a French toymaker, makes the puzzle box for a wealthy aristocrat, who is obsessed with dark magic. He and his apprentice kill a woman and use her to summon the Cenobite slave Angelique. However, Angelique betrays and kills the aristocrat. L'Merchant, in the process of inventing a design to destroy the demons, attempts to steal back the box but is discovered. Jacques, Angelique's master, callously informs the toymaker that he and his bloodline are cursed until the end of time because of the box he created, before ordering Angelique to kill him. However, his wife survives and gives birth to his son, thus continuing the bloodline and to the future where Paul is trying to destroy Pinhead and Angelique once and for all. So I really did enjoy the story of Bloodline, it was a great idea that deserved more time and money. The film does well with what it was given, but since you can tell they were not given such great finances, the film falls short in the acting and shortness of the film. It feels like a made for TV film at times that was just more bloody than others. I couldn't really get into Valentina Vargas as Angelique nor did I find her incredibly evil like Pinhead, she didn't send any chills down my spine. But the last fight with Pinhead was cool and there are some great one liners. Pinhead screaming how he couldn't die is classic considering how many more sequels there are, but this was meant to take place in the future so who knows? Maybe Pinhead really does die in the future. I was a bit disappointed that we didn't have any more Elliot Spencer who is also a very interesting character. But this story was more about how the box was created and the family and their curse to fight the cenobites forever. Over all, it's worth the look, I think this was the last good sequel before it started getting weird and that's odd to say considering this is the Hellraiser series. 5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very well done! C'mon, have you actually SEEN most other 'Horror' films...?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lathe-of-heaven
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Okay, I wasn't going to bother writing a review for this one and I rarely take the time to write reviews here, BUT... Seeing this undeservedly LOW score here made me feel that I really had to 'say' something. First off, YES, I am indeed a BIG fan of the first three films; before these just recently came out on glorious Blu-ray, years ago, I even sprang for the UK Puzzle Box set of the first three films (mainly because at the time UNCUT versions were not available here in the states and also for the full commentaries and the bonus DVD that came with it : ) Now, I know it is hard to believe, but I just NOW for the very first time saw this one, part 4; the reason being is that from casual stuff I had read I was under the impression that pretty much all the other 'HELLRAISER' films were not made very well. Well... Let me tell you, I was extremely surprised (again, as my title above mentions) compared to all the REALLY AWFUL Horror films that are excruciatingly badly made, and that is most of them, I really was truly surprised that this one was made quite well. Okay, so a lot of the fans are sort of put off because it is really different from the other films. Fine... Isn't the POINT to try to come up with different angles and new approaches rather than just remaking the same film again and again...? I thought it was genuinely very creative and kept my attention very much so throughout the film. Sure, okay, it starts in space and your thinking 'LEPRECHAUN 3'; well, it works; it really does. Obviously a LOT of thought was put into the timeline and the mythology of the box, etc., not to mention the follow through at the end. Sure, it wrapped it up rather quickly and left it kind of ambiguous, but so what?! Yes, of COURSE it doesn't have the intensity of the original or even the complexity of the next two films, but to me I was mainly impressed by not only coming up with the new idea to show the origins, etc., but also I honestly felt that everything that made up the film was done very well considering that it is a damn 'HORROR' movie! : ) I gave it a good, strong '8' which it fully deserves considering the context and type of film. I think that people get SO jaded and expect SO dang much from sequels. Hey, like I say... I mean, C'mon, compared to what, 'WITCHBOARD' I-9 or whatever the hell it is, this here is pure art! Heh, if THIS one threw you, just wait until you see part 5! I just this minute finished watching that one for the very first time also a few minutes ago and that is a WILD departure from the early films. However, it was made even much better than this one; the director was actually very, very good!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    FINALLY a decent Hellrasier movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steven Smith
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In my honest opinion, I think the Hellrasier franchise is extremely overrated in the horror genre. I didn't like Hellraiser 1 at all. I thought it was poorly acted and directed. Hellrasier 2 was an OK movie but certainly not a classic at all. Hellrasier 3 was just awful and ridiculous. So I decided to watch 'Bloodline' last night expecting to see another poor Hellrasier movie. I was completely surprised. It was actually a good movie! Unlike the other Hellrasier movies, 'Bloodline' focuses more on important story elements but it certainly doesn't shy away from the nasty death scenes which have become synonymous with Hellrasier. People will either hate the direction this film takes or will enjoy it. I personally enjoy it and think it's superior to the other Hellrasier films. That probably sounds stupid as Hellraiser 1 & 2 are often touted as "horror classics" - I've never understood why they get so much praise as classics, whatever... 'Bloodline' has both story and gore - the perfect combination for a horror flick in my opinion. People who found Hellrasier 1,2 and 3 lame might just find 'Bloodline' a decent horror movie. Watch it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Surprisingly Complete Package But With Timidity
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tabuno
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Three stories are wrapped up in this version of Hellraiser and the storyline has a nicely cyclical completion from beginning to end. The irony with this version that it seems to have toned down the very nature of hell and pain and in a timid move edited out some of the more horrifying potential elements. Not as elegant as THE CELL (2000) and variations of THE HOUSE ON HAUNTED HILL (1999), is the storyline that keeps this movie's momentum up to the end. There are elements of ALIEN but the monsters are not that spectacular and the script seems unable to capture the emotive richness available in the storyline, the temptations, the conflicting loyalty and lust associated with real life. Nevertheless, this complete package has its qualitative, if not quantitative horrifying elements.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Poorly executed and as empty as the 22nd century space setting.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    amesmonde
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This instalment of Hellraiser, IV follows the bloodline of the creator of the puzzle box the 'Toy Maker' and his plan to summon and to destroy Pinhead forever. Despite a theatrical release, bloodline looks and feels TV movie-like and the acting is below average, possibly due to the script. That said, Doug Bradley is fine as Pinhead and Valentina Vargas is note-worthy as the demon Angelique. The story's concept is quite good, and includes (one assumes) the building in the 3rd and the history of the box. It is told in flash-backs by Dr. Paul Merchant in the year 2127 and follows his descendants Phillip L'Merchant in the 18th century and John Merchant in 1996. Sadly, it's just poorly executed and let down by an uneven screenplay, bland direction and sub-par sets. The effects are a mixed bag, some are well done while others are less-convincing and tame. It appears to have a troubled shooting history as there were two directors Alan Smithee (under an alias Kevin Yagher) and Joe Chappelle (uncredited). This maybe one cause and result of such an less than satisfying fourth. Overall, producers didn't give such a bankable character as Pinhead the attention he deserved leaving the viewer as empty as the 22nd century space setting.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
