<filme>
 <id>
  594
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0113280
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1995
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Heavy
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  7.0
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  The life of an overweight, unhappy cook is forever changed after a kind, beautiful college drop-out comes to work as a waitress at he and his mother's roadside restaurant.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Victor is a cook who works in a greasy bar/restaurant owned by his mother, Dolly. It's just the two of them, a waitress named Delores, and a heavy drinking regular, Leo. But things change when Callie, a beautiful college drop-out, shows up as a new waitress and steals Victor's heart. But Victor is too shy to do anything about it, and too self-consciously overweight to dream of winning Callie away from her demanding boyfriend, Jeff. Victor's terrible loneliness overwhelms him when he has to face losing what he loves the most.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Romance
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   waitress
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   cook
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   restaurant
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   love
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   loneliness
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   James Mangold
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   James Mangold
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Pruitt Taylor Vince
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Shelley Winters
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Liv Tyler
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Corpulent cook craves company
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tieman64
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    James Magnold directs "Heavy", a slow-moving film about an obese cook who falls in love with an enchanting waitress, played by hyper-beautiful Liv Tyler. The film's plot is derivative of Paddy Chayefsky's "Marty" and Robert Altman's "Come Back To The Five and Dime, Jimmy Dean", but its likable cast help sell things. Pruitt Vince plays Victor, our corpulent cook, and the legendary Shelly Winters plays his ageing mother. Victor's painfully shy, doomed to worship Tyler from afar, who glides through the film (similar to her role in Bertolucci's "Stealing Beauty") like an ethereal, unattainable fantasy object. Our chubby hero never gets close to her, but by the film's end he's learnt to act upon his secret hopes. Victor's obesity and crippling shyness, themes the film should be preoccupied with, are never convincingly explained. 7.5/10 - Worth one viewing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Should Have Known From The Recommendation
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ccthemovieman-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/10/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The fact that "Cosmopolitan" magazine wrote this movie was "terrific" should have warned me to stay away but, like a sap, I gave it a look. What a waste of a trip to the rental store back in the late '90s. "Horrible" would have been a better one-word description of this profane-laden soap opera about a bunch of losers at a diner. Well, if you are a loser and like to watch people moping around like the main character in this movie - a fat momma's boy - watching a story that really has little plot or substance, this is your cup of tea. It does one thing, though: it will depress you, and a lot of sickos out there like movies that depress them. Go figure. They can relate to this "realistic" story, sad to say. I would have more compassion, but the characters in here, almost all of them, are nothing but annoying. No wonder "Cosmo" loved it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The realism of 'Heavy'
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ray Tucker
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/5/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I had to laugh reading the comments of matanovi (matanovi@yahoo.com), who said he was convinced that not all of this movie was fiction. 11 years after the fact I don't think I'm giving away the store, but, matanovi hit the nail right on the head. I went to high school with Jim Mangold in Washingtonville, New York, and I consider all of his other work to be genius level. 'Heavy', however, is far from fiction-it is the true life story of one Joseph Mecca, a mutual friend from high school. Vince, main character in the movie, is a verbatim duplicate of Joe Mecca, as are many other characters in the movie, including waitress Delores, who didn't even get a name change from the real life character she is modeled after. If one ever was a denizen of the former 'Mecca's' restaurant (now "Loughran's) in Salisbury Mills, NY, one has all the insight necessary into the creation of 'Heavy'. With that said, the movie is still worth a look, even if you do know the true story it is 'heavily' based on.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Moody stuff
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gritfrombray-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/5/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Mainly watched this because Liv Tyler is one of the most beautiful women on the planet and was pleasantly surprised how good it was. Poor Victor in the pizza shop is the kind of guy an awful lot of people can relate to I'm sure. Debbie Harry puts in a good performance too. The moodiness and dark settings make the film very compelling viewing indeed. Victor's outlook on life and his consciousness of his size and looks is so believable and his daydreaming is handled so well throughout. Any self conscious person should watch this as should people who pass judgment on others on looks alone. A film hard to forget.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Delicate, subtle, real
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Matthew Kirkcaldie
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/6/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Strong performances and great restraint make Heavy a deftly handled, beautiful and subtly moving piece. Despite the apparent futility of Victor's interest in Callie, they're both changed in ways which are worth seeing. Aside from Evan Dando's slight awkwardness, the acting in this film is understated and very believable - Shelley Winters is warm and careworn, even Debbie Harry manages to blend in to the low-key scenery. Beautifully shot and directed, with a superb score from Thurston Moore, "Heavy" is a piece of cinema rather than a story shoe-horned into a screenplay. This won't satisfy anyone looking for simple plot and resolution, but for the rest of us there's a lot to admire.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good representative of 90's cinema
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    EskimoChain
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/6/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Heavy indeed the title to me explained the depth of symbolism this movie had commenced. This movie to my mind shown an example ironically of life's various infatuations. In how the duration of them bloom then wither naturally as time dissolves entirety. The character "Victor" which claimed to be "fat" as compared to his interest "Callie" which of prevailing allure if you will. Considering this at all time, Victor becomes timid quite often. Only wanting the slightest bit of attention as himself besotted by her essence. This film in my opinion illuminates a life of the working class who may never have there dreams come true. Maybe the way they might have wanted. Which apparently can become laceration for this individual. In opposition to this depressing technique for life's let downs. I reside in the words of Friedrich Nietzsche. Which he so ambrosially stated.. "Love to one only is a barbarity, for it is exercised at the expense of all others. Love to God also!"
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    He's a man so shy, he doesn't even think he deserves love...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moonspinner55
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/11/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Solemn, but terrific mood piece about a shy, chubby cook in a rivertown restaurant who fantasizes about getting to know the new waitress who just hired on, a perky young thing with long brunette hair and a big charming smile. Graceful film never goes the commercial route, neither injecting shady characters into the mix nor throwing in blatant jokes to give the film comedic uplift. The picture is all on one level, which may drive some viewers batty with impatience, but I found the whole thing quietly invigorating. The lead character, Victor (Pruitt Taylor Vince), daydreams, watches airplanes, has secret hopes; he's a loner, and the filmmakers are careful not to flood the screen with potential conquests. There's Debbie Harry as a loose waitress with weary eyes and Liv Tyler, the new hire, who brings fantasy into Victor's life, but, as with all fantasies, the advent of reality diffuses the passionate tension. Everyone is sad in this film, and I imagine some audiences won't get with it, but I admire director James Mangold for putting this story on film so eloquently. It's a new "Marty". *** from ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I am fat ma!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andy (film-critic)
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/10/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watching Heavy only confirmed the idea that director James Mangold may be suffering from Attention Deficit Disorder. He needs medication or at least the ability to complete a thought before he tries to ramble us through another emotional sentence. Heavy could have been a very complete and emotional film using some raw talent that prior to this had never been explored. There could have been a very strong story developed behind Pruitt Taylor Vince's character of Victor instead of the inconsistent scenes that I witnessed. Liv Tyler could have honestly stepped up in the Hollywood atmosphere on this film alone, if she would have just attempted to take one small chance and go outside of herself. The same could be said for both Shelly Winters and Deborah Harry, who just never felt anything more creative than a walking clich&eacute;. Mangold had the power in his hands to really set the stage on fire, but instead we are forced to watch a very inconsistent, obscure, and emotionally voided film that tries to tackle too many issues, without solving any in the long run. I initially envisioned Heavy's story line to be about a man, concerned about his weight, being the outcast member of society. At first, and at brief intermittent moments of the film, that was the case, but something changed as the other characters were introduced. Liv Tyler became a disturbing obsession instead of a passionate, yet simple, love for Victor. There are scenes in which Vince thinks that he sees a dead Callie walking through his house or even floating in a puddle, but alas, they are only daydreams. Why were they daydreams? What was the overall relevance of these scenes? Was it to show a different side, a troubled side, to Victor, or was it merely used to confuse the audience? I thought that perhaps she was representing Victor's mother, but even that was stretching a bit. It was moments like this that really brought a speed bump into this film. There were other scenes similar to this one that really pulled us away from the central focus of the film, the growth of Victor. The encounters with Leo seemed forced, and the clich&eacute;d and random sexual advances of Delores seemed to come out of left field. The moments between Victor and his mother didn't even feel real. I felt as if Shelly Winters was speaking from a cue card instead of her heart. There was one emotional scene where it felt as stale as cardboard, yet it was supposed to evoke tears. Pathetic. I felt at times that Mangold had one of those "Choose your own plot books" and just randomly flipped through it during this film. Outside of random plot interjections coming at you from every angle (quite distractingly), there was some decent acting from our lead character Victor played by Pruitt Taylor Vince. Vince was able to bottle up the emotions of the situations around him very well, the twitching eyes was not something that I thought helped build his character (was that a acting trait or actually Vince's eyes), while the stress eating moments did seem very human. Vince is a strong actor. He is typically cast as the psycho in most films, but I thought in this film he did stretch his wings a bit. It wasn't far, but he brought compassion and emotion to a very forgettable character. He is the only one worth watching in this film, while the rest of the cast just hurt the film further. Liv Tyler has trouble acting. She talks about never taking an acting class before, and in this film you can tell. She brought nothing new to the screen. The connection between her and Vince was non-existent. There was no chemistry, no power, nothing that made me really see a love between the two. These two have a very silly match. Outside of the acting and the zigzag plot, there was not much else going for the film. The music was a tease. There were some scenes where you would have Vince walking along the road, powerful, emotional, and together, and the music would suddenly change. Either it was poor editing or just bad music placement, but it seemed to be jumping just as much as Vince's eyes. It made me cringe in my seat. I just get extremely worked up about films that claim to be an emotional powerhouse of an independent film, yet it feels like crayons were used instead of the power of the paintbrush. Again, Mangold had a great film under the surface of all this muck, but it just wasn't worth wading through to get to. Overall, I was not impressed with this film. If Mangold would have stayed the course, kept us glued to Vince's powerful character, and developed him using the other minor characters around him, than I think it would have been a winner. If Liv Tyler would have been a stronger central character and perhaps stepped outside of her lines, than we may have had a winner. If the point would have been to show a weak man overcome the boundaries of his life, than I think we would have had a winner. Instead, we are left with unattached moments that come from left field and walking cardboard characters that spit clich&eacute; lines into the sky instead of to the viewers. Heavy had so much potential, one can only blame Mangold for all these disasters. Skip it. Have yourself a big pizza and watch some Chris Farley films. Now, there was a big guy that was random, but could at least hold a script together! Grade: ** out of *****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A slow and realistic slice of life
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Brigid O Sullivan (wisewebwoman)
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/9/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An exquisite indie film directed by James Mangold. A very tiny story set in a typical small town diner but the direction, script and acting border on the sublime. This will not be to everyone's taste, extremely slow-moving but every frame gives us a little more information about the characters. From the empty life of Delores, the aging waitress played so well by Deborah Harry (AKA Blondie)to the achingly forlorn one of Victor in a riveting performance by Pruitt Taylor Vince, every character rings true. We have all met them along the way, some of us have shared the same experiences. To capture this so beautifully on film is to create a minor masterpiece. Liv Tyler shines in her first major role as does Shelley Winters in one of her last. Not to be missed by those who like their movies with more deeply drawn characters. 8 out of 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    extremely underrated and amazing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    raindogtrombone
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/1/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    this is one of those films that slipped right through the cracks. i rarely ever see it mentioned by friends and critics alike. a truly beautiful little movie, a sort of slice of life that is at times sad and funny. one of my favourite parts about it is the soundtrack, which really gives the film its ambiance and its moods - the Thurston Moore score coupled with the stellar music from Evan dando (singing gram parsons!) the plimsouls, eleni mandell etc. is what turned me to the film (i heard the soundtrack first). and i'm glad i saw the film. star pruitt taylor vince definitely gives a great performance in a truly subtly powerful role. not-one to be overlooked.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Corpulent cook craves company
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tieman64
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    James Magnold directs "Heavy", a slow-moving film about an obese cook who falls in love with an enchanting waitress, played by hyper-beautiful Liv Tyler. The film's plot is derivative of Paddy Chayefsky's "Marty" and Robert Altman's "Come Back To The Five and Dime, Jimmy Dean", but its likable cast help sell things. Pruitt Vince plays Victor, our corpulent cook, and the legendary Shelly Winters plays his ageing mother. Victor's painfully shy, doomed to worship Tyler from afar, who glides through the film (similar to her role in Bertolucci's "Stealing Beauty") like an ethereal, unattainable fantasy object. Our chubby hero never gets close to her, but by the film's end he's learnt to act upon his secret hopes. Victor's obesity and crippling shyness, themes the film should be preoccupied with, are never convincingly explained. 7.5/10 - Worth one viewing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Should Have Known From The Recommendation
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ccthemovieman-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/10/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The fact that "Cosmopolitan" magazine wrote this movie was "terrific" should have warned me to stay away but, like a sap, I gave it a look. What a waste of a trip to the rental store back in the late '90s. "Horrible" would have been a better one-word description of this profane-laden soap opera about a bunch of losers at a diner. Well, if you are a loser and like to watch people moping around like the main character in this movie - a fat momma's boy - watching a story that really has little plot or substance, this is your cup of tea. It does one thing, though: it will depress you, and a lot of sickos out there like movies that depress them. Go figure. They can relate to this "realistic" story, sad to say. I would have more compassion, but the characters in here, almost all of them, are nothing but annoying. No wonder "Cosmo" loved it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The realism of 'Heavy'
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ray Tucker
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/5/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I had to laugh reading the comments of matanovi (matanovi@yahoo.com), who said he was convinced that not all of this movie was fiction. 11 years after the fact I don't think I'm giving away the store, but, matanovi hit the nail right on the head. I went to high school with Jim Mangold in Washingtonville, New York, and I consider all of his other work to be genius level. 'Heavy', however, is far from fiction-it is the true life story of one Joseph Mecca, a mutual friend from high school. Vince, main character in the movie, is a verbatim duplicate of Joe Mecca, as are many other characters in the movie, including waitress Delores, who didn't even get a name change from the real life character she is modeled after. If one ever was a denizen of the former 'Mecca's' restaurant (now "Loughran's) in Salisbury Mills, NY, one has all the insight necessary into the creation of 'Heavy'. With that said, the movie is still worth a look, even if you do know the true story it is 'heavily' based on.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Moody stuff
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gritfrombray-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/5/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Mainly watched this because Liv Tyler is one of the most beautiful women on the planet and was pleasantly surprised how good it was. Poor Victor in the pizza shop is the kind of guy an awful lot of people can relate to I'm sure. Debbie Harry puts in a good performance too. The moodiness and dark settings make the film very compelling viewing indeed. Victor's outlook on life and his consciousness of his size and looks is so believable and his daydreaming is handled so well throughout. Any self conscious person should watch this as should people who pass judgment on others on looks alone. A film hard to forget.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Delicate, subtle, real
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Matthew Kirkcaldie
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/6/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Strong performances and great restraint make Heavy a deftly handled, beautiful and subtly moving piece. Despite the apparent futility of Victor's interest in Callie, they're both changed in ways which are worth seeing. Aside from Evan Dando's slight awkwardness, the acting in this film is understated and very believable - Shelley Winters is warm and careworn, even Debbie Harry manages to blend in to the low-key scenery. Beautifully shot and directed, with a superb score from Thurston Moore, "Heavy" is a piece of cinema rather than a story shoe-horned into a screenplay. This won't satisfy anyone looking for simple plot and resolution, but for the rest of us there's a lot to admire.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good representative of 90's cinema
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    EskimoChain
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/6/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Heavy indeed the title to me explained the depth of symbolism this movie had commenced. This movie to my mind shown an example ironically of life's various infatuations. In how the duration of them bloom then wither naturally as time dissolves entirety. The character "Victor" which claimed to be "fat" as compared to his interest "Callie" which of prevailing allure if you will. Considering this at all time, Victor becomes timid quite often. Only wanting the slightest bit of attention as himself besotted by her essence. This film in my opinion illuminates a life of the working class who may never have there dreams come true. Maybe the way they might have wanted. Which apparently can become laceration for this individual. In opposition to this depressing technique for life's let downs. I reside in the words of Friedrich Nietzsche. Which he so ambrosially stated.. "Love to one only is a barbarity, for it is exercised at the expense of all others. Love to God also!"
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    He's a man so shy, he doesn't even think he deserves love...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moonspinner55
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/11/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Solemn, but terrific mood piece about a shy, chubby cook in a rivertown restaurant who fantasizes about getting to know the new waitress who just hired on, a perky young thing with long brunette hair and a big charming smile. Graceful film never goes the commercial route, neither injecting shady characters into the mix nor throwing in blatant jokes to give the film comedic uplift. The picture is all on one level, which may drive some viewers batty with impatience, but I found the whole thing quietly invigorating. The lead character, Victor (Pruitt Taylor Vince), daydreams, watches airplanes, has secret hopes; he's a loner, and the filmmakers are careful not to flood the screen with potential conquests. There's Debbie Harry as a loose waitress with weary eyes and Liv Tyler, the new hire, who brings fantasy into Victor's life, but, as with all fantasies, the advent of reality diffuses the passionate tension. Everyone is sad in this film, and I imagine some audiences won't get with it, but I admire director James Mangold for putting this story on film so eloquently. It's a new "Marty". *** from ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I am fat ma!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andy (film-critic)
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/10/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watching Heavy only confirmed the idea that director James Mangold may be suffering from Attention Deficit Disorder. He needs medication or at least the ability to complete a thought before he tries to ramble us through another emotional sentence. Heavy could have been a very complete and emotional film using some raw talent that prior to this had never been explored. There could have been a very strong story developed behind Pruitt Taylor Vince's character of Victor instead of the inconsistent scenes that I witnessed. Liv Tyler could have honestly stepped up in the Hollywood atmosphere on this film alone, if she would have just attempted to take one small chance and go outside of herself. The same could be said for both Shelly Winters and Deborah Harry, who just never felt anything more creative than a walking clich&eacute;. Mangold had the power in his hands to really set the stage on fire, but instead we are forced to watch a very inconsistent, obscure, and emotionally voided film that tries to tackle too many issues, without solving any in the long run. I initially envisioned Heavy's story line to be about a man, concerned about his weight, being the outcast member of society. At first, and at brief intermittent moments of the film, that was the case, but something changed as the other characters were introduced. Liv Tyler became a disturbing obsession instead of a passionate, yet simple, love for Victor. There are scenes in which Vince thinks that he sees a dead Callie walking through his house or even floating in a puddle, but alas, they are only daydreams. Why were they daydreams? What was the overall relevance of these scenes? Was it to show a different side, a troubled side, to Victor, or was it merely used to confuse the audience? I thought that perhaps she was representing Victor's mother, but even that was stretching a bit. It was moments like this that really brought a speed bump into this film. There were other scenes similar to this one that really pulled us away from the central focus of the film, the growth of Victor. The encounters with Leo seemed forced, and the clich&eacute;d and random sexual advances of Delores seemed to come out of left field. The moments between Victor and his mother didn't even feel real. I felt as if Shelly Winters was speaking from a cue card instead of her heart. There was one emotional scene where it felt as stale as cardboard, yet it was supposed to evoke tears. Pathetic. I felt at times that Mangold had one of those "Choose your own plot books" and just randomly flipped through it during this film. Outside of random plot interjections coming at you from every angle (quite distractingly), there was some decent acting from our lead character Victor played by Pruitt Taylor Vince. Vince was able to bottle up the emotions of the situations around him very well, the twitching eyes was not something that I thought helped build his character (was that a acting trait or actually Vince's eyes), while the stress eating moments did seem very human. Vince is a strong actor. He is typically cast as the psycho in most films, but I thought in this film he did stretch his wings a bit. It wasn't far, but he brought compassion and emotion to a very forgettable character. He is the only one worth watching in this film, while the rest of the cast just hurt the film further. Liv Tyler has trouble acting. She talks about never taking an acting class before, and in this film you can tell. She brought nothing new to the screen. The connection between her and Vince was non-existent. There was no chemistry, no power, nothing that made me really see a love between the two. These two have a very silly match. Outside of the acting and the zigzag plot, there was not much else going for the film. The music was a tease. There were some scenes where you would have Vince walking along the road, powerful, emotional, and together, and the music would suddenly change. Either it was poor editing or just bad music placement, but it seemed to be jumping just as much as Vince's eyes. It made me cringe in my seat. I just get extremely worked up about films that claim to be an emotional powerhouse of an independent film, yet it feels like crayons were used instead of the power of the paintbrush. Again, Mangold had a great film under the surface of all this muck, but it just wasn't worth wading through to get to. Overall, I was not impressed with this film. If Mangold would have stayed the course, kept us glued to Vince's powerful character, and developed him using the other minor characters around him, than I think it would have been a winner. If Liv Tyler would have been a stronger central character and perhaps stepped outside of her lines, than we may have had a winner. If the point would have been to show a weak man overcome the boundaries of his life, than I think we would have had a winner. Instead, we are left with unattached moments that come from left field and walking cardboard characters that spit clich&eacute; lines into the sky instead of to the viewers. Heavy had so much potential, one can only blame Mangold for all these disasters. Skip it. Have yourself a big pizza and watch some Chris Farley films. Now, there was a big guy that was random, but could at least hold a script together! Grade: ** out of *****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A slow and realistic slice of life
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Brigid O Sullivan (wisewebwoman)
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/9/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An exquisite indie film directed by James Mangold. A very tiny story set in a typical small town diner but the direction, script and acting border on the sublime. This will not be to everyone's taste, extremely slow-moving but every frame gives us a little more information about the characters. From the empty life of Delores, the aging waitress played so well by Deborah Harry (AKA Blondie)to the achingly forlorn one of Victor in a riveting performance by Pruitt Taylor Vince, every character rings true. We have all met them along the way, some of us have shared the same experiences. To capture this so beautifully on film is to create a minor masterpiece. Liv Tyler shines in her first major role as does Shelley Winters in one of her last. Not to be missed by those who like their movies with more deeply drawn characters. 8 out of 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    extremely underrated and amazing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    raindogtrombone
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/1/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    this is one of those films that slipped right through the cracks. i rarely ever see it mentioned by friends and critics alike. a truly beautiful little movie, a sort of slice of life that is at times sad and funny. one of my favourite parts about it is the soundtrack, which really gives the film its ambiance and its moods - the Thurston Moore score coupled with the stellar music from Evan dando (singing gram parsons!) the plimsouls, eleni mandell etc. is what turned me to the film (i heard the soundtrack first). and i'm glad i saw the film. star pruitt taylor vince definitely gives a great performance in a truly subtly powerful role. not-one to be overlooked.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Corpulent cook craves company
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tieman64
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    James Magnold directs "Heavy", a slow-moving film about an obese cook who falls in love with an enchanting waitress, played by hyper-beautiful Liv Tyler. The film's plot is derivative of Paddy Chayefsky's "Marty" and Robert Altman's "Come Back To The Five and Dime, Jimmy Dean", but its likable cast help sell things. Pruitt Vince plays Victor, our corpulent cook, and the legendary Shelly Winters plays his ageing mother. Victor's painfully shy, doomed to worship Tyler from afar, who glides through the film (similar to her role in Bertolucci's "Stealing Beauty") like an ethereal, unattainable fantasy object. Our chubby hero never gets close to her, but by the film's end he's learnt to act upon his secret hopes. Victor's obesity and crippling shyness, themes the film should be preoccupied with, are never convincingly explained. 7.5/10 - Worth one viewing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Should Have Known From The Recommendation
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ccthemovieman-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/10/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The fact that "Cosmopolitan" magazine wrote this movie was "terrific" should have warned me to stay away but, like a sap, I gave it a look. What a waste of a trip to the rental store back in the late '90s. "Horrible" would have been a better one-word description of this profane-laden soap opera about a bunch of losers at a diner. Well, if you are a loser and like to watch people moping around like the main character in this movie - a fat momma's boy - watching a story that really has little plot or substance, this is your cup of tea. It does one thing, though: it will depress you, and a lot of sickos out there like movies that depress them. Go figure. They can relate to this "realistic" story, sad to say. I would have more compassion, but the characters in here, almost all of them, are nothing but annoying. No wonder "Cosmo" loved it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The realism of 'Heavy'
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ray Tucker
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/5/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I had to laugh reading the comments of matanovi (matanovi@yahoo.com), who said he was convinced that not all of this movie was fiction. 11 years after the fact I don't think I'm giving away the store, but, matanovi hit the nail right on the head. I went to high school with Jim Mangold in Washingtonville, New York, and I consider all of his other work to be genius level. 'Heavy', however, is far from fiction-it is the true life story of one Joseph Mecca, a mutual friend from high school. Vince, main character in the movie, is a verbatim duplicate of Joe Mecca, as are many other characters in the movie, including waitress Delores, who didn't even get a name change from the real life character she is modeled after. If one ever was a denizen of the former 'Mecca's' restaurant (now "Loughran's) in Salisbury Mills, NY, one has all the insight necessary into the creation of 'Heavy'. With that said, the movie is still worth a look, even if you do know the true story it is 'heavily' based on.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Moody stuff
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gritfrombray-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/5/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Mainly watched this because Liv Tyler is one of the most beautiful women on the planet and was pleasantly surprised how good it was. Poor Victor in the pizza shop is the kind of guy an awful lot of people can relate to I'm sure. Debbie Harry puts in a good performance too. The moodiness and dark settings make the film very compelling viewing indeed. Victor's outlook on life and his consciousness of his size and looks is so believable and his daydreaming is handled so well throughout. Any self conscious person should watch this as should people who pass judgment on others on looks alone. A film hard to forget.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Delicate, subtle, real
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Matthew Kirkcaldie
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/6/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Strong performances and great restraint make Heavy a deftly handled, beautiful and subtly moving piece. Despite the apparent futility of Victor's interest in Callie, they're both changed in ways which are worth seeing. Aside from Evan Dando's slight awkwardness, the acting in this film is understated and very believable - Shelley Winters is warm and careworn, even Debbie Harry manages to blend in to the low-key scenery. Beautifully shot and directed, with a superb score from Thurston Moore, "Heavy" is a piece of cinema rather than a story shoe-horned into a screenplay. This won't satisfy anyone looking for simple plot and resolution, but for the rest of us there's a lot to admire.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good representative of 90's cinema
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    EskimoChain
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/6/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Heavy indeed the title to me explained the depth of symbolism this movie had commenced. This movie to my mind shown an example ironically of life's various infatuations. In how the duration of them bloom then wither naturally as time dissolves entirety. The character "Victor" which claimed to be "fat" as compared to his interest "Callie" which of prevailing allure if you will. Considering this at all time, Victor becomes timid quite often. Only wanting the slightest bit of attention as himself besotted by her essence. This film in my opinion illuminates a life of the working class who may never have there dreams come true. Maybe the way they might have wanted. Which apparently can become laceration for this individual. In opposition to this depressing technique for life's let downs. I reside in the words of Friedrich Nietzsche. Which he so ambrosially stated.. "Love to one only is a barbarity, for it is exercised at the expense of all others. Love to God also!"
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    He's a man so shy, he doesn't even think he deserves love...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moonspinner55
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/11/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Solemn, but terrific mood piece about a shy, chubby cook in a rivertown restaurant who fantasizes about getting to know the new waitress who just hired on, a perky young thing with long brunette hair and a big charming smile. Graceful film never goes the commercial route, neither injecting shady characters into the mix nor throwing in blatant jokes to give the film comedic uplift. The picture is all on one level, which may drive some viewers batty with impatience, but I found the whole thing quietly invigorating. The lead character, Victor (Pruitt Taylor Vince), daydreams, watches airplanes, has secret hopes; he's a loner, and the filmmakers are careful not to flood the screen with potential conquests. There's Debbie Harry as a loose waitress with weary eyes and Liv Tyler, the new hire, who brings fantasy into Victor's life, but, as with all fantasies, the advent of reality diffuses the passionate tension. Everyone is sad in this film, and I imagine some audiences won't get with it, but I admire director James Mangold for putting this story on film so eloquently. It's a new "Marty". *** from ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I am fat ma!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andy (film-critic)
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/10/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watching Heavy only confirmed the idea that director James Mangold may be suffering from Attention Deficit Disorder. He needs medication or at least the ability to complete a thought before he tries to ramble us through another emotional sentence. Heavy could have been a very complete and emotional film using some raw talent that prior to this had never been explored. There could have been a very strong story developed behind Pruitt Taylor Vince's character of Victor instead of the inconsistent scenes that I witnessed. Liv Tyler could have honestly stepped up in the Hollywood atmosphere on this film alone, if she would have just attempted to take one small chance and go outside of herself. The same could be said for both Shelly Winters and Deborah Harry, who just never felt anything more creative than a walking clich&eacute;. Mangold had the power in his hands to really set the stage on fire, but instead we are forced to watch a very inconsistent, obscure, and emotionally voided film that tries to tackle too many issues, without solving any in the long run. I initially envisioned Heavy's story line to be about a man, concerned about his weight, being the outcast member of society. At first, and at brief intermittent moments of the film, that was the case, but something changed as the other characters were introduced. Liv Tyler became a disturbing obsession instead of a passionate, yet simple, love for Victor. There are scenes in which Vince thinks that he sees a dead Callie walking through his house or even floating in a puddle, but alas, they are only daydreams. Why were they daydreams? What was the overall relevance of these scenes? Was it to show a different side, a troubled side, to Victor, or was it merely used to confuse the audience? I thought that perhaps she was representing Victor's mother, but even that was stretching a bit. It was moments like this that really brought a speed bump into this film. There were other scenes similar to this one that really pulled us away from the central focus of the film, the growth of Victor. The encounters with Leo seemed forced, and the clich&eacute;d and random sexual advances of Delores seemed to come out of left field. The moments between Victor and his mother didn't even feel real. I felt as if Shelly Winters was speaking from a cue card instead of her heart. There was one emotional scene where it felt as stale as cardboard, yet it was supposed to evoke tears. Pathetic. I felt at times that Mangold had one of those "Choose your own plot books" and just randomly flipped through it during this film. Outside of random plot interjections coming at you from every angle (quite distractingly), there was some decent acting from our lead character Victor played by Pruitt Taylor Vince. Vince was able to bottle up the emotions of the situations around him very well, the twitching eyes was not something that I thought helped build his character (was that a acting trait or actually Vince's eyes), while the stress eating moments did seem very human. Vince is a strong actor. He is typically cast as the psycho in most films, but I thought in this film he did stretch his wings a bit. It wasn't far, but he brought compassion and emotion to a very forgettable character. He is the only one worth watching in this film, while the rest of the cast just hurt the film further. Liv Tyler has trouble acting. She talks about never taking an acting class before, and in this film you can tell. She brought nothing new to the screen. The connection between her and Vince was non-existent. There was no chemistry, no power, nothing that made me really see a love between the two. These two have a very silly match. Outside of the acting and the zigzag plot, there was not much else going for the film. The music was a tease. There were some scenes where you would have Vince walking along the road, powerful, emotional, and together, and the music would suddenly change. Either it was poor editing or just bad music placement, but it seemed to be jumping just as much as Vince's eyes. It made me cringe in my seat. I just get extremely worked up about films that claim to be an emotional powerhouse of an independent film, yet it feels like crayons were used instead of the power of the paintbrush. Again, Mangold had a great film under the surface of all this muck, but it just wasn't worth wading through to get to. Overall, I was not impressed with this film. If Mangold would have stayed the course, kept us glued to Vince's powerful character, and developed him using the other minor characters around him, than I think it would have been a winner. If Liv Tyler would have been a stronger central character and perhaps stepped outside of her lines, than we may have had a winner. If the point would have been to show a weak man overcome the boundaries of his life, than I think we would have had a winner. Instead, we are left with unattached moments that come from left field and walking cardboard characters that spit clich&eacute; lines into the sky instead of to the viewers. Heavy had so much potential, one can only blame Mangold for all these disasters. Skip it. Have yourself a big pizza and watch some Chris Farley films. Now, there was a big guy that was random, but could at least hold a script together! Grade: ** out of *****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A slow and realistic slice of life
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Brigid O Sullivan (wisewebwoman)
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/9/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An exquisite indie film directed by James Mangold. A very tiny story set in a typical small town diner but the direction, script and acting border on the sublime. This will not be to everyone's taste, extremely slow-moving but every frame gives us a little more information about the characters. From the empty life of Delores, the aging waitress played so well by Deborah Harry (AKA Blondie)to the achingly forlorn one of Victor in a riveting performance by Pruitt Taylor Vince, every character rings true. We have all met them along the way, some of us have shared the same experiences. To capture this so beautifully on film is to create a minor masterpiece. Liv Tyler shines in her first major role as does Shelley Winters in one of her last. Not to be missed by those who like their movies with more deeply drawn characters. 8 out of 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    extremely underrated and amazing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    raindogtrombone
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/1/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    this is one of those films that slipped right through the cracks. i rarely ever see it mentioned by friends and critics alike. a truly beautiful little movie, a sort of slice of life that is at times sad and funny. one of my favourite parts about it is the soundtrack, which really gives the film its ambiance and its moods - the Thurston Moore score coupled with the stellar music from Evan dando (singing gram parsons!) the plimsouls, eleni mandell etc. is what turned me to the film (i heard the soundtrack first). and i'm glad i saw the film. star pruitt taylor vince definitely gives a great performance in a truly subtly powerful role. not-one to be overlooked.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Corpulent cook craves company
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tieman64
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    James Magnold directs "Heavy", a slow-moving film about an obese cook who falls in love with an enchanting waitress, played by hyper-beautiful Liv Tyler. The film's plot is derivative of Paddy Chayefsky's "Marty" and Robert Altman's "Come Back To The Five and Dime, Jimmy Dean", but its likable cast help sell things. Pruitt Vince plays Victor, our corpulent cook, and the legendary Shelly Winters plays his ageing mother. Victor's painfully shy, doomed to worship Tyler from afar, who glides through the film (similar to her role in Bertolucci's "Stealing Beauty") like an ethereal, unattainable fantasy object. Our chubby hero never gets close to her, but by the film's end he's learnt to act upon his secret hopes. Victor's obesity and crippling shyness, themes the film should be preoccupied with, are never convincingly explained. 7.5/10 - Worth one viewing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Should Have Known From The Recommendation
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ccthemovieman-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/10/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The fact that "Cosmopolitan" magazine wrote this movie was "terrific" should have warned me to stay away but, like a sap, I gave it a look. What a waste of a trip to the rental store back in the late '90s. "Horrible" would have been a better one-word description of this profane-laden soap opera about a bunch of losers at a diner. Well, if you are a loser and like to watch people moping around like the main character in this movie - a fat momma's boy - watching a story that really has little plot or substance, this is your cup of tea. It does one thing, though: it will depress you, and a lot of sickos out there like movies that depress them. Go figure. They can relate to this "realistic" story, sad to say. I would have more compassion, but the characters in here, almost all of them, are nothing but annoying. No wonder "Cosmo" loved it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The realism of 'Heavy'
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ray Tucker
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/5/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I had to laugh reading the comments of matanovi (matanovi@yahoo.com), who said he was convinced that not all of this movie was fiction. 11 years after the fact I don't think I'm giving away the store, but, matanovi hit the nail right on the head. I went to high school with Jim Mangold in Washingtonville, New York, and I consider all of his other work to be genius level. 'Heavy', however, is far from fiction-it is the true life story of one Joseph Mecca, a mutual friend from high school. Vince, main character in the movie, is a verbatim duplicate of Joe Mecca, as are many other characters in the movie, including waitress Delores, who didn't even get a name change from the real life character she is modeled after. If one ever was a denizen of the former 'Mecca's' restaurant (now "Loughran's) in Salisbury Mills, NY, one has all the insight necessary into the creation of 'Heavy'. With that said, the movie is still worth a look, even if you do know the true story it is 'heavily' based on.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Moody stuff
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gritfrombray-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/5/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Mainly watched this because Liv Tyler is one of the most beautiful women on the planet and was pleasantly surprised how good it was. Poor Victor in the pizza shop is the kind of guy an awful lot of people can relate to I'm sure. Debbie Harry puts in a good performance too. The moodiness and dark settings make the film very compelling viewing indeed. Victor's outlook on life and his consciousness of his size and looks is so believable and his daydreaming is handled so well throughout. Any self conscious person should watch this as should people who pass judgment on others on looks alone. A film hard to forget.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Delicate, subtle, real
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Matthew Kirkcaldie
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/6/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Strong performances and great restraint make Heavy a deftly handled, beautiful and subtly moving piece. Despite the apparent futility of Victor's interest in Callie, they're both changed in ways which are worth seeing. Aside from Evan Dando's slight awkwardness, the acting in this film is understated and very believable - Shelley Winters is warm and careworn, even Debbie Harry manages to blend in to the low-key scenery. Beautifully shot and directed, with a superb score from Thurston Moore, "Heavy" is a piece of cinema rather than a story shoe-horned into a screenplay. This won't satisfy anyone looking for simple plot and resolution, but for the rest of us there's a lot to admire.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good representative of 90's cinema
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    EskimoChain
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/6/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Heavy indeed the title to me explained the depth of symbolism this movie had commenced. This movie to my mind shown an example ironically of life's various infatuations. In how the duration of them bloom then wither naturally as time dissolves entirety. The character "Victor" which claimed to be "fat" as compared to his interest "Callie" which of prevailing allure if you will. Considering this at all time, Victor becomes timid quite often. Only wanting the slightest bit of attention as himself besotted by her essence. This film in my opinion illuminates a life of the working class who may never have there dreams come true. Maybe the way they might have wanted. Which apparently can become laceration for this individual. In opposition to this depressing technique for life's let downs. I reside in the words of Friedrich Nietzsche. Which he so ambrosially stated.. "Love to one only is a barbarity, for it is exercised at the expense of all others. Love to God also!"
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    He's a man so shy, he doesn't even think he deserves love...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moonspinner55
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/11/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Solemn, but terrific mood piece about a shy, chubby cook in a rivertown restaurant who fantasizes about getting to know the new waitress who just hired on, a perky young thing with long brunette hair and a big charming smile. Graceful film never goes the commercial route, neither injecting shady characters into the mix nor throwing in blatant jokes to give the film comedic uplift. The picture is all on one level, which may drive some viewers batty with impatience, but I found the whole thing quietly invigorating. The lead character, Victor (Pruitt Taylor Vince), daydreams, watches airplanes, has secret hopes; he's a loner, and the filmmakers are careful not to flood the screen with potential conquests. There's Debbie Harry as a loose waitress with weary eyes and Liv Tyler, the new hire, who brings fantasy into Victor's life, but, as with all fantasies, the advent of reality diffuses the passionate tension. Everyone is sad in this film, and I imagine some audiences won't get with it, but I admire director James Mangold for putting this story on film so eloquently. It's a new "Marty". *** from ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I am fat ma!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andy (film-critic)
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/10/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watching Heavy only confirmed the idea that director James Mangold may be suffering from Attention Deficit Disorder. He needs medication or at least the ability to complete a thought before he tries to ramble us through another emotional sentence. Heavy could have been a very complete and emotional film using some raw talent that prior to this had never been explored. There could have been a very strong story developed behind Pruitt Taylor Vince's character of Victor instead of the inconsistent scenes that I witnessed. Liv Tyler could have honestly stepped up in the Hollywood atmosphere on this film alone, if she would have just attempted to take one small chance and go outside of herself. The same could be said for both Shelly Winters and Deborah Harry, who just never felt anything more creative than a walking clich&eacute;. Mangold had the power in his hands to really set the stage on fire, but instead we are forced to watch a very inconsistent, obscure, and emotionally voided film that tries to tackle too many issues, without solving any in the long run. I initially envisioned Heavy's story line to be about a man, concerned about his weight, being the outcast member of society. At first, and at brief intermittent moments of the film, that was the case, but something changed as the other characters were introduced. Liv Tyler became a disturbing obsession instead of a passionate, yet simple, love for Victor. There are scenes in which Vince thinks that he sees a dead Callie walking through his house or even floating in a puddle, but alas, they are only daydreams. Why were they daydreams? What was the overall relevance of these scenes? Was it to show a different side, a troubled side, to Victor, or was it merely used to confuse the audience? I thought that perhaps she was representing Victor's mother, but even that was stretching a bit. It was moments like this that really brought a speed bump into this film. There were other scenes similar to this one that really pulled us away from the central focus of the film, the growth of Victor. The encounters with Leo seemed forced, and the clich&eacute;d and random sexual advances of Delores seemed to come out of left field. The moments between Victor and his mother didn't even feel real. I felt as if Shelly Winters was speaking from a cue card instead of her heart. There was one emotional scene where it felt as stale as cardboard, yet it was supposed to evoke tears. Pathetic. I felt at times that Mangold had one of those "Choose your own plot books" and just randomly flipped through it during this film. Outside of random plot interjections coming at you from every angle (quite distractingly), there was some decent acting from our lead character Victor played by Pruitt Taylor Vince. Vince was able to bottle up the emotions of the situations around him very well, the twitching eyes was not something that I thought helped build his character (was that a acting trait or actually Vince's eyes), while the stress eating moments did seem very human. Vince is a strong actor. He is typically cast as the psycho in most films, but I thought in this film he did stretch his wings a bit. It wasn't far, but he brought compassion and emotion to a very forgettable character. He is the only one worth watching in this film, while the rest of the cast just hurt the film further. Liv Tyler has trouble acting. She talks about never taking an acting class before, and in this film you can tell. She brought nothing new to the screen. The connection between her and Vince was non-existent. There was no chemistry, no power, nothing that made me really see a love between the two. These two have a very silly match. Outside of the acting and the zigzag plot, there was not much else going for the film. The music was a tease. There were some scenes where you would have Vince walking along the road, powerful, emotional, and together, and the music would suddenly change. Either it was poor editing or just bad music placement, but it seemed to be jumping just as much as Vince's eyes. It made me cringe in my seat. I just get extremely worked up about films that claim to be an emotional powerhouse of an independent film, yet it feels like crayons were used instead of the power of the paintbrush. Again, Mangold had a great film under the surface of all this muck, but it just wasn't worth wading through to get to. Overall, I was not impressed with this film. If Mangold would have stayed the course, kept us glued to Vince's powerful character, and developed him using the other minor characters around him, than I think it would have been a winner. If Liv Tyler would have been a stronger central character and perhaps stepped outside of her lines, than we may have had a winner. If the point would have been to show a weak man overcome the boundaries of his life, than I think we would have had a winner. Instead, we are left with unattached moments that come from left field and walking cardboard characters that spit clich&eacute; lines into the sky instead of to the viewers. Heavy had so much potential, one can only blame Mangold for all these disasters. Skip it. Have yourself a big pizza and watch some Chris Farley films. Now, there was a big guy that was random, but could at least hold a script together! Grade: ** out of *****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A slow and realistic slice of life
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Brigid O Sullivan (wisewebwoman)
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/9/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An exquisite indie film directed by James Mangold. A very tiny story set in a typical small town diner but the direction, script and acting border on the sublime. This will not be to everyone's taste, extremely slow-moving but every frame gives us a little more information about the characters. From the empty life of Delores, the aging waitress played so well by Deborah Harry (AKA Blondie)to the achingly forlorn one of Victor in a riveting performance by Pruitt Taylor Vince, every character rings true. We have all met them along the way, some of us have shared the same experiences. To capture this so beautifully on film is to create a minor masterpiece. Liv Tyler shines in her first major role as does Shelley Winters in one of her last. Not to be missed by those who like their movies with more deeply drawn characters. 8 out of 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    extremely underrated and amazing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    raindogtrombone
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/1/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    this is one of those films that slipped right through the cracks. i rarely ever see it mentioned by friends and critics alike. a truly beautiful little movie, a sort of slice of life that is at times sad and funny. one of my favourite parts about it is the soundtrack, which really gives the film its ambiance and its moods - the Thurston Moore score coupled with the stellar music from Evan dando (singing gram parsons!) the plimsouls, eleni mandell etc. is what turned me to the film (i heard the soundtrack first). and i'm glad i saw the film. star pruitt taylor vince definitely gives a great performance in a truly subtly powerful role. not-one to be overlooked.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Corpulent cook craves company
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tieman64
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    James Magnold directs "Heavy", a slow-moving film about an obese cook who falls in love with an enchanting waitress, played by hyper-beautiful Liv Tyler. The film's plot is derivative of Paddy Chayefsky's "Marty" and Robert Altman's "Come Back To The Five and Dime, Jimmy Dean", but its likable cast help sell things. Pruitt Vince plays Victor, our corpulent cook, and the legendary Shelly Winters plays his ageing mother. Victor's painfully shy, doomed to worship Tyler from afar, who glides through the film (similar to her role in Bertolucci's "Stealing Beauty") like an ethereal, unattainable fantasy object. Our chubby hero never gets close to her, but by the film's end he's learnt to act upon his secret hopes. Victor's obesity and crippling shyness, themes the film should be preoccupied with, are never convincingly explained. 7.5/10 - Worth one viewing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Should Have Known From The Recommendation
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ccthemovieman-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/10/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The fact that "Cosmopolitan" magazine wrote this movie was "terrific" should have warned me to stay away but, like a sap, I gave it a look. What a waste of a trip to the rental store back in the late '90s. "Horrible" would have been a better one-word description of this profane-laden soap opera about a bunch of losers at a diner. Well, if you are a loser and like to watch people moping around like the main character in this movie - a fat momma's boy - watching a story that really has little plot or substance, this is your cup of tea. It does one thing, though: it will depress you, and a lot of sickos out there like movies that depress them. Go figure. They can relate to this "realistic" story, sad to say. I would have more compassion, but the characters in here, almost all of them, are nothing but annoying. No wonder "Cosmo" loved it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The realism of 'Heavy'
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ray Tucker
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/5/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I had to laugh reading the comments of matanovi (matanovi@yahoo.com), who said he was convinced that not all of this movie was fiction. 11 years after the fact I don't think I'm giving away the store, but, matanovi hit the nail right on the head. I went to high school with Jim Mangold in Washingtonville, New York, and I consider all of his other work to be genius level. 'Heavy', however, is far from fiction-it is the true life story of one Joseph Mecca, a mutual friend from high school. Vince, main character in the movie, is a verbatim duplicate of Joe Mecca, as are many other characters in the movie, including waitress Delores, who didn't even get a name change from the real life character she is modeled after. If one ever was a denizen of the former 'Mecca's' restaurant (now "Loughran's) in Salisbury Mills, NY, one has all the insight necessary into the creation of 'Heavy'. With that said, the movie is still worth a look, even if you do know the true story it is 'heavily' based on.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Moody stuff
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gritfrombray-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/5/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Mainly watched this because Liv Tyler is one of the most beautiful women on the planet and was pleasantly surprised how good it was. Poor Victor in the pizza shop is the kind of guy an awful lot of people can relate to I'm sure. Debbie Harry puts in a good performance too. The moodiness and dark settings make the film very compelling viewing indeed. Victor's outlook on life and his consciousness of his size and looks is so believable and his daydreaming is handled so well throughout. Any self conscious person should watch this as should people who pass judgment on others on looks alone. A film hard to forget.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Delicate, subtle, real
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Matthew Kirkcaldie
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/6/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Strong performances and great restraint make Heavy a deftly handled, beautiful and subtly moving piece. Despite the apparent futility of Victor's interest in Callie, they're both changed in ways which are worth seeing. Aside from Evan Dando's slight awkwardness, the acting in this film is understated and very believable - Shelley Winters is warm and careworn, even Debbie Harry manages to blend in to the low-key scenery. Beautifully shot and directed, with a superb score from Thurston Moore, "Heavy" is a piece of cinema rather than a story shoe-horned into a screenplay. This won't satisfy anyone looking for simple plot and resolution, but for the rest of us there's a lot to admire.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good representative of 90's cinema
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    EskimoChain
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/6/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Heavy indeed the title to me explained the depth of symbolism this movie had commenced. This movie to my mind shown an example ironically of life's various infatuations. In how the duration of them bloom then wither naturally as time dissolves entirety. The character "Victor" which claimed to be "fat" as compared to his interest "Callie" which of prevailing allure if you will. Considering this at all time, Victor becomes timid quite often. Only wanting the slightest bit of attention as himself besotted by her essence. This film in my opinion illuminates a life of the working class who may never have there dreams come true. Maybe the way they might have wanted. Which apparently can become laceration for this individual. In opposition to this depressing technique for life's let downs. I reside in the words of Friedrich Nietzsche. Which he so ambrosially stated.. "Love to one only is a barbarity, for it is exercised at the expense of all others. Love to God also!"
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    He's a man so shy, he doesn't even think he deserves love...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moonspinner55
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/11/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Solemn, but terrific mood piece about a shy, chubby cook in a rivertown restaurant who fantasizes about getting to know the new waitress who just hired on, a perky young thing with long brunette hair and a big charming smile. Graceful film never goes the commercial route, neither injecting shady characters into the mix nor throwing in blatant jokes to give the film comedic uplift. The picture is all on one level, which may drive some viewers batty with impatience, but I found the whole thing quietly invigorating. The lead character, Victor (Pruitt Taylor Vince), daydreams, watches airplanes, has secret hopes; he's a loner, and the filmmakers are careful not to flood the screen with potential conquests. There's Debbie Harry as a loose waitress with weary eyes and Liv Tyler, the new hire, who brings fantasy into Victor's life, but, as with all fantasies, the advent of reality diffuses the passionate tension. Everyone is sad in this film, and I imagine some audiences won't get with it, but I admire director James Mangold for putting this story on film so eloquently. It's a new "Marty". *** from ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I am fat ma!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andy (film-critic)
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/10/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watching Heavy only confirmed the idea that director James Mangold may be suffering from Attention Deficit Disorder. He needs medication or at least the ability to complete a thought before he tries to ramble us through another emotional sentence. Heavy could have been a very complete and emotional film using some raw talent that prior to this had never been explored. There could have been a very strong story developed behind Pruitt Taylor Vince's character of Victor instead of the inconsistent scenes that I witnessed. Liv Tyler could have honestly stepped up in the Hollywood atmosphere on this film alone, if she would have just attempted to take one small chance and go outside of herself. The same could be said for both Shelly Winters and Deborah Harry, who just never felt anything more creative than a walking clich&eacute;. Mangold had the power in his hands to really set the stage on fire, but instead we are forced to watch a very inconsistent, obscure, and emotionally voided film that tries to tackle too many issues, without solving any in the long run. I initially envisioned Heavy's story line to be about a man, concerned about his weight, being the outcast member of society. At first, and at brief intermittent moments of the film, that was the case, but something changed as the other characters were introduced. Liv Tyler became a disturbing obsession instead of a passionate, yet simple, love for Victor. There are scenes in which Vince thinks that he sees a dead Callie walking through his house or even floating in a puddle, but alas, they are only daydreams. Why were they daydreams? What was the overall relevance of these scenes? Was it to show a different side, a troubled side, to Victor, or was it merely used to confuse the audience? I thought that perhaps she was representing Victor's mother, but even that was stretching a bit. It was moments like this that really brought a speed bump into this film. There were other scenes similar to this one that really pulled us away from the central focus of the film, the growth of Victor. The encounters with Leo seemed forced, and the clich&eacute;d and random sexual advances of Delores seemed to come out of left field. The moments between Victor and his mother didn't even feel real. I felt as if Shelly Winters was speaking from a cue card instead of her heart. There was one emotional scene where it felt as stale as cardboard, yet it was supposed to evoke tears. Pathetic. I felt at times that Mangold had one of those "Choose your own plot books" and just randomly flipped through it during this film. Outside of random plot interjections coming at you from every angle (quite distractingly), there was some decent acting from our lead character Victor played by Pruitt Taylor Vince. Vince was able to bottle up the emotions of the situations around him very well, the twitching eyes was not something that I thought helped build his character (was that a acting trait or actually Vince's eyes), while the stress eating moments did seem very human. Vince is a strong actor. He is typically cast as the psycho in most films, but I thought in this film he did stretch his wings a bit. It wasn't far, but he brought compassion and emotion to a very forgettable character. He is the only one worth watching in this film, while the rest of the cast just hurt the film further. Liv Tyler has trouble acting. She talks about never taking an acting class before, and in this film you can tell. She brought nothing new to the screen. The connection between her and Vince was non-existent. There was no chemistry, no power, nothing that made me really see a love between the two. These two have a very silly match. Outside of the acting and the zigzag plot, there was not much else going for the film. The music was a tease. There were some scenes where you would have Vince walking along the road, powerful, emotional, and together, and the music would suddenly change. Either it was poor editing or just bad music placement, but it seemed to be jumping just as much as Vince's eyes. It made me cringe in my seat. I just get extremely worked up about films that claim to be an emotional powerhouse of an independent film, yet it feels like crayons were used instead of the power of the paintbrush. Again, Mangold had a great film under the surface of all this muck, but it just wasn't worth wading through to get to. Overall, I was not impressed with this film. If Mangold would have stayed the course, kept us glued to Vince's powerful character, and developed him using the other minor characters around him, than I think it would have been a winner. If Liv Tyler would have been a stronger central character and perhaps stepped outside of her lines, than we may have had a winner. If the point would have been to show a weak man overcome the boundaries of his life, than I think we would have had a winner. Instead, we are left with unattached moments that come from left field and walking cardboard characters that spit clich&eacute; lines into the sky instead of to the viewers. Heavy had so much potential, one can only blame Mangold for all these disasters. Skip it. Have yourself a big pizza and watch some Chris Farley films. Now, there was a big guy that was random, but could at least hold a script together! Grade: ** out of *****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A slow and realistic slice of life
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Brigid O Sullivan (wisewebwoman)
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/9/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An exquisite indie film directed by James Mangold. A very tiny story set in a typical small town diner but the direction, script and acting border on the sublime. This will not be to everyone's taste, extremely slow-moving but every frame gives us a little more information about the characters. From the empty life of Delores, the aging waitress played so well by Deborah Harry (AKA Blondie)to the achingly forlorn one of Victor in a riveting performance by Pruitt Taylor Vince, every character rings true. We have all met them along the way, some of us have shared the same experiences. To capture this so beautifully on film is to create a minor masterpiece. Liv Tyler shines in her first major role as does Shelley Winters in one of her last. Not to be missed by those who like their movies with more deeply drawn characters. 8 out of 10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    extremely underrated and amazing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    raindogtrombone
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/1/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    this is one of those films that slipped right through the cracks. i rarely ever see it mentioned by friends and critics alike. a truly beautiful little movie, a sort of slice of life that is at times sad and funny. one of my favourite parts about it is the soundtrack, which really gives the film its ambiance and its moods - the Thurston Moore score coupled with the stellar music from Evan dando (singing gram parsons!) the plimsouls, eleni mandell etc. is what turned me to the film (i heard the soundtrack first). and i'm glad i saw the film. star pruitt taylor vince definitely gives a great performance in a truly subtly powerful role. not-one to be overlooked.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
