<filme>
 <id>
  597
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0116213
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1996
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Queima de Arquivo
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  5.9
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  A Witness Protection specialist becomes suspicious of his co-workers when dealing with a case involving high-tech weapons.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  John Kruger is a U.S. marshal who is assigned to protect Lee Cullen, who works for the Cyrez Corporation, a company that manufactures top secret weapons for the military. Lee knows about a scam going on within Cyrez Corporation, and the man behind it is determined to silence Lee, because without Lee, the FBI has no case against the Cyrez Corporation. After taking Lee to New York City to hide her, John discovers that his friend, U.S. Marshal Robert Deguerin, is the mastermind behind the scam!
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Action
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Mystery
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Thriller
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   witness
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   weapon
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   u.s. marshal
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   fbi
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   identity
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Chuck Russell
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Tony Puryear
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Walon Green
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Arnold Schwarzenegger
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Vanessa Williams
  </ator>
  <ator>
   James Caan
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Arnold Erases
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Arnold Schwarzenegger plays U.S. Marshal John 'The Eraser' Kruger, a specialist in the witness protection program who is assigned to protect Lee Cullen(Vanessa Williams) who had uncovered shady dealings at a military weapons manufacturer that she had worked for. The company now wants her dead, so John takes Lee to New York City with the help of his friend, fellow U.S. Marshal Robert Guerin(played by James Caan) Unfortunately, someone in the program has betrayed them, and now John and Lee must go on the run from both forces in order to expose the true villains, and save their lives. Pretty good Arnold S. film has lots of exciting action scenes, and an appealing cast of characters. Film has a predictable plot though, and stretches credibility at times, but is mostly entertaining.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Those things on the end of pencils.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Shawn Watson (gator_macready@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The 2-year gap between True Lies and Eraser forced some action fans into thinking that Big Arn had retired. He had delivered at least one action movie per year since Terminator. Eraser had an awesome trailer, to the tune of Enigma's wonderful "I Love You, I'll Kill You", that rocked my world in the summer of 1996. I saw virtually every blockbuster that year, and the Eraser trailer was attached to every one of them. It came out out in the UK in the very last week of summer (and my first week back at school). I saw it at the now demolished UCI cinema in Edinburgh with a sold-out audience, mostly filled with guys out for a "lad's night". The movie was rated 18, and even though I was 3 years below that mark, I still got in, which was fortunate since the cinema version is the only uncut version of the film that has ever been released in the UK. For its VHS and DVD release the mad BBFC saw fit to cut 4 minutes from Eraser, turning it into an incomprehensible mess. It capped-off an awesome summer season (or so my 15-year-old self thought), and put to rest any fears that Big Arn was slowing down (although he has only made 5 action movies, to date, since then). Arn is John Kruger (an amusing choice of name since director Chuck Russell also made the 3rd Nightmare on Elm Street Movie), a Witness Protection Program Agent who is tasked with 'erasing' and protecting a high-level informant who can prove that there are traitors within the US government who are selling weapons to Russian terrorists. Naturally the informant is the lovely, and wide-eyed, Vanessa Williams, who involves herself in a subdued romantic subplot with Kruger. James Caan and the always great James Coburn provide respectable support as Kruger's antagonist and mentor, but the best support is no doubt Robert Pastorelli (an actor who I really liked who died of a heroin overdose in 2004), who plays a previous witness who is eager to please Kruger in his latest, impossible quest. Overall, it's hardly revolutionary, but what makes Eraser stand out from the crowd is the utterly breathtaking (literally) scene in which Kruger escapes a jet, mid-flight, without the comfort of a parachute on his shoulders. It's definitely one of the best action scenes in the last 20 years and, let me tell you, when that scene climaxed in the cinema, the packed audience of 'lads' totally sucked the air out of the auditorium. A massively exciting, and completely exhilarating, scene that never fails to get your heart racing. Alan Silvestri's score is one of the film's more underrated features. Silvestri scored Big Arn's Predator, a famous score in its own right, and while Eraser is not as famous as Predator you should not rule out the integrity of the score. When separated from the movie it is still one of Silvestri's best efforts. I guess the only complaint I could have about Eraser is that it's kinda anti-climatic. The best scene occurs at the end of the second act, leaving the final act pale in comparison. There's no iconic imagery to the film and it seems kinda forgettable when compared to other Arn characters who have endured the test of time. Nonetheless, it's at the top of the bottom of Arn's best movies, but make sure you the version you watch has not been butchered by the BBFC. The Blu Ray is in 2.40:1 1080p with Dolby TrueHD sound. Extras are non-existent.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The beginning of the Arnie-end. More fun for his butchering of the English language.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    oneguyrambling
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Arnie's career was really losing steam by the time Eraser came around. After all he'd played every role that suited him, often multiple times. The robot. The soldier. The cop. The special agent. The ummm barbarian. And believe it or not, as IMDb is my witness, he played ALL of those characters more than once by this time, the only difference sometimes being the Eastern European country he was supposed to have come from. So by this stage Schwarzenegger was sorta grasping at straws, the result often being awful and often recycled projects that played with his image and in desperation introduced more and more illogical and ridiculous hooks and sequences. Take Eraser, where the bad guys have heat detecting scopes on their RAY GUNS(!) that go bing-bing-bing and cut through anything in their path, and Arnie gets to kill a 90s style CGI alligator and after consigning it to its fate declares it 'luggage'. (You know what? That bit still makes me laugh.) Arnie plays John Kruger, a guy who doesn't officially exist, whose specialty is making it look like people in need of protection don't exist to keep them safe from various nefarious high-ups and/or low lives. Hence the 'erasing' reference of the title, he erases them from being mostly without even killing them! This time however the case is a young employee who is a key witness against a Big (evil) Corporation that is illegally making the naughty bing-bing-bing weapons. Eraser actually sports a fairly string cast of mainly James'; Coburn, Caan and Cromwell all get turns at being bad guys or Arnie's superiors or both. And Vanessa Williams is the damsel in distress in need of the protection only Arnie's big gun could give. The rest of the film is a series of carefully conceived yet palpably ridiculous action setpieces that are technically proficient but lack any sense of true action goodness. The plane escape sequence is fine, the zoo chase scene OK (featuring the afore-mentioned luggage) and the finale at the docks gives Arnie the chance to wield the big guns for himself. Two of them actually. But aside from these moments Eraser marks the point in Arnie's career where the enjoyment was primarily derived from mocking his butchering of the English language. To that point this was merely an added bonus in between the action. I think the scriptwriters spent more time coming up with short dialogue snippets that would sound funnier coming out of Arnie's lips  which is almost everything really  my favourite here was how he managed to turn the 4 syllables of "I work alone" into about 17 I wanted to like Eraser, and as a guilty 2 hour throwaway it served its purpose I guess. But after the 80s and 90s spoiled us (and Arnie) by casting him as super-soldiers, FBI/KGB agents and Terminators it just seems like after a decade of Coke you are forced to switch to Royal Cola for eternity. Sure it's still cola, but Final Rating  5.5 / 10. Need more evidence that this was the beginning of the end? Arnie's 5 films after Eraser: Jingle all the Way, Batman & Robin, End of Days, The 6th Day and Collateral Damage. I might argue that this was his last vaguely average film if I could summon the energy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "We're way beyond bullsh*t here."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ben Larson
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    With an Oscar nomination for sound effects an award for music, this is no B-movie. It is Schwarzenegger in one of his best film roles. He has a superb backup cast with Vanessa L. Williams, James Caan, and Robert Pastorelli. The excitement never stops with fantastic weaponry and a really great shootout in the zoo. Of course, you have to ignore the fact that Arnie manages to perform feats of magic with a shattered shoulder bone and an injured hand. He can do anything through the pain apparently. But the airplane scene makes it all worthwhile. More than a guilty pleasure, this is truly a movie worth watching over and over.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Arnie vs the weapons manufacturer
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What can I say about this movie other than it is another pointless Arnie action flick. Personally I enjoy the mindless Arnie action flicks, just as my friend enjoys wrestling. Unfortunately he cannot understand why somebody hates something that he loves and loves something that he hates. If one disagrees with him then we are the ones that have the problem. So much for opinions. Anyway, this movie is about a agent working for the witness protection program, whose job is to erase people's identities and set them up with new ones. He is assigned to look after a witness who is testifying against a large weapons corporation who are selling weapons to overseas buyers instead of the United States. This corporation has a lot of people on the payroll, so Arnie is up against the entire government, including his mentor. What I really don't understand is why a company selling its product to an overseas buyer, even if it is state of the art weaponry, would be considered treason. I guess it has something to do with using America as a base to build weaponry which will be sold to people who will end up using them against America. As such I think it is fair enough for them to be screaming treason. In the end this movie is a patriotic catching the badguys and saving the motherland. In the end America is safe and everybody can continue on being Americans. Personally, this is not one of Arnie's best movies, and unfortunately, since Terminator II, his movies seem to be downgrading a bit. Still, when one considers this movie, it is really no different to movies like Running Man, Total Recall, and Predator. In the end we do not come to see this movie to be astounded by Arnie's acting ability, but rather to see action, and as an action movie, we get plenty of it, and as such it lives up to the standards of other Arnie action movies (including the pathetic one-liners).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Arnie, big guns, and crocodiles: highly enjoyable no-brain action nonsense.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BA_Harrison
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The plot for Eraser is riddled with more holes than one of its bad guys after Arnie has unloaded a clip or two into them, and the cartoonish violence is mightily dumb at times, but although this film is undeniably a step down from it's star's previous two action films (James Cameron's True Lies and T2), it still proves to be a very enjoyable piece of slam-bang popcorn nonsense. Directed by Chuck Russell, the man who gave us Dream Warriors (the best Elm Street movie), the excellent remake of The Blob, and the hilariously warped Jim Carrey vehicle The Mask, this movie is slick, mindless fun full of great stunts, impressive special effects, and highly-improbable-yet-still-awesomely-entertaining set-pieces. As U.S. Marshal John 'The Eraser' Kruger, whose job is to provide new identities for people in the Witness Protection scheme, Arnie is required to flex everything except his acting muscles, and does so with his usual aplomb, throwing his enemies through the air with ease, effortlessly toting two massive rail-guns to lay waste to everything in sight, and generally causing a whole lot of pain and destruction. Meanwhile, Vanessa Williams simply looks ravishing and vulnerable as 'woman in peril', whilst James Caan chews up the scenery as 'treacherous boss'. Of course, It's all gets very silly at times, particularly towards the end, our hero seemingly impervious to pain and capable of superhuman strength, the bad guys being impossibly Machiavellian, and the jingoism even going so far as to depict the Russian Mafia as evil incarnate but the US's very own Italian Mafia as a bunch of lovable jokers, but with Arnie squaring off against a jet aircraft, giant crocs rampaging through New York Zoo's reptile house, and a through the roof body count, this still qualifies as one of the star's more enjoyable efforts. 7.5 out or 10, rounded up to 8 for IMDb.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You're luggage......
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    U.S. Marshal deputy John Kruger is one of the toughest Marshals, his methods are to "Erase" The identities of his witnesses he is assigned to protect. A woman named Lee Cullen who works for a corporation named Cyrez performed an undercover job for the FBI to unveil a top secret weapon which uses an electromagnetic pulse to dispatch targets. Cyrez discovered this about Lee and are now out to kill her, Kruger's job is now to protect Lee so she can testify against Cyrez. But, when Kruger was assigned to perform a job with another Marshal named Robert Deguerin, he discovers that Deguerin is behind the plot that will involve the EM Gun. Which will change hands to a Russian criminal if Kruger does not stop them, Kruger must not only protect Lee's life but his own.... Let's face it, this was Arnies last big film where he didn't play a Terminator. Back in the day where he could command a summer movie and make it score big, Eraser is a typical eighties action film in the nineties, trying to be hi-tech, so when you watch it 15 years on, it looks terribly dated. Arnie is great as the line spouting Marshal who is assigned to protect Williams. But Caan steals the show as the villain, one of the most sinister villains Arnie has faced this side of Mars. The action is over the top, the effects by todays standard are very bad, and there are so many plot holes, that it defies belief. But then you saw this movie, and you read this, so you know what to expect. Arnie getting shot in the arm, pulling items out of him that have stabbed him, jumpimg out of a plane and killing Alligators. Silly stuff, but still as watchable as it was in 1996.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Huge fun
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Neil Welch
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This late period - by which I mean Schwarzenegger's late period - action romp stars Schwarzenegger as a specialist in making people disappear - erasing them - not by killing them, but by making it look as if they have died before setting them up with new identities. He is assigned to erase Vanessa Williams but it becomes clear that she is completely expendable in the course of a plot by (not very surprisingly) Schwarzenegger's line manager James Caan to sell super-guns to foreigners. The plot doesn't really matter - it is just a vehicle for the action sequences, but it is perfectly serviceable and quite entertaining. The action sequences, typically over the top, include some CGI crocodiles and Arnold holding onto the side of a jet airliner by his fingertips (I must confess that last one stretched my credulity a little). Schwarzenegger is, well, Schwarzenegger. Williams is a feisty damsel in distress. Caan is downright dastardly. But the film is utterly stolen by Robert Pastorelli as someone erased at the start of the movie, recalled towards the end to repay a favour. This one is big fun.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Action-Packed!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'Eraser', directed by Chuck Russell, is an Action-Packed Flick, that offers some truly entertaining sequences in the goings-on. An interesting premise gets it's due, and a really energetic Arnold Schwarzenegger, does the trick. 'Eraser' tells the story of A Top-Grade Witness Protection specialist, Played by Schwarzenegger, who, becomes suspicious of his co-workers when dealing with a case involving high-tech weapons. Screenplay by Tony Puryear and Walon Green, is interesting and is aimed completely for the Masses. This Box Office Hit is meant for those who enjoy and relish Action-Flicks, that offer super stunts and sudden twists and turns. This entertainer is not meant for the pseudo critics! Chuck Russell's Direction is good, while the Stunts are applaud-worthy. Cinematography by Adam Greenberg, is passable. Editing is fair. Performance-Wise: As mentioned, Schwarzenegger is highly energetic in the central role. James Caan looks each bit of the character and is perfect, as always. Vanessa L. Williams is fairly good. James Coburn gets less scope, while Robert Pastorelli shines. Others lend good support. On the whole, An interesting action-flick, that has potential. Watch It!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of Arnie's best
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ebiros2
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    With 20 years of acting experience under his belt, Arnold has become a really good actor, and it shows in this movie. This movie was made when he was in his prime, and is one of the best movie he's done to this date. John Kruger (Arnold Schwarzenegger) is a US marshal who's task is to "erase" the identity of government witnesses under witness protection program. He's assigned to protect Lee Cullin (Vanessa Williams) who has the information to expose that her employer Cyrez Corporation is attempting to covertly smuggle rail gun rifles to international arms dealer. The master mind of this deal includes Kruger's associate Deguerin (James Khaan). Deguerin wants Cullin dead, and the only thing standing between them is Kruger. The quality of production and acting is extremely good in this movie. Arnie and Williams delivers great acting working as a team. Cinematography is beautiful, and special effects are also great. Everything comes together in this movie, making it one of Arnold's best movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Arnold Erases
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Arnold Schwarzenegger plays U.S. Marshal John 'The Eraser' Kruger, a specialist in the witness protection program who is assigned to protect Lee Cullen(Vanessa Williams) who had uncovered shady dealings at a military weapons manufacturer that she had worked for. The company now wants her dead, so John takes Lee to New York City with the help of his friend, fellow U.S. Marshal Robert Guerin(played by James Caan) Unfortunately, someone in the program has betrayed them, and now John and Lee must go on the run from both forces in order to expose the true villains, and save their lives. Pretty good Arnold S. film has lots of exciting action scenes, and an appealing cast of characters. Film has a predictable plot though, and stretches credibility at times, but is mostly entertaining.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Those things on the end of pencils.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Shawn Watson (gator_macready@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The 2-year gap between True Lies and Eraser forced some action fans into thinking that Big Arn had retired. He had delivered at least one action movie per year since Terminator. Eraser had an awesome trailer, to the tune of Enigma's wonderful "I Love You, I'll Kill You", that rocked my world in the summer of 1996. I saw virtually every blockbuster that year, and the Eraser trailer was attached to every one of them. It came out out in the UK in the very last week of summer (and my first week back at school). I saw it at the now demolished UCI cinema in Edinburgh with a sold-out audience, mostly filled with guys out for a "lad's night". The movie was rated 18, and even though I was 3 years below that mark, I still got in, which was fortunate since the cinema version is the only uncut version of the film that has ever been released in the UK. For its VHS and DVD release the mad BBFC saw fit to cut 4 minutes from Eraser, turning it into an incomprehensible mess. It capped-off an awesome summer season (or so my 15-year-old self thought), and put to rest any fears that Big Arn was slowing down (although he has only made 5 action movies, to date, since then). Arn is John Kruger (an amusing choice of name since director Chuck Russell also made the 3rd Nightmare on Elm Street Movie), a Witness Protection Program Agent who is tasked with 'erasing' and protecting a high-level informant who can prove that there are traitors within the US government who are selling weapons to Russian terrorists. Naturally the informant is the lovely, and wide-eyed, Vanessa Williams, who involves herself in a subdued romantic subplot with Kruger. James Caan and the always great James Coburn provide respectable support as Kruger's antagonist and mentor, but the best support is no doubt Robert Pastorelli (an actor who I really liked who died of a heroin overdose in 2004), who plays a previous witness who is eager to please Kruger in his latest, impossible quest. Overall, it's hardly revolutionary, but what makes Eraser stand out from the crowd is the utterly breathtaking (literally) scene in which Kruger escapes a jet, mid-flight, without the comfort of a parachute on his shoulders. It's definitely one of the best action scenes in the last 20 years and, let me tell you, when that scene climaxed in the cinema, the packed audience of 'lads' totally sucked the air out of the auditorium. A massively exciting, and completely exhilarating, scene that never fails to get your heart racing. Alan Silvestri's score is one of the film's more underrated features. Silvestri scored Big Arn's Predator, a famous score in its own right, and while Eraser is not as famous as Predator you should not rule out the integrity of the score. When separated from the movie it is still one of Silvestri's best efforts. I guess the only complaint I could have about Eraser is that it's kinda anti-climatic. The best scene occurs at the end of the second act, leaving the final act pale in comparison. There's no iconic imagery to the film and it seems kinda forgettable when compared to other Arn characters who have endured the test of time. Nonetheless, it's at the top of the bottom of Arn's best movies, but make sure you the version you watch has not been butchered by the BBFC. The Blu Ray is in 2.40:1 1080p with Dolby TrueHD sound. Extras are non-existent.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The beginning of the Arnie-end. More fun for his butchering of the English language.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    oneguyrambling
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Arnie's career was really losing steam by the time Eraser came around. After all he'd played every role that suited him, often multiple times. The robot. The soldier. The cop. The special agent. The ummm barbarian. And believe it or not, as IMDb is my witness, he played ALL of those characters more than once by this time, the only difference sometimes being the Eastern European country he was supposed to have come from. So by this stage Schwarzenegger was sorta grasping at straws, the result often being awful and often recycled projects that played with his image and in desperation introduced more and more illogical and ridiculous hooks and sequences. Take Eraser, where the bad guys have heat detecting scopes on their RAY GUNS(!) that go bing-bing-bing and cut through anything in their path, and Arnie gets to kill a 90s style CGI alligator and after consigning it to its fate declares it 'luggage'. (You know what? That bit still makes me laugh.) Arnie plays John Kruger, a guy who doesn't officially exist, whose specialty is making it look like people in need of protection don't exist to keep them safe from various nefarious high-ups and/or low lives. Hence the 'erasing' reference of the title, he erases them from being mostly without even killing them! This time however the case is a young employee who is a key witness against a Big (evil) Corporation that is illegally making the naughty bing-bing-bing weapons. Eraser actually sports a fairly string cast of mainly James'; Coburn, Caan and Cromwell all get turns at being bad guys or Arnie's superiors or both. And Vanessa Williams is the damsel in distress in need of the protection only Arnie's big gun could give. The rest of the film is a series of carefully conceived yet palpably ridiculous action setpieces that are technically proficient but lack any sense of true action goodness. The plane escape sequence is fine, the zoo chase scene OK (featuring the afore-mentioned luggage) and the finale at the docks gives Arnie the chance to wield the big guns for himself. Two of them actually. But aside from these moments Eraser marks the point in Arnie's career where the enjoyment was primarily derived from mocking his butchering of the English language. To that point this was merely an added bonus in between the action. I think the scriptwriters spent more time coming up with short dialogue snippets that would sound funnier coming out of Arnie's lips  which is almost everything really  my favourite here was how he managed to turn the 4 syllables of "I work alone" into about 17 I wanted to like Eraser, and as a guilty 2 hour throwaway it served its purpose I guess. But after the 80s and 90s spoiled us (and Arnie) by casting him as super-soldiers, FBI/KGB agents and Terminators it just seems like after a decade of Coke you are forced to switch to Royal Cola for eternity. Sure it's still cola, but Final Rating  5.5 / 10. Need more evidence that this was the beginning of the end? Arnie's 5 films after Eraser: Jingle all the Way, Batman & Robin, End of Days, The 6th Day and Collateral Damage. I might argue that this was his last vaguely average film if I could summon the energy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "We're way beyond bullsh*t here."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ben Larson
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    With an Oscar nomination for sound effects an award for music, this is no B-movie. It is Schwarzenegger in one of his best film roles. He has a superb backup cast with Vanessa L. Williams, James Caan, and Robert Pastorelli. The excitement never stops with fantastic weaponry and a really great shootout in the zoo. Of course, you have to ignore the fact that Arnie manages to perform feats of magic with a shattered shoulder bone and an injured hand. He can do anything through the pain apparently. But the airplane scene makes it all worthwhile. More than a guilty pleasure, this is truly a movie worth watching over and over.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Arnie vs the weapons manufacturer
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What can I say about this movie other than it is another pointless Arnie action flick. Personally I enjoy the mindless Arnie action flicks, just as my friend enjoys wrestling. Unfortunately he cannot understand why somebody hates something that he loves and loves something that he hates. If one disagrees with him then we are the ones that have the problem. So much for opinions. Anyway, this movie is about a agent working for the witness protection program, whose job is to erase people's identities and set them up with new ones. He is assigned to look after a witness who is testifying against a large weapons corporation who are selling weapons to overseas buyers instead of the United States. This corporation has a lot of people on the payroll, so Arnie is up against the entire government, including his mentor. What I really don't understand is why a company selling its product to an overseas buyer, even if it is state of the art weaponry, would be considered treason. I guess it has something to do with using America as a base to build weaponry which will be sold to people who will end up using them against America. As such I think it is fair enough for them to be screaming treason. In the end this movie is a patriotic catching the badguys and saving the motherland. In the end America is safe and everybody can continue on being Americans. Personally, this is not one of Arnie's best movies, and unfortunately, since Terminator II, his movies seem to be downgrading a bit. Still, when one considers this movie, it is really no different to movies like Running Man, Total Recall, and Predator. In the end we do not come to see this movie to be astounded by Arnie's acting ability, but rather to see action, and as an action movie, we get plenty of it, and as such it lives up to the standards of other Arnie action movies (including the pathetic one-liners).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Arnie, big guns, and crocodiles: highly enjoyable no-brain action nonsense.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BA_Harrison
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The plot for Eraser is riddled with more holes than one of its bad guys after Arnie has unloaded a clip or two into them, and the cartoonish violence is mightily dumb at times, but although this film is undeniably a step down from it's star's previous two action films (James Cameron's True Lies and T2), it still proves to be a very enjoyable piece of slam-bang popcorn nonsense. Directed by Chuck Russell, the man who gave us Dream Warriors (the best Elm Street movie), the excellent remake of The Blob, and the hilariously warped Jim Carrey vehicle The Mask, this movie is slick, mindless fun full of great stunts, impressive special effects, and highly-improbable-yet-still-awesomely-entertaining set-pieces. As U.S. Marshal John 'The Eraser' Kruger, whose job is to provide new identities for people in the Witness Protection scheme, Arnie is required to flex everything except his acting muscles, and does so with his usual aplomb, throwing his enemies through the air with ease, effortlessly toting two massive rail-guns to lay waste to everything in sight, and generally causing a whole lot of pain and destruction. Meanwhile, Vanessa Williams simply looks ravishing and vulnerable as 'woman in peril', whilst James Caan chews up the scenery as 'treacherous boss'. Of course, It's all gets very silly at times, particularly towards the end, our hero seemingly impervious to pain and capable of superhuman strength, the bad guys being impossibly Machiavellian, and the jingoism even going so far as to depict the Russian Mafia as evil incarnate but the US's very own Italian Mafia as a bunch of lovable jokers, but with Arnie squaring off against a jet aircraft, giant crocs rampaging through New York Zoo's reptile house, and a through the roof body count, this still qualifies as one of the star's more enjoyable efforts. 7.5 out or 10, rounded up to 8 for IMDb.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You're luggage......
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    U.S. Marshal deputy John Kruger is one of the toughest Marshals, his methods are to "Erase" The identities of his witnesses he is assigned to protect. A woman named Lee Cullen who works for a corporation named Cyrez performed an undercover job for the FBI to unveil a top secret weapon which uses an electromagnetic pulse to dispatch targets. Cyrez discovered this about Lee and are now out to kill her, Kruger's job is now to protect Lee so she can testify against Cyrez. But, when Kruger was assigned to perform a job with another Marshal named Robert Deguerin, he discovers that Deguerin is behind the plot that will involve the EM Gun. Which will change hands to a Russian criminal if Kruger does not stop them, Kruger must not only protect Lee's life but his own.... Let's face it, this was Arnies last big film where he didn't play a Terminator. Back in the day where he could command a summer movie and make it score big, Eraser is a typical eighties action film in the nineties, trying to be hi-tech, so when you watch it 15 years on, it looks terribly dated. Arnie is great as the line spouting Marshal who is assigned to protect Williams. But Caan steals the show as the villain, one of the most sinister villains Arnie has faced this side of Mars. The action is over the top, the effects by todays standard are very bad, and there are so many plot holes, that it defies belief. But then you saw this movie, and you read this, so you know what to expect. Arnie getting shot in the arm, pulling items out of him that have stabbed him, jumpimg out of a plane and killing Alligators. Silly stuff, but still as watchable as it was in 1996.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Huge fun
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Neil Welch
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This late period - by which I mean Schwarzenegger's late period - action romp stars Schwarzenegger as a specialist in making people disappear - erasing them - not by killing them, but by making it look as if they have died before setting them up with new identities. He is assigned to erase Vanessa Williams but it becomes clear that she is completely expendable in the course of a plot by (not very surprisingly) Schwarzenegger's line manager James Caan to sell super-guns to foreigners. The plot doesn't really matter - it is just a vehicle for the action sequences, but it is perfectly serviceable and quite entertaining. The action sequences, typically over the top, include some CGI crocodiles and Arnold holding onto the side of a jet airliner by his fingertips (I must confess that last one stretched my credulity a little). Schwarzenegger is, well, Schwarzenegger. Williams is a feisty damsel in distress. Caan is downright dastardly. But the film is utterly stolen by Robert Pastorelli as someone erased at the start of the movie, recalled towards the end to repay a favour. This one is big fun.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Action-Packed!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'Eraser', directed by Chuck Russell, is an Action-Packed Flick, that offers some truly entertaining sequences in the goings-on. An interesting premise gets it's due, and a really energetic Arnold Schwarzenegger, does the trick. 'Eraser' tells the story of A Top-Grade Witness Protection specialist, Played by Schwarzenegger, who, becomes suspicious of his co-workers when dealing with a case involving high-tech weapons. Screenplay by Tony Puryear and Walon Green, is interesting and is aimed completely for the Masses. This Box Office Hit is meant for those who enjoy and relish Action-Flicks, that offer super stunts and sudden twists and turns. This entertainer is not meant for the pseudo critics! Chuck Russell's Direction is good, while the Stunts are applaud-worthy. Cinematography by Adam Greenberg, is passable. Editing is fair. Performance-Wise: As mentioned, Schwarzenegger is highly energetic in the central role. James Caan looks each bit of the character and is perfect, as always. Vanessa L. Williams is fairly good. James Coburn gets less scope, while Robert Pastorelli shines. Others lend good support. On the whole, An interesting action-flick, that has potential. Watch It!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of Arnie's best
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ebiros2
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    With 20 years of acting experience under his belt, Arnold has become a really good actor, and it shows in this movie. This movie was made when he was in his prime, and is one of the best movie he's done to this date. John Kruger (Arnold Schwarzenegger) is a US marshal who's task is to "erase" the identity of government witnesses under witness protection program. He's assigned to protect Lee Cullin (Vanessa Williams) who has the information to expose that her employer Cyrez Corporation is attempting to covertly smuggle rail gun rifles to international arms dealer. The master mind of this deal includes Kruger's associate Deguerin (James Khaan). Deguerin wants Cullin dead, and the only thing standing between them is Kruger. The quality of production and acting is extremely good in this movie. Arnie and Williams delivers great acting working as a team. Cinematography is beautiful, and special effects are also great. Everything comes together in this movie, making it one of Arnold's best movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Arnold Erases
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Arnold Schwarzenegger plays U.S. Marshal John 'The Eraser' Kruger, a specialist in the witness protection program who is assigned to protect Lee Cullen(Vanessa Williams) who had uncovered shady dealings at a military weapons manufacturer that she had worked for. The company now wants her dead, so John takes Lee to New York City with the help of his friend, fellow U.S. Marshal Robert Guerin(played by James Caan) Unfortunately, someone in the program has betrayed them, and now John and Lee must go on the run from both forces in order to expose the true villains, and save their lives. Pretty good Arnold S. film has lots of exciting action scenes, and an appealing cast of characters. Film has a predictable plot though, and stretches credibility at times, but is mostly entertaining.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Those things on the end of pencils.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Shawn Watson (gator_macready@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The 2-year gap between True Lies and Eraser forced some action fans into thinking that Big Arn had retired. He had delivered at least one action movie per year since Terminator. Eraser had an awesome trailer, to the tune of Enigma's wonderful "I Love You, I'll Kill You", that rocked my world in the summer of 1996. I saw virtually every blockbuster that year, and the Eraser trailer was attached to every one of them. It came out out in the UK in the very last week of summer (and my first week back at school). I saw it at the now demolished UCI cinema in Edinburgh with a sold-out audience, mostly filled with guys out for a "lad's night". The movie was rated 18, and even though I was 3 years below that mark, I still got in, which was fortunate since the cinema version is the only uncut version of the film that has ever been released in the UK. For its VHS and DVD release the mad BBFC saw fit to cut 4 minutes from Eraser, turning it into an incomprehensible mess. It capped-off an awesome summer season (or so my 15-year-old self thought), and put to rest any fears that Big Arn was slowing down (although he has only made 5 action movies, to date, since then). Arn is John Kruger (an amusing choice of name since director Chuck Russell also made the 3rd Nightmare on Elm Street Movie), a Witness Protection Program Agent who is tasked with 'erasing' and protecting a high-level informant who can prove that there are traitors within the US government who are selling weapons to Russian terrorists. Naturally the informant is the lovely, and wide-eyed, Vanessa Williams, who involves herself in a subdued romantic subplot with Kruger. James Caan and the always great James Coburn provide respectable support as Kruger's antagonist and mentor, but the best support is no doubt Robert Pastorelli (an actor who I really liked who died of a heroin overdose in 2004), who plays a previous witness who is eager to please Kruger in his latest, impossible quest. Overall, it's hardly revolutionary, but what makes Eraser stand out from the crowd is the utterly breathtaking (literally) scene in which Kruger escapes a jet, mid-flight, without the comfort of a parachute on his shoulders. It's definitely one of the best action scenes in the last 20 years and, let me tell you, when that scene climaxed in the cinema, the packed audience of 'lads' totally sucked the air out of the auditorium. A massively exciting, and completely exhilarating, scene that never fails to get your heart racing. Alan Silvestri's score is one of the film's more underrated features. Silvestri scored Big Arn's Predator, a famous score in its own right, and while Eraser is not as famous as Predator you should not rule out the integrity of the score. When separated from the movie it is still one of Silvestri's best efforts. I guess the only complaint I could have about Eraser is that it's kinda anti-climatic. The best scene occurs at the end of the second act, leaving the final act pale in comparison. There's no iconic imagery to the film and it seems kinda forgettable when compared to other Arn characters who have endured the test of time. Nonetheless, it's at the top of the bottom of Arn's best movies, but make sure you the version you watch has not been butchered by the BBFC. The Blu Ray is in 2.40:1 1080p with Dolby TrueHD sound. Extras are non-existent.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The beginning of the Arnie-end. More fun for his butchering of the English language.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    oneguyrambling
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Arnie's career was really losing steam by the time Eraser came around. After all he'd played every role that suited him, often multiple times. The robot. The soldier. The cop. The special agent. The ummm barbarian. And believe it or not, as IMDb is my witness, he played ALL of those characters more than once by this time, the only difference sometimes being the Eastern European country he was supposed to have come from. So by this stage Schwarzenegger was sorta grasping at straws, the result often being awful and often recycled projects that played with his image and in desperation introduced more and more illogical and ridiculous hooks and sequences. Take Eraser, where the bad guys have heat detecting scopes on their RAY GUNS(!) that go bing-bing-bing and cut through anything in their path, and Arnie gets to kill a 90s style CGI alligator and after consigning it to its fate declares it 'luggage'. (You know what? That bit still makes me laugh.) Arnie plays John Kruger, a guy who doesn't officially exist, whose specialty is making it look like people in need of protection don't exist to keep them safe from various nefarious high-ups and/or low lives. Hence the 'erasing' reference of the title, he erases them from being mostly without even killing them! This time however the case is a young employee who is a key witness against a Big (evil) Corporation that is illegally making the naughty bing-bing-bing weapons. Eraser actually sports a fairly string cast of mainly James'; Coburn, Caan and Cromwell all get turns at being bad guys or Arnie's superiors or both. And Vanessa Williams is the damsel in distress in need of the protection only Arnie's big gun could give. The rest of the film is a series of carefully conceived yet palpably ridiculous action setpieces that are technically proficient but lack any sense of true action goodness. The plane escape sequence is fine, the zoo chase scene OK (featuring the afore-mentioned luggage) and the finale at the docks gives Arnie the chance to wield the big guns for himself. Two of them actually. But aside from these moments Eraser marks the point in Arnie's career where the enjoyment was primarily derived from mocking his butchering of the English language. To that point this was merely an added bonus in between the action. I think the scriptwriters spent more time coming up with short dialogue snippets that would sound funnier coming out of Arnie's lips  which is almost everything really  my favourite here was how he managed to turn the 4 syllables of "I work alone" into about 17 I wanted to like Eraser, and as a guilty 2 hour throwaway it served its purpose I guess. But after the 80s and 90s spoiled us (and Arnie) by casting him as super-soldiers, FBI/KGB agents and Terminators it just seems like after a decade of Coke you are forced to switch to Royal Cola for eternity. Sure it's still cola, but Final Rating  5.5 / 10. Need more evidence that this was the beginning of the end? Arnie's 5 films after Eraser: Jingle all the Way, Batman & Robin, End of Days, The 6th Day and Collateral Damage. I might argue that this was his last vaguely average film if I could summon the energy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "We're way beyond bullsh*t here."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ben Larson
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    With an Oscar nomination for sound effects an award for music, this is no B-movie. It is Schwarzenegger in one of his best film roles. He has a superb backup cast with Vanessa L. Williams, James Caan, and Robert Pastorelli. The excitement never stops with fantastic weaponry and a really great shootout in the zoo. Of course, you have to ignore the fact that Arnie manages to perform feats of magic with a shattered shoulder bone and an injured hand. He can do anything through the pain apparently. But the airplane scene makes it all worthwhile. More than a guilty pleasure, this is truly a movie worth watching over and over.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Arnie vs the weapons manufacturer
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What can I say about this movie other than it is another pointless Arnie action flick. Personally I enjoy the mindless Arnie action flicks, just as my friend enjoys wrestling. Unfortunately he cannot understand why somebody hates something that he loves and loves something that he hates. If one disagrees with him then we are the ones that have the problem. So much for opinions. Anyway, this movie is about a agent working for the witness protection program, whose job is to erase people's identities and set them up with new ones. He is assigned to look after a witness who is testifying against a large weapons corporation who are selling weapons to overseas buyers instead of the United States. This corporation has a lot of people on the payroll, so Arnie is up against the entire government, including his mentor. What I really don't understand is why a company selling its product to an overseas buyer, even if it is state of the art weaponry, would be considered treason. I guess it has something to do with using America as a base to build weaponry which will be sold to people who will end up using them against America. As such I think it is fair enough for them to be screaming treason. In the end this movie is a patriotic catching the badguys and saving the motherland. In the end America is safe and everybody can continue on being Americans. Personally, this is not one of Arnie's best movies, and unfortunately, since Terminator II, his movies seem to be downgrading a bit. Still, when one considers this movie, it is really no different to movies like Running Man, Total Recall, and Predator. In the end we do not come to see this movie to be astounded by Arnie's acting ability, but rather to see action, and as an action movie, we get plenty of it, and as such it lives up to the standards of other Arnie action movies (including the pathetic one-liners).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Arnie, big guns, and crocodiles: highly enjoyable no-brain action nonsense.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BA_Harrison
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The plot for Eraser is riddled with more holes than one of its bad guys after Arnie has unloaded a clip or two into them, and the cartoonish violence is mightily dumb at times, but although this film is undeniably a step down from it's star's previous two action films (James Cameron's True Lies and T2), it still proves to be a very enjoyable piece of slam-bang popcorn nonsense. Directed by Chuck Russell, the man who gave us Dream Warriors (the best Elm Street movie), the excellent remake of The Blob, and the hilariously warped Jim Carrey vehicle The Mask, this movie is slick, mindless fun full of great stunts, impressive special effects, and highly-improbable-yet-still-awesomely-entertaining set-pieces. As U.S. Marshal John 'The Eraser' Kruger, whose job is to provide new identities for people in the Witness Protection scheme, Arnie is required to flex everything except his acting muscles, and does so with his usual aplomb, throwing his enemies through the air with ease, effortlessly toting two massive rail-guns to lay waste to everything in sight, and generally causing a whole lot of pain and destruction. Meanwhile, Vanessa Williams simply looks ravishing and vulnerable as 'woman in peril', whilst James Caan chews up the scenery as 'treacherous boss'. Of course, It's all gets very silly at times, particularly towards the end, our hero seemingly impervious to pain and capable of superhuman strength, the bad guys being impossibly Machiavellian, and the jingoism even going so far as to depict the Russian Mafia as evil incarnate but the US's very own Italian Mafia as a bunch of lovable jokers, but with Arnie squaring off against a jet aircraft, giant crocs rampaging through New York Zoo's reptile house, and a through the roof body count, this still qualifies as one of the star's more enjoyable efforts. 7.5 out or 10, rounded up to 8 for IMDb.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You're luggage......
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    U.S. Marshal deputy John Kruger is one of the toughest Marshals, his methods are to "Erase" The identities of his witnesses he is assigned to protect. A woman named Lee Cullen who works for a corporation named Cyrez performed an undercover job for the FBI to unveil a top secret weapon which uses an electromagnetic pulse to dispatch targets. Cyrez discovered this about Lee and are now out to kill her, Kruger's job is now to protect Lee so she can testify against Cyrez. But, when Kruger was assigned to perform a job with another Marshal named Robert Deguerin, he discovers that Deguerin is behind the plot that will involve the EM Gun. Which will change hands to a Russian criminal if Kruger does not stop them, Kruger must not only protect Lee's life but his own.... Let's face it, this was Arnies last big film where he didn't play a Terminator. Back in the day where he could command a summer movie and make it score big, Eraser is a typical eighties action film in the nineties, trying to be hi-tech, so when you watch it 15 years on, it looks terribly dated. Arnie is great as the line spouting Marshal who is assigned to protect Williams. But Caan steals the show as the villain, one of the most sinister villains Arnie has faced this side of Mars. The action is over the top, the effects by todays standard are very bad, and there are so many plot holes, that it defies belief. But then you saw this movie, and you read this, so you know what to expect. Arnie getting shot in the arm, pulling items out of him that have stabbed him, jumpimg out of a plane and killing Alligators. Silly stuff, but still as watchable as it was in 1996.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Huge fun
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Neil Welch
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This late period - by which I mean Schwarzenegger's late period - action romp stars Schwarzenegger as a specialist in making people disappear - erasing them - not by killing them, but by making it look as if they have died before setting them up with new identities. He is assigned to erase Vanessa Williams but it becomes clear that she is completely expendable in the course of a plot by (not very surprisingly) Schwarzenegger's line manager James Caan to sell super-guns to foreigners. The plot doesn't really matter - it is just a vehicle for the action sequences, but it is perfectly serviceable and quite entertaining. The action sequences, typically over the top, include some CGI crocodiles and Arnold holding onto the side of a jet airliner by his fingertips (I must confess that last one stretched my credulity a little). Schwarzenegger is, well, Schwarzenegger. Williams is a feisty damsel in distress. Caan is downright dastardly. But the film is utterly stolen by Robert Pastorelli as someone erased at the start of the movie, recalled towards the end to repay a favour. This one is big fun.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Action-Packed!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'Eraser', directed by Chuck Russell, is an Action-Packed Flick, that offers some truly entertaining sequences in the goings-on. An interesting premise gets it's due, and a really energetic Arnold Schwarzenegger, does the trick. 'Eraser' tells the story of A Top-Grade Witness Protection specialist, Played by Schwarzenegger, who, becomes suspicious of his co-workers when dealing with a case involving high-tech weapons. Screenplay by Tony Puryear and Walon Green, is interesting and is aimed completely for the Masses. This Box Office Hit is meant for those who enjoy and relish Action-Flicks, that offer super stunts and sudden twists and turns. This entertainer is not meant for the pseudo critics! Chuck Russell's Direction is good, while the Stunts are applaud-worthy. Cinematography by Adam Greenberg, is passable. Editing is fair. Performance-Wise: As mentioned, Schwarzenegger is highly energetic in the central role. James Caan looks each bit of the character and is perfect, as always. Vanessa L. Williams is fairly good. James Coburn gets less scope, while Robert Pastorelli shines. Others lend good support. On the whole, An interesting action-flick, that has potential. Watch It!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of Arnie's best
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ebiros2
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    With 20 years of acting experience under his belt, Arnold has become a really good actor, and it shows in this movie. This movie was made when he was in his prime, and is one of the best movie he's done to this date. John Kruger (Arnold Schwarzenegger) is a US marshal who's task is to "erase" the identity of government witnesses under witness protection program. He's assigned to protect Lee Cullin (Vanessa Williams) who has the information to expose that her employer Cyrez Corporation is attempting to covertly smuggle rail gun rifles to international arms dealer. The master mind of this deal includes Kruger's associate Deguerin (James Khaan). Deguerin wants Cullin dead, and the only thing standing between them is Kruger. The quality of production and acting is extremely good in this movie. Arnie and Williams delivers great acting working as a team. Cinematography is beautiful, and special effects are also great. Everything comes together in this movie, making it one of Arnold's best movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Arnold Erases
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Arnold Schwarzenegger plays U.S. Marshal John 'The Eraser' Kruger, a specialist in the witness protection program who is assigned to protect Lee Cullen(Vanessa Williams) who had uncovered shady dealings at a military weapons manufacturer that she had worked for. The company now wants her dead, so John takes Lee to New York City with the help of his friend, fellow U.S. Marshal Robert Guerin(played by James Caan) Unfortunately, someone in the program has betrayed them, and now John and Lee must go on the run from both forces in order to expose the true villains, and save their lives. Pretty good Arnold S. film has lots of exciting action scenes, and an appealing cast of characters. Film has a predictable plot though, and stretches credibility at times, but is mostly entertaining.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Those things on the end of pencils.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Shawn Watson (gator_macready@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The 2-year gap between True Lies and Eraser forced some action fans into thinking that Big Arn had retired. He had delivered at least one action movie per year since Terminator. Eraser had an awesome trailer, to the tune of Enigma's wonderful "I Love You, I'll Kill You", that rocked my world in the summer of 1996. I saw virtually every blockbuster that year, and the Eraser trailer was attached to every one of them. It came out out in the UK in the very last week of summer (and my first week back at school). I saw it at the now demolished UCI cinema in Edinburgh with a sold-out audience, mostly filled with guys out for a "lad's night". The movie was rated 18, and even though I was 3 years below that mark, I still got in, which was fortunate since the cinema version is the only uncut version of the film that has ever been released in the UK. For its VHS and DVD release the mad BBFC saw fit to cut 4 minutes from Eraser, turning it into an incomprehensible mess. It capped-off an awesome summer season (or so my 15-year-old self thought), and put to rest any fears that Big Arn was slowing down (although he has only made 5 action movies, to date, since then). Arn is John Kruger (an amusing choice of name since director Chuck Russell also made the 3rd Nightmare on Elm Street Movie), a Witness Protection Program Agent who is tasked with 'erasing' and protecting a high-level informant who can prove that there are traitors within the US government who are selling weapons to Russian terrorists. Naturally the informant is the lovely, and wide-eyed, Vanessa Williams, who involves herself in a subdued romantic subplot with Kruger. James Caan and the always great James Coburn provide respectable support as Kruger's antagonist and mentor, but the best support is no doubt Robert Pastorelli (an actor who I really liked who died of a heroin overdose in 2004), who plays a previous witness who is eager to please Kruger in his latest, impossible quest. Overall, it's hardly revolutionary, but what makes Eraser stand out from the crowd is the utterly breathtaking (literally) scene in which Kruger escapes a jet, mid-flight, without the comfort of a parachute on his shoulders. It's definitely one of the best action scenes in the last 20 years and, let me tell you, when that scene climaxed in the cinema, the packed audience of 'lads' totally sucked the air out of the auditorium. A massively exciting, and completely exhilarating, scene that never fails to get your heart racing. Alan Silvestri's score is one of the film's more underrated features. Silvestri scored Big Arn's Predator, a famous score in its own right, and while Eraser is not as famous as Predator you should not rule out the integrity of the score. When separated from the movie it is still one of Silvestri's best efforts. I guess the only complaint I could have about Eraser is that it's kinda anti-climatic. The best scene occurs at the end of the second act, leaving the final act pale in comparison. There's no iconic imagery to the film and it seems kinda forgettable when compared to other Arn characters who have endured the test of time. Nonetheless, it's at the top of the bottom of Arn's best movies, but make sure you the version you watch has not been butchered by the BBFC. The Blu Ray is in 2.40:1 1080p with Dolby TrueHD sound. Extras are non-existent.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The beginning of the Arnie-end. More fun for his butchering of the English language.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    oneguyrambling
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Arnie's career was really losing steam by the time Eraser came around. After all he'd played every role that suited him, often multiple times. The robot. The soldier. The cop. The special agent. The ummm barbarian. And believe it or not, as IMDb is my witness, he played ALL of those characters more than once by this time, the only difference sometimes being the Eastern European country he was supposed to have come from. So by this stage Schwarzenegger was sorta grasping at straws, the result often being awful and often recycled projects that played with his image and in desperation introduced more and more illogical and ridiculous hooks and sequences. Take Eraser, where the bad guys have heat detecting scopes on their RAY GUNS(!) that go bing-bing-bing and cut through anything in their path, and Arnie gets to kill a 90s style CGI alligator and after consigning it to its fate declares it 'luggage'. (You know what? That bit still makes me laugh.) Arnie plays John Kruger, a guy who doesn't officially exist, whose specialty is making it look like people in need of protection don't exist to keep them safe from various nefarious high-ups and/or low lives. Hence the 'erasing' reference of the title, he erases them from being mostly without even killing them! This time however the case is a young employee who is a key witness against a Big (evil) Corporation that is illegally making the naughty bing-bing-bing weapons. Eraser actually sports a fairly string cast of mainly James'; Coburn, Caan and Cromwell all get turns at being bad guys or Arnie's superiors or both. And Vanessa Williams is the damsel in distress in need of the protection only Arnie's big gun could give. The rest of the film is a series of carefully conceived yet palpably ridiculous action setpieces that are technically proficient but lack any sense of true action goodness. The plane escape sequence is fine, the zoo chase scene OK (featuring the afore-mentioned luggage) and the finale at the docks gives Arnie the chance to wield the big guns for himself. Two of them actually. But aside from these moments Eraser marks the point in Arnie's career where the enjoyment was primarily derived from mocking his butchering of the English language. To that point this was merely an added bonus in between the action. I think the scriptwriters spent more time coming up with short dialogue snippets that would sound funnier coming out of Arnie's lips  which is almost everything really  my favourite here was how he managed to turn the 4 syllables of "I work alone" into about 17 I wanted to like Eraser, and as a guilty 2 hour throwaway it served its purpose I guess. But after the 80s and 90s spoiled us (and Arnie) by casting him as super-soldiers, FBI/KGB agents and Terminators it just seems like after a decade of Coke you are forced to switch to Royal Cola for eternity. Sure it's still cola, but Final Rating  5.5 / 10. Need more evidence that this was the beginning of the end? Arnie's 5 films after Eraser: Jingle all the Way, Batman & Robin, End of Days, The 6th Day and Collateral Damage. I might argue that this was his last vaguely average film if I could summon the energy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "We're way beyond bullsh*t here."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ben Larson
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    With an Oscar nomination for sound effects an award for music, this is no B-movie. It is Schwarzenegger in one of his best film roles. He has a superb backup cast with Vanessa L. Williams, James Caan, and Robert Pastorelli. The excitement never stops with fantastic weaponry and a really great shootout in the zoo. Of course, you have to ignore the fact that Arnie manages to perform feats of magic with a shattered shoulder bone and an injured hand. He can do anything through the pain apparently. But the airplane scene makes it all worthwhile. More than a guilty pleasure, this is truly a movie worth watching over and over.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Arnie vs the weapons manufacturer
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What can I say about this movie other than it is another pointless Arnie action flick. Personally I enjoy the mindless Arnie action flicks, just as my friend enjoys wrestling. Unfortunately he cannot understand why somebody hates something that he loves and loves something that he hates. If one disagrees with him then we are the ones that have the problem. So much for opinions. Anyway, this movie is about a agent working for the witness protection program, whose job is to erase people's identities and set them up with new ones. He is assigned to look after a witness who is testifying against a large weapons corporation who are selling weapons to overseas buyers instead of the United States. This corporation has a lot of people on the payroll, so Arnie is up against the entire government, including his mentor. What I really don't understand is why a company selling its product to an overseas buyer, even if it is state of the art weaponry, would be considered treason. I guess it has something to do with using America as a base to build weaponry which will be sold to people who will end up using them against America. As such I think it is fair enough for them to be screaming treason. In the end this movie is a patriotic catching the badguys and saving the motherland. In the end America is safe and everybody can continue on being Americans. Personally, this is not one of Arnie's best movies, and unfortunately, since Terminator II, his movies seem to be downgrading a bit. Still, when one considers this movie, it is really no different to movies like Running Man, Total Recall, and Predator. In the end we do not come to see this movie to be astounded by Arnie's acting ability, but rather to see action, and as an action movie, we get plenty of it, and as such it lives up to the standards of other Arnie action movies (including the pathetic one-liners).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Arnie, big guns, and crocodiles: highly enjoyable no-brain action nonsense.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BA_Harrison
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The plot for Eraser is riddled with more holes than one of its bad guys after Arnie has unloaded a clip or two into them, and the cartoonish violence is mightily dumb at times, but although this film is undeniably a step down from it's star's previous two action films (James Cameron's True Lies and T2), it still proves to be a very enjoyable piece of slam-bang popcorn nonsense. Directed by Chuck Russell, the man who gave us Dream Warriors (the best Elm Street movie), the excellent remake of The Blob, and the hilariously warped Jim Carrey vehicle The Mask, this movie is slick, mindless fun full of great stunts, impressive special effects, and highly-improbable-yet-still-awesomely-entertaining set-pieces. As U.S. Marshal John 'The Eraser' Kruger, whose job is to provide new identities for people in the Witness Protection scheme, Arnie is required to flex everything except his acting muscles, and does so with his usual aplomb, throwing his enemies through the air with ease, effortlessly toting two massive rail-guns to lay waste to everything in sight, and generally causing a whole lot of pain and destruction. Meanwhile, Vanessa Williams simply looks ravishing and vulnerable as 'woman in peril', whilst James Caan chews up the scenery as 'treacherous boss'. Of course, It's all gets very silly at times, particularly towards the end, our hero seemingly impervious to pain and capable of superhuman strength, the bad guys being impossibly Machiavellian, and the jingoism even going so far as to depict the Russian Mafia as evil incarnate but the US's very own Italian Mafia as a bunch of lovable jokers, but with Arnie squaring off against a jet aircraft, giant crocs rampaging through New York Zoo's reptile house, and a through the roof body count, this still qualifies as one of the star's more enjoyable efforts. 7.5 out or 10, rounded up to 8 for IMDb.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You're luggage......
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    U.S. Marshal deputy John Kruger is one of the toughest Marshals, his methods are to "Erase" The identities of his witnesses he is assigned to protect. A woman named Lee Cullen who works for a corporation named Cyrez performed an undercover job for the FBI to unveil a top secret weapon which uses an electromagnetic pulse to dispatch targets. Cyrez discovered this about Lee and are now out to kill her, Kruger's job is now to protect Lee so she can testify against Cyrez. But, when Kruger was assigned to perform a job with another Marshal named Robert Deguerin, he discovers that Deguerin is behind the plot that will involve the EM Gun. Which will change hands to a Russian criminal if Kruger does not stop them, Kruger must not only protect Lee's life but his own.... Let's face it, this was Arnies last big film where he didn't play a Terminator. Back in the day where he could command a summer movie and make it score big, Eraser is a typical eighties action film in the nineties, trying to be hi-tech, so when you watch it 15 years on, it looks terribly dated. Arnie is great as the line spouting Marshal who is assigned to protect Williams. But Caan steals the show as the villain, one of the most sinister villains Arnie has faced this side of Mars. The action is over the top, the effects by todays standard are very bad, and there are so many plot holes, that it defies belief. But then you saw this movie, and you read this, so you know what to expect. Arnie getting shot in the arm, pulling items out of him that have stabbed him, jumpimg out of a plane and killing Alligators. Silly stuff, but still as watchable as it was in 1996.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Huge fun
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Neil Welch
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This late period - by which I mean Schwarzenegger's late period - action romp stars Schwarzenegger as a specialist in making people disappear - erasing them - not by killing them, but by making it look as if they have died before setting them up with new identities. He is assigned to erase Vanessa Williams but it becomes clear that she is completely expendable in the course of a plot by (not very surprisingly) Schwarzenegger's line manager James Caan to sell super-guns to foreigners. The plot doesn't really matter - it is just a vehicle for the action sequences, but it is perfectly serviceable and quite entertaining. The action sequences, typically over the top, include some CGI crocodiles and Arnold holding onto the side of a jet airliner by his fingertips (I must confess that last one stretched my credulity a little). Schwarzenegger is, well, Schwarzenegger. Williams is a feisty damsel in distress. Caan is downright dastardly. But the film is utterly stolen by Robert Pastorelli as someone erased at the start of the movie, recalled towards the end to repay a favour. This one is big fun.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Action-Packed!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'Eraser', directed by Chuck Russell, is an Action-Packed Flick, that offers some truly entertaining sequences in the goings-on. An interesting premise gets it's due, and a really energetic Arnold Schwarzenegger, does the trick. 'Eraser' tells the story of A Top-Grade Witness Protection specialist, Played by Schwarzenegger, who, becomes suspicious of his co-workers when dealing with a case involving high-tech weapons. Screenplay by Tony Puryear and Walon Green, is interesting and is aimed completely for the Masses. This Box Office Hit is meant for those who enjoy and relish Action-Flicks, that offer super stunts and sudden twists and turns. This entertainer is not meant for the pseudo critics! Chuck Russell's Direction is good, while the Stunts are applaud-worthy. Cinematography by Adam Greenberg, is passable. Editing is fair. Performance-Wise: As mentioned, Schwarzenegger is highly energetic in the central role. James Caan looks each bit of the character and is perfect, as always. Vanessa L. Williams is fairly good. James Coburn gets less scope, while Robert Pastorelli shines. Others lend good support. On the whole, An interesting action-flick, that has potential. Watch It!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of Arnie's best
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ebiros2
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    With 20 years of acting experience under his belt, Arnold has become a really good actor, and it shows in this movie. This movie was made when he was in his prime, and is one of the best movie he's done to this date. John Kruger (Arnold Schwarzenegger) is a US marshal who's task is to "erase" the identity of government witnesses under witness protection program. He's assigned to protect Lee Cullin (Vanessa Williams) who has the information to expose that her employer Cyrez Corporation is attempting to covertly smuggle rail gun rifles to international arms dealer. The master mind of this deal includes Kruger's associate Deguerin (James Khaan). Deguerin wants Cullin dead, and the only thing standing between them is Kruger. The quality of production and acting is extremely good in this movie. Arnie and Williams delivers great acting working as a team. Cinematography is beautiful, and special effects are also great. Everything comes together in this movie, making it one of Arnold's best movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Arnold Erases
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Arnold Schwarzenegger plays U.S. Marshal John 'The Eraser' Kruger, a specialist in the witness protection program who is assigned to protect Lee Cullen(Vanessa Williams) who had uncovered shady dealings at a military weapons manufacturer that she had worked for. The company now wants her dead, so John takes Lee to New York City with the help of his friend, fellow U.S. Marshal Robert Guerin(played by James Caan) Unfortunately, someone in the program has betrayed them, and now John and Lee must go on the run from both forces in order to expose the true villains, and save their lives. Pretty good Arnold S. film has lots of exciting action scenes, and an appealing cast of characters. Film has a predictable plot though, and stretches credibility at times, but is mostly entertaining.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Those things on the end of pencils.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Shawn Watson (gator_macready@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The 2-year gap between True Lies and Eraser forced some action fans into thinking that Big Arn had retired. He had delivered at least one action movie per year since Terminator. Eraser had an awesome trailer, to the tune of Enigma's wonderful "I Love You, I'll Kill You", that rocked my world in the summer of 1996. I saw virtually every blockbuster that year, and the Eraser trailer was attached to every one of them. It came out out in the UK in the very last week of summer (and my first week back at school). I saw it at the now demolished UCI cinema in Edinburgh with a sold-out audience, mostly filled with guys out for a "lad's night". The movie was rated 18, and even though I was 3 years below that mark, I still got in, which was fortunate since the cinema version is the only uncut version of the film that has ever been released in the UK. For its VHS and DVD release the mad BBFC saw fit to cut 4 minutes from Eraser, turning it into an incomprehensible mess. It capped-off an awesome summer season (or so my 15-year-old self thought), and put to rest any fears that Big Arn was slowing down (although he has only made 5 action movies, to date, since then). Arn is John Kruger (an amusing choice of name since director Chuck Russell also made the 3rd Nightmare on Elm Street Movie), a Witness Protection Program Agent who is tasked with 'erasing' and protecting a high-level informant who can prove that there are traitors within the US government who are selling weapons to Russian terrorists. Naturally the informant is the lovely, and wide-eyed, Vanessa Williams, who involves herself in a subdued romantic subplot with Kruger. James Caan and the always great James Coburn provide respectable support as Kruger's antagonist and mentor, but the best support is no doubt Robert Pastorelli (an actor who I really liked who died of a heroin overdose in 2004), who plays a previous witness who is eager to please Kruger in his latest, impossible quest. Overall, it's hardly revolutionary, but what makes Eraser stand out from the crowd is the utterly breathtaking (literally) scene in which Kruger escapes a jet, mid-flight, without the comfort of a parachute on his shoulders. It's definitely one of the best action scenes in the last 20 years and, let me tell you, when that scene climaxed in the cinema, the packed audience of 'lads' totally sucked the air out of the auditorium. A massively exciting, and completely exhilarating, scene that never fails to get your heart racing. Alan Silvestri's score is one of the film's more underrated features. Silvestri scored Big Arn's Predator, a famous score in its own right, and while Eraser is not as famous as Predator you should not rule out the integrity of the score. When separated from the movie it is still one of Silvestri's best efforts. I guess the only complaint I could have about Eraser is that it's kinda anti-climatic. The best scene occurs at the end of the second act, leaving the final act pale in comparison. There's no iconic imagery to the film and it seems kinda forgettable when compared to other Arn characters who have endured the test of time. Nonetheless, it's at the top of the bottom of Arn's best movies, but make sure you the version you watch has not been butchered by the BBFC. The Blu Ray is in 2.40:1 1080p with Dolby TrueHD sound. Extras are non-existent.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The beginning of the Arnie-end. More fun for his butchering of the English language.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    oneguyrambling
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Arnie's career was really losing steam by the time Eraser came around. After all he'd played every role that suited him, often multiple times. The robot. The soldier. The cop. The special agent. The ummm barbarian. And believe it or not, as IMDb is my witness, he played ALL of those characters more than once by this time, the only difference sometimes being the Eastern European country he was supposed to have come from. So by this stage Schwarzenegger was sorta grasping at straws, the result often being awful and often recycled projects that played with his image and in desperation introduced more and more illogical and ridiculous hooks and sequences. Take Eraser, where the bad guys have heat detecting scopes on their RAY GUNS(!) that go bing-bing-bing and cut through anything in their path, and Arnie gets to kill a 90s style CGI alligator and after consigning it to its fate declares it 'luggage'. (You know what? That bit still makes me laugh.) Arnie plays John Kruger, a guy who doesn't officially exist, whose specialty is making it look like people in need of protection don't exist to keep them safe from various nefarious high-ups and/or low lives. Hence the 'erasing' reference of the title, he erases them from being mostly without even killing them! This time however the case is a young employee who is a key witness against a Big (evil) Corporation that is illegally making the naughty bing-bing-bing weapons. Eraser actually sports a fairly string cast of mainly James'; Coburn, Caan and Cromwell all get turns at being bad guys or Arnie's superiors or both. And Vanessa Williams is the damsel in distress in need of the protection only Arnie's big gun could give. The rest of the film is a series of carefully conceived yet palpably ridiculous action setpieces that are technically proficient but lack any sense of true action goodness. The plane escape sequence is fine, the zoo chase scene OK (featuring the afore-mentioned luggage) and the finale at the docks gives Arnie the chance to wield the big guns for himself. Two of them actually. But aside from these moments Eraser marks the point in Arnie's career where the enjoyment was primarily derived from mocking his butchering of the English language. To that point this was merely an added bonus in between the action. I think the scriptwriters spent more time coming up with short dialogue snippets that would sound funnier coming out of Arnie's lips  which is almost everything really  my favourite here was how he managed to turn the 4 syllables of "I work alone" into about 17 I wanted to like Eraser, and as a guilty 2 hour throwaway it served its purpose I guess. But after the 80s and 90s spoiled us (and Arnie) by casting him as super-soldiers, FBI/KGB agents and Terminators it just seems like after a decade of Coke you are forced to switch to Royal Cola for eternity. Sure it's still cola, but Final Rating  5.5 / 10. Need more evidence that this was the beginning of the end? Arnie's 5 films after Eraser: Jingle all the Way, Batman & Robin, End of Days, The 6th Day and Collateral Damage. I might argue that this was his last vaguely average film if I could summon the energy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "We're way beyond bullsh*t here."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ben Larson
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    With an Oscar nomination for sound effects an award for music, this is no B-movie. It is Schwarzenegger in one of his best film roles. He has a superb backup cast with Vanessa L. Williams, James Caan, and Robert Pastorelli. The excitement never stops with fantastic weaponry and a really great shootout in the zoo. Of course, you have to ignore the fact that Arnie manages to perform feats of magic with a shattered shoulder bone and an injured hand. He can do anything through the pain apparently. But the airplane scene makes it all worthwhile. More than a guilty pleasure, this is truly a movie worth watching over and over.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Arnie vs the weapons manufacturer
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What can I say about this movie other than it is another pointless Arnie action flick. Personally I enjoy the mindless Arnie action flicks, just as my friend enjoys wrestling. Unfortunately he cannot understand why somebody hates something that he loves and loves something that he hates. If one disagrees with him then we are the ones that have the problem. So much for opinions. Anyway, this movie is about a agent working for the witness protection program, whose job is to erase people's identities and set them up with new ones. He is assigned to look after a witness who is testifying against a large weapons corporation who are selling weapons to overseas buyers instead of the United States. This corporation has a lot of people on the payroll, so Arnie is up against the entire government, including his mentor. What I really don't understand is why a company selling its product to an overseas buyer, even if it is state of the art weaponry, would be considered treason. I guess it has something to do with using America as a base to build weaponry which will be sold to people who will end up using them against America. As such I think it is fair enough for them to be screaming treason. In the end this movie is a patriotic catching the badguys and saving the motherland. In the end America is safe and everybody can continue on being Americans. Personally, this is not one of Arnie's best movies, and unfortunately, since Terminator II, his movies seem to be downgrading a bit. Still, when one considers this movie, it is really no different to movies like Running Man, Total Recall, and Predator. In the end we do not come to see this movie to be astounded by Arnie's acting ability, but rather to see action, and as an action movie, we get plenty of it, and as such it lives up to the standards of other Arnie action movies (including the pathetic one-liners).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Arnie, big guns, and crocodiles: highly enjoyable no-brain action nonsense.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BA_Harrison
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The plot for Eraser is riddled with more holes than one of its bad guys after Arnie has unloaded a clip or two into them, and the cartoonish violence is mightily dumb at times, but although this film is undeniably a step down from it's star's previous two action films (James Cameron's True Lies and T2), it still proves to be a very enjoyable piece of slam-bang popcorn nonsense. Directed by Chuck Russell, the man who gave us Dream Warriors (the best Elm Street movie), the excellent remake of The Blob, and the hilariously warped Jim Carrey vehicle The Mask, this movie is slick, mindless fun full of great stunts, impressive special effects, and highly-improbable-yet-still-awesomely-entertaining set-pieces. As U.S. Marshal John 'The Eraser' Kruger, whose job is to provide new identities for people in the Witness Protection scheme, Arnie is required to flex everything except his acting muscles, and does so with his usual aplomb, throwing his enemies through the air with ease, effortlessly toting two massive rail-guns to lay waste to everything in sight, and generally causing a whole lot of pain and destruction. Meanwhile, Vanessa Williams simply looks ravishing and vulnerable as 'woman in peril', whilst James Caan chews up the scenery as 'treacherous boss'. Of course, It's all gets very silly at times, particularly towards the end, our hero seemingly impervious to pain and capable of superhuman strength, the bad guys being impossibly Machiavellian, and the jingoism even going so far as to depict the Russian Mafia as evil incarnate but the US's very own Italian Mafia as a bunch of lovable jokers, but with Arnie squaring off against a jet aircraft, giant crocs rampaging through New York Zoo's reptile house, and a through the roof body count, this still qualifies as one of the star's more enjoyable efforts. 7.5 out or 10, rounded up to 8 for IMDb.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You're luggage......
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    U.S. Marshal deputy John Kruger is one of the toughest Marshals, his methods are to "Erase" The identities of his witnesses he is assigned to protect. A woman named Lee Cullen who works for a corporation named Cyrez performed an undercover job for the FBI to unveil a top secret weapon which uses an electromagnetic pulse to dispatch targets. Cyrez discovered this about Lee and are now out to kill her, Kruger's job is now to protect Lee so she can testify against Cyrez. But, when Kruger was assigned to perform a job with another Marshal named Robert Deguerin, he discovers that Deguerin is behind the plot that will involve the EM Gun. Which will change hands to a Russian criminal if Kruger does not stop them, Kruger must not only protect Lee's life but his own.... Let's face it, this was Arnies last big film where he didn't play a Terminator. Back in the day where he could command a summer movie and make it score big, Eraser is a typical eighties action film in the nineties, trying to be hi-tech, so when you watch it 15 years on, it looks terribly dated. Arnie is great as the line spouting Marshal who is assigned to protect Williams. But Caan steals the show as the villain, one of the most sinister villains Arnie has faced this side of Mars. The action is over the top, the effects by todays standard are very bad, and there are so many plot holes, that it defies belief. But then you saw this movie, and you read this, so you know what to expect. Arnie getting shot in the arm, pulling items out of him that have stabbed him, jumpimg out of a plane and killing Alligators. Silly stuff, but still as watchable as it was in 1996.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Huge fun
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Neil Welch
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This late period - by which I mean Schwarzenegger's late period - action romp stars Schwarzenegger as a specialist in making people disappear - erasing them - not by killing them, but by making it look as if they have died before setting them up with new identities. He is assigned to erase Vanessa Williams but it becomes clear that she is completely expendable in the course of a plot by (not very surprisingly) Schwarzenegger's line manager James Caan to sell super-guns to foreigners. The plot doesn't really matter - it is just a vehicle for the action sequences, but it is perfectly serviceable and quite entertaining. The action sequences, typically over the top, include some CGI crocodiles and Arnold holding onto the side of a jet airliner by his fingertips (I must confess that last one stretched my credulity a little). Schwarzenegger is, well, Schwarzenegger. Williams is a feisty damsel in distress. Caan is downright dastardly. But the film is utterly stolen by Robert Pastorelli as someone erased at the start of the movie, recalled towards the end to repay a favour. This one is big fun.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Action-Packed!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'Eraser', directed by Chuck Russell, is an Action-Packed Flick, that offers some truly entertaining sequences in the goings-on. An interesting premise gets it's due, and a really energetic Arnold Schwarzenegger, does the trick. 'Eraser' tells the story of A Top-Grade Witness Protection specialist, Played by Schwarzenegger, who, becomes suspicious of his co-workers when dealing with a case involving high-tech weapons. Screenplay by Tony Puryear and Walon Green, is interesting and is aimed completely for the Masses. This Box Office Hit is meant for those who enjoy and relish Action-Flicks, that offer super stunts and sudden twists and turns. This entertainer is not meant for the pseudo critics! Chuck Russell's Direction is good, while the Stunts are applaud-worthy. Cinematography by Adam Greenberg, is passable. Editing is fair. Performance-Wise: As mentioned, Schwarzenegger is highly energetic in the central role. James Caan looks each bit of the character and is perfect, as always. Vanessa L. Williams is fairly good. James Coburn gets less scope, while Robert Pastorelli shines. Others lend good support. On the whole, An interesting action-flick, that has potential. Watch It!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of Arnie's best
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ebiros2
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    With 20 years of acting experience under his belt, Arnold has become a really good actor, and it shows in this movie. This movie was made when he was in his prime, and is one of the best movie he's done to this date. John Kruger (Arnold Schwarzenegger) is a US marshal who's task is to "erase" the identity of government witnesses under witness protection program. He's assigned to protect Lee Cullin (Vanessa Williams) who has the information to expose that her employer Cyrez Corporation is attempting to covertly smuggle rail gun rifles to international arms dealer. The master mind of this deal includes Kruger's associate Deguerin (James Khaan). Deguerin wants Cullin dead, and the only thing standing between them is Kruger. The quality of production and acting is extremely good in this movie. Arnie and Williams delivers great acting working as a team. Cinematography is beautiful, and special effects are also great. Everything comes together in this movie, making it one of Arnold's best movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Arnold Erases
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Arnold Schwarzenegger plays U.S. Marshal John 'The Eraser' Kruger, a specialist in the witness protection program who is assigned to protect Lee Cullen(Vanessa Williams) who had uncovered shady dealings at a military weapons manufacturer that she had worked for. The company now wants her dead, so John takes Lee to New York City with the help of his friend, fellow U.S. Marshal Robert Guerin(played by James Caan) Unfortunately, someone in the program has betrayed them, and now John and Lee must go on the run from both forces in order to expose the true villains, and save their lives. Pretty good Arnold S. film has lots of exciting action scenes, and an appealing cast of characters. Film has a predictable plot though, and stretches credibility at times, but is mostly entertaining.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Those things on the end of pencils.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Shawn Watson (gator_macready@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The 2-year gap between True Lies and Eraser forced some action fans into thinking that Big Arn had retired. He had delivered at least one action movie per year since Terminator. Eraser had an awesome trailer, to the tune of Enigma's wonderful "I Love You, I'll Kill You", that rocked my world in the summer of 1996. I saw virtually every blockbuster that year, and the Eraser trailer was attached to every one of them. It came out out in the UK in the very last week of summer (and my first week back at school). I saw it at the now demolished UCI cinema in Edinburgh with a sold-out audience, mostly filled with guys out for a "lad's night". The movie was rated 18, and even though I was 3 years below that mark, I still got in, which was fortunate since the cinema version is the only uncut version of the film that has ever been released in the UK. For its VHS and DVD release the mad BBFC saw fit to cut 4 minutes from Eraser, turning it into an incomprehensible mess. It capped-off an awesome summer season (or so my 15-year-old self thought), and put to rest any fears that Big Arn was slowing down (although he has only made 5 action movies, to date, since then). Arn is John Kruger (an amusing choice of name since director Chuck Russell also made the 3rd Nightmare on Elm Street Movie), a Witness Protection Program Agent who is tasked with 'erasing' and protecting a high-level informant who can prove that there are traitors within the US government who are selling weapons to Russian terrorists. Naturally the informant is the lovely, and wide-eyed, Vanessa Williams, who involves herself in a subdued romantic subplot with Kruger. James Caan and the always great James Coburn provide respectable support as Kruger's antagonist and mentor, but the best support is no doubt Robert Pastorelli (an actor who I really liked who died of a heroin overdose in 2004), who plays a previous witness who is eager to please Kruger in his latest, impossible quest. Overall, it's hardly revolutionary, but what makes Eraser stand out from the crowd is the utterly breathtaking (literally) scene in which Kruger escapes a jet, mid-flight, without the comfort of a parachute on his shoulders. It's definitely one of the best action scenes in the last 20 years and, let me tell you, when that scene climaxed in the cinema, the packed audience of 'lads' totally sucked the air out of the auditorium. A massively exciting, and completely exhilarating, scene that never fails to get your heart racing. Alan Silvestri's score is one of the film's more underrated features. Silvestri scored Big Arn's Predator, a famous score in its own right, and while Eraser is not as famous as Predator you should not rule out the integrity of the score. When separated from the movie it is still one of Silvestri's best efforts. I guess the only complaint I could have about Eraser is that it's kinda anti-climatic. The best scene occurs at the end of the second act, leaving the final act pale in comparison. There's no iconic imagery to the film and it seems kinda forgettable when compared to other Arn characters who have endured the test of time. Nonetheless, it's at the top of the bottom of Arn's best movies, but make sure you the version you watch has not been butchered by the BBFC. The Blu Ray is in 2.40:1 1080p with Dolby TrueHD sound. Extras are non-existent.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The beginning of the Arnie-end. More fun for his butchering of the English language.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    oneguyrambling
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Arnie's career was really losing steam by the time Eraser came around. After all he'd played every role that suited him, often multiple times. The robot. The soldier. The cop. The special agent. The ummm barbarian. And believe it or not, as IMDb is my witness, he played ALL of those characters more than once by this time, the only difference sometimes being the Eastern European country he was supposed to have come from. So by this stage Schwarzenegger was sorta grasping at straws, the result often being awful and often recycled projects that played with his image and in desperation introduced more and more illogical and ridiculous hooks and sequences. Take Eraser, where the bad guys have heat detecting scopes on their RAY GUNS(!) that go bing-bing-bing and cut through anything in their path, and Arnie gets to kill a 90s style CGI alligator and after consigning it to its fate declares it 'luggage'. (You know what? That bit still makes me laugh.) Arnie plays John Kruger, a guy who doesn't officially exist, whose specialty is making it look like people in need of protection don't exist to keep them safe from various nefarious high-ups and/or low lives. Hence the 'erasing' reference of the title, he erases them from being mostly without even killing them! This time however the case is a young employee who is a key witness against a Big (evil) Corporation that is illegally making the naughty bing-bing-bing weapons. Eraser actually sports a fairly string cast of mainly James'; Coburn, Caan and Cromwell all get turns at being bad guys or Arnie's superiors or both. And Vanessa Williams is the damsel in distress in need of the protection only Arnie's big gun could give. The rest of the film is a series of carefully conceived yet palpably ridiculous action setpieces that are technically proficient but lack any sense of true action goodness. The plane escape sequence is fine, the zoo chase scene OK (featuring the afore-mentioned luggage) and the finale at the docks gives Arnie the chance to wield the big guns for himself. Two of them actually. But aside from these moments Eraser marks the point in Arnie's career where the enjoyment was primarily derived from mocking his butchering of the English language. To that point this was merely an added bonus in between the action. I think the scriptwriters spent more time coming up with short dialogue snippets that would sound funnier coming out of Arnie's lips  which is almost everything really  my favourite here was how he managed to turn the 4 syllables of "I work alone" into about 17 I wanted to like Eraser, and as a guilty 2 hour throwaway it served its purpose I guess. But after the 80s and 90s spoiled us (and Arnie) by casting him as super-soldiers, FBI/KGB agents and Terminators it just seems like after a decade of Coke you are forced to switch to Royal Cola for eternity. Sure it's still cola, but Final Rating  5.5 / 10. Need more evidence that this was the beginning of the end? Arnie's 5 films after Eraser: Jingle all the Way, Batman & Robin, End of Days, The 6th Day and Collateral Damage. I might argue that this was his last vaguely average film if I could summon the energy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "We're way beyond bullsh*t here."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ben Larson
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    With an Oscar nomination for sound effects an award for music, this is no B-movie. It is Schwarzenegger in one of his best film roles. He has a superb backup cast with Vanessa L. Williams, James Caan, and Robert Pastorelli. The excitement never stops with fantastic weaponry and a really great shootout in the zoo. Of course, you have to ignore the fact that Arnie manages to perform feats of magic with a shattered shoulder bone and an injured hand. He can do anything through the pain apparently. But the airplane scene makes it all worthwhile. More than a guilty pleasure, this is truly a movie worth watching over and over.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Arnie vs the weapons manufacturer
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What can I say about this movie other than it is another pointless Arnie action flick. Personally I enjoy the mindless Arnie action flicks, just as my friend enjoys wrestling. Unfortunately he cannot understand why somebody hates something that he loves and loves something that he hates. If one disagrees with him then we are the ones that have the problem. So much for opinions. Anyway, this movie is about a agent working for the witness protection program, whose job is to erase people's identities and set them up with new ones. He is assigned to look after a witness who is testifying against a large weapons corporation who are selling weapons to overseas buyers instead of the United States. This corporation has a lot of people on the payroll, so Arnie is up against the entire government, including his mentor. What I really don't understand is why a company selling its product to an overseas buyer, even if it is state of the art weaponry, would be considered treason. I guess it has something to do with using America as a base to build weaponry which will be sold to people who will end up using them against America. As such I think it is fair enough for them to be screaming treason. In the end this movie is a patriotic catching the badguys and saving the motherland. In the end America is safe and everybody can continue on being Americans. Personally, this is not one of Arnie's best movies, and unfortunately, since Terminator II, his movies seem to be downgrading a bit. Still, when one considers this movie, it is really no different to movies like Running Man, Total Recall, and Predator. In the end we do not come to see this movie to be astounded by Arnie's acting ability, but rather to see action, and as an action movie, we get plenty of it, and as such it lives up to the standards of other Arnie action movies (including the pathetic one-liners).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Arnie, big guns, and crocodiles: highly enjoyable no-brain action nonsense.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BA_Harrison
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The plot for Eraser is riddled with more holes than one of its bad guys after Arnie has unloaded a clip or two into them, and the cartoonish violence is mightily dumb at times, but although this film is undeniably a step down from it's star's previous two action films (James Cameron's True Lies and T2), it still proves to be a very enjoyable piece of slam-bang popcorn nonsense. Directed by Chuck Russell, the man who gave us Dream Warriors (the best Elm Street movie), the excellent remake of The Blob, and the hilariously warped Jim Carrey vehicle The Mask, this movie is slick, mindless fun full of great stunts, impressive special effects, and highly-improbable-yet-still-awesomely-entertaining set-pieces. As U.S. Marshal John 'The Eraser' Kruger, whose job is to provide new identities for people in the Witness Protection scheme, Arnie is required to flex everything except his acting muscles, and does so with his usual aplomb, throwing his enemies through the air with ease, effortlessly toting two massive rail-guns to lay waste to everything in sight, and generally causing a whole lot of pain and destruction. Meanwhile, Vanessa Williams simply looks ravishing and vulnerable as 'woman in peril', whilst James Caan chews up the scenery as 'treacherous boss'. Of course, It's all gets very silly at times, particularly towards the end, our hero seemingly impervious to pain and capable of superhuman strength, the bad guys being impossibly Machiavellian, and the jingoism even going so far as to depict the Russian Mafia as evil incarnate but the US's very own Italian Mafia as a bunch of lovable jokers, but with Arnie squaring off against a jet aircraft, giant crocs rampaging through New York Zoo's reptile house, and a through the roof body count, this still qualifies as one of the star's more enjoyable efforts. 7.5 out or 10, rounded up to 8 for IMDb.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You're luggage......
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    U.S. Marshal deputy John Kruger is one of the toughest Marshals, his methods are to "Erase" The identities of his witnesses he is assigned to protect. A woman named Lee Cullen who works for a corporation named Cyrez performed an undercover job for the FBI to unveil a top secret weapon which uses an electromagnetic pulse to dispatch targets. Cyrez discovered this about Lee and are now out to kill her, Kruger's job is now to protect Lee so she can testify against Cyrez. But, when Kruger was assigned to perform a job with another Marshal named Robert Deguerin, he discovers that Deguerin is behind the plot that will involve the EM Gun. Which will change hands to a Russian criminal if Kruger does not stop them, Kruger must not only protect Lee's life but his own.... Let's face it, this was Arnies last big film where he didn't play a Terminator. Back in the day where he could command a summer movie and make it score big, Eraser is a typical eighties action film in the nineties, trying to be hi-tech, so when you watch it 15 years on, it looks terribly dated. Arnie is great as the line spouting Marshal who is assigned to protect Williams. But Caan steals the show as the villain, one of the most sinister villains Arnie has faced this side of Mars. The action is over the top, the effects by todays standard are very bad, and there are so many plot holes, that it defies belief. But then you saw this movie, and you read this, so you know what to expect. Arnie getting shot in the arm, pulling items out of him that have stabbed him, jumpimg out of a plane and killing Alligators. Silly stuff, but still as watchable as it was in 1996.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Huge fun
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Neil Welch
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This late period - by which I mean Schwarzenegger's late period - action romp stars Schwarzenegger as a specialist in making people disappear - erasing them - not by killing them, but by making it look as if they have died before setting them up with new identities. He is assigned to erase Vanessa Williams but it becomes clear that she is completely expendable in the course of a plot by (not very surprisingly) Schwarzenegger's line manager James Caan to sell super-guns to foreigners. The plot doesn't really matter - it is just a vehicle for the action sequences, but it is perfectly serviceable and quite entertaining. The action sequences, typically over the top, include some CGI crocodiles and Arnold holding onto the side of a jet airliner by his fingertips (I must confess that last one stretched my credulity a little). Schwarzenegger is, well, Schwarzenegger. Williams is a feisty damsel in distress. Caan is downright dastardly. But the film is utterly stolen by Robert Pastorelli as someone erased at the start of the movie, recalled towards the end to repay a favour. This one is big fun.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Action-Packed!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'Eraser', directed by Chuck Russell, is an Action-Packed Flick, that offers some truly entertaining sequences in the goings-on. An interesting premise gets it's due, and a really energetic Arnold Schwarzenegger, does the trick. 'Eraser' tells the story of A Top-Grade Witness Protection specialist, Played by Schwarzenegger, who, becomes suspicious of his co-workers when dealing with a case involving high-tech weapons. Screenplay by Tony Puryear and Walon Green, is interesting and is aimed completely for the Masses. This Box Office Hit is meant for those who enjoy and relish Action-Flicks, that offer super stunts and sudden twists and turns. This entertainer is not meant for the pseudo critics! Chuck Russell's Direction is good, while the Stunts are applaud-worthy. Cinematography by Adam Greenberg, is passable. Editing is fair. Performance-Wise: As mentioned, Schwarzenegger is highly energetic in the central role. James Caan looks each bit of the character and is perfect, as always. Vanessa L. Williams is fairly good. James Coburn gets less scope, while Robert Pastorelli shines. Others lend good support. On the whole, An interesting action-flick, that has potential. Watch It!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of Arnie's best
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ebiros2
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    With 20 years of acting experience under his belt, Arnold has become a really good actor, and it shows in this movie. This movie was made when he was in his prime, and is one of the best movie he's done to this date. John Kruger (Arnold Schwarzenegger) is a US marshal who's task is to "erase" the identity of government witnesses under witness protection program. He's assigned to protect Lee Cullin (Vanessa Williams) who has the information to expose that her employer Cyrez Corporation is attempting to covertly smuggle rail gun rifles to international arms dealer. The master mind of this deal includes Kruger's associate Deguerin (James Khaan). Deguerin wants Cullin dead, and the only thing standing between them is Kruger. The quality of production and acting is extremely good in this movie. Arnie and Williams delivers great acting working as a team. Cinematography is beautiful, and special effects are also great. Everything comes together in this movie, making it one of Arnold's best movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Arnold Erases
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Arnold Schwarzenegger plays U.S. Marshal John 'The Eraser' Kruger, a specialist in the witness protection program who is assigned to protect Lee Cullen(Vanessa Williams) who had uncovered shady dealings at a military weapons manufacturer that she had worked for. The company now wants her dead, so John takes Lee to New York City with the help of his friend, fellow U.S. Marshal Robert Guerin(played by James Caan) Unfortunately, someone in the program has betrayed them, and now John and Lee must go on the run from both forces in order to expose the true villains, and save their lives. Pretty good Arnold S. film has lots of exciting action scenes, and an appealing cast of characters. Film has a predictable plot though, and stretches credibility at times, but is mostly entertaining.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Those things on the end of pencils.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Shawn Watson (gator_macready@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The 2-year gap between True Lies and Eraser forced some action fans into thinking that Big Arn had retired. He had delivered at least one action movie per year since Terminator. Eraser had an awesome trailer, to the tune of Enigma's wonderful "I Love You, I'll Kill You", that rocked my world in the summer of 1996. I saw virtually every blockbuster that year, and the Eraser trailer was attached to every one of them. It came out out in the UK in the very last week of summer (and my first week back at school). I saw it at the now demolished UCI cinema in Edinburgh with a sold-out audience, mostly filled with guys out for a "lad's night". The movie was rated 18, and even though I was 3 years below that mark, I still got in, which was fortunate since the cinema version is the only uncut version of the film that has ever been released in the UK. For its VHS and DVD release the mad BBFC saw fit to cut 4 minutes from Eraser, turning it into an incomprehensible mess. It capped-off an awesome summer season (or so my 15-year-old self thought), and put to rest any fears that Big Arn was slowing down (although he has only made 5 action movies, to date, since then). Arn is John Kruger (an amusing choice of name since director Chuck Russell also made the 3rd Nightmare on Elm Street Movie), a Witness Protection Program Agent who is tasked with 'erasing' and protecting a high-level informant who can prove that there are traitors within the US government who are selling weapons to Russian terrorists. Naturally the informant is the lovely, and wide-eyed, Vanessa Williams, who involves herself in a subdued romantic subplot with Kruger. James Caan and the always great James Coburn provide respectable support as Kruger's antagonist and mentor, but the best support is no doubt Robert Pastorelli (an actor who I really liked who died of a heroin overdose in 2004), who plays a previous witness who is eager to please Kruger in his latest, impossible quest. Overall, it's hardly revolutionary, but what makes Eraser stand out from the crowd is the utterly breathtaking (literally) scene in which Kruger escapes a jet, mid-flight, without the comfort of a parachute on his shoulders. It's definitely one of the best action scenes in the last 20 years and, let me tell you, when that scene climaxed in the cinema, the packed audience of 'lads' totally sucked the air out of the auditorium. A massively exciting, and completely exhilarating, scene that never fails to get your heart racing. Alan Silvestri's score is one of the film's more underrated features. Silvestri scored Big Arn's Predator, a famous score in its own right, and while Eraser is not as famous as Predator you should not rule out the integrity of the score. When separated from the movie it is still one of Silvestri's best efforts. I guess the only complaint I could have about Eraser is that it's kinda anti-climatic. The best scene occurs at the end of the second act, leaving the final act pale in comparison. There's no iconic imagery to the film and it seems kinda forgettable when compared to other Arn characters who have endured the test of time. Nonetheless, it's at the top of the bottom of Arn's best movies, but make sure you the version you watch has not been butchered by the BBFC. The Blu Ray is in 2.40:1 1080p with Dolby TrueHD sound. Extras are non-existent.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The beginning of the Arnie-end. More fun for his butchering of the English language.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    oneguyrambling
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Arnie's career was really losing steam by the time Eraser came around. After all he'd played every role that suited him, often multiple times. The robot. The soldier. The cop. The special agent. The ummm barbarian. And believe it or not, as IMDb is my witness, he played ALL of those characters more than once by this time, the only difference sometimes being the Eastern European country he was supposed to have come from. So by this stage Schwarzenegger was sorta grasping at straws, the result often being awful and often recycled projects that played with his image and in desperation introduced more and more illogical and ridiculous hooks and sequences. Take Eraser, where the bad guys have heat detecting scopes on their RAY GUNS(!) that go bing-bing-bing and cut through anything in their path, and Arnie gets to kill a 90s style CGI alligator and after consigning it to its fate declares it 'luggage'. (You know what? That bit still makes me laugh.) Arnie plays John Kruger, a guy who doesn't officially exist, whose specialty is making it look like people in need of protection don't exist to keep them safe from various nefarious high-ups and/or low lives. Hence the 'erasing' reference of the title, he erases them from being mostly without even killing them! This time however the case is a young employee who is a key witness against a Big (evil) Corporation that is illegally making the naughty bing-bing-bing weapons. Eraser actually sports a fairly string cast of mainly James'; Coburn, Caan and Cromwell all get turns at being bad guys or Arnie's superiors or both. And Vanessa Williams is the damsel in distress in need of the protection only Arnie's big gun could give. The rest of the film is a series of carefully conceived yet palpably ridiculous action setpieces that are technically proficient but lack any sense of true action goodness. The plane escape sequence is fine, the zoo chase scene OK (featuring the afore-mentioned luggage) and the finale at the docks gives Arnie the chance to wield the big guns for himself. Two of them actually. But aside from these moments Eraser marks the point in Arnie's career where the enjoyment was primarily derived from mocking his butchering of the English language. To that point this was merely an added bonus in between the action. I think the scriptwriters spent more time coming up with short dialogue snippets that would sound funnier coming out of Arnie's lips  which is almost everything really  my favourite here was how he managed to turn the 4 syllables of "I work alone" into about 17 I wanted to like Eraser, and as a guilty 2 hour throwaway it served its purpose I guess. But after the 80s and 90s spoiled us (and Arnie) by casting him as super-soldiers, FBI/KGB agents and Terminators it just seems like after a decade of Coke you are forced to switch to Royal Cola for eternity. Sure it's still cola, but Final Rating  5.5 / 10. Need more evidence that this was the beginning of the end? Arnie's 5 films after Eraser: Jingle all the Way, Batman & Robin, End of Days, The 6th Day and Collateral Damage. I might argue that this was his last vaguely average film if I could summon the energy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "We're way beyond bullsh*t here."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ben Larson
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    With an Oscar nomination for sound effects an award for music, this is no B-movie. It is Schwarzenegger in one of his best film roles. He has a superb backup cast with Vanessa L. Williams, James Caan, and Robert Pastorelli. The excitement never stops with fantastic weaponry and a really great shootout in the zoo. Of course, you have to ignore the fact that Arnie manages to perform feats of magic with a shattered shoulder bone and an injured hand. He can do anything through the pain apparently. But the airplane scene makes it all worthwhile. More than a guilty pleasure, this is truly a movie worth watching over and over.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Arnie vs the weapons manufacturer
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What can I say about this movie other than it is another pointless Arnie action flick. Personally I enjoy the mindless Arnie action flicks, just as my friend enjoys wrestling. Unfortunately he cannot understand why somebody hates something that he loves and loves something that he hates. If one disagrees with him then we are the ones that have the problem. So much for opinions. Anyway, this movie is about a agent working for the witness protection program, whose job is to erase people's identities and set them up with new ones. He is assigned to look after a witness who is testifying against a large weapons corporation who are selling weapons to overseas buyers instead of the United States. This corporation has a lot of people on the payroll, so Arnie is up against the entire government, including his mentor. What I really don't understand is why a company selling its product to an overseas buyer, even if it is state of the art weaponry, would be considered treason. I guess it has something to do with using America as a base to build weaponry which will be sold to people who will end up using them against America. As such I think it is fair enough for them to be screaming treason. In the end this movie is a patriotic catching the badguys and saving the motherland. In the end America is safe and everybody can continue on being Americans. Personally, this is not one of Arnie's best movies, and unfortunately, since Terminator II, his movies seem to be downgrading a bit. Still, when one considers this movie, it is really no different to movies like Running Man, Total Recall, and Predator. In the end we do not come to see this movie to be astounded by Arnie's acting ability, but rather to see action, and as an action movie, we get plenty of it, and as such it lives up to the standards of other Arnie action movies (including the pathetic one-liners).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Arnie, big guns, and crocodiles: highly enjoyable no-brain action nonsense.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BA_Harrison
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The plot for Eraser is riddled with more holes than one of its bad guys after Arnie has unloaded a clip or two into them, and the cartoonish violence is mightily dumb at times, but although this film is undeniably a step down from it's star's previous two action films (James Cameron's True Lies and T2), it still proves to be a very enjoyable piece of slam-bang popcorn nonsense. Directed by Chuck Russell, the man who gave us Dream Warriors (the best Elm Street movie), the excellent remake of The Blob, and the hilariously warped Jim Carrey vehicle The Mask, this movie is slick, mindless fun full of great stunts, impressive special effects, and highly-improbable-yet-still-awesomely-entertaining set-pieces. As U.S. Marshal John 'The Eraser' Kruger, whose job is to provide new identities for people in the Witness Protection scheme, Arnie is required to flex everything except his acting muscles, and does so with his usual aplomb, throwing his enemies through the air with ease, effortlessly toting two massive rail-guns to lay waste to everything in sight, and generally causing a whole lot of pain and destruction. Meanwhile, Vanessa Williams simply looks ravishing and vulnerable as 'woman in peril', whilst James Caan chews up the scenery as 'treacherous boss'. Of course, It's all gets very silly at times, particularly towards the end, our hero seemingly impervious to pain and capable of superhuman strength, the bad guys being impossibly Machiavellian, and the jingoism even going so far as to depict the Russian Mafia as evil incarnate but the US's very own Italian Mafia as a bunch of lovable jokers, but with Arnie squaring off against a jet aircraft, giant crocs rampaging through New York Zoo's reptile house, and a through the roof body count, this still qualifies as one of the star's more enjoyable efforts. 7.5 out or 10, rounded up to 8 for IMDb.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You're luggage......
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    U.S. Marshal deputy John Kruger is one of the toughest Marshals, his methods are to "Erase" The identities of his witnesses he is assigned to protect. A woman named Lee Cullen who works for a corporation named Cyrez performed an undercover job for the FBI to unveil a top secret weapon which uses an electromagnetic pulse to dispatch targets. Cyrez discovered this about Lee and are now out to kill her, Kruger's job is now to protect Lee so she can testify against Cyrez. But, when Kruger was assigned to perform a job with another Marshal named Robert Deguerin, he discovers that Deguerin is behind the plot that will involve the EM Gun. Which will change hands to a Russian criminal if Kruger does not stop them, Kruger must not only protect Lee's life but his own.... Let's face it, this was Arnies last big film where he didn't play a Terminator. Back in the day where he could command a summer movie and make it score big, Eraser is a typical eighties action film in the nineties, trying to be hi-tech, so when you watch it 15 years on, it looks terribly dated. Arnie is great as the line spouting Marshal who is assigned to protect Williams. But Caan steals the show as the villain, one of the most sinister villains Arnie has faced this side of Mars. The action is over the top, the effects by todays standard are very bad, and there are so many plot holes, that it defies belief. But then you saw this movie, and you read this, so you know what to expect. Arnie getting shot in the arm, pulling items out of him that have stabbed him, jumpimg out of a plane and killing Alligators. Silly stuff, but still as watchable as it was in 1996.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Huge fun
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Neil Welch
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This late period - by which I mean Schwarzenegger's late period - action romp stars Schwarzenegger as a specialist in making people disappear - erasing them - not by killing them, but by making it look as if they have died before setting them up with new identities. He is assigned to erase Vanessa Williams but it becomes clear that she is completely expendable in the course of a plot by (not very surprisingly) Schwarzenegger's line manager James Caan to sell super-guns to foreigners. The plot doesn't really matter - it is just a vehicle for the action sequences, but it is perfectly serviceable and quite entertaining. The action sequences, typically over the top, include some CGI crocodiles and Arnold holding onto the side of a jet airliner by his fingertips (I must confess that last one stretched my credulity a little). Schwarzenegger is, well, Schwarzenegger. Williams is a feisty damsel in distress. Caan is downright dastardly. But the film is utterly stolen by Robert Pastorelli as someone erased at the start of the movie, recalled towards the end to repay a favour. This one is big fun.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Action-Packed!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'Eraser', directed by Chuck Russell, is an Action-Packed Flick, that offers some truly entertaining sequences in the goings-on. An interesting premise gets it's due, and a really energetic Arnold Schwarzenegger, does the trick. 'Eraser' tells the story of A Top-Grade Witness Protection specialist, Played by Schwarzenegger, who, becomes suspicious of his co-workers when dealing with a case involving high-tech weapons. Screenplay by Tony Puryear and Walon Green, is interesting and is aimed completely for the Masses. This Box Office Hit is meant for those who enjoy and relish Action-Flicks, that offer super stunts and sudden twists and turns. This entertainer is not meant for the pseudo critics! Chuck Russell's Direction is good, while the Stunts are applaud-worthy. Cinematography by Adam Greenberg, is passable. Editing is fair. Performance-Wise: As mentioned, Schwarzenegger is highly energetic in the central role. James Caan looks each bit of the character and is perfect, as always. Vanessa L. Williams is fairly good. James Coburn gets less scope, while Robert Pastorelli shines. Others lend good support. On the whole, An interesting action-flick, that has potential. Watch It!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of Arnie's best
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ebiros2
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    With 20 years of acting experience under his belt, Arnold has become a really good actor, and it shows in this movie. This movie was made when he was in his prime, and is one of the best movie he's done to this date. John Kruger (Arnold Schwarzenegger) is a US marshal who's task is to "erase" the identity of government witnesses under witness protection program. He's assigned to protect Lee Cullin (Vanessa Williams) who has the information to expose that her employer Cyrez Corporation is attempting to covertly smuggle rail gun rifles to international arms dealer. The master mind of this deal includes Kruger's associate Deguerin (James Khaan). Deguerin wants Cullin dead, and the only thing standing between them is Kruger. The quality of production and acting is extremely good in this movie. Arnie and Williams delivers great acting working as a team. Cinematography is beautiful, and special effects are also great. Everything comes together in this movie, making it one of Arnold's best movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Arnold Erases
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Arnold Schwarzenegger plays U.S. Marshal John 'The Eraser' Kruger, a specialist in the witness protection program who is assigned to protect Lee Cullen(Vanessa Williams) who had uncovered shady dealings at a military weapons manufacturer that she had worked for. The company now wants her dead, so John takes Lee to New York City with the help of his friend, fellow U.S. Marshal Robert Guerin(played by James Caan) Unfortunately, someone in the program has betrayed them, and now John and Lee must go on the run from both forces in order to expose the true villains, and save their lives. Pretty good Arnold S. film has lots of exciting action scenes, and an appealing cast of characters. Film has a predictable plot though, and stretches credibility at times, but is mostly entertaining.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Those things on the end of pencils.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Shawn Watson (gator_macready@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The 2-year gap between True Lies and Eraser forced some action fans into thinking that Big Arn had retired. He had delivered at least one action movie per year since Terminator. Eraser had an awesome trailer, to the tune of Enigma's wonderful "I Love You, I'll Kill You", that rocked my world in the summer of 1996. I saw virtually every blockbuster that year, and the Eraser trailer was attached to every one of them. It came out out in the UK in the very last week of summer (and my first week back at school). I saw it at the now demolished UCI cinema in Edinburgh with a sold-out audience, mostly filled with guys out for a "lad's night". The movie was rated 18, and even though I was 3 years below that mark, I still got in, which was fortunate since the cinema version is the only uncut version of the film that has ever been released in the UK. For its VHS and DVD release the mad BBFC saw fit to cut 4 minutes from Eraser, turning it into an incomprehensible mess. It capped-off an awesome summer season (or so my 15-year-old self thought), and put to rest any fears that Big Arn was slowing down (although he has only made 5 action movies, to date, since then). Arn is John Kruger (an amusing choice of name since director Chuck Russell also made the 3rd Nightmare on Elm Street Movie), a Witness Protection Program Agent who is tasked with 'erasing' and protecting a high-level informant who can prove that there are traitors within the US government who are selling weapons to Russian terrorists. Naturally the informant is the lovely, and wide-eyed, Vanessa Williams, who involves herself in a subdued romantic subplot with Kruger. James Caan and the always great James Coburn provide respectable support as Kruger's antagonist and mentor, but the best support is no doubt Robert Pastorelli (an actor who I really liked who died of a heroin overdose in 2004), who plays a previous witness who is eager to please Kruger in his latest, impossible quest. Overall, it's hardly revolutionary, but what makes Eraser stand out from the crowd is the utterly breathtaking (literally) scene in which Kruger escapes a jet, mid-flight, without the comfort of a parachute on his shoulders. It's definitely one of the best action scenes in the last 20 years and, let me tell you, when that scene climaxed in the cinema, the packed audience of 'lads' totally sucked the air out of the auditorium. A massively exciting, and completely exhilarating, scene that never fails to get your heart racing. Alan Silvestri's score is one of the film's more underrated features. Silvestri scored Big Arn's Predator, a famous score in its own right, and while Eraser is not as famous as Predator you should not rule out the integrity of the score. When separated from the movie it is still one of Silvestri's best efforts. I guess the only complaint I could have about Eraser is that it's kinda anti-climatic. The best scene occurs at the end of the second act, leaving the final act pale in comparison. There's no iconic imagery to the film and it seems kinda forgettable when compared to other Arn characters who have endured the test of time. Nonetheless, it's at the top of the bottom of Arn's best movies, but make sure you the version you watch has not been butchered by the BBFC. The Blu Ray is in 2.40:1 1080p with Dolby TrueHD sound. Extras are non-existent.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The beginning of the Arnie-end. More fun for his butchering of the English language.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    oneguyrambling
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Arnie's career was really losing steam by the time Eraser came around. After all he'd played every role that suited him, often multiple times. The robot. The soldier. The cop. The special agent. The ummm barbarian. And believe it or not, as IMDb is my witness, he played ALL of those characters more than once by this time, the only difference sometimes being the Eastern European country he was supposed to have come from. So by this stage Schwarzenegger was sorta grasping at straws, the result often being awful and often recycled projects that played with his image and in desperation introduced more and more illogical and ridiculous hooks and sequences. Take Eraser, where the bad guys have heat detecting scopes on their RAY GUNS(!) that go bing-bing-bing and cut through anything in their path, and Arnie gets to kill a 90s style CGI alligator and after consigning it to its fate declares it 'luggage'. (You know what? That bit still makes me laugh.) Arnie plays John Kruger, a guy who doesn't officially exist, whose specialty is making it look like people in need of protection don't exist to keep them safe from various nefarious high-ups and/or low lives. Hence the 'erasing' reference of the title, he erases them from being mostly without even killing them! This time however the case is a young employee who is a key witness against a Big (evil) Corporation that is illegally making the naughty bing-bing-bing weapons. Eraser actually sports a fairly string cast of mainly James'; Coburn, Caan and Cromwell all get turns at being bad guys or Arnie's superiors or both. And Vanessa Williams is the damsel in distress in need of the protection only Arnie's big gun could give. The rest of the film is a series of carefully conceived yet palpably ridiculous action setpieces that are technically proficient but lack any sense of true action goodness. The plane escape sequence is fine, the zoo chase scene OK (featuring the afore-mentioned luggage) and the finale at the docks gives Arnie the chance to wield the big guns for himself. Two of them actually. But aside from these moments Eraser marks the point in Arnie's career where the enjoyment was primarily derived from mocking his butchering of the English language. To that point this was merely an added bonus in between the action. I think the scriptwriters spent more time coming up with short dialogue snippets that would sound funnier coming out of Arnie's lips  which is almost everything really  my favourite here was how he managed to turn the 4 syllables of "I work alone" into about 17 I wanted to like Eraser, and as a guilty 2 hour throwaway it served its purpose I guess. But after the 80s and 90s spoiled us (and Arnie) by casting him as super-soldiers, FBI/KGB agents and Terminators it just seems like after a decade of Coke you are forced to switch to Royal Cola for eternity. Sure it's still cola, but Final Rating  5.5 / 10. Need more evidence that this was the beginning of the end? Arnie's 5 films after Eraser: Jingle all the Way, Batman & Robin, End of Days, The 6th Day and Collateral Damage. I might argue that this was his last vaguely average film if I could summon the energy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "We're way beyond bullsh*t here."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ben Larson
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    With an Oscar nomination for sound effects an award for music, this is no B-movie. It is Schwarzenegger in one of his best film roles. He has a superb backup cast with Vanessa L. Williams, James Caan, and Robert Pastorelli. The excitement never stops with fantastic weaponry and a really great shootout in the zoo. Of course, you have to ignore the fact that Arnie manages to perform feats of magic with a shattered shoulder bone and an injured hand. He can do anything through the pain apparently. But the airplane scene makes it all worthwhile. More than a guilty pleasure, this is truly a movie worth watching over and over.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Arnie vs the weapons manufacturer
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What can I say about this movie other than it is another pointless Arnie action flick. Personally I enjoy the mindless Arnie action flicks, just as my friend enjoys wrestling. Unfortunately he cannot understand why somebody hates something that he loves and loves something that he hates. If one disagrees with him then we are the ones that have the problem. So much for opinions. Anyway, this movie is about a agent working for the witness protection program, whose job is to erase people's identities and set them up with new ones. He is assigned to look after a witness who is testifying against a large weapons corporation who are selling weapons to overseas buyers instead of the United States. This corporation has a lot of people on the payroll, so Arnie is up against the entire government, including his mentor. What I really don't understand is why a company selling its product to an overseas buyer, even if it is state of the art weaponry, would be considered treason. I guess it has something to do with using America as a base to build weaponry which will be sold to people who will end up using them against America. As such I think it is fair enough for them to be screaming treason. In the end this movie is a patriotic catching the badguys and saving the motherland. In the end America is safe and everybody can continue on being Americans. Personally, this is not one of Arnie's best movies, and unfortunately, since Terminator II, his movies seem to be downgrading a bit. Still, when one considers this movie, it is really no different to movies like Running Man, Total Recall, and Predator. In the end we do not come to see this movie to be astounded by Arnie's acting ability, but rather to see action, and as an action movie, we get plenty of it, and as such it lives up to the standards of other Arnie action movies (including the pathetic one-liners).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Arnie, big guns, and crocodiles: highly enjoyable no-brain action nonsense.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BA_Harrison
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The plot for Eraser is riddled with more holes than one of its bad guys after Arnie has unloaded a clip or two into them, and the cartoonish violence is mightily dumb at times, but although this film is undeniably a step down from it's star's previous two action films (James Cameron's True Lies and T2), it still proves to be a very enjoyable piece of slam-bang popcorn nonsense. Directed by Chuck Russell, the man who gave us Dream Warriors (the best Elm Street movie), the excellent remake of The Blob, and the hilariously warped Jim Carrey vehicle The Mask, this movie is slick, mindless fun full of great stunts, impressive special effects, and highly-improbable-yet-still-awesomely-entertaining set-pieces. As U.S. Marshal John 'The Eraser' Kruger, whose job is to provide new identities for people in the Witness Protection scheme, Arnie is required to flex everything except his acting muscles, and does so with his usual aplomb, throwing his enemies through the air with ease, effortlessly toting two massive rail-guns to lay waste to everything in sight, and generally causing a whole lot of pain and destruction. Meanwhile, Vanessa Williams simply looks ravishing and vulnerable as 'woman in peril', whilst James Caan chews up the scenery as 'treacherous boss'. Of course, It's all gets very silly at times, particularly towards the end, our hero seemingly impervious to pain and capable of superhuman strength, the bad guys being impossibly Machiavellian, and the jingoism even going so far as to depict the Russian Mafia as evil incarnate but the US's very own Italian Mafia as a bunch of lovable jokers, but with Arnie squaring off against a jet aircraft, giant crocs rampaging through New York Zoo's reptile house, and a through the roof body count, this still qualifies as one of the star's more enjoyable efforts. 7.5 out or 10, rounded up to 8 for IMDb.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You're luggage......
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    U.S. Marshal deputy John Kruger is one of the toughest Marshals, his methods are to "Erase" The identities of his witnesses he is assigned to protect. A woman named Lee Cullen who works for a corporation named Cyrez performed an undercover job for the FBI to unveil a top secret weapon which uses an electromagnetic pulse to dispatch targets. Cyrez discovered this about Lee and are now out to kill her, Kruger's job is now to protect Lee so she can testify against Cyrez. But, when Kruger was assigned to perform a job with another Marshal named Robert Deguerin, he discovers that Deguerin is behind the plot that will involve the EM Gun. Which will change hands to a Russian criminal if Kruger does not stop them, Kruger must not only protect Lee's life but his own.... Let's face it, this was Arnies last big film where he didn't play a Terminator. Back in the day where he could command a summer movie and make it score big, Eraser is a typical eighties action film in the nineties, trying to be hi-tech, so when you watch it 15 years on, it looks terribly dated. Arnie is great as the line spouting Marshal who is assigned to protect Williams. But Caan steals the show as the villain, one of the most sinister villains Arnie has faced this side of Mars. The action is over the top, the effects by todays standard are very bad, and there are so many plot holes, that it defies belief. But then you saw this movie, and you read this, so you know what to expect. Arnie getting shot in the arm, pulling items out of him that have stabbed him, jumpimg out of a plane and killing Alligators. Silly stuff, but still as watchable as it was in 1996.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Huge fun
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Neil Welch
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This late period - by which I mean Schwarzenegger's late period - action romp stars Schwarzenegger as a specialist in making people disappear - erasing them - not by killing them, but by making it look as if they have died before setting them up with new identities. He is assigned to erase Vanessa Williams but it becomes clear that she is completely expendable in the course of a plot by (not very surprisingly) Schwarzenegger's line manager James Caan to sell super-guns to foreigners. The plot doesn't really matter - it is just a vehicle for the action sequences, but it is perfectly serviceable and quite entertaining. The action sequences, typically over the top, include some CGI crocodiles and Arnold holding onto the side of a jet airliner by his fingertips (I must confess that last one stretched my credulity a little). Schwarzenegger is, well, Schwarzenegger. Williams is a feisty damsel in distress. Caan is downright dastardly. But the film is utterly stolen by Robert Pastorelli as someone erased at the start of the movie, recalled towards the end to repay a favour. This one is big fun.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Action-Packed!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'Eraser', directed by Chuck Russell, is an Action-Packed Flick, that offers some truly entertaining sequences in the goings-on. An interesting premise gets it's due, and a really energetic Arnold Schwarzenegger, does the trick. 'Eraser' tells the story of A Top-Grade Witness Protection specialist, Played by Schwarzenegger, who, becomes suspicious of his co-workers when dealing with a case involving high-tech weapons. Screenplay by Tony Puryear and Walon Green, is interesting and is aimed completely for the Masses. This Box Office Hit is meant for those who enjoy and relish Action-Flicks, that offer super stunts and sudden twists and turns. This entertainer is not meant for the pseudo critics! Chuck Russell's Direction is good, while the Stunts are applaud-worthy. Cinematography by Adam Greenberg, is passable. Editing is fair. Performance-Wise: As mentioned, Schwarzenegger is highly energetic in the central role. James Caan looks each bit of the character and is perfect, as always. Vanessa L. Williams is fairly good. James Coburn gets less scope, while Robert Pastorelli shines. Others lend good support. On the whole, An interesting action-flick, that has potential. Watch It!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of Arnie's best
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ebiros2
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    With 20 years of acting experience under his belt, Arnold has become a really good actor, and it shows in this movie. This movie was made when he was in his prime, and is one of the best movie he's done to this date. John Kruger (Arnold Schwarzenegger) is a US marshal who's task is to "erase" the identity of government witnesses under witness protection program. He's assigned to protect Lee Cullin (Vanessa Williams) who has the information to expose that her employer Cyrez Corporation is attempting to covertly smuggle rail gun rifles to international arms dealer. The master mind of this deal includes Kruger's associate Deguerin (James Khaan). Deguerin wants Cullin dead, and the only thing standing between them is Kruger. The quality of production and acting is extremely good in this movie. Arnie and Williams delivers great acting working as a team. Cinematography is beautiful, and special effects are also great. Everything comes together in this movie, making it one of Arnold's best movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Arnold Erases
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Arnold Schwarzenegger plays U.S. Marshal John 'The Eraser' Kruger, a specialist in the witness protection program who is assigned to protect Lee Cullen(Vanessa Williams) who had uncovered shady dealings at a military weapons manufacturer that she had worked for. The company now wants her dead, so John takes Lee to New York City with the help of his friend, fellow U.S. Marshal Robert Guerin(played by James Caan) Unfortunately, someone in the program has betrayed them, and now John and Lee must go on the run from both forces in order to expose the true villains, and save their lives. Pretty good Arnold S. film has lots of exciting action scenes, and an appealing cast of characters. Film has a predictable plot though, and stretches credibility at times, but is mostly entertaining.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Those things on the end of pencils.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Shawn Watson (gator_macready@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The 2-year gap between True Lies and Eraser forced some action fans into thinking that Big Arn had retired. He had delivered at least one action movie per year since Terminator. Eraser had an awesome trailer, to the tune of Enigma's wonderful "I Love You, I'll Kill You", that rocked my world in the summer of 1996. I saw virtually every blockbuster that year, and the Eraser trailer was attached to every one of them. It came out out in the UK in the very last week of summer (and my first week back at school). I saw it at the now demolished UCI cinema in Edinburgh with a sold-out audience, mostly filled with guys out for a "lad's night". The movie was rated 18, and even though I was 3 years below that mark, I still got in, which was fortunate since the cinema version is the only uncut version of the film that has ever been released in the UK. For its VHS and DVD release the mad BBFC saw fit to cut 4 minutes from Eraser, turning it into an incomprehensible mess. It capped-off an awesome summer season (or so my 15-year-old self thought), and put to rest any fears that Big Arn was slowing down (although he has only made 5 action movies, to date, since then). Arn is John Kruger (an amusing choice of name since director Chuck Russell also made the 3rd Nightmare on Elm Street Movie), a Witness Protection Program Agent who is tasked with 'erasing' and protecting a high-level informant who can prove that there are traitors within the US government who are selling weapons to Russian terrorists. Naturally the informant is the lovely, and wide-eyed, Vanessa Williams, who involves herself in a subdued romantic subplot with Kruger. James Caan and the always great James Coburn provide respectable support as Kruger's antagonist and mentor, but the best support is no doubt Robert Pastorelli (an actor who I really liked who died of a heroin overdose in 2004), who plays a previous witness who is eager to please Kruger in his latest, impossible quest. Overall, it's hardly revolutionary, but what makes Eraser stand out from the crowd is the utterly breathtaking (literally) scene in which Kruger escapes a jet, mid-flight, without the comfort of a parachute on his shoulders. It's definitely one of the best action scenes in the last 20 years and, let me tell you, when that scene climaxed in the cinema, the packed audience of 'lads' totally sucked the air out of the auditorium. A massively exciting, and completely exhilarating, scene that never fails to get your heart racing. Alan Silvestri's score is one of the film's more underrated features. Silvestri scored Big Arn's Predator, a famous score in its own right, and while Eraser is not as famous as Predator you should not rule out the integrity of the score. When separated from the movie it is still one of Silvestri's best efforts. I guess the only complaint I could have about Eraser is that it's kinda anti-climatic. The best scene occurs at the end of the second act, leaving the final act pale in comparison. There's no iconic imagery to the film and it seems kinda forgettable when compared to other Arn characters who have endured the test of time. Nonetheless, it's at the top of the bottom of Arn's best movies, but make sure you the version you watch has not been butchered by the BBFC. The Blu Ray is in 2.40:1 1080p with Dolby TrueHD sound. Extras are non-existent.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The beginning of the Arnie-end. More fun for his butchering of the English language.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    oneguyrambling
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Arnie's career was really losing steam by the time Eraser came around. After all he'd played every role that suited him, often multiple times. The robot. The soldier. The cop. The special agent. The ummm barbarian. And believe it or not, as IMDb is my witness, he played ALL of those characters more than once by this time, the only difference sometimes being the Eastern European country he was supposed to have come from. So by this stage Schwarzenegger was sorta grasping at straws, the result often being awful and often recycled projects that played with his image and in desperation introduced more and more illogical and ridiculous hooks and sequences. Take Eraser, where the bad guys have heat detecting scopes on their RAY GUNS(!) that go bing-bing-bing and cut through anything in their path, and Arnie gets to kill a 90s style CGI alligator and after consigning it to its fate declares it 'luggage'. (You know what? That bit still makes me laugh.) Arnie plays John Kruger, a guy who doesn't officially exist, whose specialty is making it look like people in need of protection don't exist to keep them safe from various nefarious high-ups and/or low lives. Hence the 'erasing' reference of the title, he erases them from being mostly without even killing them! This time however the case is a young employee who is a key witness against a Big (evil) Corporation that is illegally making the naughty bing-bing-bing weapons. Eraser actually sports a fairly string cast of mainly James'; Coburn, Caan and Cromwell all get turns at being bad guys or Arnie's superiors or both. And Vanessa Williams is the damsel in distress in need of the protection only Arnie's big gun could give. The rest of the film is a series of carefully conceived yet palpably ridiculous action setpieces that are technically proficient but lack any sense of true action goodness. The plane escape sequence is fine, the zoo chase scene OK (featuring the afore-mentioned luggage) and the finale at the docks gives Arnie the chance to wield the big guns for himself. Two of them actually. But aside from these moments Eraser marks the point in Arnie's career where the enjoyment was primarily derived from mocking his butchering of the English language. To that point this was merely an added bonus in between the action. I think the scriptwriters spent more time coming up with short dialogue snippets that would sound funnier coming out of Arnie's lips  which is almost everything really  my favourite here was how he managed to turn the 4 syllables of "I work alone" into about 17 I wanted to like Eraser, and as a guilty 2 hour throwaway it served its purpose I guess. But after the 80s and 90s spoiled us (and Arnie) by casting him as super-soldiers, FBI/KGB agents and Terminators it just seems like after a decade of Coke you are forced to switch to Royal Cola for eternity. Sure it's still cola, but Final Rating  5.5 / 10. Need more evidence that this was the beginning of the end? Arnie's 5 films after Eraser: Jingle all the Way, Batman & Robin, End of Days, The 6th Day and Collateral Damage. I might argue that this was his last vaguely average film if I could summon the energy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "We're way beyond bullsh*t here."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ben Larson
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    With an Oscar nomination for sound effects an award for music, this is no B-movie. It is Schwarzenegger in one of his best film roles. He has a superb backup cast with Vanessa L. Williams, James Caan, and Robert Pastorelli. The excitement never stops with fantastic weaponry and a really great shootout in the zoo. Of course, you have to ignore the fact that Arnie manages to perform feats of magic with a shattered shoulder bone and an injured hand. He can do anything through the pain apparently. But the airplane scene makes it all worthwhile. More than a guilty pleasure, this is truly a movie worth watching over and over.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Arnie vs the weapons manufacturer
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What can I say about this movie other than it is another pointless Arnie action flick. Personally I enjoy the mindless Arnie action flicks, just as my friend enjoys wrestling. Unfortunately he cannot understand why somebody hates something that he loves and loves something that he hates. If one disagrees with him then we are the ones that have the problem. So much for opinions. Anyway, this movie is about a agent working for the witness protection program, whose job is to erase people's identities and set them up with new ones. He is assigned to look after a witness who is testifying against a large weapons corporation who are selling weapons to overseas buyers instead of the United States. This corporation has a lot of people on the payroll, so Arnie is up against the entire government, including his mentor. What I really don't understand is why a company selling its product to an overseas buyer, even if it is state of the art weaponry, would be considered treason. I guess it has something to do with using America as a base to build weaponry which will be sold to people who will end up using them against America. As such I think it is fair enough for them to be screaming treason. In the end this movie is a patriotic catching the badguys and saving the motherland. In the end America is safe and everybody can continue on being Americans. Personally, this is not one of Arnie's best movies, and unfortunately, since Terminator II, his movies seem to be downgrading a bit. Still, when one considers this movie, it is really no different to movies like Running Man, Total Recall, and Predator. In the end we do not come to see this movie to be astounded by Arnie's acting ability, but rather to see action, and as an action movie, we get plenty of it, and as such it lives up to the standards of other Arnie action movies (including the pathetic one-liners).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Arnie, big guns, and crocodiles: highly enjoyable no-brain action nonsense.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BA_Harrison
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The plot for Eraser is riddled with more holes than one of its bad guys after Arnie has unloaded a clip or two into them, and the cartoonish violence is mightily dumb at times, but although this film is undeniably a step down from it's star's previous two action films (James Cameron's True Lies and T2), it still proves to be a very enjoyable piece of slam-bang popcorn nonsense. Directed by Chuck Russell, the man who gave us Dream Warriors (the best Elm Street movie), the excellent remake of The Blob, and the hilariously warped Jim Carrey vehicle The Mask, this movie is slick, mindless fun full of great stunts, impressive special effects, and highly-improbable-yet-still-awesomely-entertaining set-pieces. As U.S. Marshal John 'The Eraser' Kruger, whose job is to provide new identities for people in the Witness Protection scheme, Arnie is required to flex everything except his acting muscles, and does so with his usual aplomb, throwing his enemies through the air with ease, effortlessly toting two massive rail-guns to lay waste to everything in sight, and generally causing a whole lot of pain and destruction. Meanwhile, Vanessa Williams simply looks ravishing and vulnerable as 'woman in peril', whilst James Caan chews up the scenery as 'treacherous boss'. Of course, It's all gets very silly at times, particularly towards the end, our hero seemingly impervious to pain and capable of superhuman strength, the bad guys being impossibly Machiavellian, and the jingoism even going so far as to depict the Russian Mafia as evil incarnate but the US's very own Italian Mafia as a bunch of lovable jokers, but with Arnie squaring off against a jet aircraft, giant crocs rampaging through New York Zoo's reptile house, and a through the roof body count, this still qualifies as one of the star's more enjoyable efforts. 7.5 out or 10, rounded up to 8 for IMDb.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You're luggage......
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    U.S. Marshal deputy John Kruger is one of the toughest Marshals, his methods are to "Erase" The identities of his witnesses he is assigned to protect. A woman named Lee Cullen who works for a corporation named Cyrez performed an undercover job for the FBI to unveil a top secret weapon which uses an electromagnetic pulse to dispatch targets. Cyrez discovered this about Lee and are now out to kill her, Kruger's job is now to protect Lee so she can testify against Cyrez. But, when Kruger was assigned to perform a job with another Marshal named Robert Deguerin, he discovers that Deguerin is behind the plot that will involve the EM Gun. Which will change hands to a Russian criminal if Kruger does not stop them, Kruger must not only protect Lee's life but his own.... Let's face it, this was Arnies last big film where he didn't play a Terminator. Back in the day where he could command a summer movie and make it score big, Eraser is a typical eighties action film in the nineties, trying to be hi-tech, so when you watch it 15 years on, it looks terribly dated. Arnie is great as the line spouting Marshal who is assigned to protect Williams. But Caan steals the show as the villain, one of the most sinister villains Arnie has faced this side of Mars. The action is over the top, the effects by todays standard are very bad, and there are so many plot holes, that it defies belief. But then you saw this movie, and you read this, so you know what to expect. Arnie getting shot in the arm, pulling items out of him that have stabbed him, jumpimg out of a plane and killing Alligators. Silly stuff, but still as watchable as it was in 1996.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Huge fun
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Neil Welch
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This late period - by which I mean Schwarzenegger's late period - action romp stars Schwarzenegger as a specialist in making people disappear - erasing them - not by killing them, but by making it look as if they have died before setting them up with new identities. He is assigned to erase Vanessa Williams but it becomes clear that she is completely expendable in the course of a plot by (not very surprisingly) Schwarzenegger's line manager James Caan to sell super-guns to foreigners. The plot doesn't really matter - it is just a vehicle for the action sequences, but it is perfectly serviceable and quite entertaining. The action sequences, typically over the top, include some CGI crocodiles and Arnold holding onto the side of a jet airliner by his fingertips (I must confess that last one stretched my credulity a little). Schwarzenegger is, well, Schwarzenegger. Williams is a feisty damsel in distress. Caan is downright dastardly. But the film is utterly stolen by Robert Pastorelli as someone erased at the start of the movie, recalled towards the end to repay a favour. This one is big fun.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Action-Packed!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'Eraser', directed by Chuck Russell, is an Action-Packed Flick, that offers some truly entertaining sequences in the goings-on. An interesting premise gets it's due, and a really energetic Arnold Schwarzenegger, does the trick. 'Eraser' tells the story of A Top-Grade Witness Protection specialist, Played by Schwarzenegger, who, becomes suspicious of his co-workers when dealing with a case involving high-tech weapons. Screenplay by Tony Puryear and Walon Green, is interesting and is aimed completely for the Masses. This Box Office Hit is meant for those who enjoy and relish Action-Flicks, that offer super stunts and sudden twists and turns. This entertainer is not meant for the pseudo critics! Chuck Russell's Direction is good, while the Stunts are applaud-worthy. Cinematography by Adam Greenberg, is passable. Editing is fair. Performance-Wise: As mentioned, Schwarzenegger is highly energetic in the central role. James Caan looks each bit of the character and is perfect, as always. Vanessa L. Williams is fairly good. James Coburn gets less scope, while Robert Pastorelli shines. Others lend good support. On the whole, An interesting action-flick, that has potential. Watch It!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of Arnie's best
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ebiros2
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    With 20 years of acting experience under his belt, Arnold has become a really good actor, and it shows in this movie. This movie was made when he was in his prime, and is one of the best movie he's done to this date. John Kruger (Arnold Schwarzenegger) is a US marshal who's task is to "erase" the identity of government witnesses under witness protection program. He's assigned to protect Lee Cullin (Vanessa Williams) who has the information to expose that her employer Cyrez Corporation is attempting to covertly smuggle rail gun rifles to international arms dealer. The master mind of this deal includes Kruger's associate Deguerin (James Khaan). Deguerin wants Cullin dead, and the only thing standing between them is Kruger. The quality of production and acting is extremely good in this movie. Arnie and Williams delivers great acting working as a team. Cinematography is beautiful, and special effects are also great. Everything comes together in this movie, making it one of Arnold's best movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Arnold Erases
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Arnold Schwarzenegger plays U.S. Marshal John 'The Eraser' Kruger, a specialist in the witness protection program who is assigned to protect Lee Cullen(Vanessa Williams) who had uncovered shady dealings at a military weapons manufacturer that she had worked for. The company now wants her dead, so John takes Lee to New York City with the help of his friend, fellow U.S. Marshal Robert Guerin(played by James Caan) Unfortunately, someone in the program has betrayed them, and now John and Lee must go on the run from both forces in order to expose the true villains, and save their lives. Pretty good Arnold S. film has lots of exciting action scenes, and an appealing cast of characters. Film has a predictable plot though, and stretches credibility at times, but is mostly entertaining.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Those things on the end of pencils.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Shawn Watson (gator_macready@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The 2-year gap between True Lies and Eraser forced some action fans into thinking that Big Arn had retired. He had delivered at least one action movie per year since Terminator. Eraser had an awesome trailer, to the tune of Enigma's wonderful "I Love You, I'll Kill You", that rocked my world in the summer of 1996. I saw virtually every blockbuster that year, and the Eraser trailer was attached to every one of them. It came out out in the UK in the very last week of summer (and my first week back at school). I saw it at the now demolished UCI cinema in Edinburgh with a sold-out audience, mostly filled with guys out for a "lad's night". The movie was rated 18, and even though I was 3 years below that mark, I still got in, which was fortunate since the cinema version is the only uncut version of the film that has ever been released in the UK. For its VHS and DVD release the mad BBFC saw fit to cut 4 minutes from Eraser, turning it into an incomprehensible mess. It capped-off an awesome summer season (or so my 15-year-old self thought), and put to rest any fears that Big Arn was slowing down (although he has only made 5 action movies, to date, since then). Arn is John Kruger (an amusing choice of name since director Chuck Russell also made the 3rd Nightmare on Elm Street Movie), a Witness Protection Program Agent who is tasked with 'erasing' and protecting a high-level informant who can prove that there are traitors within the US government who are selling weapons to Russian terrorists. Naturally the informant is the lovely, and wide-eyed, Vanessa Williams, who involves herself in a subdued romantic subplot with Kruger. James Caan and the always great James Coburn provide respectable support as Kruger's antagonist and mentor, but the best support is no doubt Robert Pastorelli (an actor who I really liked who died of a heroin overdose in 2004), who plays a previous witness who is eager to please Kruger in his latest, impossible quest. Overall, it's hardly revolutionary, but what makes Eraser stand out from the crowd is the utterly breathtaking (literally) scene in which Kruger escapes a jet, mid-flight, without the comfort of a parachute on his shoulders. It's definitely one of the best action scenes in the last 20 years and, let me tell you, when that scene climaxed in the cinema, the packed audience of 'lads' totally sucked the air out of the auditorium. A massively exciting, and completely exhilarating, scene that never fails to get your heart racing. Alan Silvestri's score is one of the film's more underrated features. Silvestri scored Big Arn's Predator, a famous score in its own right, and while Eraser is not as famous as Predator you should not rule out the integrity of the score. When separated from the movie it is still one of Silvestri's best efforts. I guess the only complaint I could have about Eraser is that it's kinda anti-climatic. The best scene occurs at the end of the second act, leaving the final act pale in comparison. There's no iconic imagery to the film and it seems kinda forgettable when compared to other Arn characters who have endured the test of time. Nonetheless, it's at the top of the bottom of Arn's best movies, but make sure you the version you watch has not been butchered by the BBFC. The Blu Ray is in 2.40:1 1080p with Dolby TrueHD sound. Extras are non-existent.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The beginning of the Arnie-end. More fun for his butchering of the English language.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    oneguyrambling
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Arnie's career was really losing steam by the time Eraser came around. After all he'd played every role that suited him, often multiple times. The robot. The soldier. The cop. The special agent. The ummm barbarian. And believe it or not, as IMDb is my witness, he played ALL of those characters more than once by this time, the only difference sometimes being the Eastern European country he was supposed to have come from. So by this stage Schwarzenegger was sorta grasping at straws, the result often being awful and often recycled projects that played with his image and in desperation introduced more and more illogical and ridiculous hooks and sequences. Take Eraser, where the bad guys have heat detecting scopes on their RAY GUNS(!) that go bing-bing-bing and cut through anything in their path, and Arnie gets to kill a 90s style CGI alligator and after consigning it to its fate declares it 'luggage'. (You know what? That bit still makes me laugh.) Arnie plays John Kruger, a guy who doesn't officially exist, whose specialty is making it look like people in need of protection don't exist to keep them safe from various nefarious high-ups and/or low lives. Hence the 'erasing' reference of the title, he erases them from being mostly without even killing them! This time however the case is a young employee who is a key witness against a Big (evil) Corporation that is illegally making the naughty bing-bing-bing weapons. Eraser actually sports a fairly string cast of mainly James'; Coburn, Caan and Cromwell all get turns at being bad guys or Arnie's superiors or both. And Vanessa Williams is the damsel in distress in need of the protection only Arnie's big gun could give. The rest of the film is a series of carefully conceived yet palpably ridiculous action setpieces that are technically proficient but lack any sense of true action goodness. The plane escape sequence is fine, the zoo chase scene OK (featuring the afore-mentioned luggage) and the finale at the docks gives Arnie the chance to wield the big guns for himself. Two of them actually. But aside from these moments Eraser marks the point in Arnie's career where the enjoyment was primarily derived from mocking his butchering of the English language. To that point this was merely an added bonus in between the action. I think the scriptwriters spent more time coming up with short dialogue snippets that would sound funnier coming out of Arnie's lips  which is almost everything really  my favourite here was how he managed to turn the 4 syllables of "I work alone" into about 17 I wanted to like Eraser, and as a guilty 2 hour throwaway it served its purpose I guess. But after the 80s and 90s spoiled us (and Arnie) by casting him as super-soldiers, FBI/KGB agents and Terminators it just seems like after a decade of Coke you are forced to switch to Royal Cola for eternity. Sure it's still cola, but Final Rating  5.5 / 10. Need more evidence that this was the beginning of the end? Arnie's 5 films after Eraser: Jingle all the Way, Batman & Robin, End of Days, The 6th Day and Collateral Damage. I might argue that this was his last vaguely average film if I could summon the energy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "We're way beyond bullsh*t here."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ben Larson
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    With an Oscar nomination for sound effects an award for music, this is no B-movie. It is Schwarzenegger in one of his best film roles. He has a superb backup cast with Vanessa L. Williams, James Caan, and Robert Pastorelli. The excitement never stops with fantastic weaponry and a really great shootout in the zoo. Of course, you have to ignore the fact that Arnie manages to perform feats of magic with a shattered shoulder bone and an injured hand. He can do anything through the pain apparently. But the airplane scene makes it all worthwhile. More than a guilty pleasure, this is truly a movie worth watching over and over.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Arnie vs the weapons manufacturer
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What can I say about this movie other than it is another pointless Arnie action flick. Personally I enjoy the mindless Arnie action flicks, just as my friend enjoys wrestling. Unfortunately he cannot understand why somebody hates something that he loves and loves something that he hates. If one disagrees with him then we are the ones that have the problem. So much for opinions. Anyway, this movie is about a agent working for the witness protection program, whose job is to erase people's identities and set them up with new ones. He is assigned to look after a witness who is testifying against a large weapons corporation who are selling weapons to overseas buyers instead of the United States. This corporation has a lot of people on the payroll, so Arnie is up against the entire government, including his mentor. What I really don't understand is why a company selling its product to an overseas buyer, even if it is state of the art weaponry, would be considered treason. I guess it has something to do with using America as a base to build weaponry which will be sold to people who will end up using them against America. As such I think it is fair enough for them to be screaming treason. In the end this movie is a patriotic catching the badguys and saving the motherland. In the end America is safe and everybody can continue on being Americans. Personally, this is not one of Arnie's best movies, and unfortunately, since Terminator II, his movies seem to be downgrading a bit. Still, when one considers this movie, it is really no different to movies like Running Man, Total Recall, and Predator. In the end we do not come to see this movie to be astounded by Arnie's acting ability, but rather to see action, and as an action movie, we get plenty of it, and as such it lives up to the standards of other Arnie action movies (including the pathetic one-liners).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Arnie, big guns, and crocodiles: highly enjoyable no-brain action nonsense.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BA_Harrison
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The plot for Eraser is riddled with more holes than one of its bad guys after Arnie has unloaded a clip or two into them, and the cartoonish violence is mightily dumb at times, but although this film is undeniably a step down from it's star's previous two action films (James Cameron's True Lies and T2), it still proves to be a very enjoyable piece of slam-bang popcorn nonsense. Directed by Chuck Russell, the man who gave us Dream Warriors (the best Elm Street movie), the excellent remake of The Blob, and the hilariously warped Jim Carrey vehicle The Mask, this movie is slick, mindless fun full of great stunts, impressive special effects, and highly-improbable-yet-still-awesomely-entertaining set-pieces. As U.S. Marshal John 'The Eraser' Kruger, whose job is to provide new identities for people in the Witness Protection scheme, Arnie is required to flex everything except his acting muscles, and does so with his usual aplomb, throwing his enemies through the air with ease, effortlessly toting two massive rail-guns to lay waste to everything in sight, and generally causing a whole lot of pain and destruction. Meanwhile, Vanessa Williams simply looks ravishing and vulnerable as 'woman in peril', whilst James Caan chews up the scenery as 'treacherous boss'. Of course, It's all gets very silly at times, particularly towards the end, our hero seemingly impervious to pain and capable of superhuman strength, the bad guys being impossibly Machiavellian, and the jingoism even going so far as to depict the Russian Mafia as evil incarnate but the US's very own Italian Mafia as a bunch of lovable jokers, but with Arnie squaring off against a jet aircraft, giant crocs rampaging through New York Zoo's reptile house, and a through the roof body count, this still qualifies as one of the star's more enjoyable efforts. 7.5 out or 10, rounded up to 8 for IMDb.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You're luggage......
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FlashCallahan
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    U.S. Marshal deputy John Kruger is one of the toughest Marshals, his methods are to "Erase" The identities of his witnesses he is assigned to protect. A woman named Lee Cullen who works for a corporation named Cyrez performed an undercover job for the FBI to unveil a top secret weapon which uses an electromagnetic pulse to dispatch targets. Cyrez discovered this about Lee and are now out to kill her, Kruger's job is now to protect Lee so she can testify against Cyrez. But, when Kruger was assigned to perform a job with another Marshal named Robert Deguerin, he discovers that Deguerin is behind the plot that will involve the EM Gun. Which will change hands to a Russian criminal if Kruger does not stop them, Kruger must not only protect Lee's life but his own.... Let's face it, this was Arnies last big film where he didn't play a Terminator. Back in the day where he could command a summer movie and make it score big, Eraser is a typical eighties action film in the nineties, trying to be hi-tech, so when you watch it 15 years on, it looks terribly dated. Arnie is great as the line spouting Marshal who is assigned to protect Williams. But Caan steals the show as the villain, one of the most sinister villains Arnie has faced this side of Mars. The action is over the top, the effects by todays standard are very bad, and there are so many plot holes, that it defies belief. But then you saw this movie, and you read this, so you know what to expect. Arnie getting shot in the arm, pulling items out of him that have stabbed him, jumpimg out of a plane and killing Alligators. Silly stuff, but still as watchable as it was in 1996.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Huge fun
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Neil Welch
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This late period - by which I mean Schwarzenegger's late period - action romp stars Schwarzenegger as a specialist in making people disappear - erasing them - not by killing them, but by making it look as if they have died before setting them up with new identities. He is assigned to erase Vanessa Williams but it becomes clear that she is completely expendable in the course of a plot by (not very surprisingly) Schwarzenegger's line manager James Caan to sell super-guns to foreigners. The plot doesn't really matter - it is just a vehicle for the action sequences, but it is perfectly serviceable and quite entertaining. The action sequences, typically over the top, include some CGI crocodiles and Arnold holding onto the side of a jet airliner by his fingertips (I must confess that last one stretched my credulity a little). Schwarzenegger is, well, Schwarzenegger. Williams is a feisty damsel in distress. Caan is downright dastardly. But the film is utterly stolen by Robert Pastorelli as someone erased at the start of the movie, recalled towards the end to repay a favour. This one is big fun.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Action-Packed!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'Eraser', directed by Chuck Russell, is an Action-Packed Flick, that offers some truly entertaining sequences in the goings-on. An interesting premise gets it's due, and a really energetic Arnold Schwarzenegger, does the trick. 'Eraser' tells the story of A Top-Grade Witness Protection specialist, Played by Schwarzenegger, who, becomes suspicious of his co-workers when dealing with a case involving high-tech weapons. Screenplay by Tony Puryear and Walon Green, is interesting and is aimed completely for the Masses. This Box Office Hit is meant for those who enjoy and relish Action-Flicks, that offer super stunts and sudden twists and turns. This entertainer is not meant for the pseudo critics! Chuck Russell's Direction is good, while the Stunts are applaud-worthy. Cinematography by Adam Greenberg, is passable. Editing is fair. Performance-Wise: As mentioned, Schwarzenegger is highly energetic in the central role. James Caan looks each bit of the character and is perfect, as always. Vanessa L. Williams is fairly good. James Coburn gets less scope, while Robert Pastorelli shines. Others lend good support. On the whole, An interesting action-flick, that has potential. Watch It!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of Arnie's best
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ebiros2
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    With 20 years of acting experience under his belt, Arnold has become a really good actor, and it shows in this movie. This movie was made when he was in his prime, and is one of the best movie he's done to this date. John Kruger (Arnold Schwarzenegger) is a US marshal who's task is to "erase" the identity of government witnesses under witness protection program. He's assigned to protect Lee Cullin (Vanessa Williams) who has the information to expose that her employer Cyrez Corporation is attempting to covertly smuggle rail gun rifles to international arms dealer. The master mind of this deal includes Kruger's associate Deguerin (James Khaan). Deguerin wants Cullin dead, and the only thing standing between them is Kruger. The quality of production and acting is extremely good in this movie. Arnie and Williams delivers great acting working as a team. Cinematography is beautiful, and special effects are also great. Everything comes together in this movie, making it one of Arnold's best movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
