<filme>
 <id>
  604
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0025316
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1934
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Aconteceu Naquela Noite
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  8.2
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  A spoiled heiress, running away from her family, is helped by a man who's actually a reporter looking for a story.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Ellie Andrews has just tied the knot with society aviator King Westley when she is whisked away to her father's yacht and out of King's clutches. Ellie jumps ship and eventually winds up on a bus headed back to her husband. Reluctantly she must accept the help of out-of- work reporter Peter Warne. Actually, Warne doesn't give her any choice: either she sticks with him until he gets her back to her husband, or he'll blow the whistle on Ellie to her father. Either way, Peter gets what (he thinks!) he wants .... a really juicy newspaper story.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Romance
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   bus
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   reporter
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   love
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   yacht
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   reward
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Frank Capra
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Robert Riskin
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Samuel Hopkins Adams
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Clark Gable
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Claudette Colbert
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Walter Connolly
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Interesting "Time Travel" to an era
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bob Pr.
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Background to that '30s era: this 1934 film is often called the first (of the many following) in the 'screwball comedy' genre; it came out in the worst of the Great Depression (US unemployment in 1928 was 2.9%, by 1933 it hit 25%; millions were hungry and desperate, leading to some antagonisms between economic classes). This was also a time when women's roles were changing in the US: the 'women's suffrage' movement gained women the right to vote in 1920 (19th Amendment), more equality in decision-making, more freedom in dress, gender & sexual roles (e.g., '20s 'Flappers'). "Screwball comedies" capitalized and fed on those changes: they typically "feature farcical situations, a combination of slap-stick with fast-paced repartee and show struggles between" (central characters of different) "economic classes. They also generally feature a self-confident and often stubborn central female protagonist and a plot involving courtship and marriage or remarriage" ("quotes" from Wikipedia). A young 30's Gable plays "Peter," a drinking, hard boiled newspaper reporter just fired from his job when he accidentally meets the young 20's "Ellie" (a young 30's Colbert) who's increasingly rebelled against the escalating but failing attempts of her upper class, super-rich father to control her. He tries to keep her on his Florida yacht while arranging to annul Ellie's impulsive marriage to a man (whom her father recognizes but Ellie doesn't as mainly interested in her wealth). But Ellie escapes her father's captivity and sets off to NYC to be reunited with her new spouse. On her way, she meets Gable who's initially interested in helping her because it'll lead to his scoop of a newspaper story (and reinstatement of his job). But then--romance eventually, gradually, starts to happen between you know who. My rating: 6 of 10 I found this interesting as a time-traveling experience--early '30s bus rides, clothes, roles, attitudes, etc.-- but all the people seemed to me to be too much caricatures and not enough real characters. (However, many people on IMDb's "Discussion Board" say the more often they've seen this film, the more highly they value it--many saying it's among their most favorite films of all--so maybe familiarity breeds appreciation?) FWIW: Neither Gable nor Colbert wanted to be in this film; MGM "loaned" them to Columbia Pictures, then a 2nd rate movie company, for this movie as punishment for each being too "uppity" and/or violating MGM policies. But, after this film gained such outstanding success (lifting Columbia's rank to among the majors) and substantially helped both Gable's & Colbert's careers, they came to appreciate it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Who would of thunk it !
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    traversvcs6
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you happen to own or rent this movie I'd suggest watching it a second time with the directors son's commentary during the picture. He gives such an inspiring outlook on just how remarkable this picture was having been made in limited limited time and budget. How under appreciated it was by the producers to make, how the main actors were more or less coerced into doing the picture. How it was first met with so so reviews by the sophisticated New York City audience. Yet it was made so across the US of A it was put in theaters and what do you know it remained there for a record number of weeks. The movie goers of the time enjoyed it so they went back to see it again bringing family and friends cause they knew they had seen something truly awesome. Come Oscar time it took the five biggies, Best Picture, Leading actor and actress, writer and director. A feat not repeated again until One Flew Over the Cuckoos Nest. Yes this is a gem and that it became so at such odds makes it more so and should be in every movie lover's library! I loved it :)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cute and delightful!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RyanCShowers
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of the most important Best Picture winners feels like one of the most unnecessary Best Picture winners by some. When one says "Best Picture Winner", you think the said film must meet a certain criteria, such as war drama or epic production value-centric story, that certifies it that prestigious title. It Happened One Night has neither of those, though it does achieve a wonderful romance brought to life by Clarke Gable and Claudette Colbert and contains a screenplay as fresh as the carrots Clarke Gable eats himself during the picture. Movies of the 1930s (and earlier) have reoccurring problems when they are put up to the task of competing with newer pictures using today's standards of film perfection: they lack the tight, technical exertion. The sound is often terrible, some dialogue may even be lost, the editing is probably loose, and the photography is assumably rugged from the restoration attempts by the studios. It Happened One Night falls prey to these shortcomings, but it's the film's only real flaw, and not a big one at that. It's still a fairly entertaining movie and the restoration is actually successful most of the times. I couldn't take my eyes of It Happened One Night! It's a delightful film that should not be missed by any generation. Before Pretty Woman and Annie Hall were "the" romantic comedies of their times, there was It Happened One Night. Most of the romantic comedy plot devices we've seen used repeatedly, originated here and were so accepted by audiences and writers that they have grown into clich&eacute;. Aside from that, It Happened One Night combines classic stories (poor little rich girl, desperate reporter, train rides, extramarital affairs) into one sublime, Hollywood picture. The thing to any successful romantic comedy, besides the script having more on its cutting board than what the average joe-blow can bring to the table, is its stars. Think about how successful those two rom-coms I mentioned earlier would have been without Julia Roberts and Richard Gere or Woody Allen and Diane Keaton? Not very. The leading couple not only has marvelous chemistry together, but they both have the bolts to screw in a great performances. Clarke Gable in particular shines. His movie-star presence and ability to flow with a picture and character are on full display here. Claudette Colbert produces first rate acting, as well. It Happened One Night is a greatly pleasing film. You'll watch it with a smile on your face. It's funny and contains one of the best movie romances out there, a relationship that starts out in hostility, evolves to friendship, and is overcome with the realization of love. It Happened One Night is cute and having inspired a whole genre of films ahead of its time. Rating: 10/10 Grade: A+
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Whimsical love story breaks all the rules about love between the classes
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lucie Uche
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    First ever winner of five Oscars in all major categories, Best Picture, Best Director, Best Actor, Best Actress and Best Screenplay, the 1934 movie It Happened One Night is a whimsical romantic tale of fortuitous love between a spoiled socialite Ellen Andrews played by Claudette Colbert and a cantankerous newspaper reporter Peter Warne played by Clark Gable. The slapstick comedy collaboration from director Frank Capra and writer Robert Riskin, still remains quintessential viewing because of its clever and amusing portrayal of the pursuit of happiness and fulfillment. Ellen, recently married to infamous pilot King Westley (Jameson Thomas) against her millionaire father (Walter Connolly)'s orders is now cooped up on a yacht against her will with her father so that he can decidedly change her mind and have her marriage to the apparent gold digging cad annulled. Defiant Ellen who believes she is in love wants no part of her father's plan for her jumps ship to shore and eventually finds herself on a bus bound for New York. Here she hopes to reunite with her husband and live happily ever after. On board the Greyhound bus she meets Peter, none the worse for wear and recently fired from his newspaper for being drunk on the job. So begins an unlikely series of dealings between the two that stem from them agreeing to help each other out for a price of sorts. Peter recognizing Ellen from newspaper headlines as the much talked about runaway heiress, agrees to help her get to New York while she in turn offers him exclusive rights to her story, his hope is to revamp his career. The journey is series of memorable, classic, comical, events that draw the two closer together. Peter never one to hold back on his opinion and ever nonchalant, often chastises "Brat" his nickname for Ellen, because of her bourgeois tendencies and take on life, whereas he is a down to earth working class man; depicted in sharp close up clarity, every handsome rugged feature proving to be aesthetically camera friendly always defining his cool no nonsense sensibility. The two collide, bicker and banter about everything. There's is not an apparent match made in heaven but their liaison becomes more meaningful the longer they spend together. Peter is assiduous in keeping his promise to Ellen; Ellen is just doe eyed and realizes she is in love with the brash outspoken journalist. A timeless feature that that suggests Ellen's beauty and fragility is achieved with the application of a filtered lens on all of her close ups; this very effective application implies a softness and purity to her character. A notable fact about this seminal movie is the precedent it set for zany romantic comedies that would follow, such as Bringing up Baby (1938) and the Philadelphia Story (1940) both starring Katherine Hepburn and the impact it still has on screwball comedies today.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An antidote for depression
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Hotwok2013
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It isn't any wonder why "It Happened One Night" struck such a chord with movie-goers in the depression-hit USA of the 1930's. Frank Capra's sparkling romantic comedy is just about as uplifting as any movie possibly can be. Whatever it is that makes a star a star, Clark Gable had it in spades more than any other leading man before or since, & how could Claudette Colbert, (or any other woman?), not fall in love with him. Even allowing for the absurdities in the plot beginning with Ellie Andrews (Colbert) jumping her rich fathers yacht into the sea & swimming to shore. She is wearing a long white silk gown & not carrying a handbag. Next we see her at Miami bus station purchasing a ticket to New York in a new outfit with handbag!. The movie is full of memorably entertaining scenes & I guarantee that if anyone is feeling a bit low this film will improve their mood.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Romantic Comedy Supreme.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SmileysWorld
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Boy meets girl.They come from different roads in life and don't see eye to eye at first,but gradually they fall in love.This is a theme we have seen again and again throughout cinema history.Sometimes it is done well and sometimes..not so much.This is definitely the film that started it all,and the mold was broken.This is by far the best romantic comedy that I have ever seen.Claudette Colbert may not have thought so,for it has been said that she said to a friend after completing production that she had just finished "the worst film I have ever done."Surely she changed her tone when they placed the Best Actress Oscar in her hands.The screen chemistry between Colbert and Gable was right on the money.It is THE laugh out loud romantic classic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Young people in love are never hu-un-gry!" The granddaddy of all rom-coms
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    LouE15
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I stumbled across this film recently, expecting it to do no more than help me kill some time. Several viewings on, I'm hooked  it seems almost incredible that it was made in 1934, not 1984 or 2004. There isn't a romantic comedy in existence, and never will be, that doesn't owe a debt to this film. It's funny, modern, charming, and meaningful about people  what more do you want? Colour? Ah, nuts. Clark Gable plays Peter, a cynical journalist who ends up on a road trip across a Depression-hit USA with runaway heiress Ellen (Claudette Colbert). Ellen's sheltered life has done nothing to prepare her for the trials that lie ahead. She's so certain that she knows what she wants, and what's best: she's naive, but sparky and intelligent. She has to be knocked down in order to have her eyes peeled open. * Some spoilers from here* I thought I knew all about Clark Gable, and wasn't that bothered, but here he radiates masterful alpha-male charm and can switch on a dime from comedy to a love scene, boyish vulnerability to hardboiled cynic and back again. I don't know which version of him I liked more, although I think my favourite mini-moment comes when he's hardboiling it for the telegram girl, pipe in mouth - Philip Marlowe if ever there was one. The script is full of wonderful details  I don't know how much was in the original short story but I get the impression a great deal must have been added in to make it funnier. Oh, let me count the ways her not understanding what a real piggy back ride ishis hilariously terrible attempts at hitchhikingMr Believe You Me...Peter's "shut up" when they're back on the bus (which brings to mind James Cagney and That Grapefruit)and then his petulant sulk when he realises he's losing the upper hand, falling in love and just a shade jealousit's all great. I was hysterical by the time we met the operatic buggy driver  ever since I first saw the film I've been turning everyday trivialities into Gilbert & Sullivan libretto  and I just loved Peter's shouty conversation with Ellen's dad. But best of all are the lessons Ellen has to learn. For all her wealth and snobbery, and for all we enjoy her gradual comeuppance, she shows she's capable of learning (finally being hungry enough to eat a raw carrot!), and is worthy of Peter's love. When, near the end, she's weepily describing to her father how poor Peter's opinion is of them both ("you should hear what he says about you!"), capping it off with "he's marvellous(sob)", you're right there with her. "It happened one night" is in danger of eclipsing William Powell's wonderful "My Man Gordon" as my favourite thirties film. It's revised my lazy opinion about Clark Gable too  but it won't make me like "Gone with the Wind" any better, I don't care what anyone says.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Part one of two. My introduction of IHON, the background story on Capra's 1st miracle film.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Larry41OnEbay-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The idea for IT HAPPENED ONE NIGHT started in a barber shop while Frank Capra was waiting for a haircut he read an old magazine article in Cosmopolitan called "Night Bus" by Samuel Hopkins Adams. It was a cute idea so Capra asked Columbia studios to buy the rights to it and then he forgot about it. Frank's previous feature was LADY FOR A DAY which got great reviews and was Columbia studio's first film ever Oscar nominated and Capra's. Irving Thalberg wanted Capra to make his next film at MGM in exchange for $50k and the loan of a star. But at the last minute Louis B. Mayer canceled the film but honored the deal. Back at Columbia Capra wanted to make Night Bus, but studio tyrant Harry Cohn and all his advisers fought against it. They said things like, "It's nothing; froth, trivia, just another bus picture, no suspense, no heart, no oomph, winter's coming and it's all exteriors." All they could get Capra to do was change the title to IT HAPPENED ONE NIGHT which they said was too long to fit on a marquee! Capra tried casting Myrna Loy  she turned it down; then Margaret Sullavan  said 'no thank you'; Miriam Hopkins was insulted and said, 'Not if I never play another part'; Constance Bennett told him to go fly a kite and then offered to buy the script and have it rewritten for her! Capra had co-written the script with his favorite writer Robert Riskin but they brought in Myles Connolly who added more sympathetic and interesting characters so people could identify with them. The pretty girl, a spoiled brat, was rich yes but bored with being an heiress now wanting something real. The man was made a guy we all know and like; a tough crusading reporter on the outs with his pigheaded editor. It's The Taming Of The Shrew, but the shrew must be worth taming and the guy must be one of us. Back to casting, this time they went after Robert Montgomery a great light comedian at MGM. Mayer called Cohn and said, "Montgomery says there are too many bus pictures and (don't take this in the wrong way) but going from MGM to lowly Columbia was an insult. But you've caught me in a good mood. I got an actor here who's been a bad boy. Wants more money. And I'd like to spank him. You can have Clark Gable." Surprisingly the next knock on Capra's shabby office door came from a very drunk and cursing Gable, reporting to Siberia as he called it. Gable's objections almost made Capra throw in the towel but then Harry Cohn suggested getting Claudette Colbert for the girl in the story. (He had heard she liked money.) So Capra and Riskin made an appointment that very night to see her at her home. When they arrived Colbert regretted agreeing to the meeting as she was packing to leave on a month long skiing vacation. Capra saw this attractive, wealthy and spoiled woman and knew she was perfect for the part. So Capra, after being bit in the butt by her dog, asked what it would take to get her in the picture. (Capra had directed her first picture, FOR THE LOVE OF MIKE a silent made in 1927 and a flop) To throw him off she said she normally made $25k a picture (a price Columbia had never paid to an actor before), he would have to double it AND she was only available from her studio Paramount during her Christmas vacation. They would have to shoot all her scenes and retakes in less than 4 weeks -- half the time they had budgeted! So Capra called Cohn to ask would he pay her the $50k, Cohn said "I can pay it if you can shoot it in 4 weeks." Capra said, he didn't know, but he'd try. So they told her, "Deal, Claudette! $50k for 4 weeks! Okay?" To which she replied, "Oh for God's sake!" She was trapped. That next day she had to report for her costume fittings and the day after that they begin filming in a hurry. While they shot film all day Capra edited and rewrote the story to tighten it up at night. To make the film and story move quicker he asked the actors to talk faster, his amazing cinematographer Joseph Walker to shoot faster. (continued...)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    wonder why they called it, it happened one night
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lagudafuad
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It Happened One Night is one of the only three movies since the commencement of the Academy Awards to have been able to win all five major Academy Awards (Best Picture, Best Director, Best Actor, Best Actress, and Best Screenplay), a feat that would not be matched until One Flew Over the Cuckoo's Nest in 1975 and of cause latter on in 1991, Anthony Hopkins The Silence of the Lambs followed suit. Here is a romantic comedy as raw as they come giving you a thrill as you watch two people miss matched from the start found a way to fall in love and tour America on their way to New York. The funny thing about the movie is the name which says, "It happened one night" when actually in the movie's story it actually went on for more than a night. The movie plot is about Ellie Andrews (Claudette Colbert) who has been whisked away by her father in his yacht to keep her away from her new husband King Westley. Ellie then jumps ship, swim to shore and heads off to New York to meet with King Westley. On her way she meets a reporter Peter Warne (Clark Gable) and both started as an unsuitable pair that grew to be lovers. Both Colbert and Gable felt the movie was not going to be good enough and gave Capra a lot of bull. Even the movie's iconic scene where Colbert lifted up her skirt to stop a car during the hitchhiking scene, was not so easy to film for Capra as Colbert refused to do the scene claiming it was not lady like, but upon seeing a body double do it, she later changed her mind and did it herself. Although picking up slow, the movie later became one the biggest hits for the studio and the thing is that at the end the movie cleared the Academy Awards and both Gable and Colbert were better off. Colbert is known to have told a friend, "I just finished the worst picture in the world." She boycotted the Academy Awards when she got a nomination believing she will not win, but she was called back to come pick up her award. Here is a movie that actually makes you smile all the way through, although like the actors themselves upon initial siting of the film you can be turned off thinking this is heading nowhere, but be patient the movie has all the familiar scenes that we see in the movies today (all taken from this old classic). This old classic is tagged the 46th greatest film in the last 100 years in the AFI's 100 Years... 100 Movies (10th Anniversary Edition). It Happened One Night is a nice DVD for one to place on the shelf. www.lagsreviews.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It Remains The Best Romantic Comedy Ever Released On Screen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It Happened One Night is a romantic comedy film with elements of screwball comedy directed by Frank Capra, in which a pampered socialite tries to get out from under her father's thumb, and falls in love with a roguish reporter. It features Clark Gable,Claudette Colbert and Walter Connolly.The plot was based on the short story Night Bus by Samuel Hopkins Adams, which provided the shooting title. Ellie Andrews is a spoiled heiress who has married fortune-hunting aviator King Westley, despite her father's objections. To keep Ellie from marrying this Lothario, her father has been holding her prisoner aboard his yacht. But Ellie bolts from the yacht, swims ashore in her clothes, and eventually slips onto a Greyhound bus bound for New York. Aboard the bus is newspaper reporter Peter Warne, who has recently been fired for drinking on the job. Peter gets the last seat on the bus but when he gets up to argue with the bus driver, Ellie takes his seat. Since it is the last seat on the bus, they have to share it. When Ellie has her purse stolen and she refuses to report it, Peter begins to suspect something. The next morning, they both miss the bus after a leisurely breakfast, and Peter reveals that he knows her identity. She makes a deal with him: if he helps her get to New York, he can write a scoop about her for his paper. Peter thinks she is a spoiled brat, however, and refuses a monetary bribe: "I'm not interested in your money or your problem. You, King Westley, your father you're all a lot of hooey to me" But as they travel northward and engage in a series of misadventures, the gruff newspaperman and the spoiled rich girl, thrown together by circumstances, fall in love with each other. Director Frank Capra took home every major Oscars for this seminal comedy. Funny and sexy, the film is full of memorable scenes often referred to in other films, such as the "walls of Jericho" and Colbert's famous flash of thigh to stop a speeding car in its tracks.This is Capra at his best, very funny and very light, with a minimum of populist posturing.His brisk, urbane brand of wit was a perfect complement to his populist faith in the common man, and that inspired combination makes this film both a spirited entertainment and an uplifting experience.This is still is pure delight to watch at present and it still remains the best screwball comedy ever released as remains unsurpassed by the countless romantic comedies it has inspired.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Interesting "Time Travel" to an era
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bob Pr.
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Background to that '30s era: this 1934 film is often called the first (of the many following) in the 'screwball comedy' genre; it came out in the worst of the Great Depression (US unemployment in 1928 was 2.9%, by 1933 it hit 25%; millions were hungry and desperate, leading to some antagonisms between economic classes). This was also a time when women's roles were changing in the US: the 'women's suffrage' movement gained women the right to vote in 1920 (19th Amendment), more equality in decision-making, more freedom in dress, gender & sexual roles (e.g., '20s 'Flappers'). "Screwball comedies" capitalized and fed on those changes: they typically "feature farcical situations, a combination of slap-stick with fast-paced repartee and show struggles between" (central characters of different) "economic classes. They also generally feature a self-confident and often stubborn central female protagonist and a plot involving courtship and marriage or remarriage" ("quotes" from Wikipedia). A young 30's Gable plays "Peter," a drinking, hard boiled newspaper reporter just fired from his job when he accidentally meets the young 20's "Ellie" (a young 30's Colbert) who's increasingly rebelled against the escalating but failing attempts of her upper class, super-rich father to control her. He tries to keep her on his Florida yacht while arranging to annul Ellie's impulsive marriage to a man (whom her father recognizes but Ellie doesn't as mainly interested in her wealth). But Ellie escapes her father's captivity and sets off to NYC to be reunited with her new spouse. On her way, she meets Gable who's initially interested in helping her because it'll lead to his scoop of a newspaper story (and reinstatement of his job). But then--romance eventually, gradually, starts to happen between you know who. My rating: 6 of 10 I found this interesting as a time-traveling experience--early '30s bus rides, clothes, roles, attitudes, etc.-- but all the people seemed to me to be too much caricatures and not enough real characters. (However, many people on IMDb's "Discussion Board" say the more often they've seen this film, the more highly they value it--many saying it's among their most favorite films of all--so maybe familiarity breeds appreciation?) FWIW: Neither Gable nor Colbert wanted to be in this film; MGM "loaned" them to Columbia Pictures, then a 2nd rate movie company, for this movie as punishment for each being too "uppity" and/or violating MGM policies. But, after this film gained such outstanding success (lifting Columbia's rank to among the majors) and substantially helped both Gable's & Colbert's careers, they came to appreciate it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Who would of thunk it !
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    traversvcs6
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you happen to own or rent this movie I'd suggest watching it a second time with the directors son's commentary during the picture. He gives such an inspiring outlook on just how remarkable this picture was having been made in limited limited time and budget. How under appreciated it was by the producers to make, how the main actors were more or less coerced into doing the picture. How it was first met with so so reviews by the sophisticated New York City audience. Yet it was made so across the US of A it was put in theaters and what do you know it remained there for a record number of weeks. The movie goers of the time enjoyed it so they went back to see it again bringing family and friends cause they knew they had seen something truly awesome. Come Oscar time it took the five biggies, Best Picture, Leading actor and actress, writer and director. A feat not repeated again until One Flew Over the Cuckoos Nest. Yes this is a gem and that it became so at such odds makes it more so and should be in every movie lover's library! I loved it :)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cute and delightful!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RyanCShowers
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of the most important Best Picture winners feels like one of the most unnecessary Best Picture winners by some. When one says "Best Picture Winner", you think the said film must meet a certain criteria, such as war drama or epic production value-centric story, that certifies it that prestigious title. It Happened One Night has neither of those, though it does achieve a wonderful romance brought to life by Clarke Gable and Claudette Colbert and contains a screenplay as fresh as the carrots Clarke Gable eats himself during the picture. Movies of the 1930s (and earlier) have reoccurring problems when they are put up to the task of competing with newer pictures using today's standards of film perfection: they lack the tight, technical exertion. The sound is often terrible, some dialogue may even be lost, the editing is probably loose, and the photography is assumably rugged from the restoration attempts by the studios. It Happened One Night falls prey to these shortcomings, but it's the film's only real flaw, and not a big one at that. It's still a fairly entertaining movie and the restoration is actually successful most of the times. I couldn't take my eyes of It Happened One Night! It's a delightful film that should not be missed by any generation. Before Pretty Woman and Annie Hall were "the" romantic comedies of their times, there was It Happened One Night. Most of the romantic comedy plot devices we've seen used repeatedly, originated here and were so accepted by audiences and writers that they have grown into clich&eacute;. Aside from that, It Happened One Night combines classic stories (poor little rich girl, desperate reporter, train rides, extramarital affairs) into one sublime, Hollywood picture. The thing to any successful romantic comedy, besides the script having more on its cutting board than what the average joe-blow can bring to the table, is its stars. Think about how successful those two rom-coms I mentioned earlier would have been without Julia Roberts and Richard Gere or Woody Allen and Diane Keaton? Not very. The leading couple not only has marvelous chemistry together, but they both have the bolts to screw in a great performances. Clarke Gable in particular shines. His movie-star presence and ability to flow with a picture and character are on full display here. Claudette Colbert produces first rate acting, as well. It Happened One Night is a greatly pleasing film. You'll watch it with a smile on your face. It's funny and contains one of the best movie romances out there, a relationship that starts out in hostility, evolves to friendship, and is overcome with the realization of love. It Happened One Night is cute and having inspired a whole genre of films ahead of its time. Rating: 10/10 Grade: A+
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Whimsical love story breaks all the rules about love between the classes
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lucie Uche
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    First ever winner of five Oscars in all major categories, Best Picture, Best Director, Best Actor, Best Actress and Best Screenplay, the 1934 movie It Happened One Night is a whimsical romantic tale of fortuitous love between a spoiled socialite Ellen Andrews played by Claudette Colbert and a cantankerous newspaper reporter Peter Warne played by Clark Gable. The slapstick comedy collaboration from director Frank Capra and writer Robert Riskin, still remains quintessential viewing because of its clever and amusing portrayal of the pursuit of happiness and fulfillment. Ellen, recently married to infamous pilot King Westley (Jameson Thomas) against her millionaire father (Walter Connolly)'s orders is now cooped up on a yacht against her will with her father so that he can decidedly change her mind and have her marriage to the apparent gold digging cad annulled. Defiant Ellen who believes she is in love wants no part of her father's plan for her jumps ship to shore and eventually finds herself on a bus bound for New York. Here she hopes to reunite with her husband and live happily ever after. On board the Greyhound bus she meets Peter, none the worse for wear and recently fired from his newspaper for being drunk on the job. So begins an unlikely series of dealings between the two that stem from them agreeing to help each other out for a price of sorts. Peter recognizing Ellen from newspaper headlines as the much talked about runaway heiress, agrees to help her get to New York while she in turn offers him exclusive rights to her story, his hope is to revamp his career. The journey is series of memorable, classic, comical, events that draw the two closer together. Peter never one to hold back on his opinion and ever nonchalant, often chastises "Brat" his nickname for Ellen, because of her bourgeois tendencies and take on life, whereas he is a down to earth working class man; depicted in sharp close up clarity, every handsome rugged feature proving to be aesthetically camera friendly always defining his cool no nonsense sensibility. The two collide, bicker and banter about everything. There's is not an apparent match made in heaven but their liaison becomes more meaningful the longer they spend together. Peter is assiduous in keeping his promise to Ellen; Ellen is just doe eyed and realizes she is in love with the brash outspoken journalist. A timeless feature that that suggests Ellen's beauty and fragility is achieved with the application of a filtered lens on all of her close ups; this very effective application implies a softness and purity to her character. A notable fact about this seminal movie is the precedent it set for zany romantic comedies that would follow, such as Bringing up Baby (1938) and the Philadelphia Story (1940) both starring Katherine Hepburn and the impact it still has on screwball comedies today.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An antidote for depression
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Hotwok2013
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It isn't any wonder why "It Happened One Night" struck such a chord with movie-goers in the depression-hit USA of the 1930's. Frank Capra's sparkling romantic comedy is just about as uplifting as any movie possibly can be. Whatever it is that makes a star a star, Clark Gable had it in spades more than any other leading man before or since, & how could Claudette Colbert, (or any other woman?), not fall in love with him. Even allowing for the absurdities in the plot beginning with Ellie Andrews (Colbert) jumping her rich fathers yacht into the sea & swimming to shore. She is wearing a long white silk gown & not carrying a handbag. Next we see her at Miami bus station purchasing a ticket to New York in a new outfit with handbag!. The movie is full of memorably entertaining scenes & I guarantee that if anyone is feeling a bit low this film will improve their mood.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Romantic Comedy Supreme.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SmileysWorld
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Boy meets girl.They come from different roads in life and don't see eye to eye at first,but gradually they fall in love.This is a theme we have seen again and again throughout cinema history.Sometimes it is done well and sometimes..not so much.This is definitely the film that started it all,and the mold was broken.This is by far the best romantic comedy that I have ever seen.Claudette Colbert may not have thought so,for it has been said that she said to a friend after completing production that she had just finished "the worst film I have ever done."Surely she changed her tone when they placed the Best Actress Oscar in her hands.The screen chemistry between Colbert and Gable was right on the money.It is THE laugh out loud romantic classic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Young people in love are never hu-un-gry!" The granddaddy of all rom-coms
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    LouE15
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I stumbled across this film recently, expecting it to do no more than help me kill some time. Several viewings on, I'm hooked  it seems almost incredible that it was made in 1934, not 1984 or 2004. There isn't a romantic comedy in existence, and never will be, that doesn't owe a debt to this film. It's funny, modern, charming, and meaningful about people  what more do you want? Colour? Ah, nuts. Clark Gable plays Peter, a cynical journalist who ends up on a road trip across a Depression-hit USA with runaway heiress Ellen (Claudette Colbert). Ellen's sheltered life has done nothing to prepare her for the trials that lie ahead. She's so certain that she knows what she wants, and what's best: she's naive, but sparky and intelligent. She has to be knocked down in order to have her eyes peeled open. * Some spoilers from here* I thought I knew all about Clark Gable, and wasn't that bothered, but here he radiates masterful alpha-male charm and can switch on a dime from comedy to a love scene, boyish vulnerability to hardboiled cynic and back again. I don't know which version of him I liked more, although I think my favourite mini-moment comes when he's hardboiling it for the telegram girl, pipe in mouth - Philip Marlowe if ever there was one. The script is full of wonderful details  I don't know how much was in the original short story but I get the impression a great deal must have been added in to make it funnier. Oh, let me count the ways her not understanding what a real piggy back ride ishis hilariously terrible attempts at hitchhikingMr Believe You Me...Peter's "shut up" when they're back on the bus (which brings to mind James Cagney and That Grapefruit)and then his petulant sulk when he realises he's losing the upper hand, falling in love and just a shade jealousit's all great. I was hysterical by the time we met the operatic buggy driver  ever since I first saw the film I've been turning everyday trivialities into Gilbert & Sullivan libretto  and I just loved Peter's shouty conversation with Ellen's dad. But best of all are the lessons Ellen has to learn. For all her wealth and snobbery, and for all we enjoy her gradual comeuppance, she shows she's capable of learning (finally being hungry enough to eat a raw carrot!), and is worthy of Peter's love. When, near the end, she's weepily describing to her father how poor Peter's opinion is of them both ("you should hear what he says about you!"), capping it off with "he's marvellous(sob)", you're right there with her. "It happened one night" is in danger of eclipsing William Powell's wonderful "My Man Gordon" as my favourite thirties film. It's revised my lazy opinion about Clark Gable too  but it won't make me like "Gone with the Wind" any better, I don't care what anyone says.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Part one of two. My introduction of IHON, the background story on Capra's 1st miracle film.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Larry41OnEbay-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The idea for IT HAPPENED ONE NIGHT started in a barber shop while Frank Capra was waiting for a haircut he read an old magazine article in Cosmopolitan called "Night Bus" by Samuel Hopkins Adams. It was a cute idea so Capra asked Columbia studios to buy the rights to it and then he forgot about it. Frank's previous feature was LADY FOR A DAY which got great reviews and was Columbia studio's first film ever Oscar nominated and Capra's. Irving Thalberg wanted Capra to make his next film at MGM in exchange for $50k and the loan of a star. But at the last minute Louis B. Mayer canceled the film but honored the deal. Back at Columbia Capra wanted to make Night Bus, but studio tyrant Harry Cohn and all his advisers fought against it. They said things like, "It's nothing; froth, trivia, just another bus picture, no suspense, no heart, no oomph, winter's coming and it's all exteriors." All they could get Capra to do was change the title to IT HAPPENED ONE NIGHT which they said was too long to fit on a marquee! Capra tried casting Myrna Loy  she turned it down; then Margaret Sullavan  said 'no thank you'; Miriam Hopkins was insulted and said, 'Not if I never play another part'; Constance Bennett told him to go fly a kite and then offered to buy the script and have it rewritten for her! Capra had co-written the script with his favorite writer Robert Riskin but they brought in Myles Connolly who added more sympathetic and interesting characters so people could identify with them. The pretty girl, a spoiled brat, was rich yes but bored with being an heiress now wanting something real. The man was made a guy we all know and like; a tough crusading reporter on the outs with his pigheaded editor. It's The Taming Of The Shrew, but the shrew must be worth taming and the guy must be one of us. Back to casting, this time they went after Robert Montgomery a great light comedian at MGM. Mayer called Cohn and said, "Montgomery says there are too many bus pictures and (don't take this in the wrong way) but going from MGM to lowly Columbia was an insult. But you've caught me in a good mood. I got an actor here who's been a bad boy. Wants more money. And I'd like to spank him. You can have Clark Gable." Surprisingly the next knock on Capra's shabby office door came from a very drunk and cursing Gable, reporting to Siberia as he called it. Gable's objections almost made Capra throw in the towel but then Harry Cohn suggested getting Claudette Colbert for the girl in the story. (He had heard she liked money.) So Capra and Riskin made an appointment that very night to see her at her home. When they arrived Colbert regretted agreeing to the meeting as she was packing to leave on a month long skiing vacation. Capra saw this attractive, wealthy and spoiled woman and knew she was perfect for the part. So Capra, after being bit in the butt by her dog, asked what it would take to get her in the picture. (Capra had directed her first picture, FOR THE LOVE OF MIKE a silent made in 1927 and a flop) To throw him off she said she normally made $25k a picture (a price Columbia had never paid to an actor before), he would have to double it AND she was only available from her studio Paramount during her Christmas vacation. They would have to shoot all her scenes and retakes in less than 4 weeks -- half the time they had budgeted! So Capra called Cohn to ask would he pay her the $50k, Cohn said "I can pay it if you can shoot it in 4 weeks." Capra said, he didn't know, but he'd try. So they told her, "Deal, Claudette! $50k for 4 weeks! Okay?" To which she replied, "Oh for God's sake!" She was trapped. That next day she had to report for her costume fittings and the day after that they begin filming in a hurry. While they shot film all day Capra edited and rewrote the story to tighten it up at night. To make the film and story move quicker he asked the actors to talk faster, his amazing cinematographer Joseph Walker to shoot faster. (continued...)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    wonder why they called it, it happened one night
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lagudafuad
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It Happened One Night is one of the only three movies since the commencement of the Academy Awards to have been able to win all five major Academy Awards (Best Picture, Best Director, Best Actor, Best Actress, and Best Screenplay), a feat that would not be matched until One Flew Over the Cuckoo's Nest in 1975 and of cause latter on in 1991, Anthony Hopkins The Silence of the Lambs followed suit. Here is a romantic comedy as raw as they come giving you a thrill as you watch two people miss matched from the start found a way to fall in love and tour America on their way to New York. The funny thing about the movie is the name which says, "It happened one night" when actually in the movie's story it actually went on for more than a night. The movie plot is about Ellie Andrews (Claudette Colbert) who has been whisked away by her father in his yacht to keep her away from her new husband King Westley. Ellie then jumps ship, swim to shore and heads off to New York to meet with King Westley. On her way she meets a reporter Peter Warne (Clark Gable) and both started as an unsuitable pair that grew to be lovers. Both Colbert and Gable felt the movie was not going to be good enough and gave Capra a lot of bull. Even the movie's iconic scene where Colbert lifted up her skirt to stop a car during the hitchhiking scene, was not so easy to film for Capra as Colbert refused to do the scene claiming it was not lady like, but upon seeing a body double do it, she later changed her mind and did it herself. Although picking up slow, the movie later became one the biggest hits for the studio and the thing is that at the end the movie cleared the Academy Awards and both Gable and Colbert were better off. Colbert is known to have told a friend, "I just finished the worst picture in the world." She boycotted the Academy Awards when she got a nomination believing she will not win, but she was called back to come pick up her award. Here is a movie that actually makes you smile all the way through, although like the actors themselves upon initial siting of the film you can be turned off thinking this is heading nowhere, but be patient the movie has all the familiar scenes that we see in the movies today (all taken from this old classic). This old classic is tagged the 46th greatest film in the last 100 years in the AFI's 100 Years... 100 Movies (10th Anniversary Edition). It Happened One Night is a nice DVD for one to place on the shelf. www.lagsreviews.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It Remains The Best Romantic Comedy Ever Released On Screen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It Happened One Night is a romantic comedy film with elements of screwball comedy directed by Frank Capra, in which a pampered socialite tries to get out from under her father's thumb, and falls in love with a roguish reporter. It features Clark Gable,Claudette Colbert and Walter Connolly.The plot was based on the short story Night Bus by Samuel Hopkins Adams, which provided the shooting title. Ellie Andrews is a spoiled heiress who has married fortune-hunting aviator King Westley, despite her father's objections. To keep Ellie from marrying this Lothario, her father has been holding her prisoner aboard his yacht. But Ellie bolts from the yacht, swims ashore in her clothes, and eventually slips onto a Greyhound bus bound for New York. Aboard the bus is newspaper reporter Peter Warne, who has recently been fired for drinking on the job. Peter gets the last seat on the bus but when he gets up to argue with the bus driver, Ellie takes his seat. Since it is the last seat on the bus, they have to share it. When Ellie has her purse stolen and she refuses to report it, Peter begins to suspect something. The next morning, they both miss the bus after a leisurely breakfast, and Peter reveals that he knows her identity. She makes a deal with him: if he helps her get to New York, he can write a scoop about her for his paper. Peter thinks she is a spoiled brat, however, and refuses a monetary bribe: "I'm not interested in your money or your problem. You, King Westley, your father you're all a lot of hooey to me" But as they travel northward and engage in a series of misadventures, the gruff newspaperman and the spoiled rich girl, thrown together by circumstances, fall in love with each other. Director Frank Capra took home every major Oscars for this seminal comedy. Funny and sexy, the film is full of memorable scenes often referred to in other films, such as the "walls of Jericho" and Colbert's famous flash of thigh to stop a speeding car in its tracks.This is Capra at his best, very funny and very light, with a minimum of populist posturing.His brisk, urbane brand of wit was a perfect complement to his populist faith in the common man, and that inspired combination makes this film both a spirited entertainment and an uplifting experience.This is still is pure delight to watch at present and it still remains the best screwball comedy ever released as remains unsurpassed by the countless romantic comedies it has inspired.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Interesting "Time Travel" to an era
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bob Pr.
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Background to that '30s era: this 1934 film is often called the first (of the many following) in the 'screwball comedy' genre; it came out in the worst of the Great Depression (US unemployment in 1928 was 2.9%, by 1933 it hit 25%; millions were hungry and desperate, leading to some antagonisms between economic classes). This was also a time when women's roles were changing in the US: the 'women's suffrage' movement gained women the right to vote in 1920 (19th Amendment), more equality in decision-making, more freedom in dress, gender & sexual roles (e.g., '20s 'Flappers'). "Screwball comedies" capitalized and fed on those changes: they typically "feature farcical situations, a combination of slap-stick with fast-paced repartee and show struggles between" (central characters of different) "economic classes. They also generally feature a self-confident and often stubborn central female protagonist and a plot involving courtship and marriage or remarriage" ("quotes" from Wikipedia). A young 30's Gable plays "Peter," a drinking, hard boiled newspaper reporter just fired from his job when he accidentally meets the young 20's "Ellie" (a young 30's Colbert) who's increasingly rebelled against the escalating but failing attempts of her upper class, super-rich father to control her. He tries to keep her on his Florida yacht while arranging to annul Ellie's impulsive marriage to a man (whom her father recognizes but Ellie doesn't as mainly interested in her wealth). But Ellie escapes her father's captivity and sets off to NYC to be reunited with her new spouse. On her way, she meets Gable who's initially interested in helping her because it'll lead to his scoop of a newspaper story (and reinstatement of his job). But then--romance eventually, gradually, starts to happen between you know who. My rating: 6 of 10 I found this interesting as a time-traveling experience--early '30s bus rides, clothes, roles, attitudes, etc.-- but all the people seemed to me to be too much caricatures and not enough real characters. (However, many people on IMDb's "Discussion Board" say the more often they've seen this film, the more highly they value it--many saying it's among their most favorite films of all--so maybe familiarity breeds appreciation?) FWIW: Neither Gable nor Colbert wanted to be in this film; MGM "loaned" them to Columbia Pictures, then a 2nd rate movie company, for this movie as punishment for each being too "uppity" and/or violating MGM policies. But, after this film gained such outstanding success (lifting Columbia's rank to among the majors) and substantially helped both Gable's & Colbert's careers, they came to appreciate it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Who would of thunk it !
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    traversvcs6
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you happen to own or rent this movie I'd suggest watching it a second time with the directors son's commentary during the picture. He gives such an inspiring outlook on just how remarkable this picture was having been made in limited limited time and budget. How under appreciated it was by the producers to make, how the main actors were more or less coerced into doing the picture. How it was first met with so so reviews by the sophisticated New York City audience. Yet it was made so across the US of A it was put in theaters and what do you know it remained there for a record number of weeks. The movie goers of the time enjoyed it so they went back to see it again bringing family and friends cause they knew they had seen something truly awesome. Come Oscar time it took the five biggies, Best Picture, Leading actor and actress, writer and director. A feat not repeated again until One Flew Over the Cuckoos Nest. Yes this is a gem and that it became so at such odds makes it more so and should be in every movie lover's library! I loved it :)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cute and delightful!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RyanCShowers
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of the most important Best Picture winners feels like one of the most unnecessary Best Picture winners by some. When one says "Best Picture Winner", you think the said film must meet a certain criteria, such as war drama or epic production value-centric story, that certifies it that prestigious title. It Happened One Night has neither of those, though it does achieve a wonderful romance brought to life by Clarke Gable and Claudette Colbert and contains a screenplay as fresh as the carrots Clarke Gable eats himself during the picture. Movies of the 1930s (and earlier) have reoccurring problems when they are put up to the task of competing with newer pictures using today's standards of film perfection: they lack the tight, technical exertion. The sound is often terrible, some dialogue may even be lost, the editing is probably loose, and the photography is assumably rugged from the restoration attempts by the studios. It Happened One Night falls prey to these shortcomings, but it's the film's only real flaw, and not a big one at that. It's still a fairly entertaining movie and the restoration is actually successful most of the times. I couldn't take my eyes of It Happened One Night! It's a delightful film that should not be missed by any generation. Before Pretty Woman and Annie Hall were "the" romantic comedies of their times, there was It Happened One Night. Most of the romantic comedy plot devices we've seen used repeatedly, originated here and were so accepted by audiences and writers that they have grown into clich&eacute;. Aside from that, It Happened One Night combines classic stories (poor little rich girl, desperate reporter, train rides, extramarital affairs) into one sublime, Hollywood picture. The thing to any successful romantic comedy, besides the script having more on its cutting board than what the average joe-blow can bring to the table, is its stars. Think about how successful those two rom-coms I mentioned earlier would have been without Julia Roberts and Richard Gere or Woody Allen and Diane Keaton? Not very. The leading couple not only has marvelous chemistry together, but they both have the bolts to screw in a great performances. Clarke Gable in particular shines. His movie-star presence and ability to flow with a picture and character are on full display here. Claudette Colbert produces first rate acting, as well. It Happened One Night is a greatly pleasing film. You'll watch it with a smile on your face. It's funny and contains one of the best movie romances out there, a relationship that starts out in hostility, evolves to friendship, and is overcome with the realization of love. It Happened One Night is cute and having inspired a whole genre of films ahead of its time. Rating: 10/10 Grade: A+
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Whimsical love story breaks all the rules about love between the classes
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lucie Uche
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    First ever winner of five Oscars in all major categories, Best Picture, Best Director, Best Actor, Best Actress and Best Screenplay, the 1934 movie It Happened One Night is a whimsical romantic tale of fortuitous love between a spoiled socialite Ellen Andrews played by Claudette Colbert and a cantankerous newspaper reporter Peter Warne played by Clark Gable. The slapstick comedy collaboration from director Frank Capra and writer Robert Riskin, still remains quintessential viewing because of its clever and amusing portrayal of the pursuit of happiness and fulfillment. Ellen, recently married to infamous pilot King Westley (Jameson Thomas) against her millionaire father (Walter Connolly)'s orders is now cooped up on a yacht against her will with her father so that he can decidedly change her mind and have her marriage to the apparent gold digging cad annulled. Defiant Ellen who believes she is in love wants no part of her father's plan for her jumps ship to shore and eventually finds herself on a bus bound for New York. Here she hopes to reunite with her husband and live happily ever after. On board the Greyhound bus she meets Peter, none the worse for wear and recently fired from his newspaper for being drunk on the job. So begins an unlikely series of dealings between the two that stem from them agreeing to help each other out for a price of sorts. Peter recognizing Ellen from newspaper headlines as the much talked about runaway heiress, agrees to help her get to New York while she in turn offers him exclusive rights to her story, his hope is to revamp his career. The journey is series of memorable, classic, comical, events that draw the two closer together. Peter never one to hold back on his opinion and ever nonchalant, often chastises "Brat" his nickname for Ellen, because of her bourgeois tendencies and take on life, whereas he is a down to earth working class man; depicted in sharp close up clarity, every handsome rugged feature proving to be aesthetically camera friendly always defining his cool no nonsense sensibility. The two collide, bicker and banter about everything. There's is not an apparent match made in heaven but their liaison becomes more meaningful the longer they spend together. Peter is assiduous in keeping his promise to Ellen; Ellen is just doe eyed and realizes she is in love with the brash outspoken journalist. A timeless feature that that suggests Ellen's beauty and fragility is achieved with the application of a filtered lens on all of her close ups; this very effective application implies a softness and purity to her character. A notable fact about this seminal movie is the precedent it set for zany romantic comedies that would follow, such as Bringing up Baby (1938) and the Philadelphia Story (1940) both starring Katherine Hepburn and the impact it still has on screwball comedies today.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An antidote for depression
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Hotwok2013
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It isn't any wonder why "It Happened One Night" struck such a chord with movie-goers in the depression-hit USA of the 1930's. Frank Capra's sparkling romantic comedy is just about as uplifting as any movie possibly can be. Whatever it is that makes a star a star, Clark Gable had it in spades more than any other leading man before or since, & how could Claudette Colbert, (or any other woman?), not fall in love with him. Even allowing for the absurdities in the plot beginning with Ellie Andrews (Colbert) jumping her rich fathers yacht into the sea & swimming to shore. She is wearing a long white silk gown & not carrying a handbag. Next we see her at Miami bus station purchasing a ticket to New York in a new outfit with handbag!. The movie is full of memorably entertaining scenes & I guarantee that if anyone is feeling a bit low this film will improve their mood.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Romantic Comedy Supreme.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SmileysWorld
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Boy meets girl.They come from different roads in life and don't see eye to eye at first,but gradually they fall in love.This is a theme we have seen again and again throughout cinema history.Sometimes it is done well and sometimes..not so much.This is definitely the film that started it all,and the mold was broken.This is by far the best romantic comedy that I have ever seen.Claudette Colbert may not have thought so,for it has been said that she said to a friend after completing production that she had just finished "the worst film I have ever done."Surely she changed her tone when they placed the Best Actress Oscar in her hands.The screen chemistry between Colbert and Gable was right on the money.It is THE laugh out loud romantic classic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Young people in love are never hu-un-gry!" The granddaddy of all rom-coms
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    LouE15
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I stumbled across this film recently, expecting it to do no more than help me kill some time. Several viewings on, I'm hooked  it seems almost incredible that it was made in 1934, not 1984 or 2004. There isn't a romantic comedy in existence, and never will be, that doesn't owe a debt to this film. It's funny, modern, charming, and meaningful about people  what more do you want? Colour? Ah, nuts. Clark Gable plays Peter, a cynical journalist who ends up on a road trip across a Depression-hit USA with runaway heiress Ellen (Claudette Colbert). Ellen's sheltered life has done nothing to prepare her for the trials that lie ahead. She's so certain that she knows what she wants, and what's best: she's naive, but sparky and intelligent. She has to be knocked down in order to have her eyes peeled open. * Some spoilers from here* I thought I knew all about Clark Gable, and wasn't that bothered, but here he radiates masterful alpha-male charm and can switch on a dime from comedy to a love scene, boyish vulnerability to hardboiled cynic and back again. I don't know which version of him I liked more, although I think my favourite mini-moment comes when he's hardboiling it for the telegram girl, pipe in mouth - Philip Marlowe if ever there was one. The script is full of wonderful details  I don't know how much was in the original short story but I get the impression a great deal must have been added in to make it funnier. Oh, let me count the ways her not understanding what a real piggy back ride ishis hilariously terrible attempts at hitchhikingMr Believe You Me...Peter's "shut up" when they're back on the bus (which brings to mind James Cagney and That Grapefruit)and then his petulant sulk when he realises he's losing the upper hand, falling in love and just a shade jealousit's all great. I was hysterical by the time we met the operatic buggy driver  ever since I first saw the film I've been turning everyday trivialities into Gilbert & Sullivan libretto  and I just loved Peter's shouty conversation with Ellen's dad. But best of all are the lessons Ellen has to learn. For all her wealth and snobbery, and for all we enjoy her gradual comeuppance, she shows she's capable of learning (finally being hungry enough to eat a raw carrot!), and is worthy of Peter's love. When, near the end, she's weepily describing to her father how poor Peter's opinion is of them both ("you should hear what he says about you!"), capping it off with "he's marvellous(sob)", you're right there with her. "It happened one night" is in danger of eclipsing William Powell's wonderful "My Man Gordon" as my favourite thirties film. It's revised my lazy opinion about Clark Gable too  but it won't make me like "Gone with the Wind" any better, I don't care what anyone says.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Part one of two. My introduction of IHON, the background story on Capra's 1st miracle film.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Larry41OnEbay-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The idea for IT HAPPENED ONE NIGHT started in a barber shop while Frank Capra was waiting for a haircut he read an old magazine article in Cosmopolitan called "Night Bus" by Samuel Hopkins Adams. It was a cute idea so Capra asked Columbia studios to buy the rights to it and then he forgot about it. Frank's previous feature was LADY FOR A DAY which got great reviews and was Columbia studio's first film ever Oscar nominated and Capra's. Irving Thalberg wanted Capra to make his next film at MGM in exchange for $50k and the loan of a star. But at the last minute Louis B. Mayer canceled the film but honored the deal. Back at Columbia Capra wanted to make Night Bus, but studio tyrant Harry Cohn and all his advisers fought against it. They said things like, "It's nothing; froth, trivia, just another bus picture, no suspense, no heart, no oomph, winter's coming and it's all exteriors." All they could get Capra to do was change the title to IT HAPPENED ONE NIGHT which they said was too long to fit on a marquee! Capra tried casting Myrna Loy  she turned it down; then Margaret Sullavan  said 'no thank you'; Miriam Hopkins was insulted and said, 'Not if I never play another part'; Constance Bennett told him to go fly a kite and then offered to buy the script and have it rewritten for her! Capra had co-written the script with his favorite writer Robert Riskin but they brought in Myles Connolly who added more sympathetic and interesting characters so people could identify with them. The pretty girl, a spoiled brat, was rich yes but bored with being an heiress now wanting something real. The man was made a guy we all know and like; a tough crusading reporter on the outs with his pigheaded editor. It's The Taming Of The Shrew, but the shrew must be worth taming and the guy must be one of us. Back to casting, this time they went after Robert Montgomery a great light comedian at MGM. Mayer called Cohn and said, "Montgomery says there are too many bus pictures and (don't take this in the wrong way) but going from MGM to lowly Columbia was an insult. But you've caught me in a good mood. I got an actor here who's been a bad boy. Wants more money. And I'd like to spank him. You can have Clark Gable." Surprisingly the next knock on Capra's shabby office door came from a very drunk and cursing Gable, reporting to Siberia as he called it. Gable's objections almost made Capra throw in the towel but then Harry Cohn suggested getting Claudette Colbert for the girl in the story. (He had heard she liked money.) So Capra and Riskin made an appointment that very night to see her at her home. When they arrived Colbert regretted agreeing to the meeting as she was packing to leave on a month long skiing vacation. Capra saw this attractive, wealthy and spoiled woman and knew she was perfect for the part. So Capra, after being bit in the butt by her dog, asked what it would take to get her in the picture. (Capra had directed her first picture, FOR THE LOVE OF MIKE a silent made in 1927 and a flop) To throw him off she said she normally made $25k a picture (a price Columbia had never paid to an actor before), he would have to double it AND she was only available from her studio Paramount during her Christmas vacation. They would have to shoot all her scenes and retakes in less than 4 weeks -- half the time they had budgeted! So Capra called Cohn to ask would he pay her the $50k, Cohn said "I can pay it if you can shoot it in 4 weeks." Capra said, he didn't know, but he'd try. So they told her, "Deal, Claudette! $50k for 4 weeks! Okay?" To which she replied, "Oh for God's sake!" She was trapped. That next day she had to report for her costume fittings and the day after that they begin filming in a hurry. While they shot film all day Capra edited and rewrote the story to tighten it up at night. To make the film and story move quicker he asked the actors to talk faster, his amazing cinematographer Joseph Walker to shoot faster. (continued...)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    wonder why they called it, it happened one night
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lagudafuad
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It Happened One Night is one of the only three movies since the commencement of the Academy Awards to have been able to win all five major Academy Awards (Best Picture, Best Director, Best Actor, Best Actress, and Best Screenplay), a feat that would not be matched until One Flew Over the Cuckoo's Nest in 1975 and of cause latter on in 1991, Anthony Hopkins The Silence of the Lambs followed suit. Here is a romantic comedy as raw as they come giving you a thrill as you watch two people miss matched from the start found a way to fall in love and tour America on their way to New York. The funny thing about the movie is the name which says, "It happened one night" when actually in the movie's story it actually went on for more than a night. The movie plot is about Ellie Andrews (Claudette Colbert) who has been whisked away by her father in his yacht to keep her away from her new husband King Westley. Ellie then jumps ship, swim to shore and heads off to New York to meet with King Westley. On her way she meets a reporter Peter Warne (Clark Gable) and both started as an unsuitable pair that grew to be lovers. Both Colbert and Gable felt the movie was not going to be good enough and gave Capra a lot of bull. Even the movie's iconic scene where Colbert lifted up her skirt to stop a car during the hitchhiking scene, was not so easy to film for Capra as Colbert refused to do the scene claiming it was not lady like, but upon seeing a body double do it, she later changed her mind and did it herself. Although picking up slow, the movie later became one the biggest hits for the studio and the thing is that at the end the movie cleared the Academy Awards and both Gable and Colbert were better off. Colbert is known to have told a friend, "I just finished the worst picture in the world." She boycotted the Academy Awards when she got a nomination believing she will not win, but she was called back to come pick up her award. Here is a movie that actually makes you smile all the way through, although like the actors themselves upon initial siting of the film you can be turned off thinking this is heading nowhere, but be patient the movie has all the familiar scenes that we see in the movies today (all taken from this old classic). This old classic is tagged the 46th greatest film in the last 100 years in the AFI's 100 Years... 100 Movies (10th Anniversary Edition). It Happened One Night is a nice DVD for one to place on the shelf. www.lagsreviews.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It Remains The Best Romantic Comedy Ever Released On Screen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It Happened One Night is a romantic comedy film with elements of screwball comedy directed by Frank Capra, in which a pampered socialite tries to get out from under her father's thumb, and falls in love with a roguish reporter. It features Clark Gable,Claudette Colbert and Walter Connolly.The plot was based on the short story Night Bus by Samuel Hopkins Adams, which provided the shooting title. Ellie Andrews is a spoiled heiress who has married fortune-hunting aviator King Westley, despite her father's objections. To keep Ellie from marrying this Lothario, her father has been holding her prisoner aboard his yacht. But Ellie bolts from the yacht, swims ashore in her clothes, and eventually slips onto a Greyhound bus bound for New York. Aboard the bus is newspaper reporter Peter Warne, who has recently been fired for drinking on the job. Peter gets the last seat on the bus but when he gets up to argue with the bus driver, Ellie takes his seat. Since it is the last seat on the bus, they have to share it. When Ellie has her purse stolen and she refuses to report it, Peter begins to suspect something. The next morning, they both miss the bus after a leisurely breakfast, and Peter reveals that he knows her identity. She makes a deal with him: if he helps her get to New York, he can write a scoop about her for his paper. Peter thinks she is a spoiled brat, however, and refuses a monetary bribe: "I'm not interested in your money or your problem. You, King Westley, your father you're all a lot of hooey to me" But as they travel northward and engage in a series of misadventures, the gruff newspaperman and the spoiled rich girl, thrown together by circumstances, fall in love with each other. Director Frank Capra took home every major Oscars for this seminal comedy. Funny and sexy, the film is full of memorable scenes often referred to in other films, such as the "walls of Jericho" and Colbert's famous flash of thigh to stop a speeding car in its tracks.This is Capra at his best, very funny and very light, with a minimum of populist posturing.His brisk, urbane brand of wit was a perfect complement to his populist faith in the common man, and that inspired combination makes this film both a spirited entertainment and an uplifting experience.This is still is pure delight to watch at present and it still remains the best screwball comedy ever released as remains unsurpassed by the countless romantic comedies it has inspired.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Interesting "Time Travel" to an era
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bob Pr.
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Background to that '30s era: this 1934 film is often called the first (of the many following) in the 'screwball comedy' genre; it came out in the worst of the Great Depression (US unemployment in 1928 was 2.9%, by 1933 it hit 25%; millions were hungry and desperate, leading to some antagonisms between economic classes). This was also a time when women's roles were changing in the US: the 'women's suffrage' movement gained women the right to vote in 1920 (19th Amendment), more equality in decision-making, more freedom in dress, gender & sexual roles (e.g., '20s 'Flappers'). "Screwball comedies" capitalized and fed on those changes: they typically "feature farcical situations, a combination of slap-stick with fast-paced repartee and show struggles between" (central characters of different) "economic classes. They also generally feature a self-confident and often stubborn central female protagonist and a plot involving courtship and marriage or remarriage" ("quotes" from Wikipedia). A young 30's Gable plays "Peter," a drinking, hard boiled newspaper reporter just fired from his job when he accidentally meets the young 20's "Ellie" (a young 30's Colbert) who's increasingly rebelled against the escalating but failing attempts of her upper class, super-rich father to control her. He tries to keep her on his Florida yacht while arranging to annul Ellie's impulsive marriage to a man (whom her father recognizes but Ellie doesn't as mainly interested in her wealth). But Ellie escapes her father's captivity and sets off to NYC to be reunited with her new spouse. On her way, she meets Gable who's initially interested in helping her because it'll lead to his scoop of a newspaper story (and reinstatement of his job). But then--romance eventually, gradually, starts to happen between you know who. My rating: 6 of 10 I found this interesting as a time-traveling experience--early '30s bus rides, clothes, roles, attitudes, etc.-- but all the people seemed to me to be too much caricatures and not enough real characters. (However, many people on IMDb's "Discussion Board" say the more often they've seen this film, the more highly they value it--many saying it's among their most favorite films of all--so maybe familiarity breeds appreciation?) FWIW: Neither Gable nor Colbert wanted to be in this film; MGM "loaned" them to Columbia Pictures, then a 2nd rate movie company, for this movie as punishment for each being too "uppity" and/or violating MGM policies. But, after this film gained such outstanding success (lifting Columbia's rank to among the majors) and substantially helped both Gable's & Colbert's careers, they came to appreciate it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Who would of thunk it !
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    traversvcs6
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you happen to own or rent this movie I'd suggest watching it a second time with the directors son's commentary during the picture. He gives such an inspiring outlook on just how remarkable this picture was having been made in limited limited time and budget. How under appreciated it was by the producers to make, how the main actors were more or less coerced into doing the picture. How it was first met with so so reviews by the sophisticated New York City audience. Yet it was made so across the US of A it was put in theaters and what do you know it remained there for a record number of weeks. The movie goers of the time enjoyed it so they went back to see it again bringing family and friends cause they knew they had seen something truly awesome. Come Oscar time it took the five biggies, Best Picture, Leading actor and actress, writer and director. A feat not repeated again until One Flew Over the Cuckoos Nest. Yes this is a gem and that it became so at such odds makes it more so and should be in every movie lover's library! I loved it :)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cute and delightful!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RyanCShowers
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of the most important Best Picture winners feels like one of the most unnecessary Best Picture winners by some. When one says "Best Picture Winner", you think the said film must meet a certain criteria, such as war drama or epic production value-centric story, that certifies it that prestigious title. It Happened One Night has neither of those, though it does achieve a wonderful romance brought to life by Clarke Gable and Claudette Colbert and contains a screenplay as fresh as the carrots Clarke Gable eats himself during the picture. Movies of the 1930s (and earlier) have reoccurring problems when they are put up to the task of competing with newer pictures using today's standards of film perfection: they lack the tight, technical exertion. The sound is often terrible, some dialogue may even be lost, the editing is probably loose, and the photography is assumably rugged from the restoration attempts by the studios. It Happened One Night falls prey to these shortcomings, but it's the film's only real flaw, and not a big one at that. It's still a fairly entertaining movie and the restoration is actually successful most of the times. I couldn't take my eyes of It Happened One Night! It's a delightful film that should not be missed by any generation. Before Pretty Woman and Annie Hall were "the" romantic comedies of their times, there was It Happened One Night. Most of the romantic comedy plot devices we've seen used repeatedly, originated here and were so accepted by audiences and writers that they have grown into clich&eacute;. Aside from that, It Happened One Night combines classic stories (poor little rich girl, desperate reporter, train rides, extramarital affairs) into one sublime, Hollywood picture. The thing to any successful romantic comedy, besides the script having more on its cutting board than what the average joe-blow can bring to the table, is its stars. Think about how successful those two rom-coms I mentioned earlier would have been without Julia Roberts and Richard Gere or Woody Allen and Diane Keaton? Not very. The leading couple not only has marvelous chemistry together, but they both have the bolts to screw in a great performances. Clarke Gable in particular shines. His movie-star presence and ability to flow with a picture and character are on full display here. Claudette Colbert produces first rate acting, as well. It Happened One Night is a greatly pleasing film. You'll watch it with a smile on your face. It's funny and contains one of the best movie romances out there, a relationship that starts out in hostility, evolves to friendship, and is overcome with the realization of love. It Happened One Night is cute and having inspired a whole genre of films ahead of its time. Rating: 10/10 Grade: A+
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Whimsical love story breaks all the rules about love between the classes
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lucie Uche
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    First ever winner of five Oscars in all major categories, Best Picture, Best Director, Best Actor, Best Actress and Best Screenplay, the 1934 movie It Happened One Night is a whimsical romantic tale of fortuitous love between a spoiled socialite Ellen Andrews played by Claudette Colbert and a cantankerous newspaper reporter Peter Warne played by Clark Gable. The slapstick comedy collaboration from director Frank Capra and writer Robert Riskin, still remains quintessential viewing because of its clever and amusing portrayal of the pursuit of happiness and fulfillment. Ellen, recently married to infamous pilot King Westley (Jameson Thomas) against her millionaire father (Walter Connolly)'s orders is now cooped up on a yacht against her will with her father so that he can decidedly change her mind and have her marriage to the apparent gold digging cad annulled. Defiant Ellen who believes she is in love wants no part of her father's plan for her jumps ship to shore and eventually finds herself on a bus bound for New York. Here she hopes to reunite with her husband and live happily ever after. On board the Greyhound bus she meets Peter, none the worse for wear and recently fired from his newspaper for being drunk on the job. So begins an unlikely series of dealings between the two that stem from them agreeing to help each other out for a price of sorts. Peter recognizing Ellen from newspaper headlines as the much talked about runaway heiress, agrees to help her get to New York while she in turn offers him exclusive rights to her story, his hope is to revamp his career. The journey is series of memorable, classic, comical, events that draw the two closer together. Peter never one to hold back on his opinion and ever nonchalant, often chastises "Brat" his nickname for Ellen, because of her bourgeois tendencies and take on life, whereas he is a down to earth working class man; depicted in sharp close up clarity, every handsome rugged feature proving to be aesthetically camera friendly always defining his cool no nonsense sensibility. The two collide, bicker and banter about everything. There's is not an apparent match made in heaven but their liaison becomes more meaningful the longer they spend together. Peter is assiduous in keeping his promise to Ellen; Ellen is just doe eyed and realizes she is in love with the brash outspoken journalist. A timeless feature that that suggests Ellen's beauty and fragility is achieved with the application of a filtered lens on all of her close ups; this very effective application implies a softness and purity to her character. A notable fact about this seminal movie is the precedent it set for zany romantic comedies that would follow, such as Bringing up Baby (1938) and the Philadelphia Story (1940) both starring Katherine Hepburn and the impact it still has on screwball comedies today.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An antidote for depression
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Hotwok2013
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It isn't any wonder why "It Happened One Night" struck such a chord with movie-goers in the depression-hit USA of the 1930's. Frank Capra's sparkling romantic comedy is just about as uplifting as any movie possibly can be. Whatever it is that makes a star a star, Clark Gable had it in spades more than any other leading man before or since, & how could Claudette Colbert, (or any other woman?), not fall in love with him. Even allowing for the absurdities in the plot beginning with Ellie Andrews (Colbert) jumping her rich fathers yacht into the sea & swimming to shore. She is wearing a long white silk gown & not carrying a handbag. Next we see her at Miami bus station purchasing a ticket to New York in a new outfit with handbag!. The movie is full of memorably entertaining scenes & I guarantee that if anyone is feeling a bit low this film will improve their mood.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Romantic Comedy Supreme.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SmileysWorld
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Boy meets girl.They come from different roads in life and don't see eye to eye at first,but gradually they fall in love.This is a theme we have seen again and again throughout cinema history.Sometimes it is done well and sometimes..not so much.This is definitely the film that started it all,and the mold was broken.This is by far the best romantic comedy that I have ever seen.Claudette Colbert may not have thought so,for it has been said that she said to a friend after completing production that she had just finished "the worst film I have ever done."Surely she changed her tone when they placed the Best Actress Oscar in her hands.The screen chemistry between Colbert and Gable was right on the money.It is THE laugh out loud romantic classic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Young people in love are never hu-un-gry!" The granddaddy of all rom-coms
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    LouE15
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I stumbled across this film recently, expecting it to do no more than help me kill some time. Several viewings on, I'm hooked  it seems almost incredible that it was made in 1934, not 1984 or 2004. There isn't a romantic comedy in existence, and never will be, that doesn't owe a debt to this film. It's funny, modern, charming, and meaningful about people  what more do you want? Colour? Ah, nuts. Clark Gable plays Peter, a cynical journalist who ends up on a road trip across a Depression-hit USA with runaway heiress Ellen (Claudette Colbert). Ellen's sheltered life has done nothing to prepare her for the trials that lie ahead. She's so certain that she knows what she wants, and what's best: she's naive, but sparky and intelligent. She has to be knocked down in order to have her eyes peeled open. * Some spoilers from here* I thought I knew all about Clark Gable, and wasn't that bothered, but here he radiates masterful alpha-male charm and can switch on a dime from comedy to a love scene, boyish vulnerability to hardboiled cynic and back again. I don't know which version of him I liked more, although I think my favourite mini-moment comes when he's hardboiling it for the telegram girl, pipe in mouth - Philip Marlowe if ever there was one. The script is full of wonderful details  I don't know how much was in the original short story but I get the impression a great deal must have been added in to make it funnier. Oh, let me count the ways her not understanding what a real piggy back ride ishis hilariously terrible attempts at hitchhikingMr Believe You Me...Peter's "shut up" when they're back on the bus (which brings to mind James Cagney and That Grapefruit)and then his petulant sulk when he realises he's losing the upper hand, falling in love and just a shade jealousit's all great. I was hysterical by the time we met the operatic buggy driver  ever since I first saw the film I've been turning everyday trivialities into Gilbert & Sullivan libretto  and I just loved Peter's shouty conversation with Ellen's dad. But best of all are the lessons Ellen has to learn. For all her wealth and snobbery, and for all we enjoy her gradual comeuppance, she shows she's capable of learning (finally being hungry enough to eat a raw carrot!), and is worthy of Peter's love. When, near the end, she's weepily describing to her father how poor Peter's opinion is of them both ("you should hear what he says about you!"), capping it off with "he's marvellous(sob)", you're right there with her. "It happened one night" is in danger of eclipsing William Powell's wonderful "My Man Gordon" as my favourite thirties film. It's revised my lazy opinion about Clark Gable too  but it won't make me like "Gone with the Wind" any better, I don't care what anyone says.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Part one of two. My introduction of IHON, the background story on Capra's 1st miracle film.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Larry41OnEbay-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The idea for IT HAPPENED ONE NIGHT started in a barber shop while Frank Capra was waiting for a haircut he read an old magazine article in Cosmopolitan called "Night Bus" by Samuel Hopkins Adams. It was a cute idea so Capra asked Columbia studios to buy the rights to it and then he forgot about it. Frank's previous feature was LADY FOR A DAY which got great reviews and was Columbia studio's first film ever Oscar nominated and Capra's. Irving Thalberg wanted Capra to make his next film at MGM in exchange for $50k and the loan of a star. But at the last minute Louis B. Mayer canceled the film but honored the deal. Back at Columbia Capra wanted to make Night Bus, but studio tyrant Harry Cohn and all his advisers fought against it. They said things like, "It's nothing; froth, trivia, just another bus picture, no suspense, no heart, no oomph, winter's coming and it's all exteriors." All they could get Capra to do was change the title to IT HAPPENED ONE NIGHT which they said was too long to fit on a marquee! Capra tried casting Myrna Loy  she turned it down; then Margaret Sullavan  said 'no thank you'; Miriam Hopkins was insulted and said, 'Not if I never play another part'; Constance Bennett told him to go fly a kite and then offered to buy the script and have it rewritten for her! Capra had co-written the script with his favorite writer Robert Riskin but they brought in Myles Connolly who added more sympathetic and interesting characters so people could identify with them. The pretty girl, a spoiled brat, was rich yes but bored with being an heiress now wanting something real. The man was made a guy we all know and like; a tough crusading reporter on the outs with his pigheaded editor. It's The Taming Of The Shrew, but the shrew must be worth taming and the guy must be one of us. Back to casting, this time they went after Robert Montgomery a great light comedian at MGM. Mayer called Cohn and said, "Montgomery says there are too many bus pictures and (don't take this in the wrong way) but going from MGM to lowly Columbia was an insult. But you've caught me in a good mood. I got an actor here who's been a bad boy. Wants more money. And I'd like to spank him. You can have Clark Gable." Surprisingly the next knock on Capra's shabby office door came from a very drunk and cursing Gable, reporting to Siberia as he called it. Gable's objections almost made Capra throw in the towel but then Harry Cohn suggested getting Claudette Colbert for the girl in the story. (He had heard she liked money.) So Capra and Riskin made an appointment that very night to see her at her home. When they arrived Colbert regretted agreeing to the meeting as she was packing to leave on a month long skiing vacation. Capra saw this attractive, wealthy and spoiled woman and knew she was perfect for the part. So Capra, after being bit in the butt by her dog, asked what it would take to get her in the picture. (Capra had directed her first picture, FOR THE LOVE OF MIKE a silent made in 1927 and a flop) To throw him off she said she normally made $25k a picture (a price Columbia had never paid to an actor before), he would have to double it AND she was only available from her studio Paramount during her Christmas vacation. They would have to shoot all her scenes and retakes in less than 4 weeks -- half the time they had budgeted! So Capra called Cohn to ask would he pay her the $50k, Cohn said "I can pay it if you can shoot it in 4 weeks." Capra said, he didn't know, but he'd try. So they told her, "Deal, Claudette! $50k for 4 weeks! Okay?" To which she replied, "Oh for God's sake!" She was trapped. That next day she had to report for her costume fittings and the day after that they begin filming in a hurry. While they shot film all day Capra edited and rewrote the story to tighten it up at night. To make the film and story move quicker he asked the actors to talk faster, his amazing cinematographer Joseph Walker to shoot faster. (continued...)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    wonder why they called it, it happened one night
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lagudafuad
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It Happened One Night is one of the only three movies since the commencement of the Academy Awards to have been able to win all five major Academy Awards (Best Picture, Best Director, Best Actor, Best Actress, and Best Screenplay), a feat that would not be matched until One Flew Over the Cuckoo's Nest in 1975 and of cause latter on in 1991, Anthony Hopkins The Silence of the Lambs followed suit. Here is a romantic comedy as raw as they come giving you a thrill as you watch two people miss matched from the start found a way to fall in love and tour America on their way to New York. The funny thing about the movie is the name which says, "It happened one night" when actually in the movie's story it actually went on for more than a night. The movie plot is about Ellie Andrews (Claudette Colbert) who has been whisked away by her father in his yacht to keep her away from her new husband King Westley. Ellie then jumps ship, swim to shore and heads off to New York to meet with King Westley. On her way she meets a reporter Peter Warne (Clark Gable) and both started as an unsuitable pair that grew to be lovers. Both Colbert and Gable felt the movie was not going to be good enough and gave Capra a lot of bull. Even the movie's iconic scene where Colbert lifted up her skirt to stop a car during the hitchhiking scene, was not so easy to film for Capra as Colbert refused to do the scene claiming it was not lady like, but upon seeing a body double do it, she later changed her mind and did it herself. Although picking up slow, the movie later became one the biggest hits for the studio and the thing is that at the end the movie cleared the Academy Awards and both Gable and Colbert were better off. Colbert is known to have told a friend, "I just finished the worst picture in the world." She boycotted the Academy Awards when she got a nomination believing she will not win, but she was called back to come pick up her award. Here is a movie that actually makes you smile all the way through, although like the actors themselves upon initial siting of the film you can be turned off thinking this is heading nowhere, but be patient the movie has all the familiar scenes that we see in the movies today (all taken from this old classic). This old classic is tagged the 46th greatest film in the last 100 years in the AFI's 100 Years... 100 Movies (10th Anniversary Edition). It Happened One Night is a nice DVD for one to place on the shelf. www.lagsreviews.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It Remains The Best Romantic Comedy Ever Released On Screen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It Happened One Night is a romantic comedy film with elements of screwball comedy directed by Frank Capra, in which a pampered socialite tries to get out from under her father's thumb, and falls in love with a roguish reporter. It features Clark Gable,Claudette Colbert and Walter Connolly.The plot was based on the short story Night Bus by Samuel Hopkins Adams, which provided the shooting title. Ellie Andrews is a spoiled heiress who has married fortune-hunting aviator King Westley, despite her father's objections. To keep Ellie from marrying this Lothario, her father has been holding her prisoner aboard his yacht. But Ellie bolts from the yacht, swims ashore in her clothes, and eventually slips onto a Greyhound bus bound for New York. Aboard the bus is newspaper reporter Peter Warne, who has recently been fired for drinking on the job. Peter gets the last seat on the bus but when he gets up to argue with the bus driver, Ellie takes his seat. Since it is the last seat on the bus, they have to share it. When Ellie has her purse stolen and she refuses to report it, Peter begins to suspect something. The next morning, they both miss the bus after a leisurely breakfast, and Peter reveals that he knows her identity. She makes a deal with him: if he helps her get to New York, he can write a scoop about her for his paper. Peter thinks she is a spoiled brat, however, and refuses a monetary bribe: "I'm not interested in your money or your problem. You, King Westley, your father you're all a lot of hooey to me" But as they travel northward and engage in a series of misadventures, the gruff newspaperman and the spoiled rich girl, thrown together by circumstances, fall in love with each other. Director Frank Capra took home every major Oscars for this seminal comedy. Funny and sexy, the film is full of memorable scenes often referred to in other films, such as the "walls of Jericho" and Colbert's famous flash of thigh to stop a speeding car in its tracks.This is Capra at his best, very funny and very light, with a minimum of populist posturing.His brisk, urbane brand of wit was a perfect complement to his populist faith in the common man, and that inspired combination makes this film both a spirited entertainment and an uplifting experience.This is still is pure delight to watch at present and it still remains the best screwball comedy ever released as remains unsurpassed by the countless romantic comedies it has inspired.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Interesting "Time Travel" to an era
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bob Pr.
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Background to that '30s era: this 1934 film is often called the first (of the many following) in the 'screwball comedy' genre; it came out in the worst of the Great Depression (US unemployment in 1928 was 2.9%, by 1933 it hit 25%; millions were hungry and desperate, leading to some antagonisms between economic classes). This was also a time when women's roles were changing in the US: the 'women's suffrage' movement gained women the right to vote in 1920 (19th Amendment), more equality in decision-making, more freedom in dress, gender & sexual roles (e.g., '20s 'Flappers'). "Screwball comedies" capitalized and fed on those changes: they typically "feature farcical situations, a combination of slap-stick with fast-paced repartee and show struggles between" (central characters of different) "economic classes. They also generally feature a self-confident and often stubborn central female protagonist and a plot involving courtship and marriage or remarriage" ("quotes" from Wikipedia). A young 30's Gable plays "Peter," a drinking, hard boiled newspaper reporter just fired from his job when he accidentally meets the young 20's "Ellie" (a young 30's Colbert) who's increasingly rebelled against the escalating but failing attempts of her upper class, super-rich father to control her. He tries to keep her on his Florida yacht while arranging to annul Ellie's impulsive marriage to a man (whom her father recognizes but Ellie doesn't as mainly interested in her wealth). But Ellie escapes her father's captivity and sets off to NYC to be reunited with her new spouse. On her way, she meets Gable who's initially interested in helping her because it'll lead to his scoop of a newspaper story (and reinstatement of his job). But then--romance eventually, gradually, starts to happen between you know who. My rating: 6 of 10 I found this interesting as a time-traveling experience--early '30s bus rides, clothes, roles, attitudes, etc.-- but all the people seemed to me to be too much caricatures and not enough real characters. (However, many people on IMDb's "Discussion Board" say the more often they've seen this film, the more highly they value it--many saying it's among their most favorite films of all--so maybe familiarity breeds appreciation?) FWIW: Neither Gable nor Colbert wanted to be in this film; MGM "loaned" them to Columbia Pictures, then a 2nd rate movie company, for this movie as punishment for each being too "uppity" and/or violating MGM policies. But, after this film gained such outstanding success (lifting Columbia's rank to among the majors) and substantially helped both Gable's & Colbert's careers, they came to appreciate it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Who would of thunk it !
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    traversvcs6
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you happen to own or rent this movie I'd suggest watching it a second time with the directors son's commentary during the picture. He gives such an inspiring outlook on just how remarkable this picture was having been made in limited limited time and budget. How under appreciated it was by the producers to make, how the main actors were more or less coerced into doing the picture. How it was first met with so so reviews by the sophisticated New York City audience. Yet it was made so across the US of A it was put in theaters and what do you know it remained there for a record number of weeks. The movie goers of the time enjoyed it so they went back to see it again bringing family and friends cause they knew they had seen something truly awesome. Come Oscar time it took the five biggies, Best Picture, Leading actor and actress, writer and director. A feat not repeated again until One Flew Over the Cuckoos Nest. Yes this is a gem and that it became so at such odds makes it more so and should be in every movie lover's library! I loved it :)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cute and delightful!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RyanCShowers
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of the most important Best Picture winners feels like one of the most unnecessary Best Picture winners by some. When one says "Best Picture Winner", you think the said film must meet a certain criteria, such as war drama or epic production value-centric story, that certifies it that prestigious title. It Happened One Night has neither of those, though it does achieve a wonderful romance brought to life by Clarke Gable and Claudette Colbert and contains a screenplay as fresh as the carrots Clarke Gable eats himself during the picture. Movies of the 1930s (and earlier) have reoccurring problems when they are put up to the task of competing with newer pictures using today's standards of film perfection: they lack the tight, technical exertion. The sound is often terrible, some dialogue may even be lost, the editing is probably loose, and the photography is assumably rugged from the restoration attempts by the studios. It Happened One Night falls prey to these shortcomings, but it's the film's only real flaw, and not a big one at that. It's still a fairly entertaining movie and the restoration is actually successful most of the times. I couldn't take my eyes of It Happened One Night! It's a delightful film that should not be missed by any generation. Before Pretty Woman and Annie Hall were "the" romantic comedies of their times, there was It Happened One Night. Most of the romantic comedy plot devices we've seen used repeatedly, originated here and were so accepted by audiences and writers that they have grown into clich&eacute;. Aside from that, It Happened One Night combines classic stories (poor little rich girl, desperate reporter, train rides, extramarital affairs) into one sublime, Hollywood picture. The thing to any successful romantic comedy, besides the script having more on its cutting board than what the average joe-blow can bring to the table, is its stars. Think about how successful those two rom-coms I mentioned earlier would have been without Julia Roberts and Richard Gere or Woody Allen and Diane Keaton? Not very. The leading couple not only has marvelous chemistry together, but they both have the bolts to screw in a great performances. Clarke Gable in particular shines. His movie-star presence and ability to flow with a picture and character are on full display here. Claudette Colbert produces first rate acting, as well. It Happened One Night is a greatly pleasing film. You'll watch it with a smile on your face. It's funny and contains one of the best movie romances out there, a relationship that starts out in hostility, evolves to friendship, and is overcome with the realization of love. It Happened One Night is cute and having inspired a whole genre of films ahead of its time. Rating: 10/10 Grade: A+
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Whimsical love story breaks all the rules about love between the classes
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lucie Uche
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    First ever winner of five Oscars in all major categories, Best Picture, Best Director, Best Actor, Best Actress and Best Screenplay, the 1934 movie It Happened One Night is a whimsical romantic tale of fortuitous love between a spoiled socialite Ellen Andrews played by Claudette Colbert and a cantankerous newspaper reporter Peter Warne played by Clark Gable. The slapstick comedy collaboration from director Frank Capra and writer Robert Riskin, still remains quintessential viewing because of its clever and amusing portrayal of the pursuit of happiness and fulfillment. Ellen, recently married to infamous pilot King Westley (Jameson Thomas) against her millionaire father (Walter Connolly)'s orders is now cooped up on a yacht against her will with her father so that he can decidedly change her mind and have her marriage to the apparent gold digging cad annulled. Defiant Ellen who believes she is in love wants no part of her father's plan for her jumps ship to shore and eventually finds herself on a bus bound for New York. Here she hopes to reunite with her husband and live happily ever after. On board the Greyhound bus she meets Peter, none the worse for wear and recently fired from his newspaper for being drunk on the job. So begins an unlikely series of dealings between the two that stem from them agreeing to help each other out for a price of sorts. Peter recognizing Ellen from newspaper headlines as the much talked about runaway heiress, agrees to help her get to New York while she in turn offers him exclusive rights to her story, his hope is to revamp his career. The journey is series of memorable, classic, comical, events that draw the two closer together. Peter never one to hold back on his opinion and ever nonchalant, often chastises "Brat" his nickname for Ellen, because of her bourgeois tendencies and take on life, whereas he is a down to earth working class man; depicted in sharp close up clarity, every handsome rugged feature proving to be aesthetically camera friendly always defining his cool no nonsense sensibility. The two collide, bicker and banter about everything. There's is not an apparent match made in heaven but their liaison becomes more meaningful the longer they spend together. Peter is assiduous in keeping his promise to Ellen; Ellen is just doe eyed and realizes she is in love with the brash outspoken journalist. A timeless feature that that suggests Ellen's beauty and fragility is achieved with the application of a filtered lens on all of her close ups; this very effective application implies a softness and purity to her character. A notable fact about this seminal movie is the precedent it set for zany romantic comedies that would follow, such as Bringing up Baby (1938) and the Philadelphia Story (1940) both starring Katherine Hepburn and the impact it still has on screwball comedies today.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An antidote for depression
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Hotwok2013
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It isn't any wonder why "It Happened One Night" struck such a chord with movie-goers in the depression-hit USA of the 1930's. Frank Capra's sparkling romantic comedy is just about as uplifting as any movie possibly can be. Whatever it is that makes a star a star, Clark Gable had it in spades more than any other leading man before or since, & how could Claudette Colbert, (or any other woman?), not fall in love with him. Even allowing for the absurdities in the plot beginning with Ellie Andrews (Colbert) jumping her rich fathers yacht into the sea & swimming to shore. She is wearing a long white silk gown & not carrying a handbag. Next we see her at Miami bus station purchasing a ticket to New York in a new outfit with handbag!. The movie is full of memorably entertaining scenes & I guarantee that if anyone is feeling a bit low this film will improve their mood.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Romantic Comedy Supreme.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SmileysWorld
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Boy meets girl.They come from different roads in life and don't see eye to eye at first,but gradually they fall in love.This is a theme we have seen again and again throughout cinema history.Sometimes it is done well and sometimes..not so much.This is definitely the film that started it all,and the mold was broken.This is by far the best romantic comedy that I have ever seen.Claudette Colbert may not have thought so,for it has been said that she said to a friend after completing production that she had just finished "the worst film I have ever done."Surely she changed her tone when they placed the Best Actress Oscar in her hands.The screen chemistry between Colbert and Gable was right on the money.It is THE laugh out loud romantic classic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Young people in love are never hu-un-gry!" The granddaddy of all rom-coms
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    LouE15
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I stumbled across this film recently, expecting it to do no more than help me kill some time. Several viewings on, I'm hooked  it seems almost incredible that it was made in 1934, not 1984 or 2004. There isn't a romantic comedy in existence, and never will be, that doesn't owe a debt to this film. It's funny, modern, charming, and meaningful about people  what more do you want? Colour? Ah, nuts. Clark Gable plays Peter, a cynical journalist who ends up on a road trip across a Depression-hit USA with runaway heiress Ellen (Claudette Colbert). Ellen's sheltered life has done nothing to prepare her for the trials that lie ahead. She's so certain that she knows what she wants, and what's best: she's naive, but sparky and intelligent. She has to be knocked down in order to have her eyes peeled open. * Some spoilers from here* I thought I knew all about Clark Gable, and wasn't that bothered, but here he radiates masterful alpha-male charm and can switch on a dime from comedy to a love scene, boyish vulnerability to hardboiled cynic and back again. I don't know which version of him I liked more, although I think my favourite mini-moment comes when he's hardboiling it for the telegram girl, pipe in mouth - Philip Marlowe if ever there was one. The script is full of wonderful details  I don't know how much was in the original short story but I get the impression a great deal must have been added in to make it funnier. Oh, let me count the ways her not understanding what a real piggy back ride ishis hilariously terrible attempts at hitchhikingMr Believe You Me...Peter's "shut up" when they're back on the bus (which brings to mind James Cagney and That Grapefruit)and then his petulant sulk when he realises he's losing the upper hand, falling in love and just a shade jealousit's all great. I was hysterical by the time we met the operatic buggy driver  ever since I first saw the film I've been turning everyday trivialities into Gilbert & Sullivan libretto  and I just loved Peter's shouty conversation with Ellen's dad. But best of all are the lessons Ellen has to learn. For all her wealth and snobbery, and for all we enjoy her gradual comeuppance, she shows she's capable of learning (finally being hungry enough to eat a raw carrot!), and is worthy of Peter's love. When, near the end, she's weepily describing to her father how poor Peter's opinion is of them both ("you should hear what he says about you!"), capping it off with "he's marvellous(sob)", you're right there with her. "It happened one night" is in danger of eclipsing William Powell's wonderful "My Man Gordon" as my favourite thirties film. It's revised my lazy opinion about Clark Gable too  but it won't make me like "Gone with the Wind" any better, I don't care what anyone says.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Part one of two. My introduction of IHON, the background story on Capra's 1st miracle film.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Larry41OnEbay-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The idea for IT HAPPENED ONE NIGHT started in a barber shop while Frank Capra was waiting for a haircut he read an old magazine article in Cosmopolitan called "Night Bus" by Samuel Hopkins Adams. It was a cute idea so Capra asked Columbia studios to buy the rights to it and then he forgot about it. Frank's previous feature was LADY FOR A DAY which got great reviews and was Columbia studio's first film ever Oscar nominated and Capra's. Irving Thalberg wanted Capra to make his next film at MGM in exchange for $50k and the loan of a star. But at the last minute Louis B. Mayer canceled the film but honored the deal. Back at Columbia Capra wanted to make Night Bus, but studio tyrant Harry Cohn and all his advisers fought against it. They said things like, "It's nothing; froth, trivia, just another bus picture, no suspense, no heart, no oomph, winter's coming and it's all exteriors." All they could get Capra to do was change the title to IT HAPPENED ONE NIGHT which they said was too long to fit on a marquee! Capra tried casting Myrna Loy  she turned it down; then Margaret Sullavan  said 'no thank you'; Miriam Hopkins was insulted and said, 'Not if I never play another part'; Constance Bennett told him to go fly a kite and then offered to buy the script and have it rewritten for her! Capra had co-written the script with his favorite writer Robert Riskin but they brought in Myles Connolly who added more sympathetic and interesting characters so people could identify with them. The pretty girl, a spoiled brat, was rich yes but bored with being an heiress now wanting something real. The man was made a guy we all know and like; a tough crusading reporter on the outs with his pigheaded editor. It's The Taming Of The Shrew, but the shrew must be worth taming and the guy must be one of us. Back to casting, this time they went after Robert Montgomery a great light comedian at MGM. Mayer called Cohn and said, "Montgomery says there are too many bus pictures and (don't take this in the wrong way) but going from MGM to lowly Columbia was an insult. But you've caught me in a good mood. I got an actor here who's been a bad boy. Wants more money. And I'd like to spank him. You can have Clark Gable." Surprisingly the next knock on Capra's shabby office door came from a very drunk and cursing Gable, reporting to Siberia as he called it. Gable's objections almost made Capra throw in the towel but then Harry Cohn suggested getting Claudette Colbert for the girl in the story. (He had heard she liked money.) So Capra and Riskin made an appointment that very night to see her at her home. When they arrived Colbert regretted agreeing to the meeting as she was packing to leave on a month long skiing vacation. Capra saw this attractive, wealthy and spoiled woman and knew she was perfect for the part. So Capra, after being bit in the butt by her dog, asked what it would take to get her in the picture. (Capra had directed her first picture, FOR THE LOVE OF MIKE a silent made in 1927 and a flop) To throw him off she said she normally made $25k a picture (a price Columbia had never paid to an actor before), he would have to double it AND she was only available from her studio Paramount during her Christmas vacation. They would have to shoot all her scenes and retakes in less than 4 weeks -- half the time they had budgeted! So Capra called Cohn to ask would he pay her the $50k, Cohn said "I can pay it if you can shoot it in 4 weeks." Capra said, he didn't know, but he'd try. So they told her, "Deal, Claudette! $50k for 4 weeks! Okay?" To which she replied, "Oh for God's sake!" She was trapped. That next day she had to report for her costume fittings and the day after that they begin filming in a hurry. While they shot film all day Capra edited and rewrote the story to tighten it up at night. To make the film and story move quicker he asked the actors to talk faster, his amazing cinematographer Joseph Walker to shoot faster. (continued...)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    wonder why they called it, it happened one night
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lagudafuad
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It Happened One Night is one of the only three movies since the commencement of the Academy Awards to have been able to win all five major Academy Awards (Best Picture, Best Director, Best Actor, Best Actress, and Best Screenplay), a feat that would not be matched until One Flew Over the Cuckoo's Nest in 1975 and of cause latter on in 1991, Anthony Hopkins The Silence of the Lambs followed suit. Here is a romantic comedy as raw as they come giving you a thrill as you watch two people miss matched from the start found a way to fall in love and tour America on their way to New York. The funny thing about the movie is the name which says, "It happened one night" when actually in the movie's story it actually went on for more than a night. The movie plot is about Ellie Andrews (Claudette Colbert) who has been whisked away by her father in his yacht to keep her away from her new husband King Westley. Ellie then jumps ship, swim to shore and heads off to New York to meet with King Westley. On her way she meets a reporter Peter Warne (Clark Gable) and both started as an unsuitable pair that grew to be lovers. Both Colbert and Gable felt the movie was not going to be good enough and gave Capra a lot of bull. Even the movie's iconic scene where Colbert lifted up her skirt to stop a car during the hitchhiking scene, was not so easy to film for Capra as Colbert refused to do the scene claiming it was not lady like, but upon seeing a body double do it, she later changed her mind and did it herself. Although picking up slow, the movie later became one the biggest hits for the studio and the thing is that at the end the movie cleared the Academy Awards and both Gable and Colbert were better off. Colbert is known to have told a friend, "I just finished the worst picture in the world." She boycotted the Academy Awards when she got a nomination believing she will not win, but she was called back to come pick up her award. Here is a movie that actually makes you smile all the way through, although like the actors themselves upon initial siting of the film you can be turned off thinking this is heading nowhere, but be patient the movie has all the familiar scenes that we see in the movies today (all taken from this old classic). This old classic is tagged the 46th greatest film in the last 100 years in the AFI's 100 Years... 100 Movies (10th Anniversary Edition). It Happened One Night is a nice DVD for one to place on the shelf. www.lagsreviews.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It Remains The Best Romantic Comedy Ever Released On Screen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It Happened One Night is a romantic comedy film with elements of screwball comedy directed by Frank Capra, in which a pampered socialite tries to get out from under her father's thumb, and falls in love with a roguish reporter. It features Clark Gable,Claudette Colbert and Walter Connolly.The plot was based on the short story Night Bus by Samuel Hopkins Adams, which provided the shooting title. Ellie Andrews is a spoiled heiress who has married fortune-hunting aviator King Westley, despite her father's objections. To keep Ellie from marrying this Lothario, her father has been holding her prisoner aboard his yacht. But Ellie bolts from the yacht, swims ashore in her clothes, and eventually slips onto a Greyhound bus bound for New York. Aboard the bus is newspaper reporter Peter Warne, who has recently been fired for drinking on the job. Peter gets the last seat on the bus but when he gets up to argue with the bus driver, Ellie takes his seat. Since it is the last seat on the bus, they have to share it. When Ellie has her purse stolen and she refuses to report it, Peter begins to suspect something. The next morning, they both miss the bus after a leisurely breakfast, and Peter reveals that he knows her identity. She makes a deal with him: if he helps her get to New York, he can write a scoop about her for his paper. Peter thinks she is a spoiled brat, however, and refuses a monetary bribe: "I'm not interested in your money or your problem. You, King Westley, your father you're all a lot of hooey to me" But as they travel northward and engage in a series of misadventures, the gruff newspaperman and the spoiled rich girl, thrown together by circumstances, fall in love with each other. Director Frank Capra took home every major Oscars for this seminal comedy. Funny and sexy, the film is full of memorable scenes often referred to in other films, such as the "walls of Jericho" and Colbert's famous flash of thigh to stop a speeding car in its tracks.This is Capra at his best, very funny and very light, with a minimum of populist posturing.His brisk, urbane brand of wit was a perfect complement to his populist faith in the common man, and that inspired combination makes this film both a spirited entertainment and an uplifting experience.This is still is pure delight to watch at present and it still remains the best screwball comedy ever released as remains unsurpassed by the countless romantic comedies it has inspired.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Interesting "Time Travel" to an era
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bob Pr.
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Background to that '30s era: this 1934 film is often called the first (of the many following) in the 'screwball comedy' genre; it came out in the worst of the Great Depression (US unemployment in 1928 was 2.9%, by 1933 it hit 25%; millions were hungry and desperate, leading to some antagonisms between economic classes). This was also a time when women's roles were changing in the US: the 'women's suffrage' movement gained women the right to vote in 1920 (19th Amendment), more equality in decision-making, more freedom in dress, gender & sexual roles (e.g., '20s 'Flappers'). "Screwball comedies" capitalized and fed on those changes: they typically "feature farcical situations, a combination of slap-stick with fast-paced repartee and show struggles between" (central characters of different) "economic classes. They also generally feature a self-confident and often stubborn central female protagonist and a plot involving courtship and marriage or remarriage" ("quotes" from Wikipedia). A young 30's Gable plays "Peter," a drinking, hard boiled newspaper reporter just fired from his job when he accidentally meets the young 20's "Ellie" (a young 30's Colbert) who's increasingly rebelled against the escalating but failing attempts of her upper class, super-rich father to control her. He tries to keep her on his Florida yacht while arranging to annul Ellie's impulsive marriage to a man (whom her father recognizes but Ellie doesn't as mainly interested in her wealth). But Ellie escapes her father's captivity and sets off to NYC to be reunited with her new spouse. On her way, she meets Gable who's initially interested in helping her because it'll lead to his scoop of a newspaper story (and reinstatement of his job). But then--romance eventually, gradually, starts to happen between you know who. My rating: 6 of 10 I found this interesting as a time-traveling experience--early '30s bus rides, clothes, roles, attitudes, etc.-- but all the people seemed to me to be too much caricatures and not enough real characters. (However, many people on IMDb's "Discussion Board" say the more often they've seen this film, the more highly they value it--many saying it's among their most favorite films of all--so maybe familiarity breeds appreciation?) FWIW: Neither Gable nor Colbert wanted to be in this film; MGM "loaned" them to Columbia Pictures, then a 2nd rate movie company, for this movie as punishment for each being too "uppity" and/or violating MGM policies. But, after this film gained such outstanding success (lifting Columbia's rank to among the majors) and substantially helped both Gable's & Colbert's careers, they came to appreciate it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Who would of thunk it !
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    traversvcs6
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you happen to own or rent this movie I'd suggest watching it a second time with the directors son's commentary during the picture. He gives such an inspiring outlook on just how remarkable this picture was having been made in limited limited time and budget. How under appreciated it was by the producers to make, how the main actors were more or less coerced into doing the picture. How it was first met with so so reviews by the sophisticated New York City audience. Yet it was made so across the US of A it was put in theaters and what do you know it remained there for a record number of weeks. The movie goers of the time enjoyed it so they went back to see it again bringing family and friends cause they knew they had seen something truly awesome. Come Oscar time it took the five biggies, Best Picture, Leading actor and actress, writer and director. A feat not repeated again until One Flew Over the Cuckoos Nest. Yes this is a gem and that it became so at such odds makes it more so and should be in every movie lover's library! I loved it :)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cute and delightful!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RyanCShowers
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of the most important Best Picture winners feels like one of the most unnecessary Best Picture winners by some. When one says "Best Picture Winner", you think the said film must meet a certain criteria, such as war drama or epic production value-centric story, that certifies it that prestigious title. It Happened One Night has neither of those, though it does achieve a wonderful romance brought to life by Clarke Gable and Claudette Colbert and contains a screenplay as fresh as the carrots Clarke Gable eats himself during the picture. Movies of the 1930s (and earlier) have reoccurring problems when they are put up to the task of competing with newer pictures using today's standards of film perfection: they lack the tight, technical exertion. The sound is often terrible, some dialogue may even be lost, the editing is probably loose, and the photography is assumably rugged from the restoration attempts by the studios. It Happened One Night falls prey to these shortcomings, but it's the film's only real flaw, and not a big one at that. It's still a fairly entertaining movie and the restoration is actually successful most of the times. I couldn't take my eyes of It Happened One Night! It's a delightful film that should not be missed by any generation. Before Pretty Woman and Annie Hall were "the" romantic comedies of their times, there was It Happened One Night. Most of the romantic comedy plot devices we've seen used repeatedly, originated here and were so accepted by audiences and writers that they have grown into clich&eacute;. Aside from that, It Happened One Night combines classic stories (poor little rich girl, desperate reporter, train rides, extramarital affairs) into one sublime, Hollywood picture. The thing to any successful romantic comedy, besides the script having more on its cutting board than what the average joe-blow can bring to the table, is its stars. Think about how successful those two rom-coms I mentioned earlier would have been without Julia Roberts and Richard Gere or Woody Allen and Diane Keaton? Not very. The leading couple not only has marvelous chemistry together, but they both have the bolts to screw in a great performances. Clarke Gable in particular shines. His movie-star presence and ability to flow with a picture and character are on full display here. Claudette Colbert produces first rate acting, as well. It Happened One Night is a greatly pleasing film. You'll watch it with a smile on your face. It's funny and contains one of the best movie romances out there, a relationship that starts out in hostility, evolves to friendship, and is overcome with the realization of love. It Happened One Night is cute and having inspired a whole genre of films ahead of its time. Rating: 10/10 Grade: A+
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Whimsical love story breaks all the rules about love between the classes
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lucie Uche
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    First ever winner of five Oscars in all major categories, Best Picture, Best Director, Best Actor, Best Actress and Best Screenplay, the 1934 movie It Happened One Night is a whimsical romantic tale of fortuitous love between a spoiled socialite Ellen Andrews played by Claudette Colbert and a cantankerous newspaper reporter Peter Warne played by Clark Gable. The slapstick comedy collaboration from director Frank Capra and writer Robert Riskin, still remains quintessential viewing because of its clever and amusing portrayal of the pursuit of happiness and fulfillment. Ellen, recently married to infamous pilot King Westley (Jameson Thomas) against her millionaire father (Walter Connolly)'s orders is now cooped up on a yacht against her will with her father so that he can decidedly change her mind and have her marriage to the apparent gold digging cad annulled. Defiant Ellen who believes she is in love wants no part of her father's plan for her jumps ship to shore and eventually finds herself on a bus bound for New York. Here she hopes to reunite with her husband and live happily ever after. On board the Greyhound bus she meets Peter, none the worse for wear and recently fired from his newspaper for being drunk on the job. So begins an unlikely series of dealings between the two that stem from them agreeing to help each other out for a price of sorts. Peter recognizing Ellen from newspaper headlines as the much talked about runaway heiress, agrees to help her get to New York while she in turn offers him exclusive rights to her story, his hope is to revamp his career. The journey is series of memorable, classic, comical, events that draw the two closer together. Peter never one to hold back on his opinion and ever nonchalant, often chastises "Brat" his nickname for Ellen, because of her bourgeois tendencies and take on life, whereas he is a down to earth working class man; depicted in sharp close up clarity, every handsome rugged feature proving to be aesthetically camera friendly always defining his cool no nonsense sensibility. The two collide, bicker and banter about everything. There's is not an apparent match made in heaven but their liaison becomes more meaningful the longer they spend together. Peter is assiduous in keeping his promise to Ellen; Ellen is just doe eyed and realizes she is in love with the brash outspoken journalist. A timeless feature that that suggests Ellen's beauty and fragility is achieved with the application of a filtered lens on all of her close ups; this very effective application implies a softness and purity to her character. A notable fact about this seminal movie is the precedent it set for zany romantic comedies that would follow, such as Bringing up Baby (1938) and the Philadelphia Story (1940) both starring Katherine Hepburn and the impact it still has on screwball comedies today.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An antidote for depression
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Hotwok2013
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It isn't any wonder why "It Happened One Night" struck such a chord with movie-goers in the depression-hit USA of the 1930's. Frank Capra's sparkling romantic comedy is just about as uplifting as any movie possibly can be. Whatever it is that makes a star a star, Clark Gable had it in spades more than any other leading man before or since, & how could Claudette Colbert, (or any other woman?), not fall in love with him. Even allowing for the absurdities in the plot beginning with Ellie Andrews (Colbert) jumping her rich fathers yacht into the sea & swimming to shore. She is wearing a long white silk gown & not carrying a handbag. Next we see her at Miami bus station purchasing a ticket to New York in a new outfit with handbag!. The movie is full of memorably entertaining scenes & I guarantee that if anyone is feeling a bit low this film will improve their mood.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Romantic Comedy Supreme.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SmileysWorld
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Boy meets girl.They come from different roads in life and don't see eye to eye at first,but gradually they fall in love.This is a theme we have seen again and again throughout cinema history.Sometimes it is done well and sometimes..not so much.This is definitely the film that started it all,and the mold was broken.This is by far the best romantic comedy that I have ever seen.Claudette Colbert may not have thought so,for it has been said that she said to a friend after completing production that she had just finished "the worst film I have ever done."Surely she changed her tone when they placed the Best Actress Oscar in her hands.The screen chemistry between Colbert and Gable was right on the money.It is THE laugh out loud romantic classic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Young people in love are never hu-un-gry!" The granddaddy of all rom-coms
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    LouE15
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I stumbled across this film recently, expecting it to do no more than help me kill some time. Several viewings on, I'm hooked  it seems almost incredible that it was made in 1934, not 1984 or 2004. There isn't a romantic comedy in existence, and never will be, that doesn't owe a debt to this film. It's funny, modern, charming, and meaningful about people  what more do you want? Colour? Ah, nuts. Clark Gable plays Peter, a cynical journalist who ends up on a road trip across a Depression-hit USA with runaway heiress Ellen (Claudette Colbert). Ellen's sheltered life has done nothing to prepare her for the trials that lie ahead. She's so certain that she knows what she wants, and what's best: she's naive, but sparky and intelligent. She has to be knocked down in order to have her eyes peeled open. * Some spoilers from here* I thought I knew all about Clark Gable, and wasn't that bothered, but here he radiates masterful alpha-male charm and can switch on a dime from comedy to a love scene, boyish vulnerability to hardboiled cynic and back again. I don't know which version of him I liked more, although I think my favourite mini-moment comes when he's hardboiling it for the telegram girl, pipe in mouth - Philip Marlowe if ever there was one. The script is full of wonderful details  I don't know how much was in the original short story but I get the impression a great deal must have been added in to make it funnier. Oh, let me count the ways her not understanding what a real piggy back ride ishis hilariously terrible attempts at hitchhikingMr Believe You Me...Peter's "shut up" when they're back on the bus (which brings to mind James Cagney and That Grapefruit)and then his petulant sulk when he realises he's losing the upper hand, falling in love and just a shade jealousit's all great. I was hysterical by the time we met the operatic buggy driver  ever since I first saw the film I've been turning everyday trivialities into Gilbert & Sullivan libretto  and I just loved Peter's shouty conversation with Ellen's dad. But best of all are the lessons Ellen has to learn. For all her wealth and snobbery, and for all we enjoy her gradual comeuppance, she shows she's capable of learning (finally being hungry enough to eat a raw carrot!), and is worthy of Peter's love. When, near the end, she's weepily describing to her father how poor Peter's opinion is of them both ("you should hear what he says about you!"), capping it off with "he's marvellous(sob)", you're right there with her. "It happened one night" is in danger of eclipsing William Powell's wonderful "My Man Gordon" as my favourite thirties film. It's revised my lazy opinion about Clark Gable too  but it won't make me like "Gone with the Wind" any better, I don't care what anyone says.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Part one of two. My introduction of IHON, the background story on Capra's 1st miracle film.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Larry41OnEbay-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The idea for IT HAPPENED ONE NIGHT started in a barber shop while Frank Capra was waiting for a haircut he read an old magazine article in Cosmopolitan called "Night Bus" by Samuel Hopkins Adams. It was a cute idea so Capra asked Columbia studios to buy the rights to it and then he forgot about it. Frank's previous feature was LADY FOR A DAY which got great reviews and was Columbia studio's first film ever Oscar nominated and Capra's. Irving Thalberg wanted Capra to make his next film at MGM in exchange for $50k and the loan of a star. But at the last minute Louis B. Mayer canceled the film but honored the deal. Back at Columbia Capra wanted to make Night Bus, but studio tyrant Harry Cohn and all his advisers fought against it. They said things like, "It's nothing; froth, trivia, just another bus picture, no suspense, no heart, no oomph, winter's coming and it's all exteriors." All they could get Capra to do was change the title to IT HAPPENED ONE NIGHT which they said was too long to fit on a marquee! Capra tried casting Myrna Loy  she turned it down; then Margaret Sullavan  said 'no thank you'; Miriam Hopkins was insulted and said, 'Not if I never play another part'; Constance Bennett told him to go fly a kite and then offered to buy the script and have it rewritten for her! Capra had co-written the script with his favorite writer Robert Riskin but they brought in Myles Connolly who added more sympathetic and interesting characters so people could identify with them. The pretty girl, a spoiled brat, was rich yes but bored with being an heiress now wanting something real. The man was made a guy we all know and like; a tough crusading reporter on the outs with his pigheaded editor. It's The Taming Of The Shrew, but the shrew must be worth taming and the guy must be one of us. Back to casting, this time they went after Robert Montgomery a great light comedian at MGM. Mayer called Cohn and said, "Montgomery says there are too many bus pictures and (don't take this in the wrong way) but going from MGM to lowly Columbia was an insult. But you've caught me in a good mood. I got an actor here who's been a bad boy. Wants more money. And I'd like to spank him. You can have Clark Gable." Surprisingly the next knock on Capra's shabby office door came from a very drunk and cursing Gable, reporting to Siberia as he called it. Gable's objections almost made Capra throw in the towel but then Harry Cohn suggested getting Claudette Colbert for the girl in the story. (He had heard she liked money.) So Capra and Riskin made an appointment that very night to see her at her home. When they arrived Colbert regretted agreeing to the meeting as she was packing to leave on a month long skiing vacation. Capra saw this attractive, wealthy and spoiled woman and knew she was perfect for the part. So Capra, after being bit in the butt by her dog, asked what it would take to get her in the picture. (Capra had directed her first picture, FOR THE LOVE OF MIKE a silent made in 1927 and a flop) To throw him off she said she normally made $25k a picture (a price Columbia had never paid to an actor before), he would have to double it AND she was only available from her studio Paramount during her Christmas vacation. They would have to shoot all her scenes and retakes in less than 4 weeks -- half the time they had budgeted! So Capra called Cohn to ask would he pay her the $50k, Cohn said "I can pay it if you can shoot it in 4 weeks." Capra said, he didn't know, but he'd try. So they told her, "Deal, Claudette! $50k for 4 weeks! Okay?" To which she replied, "Oh for God's sake!" She was trapped. That next day she had to report for her costume fittings and the day after that they begin filming in a hurry. While they shot film all day Capra edited and rewrote the story to tighten it up at night. To make the film and story move quicker he asked the actors to talk faster, his amazing cinematographer Joseph Walker to shoot faster. (continued...)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    wonder why they called it, it happened one night
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lagudafuad
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It Happened One Night is one of the only three movies since the commencement of the Academy Awards to have been able to win all five major Academy Awards (Best Picture, Best Director, Best Actor, Best Actress, and Best Screenplay), a feat that would not be matched until One Flew Over the Cuckoo's Nest in 1975 and of cause latter on in 1991, Anthony Hopkins The Silence of the Lambs followed suit. Here is a romantic comedy as raw as they come giving you a thrill as you watch two people miss matched from the start found a way to fall in love and tour America on their way to New York. The funny thing about the movie is the name which says, "It happened one night" when actually in the movie's story it actually went on for more than a night. The movie plot is about Ellie Andrews (Claudette Colbert) who has been whisked away by her father in his yacht to keep her away from her new husband King Westley. Ellie then jumps ship, swim to shore and heads off to New York to meet with King Westley. On her way she meets a reporter Peter Warne (Clark Gable) and both started as an unsuitable pair that grew to be lovers. Both Colbert and Gable felt the movie was not going to be good enough and gave Capra a lot of bull. Even the movie's iconic scene where Colbert lifted up her skirt to stop a car during the hitchhiking scene, was not so easy to film for Capra as Colbert refused to do the scene claiming it was not lady like, but upon seeing a body double do it, she later changed her mind and did it herself. Although picking up slow, the movie later became one the biggest hits for the studio and the thing is that at the end the movie cleared the Academy Awards and both Gable and Colbert were better off. Colbert is known to have told a friend, "I just finished the worst picture in the world." She boycotted the Academy Awards when she got a nomination believing she will not win, but she was called back to come pick up her award. Here is a movie that actually makes you smile all the way through, although like the actors themselves upon initial siting of the film you can be turned off thinking this is heading nowhere, but be patient the movie has all the familiar scenes that we see in the movies today (all taken from this old classic). This old classic is tagged the 46th greatest film in the last 100 years in the AFI's 100 Years... 100 Movies (10th Anniversary Edition). It Happened One Night is a nice DVD for one to place on the shelf. www.lagsreviews.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It Remains The Best Romantic Comedy Ever Released On Screen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It Happened One Night is a romantic comedy film with elements of screwball comedy directed by Frank Capra, in which a pampered socialite tries to get out from under her father's thumb, and falls in love with a roguish reporter. It features Clark Gable,Claudette Colbert and Walter Connolly.The plot was based on the short story Night Bus by Samuel Hopkins Adams, which provided the shooting title. Ellie Andrews is a spoiled heiress who has married fortune-hunting aviator King Westley, despite her father's objections. To keep Ellie from marrying this Lothario, her father has been holding her prisoner aboard his yacht. But Ellie bolts from the yacht, swims ashore in her clothes, and eventually slips onto a Greyhound bus bound for New York. Aboard the bus is newspaper reporter Peter Warne, who has recently been fired for drinking on the job. Peter gets the last seat on the bus but when he gets up to argue with the bus driver, Ellie takes his seat. Since it is the last seat on the bus, they have to share it. When Ellie has her purse stolen and she refuses to report it, Peter begins to suspect something. The next morning, they both miss the bus after a leisurely breakfast, and Peter reveals that he knows her identity. She makes a deal with him: if he helps her get to New York, he can write a scoop about her for his paper. Peter thinks she is a spoiled brat, however, and refuses a monetary bribe: "I'm not interested in your money or your problem. You, King Westley, your father you're all a lot of hooey to me" But as they travel northward and engage in a series of misadventures, the gruff newspaperman and the spoiled rich girl, thrown together by circumstances, fall in love with each other. Director Frank Capra took home every major Oscars for this seminal comedy. Funny and sexy, the film is full of memorable scenes often referred to in other films, such as the "walls of Jericho" and Colbert's famous flash of thigh to stop a speeding car in its tracks.This is Capra at his best, very funny and very light, with a minimum of populist posturing.His brisk, urbane brand of wit was a perfect complement to his populist faith in the common man, and that inspired combination makes this film both a spirited entertainment and an uplifting experience.This is still is pure delight to watch at present and it still remains the best screwball comedy ever released as remains unsurpassed by the countless romantic comedies it has inspired.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Interesting "Time Travel" to an era
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bob Pr.
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Background to that '30s era: this 1934 film is often called the first (of the many following) in the 'screwball comedy' genre; it came out in the worst of the Great Depression (US unemployment in 1928 was 2.9%, by 1933 it hit 25%; millions were hungry and desperate, leading to some antagonisms between economic classes). This was also a time when women's roles were changing in the US: the 'women's suffrage' movement gained women the right to vote in 1920 (19th Amendment), more equality in decision-making, more freedom in dress, gender & sexual roles (e.g., '20s 'Flappers'). "Screwball comedies" capitalized and fed on those changes: they typically "feature farcical situations, a combination of slap-stick with fast-paced repartee and show struggles between" (central characters of different) "economic classes. They also generally feature a self-confident and often stubborn central female protagonist and a plot involving courtship and marriage or remarriage" ("quotes" from Wikipedia). A young 30's Gable plays "Peter," a drinking, hard boiled newspaper reporter just fired from his job when he accidentally meets the young 20's "Ellie" (a young 30's Colbert) who's increasingly rebelled against the escalating but failing attempts of her upper class, super-rich father to control her. He tries to keep her on his Florida yacht while arranging to annul Ellie's impulsive marriage to a man (whom her father recognizes but Ellie doesn't as mainly interested in her wealth). But Ellie escapes her father's captivity and sets off to NYC to be reunited with her new spouse. On her way, she meets Gable who's initially interested in helping her because it'll lead to his scoop of a newspaper story (and reinstatement of his job). But then--romance eventually, gradually, starts to happen between you know who. My rating: 6 of 10 I found this interesting as a time-traveling experience--early '30s bus rides, clothes, roles, attitudes, etc.-- but all the people seemed to me to be too much caricatures and not enough real characters. (However, many people on IMDb's "Discussion Board" say the more often they've seen this film, the more highly they value it--many saying it's among their most favorite films of all--so maybe familiarity breeds appreciation?) FWIW: Neither Gable nor Colbert wanted to be in this film; MGM "loaned" them to Columbia Pictures, then a 2nd rate movie company, for this movie as punishment for each being too "uppity" and/or violating MGM policies. But, after this film gained such outstanding success (lifting Columbia's rank to among the majors) and substantially helped both Gable's & Colbert's careers, they came to appreciate it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Who would of thunk it !
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    traversvcs6
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you happen to own or rent this movie I'd suggest watching it a second time with the directors son's commentary during the picture. He gives such an inspiring outlook on just how remarkable this picture was having been made in limited limited time and budget. How under appreciated it was by the producers to make, how the main actors were more or less coerced into doing the picture. How it was first met with so so reviews by the sophisticated New York City audience. Yet it was made so across the US of A it was put in theaters and what do you know it remained there for a record number of weeks. The movie goers of the time enjoyed it so they went back to see it again bringing family and friends cause they knew they had seen something truly awesome. Come Oscar time it took the five biggies, Best Picture, Leading actor and actress, writer and director. A feat not repeated again until One Flew Over the Cuckoos Nest. Yes this is a gem and that it became so at such odds makes it more so and should be in every movie lover's library! I loved it :)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cute and delightful!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RyanCShowers
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of the most important Best Picture winners feels like one of the most unnecessary Best Picture winners by some. When one says "Best Picture Winner", you think the said film must meet a certain criteria, such as war drama or epic production value-centric story, that certifies it that prestigious title. It Happened One Night has neither of those, though it does achieve a wonderful romance brought to life by Clarke Gable and Claudette Colbert and contains a screenplay as fresh as the carrots Clarke Gable eats himself during the picture. Movies of the 1930s (and earlier) have reoccurring problems when they are put up to the task of competing with newer pictures using today's standards of film perfection: they lack the tight, technical exertion. The sound is often terrible, some dialogue may even be lost, the editing is probably loose, and the photography is assumably rugged from the restoration attempts by the studios. It Happened One Night falls prey to these shortcomings, but it's the film's only real flaw, and not a big one at that. It's still a fairly entertaining movie and the restoration is actually successful most of the times. I couldn't take my eyes of It Happened One Night! It's a delightful film that should not be missed by any generation. Before Pretty Woman and Annie Hall were "the" romantic comedies of their times, there was It Happened One Night. Most of the romantic comedy plot devices we've seen used repeatedly, originated here and were so accepted by audiences and writers that they have grown into clich&eacute;. Aside from that, It Happened One Night combines classic stories (poor little rich girl, desperate reporter, train rides, extramarital affairs) into one sublime, Hollywood picture. The thing to any successful romantic comedy, besides the script having more on its cutting board than what the average joe-blow can bring to the table, is its stars. Think about how successful those two rom-coms I mentioned earlier would have been without Julia Roberts and Richard Gere or Woody Allen and Diane Keaton? Not very. The leading couple not only has marvelous chemistry together, but they both have the bolts to screw in a great performances. Clarke Gable in particular shines. His movie-star presence and ability to flow with a picture and character are on full display here. Claudette Colbert produces first rate acting, as well. It Happened One Night is a greatly pleasing film. You'll watch it with a smile on your face. It's funny and contains one of the best movie romances out there, a relationship that starts out in hostility, evolves to friendship, and is overcome with the realization of love. It Happened One Night is cute and having inspired a whole genre of films ahead of its time. Rating: 10/10 Grade: A+
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Whimsical love story breaks all the rules about love between the classes
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lucie Uche
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    First ever winner of five Oscars in all major categories, Best Picture, Best Director, Best Actor, Best Actress and Best Screenplay, the 1934 movie It Happened One Night is a whimsical romantic tale of fortuitous love between a spoiled socialite Ellen Andrews played by Claudette Colbert and a cantankerous newspaper reporter Peter Warne played by Clark Gable. The slapstick comedy collaboration from director Frank Capra and writer Robert Riskin, still remains quintessential viewing because of its clever and amusing portrayal of the pursuit of happiness and fulfillment. Ellen, recently married to infamous pilot King Westley (Jameson Thomas) against her millionaire father (Walter Connolly)'s orders is now cooped up on a yacht against her will with her father so that he can decidedly change her mind and have her marriage to the apparent gold digging cad annulled. Defiant Ellen who believes she is in love wants no part of her father's plan for her jumps ship to shore and eventually finds herself on a bus bound for New York. Here she hopes to reunite with her husband and live happily ever after. On board the Greyhound bus she meets Peter, none the worse for wear and recently fired from his newspaper for being drunk on the job. So begins an unlikely series of dealings between the two that stem from them agreeing to help each other out for a price of sorts. Peter recognizing Ellen from newspaper headlines as the much talked about runaway heiress, agrees to help her get to New York while she in turn offers him exclusive rights to her story, his hope is to revamp his career. The journey is series of memorable, classic, comical, events that draw the two closer together. Peter never one to hold back on his opinion and ever nonchalant, often chastises "Brat" his nickname for Ellen, because of her bourgeois tendencies and take on life, whereas he is a down to earth working class man; depicted in sharp close up clarity, every handsome rugged feature proving to be aesthetically camera friendly always defining his cool no nonsense sensibility. The two collide, bicker and banter about everything. There's is not an apparent match made in heaven but their liaison becomes more meaningful the longer they spend together. Peter is assiduous in keeping his promise to Ellen; Ellen is just doe eyed and realizes she is in love with the brash outspoken journalist. A timeless feature that that suggests Ellen's beauty and fragility is achieved with the application of a filtered lens on all of her close ups; this very effective application implies a softness and purity to her character. A notable fact about this seminal movie is the precedent it set for zany romantic comedies that would follow, such as Bringing up Baby (1938) and the Philadelphia Story (1940) both starring Katherine Hepburn and the impact it still has on screwball comedies today.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An antidote for depression
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Hotwok2013
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It isn't any wonder why "It Happened One Night" struck such a chord with movie-goers in the depression-hit USA of the 1930's. Frank Capra's sparkling romantic comedy is just about as uplifting as any movie possibly can be. Whatever it is that makes a star a star, Clark Gable had it in spades more than any other leading man before or since, & how could Claudette Colbert, (or any other woman?), not fall in love with him. Even allowing for the absurdities in the plot beginning with Ellie Andrews (Colbert) jumping her rich fathers yacht into the sea & swimming to shore. She is wearing a long white silk gown & not carrying a handbag. Next we see her at Miami bus station purchasing a ticket to New York in a new outfit with handbag!. The movie is full of memorably entertaining scenes & I guarantee that if anyone is feeling a bit low this film will improve their mood.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Romantic Comedy Supreme.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SmileysWorld
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Boy meets girl.They come from different roads in life and don't see eye to eye at first,but gradually they fall in love.This is a theme we have seen again and again throughout cinema history.Sometimes it is done well and sometimes..not so much.This is definitely the film that started it all,and the mold was broken.This is by far the best romantic comedy that I have ever seen.Claudette Colbert may not have thought so,for it has been said that she said to a friend after completing production that she had just finished "the worst film I have ever done."Surely she changed her tone when they placed the Best Actress Oscar in her hands.The screen chemistry between Colbert and Gable was right on the money.It is THE laugh out loud romantic classic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Young people in love are never hu-un-gry!" The granddaddy of all rom-coms
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    LouE15
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I stumbled across this film recently, expecting it to do no more than help me kill some time. Several viewings on, I'm hooked  it seems almost incredible that it was made in 1934, not 1984 or 2004. There isn't a romantic comedy in existence, and never will be, that doesn't owe a debt to this film. It's funny, modern, charming, and meaningful about people  what more do you want? Colour? Ah, nuts. Clark Gable plays Peter, a cynical journalist who ends up on a road trip across a Depression-hit USA with runaway heiress Ellen (Claudette Colbert). Ellen's sheltered life has done nothing to prepare her for the trials that lie ahead. She's so certain that she knows what she wants, and what's best: she's naive, but sparky and intelligent. She has to be knocked down in order to have her eyes peeled open. * Some spoilers from here* I thought I knew all about Clark Gable, and wasn't that bothered, but here he radiates masterful alpha-male charm and can switch on a dime from comedy to a love scene, boyish vulnerability to hardboiled cynic and back again. I don't know which version of him I liked more, although I think my favourite mini-moment comes when he's hardboiling it for the telegram girl, pipe in mouth - Philip Marlowe if ever there was one. The script is full of wonderful details  I don't know how much was in the original short story but I get the impression a great deal must have been added in to make it funnier. Oh, let me count the ways her not understanding what a real piggy back ride ishis hilariously terrible attempts at hitchhikingMr Believe You Me...Peter's "shut up" when they're back on the bus (which brings to mind James Cagney and That Grapefruit)and then his petulant sulk when he realises he's losing the upper hand, falling in love and just a shade jealousit's all great. I was hysterical by the time we met the operatic buggy driver  ever since I first saw the film I've been turning everyday trivialities into Gilbert & Sullivan libretto  and I just loved Peter's shouty conversation with Ellen's dad. But best of all are the lessons Ellen has to learn. For all her wealth and snobbery, and for all we enjoy her gradual comeuppance, she shows she's capable of learning (finally being hungry enough to eat a raw carrot!), and is worthy of Peter's love. When, near the end, she's weepily describing to her father how poor Peter's opinion is of them both ("you should hear what he says about you!"), capping it off with "he's marvellous(sob)", you're right there with her. "It happened one night" is in danger of eclipsing William Powell's wonderful "My Man Gordon" as my favourite thirties film. It's revised my lazy opinion about Clark Gable too  but it won't make me like "Gone with the Wind" any better, I don't care what anyone says.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Part one of two. My introduction of IHON, the background story on Capra's 1st miracle film.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Larry41OnEbay-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The idea for IT HAPPENED ONE NIGHT started in a barber shop while Frank Capra was waiting for a haircut he read an old magazine article in Cosmopolitan called "Night Bus" by Samuel Hopkins Adams. It was a cute idea so Capra asked Columbia studios to buy the rights to it and then he forgot about it. Frank's previous feature was LADY FOR A DAY which got great reviews and was Columbia studio's first film ever Oscar nominated and Capra's. Irving Thalberg wanted Capra to make his next film at MGM in exchange for $50k and the loan of a star. But at the last minute Louis B. Mayer canceled the film but honored the deal. Back at Columbia Capra wanted to make Night Bus, but studio tyrant Harry Cohn and all his advisers fought against it. They said things like, "It's nothing; froth, trivia, just another bus picture, no suspense, no heart, no oomph, winter's coming and it's all exteriors." All they could get Capra to do was change the title to IT HAPPENED ONE NIGHT which they said was too long to fit on a marquee! Capra tried casting Myrna Loy  she turned it down; then Margaret Sullavan  said 'no thank you'; Miriam Hopkins was insulted and said, 'Not if I never play another part'; Constance Bennett told him to go fly a kite and then offered to buy the script and have it rewritten for her! Capra had co-written the script with his favorite writer Robert Riskin but they brought in Myles Connolly who added more sympathetic and interesting characters so people could identify with them. The pretty girl, a spoiled brat, was rich yes but bored with being an heiress now wanting something real. The man was made a guy we all know and like; a tough crusading reporter on the outs with his pigheaded editor. It's The Taming Of The Shrew, but the shrew must be worth taming and the guy must be one of us. Back to casting, this time they went after Robert Montgomery a great light comedian at MGM. Mayer called Cohn and said, "Montgomery says there are too many bus pictures and (don't take this in the wrong way) but going from MGM to lowly Columbia was an insult. But you've caught me in a good mood. I got an actor here who's been a bad boy. Wants more money. And I'd like to spank him. You can have Clark Gable." Surprisingly the next knock on Capra's shabby office door came from a very drunk and cursing Gable, reporting to Siberia as he called it. Gable's objections almost made Capra throw in the towel but then Harry Cohn suggested getting Claudette Colbert for the girl in the story. (He had heard she liked money.) So Capra and Riskin made an appointment that very night to see her at her home. When they arrived Colbert regretted agreeing to the meeting as she was packing to leave on a month long skiing vacation. Capra saw this attractive, wealthy and spoiled woman and knew she was perfect for the part. So Capra, after being bit in the butt by her dog, asked what it would take to get her in the picture. (Capra had directed her first picture, FOR THE LOVE OF MIKE a silent made in 1927 and a flop) To throw him off she said she normally made $25k a picture (a price Columbia had never paid to an actor before), he would have to double it AND she was only available from her studio Paramount during her Christmas vacation. They would have to shoot all her scenes and retakes in less than 4 weeks -- half the time they had budgeted! So Capra called Cohn to ask would he pay her the $50k, Cohn said "I can pay it if you can shoot it in 4 weeks." Capra said, he didn't know, but he'd try. So they told her, "Deal, Claudette! $50k for 4 weeks! Okay?" To which she replied, "Oh for God's sake!" She was trapped. That next day she had to report for her costume fittings and the day after that they begin filming in a hurry. While they shot film all day Capra edited and rewrote the story to tighten it up at night. To make the film and story move quicker he asked the actors to talk faster, his amazing cinematographer Joseph Walker to shoot faster. (continued...)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    wonder why they called it, it happened one night
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lagudafuad
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It Happened One Night is one of the only three movies since the commencement of the Academy Awards to have been able to win all five major Academy Awards (Best Picture, Best Director, Best Actor, Best Actress, and Best Screenplay), a feat that would not be matched until One Flew Over the Cuckoo's Nest in 1975 and of cause latter on in 1991, Anthony Hopkins The Silence of the Lambs followed suit. Here is a romantic comedy as raw as they come giving you a thrill as you watch two people miss matched from the start found a way to fall in love and tour America on their way to New York. The funny thing about the movie is the name which says, "It happened one night" when actually in the movie's story it actually went on for more than a night. The movie plot is about Ellie Andrews (Claudette Colbert) who has been whisked away by her father in his yacht to keep her away from her new husband King Westley. Ellie then jumps ship, swim to shore and heads off to New York to meet with King Westley. On her way she meets a reporter Peter Warne (Clark Gable) and both started as an unsuitable pair that grew to be lovers. Both Colbert and Gable felt the movie was not going to be good enough and gave Capra a lot of bull. Even the movie's iconic scene where Colbert lifted up her skirt to stop a car during the hitchhiking scene, was not so easy to film for Capra as Colbert refused to do the scene claiming it was not lady like, but upon seeing a body double do it, she later changed her mind and did it herself. Although picking up slow, the movie later became one the biggest hits for the studio and the thing is that at the end the movie cleared the Academy Awards and both Gable and Colbert were better off. Colbert is known to have told a friend, "I just finished the worst picture in the world." She boycotted the Academy Awards when she got a nomination believing she will not win, but she was called back to come pick up her award. Here is a movie that actually makes you smile all the way through, although like the actors themselves upon initial siting of the film you can be turned off thinking this is heading nowhere, but be patient the movie has all the familiar scenes that we see in the movies today (all taken from this old classic). This old classic is tagged the 46th greatest film in the last 100 years in the AFI's 100 Years... 100 Movies (10th Anniversary Edition). It Happened One Night is a nice DVD for one to place on the shelf. www.lagsreviews.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It Remains The Best Romantic Comedy Ever Released On Screen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It Happened One Night is a romantic comedy film with elements of screwball comedy directed by Frank Capra, in which a pampered socialite tries to get out from under her father's thumb, and falls in love with a roguish reporter. It features Clark Gable,Claudette Colbert and Walter Connolly.The plot was based on the short story Night Bus by Samuel Hopkins Adams, which provided the shooting title. Ellie Andrews is a spoiled heiress who has married fortune-hunting aviator King Westley, despite her father's objections. To keep Ellie from marrying this Lothario, her father has been holding her prisoner aboard his yacht. But Ellie bolts from the yacht, swims ashore in her clothes, and eventually slips onto a Greyhound bus bound for New York. Aboard the bus is newspaper reporter Peter Warne, who has recently been fired for drinking on the job. Peter gets the last seat on the bus but when he gets up to argue with the bus driver, Ellie takes his seat. Since it is the last seat on the bus, they have to share it. When Ellie has her purse stolen and she refuses to report it, Peter begins to suspect something. The next morning, they both miss the bus after a leisurely breakfast, and Peter reveals that he knows her identity. She makes a deal with him: if he helps her get to New York, he can write a scoop about her for his paper. Peter thinks she is a spoiled brat, however, and refuses a monetary bribe: "I'm not interested in your money or your problem. You, King Westley, your father you're all a lot of hooey to me" But as they travel northward and engage in a series of misadventures, the gruff newspaperman and the spoiled rich girl, thrown together by circumstances, fall in love with each other. Director Frank Capra took home every major Oscars for this seminal comedy. Funny and sexy, the film is full of memorable scenes often referred to in other films, such as the "walls of Jericho" and Colbert's famous flash of thigh to stop a speeding car in its tracks.This is Capra at his best, very funny and very light, with a minimum of populist posturing.His brisk, urbane brand of wit was a perfect complement to his populist faith in the common man, and that inspired combination makes this film both a spirited entertainment and an uplifting experience.This is still is pure delight to watch at present and it still remains the best screwball comedy ever released as remains unsurpassed by the countless romantic comedies it has inspired.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Interesting "Time Travel" to an era
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bob Pr.
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Background to that '30s era: this 1934 film is often called the first (of the many following) in the 'screwball comedy' genre; it came out in the worst of the Great Depression (US unemployment in 1928 was 2.9%, by 1933 it hit 25%; millions were hungry and desperate, leading to some antagonisms between economic classes). This was also a time when women's roles were changing in the US: the 'women's suffrage' movement gained women the right to vote in 1920 (19th Amendment), more equality in decision-making, more freedom in dress, gender & sexual roles (e.g., '20s 'Flappers'). "Screwball comedies" capitalized and fed on those changes: they typically "feature farcical situations, a combination of slap-stick with fast-paced repartee and show struggles between" (central characters of different) "economic classes. They also generally feature a self-confident and often stubborn central female protagonist and a plot involving courtship and marriage or remarriage" ("quotes" from Wikipedia). A young 30's Gable plays "Peter," a drinking, hard boiled newspaper reporter just fired from his job when he accidentally meets the young 20's "Ellie" (a young 30's Colbert) who's increasingly rebelled against the escalating but failing attempts of her upper class, super-rich father to control her. He tries to keep her on his Florida yacht while arranging to annul Ellie's impulsive marriage to a man (whom her father recognizes but Ellie doesn't as mainly interested in her wealth). But Ellie escapes her father's captivity and sets off to NYC to be reunited with her new spouse. On her way, she meets Gable who's initially interested in helping her because it'll lead to his scoop of a newspaper story (and reinstatement of his job). But then--romance eventually, gradually, starts to happen between you know who. My rating: 6 of 10 I found this interesting as a time-traveling experience--early '30s bus rides, clothes, roles, attitudes, etc.-- but all the people seemed to me to be too much caricatures and not enough real characters. (However, many people on IMDb's "Discussion Board" say the more often they've seen this film, the more highly they value it--many saying it's among their most favorite films of all--so maybe familiarity breeds appreciation?) FWIW: Neither Gable nor Colbert wanted to be in this film; MGM "loaned" them to Columbia Pictures, then a 2nd rate movie company, for this movie as punishment for each being too "uppity" and/or violating MGM policies. But, after this film gained such outstanding success (lifting Columbia's rank to among the majors) and substantially helped both Gable's & Colbert's careers, they came to appreciate it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Who would of thunk it !
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    traversvcs6
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you happen to own or rent this movie I'd suggest watching it a second time with the directors son's commentary during the picture. He gives such an inspiring outlook on just how remarkable this picture was having been made in limited limited time and budget. How under appreciated it was by the producers to make, how the main actors were more or less coerced into doing the picture. How it was first met with so so reviews by the sophisticated New York City audience. Yet it was made so across the US of A it was put in theaters and what do you know it remained there for a record number of weeks. The movie goers of the time enjoyed it so they went back to see it again bringing family and friends cause they knew they had seen something truly awesome. Come Oscar time it took the five biggies, Best Picture, Leading actor and actress, writer and director. A feat not repeated again until One Flew Over the Cuckoos Nest. Yes this is a gem and that it became so at such odds makes it more so and should be in every movie lover's library! I loved it :)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cute and delightful!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RyanCShowers
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of the most important Best Picture winners feels like one of the most unnecessary Best Picture winners by some. When one says "Best Picture Winner", you think the said film must meet a certain criteria, such as war drama or epic production value-centric story, that certifies it that prestigious title. It Happened One Night has neither of those, though it does achieve a wonderful romance brought to life by Clarke Gable and Claudette Colbert and contains a screenplay as fresh as the carrots Clarke Gable eats himself during the picture. Movies of the 1930s (and earlier) have reoccurring problems when they are put up to the task of competing with newer pictures using today's standards of film perfection: they lack the tight, technical exertion. The sound is often terrible, some dialogue may even be lost, the editing is probably loose, and the photography is assumably rugged from the restoration attempts by the studios. It Happened One Night falls prey to these shortcomings, but it's the film's only real flaw, and not a big one at that. It's still a fairly entertaining movie and the restoration is actually successful most of the times. I couldn't take my eyes of It Happened One Night! It's a delightful film that should not be missed by any generation. Before Pretty Woman and Annie Hall were "the" romantic comedies of their times, there was It Happened One Night. Most of the romantic comedy plot devices we've seen used repeatedly, originated here and were so accepted by audiences and writers that they have grown into clich&eacute;. Aside from that, It Happened One Night combines classic stories (poor little rich girl, desperate reporter, train rides, extramarital affairs) into one sublime, Hollywood picture. The thing to any successful romantic comedy, besides the script having more on its cutting board than what the average joe-blow can bring to the table, is its stars. Think about how successful those two rom-coms I mentioned earlier would have been without Julia Roberts and Richard Gere or Woody Allen and Diane Keaton? Not very. The leading couple not only has marvelous chemistry together, but they both have the bolts to screw in a great performances. Clarke Gable in particular shines. His movie-star presence and ability to flow with a picture and character are on full display here. Claudette Colbert produces first rate acting, as well. It Happened One Night is a greatly pleasing film. You'll watch it with a smile on your face. It's funny and contains one of the best movie romances out there, a relationship that starts out in hostility, evolves to friendship, and is overcome with the realization of love. It Happened One Night is cute and having inspired a whole genre of films ahead of its time. Rating: 10/10 Grade: A+
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Whimsical love story breaks all the rules about love between the classes
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lucie Uche
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    First ever winner of five Oscars in all major categories, Best Picture, Best Director, Best Actor, Best Actress and Best Screenplay, the 1934 movie It Happened One Night is a whimsical romantic tale of fortuitous love between a spoiled socialite Ellen Andrews played by Claudette Colbert and a cantankerous newspaper reporter Peter Warne played by Clark Gable. The slapstick comedy collaboration from director Frank Capra and writer Robert Riskin, still remains quintessential viewing because of its clever and amusing portrayal of the pursuit of happiness and fulfillment. Ellen, recently married to infamous pilot King Westley (Jameson Thomas) against her millionaire father (Walter Connolly)'s orders is now cooped up on a yacht against her will with her father so that he can decidedly change her mind and have her marriage to the apparent gold digging cad annulled. Defiant Ellen who believes she is in love wants no part of her father's plan for her jumps ship to shore and eventually finds herself on a bus bound for New York. Here she hopes to reunite with her husband and live happily ever after. On board the Greyhound bus she meets Peter, none the worse for wear and recently fired from his newspaper for being drunk on the job. So begins an unlikely series of dealings between the two that stem from them agreeing to help each other out for a price of sorts. Peter recognizing Ellen from newspaper headlines as the much talked about runaway heiress, agrees to help her get to New York while she in turn offers him exclusive rights to her story, his hope is to revamp his career. The journey is series of memorable, classic, comical, events that draw the two closer together. Peter never one to hold back on his opinion and ever nonchalant, often chastises "Brat" his nickname for Ellen, because of her bourgeois tendencies and take on life, whereas he is a down to earth working class man; depicted in sharp close up clarity, every handsome rugged feature proving to be aesthetically camera friendly always defining his cool no nonsense sensibility. The two collide, bicker and banter about everything. There's is not an apparent match made in heaven but their liaison becomes more meaningful the longer they spend together. Peter is assiduous in keeping his promise to Ellen; Ellen is just doe eyed and realizes she is in love with the brash outspoken journalist. A timeless feature that that suggests Ellen's beauty and fragility is achieved with the application of a filtered lens on all of her close ups; this very effective application implies a softness and purity to her character. A notable fact about this seminal movie is the precedent it set for zany romantic comedies that would follow, such as Bringing up Baby (1938) and the Philadelphia Story (1940) both starring Katherine Hepburn and the impact it still has on screwball comedies today.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An antidote for depression
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Hotwok2013
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It isn't any wonder why "It Happened One Night" struck such a chord with movie-goers in the depression-hit USA of the 1930's. Frank Capra's sparkling romantic comedy is just about as uplifting as any movie possibly can be. Whatever it is that makes a star a star, Clark Gable had it in spades more than any other leading man before or since, & how could Claudette Colbert, (or any other woman?), not fall in love with him. Even allowing for the absurdities in the plot beginning with Ellie Andrews (Colbert) jumping her rich fathers yacht into the sea & swimming to shore. She is wearing a long white silk gown & not carrying a handbag. Next we see her at Miami bus station purchasing a ticket to New York in a new outfit with handbag!. The movie is full of memorably entertaining scenes & I guarantee that if anyone is feeling a bit low this film will improve their mood.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Romantic Comedy Supreme.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SmileysWorld
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Boy meets girl.They come from different roads in life and don't see eye to eye at first,but gradually they fall in love.This is a theme we have seen again and again throughout cinema history.Sometimes it is done well and sometimes..not so much.This is definitely the film that started it all,and the mold was broken.This is by far the best romantic comedy that I have ever seen.Claudette Colbert may not have thought so,for it has been said that she said to a friend after completing production that she had just finished "the worst film I have ever done."Surely she changed her tone when they placed the Best Actress Oscar in her hands.The screen chemistry between Colbert and Gable was right on the money.It is THE laugh out loud romantic classic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Young people in love are never hu-un-gry!" The granddaddy of all rom-coms
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    LouE15
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I stumbled across this film recently, expecting it to do no more than help me kill some time. Several viewings on, I'm hooked  it seems almost incredible that it was made in 1934, not 1984 or 2004. There isn't a romantic comedy in existence, and never will be, that doesn't owe a debt to this film. It's funny, modern, charming, and meaningful about people  what more do you want? Colour? Ah, nuts. Clark Gable plays Peter, a cynical journalist who ends up on a road trip across a Depression-hit USA with runaway heiress Ellen (Claudette Colbert). Ellen's sheltered life has done nothing to prepare her for the trials that lie ahead. She's so certain that she knows what she wants, and what's best: she's naive, but sparky and intelligent. She has to be knocked down in order to have her eyes peeled open. * Some spoilers from here* I thought I knew all about Clark Gable, and wasn't that bothered, but here he radiates masterful alpha-male charm and can switch on a dime from comedy to a love scene, boyish vulnerability to hardboiled cynic and back again. I don't know which version of him I liked more, although I think my favourite mini-moment comes when he's hardboiling it for the telegram girl, pipe in mouth - Philip Marlowe if ever there was one. The script is full of wonderful details  I don't know how much was in the original short story but I get the impression a great deal must have been added in to make it funnier. Oh, let me count the ways her not understanding what a real piggy back ride ishis hilariously terrible attempts at hitchhikingMr Believe You Me...Peter's "shut up" when they're back on the bus (which brings to mind James Cagney and That Grapefruit)and then his petulant sulk when he realises he's losing the upper hand, falling in love and just a shade jealousit's all great. I was hysterical by the time we met the operatic buggy driver  ever since I first saw the film I've been turning everyday trivialities into Gilbert & Sullivan libretto  and I just loved Peter's shouty conversation with Ellen's dad. But best of all are the lessons Ellen has to learn. For all her wealth and snobbery, and for all we enjoy her gradual comeuppance, she shows she's capable of learning (finally being hungry enough to eat a raw carrot!), and is worthy of Peter's love. When, near the end, she's weepily describing to her father how poor Peter's opinion is of them both ("you should hear what he says about you!"), capping it off with "he's marvellous(sob)", you're right there with her. "It happened one night" is in danger of eclipsing William Powell's wonderful "My Man Gordon" as my favourite thirties film. It's revised my lazy opinion about Clark Gable too  but it won't make me like "Gone with the Wind" any better, I don't care what anyone says.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Part one of two. My introduction of IHON, the background story on Capra's 1st miracle film.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Larry41OnEbay-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The idea for IT HAPPENED ONE NIGHT started in a barber shop while Frank Capra was waiting for a haircut he read an old magazine article in Cosmopolitan called "Night Bus" by Samuel Hopkins Adams. It was a cute idea so Capra asked Columbia studios to buy the rights to it and then he forgot about it. Frank's previous feature was LADY FOR A DAY which got great reviews and was Columbia studio's first film ever Oscar nominated and Capra's. Irving Thalberg wanted Capra to make his next film at MGM in exchange for $50k and the loan of a star. But at the last minute Louis B. Mayer canceled the film but honored the deal. Back at Columbia Capra wanted to make Night Bus, but studio tyrant Harry Cohn and all his advisers fought against it. They said things like, "It's nothing; froth, trivia, just another bus picture, no suspense, no heart, no oomph, winter's coming and it's all exteriors." All they could get Capra to do was change the title to IT HAPPENED ONE NIGHT which they said was too long to fit on a marquee! Capra tried casting Myrna Loy  she turned it down; then Margaret Sullavan  said 'no thank you'; Miriam Hopkins was insulted and said, 'Not if I never play another part'; Constance Bennett told him to go fly a kite and then offered to buy the script and have it rewritten for her! Capra had co-written the script with his favorite writer Robert Riskin but they brought in Myles Connolly who added more sympathetic and interesting characters so people could identify with them. The pretty girl, a spoiled brat, was rich yes but bored with being an heiress now wanting something real. The man was made a guy we all know and like; a tough crusading reporter on the outs with his pigheaded editor. It's The Taming Of The Shrew, but the shrew must be worth taming and the guy must be one of us. Back to casting, this time they went after Robert Montgomery a great light comedian at MGM. Mayer called Cohn and said, "Montgomery says there are too many bus pictures and (don't take this in the wrong way) but going from MGM to lowly Columbia was an insult. But you've caught me in a good mood. I got an actor here who's been a bad boy. Wants more money. And I'd like to spank him. You can have Clark Gable." Surprisingly the next knock on Capra's shabby office door came from a very drunk and cursing Gable, reporting to Siberia as he called it. Gable's objections almost made Capra throw in the towel but then Harry Cohn suggested getting Claudette Colbert for the girl in the story. (He had heard she liked money.) So Capra and Riskin made an appointment that very night to see her at her home. When they arrived Colbert regretted agreeing to the meeting as she was packing to leave on a month long skiing vacation. Capra saw this attractive, wealthy and spoiled woman and knew she was perfect for the part. So Capra, after being bit in the butt by her dog, asked what it would take to get her in the picture. (Capra had directed her first picture, FOR THE LOVE OF MIKE a silent made in 1927 and a flop) To throw him off she said she normally made $25k a picture (a price Columbia had never paid to an actor before), he would have to double it AND she was only available from her studio Paramount during her Christmas vacation. They would have to shoot all her scenes and retakes in less than 4 weeks -- half the time they had budgeted! So Capra called Cohn to ask would he pay her the $50k, Cohn said "I can pay it if you can shoot it in 4 weeks." Capra said, he didn't know, but he'd try. So they told her, "Deal, Claudette! $50k for 4 weeks! Okay?" To which she replied, "Oh for God's sake!" She was trapped. That next day she had to report for her costume fittings and the day after that they begin filming in a hurry. While they shot film all day Capra edited and rewrote the story to tighten it up at night. To make the film and story move quicker he asked the actors to talk faster, his amazing cinematographer Joseph Walker to shoot faster. (continued...)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    wonder why they called it, it happened one night
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lagudafuad
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It Happened One Night is one of the only three movies since the commencement of the Academy Awards to have been able to win all five major Academy Awards (Best Picture, Best Director, Best Actor, Best Actress, and Best Screenplay), a feat that would not be matched until One Flew Over the Cuckoo's Nest in 1975 and of cause latter on in 1991, Anthony Hopkins The Silence of the Lambs followed suit. Here is a romantic comedy as raw as they come giving you a thrill as you watch two people miss matched from the start found a way to fall in love and tour America on their way to New York. The funny thing about the movie is the name which says, "It happened one night" when actually in the movie's story it actually went on for more than a night. The movie plot is about Ellie Andrews (Claudette Colbert) who has been whisked away by her father in his yacht to keep her away from her new husband King Westley. Ellie then jumps ship, swim to shore and heads off to New York to meet with King Westley. On her way she meets a reporter Peter Warne (Clark Gable) and both started as an unsuitable pair that grew to be lovers. Both Colbert and Gable felt the movie was not going to be good enough and gave Capra a lot of bull. Even the movie's iconic scene where Colbert lifted up her skirt to stop a car during the hitchhiking scene, was not so easy to film for Capra as Colbert refused to do the scene claiming it was not lady like, but upon seeing a body double do it, she later changed her mind and did it herself. Although picking up slow, the movie later became one the biggest hits for the studio and the thing is that at the end the movie cleared the Academy Awards and both Gable and Colbert were better off. Colbert is known to have told a friend, "I just finished the worst picture in the world." She boycotted the Academy Awards when she got a nomination believing she will not win, but she was called back to come pick up her award. Here is a movie that actually makes you smile all the way through, although like the actors themselves upon initial siting of the film you can be turned off thinking this is heading nowhere, but be patient the movie has all the familiar scenes that we see in the movies today (all taken from this old classic). This old classic is tagged the 46th greatest film in the last 100 years in the AFI's 100 Years... 100 Movies (10th Anniversary Edition). It Happened One Night is a nice DVD for one to place on the shelf. www.lagsreviews.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It Remains The Best Romantic Comedy Ever Released On Screen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It Happened One Night is a romantic comedy film with elements of screwball comedy directed by Frank Capra, in which a pampered socialite tries to get out from under her father's thumb, and falls in love with a roguish reporter. It features Clark Gable,Claudette Colbert and Walter Connolly.The plot was based on the short story Night Bus by Samuel Hopkins Adams, which provided the shooting title. Ellie Andrews is a spoiled heiress who has married fortune-hunting aviator King Westley, despite her father's objections. To keep Ellie from marrying this Lothario, her father has been holding her prisoner aboard his yacht. But Ellie bolts from the yacht, swims ashore in her clothes, and eventually slips onto a Greyhound bus bound for New York. Aboard the bus is newspaper reporter Peter Warne, who has recently been fired for drinking on the job. Peter gets the last seat on the bus but when he gets up to argue with the bus driver, Ellie takes his seat. Since it is the last seat on the bus, they have to share it. When Ellie has her purse stolen and she refuses to report it, Peter begins to suspect something. The next morning, they both miss the bus after a leisurely breakfast, and Peter reveals that he knows her identity. She makes a deal with him: if he helps her get to New York, he can write a scoop about her for his paper. Peter thinks she is a spoiled brat, however, and refuses a monetary bribe: "I'm not interested in your money or your problem. You, King Westley, your father you're all a lot of hooey to me" But as they travel northward and engage in a series of misadventures, the gruff newspaperman and the spoiled rich girl, thrown together by circumstances, fall in love with each other. Director Frank Capra took home every major Oscars for this seminal comedy. Funny and sexy, the film is full of memorable scenes often referred to in other films, such as the "walls of Jericho" and Colbert's famous flash of thigh to stop a speeding car in its tracks.This is Capra at his best, very funny and very light, with a minimum of populist posturing.His brisk, urbane brand of wit was a perfect complement to his populist faith in the common man, and that inspired combination makes this film both a spirited entertainment and an uplifting experience.This is still is pure delight to watch at present and it still remains the best screwball comedy ever released as remains unsurpassed by the countless romantic comedies it has inspired.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Interesting "Time Travel" to an era
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bob Pr.
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Background to that '30s era: this 1934 film is often called the first (of the many following) in the 'screwball comedy' genre; it came out in the worst of the Great Depression (US unemployment in 1928 was 2.9%, by 1933 it hit 25%; millions were hungry and desperate, leading to some antagonisms between economic classes). This was also a time when women's roles were changing in the US: the 'women's suffrage' movement gained women the right to vote in 1920 (19th Amendment), more equality in decision-making, more freedom in dress, gender & sexual roles (e.g., '20s 'Flappers'). "Screwball comedies" capitalized and fed on those changes: they typically "feature farcical situations, a combination of slap-stick with fast-paced repartee and show struggles between" (central characters of different) "economic classes. They also generally feature a self-confident and often stubborn central female protagonist and a plot involving courtship and marriage or remarriage" ("quotes" from Wikipedia). A young 30's Gable plays "Peter," a drinking, hard boiled newspaper reporter just fired from his job when he accidentally meets the young 20's "Ellie" (a young 30's Colbert) who's increasingly rebelled against the escalating but failing attempts of her upper class, super-rich father to control her. He tries to keep her on his Florida yacht while arranging to annul Ellie's impulsive marriage to a man (whom her father recognizes but Ellie doesn't as mainly interested in her wealth). But Ellie escapes her father's captivity and sets off to NYC to be reunited with her new spouse. On her way, she meets Gable who's initially interested in helping her because it'll lead to his scoop of a newspaper story (and reinstatement of his job). But then--romance eventually, gradually, starts to happen between you know who. My rating: 6 of 10 I found this interesting as a time-traveling experience--early '30s bus rides, clothes, roles, attitudes, etc.-- but all the people seemed to me to be too much caricatures and not enough real characters. (However, many people on IMDb's "Discussion Board" say the more often they've seen this film, the more highly they value it--many saying it's among their most favorite films of all--so maybe familiarity breeds appreciation?) FWIW: Neither Gable nor Colbert wanted to be in this film; MGM "loaned" them to Columbia Pictures, then a 2nd rate movie company, for this movie as punishment for each being too "uppity" and/or violating MGM policies. But, after this film gained such outstanding success (lifting Columbia's rank to among the majors) and substantially helped both Gable's & Colbert's careers, they came to appreciate it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Who would of thunk it !
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    traversvcs6
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you happen to own or rent this movie I'd suggest watching it a second time with the directors son's commentary during the picture. He gives such an inspiring outlook on just how remarkable this picture was having been made in limited limited time and budget. How under appreciated it was by the producers to make, how the main actors were more or less coerced into doing the picture. How it was first met with so so reviews by the sophisticated New York City audience. Yet it was made so across the US of A it was put in theaters and what do you know it remained there for a record number of weeks. The movie goers of the time enjoyed it so they went back to see it again bringing family and friends cause they knew they had seen something truly awesome. Come Oscar time it took the five biggies, Best Picture, Leading actor and actress, writer and director. A feat not repeated again until One Flew Over the Cuckoos Nest. Yes this is a gem and that it became so at such odds makes it more so and should be in every movie lover's library! I loved it :)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cute and delightful!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RyanCShowers
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of the most important Best Picture winners feels like one of the most unnecessary Best Picture winners by some. When one says "Best Picture Winner", you think the said film must meet a certain criteria, such as war drama or epic production value-centric story, that certifies it that prestigious title. It Happened One Night has neither of those, though it does achieve a wonderful romance brought to life by Clarke Gable and Claudette Colbert and contains a screenplay as fresh as the carrots Clarke Gable eats himself during the picture. Movies of the 1930s (and earlier) have reoccurring problems when they are put up to the task of competing with newer pictures using today's standards of film perfection: they lack the tight, technical exertion. The sound is often terrible, some dialogue may even be lost, the editing is probably loose, and the photography is assumably rugged from the restoration attempts by the studios. It Happened One Night falls prey to these shortcomings, but it's the film's only real flaw, and not a big one at that. It's still a fairly entertaining movie and the restoration is actually successful most of the times. I couldn't take my eyes of It Happened One Night! It's a delightful film that should not be missed by any generation. Before Pretty Woman and Annie Hall were "the" romantic comedies of their times, there was It Happened One Night. Most of the romantic comedy plot devices we've seen used repeatedly, originated here and were so accepted by audiences and writers that they have grown into clich&eacute;. Aside from that, It Happened One Night combines classic stories (poor little rich girl, desperate reporter, train rides, extramarital affairs) into one sublime, Hollywood picture. The thing to any successful romantic comedy, besides the script having more on its cutting board than what the average joe-blow can bring to the table, is its stars. Think about how successful those two rom-coms I mentioned earlier would have been without Julia Roberts and Richard Gere or Woody Allen and Diane Keaton? Not very. The leading couple not only has marvelous chemistry together, but they both have the bolts to screw in a great performances. Clarke Gable in particular shines. His movie-star presence and ability to flow with a picture and character are on full display here. Claudette Colbert produces first rate acting, as well. It Happened One Night is a greatly pleasing film. You'll watch it with a smile on your face. It's funny and contains one of the best movie romances out there, a relationship that starts out in hostility, evolves to friendship, and is overcome with the realization of love. It Happened One Night is cute and having inspired a whole genre of films ahead of its time. Rating: 10/10 Grade: A+
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Whimsical love story breaks all the rules about love between the classes
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lucie Uche
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    First ever winner of five Oscars in all major categories, Best Picture, Best Director, Best Actor, Best Actress and Best Screenplay, the 1934 movie It Happened One Night is a whimsical romantic tale of fortuitous love between a spoiled socialite Ellen Andrews played by Claudette Colbert and a cantankerous newspaper reporter Peter Warne played by Clark Gable. The slapstick comedy collaboration from director Frank Capra and writer Robert Riskin, still remains quintessential viewing because of its clever and amusing portrayal of the pursuit of happiness and fulfillment. Ellen, recently married to infamous pilot King Westley (Jameson Thomas) against her millionaire father (Walter Connolly)'s orders is now cooped up on a yacht against her will with her father so that he can decidedly change her mind and have her marriage to the apparent gold digging cad annulled. Defiant Ellen who believes she is in love wants no part of her father's plan for her jumps ship to shore and eventually finds herself on a bus bound for New York. Here she hopes to reunite with her husband and live happily ever after. On board the Greyhound bus she meets Peter, none the worse for wear and recently fired from his newspaper for being drunk on the job. So begins an unlikely series of dealings between the two that stem from them agreeing to help each other out for a price of sorts. Peter recognizing Ellen from newspaper headlines as the much talked about runaway heiress, agrees to help her get to New York while she in turn offers him exclusive rights to her story, his hope is to revamp his career. The journey is series of memorable, classic, comical, events that draw the two closer together. Peter never one to hold back on his opinion and ever nonchalant, often chastises "Brat" his nickname for Ellen, because of her bourgeois tendencies and take on life, whereas he is a down to earth working class man; depicted in sharp close up clarity, every handsome rugged feature proving to be aesthetically camera friendly always defining his cool no nonsense sensibility. The two collide, bicker and banter about everything. There's is not an apparent match made in heaven but their liaison becomes more meaningful the longer they spend together. Peter is assiduous in keeping his promise to Ellen; Ellen is just doe eyed and realizes she is in love with the brash outspoken journalist. A timeless feature that that suggests Ellen's beauty and fragility is achieved with the application of a filtered lens on all of her close ups; this very effective application implies a softness and purity to her character. A notable fact about this seminal movie is the precedent it set for zany romantic comedies that would follow, such as Bringing up Baby (1938) and the Philadelphia Story (1940) both starring Katherine Hepburn and the impact it still has on screwball comedies today.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An antidote for depression
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Hotwok2013
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It isn't any wonder why "It Happened One Night" struck such a chord with movie-goers in the depression-hit USA of the 1930's. Frank Capra's sparkling romantic comedy is just about as uplifting as any movie possibly can be. Whatever it is that makes a star a star, Clark Gable had it in spades more than any other leading man before or since, & how could Claudette Colbert, (or any other woman?), not fall in love with him. Even allowing for the absurdities in the plot beginning with Ellie Andrews (Colbert) jumping her rich fathers yacht into the sea & swimming to shore. She is wearing a long white silk gown & not carrying a handbag. Next we see her at Miami bus station purchasing a ticket to New York in a new outfit with handbag!. The movie is full of memorably entertaining scenes & I guarantee that if anyone is feeling a bit low this film will improve their mood.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Romantic Comedy Supreme.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SmileysWorld
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Boy meets girl.They come from different roads in life and don't see eye to eye at first,but gradually they fall in love.This is a theme we have seen again and again throughout cinema history.Sometimes it is done well and sometimes..not so much.This is definitely the film that started it all,and the mold was broken.This is by far the best romantic comedy that I have ever seen.Claudette Colbert may not have thought so,for it has been said that she said to a friend after completing production that she had just finished "the worst film I have ever done."Surely she changed her tone when they placed the Best Actress Oscar in her hands.The screen chemistry between Colbert and Gable was right on the money.It is THE laugh out loud romantic classic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Young people in love are never hu-un-gry!" The granddaddy of all rom-coms
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    LouE15
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I stumbled across this film recently, expecting it to do no more than help me kill some time. Several viewings on, I'm hooked  it seems almost incredible that it was made in 1934, not 1984 or 2004. There isn't a romantic comedy in existence, and never will be, that doesn't owe a debt to this film. It's funny, modern, charming, and meaningful about people  what more do you want? Colour? Ah, nuts. Clark Gable plays Peter, a cynical journalist who ends up on a road trip across a Depression-hit USA with runaway heiress Ellen (Claudette Colbert). Ellen's sheltered life has done nothing to prepare her for the trials that lie ahead. She's so certain that she knows what she wants, and what's best: she's naive, but sparky and intelligent. She has to be knocked down in order to have her eyes peeled open. * Some spoilers from here* I thought I knew all about Clark Gable, and wasn't that bothered, but here he radiates masterful alpha-male charm and can switch on a dime from comedy to a love scene, boyish vulnerability to hardboiled cynic and back again. I don't know which version of him I liked more, although I think my favourite mini-moment comes when he's hardboiling it for the telegram girl, pipe in mouth - Philip Marlowe if ever there was one. The script is full of wonderful details  I don't know how much was in the original short story but I get the impression a great deal must have been added in to make it funnier. Oh, let me count the ways her not understanding what a real piggy back ride ishis hilariously terrible attempts at hitchhikingMr Believe You Me...Peter's "shut up" when they're back on the bus (which brings to mind James Cagney and That Grapefruit)and then his petulant sulk when he realises he's losing the upper hand, falling in love and just a shade jealousit's all great. I was hysterical by the time we met the operatic buggy driver  ever since I first saw the film I've been turning everyday trivialities into Gilbert & Sullivan libretto  and I just loved Peter's shouty conversation with Ellen's dad. But best of all are the lessons Ellen has to learn. For all her wealth and snobbery, and for all we enjoy her gradual comeuppance, she shows she's capable of learning (finally being hungry enough to eat a raw carrot!), and is worthy of Peter's love. When, near the end, she's weepily describing to her father how poor Peter's opinion is of them both ("you should hear what he says about you!"), capping it off with "he's marvellous(sob)", you're right there with her. "It happened one night" is in danger of eclipsing William Powell's wonderful "My Man Gordon" as my favourite thirties film. It's revised my lazy opinion about Clark Gable too  but it won't make me like "Gone with the Wind" any better, I don't care what anyone says.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Part one of two. My introduction of IHON, the background story on Capra's 1st miracle film.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Larry41OnEbay-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The idea for IT HAPPENED ONE NIGHT started in a barber shop while Frank Capra was waiting for a haircut he read an old magazine article in Cosmopolitan called "Night Bus" by Samuel Hopkins Adams. It was a cute idea so Capra asked Columbia studios to buy the rights to it and then he forgot about it. Frank's previous feature was LADY FOR A DAY which got great reviews and was Columbia studio's first film ever Oscar nominated and Capra's. Irving Thalberg wanted Capra to make his next film at MGM in exchange for $50k and the loan of a star. But at the last minute Louis B. Mayer canceled the film but honored the deal. Back at Columbia Capra wanted to make Night Bus, but studio tyrant Harry Cohn and all his advisers fought against it. They said things like, "It's nothing; froth, trivia, just another bus picture, no suspense, no heart, no oomph, winter's coming and it's all exteriors." All they could get Capra to do was change the title to IT HAPPENED ONE NIGHT which they said was too long to fit on a marquee! Capra tried casting Myrna Loy  she turned it down; then Margaret Sullavan  said 'no thank you'; Miriam Hopkins was insulted and said, 'Not if I never play another part'; Constance Bennett told him to go fly a kite and then offered to buy the script and have it rewritten for her! Capra had co-written the script with his favorite writer Robert Riskin but they brought in Myles Connolly who added more sympathetic and interesting characters so people could identify with them. The pretty girl, a spoiled brat, was rich yes but bored with being an heiress now wanting something real. The man was made a guy we all know and like; a tough crusading reporter on the outs with his pigheaded editor. It's The Taming Of The Shrew, but the shrew must be worth taming and the guy must be one of us. Back to casting, this time they went after Robert Montgomery a great light comedian at MGM. Mayer called Cohn and said, "Montgomery says there are too many bus pictures and (don't take this in the wrong way) but going from MGM to lowly Columbia was an insult. But you've caught me in a good mood. I got an actor here who's been a bad boy. Wants more money. And I'd like to spank him. You can have Clark Gable." Surprisingly the next knock on Capra's shabby office door came from a very drunk and cursing Gable, reporting to Siberia as he called it. Gable's objections almost made Capra throw in the towel but then Harry Cohn suggested getting Claudette Colbert for the girl in the story. (He had heard she liked money.) So Capra and Riskin made an appointment that very night to see her at her home. When they arrived Colbert regretted agreeing to the meeting as she was packing to leave on a month long skiing vacation. Capra saw this attractive, wealthy and spoiled woman and knew she was perfect for the part. So Capra, after being bit in the butt by her dog, asked what it would take to get her in the picture. (Capra had directed her first picture, FOR THE LOVE OF MIKE a silent made in 1927 and a flop) To throw him off she said she normally made $25k a picture (a price Columbia had never paid to an actor before), he would have to double it AND she was only available from her studio Paramount during her Christmas vacation. They would have to shoot all her scenes and retakes in less than 4 weeks -- half the time they had budgeted! So Capra called Cohn to ask would he pay her the $50k, Cohn said "I can pay it if you can shoot it in 4 weeks." Capra said, he didn't know, but he'd try. So they told her, "Deal, Claudette! $50k for 4 weeks! Okay?" To which she replied, "Oh for God's sake!" She was trapped. That next day she had to report for her costume fittings and the day after that they begin filming in a hurry. While they shot film all day Capra edited and rewrote the story to tighten it up at night. To make the film and story move quicker he asked the actors to talk faster, his amazing cinematographer Joseph Walker to shoot faster. (continued...)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    wonder why they called it, it happened one night
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lagudafuad
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It Happened One Night is one of the only three movies since the commencement of the Academy Awards to have been able to win all five major Academy Awards (Best Picture, Best Director, Best Actor, Best Actress, and Best Screenplay), a feat that would not be matched until One Flew Over the Cuckoo's Nest in 1975 and of cause latter on in 1991, Anthony Hopkins The Silence of the Lambs followed suit. Here is a romantic comedy as raw as they come giving you a thrill as you watch two people miss matched from the start found a way to fall in love and tour America on their way to New York. The funny thing about the movie is the name which says, "It happened one night" when actually in the movie's story it actually went on for more than a night. The movie plot is about Ellie Andrews (Claudette Colbert) who has been whisked away by her father in his yacht to keep her away from her new husband King Westley. Ellie then jumps ship, swim to shore and heads off to New York to meet with King Westley. On her way she meets a reporter Peter Warne (Clark Gable) and both started as an unsuitable pair that grew to be lovers. Both Colbert and Gable felt the movie was not going to be good enough and gave Capra a lot of bull. Even the movie's iconic scene where Colbert lifted up her skirt to stop a car during the hitchhiking scene, was not so easy to film for Capra as Colbert refused to do the scene claiming it was not lady like, but upon seeing a body double do it, she later changed her mind and did it herself. Although picking up slow, the movie later became one the biggest hits for the studio and the thing is that at the end the movie cleared the Academy Awards and both Gable and Colbert were better off. Colbert is known to have told a friend, "I just finished the worst picture in the world." She boycotted the Academy Awards when she got a nomination believing she will not win, but she was called back to come pick up her award. Here is a movie that actually makes you smile all the way through, although like the actors themselves upon initial siting of the film you can be turned off thinking this is heading nowhere, but be patient the movie has all the familiar scenes that we see in the movies today (all taken from this old classic). This old classic is tagged the 46th greatest film in the last 100 years in the AFI's 100 Years... 100 Movies (10th Anniversary Edition). It Happened One Night is a nice DVD for one to place on the shelf. www.lagsreviews.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It Remains The Best Romantic Comedy Ever Released On Screen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It Happened One Night is a romantic comedy film with elements of screwball comedy directed by Frank Capra, in which a pampered socialite tries to get out from under her father's thumb, and falls in love with a roguish reporter. It features Clark Gable,Claudette Colbert and Walter Connolly.The plot was based on the short story Night Bus by Samuel Hopkins Adams, which provided the shooting title. Ellie Andrews is a spoiled heiress who has married fortune-hunting aviator King Westley, despite her father's objections. To keep Ellie from marrying this Lothario, her father has been holding her prisoner aboard his yacht. But Ellie bolts from the yacht, swims ashore in her clothes, and eventually slips onto a Greyhound bus bound for New York. Aboard the bus is newspaper reporter Peter Warne, who has recently been fired for drinking on the job. Peter gets the last seat on the bus but when he gets up to argue with the bus driver, Ellie takes his seat. Since it is the last seat on the bus, they have to share it. When Ellie has her purse stolen and she refuses to report it, Peter begins to suspect something. The next morning, they both miss the bus after a leisurely breakfast, and Peter reveals that he knows her identity. She makes a deal with him: if he helps her get to New York, he can write a scoop about her for his paper. Peter thinks she is a spoiled brat, however, and refuses a monetary bribe: "I'm not interested in your money or your problem. You, King Westley, your father you're all a lot of hooey to me" But as they travel northward and engage in a series of misadventures, the gruff newspaperman and the spoiled rich girl, thrown together by circumstances, fall in love with each other. Director Frank Capra took home every major Oscars for this seminal comedy. Funny and sexy, the film is full of memorable scenes often referred to in other films, such as the "walls of Jericho" and Colbert's famous flash of thigh to stop a speeding car in its tracks.This is Capra at his best, very funny and very light, with a minimum of populist posturing.His brisk, urbane brand of wit was a perfect complement to his populist faith in the common man, and that inspired combination makes this film both a spirited entertainment and an uplifting experience.This is still is pure delight to watch at present and it still remains the best screwball comedy ever released as remains unsurpassed by the countless romantic comedies it has inspired.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Interesting "Time Travel" to an era
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bob Pr.
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Background to that '30s era: this 1934 film is often called the first (of the many following) in the 'screwball comedy' genre; it came out in the worst of the Great Depression (US unemployment in 1928 was 2.9%, by 1933 it hit 25%; millions were hungry and desperate, leading to some antagonisms between economic classes). This was also a time when women's roles were changing in the US: the 'women's suffrage' movement gained women the right to vote in 1920 (19th Amendment), more equality in decision-making, more freedom in dress, gender & sexual roles (e.g., '20s 'Flappers'). "Screwball comedies" capitalized and fed on those changes: they typically "feature farcical situations, a combination of slap-stick with fast-paced repartee and show struggles between" (central characters of different) "economic classes. They also generally feature a self-confident and often stubborn central female protagonist and a plot involving courtship and marriage or remarriage" ("quotes" from Wikipedia). A young 30's Gable plays "Peter," a drinking, hard boiled newspaper reporter just fired from his job when he accidentally meets the young 20's "Ellie" (a young 30's Colbert) who's increasingly rebelled against the escalating but failing attempts of her upper class, super-rich father to control her. He tries to keep her on his Florida yacht while arranging to annul Ellie's impulsive marriage to a man (whom her father recognizes but Ellie doesn't as mainly interested in her wealth). But Ellie escapes her father's captivity and sets off to NYC to be reunited with her new spouse. On her way, she meets Gable who's initially interested in helping her because it'll lead to his scoop of a newspaper story (and reinstatement of his job). But then--romance eventually, gradually, starts to happen between you know who. My rating: 6 of 10 I found this interesting as a time-traveling experience--early '30s bus rides, clothes, roles, attitudes, etc.-- but all the people seemed to me to be too much caricatures and not enough real characters. (However, many people on IMDb's "Discussion Board" say the more often they've seen this film, the more highly they value it--many saying it's among their most favorite films of all--so maybe familiarity breeds appreciation?) FWIW: Neither Gable nor Colbert wanted to be in this film; MGM "loaned" them to Columbia Pictures, then a 2nd rate movie company, for this movie as punishment for each being too "uppity" and/or violating MGM policies. But, after this film gained such outstanding success (lifting Columbia's rank to among the majors) and substantially helped both Gable's & Colbert's careers, they came to appreciate it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Who would of thunk it !
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    traversvcs6
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you happen to own or rent this movie I'd suggest watching it a second time with the directors son's commentary during the picture. He gives such an inspiring outlook on just how remarkable this picture was having been made in limited limited time and budget. How under appreciated it was by the producers to make, how the main actors were more or less coerced into doing the picture. How it was first met with so so reviews by the sophisticated New York City audience. Yet it was made so across the US of A it was put in theaters and what do you know it remained there for a record number of weeks. The movie goers of the time enjoyed it so they went back to see it again bringing family and friends cause they knew they had seen something truly awesome. Come Oscar time it took the five biggies, Best Picture, Leading actor and actress, writer and director. A feat not repeated again until One Flew Over the Cuckoos Nest. Yes this is a gem and that it became so at such odds makes it more so and should be in every movie lover's library! I loved it :)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cute and delightful!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RyanCShowers
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of the most important Best Picture winners feels like one of the most unnecessary Best Picture winners by some. When one says "Best Picture Winner", you think the said film must meet a certain criteria, such as war drama or epic production value-centric story, that certifies it that prestigious title. It Happened One Night has neither of those, though it does achieve a wonderful romance brought to life by Clarke Gable and Claudette Colbert and contains a screenplay as fresh as the carrots Clarke Gable eats himself during the picture. Movies of the 1930s (and earlier) have reoccurring problems when they are put up to the task of competing with newer pictures using today's standards of film perfection: they lack the tight, technical exertion. The sound is often terrible, some dialogue may even be lost, the editing is probably loose, and the photography is assumably rugged from the restoration attempts by the studios. It Happened One Night falls prey to these shortcomings, but it's the film's only real flaw, and not a big one at that. It's still a fairly entertaining movie and the restoration is actually successful most of the times. I couldn't take my eyes of It Happened One Night! It's a delightful film that should not be missed by any generation. Before Pretty Woman and Annie Hall were "the" romantic comedies of their times, there was It Happened One Night. Most of the romantic comedy plot devices we've seen used repeatedly, originated here and were so accepted by audiences and writers that they have grown into clich&eacute;. Aside from that, It Happened One Night combines classic stories (poor little rich girl, desperate reporter, train rides, extramarital affairs) into one sublime, Hollywood picture. The thing to any successful romantic comedy, besides the script having more on its cutting board than what the average joe-blow can bring to the table, is its stars. Think about how successful those two rom-coms I mentioned earlier would have been without Julia Roberts and Richard Gere or Woody Allen and Diane Keaton? Not very. The leading couple not only has marvelous chemistry together, but they both have the bolts to screw in a great performances. Clarke Gable in particular shines. His movie-star presence and ability to flow with a picture and character are on full display here. Claudette Colbert produces first rate acting, as well. It Happened One Night is a greatly pleasing film. You'll watch it with a smile on your face. It's funny and contains one of the best movie romances out there, a relationship that starts out in hostility, evolves to friendship, and is overcome with the realization of love. It Happened One Night is cute and having inspired a whole genre of films ahead of its time. Rating: 10/10 Grade: A+
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Whimsical love story breaks all the rules about love between the classes
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lucie Uche
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    First ever winner of five Oscars in all major categories, Best Picture, Best Director, Best Actor, Best Actress and Best Screenplay, the 1934 movie It Happened One Night is a whimsical romantic tale of fortuitous love between a spoiled socialite Ellen Andrews played by Claudette Colbert and a cantankerous newspaper reporter Peter Warne played by Clark Gable. The slapstick comedy collaboration from director Frank Capra and writer Robert Riskin, still remains quintessential viewing because of its clever and amusing portrayal of the pursuit of happiness and fulfillment. Ellen, recently married to infamous pilot King Westley (Jameson Thomas) against her millionaire father (Walter Connolly)'s orders is now cooped up on a yacht against her will with her father so that he can decidedly change her mind and have her marriage to the apparent gold digging cad annulled. Defiant Ellen who believes she is in love wants no part of her father's plan for her jumps ship to shore and eventually finds herself on a bus bound for New York. Here she hopes to reunite with her husband and live happily ever after. On board the Greyhound bus she meets Peter, none the worse for wear and recently fired from his newspaper for being drunk on the job. So begins an unlikely series of dealings between the two that stem from them agreeing to help each other out for a price of sorts. Peter recognizing Ellen from newspaper headlines as the much talked about runaway heiress, agrees to help her get to New York while she in turn offers him exclusive rights to her story, his hope is to revamp his career. The journey is series of memorable, classic, comical, events that draw the two closer together. Peter never one to hold back on his opinion and ever nonchalant, often chastises "Brat" his nickname for Ellen, because of her bourgeois tendencies and take on life, whereas he is a down to earth working class man; depicted in sharp close up clarity, every handsome rugged feature proving to be aesthetically camera friendly always defining his cool no nonsense sensibility. The two collide, bicker and banter about everything. There's is not an apparent match made in heaven but their liaison becomes more meaningful the longer they spend together. Peter is assiduous in keeping his promise to Ellen; Ellen is just doe eyed and realizes she is in love with the brash outspoken journalist. A timeless feature that that suggests Ellen's beauty and fragility is achieved with the application of a filtered lens on all of her close ups; this very effective application implies a softness and purity to her character. A notable fact about this seminal movie is the precedent it set for zany romantic comedies that would follow, such as Bringing up Baby (1938) and the Philadelphia Story (1940) both starring Katherine Hepburn and the impact it still has on screwball comedies today.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An antidote for depression
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Hotwok2013
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It isn't any wonder why "It Happened One Night" struck such a chord with movie-goers in the depression-hit USA of the 1930's. Frank Capra's sparkling romantic comedy is just about as uplifting as any movie possibly can be. Whatever it is that makes a star a star, Clark Gable had it in spades more than any other leading man before or since, & how could Claudette Colbert, (or any other woman?), not fall in love with him. Even allowing for the absurdities in the plot beginning with Ellie Andrews (Colbert) jumping her rich fathers yacht into the sea & swimming to shore. She is wearing a long white silk gown & not carrying a handbag. Next we see her at Miami bus station purchasing a ticket to New York in a new outfit with handbag!. The movie is full of memorably entertaining scenes & I guarantee that if anyone is feeling a bit low this film will improve their mood.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Romantic Comedy Supreme.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SmileysWorld
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Boy meets girl.They come from different roads in life and don't see eye to eye at first,but gradually they fall in love.This is a theme we have seen again and again throughout cinema history.Sometimes it is done well and sometimes..not so much.This is definitely the film that started it all,and the mold was broken.This is by far the best romantic comedy that I have ever seen.Claudette Colbert may not have thought so,for it has been said that she said to a friend after completing production that she had just finished "the worst film I have ever done."Surely she changed her tone when they placed the Best Actress Oscar in her hands.The screen chemistry between Colbert and Gable was right on the money.It is THE laugh out loud romantic classic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Young people in love are never hu-un-gry!" The granddaddy of all rom-coms
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    LouE15
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I stumbled across this film recently, expecting it to do no more than help me kill some time. Several viewings on, I'm hooked  it seems almost incredible that it was made in 1934, not 1984 or 2004. There isn't a romantic comedy in existence, and never will be, that doesn't owe a debt to this film. It's funny, modern, charming, and meaningful about people  what more do you want? Colour? Ah, nuts. Clark Gable plays Peter, a cynical journalist who ends up on a road trip across a Depression-hit USA with runaway heiress Ellen (Claudette Colbert). Ellen's sheltered life has done nothing to prepare her for the trials that lie ahead. She's so certain that she knows what she wants, and what's best: she's naive, but sparky and intelligent. She has to be knocked down in order to have her eyes peeled open. * Some spoilers from here* I thought I knew all about Clark Gable, and wasn't that bothered, but here he radiates masterful alpha-male charm and can switch on a dime from comedy to a love scene, boyish vulnerability to hardboiled cynic and back again. I don't know which version of him I liked more, although I think my favourite mini-moment comes when he's hardboiling it for the telegram girl, pipe in mouth - Philip Marlowe if ever there was one. The script is full of wonderful details  I don't know how much was in the original short story but I get the impression a great deal must have been added in to make it funnier. Oh, let me count the ways her not understanding what a real piggy back ride ishis hilariously terrible attempts at hitchhikingMr Believe You Me...Peter's "shut up" when they're back on the bus (which brings to mind James Cagney and That Grapefruit)and then his petulant sulk when he realises he's losing the upper hand, falling in love and just a shade jealousit's all great. I was hysterical by the time we met the operatic buggy driver  ever since I first saw the film I've been turning everyday trivialities into Gilbert & Sullivan libretto  and I just loved Peter's shouty conversation with Ellen's dad. But best of all are the lessons Ellen has to learn. For all her wealth and snobbery, and for all we enjoy her gradual comeuppance, she shows she's capable of learning (finally being hungry enough to eat a raw carrot!), and is worthy of Peter's love. When, near the end, she's weepily describing to her father how poor Peter's opinion is of them both ("you should hear what he says about you!"), capping it off with "he's marvellous(sob)", you're right there with her. "It happened one night" is in danger of eclipsing William Powell's wonderful "My Man Gordon" as my favourite thirties film. It's revised my lazy opinion about Clark Gable too  but it won't make me like "Gone with the Wind" any better, I don't care what anyone says.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Part one of two. My introduction of IHON, the background story on Capra's 1st miracle film.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Larry41OnEbay-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The idea for IT HAPPENED ONE NIGHT started in a barber shop while Frank Capra was waiting for a haircut he read an old magazine article in Cosmopolitan called "Night Bus" by Samuel Hopkins Adams. It was a cute idea so Capra asked Columbia studios to buy the rights to it and then he forgot about it. Frank's previous feature was LADY FOR A DAY which got great reviews and was Columbia studio's first film ever Oscar nominated and Capra's. Irving Thalberg wanted Capra to make his next film at MGM in exchange for $50k and the loan of a star. But at the last minute Louis B. Mayer canceled the film but honored the deal. Back at Columbia Capra wanted to make Night Bus, but studio tyrant Harry Cohn and all his advisers fought against it. They said things like, "It's nothing; froth, trivia, just another bus picture, no suspense, no heart, no oomph, winter's coming and it's all exteriors." All they could get Capra to do was change the title to IT HAPPENED ONE NIGHT which they said was too long to fit on a marquee! Capra tried casting Myrna Loy  she turned it down; then Margaret Sullavan  said 'no thank you'; Miriam Hopkins was insulted and said, 'Not if I never play another part'; Constance Bennett told him to go fly a kite and then offered to buy the script and have it rewritten for her! Capra had co-written the script with his favorite writer Robert Riskin but they brought in Myles Connolly who added more sympathetic and interesting characters so people could identify with them. The pretty girl, a spoiled brat, was rich yes but bored with being an heiress now wanting something real. The man was made a guy we all know and like; a tough crusading reporter on the outs with his pigheaded editor. It's The Taming Of The Shrew, but the shrew must be worth taming and the guy must be one of us. Back to casting, this time they went after Robert Montgomery a great light comedian at MGM. Mayer called Cohn and said, "Montgomery says there are too many bus pictures and (don't take this in the wrong way) but going from MGM to lowly Columbia was an insult. But you've caught me in a good mood. I got an actor here who's been a bad boy. Wants more money. And I'd like to spank him. You can have Clark Gable." Surprisingly the next knock on Capra's shabby office door came from a very drunk and cursing Gable, reporting to Siberia as he called it. Gable's objections almost made Capra throw in the towel but then Harry Cohn suggested getting Claudette Colbert for the girl in the story. (He had heard she liked money.) So Capra and Riskin made an appointment that very night to see her at her home. When they arrived Colbert regretted agreeing to the meeting as she was packing to leave on a month long skiing vacation. Capra saw this attractive, wealthy and spoiled woman and knew she was perfect for the part. So Capra, after being bit in the butt by her dog, asked what it would take to get her in the picture. (Capra had directed her first picture, FOR THE LOVE OF MIKE a silent made in 1927 and a flop) To throw him off she said she normally made $25k a picture (a price Columbia had never paid to an actor before), he would have to double it AND she was only available from her studio Paramount during her Christmas vacation. They would have to shoot all her scenes and retakes in less than 4 weeks -- half the time they had budgeted! So Capra called Cohn to ask would he pay her the $50k, Cohn said "I can pay it if you can shoot it in 4 weeks." Capra said, he didn't know, but he'd try. So they told her, "Deal, Claudette! $50k for 4 weeks! Okay?" To which she replied, "Oh for God's sake!" She was trapped. That next day she had to report for her costume fittings and the day after that they begin filming in a hurry. While they shot film all day Capra edited and rewrote the story to tighten it up at night. To make the film and story move quicker he asked the actors to talk faster, his amazing cinematographer Joseph Walker to shoot faster. (continued...)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    wonder why they called it, it happened one night
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lagudafuad
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It Happened One Night is one of the only three movies since the commencement of the Academy Awards to have been able to win all five major Academy Awards (Best Picture, Best Director, Best Actor, Best Actress, and Best Screenplay), a feat that would not be matched until One Flew Over the Cuckoo's Nest in 1975 and of cause latter on in 1991, Anthony Hopkins The Silence of the Lambs followed suit. Here is a romantic comedy as raw as they come giving you a thrill as you watch two people miss matched from the start found a way to fall in love and tour America on their way to New York. The funny thing about the movie is the name which says, "It happened one night" when actually in the movie's story it actually went on for more than a night. The movie plot is about Ellie Andrews (Claudette Colbert) who has been whisked away by her father in his yacht to keep her away from her new husband King Westley. Ellie then jumps ship, swim to shore and heads off to New York to meet with King Westley. On her way she meets a reporter Peter Warne (Clark Gable) and both started as an unsuitable pair that grew to be lovers. Both Colbert and Gable felt the movie was not going to be good enough and gave Capra a lot of bull. Even the movie's iconic scene where Colbert lifted up her skirt to stop a car during the hitchhiking scene, was not so easy to film for Capra as Colbert refused to do the scene claiming it was not lady like, but upon seeing a body double do it, she later changed her mind and did it herself. Although picking up slow, the movie later became one the biggest hits for the studio and the thing is that at the end the movie cleared the Academy Awards and both Gable and Colbert were better off. Colbert is known to have told a friend, "I just finished the worst picture in the world." She boycotted the Academy Awards when she got a nomination believing she will not win, but she was called back to come pick up her award. Here is a movie that actually makes you smile all the way through, although like the actors themselves upon initial siting of the film you can be turned off thinking this is heading nowhere, but be patient the movie has all the familiar scenes that we see in the movies today (all taken from this old classic). This old classic is tagged the 46th greatest film in the last 100 years in the AFI's 100 Years... 100 Movies (10th Anniversary Edition). It Happened One Night is a nice DVD for one to place on the shelf. www.lagsreviews.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It Remains The Best Romantic Comedy Ever Released On Screen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It Happened One Night is a romantic comedy film with elements of screwball comedy directed by Frank Capra, in which a pampered socialite tries to get out from under her father's thumb, and falls in love with a roguish reporter. It features Clark Gable,Claudette Colbert and Walter Connolly.The plot was based on the short story Night Bus by Samuel Hopkins Adams, which provided the shooting title. Ellie Andrews is a spoiled heiress who has married fortune-hunting aviator King Westley, despite her father's objections. To keep Ellie from marrying this Lothario, her father has been holding her prisoner aboard his yacht. But Ellie bolts from the yacht, swims ashore in her clothes, and eventually slips onto a Greyhound bus bound for New York. Aboard the bus is newspaper reporter Peter Warne, who has recently been fired for drinking on the job. Peter gets the last seat on the bus but when he gets up to argue with the bus driver, Ellie takes his seat. Since it is the last seat on the bus, they have to share it. When Ellie has her purse stolen and she refuses to report it, Peter begins to suspect something. The next morning, they both miss the bus after a leisurely breakfast, and Peter reveals that he knows her identity. She makes a deal with him: if he helps her get to New York, he can write a scoop about her for his paper. Peter thinks she is a spoiled brat, however, and refuses a monetary bribe: "I'm not interested in your money or your problem. You, King Westley, your father you're all a lot of hooey to me" But as they travel northward and engage in a series of misadventures, the gruff newspaperman and the spoiled rich girl, thrown together by circumstances, fall in love with each other. Director Frank Capra took home every major Oscars for this seminal comedy. Funny and sexy, the film is full of memorable scenes often referred to in other films, such as the "walls of Jericho" and Colbert's famous flash of thigh to stop a speeding car in its tracks.This is Capra at his best, very funny and very light, with a minimum of populist posturing.His brisk, urbane brand of wit was a perfect complement to his populist faith in the common man, and that inspired combination makes this film both a spirited entertainment and an uplifting experience.This is still is pure delight to watch at present and it still remains the best screwball comedy ever released as remains unsurpassed by the countless romantic comedies it has inspired.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
