<filme>
 <id>
  610
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0051658
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1958
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Gigi
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.8
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Weary of the conventions of Parisian society, a rich playboy and a youthful courtesan-in-training enjoy a platonic friendship, but it may not stay platonic for long.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Weary of the conventions of Parisian society, a rich playboy and a youthful courtesan-in-training enjoy a platonic friendship, but it may not stay platonic for long. Gaston, the scion of a wealthy Parisian family finds emotional refuge from the superficial lifestyle of upper class Parisian 1900s society with the former mistress of his uncle and her outgoing, tomboy granddaughter, Gigi. When Gaston becomes aware that Gigi has matured into a woman, her grandmother and aunt, who have educated Gigi to be a wealthy man's mistress, urge the pair to act out their roles but love adds a surprise twist to this delightful turn-of-the 20th century Cinderella story.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Musical
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Romance
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   playboy
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   1900s
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   love
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   ice rink
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   courtship
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Vincente Minnelli
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Alan Jay Lerner
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Colette
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Leslie Caron
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Maurice Chevalier
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Louis Jourdan
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unintentionally creepy, with only one standout song
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Conrad
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A musical with only two memorable songs ("Thank Heaven for Little Girls" and "It's a Bore"), only one of which is good ("It's a Bore"), is not likely to be a good musical. Indeed, this is one of the most boring and poorly-acted in the history of the genre. The story ostensibly takes place in France, but it seems to unfold mainly in bland, claustrophobic drawing rooms. The title character's naive, youthful waifishness makes the relationship aspect of the film feel vaguely inappropriate, and this is only underscored by the aforementioned song about little girls, which is sung by a quintessentially creepy old man. This is a contender for worst Best Picture winner.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I Remembered It Wrong....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mark.waltz
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I first saw "Gigi" as a teenager, I was bewitched by its lavish costumes, sumptuous sets and delightful score, but in repeat viewings of it, I had to rank it as an overrated disappointment. Now some 25 years later, I watched it again, and while I don't consider it a perfect film (one worthy of a Best Picture Oscar), I do see it in a different light and appreciated it a bit more, taking my rating up from a 5 to an 8, **1/2 to ***1/2 on the Maltin scale. The days of living like Paris in the early 1900's are long gone, but it is certainly nice to re-visit them and the sweet duet between the aging Maurice Chevalier and Hermoine Gingold, the two scene-stealers of this film. Chevalier isn't the leading man he once was; In fact, Louis Jourdan, playing a part that Chevalier might have portrayed at Paramount during the early 1930's, doesn't seem quite up to the assignment, even if he is handsome, charming and well to do. Leslie Caron, however, does win in the title role, replacing Audrey Hepburn (from the stage productions) and being totally likable, especially when she sings "I Don't Understand the Parisians". Watching her grow from somewhat innocent teen to sophisticated young lady isn't quite like Hepburn going from guttersnipe to sophisticate in "My Fair Lady", even if the stories have a lot in common. The musical score has some bright moments, but some of the songs aren't as memorable as Lerner and Lowe's stage songs. The title song, in particular, suffers from some weak lyrics, and that defuses the dramatic impact of what it is trying to do. But when Chevalier and Gingold get together to reminisce in "I Remember It Well" and Gingold dances around with Jordan and Caron to "The Night They Invented Champagne", magic is made. Chevalier has a sly wink as the aging Honore, and in his relatively few scenes is the glue which holds the movie together. In smaller roles, Eva Gabor (as a two-timing lover of Jordan's) and Isabel Jeans (as the courtesan sister of Gingold) offer sophisticated bitchery. Gingold, a magic performer in everything she does, could be funny just looking around, and you wonder if her much later Broadway character of Madame Armfeldt in "A Little Night Music" could be a distant cousin of the family's. Superbly put together by the master of art in MGM musicals (Vincent Minnelli), "Gigi" can be appreciated more in repeat viewings as you get older, but some slow dramatic spots really cause it to drag a bit. That is minor, however, as this French creme pastry is lovely to look at, even though it may not entirely fill you up.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the most beautifully presented Musicals of all time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Koundinya
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The first time i watched the movie, i felt it was a "bore". The movie hardly has any running time of the character Gigi. The characters were melodramatic and their language was a butchered version of English. I never found the most vital element of Humor missing in the movie and was totally let down after having watched musicals like Singin' in the Rain and Wizard of Oz. Well, it was quite a long time back. I must agree i matured as a person who understands movie and appreciates it and not merely judge a movie based on its efficacy in entertaining. The movie is undoubtedly an entertainer. As the movie progressed, i started to understand the uniqueness of the movie and was enthralled by the songs and art setting. The movie is set in Paris at the turn of the century and the lifestyle, sartorial, marital and tonsorial preferences of the inhabitants is discreetly presented. The songs are brilliantly written and set to euphonious background music and when i paid heed to the lyrics, i realized what i greatly missed the first time i watched it- Humor. The movie also brings forth a message that no matter how rich and famous a man is, his heart remains vacant for a woman who remains herself and not be camouflaged with book-learned principles on satisfying a man.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    6.9?!?!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Gigi" won more Oscars than almost any other film in history. Yet, very oddly, it currently has an IMDb score of only 6.9! This makes no sense--especially since the film is magnificent throughout. The film is based on the story by Colette. It's about a sweet young lady, Gigi, and her family's insane intention of turning her into a very high-priced mistress to the rich and famous. However, because Gigi is so sweet, she just can't allow herself to have such a life and she insists on more--which causes problems with the man she loves (Louis Jourdan). While the plot is very simple (as it often is with musicals), the film works magnificently for several reasons. Most importantly, the Lerner and Lowe songs are among the best of any musical and are very memorable. In addition, the acting is so nice--and Leslie Caron is radiant and at her very best. Additionally, the film is just gorgeous--and replicates the grandeur of Paris circa 1900. Why this film has such a current mediocre score is beyond me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Curiously, no dancing...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dave from Ottawa
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Big Hollywood Musical genre in the 1950s was paved with ever more elaborate dance production numbers due to the popularity of stars like Gene Kelly, Fred Astaire and Cyd Charisse and yet rather curiously the ballet-trained Leslie Caron does not dance in this one and neither does anybody else. Still, 19th century Paris (the parks, the boulevards, Maxim's, the Follies etc.) is lavishly re-created, the costume designs are marvelous and the Lerner and Lowe songs are very good, if somewhat static in their presentation. The story is almost lighter than air, something about Caron reluctantly being groomed as a chic courtesan, but there is only enough to plot the keep things moving ahead as the camera tracks through or peeks into one gorgeously designed Parisian backdrop after another. The picture remains an old fashioned charmer thanks to million pretty things to look at and winning performances by Caron and especially Maurice Chevalier as an older rogue tutoring younger Louis Jourdan.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    At least I got 15 min sleep near the end
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    frankf-10
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I had seen this before years ago, but only could remember that it didn't impress me much. My wife selected the DVD via Netflix and 20 minutes into the film, all I could say to her was, "When is this movie going to start?" Slow moving hardly describes it. And Gaston repeating endlessly how boring things were for him hardly seems a way to entertain. I have never been much of a Maurice Chevalier fan and seeing him, as others have noted, oogling young girls in this flick is definitely weird now. Reading through reviews here, I was reminded how many Academy Awards it won - yikes! The Academy BS I can almost understand, but why IMDb reviewers found this leaden clunker so terrific is beyond me. Thank gawd I did get some shuteye toward the end.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Colourful character study which does remarkably well with two people crashing head first into a newfound state of thinking in regards to a chauvinistic lifestyle.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    johnnyboyz (j_l_h_m@yahoo.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gigi is a film about a young female protagonist asked to fall in with a highly specific male crowd; a crowd of whom carry with them the idea that something called "gender patriotism" consists of the wrecking of a woman's life, if she should ever leave you, by using your deep pockets of filthy wealth to buy off the man for whom she left you and convince him to leave town so that she is thus rendered totally heartbroken. If they suffer, why should't she? The men within this clique celebrate such an ideology, laughing and joking with one another; even taking time to indulge in speaking of the living by such rules with their barber, whom appears equally as enthused by such behaviour. On one occasion, it even led to the attempted suicide of one of those women  ah, well. But the film is not as it sounds, and will go on to cover this young female protagonist as well as her consequent frustrations out of trying to reject, or steer clear of, such an ill-gotten series of men and their livelihoods; the film eventually forming a piece about character we pray can find some sort of common-ground amidst what they exist - the film eventually an exuberant; careful piece treading along a fine line of bourgeoises indulgence and materialistic exploitation that comes together and actually works. The film unfolds in Paris; the year-clock in the French capital registering 1900. Leslie Caron plays the titular Gigi and that young protagonist slowly but surely being taught and groomed into falling in with a man to whom she may be able to act politely; overtly eloquently and essentially become the drone-wife that speaks when spoken to and laughs at her husband and his rich friend's anecdotes on prompt  after having brought out the tea for them, of course. But Gigi has an edge to her; a certain 'bite' and she is a faster and looser girl to that of what her contemporaries would like. In spite of being born into a fairly rich family, Gigi wishes not to head down a route of snobbery and such; instead, draws on inspiration from her mother - someone whom wanted more than what was offered, although someone, as her grandmother points out, whom chased a dream and failed to amount to what it was she desired when menial work at an opera house was the end product. In spite of this warning, as well as her grandmother's dismissive or hopeful tone that she will fail, we find it easy to get behind her. The man with whom she will come to interact a great deal more throughout is Louis Jourdan's Gaston Lachaille, the nephew of an elderly man named Honor&eacute; (Chevalier), whose attitudes towards women both now and throughout his life have been false and somewhat hate-filled although distilled through a filter of deft tones and extravagance. When we begin with him, he speaks to us on how he classifies his life profession as "lover" and we are drawn into a romanticised tone complimenting the sort of lifestyle in which a man like Honor&eacute; may waltz down a public street harbouring the opinions he has on the opposite sex. If we react as strongly as we ought to, our alignment with Gigi slips even easier into happening as she herself attempts to reject a kind of coercement director Vincente Minnelli attempts to relate onto that of the audience during the opening beats. Like Gigi, Gaston faces a seeping influence agonisingly trickling down from his peers and relations in regards to lifestyle choices and attitudes towards the other gender. Unlike most of his ilk, Gaston is fed up with the predominant items available and desires a change from socialite holidays to nations such as Italy and Spain, as well as the finer things on offer in Paris in the form of wines and such; something established through one of the film's many delightful musical numbers and a reoccurring quote throughout of "it's a bore" confirming this. Life for Gigi has reached a point in which honing skills in acting the socialite-come-snob for interactions should be the norm; the girl ambitious, and rather well off before this transitional phase, but her statements reiterating that she "doesn't understand Parisians" and that "there must be more to life than this" firmly establish her alienation to not only where she is, but the sorts of people with which she bonds. Primarily, these two characters coming together after seeking immense change from the patriarchal norm drives the film; Gaston's fondness for Gigi not equalled by her still prejudiced thinking when she deems him just as bad as anyone else in this messy cesspit of socialisation. One of the subtler moments of Jourdan's performance, going on neatly to project how he feels on what surrounds him, lies in the scene during which he loiters with his fellow men in that fatuous circle of elitism; a champagne toast to what they believe is carried out with a profound sense of glee evident on the faces of most of those present, but a wry peek at Gaston's facial expression amidst the extravagance and so-forth as everyone takes a sip reveals someone in deeper thought about this way of life than any of the others. In a film rich in colour; set decoration and faux-romanticism, best surmised when that wily rouge Honor&eacute; keeps getting his recollections shot down as he recalls decades-ago interludes with women now of his age, the film is deathly efficient in targeting people wanting out and away or something else anew. Many of the musical numbers work well, with one in which Gaston struggles with the coming to terms on how he feels for Gigi particularly standing out in memory, and the film generally pulls us in with its overlying juxtaposition of mise-en-scene with interior thematics; a deconstructing and retelling of stories of those within consummately seeing it home.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Enjoyable, but a wasted opportunity...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BlueEyes72
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gigi (Leslie Caron) is a young girl living in Paris in 1900, and being raised by her grandmother and great aunt to be a courtesan. Gaston (Louis Jourdan) is a rich Parisian playboy, who has become bored of his superficial lifestyle. He and Gigi have a platonic friendship, but as she becomes more sophisticated and grown up, the dynamic of their relationship starts to change This film, based on the novel by French author Colette, was not the last musical released by the MGM studios, but it was the last musical made by the Arthur Freed Unit at MGM (this unit was responsible for many of the classic musicals of the day, including Easter Parade, An American in Paris, and of course, Singin' In The Rain). The unit's swansong did very well, being nominated for nine Oscar awards, and winning all of them, breaking the then record of eight Oscars, held by Gone With The Wind. I thought the film was good, but not great. Some parts of it definitely worked  Leslie Caron was a delight as Gigi. I was not convinced by her performance in An American In Paris (although I l0ve An American In Paris and never get bored of watching it), but here she was great, and actually rather adorable. Audrey Hepburn was originally picked to play the part (having played Gigi on stage before she was famous), but due to other filming commitments, she was not available. Audrey is one of my favourite actresses, and I think she would have been perfect in the role, but Leslie Caron really worked well. Louis Jourdan was also great as the cynical and bored Gaston  making what could have been rather a dislikeable character into someone who the viewer liked a lot. Hermione Gingold and Isabel Jeans provided good support as Gigi's grandmother and great aunt. There were some lovely songs, in particular the title number sung by Louis Jourdan as he wanders throughout Paris, realising that his feelings for Gigi are changing; and the incredibly catchy The Night They Invented Champagne which I couldn't get out of my head after watching the film. Paris itself looks fabulous  most of the film was shot on location there, and it really is a lovely setting, very colourful and pretty. There were some parts that I didn't like  Maurice Chevalier's character Honore (the uncle of Gaston) seemed an unnecessary and distasteful character. This is no criticism of Chevalier's acting, which was fine, but the character was hard for me to warm to. In one scene Honore is highly delighted upon hearing that a former girlfriend of Gaston's has tried to kill herself after he ended her relationship. Honore toasts Gaston and says that he hopes this will be the first of many suicides. It may have been written flippantly, but this scene did not sit well with me. (Indeed the whole storyline of two women training their young relation to be a courtesan could be distasteful, although it was handled fairly well and with humour.) I was also slightly disappointed that there was no dancing in this film! I love to see fabulous dancing in musicals, and with Leslie Caron being an excellent ballet dancer, it feels like a missed opportunity not to show off her skills. Overall then, it's an enjoyable film, but ultimately a forgettable one. Worth watching for fans of musicals.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gee its grand to watch Gigi over and over, a film my sisters and I have adored from childhood
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Amy Adler
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In Paris, during the middle of the 19th century, handsome Gaston (Louis Jordan) is a sugar empire heir with a great deal of money. Like his father, Honore (Maurice Chevalier), he has shunned marriage in favor of having a succession of beautiful women. His present love, Lianne (Eva Gabor) is certainly pretty. But, as Gaston relates in song, he is truly bored with his lofty position in society, with women, and with parties. The only place he feels comfortable is at the home of an old friend (and former flame of Honore's), Mamita (Hermione Gingold). Odd it is, because the dear lady is rather poor and lives in an unfashionable neighborhood with her opera singing daughter AND her vivacious granddaughter, Gigi (Leslie Caron). Although she is in her middle teen years, Gigi is still treated by Gaston and her grandmama as a little girl and, in truth, she still acts as one, being very innocent and wide-eyed. Gaston loves eating Mamita's great cooking and playing cards with Gigi, away from the social scene. Unhappily, the sugar king soon finds that his "lady love" has been unfaithful and he makes a very publicized break with Lianne. To boost his spirits and pay off a card game debt to Gigi, Gaston, Mamita, and Gigi all go to the seashore for a vacation. They have a great time. But, Mamita's sister, also a former courtesan, wishes to change things when the trio returns to Paris. She sees that Gigi is really a young woman and, perhaps, they have a chance to offer her up as Gaston's next courtesan? She'd be well taken care of that's for certain. The only problem is that Gigi may not want to become the kind of woman who gets "passed around" but, rather, might want to be married and have children. What will the next season bring? Gee willikers is Gigi a pleasure to watch, as I and my sisters have done since our sixties' childhood. A musical, it nevertheless has enough non-musical action to satisfy those who don't particularly care for the genre. However, the songs are lovely and integral to the plot. Then, the acting is great, with Caron, Jordan, Chevalier, Ginggold and all of the others being near perfect in their respective roles. Also, the Paris setting, the terrific costumes, the lovely photography, and the superb direction by Vincente Minelli all contribute to the movie's enjoyment. It was awarded an Academy Award as best picture in 1958 and deservedly so. With that fact in mind, why not seek out Gigi ASAP?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "A gigantic, romantic clich&eacute;"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steffi_P
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There was a wave of stage-to-screen adaptations of hit musicals in the mid-1950s, translating the work of the two celebrated theatrical duos Rodgers and Hammerstein and Lerner and Loewe for a new audience. However this Arthur Freed production moves the other way, as Alan Jay Lerner and Frederick Loewe were hired by MGM to create a musical directly for the cinema, a sign perhaps that Broadway was beginning to take its rival more seriously. The result is in many ways an elaborately cinematic affair. Gigi takes advantage of the medium, having for example Maurice Chevalier break that pesky fourth wall and address the audience eye-to-eye, in reference to his screen musicals of the early 30s. We also have, in "She Is Not Thinking of Me", a song done in voice-over as an internal monologue  not, I believe, an original idea but certainly one that would be impossible (or at least very awkward) on the stage. As in their recent stage success My Fair Lady, Lerner and Loewe's songwriting is led by the lyrics, with a number like "It's a Bore" playing out like a musical conversation, with Loewe's melody skittering along to Lerner's vibrant wordplay. Their songs often serve to define character and relationships between characters. "It's a Bore" and "I Don't Understand the Parisians" are companion pieces as it were, and their similarities set up Gigi and Gaston as kindred spirits. Still, there are only a handful of really great numbers here ("The Night they Invented Champagne" being the standout), and one can't help getting the impression that Gigi is made up of cast-offs from the perfect My Fair Lady score. The lavishness of an Arthur Freed production ensured that his musicals were as much about look as they were sound. Gigi represents an astounding collaboration between cinematographer Joseph Ruttenberg, production designer Cecil Beaton and director Vincente Minnelli to reproduce the quality of fin-de-siecle painting, especially that of Auguste Renoir. The deliberate use of unfocused backgrounds in the opening scene is one of the best ever recreations of the impressionist style on screen. Minnelli (himself a keen painter) has a fine handling of perspective. Take the scene where Leslie Caron and Louis Jourdan are shelling peas. There is a chair in the foreground on the left-hand side, while on the right there is an open doorway into the kitchen. This contrast between closeness on one side and distance on the other not only adds real definition to the space, it allows the eye to be easily drawn from one end of the frame to the other, keeping Hermione Gingold highlighted even though she is in the background without having to resort to lots of obtrusive cutting. This is just one example, but it's a trick Minnelli pulls in almost every shot. The production is extremely lucky to have three genuine French stars for its principle parts, especially ones who were familiar enough with Hollywood to give an acceptable impression of Frenchness. Leslie Caron does a very credible job of playing a young girl on the verge of womanhood (she was in reality twenty-six) in a comically playful turn. Louis Jourdan is a little bland but by all means likable, and besides it suits him to look a little flat to all the better show off co-stars Caron and Chevalier. Ah oui, monsieur Chevalier, a man who is to an authentic portrayal of France what a crate of absinthe is to a light soiree. But for all his over-the-topness, he is great fun, slipping on the character of the ageing Lothario like an old glove. And those Lerner and Loewe songs like "I Remember It Well", where normal speech dovetails into singing, suit him very well. But while Gigi contains much to delight, as a whole it is lacking something. There just doesn't seem to be the heart or substance to the telling of the story that other Oscar-winning musicals have. Loewe in particular was reportedly reluctant to work in cinema, and both he and Lerner were overruled on a few decisions such as casting and inclusion of certain songs, so perhaps this explains the below-par score. Unsurprisingly it was a flop when adapted for the stage fifteen years later. Such is the care that has gone into those wonderful images, Gigi is far more a treat for the eyes than the ears, a coup were this purely a purely visual medium, but it falls some way short of being a superlative musical.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unintentionally creepy, with only one standout song
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Conrad
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A musical with only two memorable songs ("Thank Heaven for Little Girls" and "It's a Bore"), only one of which is good ("It's a Bore"), is not likely to be a good musical. Indeed, this is one of the most boring and poorly-acted in the history of the genre. The story ostensibly takes place in France, but it seems to unfold mainly in bland, claustrophobic drawing rooms. The title character's naive, youthful waifishness makes the relationship aspect of the film feel vaguely inappropriate, and this is only underscored by the aforementioned song about little girls, which is sung by a quintessentially creepy old man. This is a contender for worst Best Picture winner.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I Remembered It Wrong....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mark.waltz
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I first saw "Gigi" as a teenager, I was bewitched by its lavish costumes, sumptuous sets and delightful score, but in repeat viewings of it, I had to rank it as an overrated disappointment. Now some 25 years later, I watched it again, and while I don't consider it a perfect film (one worthy of a Best Picture Oscar), I do see it in a different light and appreciated it a bit more, taking my rating up from a 5 to an 8, **1/2 to ***1/2 on the Maltin scale. The days of living like Paris in the early 1900's are long gone, but it is certainly nice to re-visit them and the sweet duet between the aging Maurice Chevalier and Hermoine Gingold, the two scene-stealers of this film. Chevalier isn't the leading man he once was; In fact, Louis Jourdan, playing a part that Chevalier might have portrayed at Paramount during the early 1930's, doesn't seem quite up to the assignment, even if he is handsome, charming and well to do. Leslie Caron, however, does win in the title role, replacing Audrey Hepburn (from the stage productions) and being totally likable, especially when she sings "I Don't Understand the Parisians". Watching her grow from somewhat innocent teen to sophisticated young lady isn't quite like Hepburn going from guttersnipe to sophisticate in "My Fair Lady", even if the stories have a lot in common. The musical score has some bright moments, but some of the songs aren't as memorable as Lerner and Lowe's stage songs. The title song, in particular, suffers from some weak lyrics, and that defuses the dramatic impact of what it is trying to do. But when Chevalier and Gingold get together to reminisce in "I Remember It Well" and Gingold dances around with Jordan and Caron to "The Night They Invented Champagne", magic is made. Chevalier has a sly wink as the aging Honore, and in his relatively few scenes is the glue which holds the movie together. In smaller roles, Eva Gabor (as a two-timing lover of Jordan's) and Isabel Jeans (as the courtesan sister of Gingold) offer sophisticated bitchery. Gingold, a magic performer in everything she does, could be funny just looking around, and you wonder if her much later Broadway character of Madame Armfeldt in "A Little Night Music" could be a distant cousin of the family's. Superbly put together by the master of art in MGM musicals (Vincent Minnelli), "Gigi" can be appreciated more in repeat viewings as you get older, but some slow dramatic spots really cause it to drag a bit. That is minor, however, as this French creme pastry is lovely to look at, even though it may not entirely fill you up.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the most beautifully presented Musicals of all time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Koundinya
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The first time i watched the movie, i felt it was a "bore". The movie hardly has any running time of the character Gigi. The characters were melodramatic and their language was a butchered version of English. I never found the most vital element of Humor missing in the movie and was totally let down after having watched musicals like Singin' in the Rain and Wizard of Oz. Well, it was quite a long time back. I must agree i matured as a person who understands movie and appreciates it and not merely judge a movie based on its efficacy in entertaining. The movie is undoubtedly an entertainer. As the movie progressed, i started to understand the uniqueness of the movie and was enthralled by the songs and art setting. The movie is set in Paris at the turn of the century and the lifestyle, sartorial, marital and tonsorial preferences of the inhabitants is discreetly presented. The songs are brilliantly written and set to euphonious background music and when i paid heed to the lyrics, i realized what i greatly missed the first time i watched it- Humor. The movie also brings forth a message that no matter how rich and famous a man is, his heart remains vacant for a woman who remains herself and not be camouflaged with book-learned principles on satisfying a man.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    6.9?!?!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Gigi" won more Oscars than almost any other film in history. Yet, very oddly, it currently has an IMDb score of only 6.9! This makes no sense--especially since the film is magnificent throughout. The film is based on the story by Colette. It's about a sweet young lady, Gigi, and her family's insane intention of turning her into a very high-priced mistress to the rich and famous. However, because Gigi is so sweet, she just can't allow herself to have such a life and she insists on more--which causes problems with the man she loves (Louis Jourdan). While the plot is very simple (as it often is with musicals), the film works magnificently for several reasons. Most importantly, the Lerner and Lowe songs are among the best of any musical and are very memorable. In addition, the acting is so nice--and Leslie Caron is radiant and at her very best. Additionally, the film is just gorgeous--and replicates the grandeur of Paris circa 1900. Why this film has such a current mediocre score is beyond me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Curiously, no dancing...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dave from Ottawa
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Big Hollywood Musical genre in the 1950s was paved with ever more elaborate dance production numbers due to the popularity of stars like Gene Kelly, Fred Astaire and Cyd Charisse and yet rather curiously the ballet-trained Leslie Caron does not dance in this one and neither does anybody else. Still, 19th century Paris (the parks, the boulevards, Maxim's, the Follies etc.) is lavishly re-created, the costume designs are marvelous and the Lerner and Lowe songs are very good, if somewhat static in their presentation. The story is almost lighter than air, something about Caron reluctantly being groomed as a chic courtesan, but there is only enough to plot the keep things moving ahead as the camera tracks through or peeks into one gorgeously designed Parisian backdrop after another. The picture remains an old fashioned charmer thanks to million pretty things to look at and winning performances by Caron and especially Maurice Chevalier as an older rogue tutoring younger Louis Jourdan.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    At least I got 15 min sleep near the end
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    frankf-10
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I had seen this before years ago, but only could remember that it didn't impress me much. My wife selected the DVD via Netflix and 20 minutes into the film, all I could say to her was, "When is this movie going to start?" Slow moving hardly describes it. And Gaston repeating endlessly how boring things were for him hardly seems a way to entertain. I have never been much of a Maurice Chevalier fan and seeing him, as others have noted, oogling young girls in this flick is definitely weird now. Reading through reviews here, I was reminded how many Academy Awards it won - yikes! The Academy BS I can almost understand, but why IMDb reviewers found this leaden clunker so terrific is beyond me. Thank gawd I did get some shuteye toward the end.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Colourful character study which does remarkably well with two people crashing head first into a newfound state of thinking in regards to a chauvinistic lifestyle.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    johnnyboyz (j_l_h_m@yahoo.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gigi is a film about a young female protagonist asked to fall in with a highly specific male crowd; a crowd of whom carry with them the idea that something called "gender patriotism" consists of the wrecking of a woman's life, if she should ever leave you, by using your deep pockets of filthy wealth to buy off the man for whom she left you and convince him to leave town so that she is thus rendered totally heartbroken. If they suffer, why should't she? The men within this clique celebrate such an ideology, laughing and joking with one another; even taking time to indulge in speaking of the living by such rules with their barber, whom appears equally as enthused by such behaviour. On one occasion, it even led to the attempted suicide of one of those women  ah, well. But the film is not as it sounds, and will go on to cover this young female protagonist as well as her consequent frustrations out of trying to reject, or steer clear of, such an ill-gotten series of men and their livelihoods; the film eventually forming a piece about character we pray can find some sort of common-ground amidst what they exist - the film eventually an exuberant; careful piece treading along a fine line of bourgeoises indulgence and materialistic exploitation that comes together and actually works. The film unfolds in Paris; the year-clock in the French capital registering 1900. Leslie Caron plays the titular Gigi and that young protagonist slowly but surely being taught and groomed into falling in with a man to whom she may be able to act politely; overtly eloquently and essentially become the drone-wife that speaks when spoken to and laughs at her husband and his rich friend's anecdotes on prompt  after having brought out the tea for them, of course. But Gigi has an edge to her; a certain 'bite' and she is a faster and looser girl to that of what her contemporaries would like. In spite of being born into a fairly rich family, Gigi wishes not to head down a route of snobbery and such; instead, draws on inspiration from her mother - someone whom wanted more than what was offered, although someone, as her grandmother points out, whom chased a dream and failed to amount to what it was she desired when menial work at an opera house was the end product. In spite of this warning, as well as her grandmother's dismissive or hopeful tone that she will fail, we find it easy to get behind her. The man with whom she will come to interact a great deal more throughout is Louis Jourdan's Gaston Lachaille, the nephew of an elderly man named Honor&eacute; (Chevalier), whose attitudes towards women both now and throughout his life have been false and somewhat hate-filled although distilled through a filter of deft tones and extravagance. When we begin with him, he speaks to us on how he classifies his life profession as "lover" and we are drawn into a romanticised tone complimenting the sort of lifestyle in which a man like Honor&eacute; may waltz down a public street harbouring the opinions he has on the opposite sex. If we react as strongly as we ought to, our alignment with Gigi slips even easier into happening as she herself attempts to reject a kind of coercement director Vincente Minnelli attempts to relate onto that of the audience during the opening beats. Like Gigi, Gaston faces a seeping influence agonisingly trickling down from his peers and relations in regards to lifestyle choices and attitudes towards the other gender. Unlike most of his ilk, Gaston is fed up with the predominant items available and desires a change from socialite holidays to nations such as Italy and Spain, as well as the finer things on offer in Paris in the form of wines and such; something established through one of the film's many delightful musical numbers and a reoccurring quote throughout of "it's a bore" confirming this. Life for Gigi has reached a point in which honing skills in acting the socialite-come-snob for interactions should be the norm; the girl ambitious, and rather well off before this transitional phase, but her statements reiterating that she "doesn't understand Parisians" and that "there must be more to life than this" firmly establish her alienation to not only where she is, but the sorts of people with which she bonds. Primarily, these two characters coming together after seeking immense change from the patriarchal norm drives the film; Gaston's fondness for Gigi not equalled by her still prejudiced thinking when she deems him just as bad as anyone else in this messy cesspit of socialisation. One of the subtler moments of Jourdan's performance, going on neatly to project how he feels on what surrounds him, lies in the scene during which he loiters with his fellow men in that fatuous circle of elitism; a champagne toast to what they believe is carried out with a profound sense of glee evident on the faces of most of those present, but a wry peek at Gaston's facial expression amidst the extravagance and so-forth as everyone takes a sip reveals someone in deeper thought about this way of life than any of the others. In a film rich in colour; set decoration and faux-romanticism, best surmised when that wily rouge Honor&eacute; keeps getting his recollections shot down as he recalls decades-ago interludes with women now of his age, the film is deathly efficient in targeting people wanting out and away or something else anew. Many of the musical numbers work well, with one in which Gaston struggles with the coming to terms on how he feels for Gigi particularly standing out in memory, and the film generally pulls us in with its overlying juxtaposition of mise-en-scene with interior thematics; a deconstructing and retelling of stories of those within consummately seeing it home.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Enjoyable, but a wasted opportunity...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BlueEyes72
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gigi (Leslie Caron) is a young girl living in Paris in 1900, and being raised by her grandmother and great aunt to be a courtesan. Gaston (Louis Jourdan) is a rich Parisian playboy, who has become bored of his superficial lifestyle. He and Gigi have a platonic friendship, but as she becomes more sophisticated and grown up, the dynamic of their relationship starts to change This film, based on the novel by French author Colette, was not the last musical released by the MGM studios, but it was the last musical made by the Arthur Freed Unit at MGM (this unit was responsible for many of the classic musicals of the day, including Easter Parade, An American in Paris, and of course, Singin' In The Rain). The unit's swansong did very well, being nominated for nine Oscar awards, and winning all of them, breaking the then record of eight Oscars, held by Gone With The Wind. I thought the film was good, but not great. Some parts of it definitely worked  Leslie Caron was a delight as Gigi. I was not convinced by her performance in An American In Paris (although I l0ve An American In Paris and never get bored of watching it), but here she was great, and actually rather adorable. Audrey Hepburn was originally picked to play the part (having played Gigi on stage before she was famous), but due to other filming commitments, she was not available. Audrey is one of my favourite actresses, and I think she would have been perfect in the role, but Leslie Caron really worked well. Louis Jourdan was also great as the cynical and bored Gaston  making what could have been rather a dislikeable character into someone who the viewer liked a lot. Hermione Gingold and Isabel Jeans provided good support as Gigi's grandmother and great aunt. There were some lovely songs, in particular the title number sung by Louis Jourdan as he wanders throughout Paris, realising that his feelings for Gigi are changing; and the incredibly catchy The Night They Invented Champagne which I couldn't get out of my head after watching the film. Paris itself looks fabulous  most of the film was shot on location there, and it really is a lovely setting, very colourful and pretty. There were some parts that I didn't like  Maurice Chevalier's character Honore (the uncle of Gaston) seemed an unnecessary and distasteful character. This is no criticism of Chevalier's acting, which was fine, but the character was hard for me to warm to. In one scene Honore is highly delighted upon hearing that a former girlfriend of Gaston's has tried to kill herself after he ended her relationship. Honore toasts Gaston and says that he hopes this will be the first of many suicides. It may have been written flippantly, but this scene did not sit well with me. (Indeed the whole storyline of two women training their young relation to be a courtesan could be distasteful, although it was handled fairly well and with humour.) I was also slightly disappointed that there was no dancing in this film! I love to see fabulous dancing in musicals, and with Leslie Caron being an excellent ballet dancer, it feels like a missed opportunity not to show off her skills. Overall then, it's an enjoyable film, but ultimately a forgettable one. Worth watching for fans of musicals.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gee its grand to watch Gigi over and over, a film my sisters and I have adored from childhood
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Amy Adler
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In Paris, during the middle of the 19th century, handsome Gaston (Louis Jordan) is a sugar empire heir with a great deal of money. Like his father, Honore (Maurice Chevalier), he has shunned marriage in favor of having a succession of beautiful women. His present love, Lianne (Eva Gabor) is certainly pretty. But, as Gaston relates in song, he is truly bored with his lofty position in society, with women, and with parties. The only place he feels comfortable is at the home of an old friend (and former flame of Honore's), Mamita (Hermione Gingold). Odd it is, because the dear lady is rather poor and lives in an unfashionable neighborhood with her opera singing daughter AND her vivacious granddaughter, Gigi (Leslie Caron). Although she is in her middle teen years, Gigi is still treated by Gaston and her grandmama as a little girl and, in truth, she still acts as one, being very innocent and wide-eyed. Gaston loves eating Mamita's great cooking and playing cards with Gigi, away from the social scene. Unhappily, the sugar king soon finds that his "lady love" has been unfaithful and he makes a very publicized break with Lianne. To boost his spirits and pay off a card game debt to Gigi, Gaston, Mamita, and Gigi all go to the seashore for a vacation. They have a great time. But, Mamita's sister, also a former courtesan, wishes to change things when the trio returns to Paris. She sees that Gigi is really a young woman and, perhaps, they have a chance to offer her up as Gaston's next courtesan? She'd be well taken care of that's for certain. The only problem is that Gigi may not want to become the kind of woman who gets "passed around" but, rather, might want to be married and have children. What will the next season bring? Gee willikers is Gigi a pleasure to watch, as I and my sisters have done since our sixties' childhood. A musical, it nevertheless has enough non-musical action to satisfy those who don't particularly care for the genre. However, the songs are lovely and integral to the plot. Then, the acting is great, with Caron, Jordan, Chevalier, Ginggold and all of the others being near perfect in their respective roles. Also, the Paris setting, the terrific costumes, the lovely photography, and the superb direction by Vincente Minelli all contribute to the movie's enjoyment. It was awarded an Academy Award as best picture in 1958 and deservedly so. With that fact in mind, why not seek out Gigi ASAP?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "A gigantic, romantic clich&eacute;"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steffi_P
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There was a wave of stage-to-screen adaptations of hit musicals in the mid-1950s, translating the work of the two celebrated theatrical duos Rodgers and Hammerstein and Lerner and Loewe for a new audience. However this Arthur Freed production moves the other way, as Alan Jay Lerner and Frederick Loewe were hired by MGM to create a musical directly for the cinema, a sign perhaps that Broadway was beginning to take its rival more seriously. The result is in many ways an elaborately cinematic affair. Gigi takes advantage of the medium, having for example Maurice Chevalier break that pesky fourth wall and address the audience eye-to-eye, in reference to his screen musicals of the early 30s. We also have, in "She Is Not Thinking of Me", a song done in voice-over as an internal monologue  not, I believe, an original idea but certainly one that would be impossible (or at least very awkward) on the stage. As in their recent stage success My Fair Lady, Lerner and Loewe's songwriting is led by the lyrics, with a number like "It's a Bore" playing out like a musical conversation, with Loewe's melody skittering along to Lerner's vibrant wordplay. Their songs often serve to define character and relationships between characters. "It's a Bore" and "I Don't Understand the Parisians" are companion pieces as it were, and their similarities set up Gigi and Gaston as kindred spirits. Still, there are only a handful of really great numbers here ("The Night they Invented Champagne" being the standout), and one can't help getting the impression that Gigi is made up of cast-offs from the perfect My Fair Lady score. The lavishness of an Arthur Freed production ensured that his musicals were as much about look as they were sound. Gigi represents an astounding collaboration between cinematographer Joseph Ruttenberg, production designer Cecil Beaton and director Vincente Minnelli to reproduce the quality of fin-de-siecle painting, especially that of Auguste Renoir. The deliberate use of unfocused backgrounds in the opening scene is one of the best ever recreations of the impressionist style on screen. Minnelli (himself a keen painter) has a fine handling of perspective. Take the scene where Leslie Caron and Louis Jourdan are shelling peas. There is a chair in the foreground on the left-hand side, while on the right there is an open doorway into the kitchen. This contrast between closeness on one side and distance on the other not only adds real definition to the space, it allows the eye to be easily drawn from one end of the frame to the other, keeping Hermione Gingold highlighted even though she is in the background without having to resort to lots of obtrusive cutting. This is just one example, but it's a trick Minnelli pulls in almost every shot. The production is extremely lucky to have three genuine French stars for its principle parts, especially ones who were familiar enough with Hollywood to give an acceptable impression of Frenchness. Leslie Caron does a very credible job of playing a young girl on the verge of womanhood (she was in reality twenty-six) in a comically playful turn. Louis Jourdan is a little bland but by all means likable, and besides it suits him to look a little flat to all the better show off co-stars Caron and Chevalier. Ah oui, monsieur Chevalier, a man who is to an authentic portrayal of France what a crate of absinthe is to a light soiree. But for all his over-the-topness, he is great fun, slipping on the character of the ageing Lothario like an old glove. And those Lerner and Loewe songs like "I Remember It Well", where normal speech dovetails into singing, suit him very well. But while Gigi contains much to delight, as a whole it is lacking something. There just doesn't seem to be the heart or substance to the telling of the story that other Oscar-winning musicals have. Loewe in particular was reportedly reluctant to work in cinema, and both he and Lerner were overruled on a few decisions such as casting and inclusion of certain songs, so perhaps this explains the below-par score. Unsurprisingly it was a flop when adapted for the stage fifteen years later. Such is the care that has gone into those wonderful images, Gigi is far more a treat for the eyes than the ears, a coup were this purely a purely visual medium, but it falls some way short of being a superlative musical.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unintentionally creepy, with only one standout song
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Conrad
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A musical with only two memorable songs ("Thank Heaven for Little Girls" and "It's a Bore"), only one of which is good ("It's a Bore"), is not likely to be a good musical. Indeed, this is one of the most boring and poorly-acted in the history of the genre. The story ostensibly takes place in France, but it seems to unfold mainly in bland, claustrophobic drawing rooms. The title character's naive, youthful waifishness makes the relationship aspect of the film feel vaguely inappropriate, and this is only underscored by the aforementioned song about little girls, which is sung by a quintessentially creepy old man. This is a contender for worst Best Picture winner.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I Remembered It Wrong....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mark.waltz
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I first saw "Gigi" as a teenager, I was bewitched by its lavish costumes, sumptuous sets and delightful score, but in repeat viewings of it, I had to rank it as an overrated disappointment. Now some 25 years later, I watched it again, and while I don't consider it a perfect film (one worthy of a Best Picture Oscar), I do see it in a different light and appreciated it a bit more, taking my rating up from a 5 to an 8, **1/2 to ***1/2 on the Maltin scale. The days of living like Paris in the early 1900's are long gone, but it is certainly nice to re-visit them and the sweet duet between the aging Maurice Chevalier and Hermoine Gingold, the two scene-stealers of this film. Chevalier isn't the leading man he once was; In fact, Louis Jourdan, playing a part that Chevalier might have portrayed at Paramount during the early 1930's, doesn't seem quite up to the assignment, even if he is handsome, charming and well to do. Leslie Caron, however, does win in the title role, replacing Audrey Hepburn (from the stage productions) and being totally likable, especially when she sings "I Don't Understand the Parisians". Watching her grow from somewhat innocent teen to sophisticated young lady isn't quite like Hepburn going from guttersnipe to sophisticate in "My Fair Lady", even if the stories have a lot in common. The musical score has some bright moments, but some of the songs aren't as memorable as Lerner and Lowe's stage songs. The title song, in particular, suffers from some weak lyrics, and that defuses the dramatic impact of what it is trying to do. But when Chevalier and Gingold get together to reminisce in "I Remember It Well" and Gingold dances around with Jordan and Caron to "The Night They Invented Champagne", magic is made. Chevalier has a sly wink as the aging Honore, and in his relatively few scenes is the glue which holds the movie together. In smaller roles, Eva Gabor (as a two-timing lover of Jordan's) and Isabel Jeans (as the courtesan sister of Gingold) offer sophisticated bitchery. Gingold, a magic performer in everything she does, could be funny just looking around, and you wonder if her much later Broadway character of Madame Armfeldt in "A Little Night Music" could be a distant cousin of the family's. Superbly put together by the master of art in MGM musicals (Vincent Minnelli), "Gigi" can be appreciated more in repeat viewings as you get older, but some slow dramatic spots really cause it to drag a bit. That is minor, however, as this French creme pastry is lovely to look at, even though it may not entirely fill you up.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the most beautifully presented Musicals of all time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Koundinya
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The first time i watched the movie, i felt it was a "bore". The movie hardly has any running time of the character Gigi. The characters were melodramatic and their language was a butchered version of English. I never found the most vital element of Humor missing in the movie and was totally let down after having watched musicals like Singin' in the Rain and Wizard of Oz. Well, it was quite a long time back. I must agree i matured as a person who understands movie and appreciates it and not merely judge a movie based on its efficacy in entertaining. The movie is undoubtedly an entertainer. As the movie progressed, i started to understand the uniqueness of the movie and was enthralled by the songs and art setting. The movie is set in Paris at the turn of the century and the lifestyle, sartorial, marital and tonsorial preferences of the inhabitants is discreetly presented. The songs are brilliantly written and set to euphonious background music and when i paid heed to the lyrics, i realized what i greatly missed the first time i watched it- Humor. The movie also brings forth a message that no matter how rich and famous a man is, his heart remains vacant for a woman who remains herself and not be camouflaged with book-learned principles on satisfying a man.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    6.9?!?!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Gigi" won more Oscars than almost any other film in history. Yet, very oddly, it currently has an IMDb score of only 6.9! This makes no sense--especially since the film is magnificent throughout. The film is based on the story by Colette. It's about a sweet young lady, Gigi, and her family's insane intention of turning her into a very high-priced mistress to the rich and famous. However, because Gigi is so sweet, she just can't allow herself to have such a life and she insists on more--which causes problems with the man she loves (Louis Jourdan). While the plot is very simple (as it often is with musicals), the film works magnificently for several reasons. Most importantly, the Lerner and Lowe songs are among the best of any musical and are very memorable. In addition, the acting is so nice--and Leslie Caron is radiant and at her very best. Additionally, the film is just gorgeous--and replicates the grandeur of Paris circa 1900. Why this film has such a current mediocre score is beyond me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Curiously, no dancing...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dave from Ottawa
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Big Hollywood Musical genre in the 1950s was paved with ever more elaborate dance production numbers due to the popularity of stars like Gene Kelly, Fred Astaire and Cyd Charisse and yet rather curiously the ballet-trained Leslie Caron does not dance in this one and neither does anybody else. Still, 19th century Paris (the parks, the boulevards, Maxim's, the Follies etc.) is lavishly re-created, the costume designs are marvelous and the Lerner and Lowe songs are very good, if somewhat static in their presentation. The story is almost lighter than air, something about Caron reluctantly being groomed as a chic courtesan, but there is only enough to plot the keep things moving ahead as the camera tracks through or peeks into one gorgeously designed Parisian backdrop after another. The picture remains an old fashioned charmer thanks to million pretty things to look at and winning performances by Caron and especially Maurice Chevalier as an older rogue tutoring younger Louis Jourdan.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    At least I got 15 min sleep near the end
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    frankf-10
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I had seen this before years ago, but only could remember that it didn't impress me much. My wife selected the DVD via Netflix and 20 minutes into the film, all I could say to her was, "When is this movie going to start?" Slow moving hardly describes it. And Gaston repeating endlessly how boring things were for him hardly seems a way to entertain. I have never been much of a Maurice Chevalier fan and seeing him, as others have noted, oogling young girls in this flick is definitely weird now. Reading through reviews here, I was reminded how many Academy Awards it won - yikes! The Academy BS I can almost understand, but why IMDb reviewers found this leaden clunker so terrific is beyond me. Thank gawd I did get some shuteye toward the end.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Colourful character study which does remarkably well with two people crashing head first into a newfound state of thinking in regards to a chauvinistic lifestyle.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    johnnyboyz (j_l_h_m@yahoo.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gigi is a film about a young female protagonist asked to fall in with a highly specific male crowd; a crowd of whom carry with them the idea that something called "gender patriotism" consists of the wrecking of a woman's life, if she should ever leave you, by using your deep pockets of filthy wealth to buy off the man for whom she left you and convince him to leave town so that she is thus rendered totally heartbroken. If they suffer, why should't she? The men within this clique celebrate such an ideology, laughing and joking with one another; even taking time to indulge in speaking of the living by such rules with their barber, whom appears equally as enthused by such behaviour. On one occasion, it even led to the attempted suicide of one of those women  ah, well. But the film is not as it sounds, and will go on to cover this young female protagonist as well as her consequent frustrations out of trying to reject, or steer clear of, such an ill-gotten series of men and their livelihoods; the film eventually forming a piece about character we pray can find some sort of common-ground amidst what they exist - the film eventually an exuberant; careful piece treading along a fine line of bourgeoises indulgence and materialistic exploitation that comes together and actually works. The film unfolds in Paris; the year-clock in the French capital registering 1900. Leslie Caron plays the titular Gigi and that young protagonist slowly but surely being taught and groomed into falling in with a man to whom she may be able to act politely; overtly eloquently and essentially become the drone-wife that speaks when spoken to and laughs at her husband and his rich friend's anecdotes on prompt  after having brought out the tea for them, of course. But Gigi has an edge to her; a certain 'bite' and she is a faster and looser girl to that of what her contemporaries would like. In spite of being born into a fairly rich family, Gigi wishes not to head down a route of snobbery and such; instead, draws on inspiration from her mother - someone whom wanted more than what was offered, although someone, as her grandmother points out, whom chased a dream and failed to amount to what it was she desired when menial work at an opera house was the end product. In spite of this warning, as well as her grandmother's dismissive or hopeful tone that she will fail, we find it easy to get behind her. The man with whom she will come to interact a great deal more throughout is Louis Jourdan's Gaston Lachaille, the nephew of an elderly man named Honor&eacute; (Chevalier), whose attitudes towards women both now and throughout his life have been false and somewhat hate-filled although distilled through a filter of deft tones and extravagance. When we begin with him, he speaks to us on how he classifies his life profession as "lover" and we are drawn into a romanticised tone complimenting the sort of lifestyle in which a man like Honor&eacute; may waltz down a public street harbouring the opinions he has on the opposite sex. If we react as strongly as we ought to, our alignment with Gigi slips even easier into happening as she herself attempts to reject a kind of coercement director Vincente Minnelli attempts to relate onto that of the audience during the opening beats. Like Gigi, Gaston faces a seeping influence agonisingly trickling down from his peers and relations in regards to lifestyle choices and attitudes towards the other gender. Unlike most of his ilk, Gaston is fed up with the predominant items available and desires a change from socialite holidays to nations such as Italy and Spain, as well as the finer things on offer in Paris in the form of wines and such; something established through one of the film's many delightful musical numbers and a reoccurring quote throughout of "it's a bore" confirming this. Life for Gigi has reached a point in which honing skills in acting the socialite-come-snob for interactions should be the norm; the girl ambitious, and rather well off before this transitional phase, but her statements reiterating that she "doesn't understand Parisians" and that "there must be more to life than this" firmly establish her alienation to not only where she is, but the sorts of people with which she bonds. Primarily, these two characters coming together after seeking immense change from the patriarchal norm drives the film; Gaston's fondness for Gigi not equalled by her still prejudiced thinking when she deems him just as bad as anyone else in this messy cesspit of socialisation. One of the subtler moments of Jourdan's performance, going on neatly to project how he feels on what surrounds him, lies in the scene during which he loiters with his fellow men in that fatuous circle of elitism; a champagne toast to what they believe is carried out with a profound sense of glee evident on the faces of most of those present, but a wry peek at Gaston's facial expression amidst the extravagance and so-forth as everyone takes a sip reveals someone in deeper thought about this way of life than any of the others. In a film rich in colour; set decoration and faux-romanticism, best surmised when that wily rouge Honor&eacute; keeps getting his recollections shot down as he recalls decades-ago interludes with women now of his age, the film is deathly efficient in targeting people wanting out and away or something else anew. Many of the musical numbers work well, with one in which Gaston struggles with the coming to terms on how he feels for Gigi particularly standing out in memory, and the film generally pulls us in with its overlying juxtaposition of mise-en-scene with interior thematics; a deconstructing and retelling of stories of those within consummately seeing it home.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Enjoyable, but a wasted opportunity...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BlueEyes72
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gigi (Leslie Caron) is a young girl living in Paris in 1900, and being raised by her grandmother and great aunt to be a courtesan. Gaston (Louis Jourdan) is a rich Parisian playboy, who has become bored of his superficial lifestyle. He and Gigi have a platonic friendship, but as she becomes more sophisticated and grown up, the dynamic of their relationship starts to change This film, based on the novel by French author Colette, was not the last musical released by the MGM studios, but it was the last musical made by the Arthur Freed Unit at MGM (this unit was responsible for many of the classic musicals of the day, including Easter Parade, An American in Paris, and of course, Singin' In The Rain). The unit's swansong did very well, being nominated for nine Oscar awards, and winning all of them, breaking the then record of eight Oscars, held by Gone With The Wind. I thought the film was good, but not great. Some parts of it definitely worked  Leslie Caron was a delight as Gigi. I was not convinced by her performance in An American In Paris (although I l0ve An American In Paris and never get bored of watching it), but here she was great, and actually rather adorable. Audrey Hepburn was originally picked to play the part (having played Gigi on stage before she was famous), but due to other filming commitments, she was not available. Audrey is one of my favourite actresses, and I think she would have been perfect in the role, but Leslie Caron really worked well. Louis Jourdan was also great as the cynical and bored Gaston  making what could have been rather a dislikeable character into someone who the viewer liked a lot. Hermione Gingold and Isabel Jeans provided good support as Gigi's grandmother and great aunt. There were some lovely songs, in particular the title number sung by Louis Jourdan as he wanders throughout Paris, realising that his feelings for Gigi are changing; and the incredibly catchy The Night They Invented Champagne which I couldn't get out of my head after watching the film. Paris itself looks fabulous  most of the film was shot on location there, and it really is a lovely setting, very colourful and pretty. There were some parts that I didn't like  Maurice Chevalier's character Honore (the uncle of Gaston) seemed an unnecessary and distasteful character. This is no criticism of Chevalier's acting, which was fine, but the character was hard for me to warm to. In one scene Honore is highly delighted upon hearing that a former girlfriend of Gaston's has tried to kill herself after he ended her relationship. Honore toasts Gaston and says that he hopes this will be the first of many suicides. It may have been written flippantly, but this scene did not sit well with me. (Indeed the whole storyline of two women training their young relation to be a courtesan could be distasteful, although it was handled fairly well and with humour.) I was also slightly disappointed that there was no dancing in this film! I love to see fabulous dancing in musicals, and with Leslie Caron being an excellent ballet dancer, it feels like a missed opportunity not to show off her skills. Overall then, it's an enjoyable film, but ultimately a forgettable one. Worth watching for fans of musicals.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gee its grand to watch Gigi over and over, a film my sisters and I have adored from childhood
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Amy Adler
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In Paris, during the middle of the 19th century, handsome Gaston (Louis Jordan) is a sugar empire heir with a great deal of money. Like his father, Honore (Maurice Chevalier), he has shunned marriage in favor of having a succession of beautiful women. His present love, Lianne (Eva Gabor) is certainly pretty. But, as Gaston relates in song, he is truly bored with his lofty position in society, with women, and with parties. The only place he feels comfortable is at the home of an old friend (and former flame of Honore's), Mamita (Hermione Gingold). Odd it is, because the dear lady is rather poor and lives in an unfashionable neighborhood with her opera singing daughter AND her vivacious granddaughter, Gigi (Leslie Caron). Although she is in her middle teen years, Gigi is still treated by Gaston and her grandmama as a little girl and, in truth, she still acts as one, being very innocent and wide-eyed. Gaston loves eating Mamita's great cooking and playing cards with Gigi, away from the social scene. Unhappily, the sugar king soon finds that his "lady love" has been unfaithful and he makes a very publicized break with Lianne. To boost his spirits and pay off a card game debt to Gigi, Gaston, Mamita, and Gigi all go to the seashore for a vacation. They have a great time. But, Mamita's sister, also a former courtesan, wishes to change things when the trio returns to Paris. She sees that Gigi is really a young woman and, perhaps, they have a chance to offer her up as Gaston's next courtesan? She'd be well taken care of that's for certain. The only problem is that Gigi may not want to become the kind of woman who gets "passed around" but, rather, might want to be married and have children. What will the next season bring? Gee willikers is Gigi a pleasure to watch, as I and my sisters have done since our sixties' childhood. A musical, it nevertheless has enough non-musical action to satisfy those who don't particularly care for the genre. However, the songs are lovely and integral to the plot. Then, the acting is great, with Caron, Jordan, Chevalier, Ginggold and all of the others being near perfect in their respective roles. Also, the Paris setting, the terrific costumes, the lovely photography, and the superb direction by Vincente Minelli all contribute to the movie's enjoyment. It was awarded an Academy Award as best picture in 1958 and deservedly so. With that fact in mind, why not seek out Gigi ASAP?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "A gigantic, romantic clich&eacute;"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steffi_P
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There was a wave of stage-to-screen adaptations of hit musicals in the mid-1950s, translating the work of the two celebrated theatrical duos Rodgers and Hammerstein and Lerner and Loewe for a new audience. However this Arthur Freed production moves the other way, as Alan Jay Lerner and Frederick Loewe were hired by MGM to create a musical directly for the cinema, a sign perhaps that Broadway was beginning to take its rival more seriously. The result is in many ways an elaborately cinematic affair. Gigi takes advantage of the medium, having for example Maurice Chevalier break that pesky fourth wall and address the audience eye-to-eye, in reference to his screen musicals of the early 30s. We also have, in "She Is Not Thinking of Me", a song done in voice-over as an internal monologue  not, I believe, an original idea but certainly one that would be impossible (or at least very awkward) on the stage. As in their recent stage success My Fair Lady, Lerner and Loewe's songwriting is led by the lyrics, with a number like "It's a Bore" playing out like a musical conversation, with Loewe's melody skittering along to Lerner's vibrant wordplay. Their songs often serve to define character and relationships between characters. "It's a Bore" and "I Don't Understand the Parisians" are companion pieces as it were, and their similarities set up Gigi and Gaston as kindred spirits. Still, there are only a handful of really great numbers here ("The Night they Invented Champagne" being the standout), and one can't help getting the impression that Gigi is made up of cast-offs from the perfect My Fair Lady score. The lavishness of an Arthur Freed production ensured that his musicals were as much about look as they were sound. Gigi represents an astounding collaboration between cinematographer Joseph Ruttenberg, production designer Cecil Beaton and director Vincente Minnelli to reproduce the quality of fin-de-siecle painting, especially that of Auguste Renoir. The deliberate use of unfocused backgrounds in the opening scene is one of the best ever recreations of the impressionist style on screen. Minnelli (himself a keen painter) has a fine handling of perspective. Take the scene where Leslie Caron and Louis Jourdan are shelling peas. There is a chair in the foreground on the left-hand side, while on the right there is an open doorway into the kitchen. This contrast between closeness on one side and distance on the other not only adds real definition to the space, it allows the eye to be easily drawn from one end of the frame to the other, keeping Hermione Gingold highlighted even though she is in the background without having to resort to lots of obtrusive cutting. This is just one example, but it's a trick Minnelli pulls in almost every shot. The production is extremely lucky to have three genuine French stars for its principle parts, especially ones who were familiar enough with Hollywood to give an acceptable impression of Frenchness. Leslie Caron does a very credible job of playing a young girl on the verge of womanhood (she was in reality twenty-six) in a comically playful turn. Louis Jourdan is a little bland but by all means likable, and besides it suits him to look a little flat to all the better show off co-stars Caron and Chevalier. Ah oui, monsieur Chevalier, a man who is to an authentic portrayal of France what a crate of absinthe is to a light soiree. But for all his over-the-topness, he is great fun, slipping on the character of the ageing Lothario like an old glove. And those Lerner and Loewe songs like "I Remember It Well", where normal speech dovetails into singing, suit him very well. But while Gigi contains much to delight, as a whole it is lacking something. There just doesn't seem to be the heart or substance to the telling of the story that other Oscar-winning musicals have. Loewe in particular was reportedly reluctant to work in cinema, and both he and Lerner were overruled on a few decisions such as casting and inclusion of certain songs, so perhaps this explains the below-par score. Unsurprisingly it was a flop when adapted for the stage fifteen years later. Such is the care that has gone into those wonderful images, Gigi is far more a treat for the eyes than the ears, a coup were this purely a purely visual medium, but it falls some way short of being a superlative musical.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unintentionally creepy, with only one standout song
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Conrad
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A musical with only two memorable songs ("Thank Heaven for Little Girls" and "It's a Bore"), only one of which is good ("It's a Bore"), is not likely to be a good musical. Indeed, this is one of the most boring and poorly-acted in the history of the genre. The story ostensibly takes place in France, but it seems to unfold mainly in bland, claustrophobic drawing rooms. The title character's naive, youthful waifishness makes the relationship aspect of the film feel vaguely inappropriate, and this is only underscored by the aforementioned song about little girls, which is sung by a quintessentially creepy old man. This is a contender for worst Best Picture winner.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I Remembered It Wrong....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mark.waltz
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I first saw "Gigi" as a teenager, I was bewitched by its lavish costumes, sumptuous sets and delightful score, but in repeat viewings of it, I had to rank it as an overrated disappointment. Now some 25 years later, I watched it again, and while I don't consider it a perfect film (one worthy of a Best Picture Oscar), I do see it in a different light and appreciated it a bit more, taking my rating up from a 5 to an 8, **1/2 to ***1/2 on the Maltin scale. The days of living like Paris in the early 1900's are long gone, but it is certainly nice to re-visit them and the sweet duet between the aging Maurice Chevalier and Hermoine Gingold, the two scene-stealers of this film. Chevalier isn't the leading man he once was; In fact, Louis Jourdan, playing a part that Chevalier might have portrayed at Paramount during the early 1930's, doesn't seem quite up to the assignment, even if he is handsome, charming and well to do. Leslie Caron, however, does win in the title role, replacing Audrey Hepburn (from the stage productions) and being totally likable, especially when she sings "I Don't Understand the Parisians". Watching her grow from somewhat innocent teen to sophisticated young lady isn't quite like Hepburn going from guttersnipe to sophisticate in "My Fair Lady", even if the stories have a lot in common. The musical score has some bright moments, but some of the songs aren't as memorable as Lerner and Lowe's stage songs. The title song, in particular, suffers from some weak lyrics, and that defuses the dramatic impact of what it is trying to do. But when Chevalier and Gingold get together to reminisce in "I Remember It Well" and Gingold dances around with Jordan and Caron to "The Night They Invented Champagne", magic is made. Chevalier has a sly wink as the aging Honore, and in his relatively few scenes is the glue which holds the movie together. In smaller roles, Eva Gabor (as a two-timing lover of Jordan's) and Isabel Jeans (as the courtesan sister of Gingold) offer sophisticated bitchery. Gingold, a magic performer in everything she does, could be funny just looking around, and you wonder if her much later Broadway character of Madame Armfeldt in "A Little Night Music" could be a distant cousin of the family's. Superbly put together by the master of art in MGM musicals (Vincent Minnelli), "Gigi" can be appreciated more in repeat viewings as you get older, but some slow dramatic spots really cause it to drag a bit. That is minor, however, as this French creme pastry is lovely to look at, even though it may not entirely fill you up.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the most beautifully presented Musicals of all time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Koundinya
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The first time i watched the movie, i felt it was a "bore". The movie hardly has any running time of the character Gigi. The characters were melodramatic and their language was a butchered version of English. I never found the most vital element of Humor missing in the movie and was totally let down after having watched musicals like Singin' in the Rain and Wizard of Oz. Well, it was quite a long time back. I must agree i matured as a person who understands movie and appreciates it and not merely judge a movie based on its efficacy in entertaining. The movie is undoubtedly an entertainer. As the movie progressed, i started to understand the uniqueness of the movie and was enthralled by the songs and art setting. The movie is set in Paris at the turn of the century and the lifestyle, sartorial, marital and tonsorial preferences of the inhabitants is discreetly presented. The songs are brilliantly written and set to euphonious background music and when i paid heed to the lyrics, i realized what i greatly missed the first time i watched it- Humor. The movie also brings forth a message that no matter how rich and famous a man is, his heart remains vacant for a woman who remains herself and not be camouflaged with book-learned principles on satisfying a man.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    6.9?!?!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Gigi" won more Oscars than almost any other film in history. Yet, very oddly, it currently has an IMDb score of only 6.9! This makes no sense--especially since the film is magnificent throughout. The film is based on the story by Colette. It's about a sweet young lady, Gigi, and her family's insane intention of turning her into a very high-priced mistress to the rich and famous. However, because Gigi is so sweet, she just can't allow herself to have such a life and she insists on more--which causes problems with the man she loves (Louis Jourdan). While the plot is very simple (as it often is with musicals), the film works magnificently for several reasons. Most importantly, the Lerner and Lowe songs are among the best of any musical and are very memorable. In addition, the acting is so nice--and Leslie Caron is radiant and at her very best. Additionally, the film is just gorgeous--and replicates the grandeur of Paris circa 1900. Why this film has such a current mediocre score is beyond me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Curiously, no dancing...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dave from Ottawa
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Big Hollywood Musical genre in the 1950s was paved with ever more elaborate dance production numbers due to the popularity of stars like Gene Kelly, Fred Astaire and Cyd Charisse and yet rather curiously the ballet-trained Leslie Caron does not dance in this one and neither does anybody else. Still, 19th century Paris (the parks, the boulevards, Maxim's, the Follies etc.) is lavishly re-created, the costume designs are marvelous and the Lerner and Lowe songs are very good, if somewhat static in their presentation. The story is almost lighter than air, something about Caron reluctantly being groomed as a chic courtesan, but there is only enough to plot the keep things moving ahead as the camera tracks through or peeks into one gorgeously designed Parisian backdrop after another. The picture remains an old fashioned charmer thanks to million pretty things to look at and winning performances by Caron and especially Maurice Chevalier as an older rogue tutoring younger Louis Jourdan.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    At least I got 15 min sleep near the end
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    frankf-10
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I had seen this before years ago, but only could remember that it didn't impress me much. My wife selected the DVD via Netflix and 20 minutes into the film, all I could say to her was, "When is this movie going to start?" Slow moving hardly describes it. And Gaston repeating endlessly how boring things were for him hardly seems a way to entertain. I have never been much of a Maurice Chevalier fan and seeing him, as others have noted, oogling young girls in this flick is definitely weird now. Reading through reviews here, I was reminded how many Academy Awards it won - yikes! The Academy BS I can almost understand, but why IMDb reviewers found this leaden clunker so terrific is beyond me. Thank gawd I did get some shuteye toward the end.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Colourful character study which does remarkably well with two people crashing head first into a newfound state of thinking in regards to a chauvinistic lifestyle.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    johnnyboyz (j_l_h_m@yahoo.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gigi is a film about a young female protagonist asked to fall in with a highly specific male crowd; a crowd of whom carry with them the idea that something called "gender patriotism" consists of the wrecking of a woman's life, if she should ever leave you, by using your deep pockets of filthy wealth to buy off the man for whom she left you and convince him to leave town so that she is thus rendered totally heartbroken. If they suffer, why should't she? The men within this clique celebrate such an ideology, laughing and joking with one another; even taking time to indulge in speaking of the living by such rules with their barber, whom appears equally as enthused by such behaviour. On one occasion, it even led to the attempted suicide of one of those women  ah, well. But the film is not as it sounds, and will go on to cover this young female protagonist as well as her consequent frustrations out of trying to reject, or steer clear of, such an ill-gotten series of men and their livelihoods; the film eventually forming a piece about character we pray can find some sort of common-ground amidst what they exist - the film eventually an exuberant; careful piece treading along a fine line of bourgeoises indulgence and materialistic exploitation that comes together and actually works. The film unfolds in Paris; the year-clock in the French capital registering 1900. Leslie Caron plays the titular Gigi and that young protagonist slowly but surely being taught and groomed into falling in with a man to whom she may be able to act politely; overtly eloquently and essentially become the drone-wife that speaks when spoken to and laughs at her husband and his rich friend's anecdotes on prompt  after having brought out the tea for them, of course. But Gigi has an edge to her; a certain 'bite' and she is a faster and looser girl to that of what her contemporaries would like. In spite of being born into a fairly rich family, Gigi wishes not to head down a route of snobbery and such; instead, draws on inspiration from her mother - someone whom wanted more than what was offered, although someone, as her grandmother points out, whom chased a dream and failed to amount to what it was she desired when menial work at an opera house was the end product. In spite of this warning, as well as her grandmother's dismissive or hopeful tone that she will fail, we find it easy to get behind her. The man with whom she will come to interact a great deal more throughout is Louis Jourdan's Gaston Lachaille, the nephew of an elderly man named Honor&eacute; (Chevalier), whose attitudes towards women both now and throughout his life have been false and somewhat hate-filled although distilled through a filter of deft tones and extravagance. When we begin with him, he speaks to us on how he classifies his life profession as "lover" and we are drawn into a romanticised tone complimenting the sort of lifestyle in which a man like Honor&eacute; may waltz down a public street harbouring the opinions he has on the opposite sex. If we react as strongly as we ought to, our alignment with Gigi slips even easier into happening as she herself attempts to reject a kind of coercement director Vincente Minnelli attempts to relate onto that of the audience during the opening beats. Like Gigi, Gaston faces a seeping influence agonisingly trickling down from his peers and relations in regards to lifestyle choices and attitudes towards the other gender. Unlike most of his ilk, Gaston is fed up with the predominant items available and desires a change from socialite holidays to nations such as Italy and Spain, as well as the finer things on offer in Paris in the form of wines and such; something established through one of the film's many delightful musical numbers and a reoccurring quote throughout of "it's a bore" confirming this. Life for Gigi has reached a point in which honing skills in acting the socialite-come-snob for interactions should be the norm; the girl ambitious, and rather well off before this transitional phase, but her statements reiterating that she "doesn't understand Parisians" and that "there must be more to life than this" firmly establish her alienation to not only where she is, but the sorts of people with which she bonds. Primarily, these two characters coming together after seeking immense change from the patriarchal norm drives the film; Gaston's fondness for Gigi not equalled by her still prejudiced thinking when she deems him just as bad as anyone else in this messy cesspit of socialisation. One of the subtler moments of Jourdan's performance, going on neatly to project how he feels on what surrounds him, lies in the scene during which he loiters with his fellow men in that fatuous circle of elitism; a champagne toast to what they believe is carried out with a profound sense of glee evident on the faces of most of those present, but a wry peek at Gaston's facial expression amidst the extravagance and so-forth as everyone takes a sip reveals someone in deeper thought about this way of life than any of the others. In a film rich in colour; set decoration and faux-romanticism, best surmised when that wily rouge Honor&eacute; keeps getting his recollections shot down as he recalls decades-ago interludes with women now of his age, the film is deathly efficient in targeting people wanting out and away or something else anew. Many of the musical numbers work well, with one in which Gaston struggles with the coming to terms on how he feels for Gigi particularly standing out in memory, and the film generally pulls us in with its overlying juxtaposition of mise-en-scene with interior thematics; a deconstructing and retelling of stories of those within consummately seeing it home.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Enjoyable, but a wasted opportunity...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BlueEyes72
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gigi (Leslie Caron) is a young girl living in Paris in 1900, and being raised by her grandmother and great aunt to be a courtesan. Gaston (Louis Jourdan) is a rich Parisian playboy, who has become bored of his superficial lifestyle. He and Gigi have a platonic friendship, but as she becomes more sophisticated and grown up, the dynamic of their relationship starts to change This film, based on the novel by French author Colette, was not the last musical released by the MGM studios, but it was the last musical made by the Arthur Freed Unit at MGM (this unit was responsible for many of the classic musicals of the day, including Easter Parade, An American in Paris, and of course, Singin' In The Rain). The unit's swansong did very well, being nominated for nine Oscar awards, and winning all of them, breaking the then record of eight Oscars, held by Gone With The Wind. I thought the film was good, but not great. Some parts of it definitely worked  Leslie Caron was a delight as Gigi. I was not convinced by her performance in An American In Paris (although I l0ve An American In Paris and never get bored of watching it), but here she was great, and actually rather adorable. Audrey Hepburn was originally picked to play the part (having played Gigi on stage before she was famous), but due to other filming commitments, she was not available. Audrey is one of my favourite actresses, and I think she would have been perfect in the role, but Leslie Caron really worked well. Louis Jourdan was also great as the cynical and bored Gaston  making what could have been rather a dislikeable character into someone who the viewer liked a lot. Hermione Gingold and Isabel Jeans provided good support as Gigi's grandmother and great aunt. There were some lovely songs, in particular the title number sung by Louis Jourdan as he wanders throughout Paris, realising that his feelings for Gigi are changing; and the incredibly catchy The Night They Invented Champagne which I couldn't get out of my head after watching the film. Paris itself looks fabulous  most of the film was shot on location there, and it really is a lovely setting, very colourful and pretty. There were some parts that I didn't like  Maurice Chevalier's character Honore (the uncle of Gaston) seemed an unnecessary and distasteful character. This is no criticism of Chevalier's acting, which was fine, but the character was hard for me to warm to. In one scene Honore is highly delighted upon hearing that a former girlfriend of Gaston's has tried to kill herself after he ended her relationship. Honore toasts Gaston and says that he hopes this will be the first of many suicides. It may have been written flippantly, but this scene did not sit well with me. (Indeed the whole storyline of two women training their young relation to be a courtesan could be distasteful, although it was handled fairly well and with humour.) I was also slightly disappointed that there was no dancing in this film! I love to see fabulous dancing in musicals, and with Leslie Caron being an excellent ballet dancer, it feels like a missed opportunity not to show off her skills. Overall then, it's an enjoyable film, but ultimately a forgettable one. Worth watching for fans of musicals.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gee its grand to watch Gigi over and over, a film my sisters and I have adored from childhood
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Amy Adler
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In Paris, during the middle of the 19th century, handsome Gaston (Louis Jordan) is a sugar empire heir with a great deal of money. Like his father, Honore (Maurice Chevalier), he has shunned marriage in favor of having a succession of beautiful women. His present love, Lianne (Eva Gabor) is certainly pretty. But, as Gaston relates in song, he is truly bored with his lofty position in society, with women, and with parties. The only place he feels comfortable is at the home of an old friend (and former flame of Honore's), Mamita (Hermione Gingold). Odd it is, because the dear lady is rather poor and lives in an unfashionable neighborhood with her opera singing daughter AND her vivacious granddaughter, Gigi (Leslie Caron). Although she is in her middle teen years, Gigi is still treated by Gaston and her grandmama as a little girl and, in truth, she still acts as one, being very innocent and wide-eyed. Gaston loves eating Mamita's great cooking and playing cards with Gigi, away from the social scene. Unhappily, the sugar king soon finds that his "lady love" has been unfaithful and he makes a very publicized break with Lianne. To boost his spirits and pay off a card game debt to Gigi, Gaston, Mamita, and Gigi all go to the seashore for a vacation. They have a great time. But, Mamita's sister, also a former courtesan, wishes to change things when the trio returns to Paris. She sees that Gigi is really a young woman and, perhaps, they have a chance to offer her up as Gaston's next courtesan? She'd be well taken care of that's for certain. The only problem is that Gigi may not want to become the kind of woman who gets "passed around" but, rather, might want to be married and have children. What will the next season bring? Gee willikers is Gigi a pleasure to watch, as I and my sisters have done since our sixties' childhood. A musical, it nevertheless has enough non-musical action to satisfy those who don't particularly care for the genre. However, the songs are lovely and integral to the plot. Then, the acting is great, with Caron, Jordan, Chevalier, Ginggold and all of the others being near perfect in their respective roles. Also, the Paris setting, the terrific costumes, the lovely photography, and the superb direction by Vincente Minelli all contribute to the movie's enjoyment. It was awarded an Academy Award as best picture in 1958 and deservedly so. With that fact in mind, why not seek out Gigi ASAP?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "A gigantic, romantic clich&eacute;"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steffi_P
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There was a wave of stage-to-screen adaptations of hit musicals in the mid-1950s, translating the work of the two celebrated theatrical duos Rodgers and Hammerstein and Lerner and Loewe for a new audience. However this Arthur Freed production moves the other way, as Alan Jay Lerner and Frederick Loewe were hired by MGM to create a musical directly for the cinema, a sign perhaps that Broadway was beginning to take its rival more seriously. The result is in many ways an elaborately cinematic affair. Gigi takes advantage of the medium, having for example Maurice Chevalier break that pesky fourth wall and address the audience eye-to-eye, in reference to his screen musicals of the early 30s. We also have, in "She Is Not Thinking of Me", a song done in voice-over as an internal monologue  not, I believe, an original idea but certainly one that would be impossible (or at least very awkward) on the stage. As in their recent stage success My Fair Lady, Lerner and Loewe's songwriting is led by the lyrics, with a number like "It's a Bore" playing out like a musical conversation, with Loewe's melody skittering along to Lerner's vibrant wordplay. Their songs often serve to define character and relationships between characters. "It's a Bore" and "I Don't Understand the Parisians" are companion pieces as it were, and their similarities set up Gigi and Gaston as kindred spirits. Still, there are only a handful of really great numbers here ("The Night they Invented Champagne" being the standout), and one can't help getting the impression that Gigi is made up of cast-offs from the perfect My Fair Lady score. The lavishness of an Arthur Freed production ensured that his musicals were as much about look as they were sound. Gigi represents an astounding collaboration between cinematographer Joseph Ruttenberg, production designer Cecil Beaton and director Vincente Minnelli to reproduce the quality of fin-de-siecle painting, especially that of Auguste Renoir. The deliberate use of unfocused backgrounds in the opening scene is one of the best ever recreations of the impressionist style on screen. Minnelli (himself a keen painter) has a fine handling of perspective. Take the scene where Leslie Caron and Louis Jourdan are shelling peas. There is a chair in the foreground on the left-hand side, while on the right there is an open doorway into the kitchen. This contrast between closeness on one side and distance on the other not only adds real definition to the space, it allows the eye to be easily drawn from one end of the frame to the other, keeping Hermione Gingold highlighted even though she is in the background without having to resort to lots of obtrusive cutting. This is just one example, but it's a trick Minnelli pulls in almost every shot. The production is extremely lucky to have three genuine French stars for its principle parts, especially ones who were familiar enough with Hollywood to give an acceptable impression of Frenchness. Leslie Caron does a very credible job of playing a young girl on the verge of womanhood (she was in reality twenty-six) in a comically playful turn. Louis Jourdan is a little bland but by all means likable, and besides it suits him to look a little flat to all the better show off co-stars Caron and Chevalier. Ah oui, monsieur Chevalier, a man who is to an authentic portrayal of France what a crate of absinthe is to a light soiree. But for all his over-the-topness, he is great fun, slipping on the character of the ageing Lothario like an old glove. And those Lerner and Loewe songs like "I Remember It Well", where normal speech dovetails into singing, suit him very well. But while Gigi contains much to delight, as a whole it is lacking something. There just doesn't seem to be the heart or substance to the telling of the story that other Oscar-winning musicals have. Loewe in particular was reportedly reluctant to work in cinema, and both he and Lerner were overruled on a few decisions such as casting and inclusion of certain songs, so perhaps this explains the below-par score. Unsurprisingly it was a flop when adapted for the stage fifteen years later. Such is the care that has gone into those wonderful images, Gigi is far more a treat for the eyes than the ears, a coup were this purely a purely visual medium, but it falls some way short of being a superlative musical.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unintentionally creepy, with only one standout song
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Conrad
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A musical with only two memorable songs ("Thank Heaven for Little Girls" and "It's a Bore"), only one of which is good ("It's a Bore"), is not likely to be a good musical. Indeed, this is one of the most boring and poorly-acted in the history of the genre. The story ostensibly takes place in France, but it seems to unfold mainly in bland, claustrophobic drawing rooms. The title character's naive, youthful waifishness makes the relationship aspect of the film feel vaguely inappropriate, and this is only underscored by the aforementioned song about little girls, which is sung by a quintessentially creepy old man. This is a contender for worst Best Picture winner.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I Remembered It Wrong....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mark.waltz
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I first saw "Gigi" as a teenager, I was bewitched by its lavish costumes, sumptuous sets and delightful score, but in repeat viewings of it, I had to rank it as an overrated disappointment. Now some 25 years later, I watched it again, and while I don't consider it a perfect film (one worthy of a Best Picture Oscar), I do see it in a different light and appreciated it a bit more, taking my rating up from a 5 to an 8, **1/2 to ***1/2 on the Maltin scale. The days of living like Paris in the early 1900's are long gone, but it is certainly nice to re-visit them and the sweet duet between the aging Maurice Chevalier and Hermoine Gingold, the two scene-stealers of this film. Chevalier isn't the leading man he once was; In fact, Louis Jourdan, playing a part that Chevalier might have portrayed at Paramount during the early 1930's, doesn't seem quite up to the assignment, even if he is handsome, charming and well to do. Leslie Caron, however, does win in the title role, replacing Audrey Hepburn (from the stage productions) and being totally likable, especially when she sings "I Don't Understand the Parisians". Watching her grow from somewhat innocent teen to sophisticated young lady isn't quite like Hepburn going from guttersnipe to sophisticate in "My Fair Lady", even if the stories have a lot in common. The musical score has some bright moments, but some of the songs aren't as memorable as Lerner and Lowe's stage songs. The title song, in particular, suffers from some weak lyrics, and that defuses the dramatic impact of what it is trying to do. But when Chevalier and Gingold get together to reminisce in "I Remember It Well" and Gingold dances around with Jordan and Caron to "The Night They Invented Champagne", magic is made. Chevalier has a sly wink as the aging Honore, and in his relatively few scenes is the glue which holds the movie together. In smaller roles, Eva Gabor (as a two-timing lover of Jordan's) and Isabel Jeans (as the courtesan sister of Gingold) offer sophisticated bitchery. Gingold, a magic performer in everything she does, could be funny just looking around, and you wonder if her much later Broadway character of Madame Armfeldt in "A Little Night Music" could be a distant cousin of the family's. Superbly put together by the master of art in MGM musicals (Vincent Minnelli), "Gigi" can be appreciated more in repeat viewings as you get older, but some slow dramatic spots really cause it to drag a bit. That is minor, however, as this French creme pastry is lovely to look at, even though it may not entirely fill you up.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the most beautifully presented Musicals of all time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Koundinya
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The first time i watched the movie, i felt it was a "bore". The movie hardly has any running time of the character Gigi. The characters were melodramatic and their language was a butchered version of English. I never found the most vital element of Humor missing in the movie and was totally let down after having watched musicals like Singin' in the Rain and Wizard of Oz. Well, it was quite a long time back. I must agree i matured as a person who understands movie and appreciates it and not merely judge a movie based on its efficacy in entertaining. The movie is undoubtedly an entertainer. As the movie progressed, i started to understand the uniqueness of the movie and was enthralled by the songs and art setting. The movie is set in Paris at the turn of the century and the lifestyle, sartorial, marital and tonsorial preferences of the inhabitants is discreetly presented. The songs are brilliantly written and set to euphonious background music and when i paid heed to the lyrics, i realized what i greatly missed the first time i watched it- Humor. The movie also brings forth a message that no matter how rich and famous a man is, his heart remains vacant for a woman who remains herself and not be camouflaged with book-learned principles on satisfying a man.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    6.9?!?!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Gigi" won more Oscars than almost any other film in history. Yet, very oddly, it currently has an IMDb score of only 6.9! This makes no sense--especially since the film is magnificent throughout. The film is based on the story by Colette. It's about a sweet young lady, Gigi, and her family's insane intention of turning her into a very high-priced mistress to the rich and famous. However, because Gigi is so sweet, she just can't allow herself to have such a life and she insists on more--which causes problems with the man she loves (Louis Jourdan). While the plot is very simple (as it often is with musicals), the film works magnificently for several reasons. Most importantly, the Lerner and Lowe songs are among the best of any musical and are very memorable. In addition, the acting is so nice--and Leslie Caron is radiant and at her very best. Additionally, the film is just gorgeous--and replicates the grandeur of Paris circa 1900. Why this film has such a current mediocre score is beyond me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Curiously, no dancing...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dave from Ottawa
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Big Hollywood Musical genre in the 1950s was paved with ever more elaborate dance production numbers due to the popularity of stars like Gene Kelly, Fred Astaire and Cyd Charisse and yet rather curiously the ballet-trained Leslie Caron does not dance in this one and neither does anybody else. Still, 19th century Paris (the parks, the boulevards, Maxim's, the Follies etc.) is lavishly re-created, the costume designs are marvelous and the Lerner and Lowe songs are very good, if somewhat static in their presentation. The story is almost lighter than air, something about Caron reluctantly being groomed as a chic courtesan, but there is only enough to plot the keep things moving ahead as the camera tracks through or peeks into one gorgeously designed Parisian backdrop after another. The picture remains an old fashioned charmer thanks to million pretty things to look at and winning performances by Caron and especially Maurice Chevalier as an older rogue tutoring younger Louis Jourdan.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    At least I got 15 min sleep near the end
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    frankf-10
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I had seen this before years ago, but only could remember that it didn't impress me much. My wife selected the DVD via Netflix and 20 minutes into the film, all I could say to her was, "When is this movie going to start?" Slow moving hardly describes it. And Gaston repeating endlessly how boring things were for him hardly seems a way to entertain. I have never been much of a Maurice Chevalier fan and seeing him, as others have noted, oogling young girls in this flick is definitely weird now. Reading through reviews here, I was reminded how many Academy Awards it won - yikes! The Academy BS I can almost understand, but why IMDb reviewers found this leaden clunker so terrific is beyond me. Thank gawd I did get some shuteye toward the end.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Colourful character study which does remarkably well with two people crashing head first into a newfound state of thinking in regards to a chauvinistic lifestyle.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    johnnyboyz (j_l_h_m@yahoo.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gigi is a film about a young female protagonist asked to fall in with a highly specific male crowd; a crowd of whom carry with them the idea that something called "gender patriotism" consists of the wrecking of a woman's life, if she should ever leave you, by using your deep pockets of filthy wealth to buy off the man for whom she left you and convince him to leave town so that she is thus rendered totally heartbroken. If they suffer, why should't she? The men within this clique celebrate such an ideology, laughing and joking with one another; even taking time to indulge in speaking of the living by such rules with their barber, whom appears equally as enthused by such behaviour. On one occasion, it even led to the attempted suicide of one of those women  ah, well. But the film is not as it sounds, and will go on to cover this young female protagonist as well as her consequent frustrations out of trying to reject, or steer clear of, such an ill-gotten series of men and their livelihoods; the film eventually forming a piece about character we pray can find some sort of common-ground amidst what they exist - the film eventually an exuberant; careful piece treading along a fine line of bourgeoises indulgence and materialistic exploitation that comes together and actually works. The film unfolds in Paris; the year-clock in the French capital registering 1900. Leslie Caron plays the titular Gigi and that young protagonist slowly but surely being taught and groomed into falling in with a man to whom she may be able to act politely; overtly eloquently and essentially become the drone-wife that speaks when spoken to and laughs at her husband and his rich friend's anecdotes on prompt  after having brought out the tea for them, of course. But Gigi has an edge to her; a certain 'bite' and she is a faster and looser girl to that of what her contemporaries would like. In spite of being born into a fairly rich family, Gigi wishes not to head down a route of snobbery and such; instead, draws on inspiration from her mother - someone whom wanted more than what was offered, although someone, as her grandmother points out, whom chased a dream and failed to amount to what it was she desired when menial work at an opera house was the end product. In spite of this warning, as well as her grandmother's dismissive or hopeful tone that she will fail, we find it easy to get behind her. The man with whom she will come to interact a great deal more throughout is Louis Jourdan's Gaston Lachaille, the nephew of an elderly man named Honor&eacute; (Chevalier), whose attitudes towards women both now and throughout his life have been false and somewhat hate-filled although distilled through a filter of deft tones and extravagance. When we begin with him, he speaks to us on how he classifies his life profession as "lover" and we are drawn into a romanticised tone complimenting the sort of lifestyle in which a man like Honor&eacute; may waltz down a public street harbouring the opinions he has on the opposite sex. If we react as strongly as we ought to, our alignment with Gigi slips even easier into happening as she herself attempts to reject a kind of coercement director Vincente Minnelli attempts to relate onto that of the audience during the opening beats. Like Gigi, Gaston faces a seeping influence agonisingly trickling down from his peers and relations in regards to lifestyle choices and attitudes towards the other gender. Unlike most of his ilk, Gaston is fed up with the predominant items available and desires a change from socialite holidays to nations such as Italy and Spain, as well as the finer things on offer in Paris in the form of wines and such; something established through one of the film's many delightful musical numbers and a reoccurring quote throughout of "it's a bore" confirming this. Life for Gigi has reached a point in which honing skills in acting the socialite-come-snob for interactions should be the norm; the girl ambitious, and rather well off before this transitional phase, but her statements reiterating that she "doesn't understand Parisians" and that "there must be more to life than this" firmly establish her alienation to not only where she is, but the sorts of people with which she bonds. Primarily, these two characters coming together after seeking immense change from the patriarchal norm drives the film; Gaston's fondness for Gigi not equalled by her still prejudiced thinking when she deems him just as bad as anyone else in this messy cesspit of socialisation. One of the subtler moments of Jourdan's performance, going on neatly to project how he feels on what surrounds him, lies in the scene during which he loiters with his fellow men in that fatuous circle of elitism; a champagne toast to what they believe is carried out with a profound sense of glee evident on the faces of most of those present, but a wry peek at Gaston's facial expression amidst the extravagance and so-forth as everyone takes a sip reveals someone in deeper thought about this way of life than any of the others. In a film rich in colour; set decoration and faux-romanticism, best surmised when that wily rouge Honor&eacute; keeps getting his recollections shot down as he recalls decades-ago interludes with women now of his age, the film is deathly efficient in targeting people wanting out and away or something else anew. Many of the musical numbers work well, with one in which Gaston struggles with the coming to terms on how he feels for Gigi particularly standing out in memory, and the film generally pulls us in with its overlying juxtaposition of mise-en-scene with interior thematics; a deconstructing and retelling of stories of those within consummately seeing it home.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Enjoyable, but a wasted opportunity...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BlueEyes72
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gigi (Leslie Caron) is a young girl living in Paris in 1900, and being raised by her grandmother and great aunt to be a courtesan. Gaston (Louis Jourdan) is a rich Parisian playboy, who has become bored of his superficial lifestyle. He and Gigi have a platonic friendship, but as she becomes more sophisticated and grown up, the dynamic of their relationship starts to change This film, based on the novel by French author Colette, was not the last musical released by the MGM studios, but it was the last musical made by the Arthur Freed Unit at MGM (this unit was responsible for many of the classic musicals of the day, including Easter Parade, An American in Paris, and of course, Singin' In The Rain). The unit's swansong did very well, being nominated for nine Oscar awards, and winning all of them, breaking the then record of eight Oscars, held by Gone With The Wind. I thought the film was good, but not great. Some parts of it definitely worked  Leslie Caron was a delight as Gigi. I was not convinced by her performance in An American In Paris (although I l0ve An American In Paris and never get bored of watching it), but here she was great, and actually rather adorable. Audrey Hepburn was originally picked to play the part (having played Gigi on stage before she was famous), but due to other filming commitments, she was not available. Audrey is one of my favourite actresses, and I think she would have been perfect in the role, but Leslie Caron really worked well. Louis Jourdan was also great as the cynical and bored Gaston  making what could have been rather a dislikeable character into someone who the viewer liked a lot. Hermione Gingold and Isabel Jeans provided good support as Gigi's grandmother and great aunt. There were some lovely songs, in particular the title number sung by Louis Jourdan as he wanders throughout Paris, realising that his feelings for Gigi are changing; and the incredibly catchy The Night They Invented Champagne which I couldn't get out of my head after watching the film. Paris itself looks fabulous  most of the film was shot on location there, and it really is a lovely setting, very colourful and pretty. There were some parts that I didn't like  Maurice Chevalier's character Honore (the uncle of Gaston) seemed an unnecessary and distasteful character. This is no criticism of Chevalier's acting, which was fine, but the character was hard for me to warm to. In one scene Honore is highly delighted upon hearing that a former girlfriend of Gaston's has tried to kill herself after he ended her relationship. Honore toasts Gaston and says that he hopes this will be the first of many suicides. It may have been written flippantly, but this scene did not sit well with me. (Indeed the whole storyline of two women training their young relation to be a courtesan could be distasteful, although it was handled fairly well and with humour.) I was also slightly disappointed that there was no dancing in this film! I love to see fabulous dancing in musicals, and with Leslie Caron being an excellent ballet dancer, it feels like a missed opportunity not to show off her skills. Overall then, it's an enjoyable film, but ultimately a forgettable one. Worth watching for fans of musicals.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gee its grand to watch Gigi over and over, a film my sisters and I have adored from childhood
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Amy Adler
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In Paris, during the middle of the 19th century, handsome Gaston (Louis Jordan) is a sugar empire heir with a great deal of money. Like his father, Honore (Maurice Chevalier), he has shunned marriage in favor of having a succession of beautiful women. His present love, Lianne (Eva Gabor) is certainly pretty. But, as Gaston relates in song, he is truly bored with his lofty position in society, with women, and with parties. The only place he feels comfortable is at the home of an old friend (and former flame of Honore's), Mamita (Hermione Gingold). Odd it is, because the dear lady is rather poor and lives in an unfashionable neighborhood with her opera singing daughter AND her vivacious granddaughter, Gigi (Leslie Caron). Although she is in her middle teen years, Gigi is still treated by Gaston and her grandmama as a little girl and, in truth, she still acts as one, being very innocent and wide-eyed. Gaston loves eating Mamita's great cooking and playing cards with Gigi, away from the social scene. Unhappily, the sugar king soon finds that his "lady love" has been unfaithful and he makes a very publicized break with Lianne. To boost his spirits and pay off a card game debt to Gigi, Gaston, Mamita, and Gigi all go to the seashore for a vacation. They have a great time. But, Mamita's sister, also a former courtesan, wishes to change things when the trio returns to Paris. She sees that Gigi is really a young woman and, perhaps, they have a chance to offer her up as Gaston's next courtesan? She'd be well taken care of that's for certain. The only problem is that Gigi may not want to become the kind of woman who gets "passed around" but, rather, might want to be married and have children. What will the next season bring? Gee willikers is Gigi a pleasure to watch, as I and my sisters have done since our sixties' childhood. A musical, it nevertheless has enough non-musical action to satisfy those who don't particularly care for the genre. However, the songs are lovely and integral to the plot. Then, the acting is great, with Caron, Jordan, Chevalier, Ginggold and all of the others being near perfect in their respective roles. Also, the Paris setting, the terrific costumes, the lovely photography, and the superb direction by Vincente Minelli all contribute to the movie's enjoyment. It was awarded an Academy Award as best picture in 1958 and deservedly so. With that fact in mind, why not seek out Gigi ASAP?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "A gigantic, romantic clich&eacute;"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steffi_P
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There was a wave of stage-to-screen adaptations of hit musicals in the mid-1950s, translating the work of the two celebrated theatrical duos Rodgers and Hammerstein and Lerner and Loewe for a new audience. However this Arthur Freed production moves the other way, as Alan Jay Lerner and Frederick Loewe were hired by MGM to create a musical directly for the cinema, a sign perhaps that Broadway was beginning to take its rival more seriously. The result is in many ways an elaborately cinematic affair. Gigi takes advantage of the medium, having for example Maurice Chevalier break that pesky fourth wall and address the audience eye-to-eye, in reference to his screen musicals of the early 30s. We also have, in "She Is Not Thinking of Me", a song done in voice-over as an internal monologue  not, I believe, an original idea but certainly one that would be impossible (or at least very awkward) on the stage. As in their recent stage success My Fair Lady, Lerner and Loewe's songwriting is led by the lyrics, with a number like "It's a Bore" playing out like a musical conversation, with Loewe's melody skittering along to Lerner's vibrant wordplay. Their songs often serve to define character and relationships between characters. "It's a Bore" and "I Don't Understand the Parisians" are companion pieces as it were, and their similarities set up Gigi and Gaston as kindred spirits. Still, there are only a handful of really great numbers here ("The Night they Invented Champagne" being the standout), and one can't help getting the impression that Gigi is made up of cast-offs from the perfect My Fair Lady score. The lavishness of an Arthur Freed production ensured that his musicals were as much about look as they were sound. Gigi represents an astounding collaboration between cinematographer Joseph Ruttenberg, production designer Cecil Beaton and director Vincente Minnelli to reproduce the quality of fin-de-siecle painting, especially that of Auguste Renoir. The deliberate use of unfocused backgrounds in the opening scene is one of the best ever recreations of the impressionist style on screen. Minnelli (himself a keen painter) has a fine handling of perspective. Take the scene where Leslie Caron and Louis Jourdan are shelling peas. There is a chair in the foreground on the left-hand side, while on the right there is an open doorway into the kitchen. This contrast between closeness on one side and distance on the other not only adds real definition to the space, it allows the eye to be easily drawn from one end of the frame to the other, keeping Hermione Gingold highlighted even though she is in the background without having to resort to lots of obtrusive cutting. This is just one example, but it's a trick Minnelli pulls in almost every shot. The production is extremely lucky to have three genuine French stars for its principle parts, especially ones who were familiar enough with Hollywood to give an acceptable impression of Frenchness. Leslie Caron does a very credible job of playing a young girl on the verge of womanhood (she was in reality twenty-six) in a comically playful turn. Louis Jourdan is a little bland but by all means likable, and besides it suits him to look a little flat to all the better show off co-stars Caron and Chevalier. Ah oui, monsieur Chevalier, a man who is to an authentic portrayal of France what a crate of absinthe is to a light soiree. But for all his over-the-topness, he is great fun, slipping on the character of the ageing Lothario like an old glove. And those Lerner and Loewe songs like "I Remember It Well", where normal speech dovetails into singing, suit him very well. But while Gigi contains much to delight, as a whole it is lacking something. There just doesn't seem to be the heart or substance to the telling of the story that other Oscar-winning musicals have. Loewe in particular was reportedly reluctant to work in cinema, and both he and Lerner were overruled on a few decisions such as casting and inclusion of certain songs, so perhaps this explains the below-par score. Unsurprisingly it was a flop when adapted for the stage fifteen years later. Such is the care that has gone into those wonderful images, Gigi is far more a treat for the eyes than the ears, a coup were this purely a purely visual medium, but it falls some way short of being a superlative musical.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unintentionally creepy, with only one standout song
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Conrad
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A musical with only two memorable songs ("Thank Heaven for Little Girls" and "It's a Bore"), only one of which is good ("It's a Bore"), is not likely to be a good musical. Indeed, this is one of the most boring and poorly-acted in the history of the genre. The story ostensibly takes place in France, but it seems to unfold mainly in bland, claustrophobic drawing rooms. The title character's naive, youthful waifishness makes the relationship aspect of the film feel vaguely inappropriate, and this is only underscored by the aforementioned song about little girls, which is sung by a quintessentially creepy old man. This is a contender for worst Best Picture winner.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I Remembered It Wrong....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mark.waltz
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I first saw "Gigi" as a teenager, I was bewitched by its lavish costumes, sumptuous sets and delightful score, but in repeat viewings of it, I had to rank it as an overrated disappointment. Now some 25 years later, I watched it again, and while I don't consider it a perfect film (one worthy of a Best Picture Oscar), I do see it in a different light and appreciated it a bit more, taking my rating up from a 5 to an 8, **1/2 to ***1/2 on the Maltin scale. The days of living like Paris in the early 1900's are long gone, but it is certainly nice to re-visit them and the sweet duet between the aging Maurice Chevalier and Hermoine Gingold, the two scene-stealers of this film. Chevalier isn't the leading man he once was; In fact, Louis Jourdan, playing a part that Chevalier might have portrayed at Paramount during the early 1930's, doesn't seem quite up to the assignment, even if he is handsome, charming and well to do. Leslie Caron, however, does win in the title role, replacing Audrey Hepburn (from the stage productions) and being totally likable, especially when she sings "I Don't Understand the Parisians". Watching her grow from somewhat innocent teen to sophisticated young lady isn't quite like Hepburn going from guttersnipe to sophisticate in "My Fair Lady", even if the stories have a lot in common. The musical score has some bright moments, but some of the songs aren't as memorable as Lerner and Lowe's stage songs. The title song, in particular, suffers from some weak lyrics, and that defuses the dramatic impact of what it is trying to do. But when Chevalier and Gingold get together to reminisce in "I Remember It Well" and Gingold dances around with Jordan and Caron to "The Night They Invented Champagne", magic is made. Chevalier has a sly wink as the aging Honore, and in his relatively few scenes is the glue which holds the movie together. In smaller roles, Eva Gabor (as a two-timing lover of Jordan's) and Isabel Jeans (as the courtesan sister of Gingold) offer sophisticated bitchery. Gingold, a magic performer in everything she does, could be funny just looking around, and you wonder if her much later Broadway character of Madame Armfeldt in "A Little Night Music" could be a distant cousin of the family's. Superbly put together by the master of art in MGM musicals (Vincent Minnelli), "Gigi" can be appreciated more in repeat viewings as you get older, but some slow dramatic spots really cause it to drag a bit. That is minor, however, as this French creme pastry is lovely to look at, even though it may not entirely fill you up.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the most beautifully presented Musicals of all time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Koundinya
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The first time i watched the movie, i felt it was a "bore". The movie hardly has any running time of the character Gigi. The characters were melodramatic and their language was a butchered version of English. I never found the most vital element of Humor missing in the movie and was totally let down after having watched musicals like Singin' in the Rain and Wizard of Oz. Well, it was quite a long time back. I must agree i matured as a person who understands movie and appreciates it and not merely judge a movie based on its efficacy in entertaining. The movie is undoubtedly an entertainer. As the movie progressed, i started to understand the uniqueness of the movie and was enthralled by the songs and art setting. The movie is set in Paris at the turn of the century and the lifestyle, sartorial, marital and tonsorial preferences of the inhabitants is discreetly presented. The songs are brilliantly written and set to euphonious background music and when i paid heed to the lyrics, i realized what i greatly missed the first time i watched it- Humor. The movie also brings forth a message that no matter how rich and famous a man is, his heart remains vacant for a woman who remains herself and not be camouflaged with book-learned principles on satisfying a man.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    6.9?!?!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Gigi" won more Oscars than almost any other film in history. Yet, very oddly, it currently has an IMDb score of only 6.9! This makes no sense--especially since the film is magnificent throughout. The film is based on the story by Colette. It's about a sweet young lady, Gigi, and her family's insane intention of turning her into a very high-priced mistress to the rich and famous. However, because Gigi is so sweet, she just can't allow herself to have such a life and she insists on more--which causes problems with the man she loves (Louis Jourdan). While the plot is very simple (as it often is with musicals), the film works magnificently for several reasons. Most importantly, the Lerner and Lowe songs are among the best of any musical and are very memorable. In addition, the acting is so nice--and Leslie Caron is radiant and at her very best. Additionally, the film is just gorgeous--and replicates the grandeur of Paris circa 1900. Why this film has such a current mediocre score is beyond me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Curiously, no dancing...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dave from Ottawa
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Big Hollywood Musical genre in the 1950s was paved with ever more elaborate dance production numbers due to the popularity of stars like Gene Kelly, Fred Astaire and Cyd Charisse and yet rather curiously the ballet-trained Leslie Caron does not dance in this one and neither does anybody else. Still, 19th century Paris (the parks, the boulevards, Maxim's, the Follies etc.) is lavishly re-created, the costume designs are marvelous and the Lerner and Lowe songs are very good, if somewhat static in their presentation. The story is almost lighter than air, something about Caron reluctantly being groomed as a chic courtesan, but there is only enough to plot the keep things moving ahead as the camera tracks through or peeks into one gorgeously designed Parisian backdrop after another. The picture remains an old fashioned charmer thanks to million pretty things to look at and winning performances by Caron and especially Maurice Chevalier as an older rogue tutoring younger Louis Jourdan.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    At least I got 15 min sleep near the end
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    frankf-10
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I had seen this before years ago, but only could remember that it didn't impress me much. My wife selected the DVD via Netflix and 20 minutes into the film, all I could say to her was, "When is this movie going to start?" Slow moving hardly describes it. And Gaston repeating endlessly how boring things were for him hardly seems a way to entertain. I have never been much of a Maurice Chevalier fan and seeing him, as others have noted, oogling young girls in this flick is definitely weird now. Reading through reviews here, I was reminded how many Academy Awards it won - yikes! The Academy BS I can almost understand, but why IMDb reviewers found this leaden clunker so terrific is beyond me. Thank gawd I did get some shuteye toward the end.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Colourful character study which does remarkably well with two people crashing head first into a newfound state of thinking in regards to a chauvinistic lifestyle.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    johnnyboyz (j_l_h_m@yahoo.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gigi is a film about a young female protagonist asked to fall in with a highly specific male crowd; a crowd of whom carry with them the idea that something called "gender patriotism" consists of the wrecking of a woman's life, if she should ever leave you, by using your deep pockets of filthy wealth to buy off the man for whom she left you and convince him to leave town so that she is thus rendered totally heartbroken. If they suffer, why should't she? The men within this clique celebrate such an ideology, laughing and joking with one another; even taking time to indulge in speaking of the living by such rules with their barber, whom appears equally as enthused by such behaviour. On one occasion, it even led to the attempted suicide of one of those women  ah, well. But the film is not as it sounds, and will go on to cover this young female protagonist as well as her consequent frustrations out of trying to reject, or steer clear of, such an ill-gotten series of men and their livelihoods; the film eventually forming a piece about character we pray can find some sort of common-ground amidst what they exist - the film eventually an exuberant; careful piece treading along a fine line of bourgeoises indulgence and materialistic exploitation that comes together and actually works. The film unfolds in Paris; the year-clock in the French capital registering 1900. Leslie Caron plays the titular Gigi and that young protagonist slowly but surely being taught and groomed into falling in with a man to whom she may be able to act politely; overtly eloquently and essentially become the drone-wife that speaks when spoken to and laughs at her husband and his rich friend's anecdotes on prompt  after having brought out the tea for them, of course. But Gigi has an edge to her; a certain 'bite' and she is a faster and looser girl to that of what her contemporaries would like. In spite of being born into a fairly rich family, Gigi wishes not to head down a route of snobbery and such; instead, draws on inspiration from her mother - someone whom wanted more than what was offered, although someone, as her grandmother points out, whom chased a dream and failed to amount to what it was she desired when menial work at an opera house was the end product. In spite of this warning, as well as her grandmother's dismissive or hopeful tone that she will fail, we find it easy to get behind her. The man with whom she will come to interact a great deal more throughout is Louis Jourdan's Gaston Lachaille, the nephew of an elderly man named Honor&eacute; (Chevalier), whose attitudes towards women both now and throughout his life have been false and somewhat hate-filled although distilled through a filter of deft tones and extravagance. When we begin with him, he speaks to us on how he classifies his life profession as "lover" and we are drawn into a romanticised tone complimenting the sort of lifestyle in which a man like Honor&eacute; may waltz down a public street harbouring the opinions he has on the opposite sex. If we react as strongly as we ought to, our alignment with Gigi slips even easier into happening as she herself attempts to reject a kind of coercement director Vincente Minnelli attempts to relate onto that of the audience during the opening beats. Like Gigi, Gaston faces a seeping influence agonisingly trickling down from his peers and relations in regards to lifestyle choices and attitudes towards the other gender. Unlike most of his ilk, Gaston is fed up with the predominant items available and desires a change from socialite holidays to nations such as Italy and Spain, as well as the finer things on offer in Paris in the form of wines and such; something established through one of the film's many delightful musical numbers and a reoccurring quote throughout of "it's a bore" confirming this. Life for Gigi has reached a point in which honing skills in acting the socialite-come-snob for interactions should be the norm; the girl ambitious, and rather well off before this transitional phase, but her statements reiterating that she "doesn't understand Parisians" and that "there must be more to life than this" firmly establish her alienation to not only where she is, but the sorts of people with which she bonds. Primarily, these two characters coming together after seeking immense change from the patriarchal norm drives the film; Gaston's fondness for Gigi not equalled by her still prejudiced thinking when she deems him just as bad as anyone else in this messy cesspit of socialisation. One of the subtler moments of Jourdan's performance, going on neatly to project how he feels on what surrounds him, lies in the scene during which he loiters with his fellow men in that fatuous circle of elitism; a champagne toast to what they believe is carried out with a profound sense of glee evident on the faces of most of those present, but a wry peek at Gaston's facial expression amidst the extravagance and so-forth as everyone takes a sip reveals someone in deeper thought about this way of life than any of the others. In a film rich in colour; set decoration and faux-romanticism, best surmised when that wily rouge Honor&eacute; keeps getting his recollections shot down as he recalls decades-ago interludes with women now of his age, the film is deathly efficient in targeting people wanting out and away or something else anew. Many of the musical numbers work well, with one in which Gaston struggles with the coming to terms on how he feels for Gigi particularly standing out in memory, and the film generally pulls us in with its overlying juxtaposition of mise-en-scene with interior thematics; a deconstructing and retelling of stories of those within consummately seeing it home.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Enjoyable, but a wasted opportunity...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BlueEyes72
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gigi (Leslie Caron) is a young girl living in Paris in 1900, and being raised by her grandmother and great aunt to be a courtesan. Gaston (Louis Jourdan) is a rich Parisian playboy, who has become bored of his superficial lifestyle. He and Gigi have a platonic friendship, but as she becomes more sophisticated and grown up, the dynamic of their relationship starts to change This film, based on the novel by French author Colette, was not the last musical released by the MGM studios, but it was the last musical made by the Arthur Freed Unit at MGM (this unit was responsible for many of the classic musicals of the day, including Easter Parade, An American in Paris, and of course, Singin' In The Rain). The unit's swansong did very well, being nominated for nine Oscar awards, and winning all of them, breaking the then record of eight Oscars, held by Gone With The Wind. I thought the film was good, but not great. Some parts of it definitely worked  Leslie Caron was a delight as Gigi. I was not convinced by her performance in An American In Paris (although I l0ve An American In Paris and never get bored of watching it), but here she was great, and actually rather adorable. Audrey Hepburn was originally picked to play the part (having played Gigi on stage before she was famous), but due to other filming commitments, she was not available. Audrey is one of my favourite actresses, and I think she would have been perfect in the role, but Leslie Caron really worked well. Louis Jourdan was also great as the cynical and bored Gaston  making what could have been rather a dislikeable character into someone who the viewer liked a lot. Hermione Gingold and Isabel Jeans provided good support as Gigi's grandmother and great aunt. There were some lovely songs, in particular the title number sung by Louis Jourdan as he wanders throughout Paris, realising that his feelings for Gigi are changing; and the incredibly catchy The Night They Invented Champagne which I couldn't get out of my head after watching the film. Paris itself looks fabulous  most of the film was shot on location there, and it really is a lovely setting, very colourful and pretty. There were some parts that I didn't like  Maurice Chevalier's character Honore (the uncle of Gaston) seemed an unnecessary and distasteful character. This is no criticism of Chevalier's acting, which was fine, but the character was hard for me to warm to. In one scene Honore is highly delighted upon hearing that a former girlfriend of Gaston's has tried to kill herself after he ended her relationship. Honore toasts Gaston and says that he hopes this will be the first of many suicides. It may have been written flippantly, but this scene did not sit well with me. (Indeed the whole storyline of two women training their young relation to be a courtesan could be distasteful, although it was handled fairly well and with humour.) I was also slightly disappointed that there was no dancing in this film! I love to see fabulous dancing in musicals, and with Leslie Caron being an excellent ballet dancer, it feels like a missed opportunity not to show off her skills. Overall then, it's an enjoyable film, but ultimately a forgettable one. Worth watching for fans of musicals.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gee its grand to watch Gigi over and over, a film my sisters and I have adored from childhood
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Amy Adler
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In Paris, during the middle of the 19th century, handsome Gaston (Louis Jordan) is a sugar empire heir with a great deal of money. Like his father, Honore (Maurice Chevalier), he has shunned marriage in favor of having a succession of beautiful women. His present love, Lianne (Eva Gabor) is certainly pretty. But, as Gaston relates in song, he is truly bored with his lofty position in society, with women, and with parties. The only place he feels comfortable is at the home of an old friend (and former flame of Honore's), Mamita (Hermione Gingold). Odd it is, because the dear lady is rather poor and lives in an unfashionable neighborhood with her opera singing daughter AND her vivacious granddaughter, Gigi (Leslie Caron). Although she is in her middle teen years, Gigi is still treated by Gaston and her grandmama as a little girl and, in truth, she still acts as one, being very innocent and wide-eyed. Gaston loves eating Mamita's great cooking and playing cards with Gigi, away from the social scene. Unhappily, the sugar king soon finds that his "lady love" has been unfaithful and he makes a very publicized break with Lianne. To boost his spirits and pay off a card game debt to Gigi, Gaston, Mamita, and Gigi all go to the seashore for a vacation. They have a great time. But, Mamita's sister, also a former courtesan, wishes to change things when the trio returns to Paris. She sees that Gigi is really a young woman and, perhaps, they have a chance to offer her up as Gaston's next courtesan? She'd be well taken care of that's for certain. The only problem is that Gigi may not want to become the kind of woman who gets "passed around" but, rather, might want to be married and have children. What will the next season bring? Gee willikers is Gigi a pleasure to watch, as I and my sisters have done since our sixties' childhood. A musical, it nevertheless has enough non-musical action to satisfy those who don't particularly care for the genre. However, the songs are lovely and integral to the plot. Then, the acting is great, with Caron, Jordan, Chevalier, Ginggold and all of the others being near perfect in their respective roles. Also, the Paris setting, the terrific costumes, the lovely photography, and the superb direction by Vincente Minelli all contribute to the movie's enjoyment. It was awarded an Academy Award as best picture in 1958 and deservedly so. With that fact in mind, why not seek out Gigi ASAP?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "A gigantic, romantic clich&eacute;"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steffi_P
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There was a wave of stage-to-screen adaptations of hit musicals in the mid-1950s, translating the work of the two celebrated theatrical duos Rodgers and Hammerstein and Lerner and Loewe for a new audience. However this Arthur Freed production moves the other way, as Alan Jay Lerner and Frederick Loewe were hired by MGM to create a musical directly for the cinema, a sign perhaps that Broadway was beginning to take its rival more seriously. The result is in many ways an elaborately cinematic affair. Gigi takes advantage of the medium, having for example Maurice Chevalier break that pesky fourth wall and address the audience eye-to-eye, in reference to his screen musicals of the early 30s. We also have, in "She Is Not Thinking of Me", a song done in voice-over as an internal monologue  not, I believe, an original idea but certainly one that would be impossible (or at least very awkward) on the stage. As in their recent stage success My Fair Lady, Lerner and Loewe's songwriting is led by the lyrics, with a number like "It's a Bore" playing out like a musical conversation, with Loewe's melody skittering along to Lerner's vibrant wordplay. Their songs often serve to define character and relationships between characters. "It's a Bore" and "I Don't Understand the Parisians" are companion pieces as it were, and their similarities set up Gigi and Gaston as kindred spirits. Still, there are only a handful of really great numbers here ("The Night they Invented Champagne" being the standout), and one can't help getting the impression that Gigi is made up of cast-offs from the perfect My Fair Lady score. The lavishness of an Arthur Freed production ensured that his musicals were as much about look as they were sound. Gigi represents an astounding collaboration between cinematographer Joseph Ruttenberg, production designer Cecil Beaton and director Vincente Minnelli to reproduce the quality of fin-de-siecle painting, especially that of Auguste Renoir. The deliberate use of unfocused backgrounds in the opening scene is one of the best ever recreations of the impressionist style on screen. Minnelli (himself a keen painter) has a fine handling of perspective. Take the scene where Leslie Caron and Louis Jourdan are shelling peas. There is a chair in the foreground on the left-hand side, while on the right there is an open doorway into the kitchen. This contrast between closeness on one side and distance on the other not only adds real definition to the space, it allows the eye to be easily drawn from one end of the frame to the other, keeping Hermione Gingold highlighted even though she is in the background without having to resort to lots of obtrusive cutting. This is just one example, but it's a trick Minnelli pulls in almost every shot. The production is extremely lucky to have three genuine French stars for its principle parts, especially ones who were familiar enough with Hollywood to give an acceptable impression of Frenchness. Leslie Caron does a very credible job of playing a young girl on the verge of womanhood (she was in reality twenty-six) in a comically playful turn. Louis Jourdan is a little bland but by all means likable, and besides it suits him to look a little flat to all the better show off co-stars Caron and Chevalier. Ah oui, monsieur Chevalier, a man who is to an authentic portrayal of France what a crate of absinthe is to a light soiree. But for all his over-the-topness, he is great fun, slipping on the character of the ageing Lothario like an old glove. And those Lerner and Loewe songs like "I Remember It Well", where normal speech dovetails into singing, suit him very well. But while Gigi contains much to delight, as a whole it is lacking something. There just doesn't seem to be the heart or substance to the telling of the story that other Oscar-winning musicals have. Loewe in particular was reportedly reluctant to work in cinema, and both he and Lerner were overruled on a few decisions such as casting and inclusion of certain songs, so perhaps this explains the below-par score. Unsurprisingly it was a flop when adapted for the stage fifteen years later. Such is the care that has gone into those wonderful images, Gigi is far more a treat for the eyes than the ears, a coup were this purely a purely visual medium, but it falls some way short of being a superlative musical.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unintentionally creepy, with only one standout song
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Conrad
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A musical with only two memorable songs ("Thank Heaven for Little Girls" and "It's a Bore"), only one of which is good ("It's a Bore"), is not likely to be a good musical. Indeed, this is one of the most boring and poorly-acted in the history of the genre. The story ostensibly takes place in France, but it seems to unfold mainly in bland, claustrophobic drawing rooms. The title character's naive, youthful waifishness makes the relationship aspect of the film feel vaguely inappropriate, and this is only underscored by the aforementioned song about little girls, which is sung by a quintessentially creepy old man. This is a contender for worst Best Picture winner.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I Remembered It Wrong....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mark.waltz
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I first saw "Gigi" as a teenager, I was bewitched by its lavish costumes, sumptuous sets and delightful score, but in repeat viewings of it, I had to rank it as an overrated disappointment. Now some 25 years later, I watched it again, and while I don't consider it a perfect film (one worthy of a Best Picture Oscar), I do see it in a different light and appreciated it a bit more, taking my rating up from a 5 to an 8, **1/2 to ***1/2 on the Maltin scale. The days of living like Paris in the early 1900's are long gone, but it is certainly nice to re-visit them and the sweet duet between the aging Maurice Chevalier and Hermoine Gingold, the two scene-stealers of this film. Chevalier isn't the leading man he once was; In fact, Louis Jourdan, playing a part that Chevalier might have portrayed at Paramount during the early 1930's, doesn't seem quite up to the assignment, even if he is handsome, charming and well to do. Leslie Caron, however, does win in the title role, replacing Audrey Hepburn (from the stage productions) and being totally likable, especially when she sings "I Don't Understand the Parisians". Watching her grow from somewhat innocent teen to sophisticated young lady isn't quite like Hepburn going from guttersnipe to sophisticate in "My Fair Lady", even if the stories have a lot in common. The musical score has some bright moments, but some of the songs aren't as memorable as Lerner and Lowe's stage songs. The title song, in particular, suffers from some weak lyrics, and that defuses the dramatic impact of what it is trying to do. But when Chevalier and Gingold get together to reminisce in "I Remember It Well" and Gingold dances around with Jordan and Caron to "The Night They Invented Champagne", magic is made. Chevalier has a sly wink as the aging Honore, and in his relatively few scenes is the glue which holds the movie together. In smaller roles, Eva Gabor (as a two-timing lover of Jordan's) and Isabel Jeans (as the courtesan sister of Gingold) offer sophisticated bitchery. Gingold, a magic performer in everything she does, could be funny just looking around, and you wonder if her much later Broadway character of Madame Armfeldt in "A Little Night Music" could be a distant cousin of the family's. Superbly put together by the master of art in MGM musicals (Vincent Minnelli), "Gigi" can be appreciated more in repeat viewings as you get older, but some slow dramatic spots really cause it to drag a bit. That is minor, however, as this French creme pastry is lovely to look at, even though it may not entirely fill you up.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the most beautifully presented Musicals of all time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Koundinya
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The first time i watched the movie, i felt it was a "bore". The movie hardly has any running time of the character Gigi. The characters were melodramatic and their language was a butchered version of English. I never found the most vital element of Humor missing in the movie and was totally let down after having watched musicals like Singin' in the Rain and Wizard of Oz. Well, it was quite a long time back. I must agree i matured as a person who understands movie and appreciates it and not merely judge a movie based on its efficacy in entertaining. The movie is undoubtedly an entertainer. As the movie progressed, i started to understand the uniqueness of the movie and was enthralled by the songs and art setting. The movie is set in Paris at the turn of the century and the lifestyle, sartorial, marital and tonsorial preferences of the inhabitants is discreetly presented. The songs are brilliantly written and set to euphonious background music and when i paid heed to the lyrics, i realized what i greatly missed the first time i watched it- Humor. The movie also brings forth a message that no matter how rich and famous a man is, his heart remains vacant for a woman who remains herself and not be camouflaged with book-learned principles on satisfying a man.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    6.9?!?!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Gigi" won more Oscars than almost any other film in history. Yet, very oddly, it currently has an IMDb score of only 6.9! This makes no sense--especially since the film is magnificent throughout. The film is based on the story by Colette. It's about a sweet young lady, Gigi, and her family's insane intention of turning her into a very high-priced mistress to the rich and famous. However, because Gigi is so sweet, she just can't allow herself to have such a life and she insists on more--which causes problems with the man she loves (Louis Jourdan). While the plot is very simple (as it often is with musicals), the film works magnificently for several reasons. Most importantly, the Lerner and Lowe songs are among the best of any musical and are very memorable. In addition, the acting is so nice--and Leslie Caron is radiant and at her very best. Additionally, the film is just gorgeous--and replicates the grandeur of Paris circa 1900. Why this film has such a current mediocre score is beyond me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Curiously, no dancing...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dave from Ottawa
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Big Hollywood Musical genre in the 1950s was paved with ever more elaborate dance production numbers due to the popularity of stars like Gene Kelly, Fred Astaire and Cyd Charisse and yet rather curiously the ballet-trained Leslie Caron does not dance in this one and neither does anybody else. Still, 19th century Paris (the parks, the boulevards, Maxim's, the Follies etc.) is lavishly re-created, the costume designs are marvelous and the Lerner and Lowe songs are very good, if somewhat static in their presentation. The story is almost lighter than air, something about Caron reluctantly being groomed as a chic courtesan, but there is only enough to plot the keep things moving ahead as the camera tracks through or peeks into one gorgeously designed Parisian backdrop after another. The picture remains an old fashioned charmer thanks to million pretty things to look at and winning performances by Caron and especially Maurice Chevalier as an older rogue tutoring younger Louis Jourdan.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    At least I got 15 min sleep near the end
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    frankf-10
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I had seen this before years ago, but only could remember that it didn't impress me much. My wife selected the DVD via Netflix and 20 minutes into the film, all I could say to her was, "When is this movie going to start?" Slow moving hardly describes it. And Gaston repeating endlessly how boring things were for him hardly seems a way to entertain. I have never been much of a Maurice Chevalier fan and seeing him, as others have noted, oogling young girls in this flick is definitely weird now. Reading through reviews here, I was reminded how many Academy Awards it won - yikes! The Academy BS I can almost understand, but why IMDb reviewers found this leaden clunker so terrific is beyond me. Thank gawd I did get some shuteye toward the end.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Colourful character study which does remarkably well with two people crashing head first into a newfound state of thinking in regards to a chauvinistic lifestyle.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    johnnyboyz (j_l_h_m@yahoo.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gigi is a film about a young female protagonist asked to fall in with a highly specific male crowd; a crowd of whom carry with them the idea that something called "gender patriotism" consists of the wrecking of a woman's life, if she should ever leave you, by using your deep pockets of filthy wealth to buy off the man for whom she left you and convince him to leave town so that she is thus rendered totally heartbroken. If they suffer, why should't she? The men within this clique celebrate such an ideology, laughing and joking with one another; even taking time to indulge in speaking of the living by such rules with their barber, whom appears equally as enthused by such behaviour. On one occasion, it even led to the attempted suicide of one of those women  ah, well. But the film is not as it sounds, and will go on to cover this young female protagonist as well as her consequent frustrations out of trying to reject, or steer clear of, such an ill-gotten series of men and their livelihoods; the film eventually forming a piece about character we pray can find some sort of common-ground amidst what they exist - the film eventually an exuberant; careful piece treading along a fine line of bourgeoises indulgence and materialistic exploitation that comes together and actually works. The film unfolds in Paris; the year-clock in the French capital registering 1900. Leslie Caron plays the titular Gigi and that young protagonist slowly but surely being taught and groomed into falling in with a man to whom she may be able to act politely; overtly eloquently and essentially become the drone-wife that speaks when spoken to and laughs at her husband and his rich friend's anecdotes on prompt  after having brought out the tea for them, of course. But Gigi has an edge to her; a certain 'bite' and she is a faster and looser girl to that of what her contemporaries would like. In spite of being born into a fairly rich family, Gigi wishes not to head down a route of snobbery and such; instead, draws on inspiration from her mother - someone whom wanted more than what was offered, although someone, as her grandmother points out, whom chased a dream and failed to amount to what it was she desired when menial work at an opera house was the end product. In spite of this warning, as well as her grandmother's dismissive or hopeful tone that she will fail, we find it easy to get behind her. The man with whom she will come to interact a great deal more throughout is Louis Jourdan's Gaston Lachaille, the nephew of an elderly man named Honor&eacute; (Chevalier), whose attitudes towards women both now and throughout his life have been false and somewhat hate-filled although distilled through a filter of deft tones and extravagance. When we begin with him, he speaks to us on how he classifies his life profession as "lover" and we are drawn into a romanticised tone complimenting the sort of lifestyle in which a man like Honor&eacute; may waltz down a public street harbouring the opinions he has on the opposite sex. If we react as strongly as we ought to, our alignment with Gigi slips even easier into happening as she herself attempts to reject a kind of coercement director Vincente Minnelli attempts to relate onto that of the audience during the opening beats. Like Gigi, Gaston faces a seeping influence agonisingly trickling down from his peers and relations in regards to lifestyle choices and attitudes towards the other gender. Unlike most of his ilk, Gaston is fed up with the predominant items available and desires a change from socialite holidays to nations such as Italy and Spain, as well as the finer things on offer in Paris in the form of wines and such; something established through one of the film's many delightful musical numbers and a reoccurring quote throughout of "it's a bore" confirming this. Life for Gigi has reached a point in which honing skills in acting the socialite-come-snob for interactions should be the norm; the girl ambitious, and rather well off before this transitional phase, but her statements reiterating that she "doesn't understand Parisians" and that "there must be more to life than this" firmly establish her alienation to not only where she is, but the sorts of people with which she bonds. Primarily, these two characters coming together after seeking immense change from the patriarchal norm drives the film; Gaston's fondness for Gigi not equalled by her still prejudiced thinking when she deems him just as bad as anyone else in this messy cesspit of socialisation. One of the subtler moments of Jourdan's performance, going on neatly to project how he feels on what surrounds him, lies in the scene during which he loiters with his fellow men in that fatuous circle of elitism; a champagne toast to what they believe is carried out with a profound sense of glee evident on the faces of most of those present, but a wry peek at Gaston's facial expression amidst the extravagance and so-forth as everyone takes a sip reveals someone in deeper thought about this way of life than any of the others. In a film rich in colour; set decoration and faux-romanticism, best surmised when that wily rouge Honor&eacute; keeps getting his recollections shot down as he recalls decades-ago interludes with women now of his age, the film is deathly efficient in targeting people wanting out and away or something else anew. Many of the musical numbers work well, with one in which Gaston struggles with the coming to terms on how he feels for Gigi particularly standing out in memory, and the film generally pulls us in with its overlying juxtaposition of mise-en-scene with interior thematics; a deconstructing and retelling of stories of those within consummately seeing it home.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Enjoyable, but a wasted opportunity...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BlueEyes72
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gigi (Leslie Caron) is a young girl living in Paris in 1900, and being raised by her grandmother and great aunt to be a courtesan. Gaston (Louis Jourdan) is a rich Parisian playboy, who has become bored of his superficial lifestyle. He and Gigi have a platonic friendship, but as she becomes more sophisticated and grown up, the dynamic of their relationship starts to change This film, based on the novel by French author Colette, was not the last musical released by the MGM studios, but it was the last musical made by the Arthur Freed Unit at MGM (this unit was responsible for many of the classic musicals of the day, including Easter Parade, An American in Paris, and of course, Singin' In The Rain). The unit's swansong did very well, being nominated for nine Oscar awards, and winning all of them, breaking the then record of eight Oscars, held by Gone With The Wind. I thought the film was good, but not great. Some parts of it definitely worked  Leslie Caron was a delight as Gigi. I was not convinced by her performance in An American In Paris (although I l0ve An American In Paris and never get bored of watching it), but here she was great, and actually rather adorable. Audrey Hepburn was originally picked to play the part (having played Gigi on stage before she was famous), but due to other filming commitments, she was not available. Audrey is one of my favourite actresses, and I think she would have been perfect in the role, but Leslie Caron really worked well. Louis Jourdan was also great as the cynical and bored Gaston  making what could have been rather a dislikeable character into someone who the viewer liked a lot. Hermione Gingold and Isabel Jeans provided good support as Gigi's grandmother and great aunt. There were some lovely songs, in particular the title number sung by Louis Jourdan as he wanders throughout Paris, realising that his feelings for Gigi are changing; and the incredibly catchy The Night They Invented Champagne which I couldn't get out of my head after watching the film. Paris itself looks fabulous  most of the film was shot on location there, and it really is a lovely setting, very colourful and pretty. There were some parts that I didn't like  Maurice Chevalier's character Honore (the uncle of Gaston) seemed an unnecessary and distasteful character. This is no criticism of Chevalier's acting, which was fine, but the character was hard for me to warm to. In one scene Honore is highly delighted upon hearing that a former girlfriend of Gaston's has tried to kill herself after he ended her relationship. Honore toasts Gaston and says that he hopes this will be the first of many suicides. It may have been written flippantly, but this scene did not sit well with me. (Indeed the whole storyline of two women training their young relation to be a courtesan could be distasteful, although it was handled fairly well and with humour.) I was also slightly disappointed that there was no dancing in this film! I love to see fabulous dancing in musicals, and with Leslie Caron being an excellent ballet dancer, it feels like a missed opportunity not to show off her skills. Overall then, it's an enjoyable film, but ultimately a forgettable one. Worth watching for fans of musicals.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gee its grand to watch Gigi over and over, a film my sisters and I have adored from childhood
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Amy Adler
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In Paris, during the middle of the 19th century, handsome Gaston (Louis Jordan) is a sugar empire heir with a great deal of money. Like his father, Honore (Maurice Chevalier), he has shunned marriage in favor of having a succession of beautiful women. His present love, Lianne (Eva Gabor) is certainly pretty. But, as Gaston relates in song, he is truly bored with his lofty position in society, with women, and with parties. The only place he feels comfortable is at the home of an old friend (and former flame of Honore's), Mamita (Hermione Gingold). Odd it is, because the dear lady is rather poor and lives in an unfashionable neighborhood with her opera singing daughter AND her vivacious granddaughter, Gigi (Leslie Caron). Although she is in her middle teen years, Gigi is still treated by Gaston and her grandmama as a little girl and, in truth, she still acts as one, being very innocent and wide-eyed. Gaston loves eating Mamita's great cooking and playing cards with Gigi, away from the social scene. Unhappily, the sugar king soon finds that his "lady love" has been unfaithful and he makes a very publicized break with Lianne. To boost his spirits and pay off a card game debt to Gigi, Gaston, Mamita, and Gigi all go to the seashore for a vacation. They have a great time. But, Mamita's sister, also a former courtesan, wishes to change things when the trio returns to Paris. She sees that Gigi is really a young woman and, perhaps, they have a chance to offer her up as Gaston's next courtesan? She'd be well taken care of that's for certain. The only problem is that Gigi may not want to become the kind of woman who gets "passed around" but, rather, might want to be married and have children. What will the next season bring? Gee willikers is Gigi a pleasure to watch, as I and my sisters have done since our sixties' childhood. A musical, it nevertheless has enough non-musical action to satisfy those who don't particularly care for the genre. However, the songs are lovely and integral to the plot. Then, the acting is great, with Caron, Jordan, Chevalier, Ginggold and all of the others being near perfect in their respective roles. Also, the Paris setting, the terrific costumes, the lovely photography, and the superb direction by Vincente Minelli all contribute to the movie's enjoyment. It was awarded an Academy Award as best picture in 1958 and deservedly so. With that fact in mind, why not seek out Gigi ASAP?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "A gigantic, romantic clich&eacute;"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steffi_P
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There was a wave of stage-to-screen adaptations of hit musicals in the mid-1950s, translating the work of the two celebrated theatrical duos Rodgers and Hammerstein and Lerner and Loewe for a new audience. However this Arthur Freed production moves the other way, as Alan Jay Lerner and Frederick Loewe were hired by MGM to create a musical directly for the cinema, a sign perhaps that Broadway was beginning to take its rival more seriously. The result is in many ways an elaborately cinematic affair. Gigi takes advantage of the medium, having for example Maurice Chevalier break that pesky fourth wall and address the audience eye-to-eye, in reference to his screen musicals of the early 30s. We also have, in "She Is Not Thinking of Me", a song done in voice-over as an internal monologue  not, I believe, an original idea but certainly one that would be impossible (or at least very awkward) on the stage. As in their recent stage success My Fair Lady, Lerner and Loewe's songwriting is led by the lyrics, with a number like "It's a Bore" playing out like a musical conversation, with Loewe's melody skittering along to Lerner's vibrant wordplay. Their songs often serve to define character and relationships between characters. "It's a Bore" and "I Don't Understand the Parisians" are companion pieces as it were, and their similarities set up Gigi and Gaston as kindred spirits. Still, there are only a handful of really great numbers here ("The Night they Invented Champagne" being the standout), and one can't help getting the impression that Gigi is made up of cast-offs from the perfect My Fair Lady score. The lavishness of an Arthur Freed production ensured that his musicals were as much about look as they were sound. Gigi represents an astounding collaboration between cinematographer Joseph Ruttenberg, production designer Cecil Beaton and director Vincente Minnelli to reproduce the quality of fin-de-siecle painting, especially that of Auguste Renoir. The deliberate use of unfocused backgrounds in the opening scene is one of the best ever recreations of the impressionist style on screen. Minnelli (himself a keen painter) has a fine handling of perspective. Take the scene where Leslie Caron and Louis Jourdan are shelling peas. There is a chair in the foreground on the left-hand side, while on the right there is an open doorway into the kitchen. This contrast between closeness on one side and distance on the other not only adds real definition to the space, it allows the eye to be easily drawn from one end of the frame to the other, keeping Hermione Gingold highlighted even though she is in the background without having to resort to lots of obtrusive cutting. This is just one example, but it's a trick Minnelli pulls in almost every shot. The production is extremely lucky to have three genuine French stars for its principle parts, especially ones who were familiar enough with Hollywood to give an acceptable impression of Frenchness. Leslie Caron does a very credible job of playing a young girl on the verge of womanhood (she was in reality twenty-six) in a comically playful turn. Louis Jourdan is a little bland but by all means likable, and besides it suits him to look a little flat to all the better show off co-stars Caron and Chevalier. Ah oui, monsieur Chevalier, a man who is to an authentic portrayal of France what a crate of absinthe is to a light soiree. But for all his over-the-topness, he is great fun, slipping on the character of the ageing Lothario like an old glove. And those Lerner and Loewe songs like "I Remember It Well", where normal speech dovetails into singing, suit him very well. But while Gigi contains much to delight, as a whole it is lacking something. There just doesn't seem to be the heart or substance to the telling of the story that other Oscar-winning musicals have. Loewe in particular was reportedly reluctant to work in cinema, and both he and Lerner were overruled on a few decisions such as casting and inclusion of certain songs, so perhaps this explains the below-par score. Unsurprisingly it was a flop when adapted for the stage fifteen years later. Such is the care that has gone into those wonderful images, Gigi is far more a treat for the eyes than the ears, a coup were this purely a purely visual medium, but it falls some way short of being a superlative musical.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unintentionally creepy, with only one standout song
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Conrad
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A musical with only two memorable songs ("Thank Heaven for Little Girls" and "It's a Bore"), only one of which is good ("It's a Bore"), is not likely to be a good musical. Indeed, this is one of the most boring and poorly-acted in the history of the genre. The story ostensibly takes place in France, but it seems to unfold mainly in bland, claustrophobic drawing rooms. The title character's naive, youthful waifishness makes the relationship aspect of the film feel vaguely inappropriate, and this is only underscored by the aforementioned song about little girls, which is sung by a quintessentially creepy old man. This is a contender for worst Best Picture winner.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I Remembered It Wrong....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mark.waltz
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I first saw "Gigi" as a teenager, I was bewitched by its lavish costumes, sumptuous sets and delightful score, but in repeat viewings of it, I had to rank it as an overrated disappointment. Now some 25 years later, I watched it again, and while I don't consider it a perfect film (one worthy of a Best Picture Oscar), I do see it in a different light and appreciated it a bit more, taking my rating up from a 5 to an 8, **1/2 to ***1/2 on the Maltin scale. The days of living like Paris in the early 1900's are long gone, but it is certainly nice to re-visit them and the sweet duet between the aging Maurice Chevalier and Hermoine Gingold, the two scene-stealers of this film. Chevalier isn't the leading man he once was; In fact, Louis Jourdan, playing a part that Chevalier might have portrayed at Paramount during the early 1930's, doesn't seem quite up to the assignment, even if he is handsome, charming and well to do. Leslie Caron, however, does win in the title role, replacing Audrey Hepburn (from the stage productions) and being totally likable, especially when she sings "I Don't Understand the Parisians". Watching her grow from somewhat innocent teen to sophisticated young lady isn't quite like Hepburn going from guttersnipe to sophisticate in "My Fair Lady", even if the stories have a lot in common. The musical score has some bright moments, but some of the songs aren't as memorable as Lerner and Lowe's stage songs. The title song, in particular, suffers from some weak lyrics, and that defuses the dramatic impact of what it is trying to do. But when Chevalier and Gingold get together to reminisce in "I Remember It Well" and Gingold dances around with Jordan and Caron to "The Night They Invented Champagne", magic is made. Chevalier has a sly wink as the aging Honore, and in his relatively few scenes is the glue which holds the movie together. In smaller roles, Eva Gabor (as a two-timing lover of Jordan's) and Isabel Jeans (as the courtesan sister of Gingold) offer sophisticated bitchery. Gingold, a magic performer in everything she does, could be funny just looking around, and you wonder if her much later Broadway character of Madame Armfeldt in "A Little Night Music" could be a distant cousin of the family's. Superbly put together by the master of art in MGM musicals (Vincent Minnelli), "Gigi" can be appreciated more in repeat viewings as you get older, but some slow dramatic spots really cause it to drag a bit. That is minor, however, as this French creme pastry is lovely to look at, even though it may not entirely fill you up.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the most beautifully presented Musicals of all time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Koundinya
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The first time i watched the movie, i felt it was a "bore". The movie hardly has any running time of the character Gigi. The characters were melodramatic and their language was a butchered version of English. I never found the most vital element of Humor missing in the movie and was totally let down after having watched musicals like Singin' in the Rain and Wizard of Oz. Well, it was quite a long time back. I must agree i matured as a person who understands movie and appreciates it and not merely judge a movie based on its efficacy in entertaining. The movie is undoubtedly an entertainer. As the movie progressed, i started to understand the uniqueness of the movie and was enthralled by the songs and art setting. The movie is set in Paris at the turn of the century and the lifestyle, sartorial, marital and tonsorial preferences of the inhabitants is discreetly presented. The songs are brilliantly written and set to euphonious background music and when i paid heed to the lyrics, i realized what i greatly missed the first time i watched it- Humor. The movie also brings forth a message that no matter how rich and famous a man is, his heart remains vacant for a woman who remains herself and not be camouflaged with book-learned principles on satisfying a man.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    6.9?!?!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Gigi" won more Oscars than almost any other film in history. Yet, very oddly, it currently has an IMDb score of only 6.9! This makes no sense--especially since the film is magnificent throughout. The film is based on the story by Colette. It's about a sweet young lady, Gigi, and her family's insane intention of turning her into a very high-priced mistress to the rich and famous. However, because Gigi is so sweet, she just can't allow herself to have such a life and she insists on more--which causes problems with the man she loves (Louis Jourdan). While the plot is very simple (as it often is with musicals), the film works magnificently for several reasons. Most importantly, the Lerner and Lowe songs are among the best of any musical and are very memorable. In addition, the acting is so nice--and Leslie Caron is radiant and at her very best. Additionally, the film is just gorgeous--and replicates the grandeur of Paris circa 1900. Why this film has such a current mediocre score is beyond me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Curiously, no dancing...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dave from Ottawa
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Big Hollywood Musical genre in the 1950s was paved with ever more elaborate dance production numbers due to the popularity of stars like Gene Kelly, Fred Astaire and Cyd Charisse and yet rather curiously the ballet-trained Leslie Caron does not dance in this one and neither does anybody else. Still, 19th century Paris (the parks, the boulevards, Maxim's, the Follies etc.) is lavishly re-created, the costume designs are marvelous and the Lerner and Lowe songs are very good, if somewhat static in their presentation. The story is almost lighter than air, something about Caron reluctantly being groomed as a chic courtesan, but there is only enough to plot the keep things moving ahead as the camera tracks through or peeks into one gorgeously designed Parisian backdrop after another. The picture remains an old fashioned charmer thanks to million pretty things to look at and winning performances by Caron and especially Maurice Chevalier as an older rogue tutoring younger Louis Jourdan.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    At least I got 15 min sleep near the end
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    frankf-10
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I had seen this before years ago, but only could remember that it didn't impress me much. My wife selected the DVD via Netflix and 20 minutes into the film, all I could say to her was, "When is this movie going to start?" Slow moving hardly describes it. And Gaston repeating endlessly how boring things were for him hardly seems a way to entertain. I have never been much of a Maurice Chevalier fan and seeing him, as others have noted, oogling young girls in this flick is definitely weird now. Reading through reviews here, I was reminded how many Academy Awards it won - yikes! The Academy BS I can almost understand, but why IMDb reviewers found this leaden clunker so terrific is beyond me. Thank gawd I did get some shuteye toward the end.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Colourful character study which does remarkably well with two people crashing head first into a newfound state of thinking in regards to a chauvinistic lifestyle.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    johnnyboyz (j_l_h_m@yahoo.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gigi is a film about a young female protagonist asked to fall in with a highly specific male crowd; a crowd of whom carry with them the idea that something called "gender patriotism" consists of the wrecking of a woman's life, if she should ever leave you, by using your deep pockets of filthy wealth to buy off the man for whom she left you and convince him to leave town so that she is thus rendered totally heartbroken. If they suffer, why should't she? The men within this clique celebrate such an ideology, laughing and joking with one another; even taking time to indulge in speaking of the living by such rules with their barber, whom appears equally as enthused by such behaviour. On one occasion, it even led to the attempted suicide of one of those women  ah, well. But the film is not as it sounds, and will go on to cover this young female protagonist as well as her consequent frustrations out of trying to reject, or steer clear of, such an ill-gotten series of men and their livelihoods; the film eventually forming a piece about character we pray can find some sort of common-ground amidst what they exist - the film eventually an exuberant; careful piece treading along a fine line of bourgeoises indulgence and materialistic exploitation that comes together and actually works. The film unfolds in Paris; the year-clock in the French capital registering 1900. Leslie Caron plays the titular Gigi and that young protagonist slowly but surely being taught and groomed into falling in with a man to whom she may be able to act politely; overtly eloquently and essentially become the drone-wife that speaks when spoken to and laughs at her husband and his rich friend's anecdotes on prompt  after having brought out the tea for them, of course. But Gigi has an edge to her; a certain 'bite' and she is a faster and looser girl to that of what her contemporaries would like. In spite of being born into a fairly rich family, Gigi wishes not to head down a route of snobbery and such; instead, draws on inspiration from her mother - someone whom wanted more than what was offered, although someone, as her grandmother points out, whom chased a dream and failed to amount to what it was she desired when menial work at an opera house was the end product. In spite of this warning, as well as her grandmother's dismissive or hopeful tone that she will fail, we find it easy to get behind her. The man with whom she will come to interact a great deal more throughout is Louis Jourdan's Gaston Lachaille, the nephew of an elderly man named Honor&eacute; (Chevalier), whose attitudes towards women both now and throughout his life have been false and somewhat hate-filled although distilled through a filter of deft tones and extravagance. When we begin with him, he speaks to us on how he classifies his life profession as "lover" and we are drawn into a romanticised tone complimenting the sort of lifestyle in which a man like Honor&eacute; may waltz down a public street harbouring the opinions he has on the opposite sex. If we react as strongly as we ought to, our alignment with Gigi slips even easier into happening as she herself attempts to reject a kind of coercement director Vincente Minnelli attempts to relate onto that of the audience during the opening beats. Like Gigi, Gaston faces a seeping influence agonisingly trickling down from his peers and relations in regards to lifestyle choices and attitudes towards the other gender. Unlike most of his ilk, Gaston is fed up with the predominant items available and desires a change from socialite holidays to nations such as Italy and Spain, as well as the finer things on offer in Paris in the form of wines and such; something established through one of the film's many delightful musical numbers and a reoccurring quote throughout of "it's a bore" confirming this. Life for Gigi has reached a point in which honing skills in acting the socialite-come-snob for interactions should be the norm; the girl ambitious, and rather well off before this transitional phase, but her statements reiterating that she "doesn't understand Parisians" and that "there must be more to life than this" firmly establish her alienation to not only where she is, but the sorts of people with which she bonds. Primarily, these two characters coming together after seeking immense change from the patriarchal norm drives the film; Gaston's fondness for Gigi not equalled by her still prejudiced thinking when she deems him just as bad as anyone else in this messy cesspit of socialisation. One of the subtler moments of Jourdan's performance, going on neatly to project how he feels on what surrounds him, lies in the scene during which he loiters with his fellow men in that fatuous circle of elitism; a champagne toast to what they believe is carried out with a profound sense of glee evident on the faces of most of those present, but a wry peek at Gaston's facial expression amidst the extravagance and so-forth as everyone takes a sip reveals someone in deeper thought about this way of life than any of the others. In a film rich in colour; set decoration and faux-romanticism, best surmised when that wily rouge Honor&eacute; keeps getting his recollections shot down as he recalls decades-ago interludes with women now of his age, the film is deathly efficient in targeting people wanting out and away or something else anew. Many of the musical numbers work well, with one in which Gaston struggles with the coming to terms on how he feels for Gigi particularly standing out in memory, and the film generally pulls us in with its overlying juxtaposition of mise-en-scene with interior thematics; a deconstructing and retelling of stories of those within consummately seeing it home.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Enjoyable, but a wasted opportunity...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BlueEyes72
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gigi (Leslie Caron) is a young girl living in Paris in 1900, and being raised by her grandmother and great aunt to be a courtesan. Gaston (Louis Jourdan) is a rich Parisian playboy, who has become bored of his superficial lifestyle. He and Gigi have a platonic friendship, but as she becomes more sophisticated and grown up, the dynamic of their relationship starts to change This film, based on the novel by French author Colette, was not the last musical released by the MGM studios, but it was the last musical made by the Arthur Freed Unit at MGM (this unit was responsible for many of the classic musicals of the day, including Easter Parade, An American in Paris, and of course, Singin' In The Rain). The unit's swansong did very well, being nominated for nine Oscar awards, and winning all of them, breaking the then record of eight Oscars, held by Gone With The Wind. I thought the film was good, but not great. Some parts of it definitely worked  Leslie Caron was a delight as Gigi. I was not convinced by her performance in An American In Paris (although I l0ve An American In Paris and never get bored of watching it), but here she was great, and actually rather adorable. Audrey Hepburn was originally picked to play the part (having played Gigi on stage before she was famous), but due to other filming commitments, she was not available. Audrey is one of my favourite actresses, and I think she would have been perfect in the role, but Leslie Caron really worked well. Louis Jourdan was also great as the cynical and bored Gaston  making what could have been rather a dislikeable character into someone who the viewer liked a lot. Hermione Gingold and Isabel Jeans provided good support as Gigi's grandmother and great aunt. There were some lovely songs, in particular the title number sung by Louis Jourdan as he wanders throughout Paris, realising that his feelings for Gigi are changing; and the incredibly catchy The Night They Invented Champagne which I couldn't get out of my head after watching the film. Paris itself looks fabulous  most of the film was shot on location there, and it really is a lovely setting, very colourful and pretty. There were some parts that I didn't like  Maurice Chevalier's character Honore (the uncle of Gaston) seemed an unnecessary and distasteful character. This is no criticism of Chevalier's acting, which was fine, but the character was hard for me to warm to. In one scene Honore is highly delighted upon hearing that a former girlfriend of Gaston's has tried to kill herself after he ended her relationship. Honore toasts Gaston and says that he hopes this will be the first of many suicides. It may have been written flippantly, but this scene did not sit well with me. (Indeed the whole storyline of two women training their young relation to be a courtesan could be distasteful, although it was handled fairly well and with humour.) I was also slightly disappointed that there was no dancing in this film! I love to see fabulous dancing in musicals, and with Leslie Caron being an excellent ballet dancer, it feels like a missed opportunity not to show off her skills. Overall then, it's an enjoyable film, but ultimately a forgettable one. Worth watching for fans of musicals.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gee its grand to watch Gigi over and over, a film my sisters and I have adored from childhood
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Amy Adler
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In Paris, during the middle of the 19th century, handsome Gaston (Louis Jordan) is a sugar empire heir with a great deal of money. Like his father, Honore (Maurice Chevalier), he has shunned marriage in favor of having a succession of beautiful women. His present love, Lianne (Eva Gabor) is certainly pretty. But, as Gaston relates in song, he is truly bored with his lofty position in society, with women, and with parties. The only place he feels comfortable is at the home of an old friend (and former flame of Honore's), Mamita (Hermione Gingold). Odd it is, because the dear lady is rather poor and lives in an unfashionable neighborhood with her opera singing daughter AND her vivacious granddaughter, Gigi (Leslie Caron). Although she is in her middle teen years, Gigi is still treated by Gaston and her grandmama as a little girl and, in truth, she still acts as one, being very innocent and wide-eyed. Gaston loves eating Mamita's great cooking and playing cards with Gigi, away from the social scene. Unhappily, the sugar king soon finds that his "lady love" has been unfaithful and he makes a very publicized break with Lianne. To boost his spirits and pay off a card game debt to Gigi, Gaston, Mamita, and Gigi all go to the seashore for a vacation. They have a great time. But, Mamita's sister, also a former courtesan, wishes to change things when the trio returns to Paris. She sees that Gigi is really a young woman and, perhaps, they have a chance to offer her up as Gaston's next courtesan? She'd be well taken care of that's for certain. The only problem is that Gigi may not want to become the kind of woman who gets "passed around" but, rather, might want to be married and have children. What will the next season bring? Gee willikers is Gigi a pleasure to watch, as I and my sisters have done since our sixties' childhood. A musical, it nevertheless has enough non-musical action to satisfy those who don't particularly care for the genre. However, the songs are lovely and integral to the plot. Then, the acting is great, with Caron, Jordan, Chevalier, Ginggold and all of the others being near perfect in their respective roles. Also, the Paris setting, the terrific costumes, the lovely photography, and the superb direction by Vincente Minelli all contribute to the movie's enjoyment. It was awarded an Academy Award as best picture in 1958 and deservedly so. With that fact in mind, why not seek out Gigi ASAP?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "A gigantic, romantic clich&eacute;"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steffi_P
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There was a wave of stage-to-screen adaptations of hit musicals in the mid-1950s, translating the work of the two celebrated theatrical duos Rodgers and Hammerstein and Lerner and Loewe for a new audience. However this Arthur Freed production moves the other way, as Alan Jay Lerner and Frederick Loewe were hired by MGM to create a musical directly for the cinema, a sign perhaps that Broadway was beginning to take its rival more seriously. The result is in many ways an elaborately cinematic affair. Gigi takes advantage of the medium, having for example Maurice Chevalier break that pesky fourth wall and address the audience eye-to-eye, in reference to his screen musicals of the early 30s. We also have, in "She Is Not Thinking of Me", a song done in voice-over as an internal monologue  not, I believe, an original idea but certainly one that would be impossible (or at least very awkward) on the stage. As in their recent stage success My Fair Lady, Lerner and Loewe's songwriting is led by the lyrics, with a number like "It's a Bore" playing out like a musical conversation, with Loewe's melody skittering along to Lerner's vibrant wordplay. Their songs often serve to define character and relationships between characters. "It's a Bore" and "I Don't Understand the Parisians" are companion pieces as it were, and their similarities set up Gigi and Gaston as kindred spirits. Still, there are only a handful of really great numbers here ("The Night they Invented Champagne" being the standout), and one can't help getting the impression that Gigi is made up of cast-offs from the perfect My Fair Lady score. The lavishness of an Arthur Freed production ensured that his musicals were as much about look as they were sound. Gigi represents an astounding collaboration between cinematographer Joseph Ruttenberg, production designer Cecil Beaton and director Vincente Minnelli to reproduce the quality of fin-de-siecle painting, especially that of Auguste Renoir. The deliberate use of unfocused backgrounds in the opening scene is one of the best ever recreations of the impressionist style on screen. Minnelli (himself a keen painter) has a fine handling of perspective. Take the scene where Leslie Caron and Louis Jourdan are shelling peas. There is a chair in the foreground on the left-hand side, while on the right there is an open doorway into the kitchen. This contrast between closeness on one side and distance on the other not only adds real definition to the space, it allows the eye to be easily drawn from one end of the frame to the other, keeping Hermione Gingold highlighted even though she is in the background without having to resort to lots of obtrusive cutting. This is just one example, but it's a trick Minnelli pulls in almost every shot. The production is extremely lucky to have three genuine French stars for its principle parts, especially ones who were familiar enough with Hollywood to give an acceptable impression of Frenchness. Leslie Caron does a very credible job of playing a young girl on the verge of womanhood (she was in reality twenty-six) in a comically playful turn. Louis Jourdan is a little bland but by all means likable, and besides it suits him to look a little flat to all the better show off co-stars Caron and Chevalier. Ah oui, monsieur Chevalier, a man who is to an authentic portrayal of France what a crate of absinthe is to a light soiree. But for all his over-the-topness, he is great fun, slipping on the character of the ageing Lothario like an old glove. And those Lerner and Loewe songs like "I Remember It Well", where normal speech dovetails into singing, suit him very well. But while Gigi contains much to delight, as a whole it is lacking something. There just doesn't seem to be the heart or substance to the telling of the story that other Oscar-winning musicals have. Loewe in particular was reportedly reluctant to work in cinema, and both he and Lerner were overruled on a few decisions such as casting and inclusion of certain songs, so perhaps this explains the below-par score. Unsurprisingly it was a flop when adapted for the stage fifteen years later. Such is the care that has gone into those wonderful images, Gigi is far more a treat for the eyes than the ears, a coup were this purely a purely visual medium, but it falls some way short of being a superlative musical.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unintentionally creepy, with only one standout song
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Conrad
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A musical with only two memorable songs ("Thank Heaven for Little Girls" and "It's a Bore"), only one of which is good ("It's a Bore"), is not likely to be a good musical. Indeed, this is one of the most boring and poorly-acted in the history of the genre. The story ostensibly takes place in France, but it seems to unfold mainly in bland, claustrophobic drawing rooms. The title character's naive, youthful waifishness makes the relationship aspect of the film feel vaguely inappropriate, and this is only underscored by the aforementioned song about little girls, which is sung by a quintessentially creepy old man. This is a contender for worst Best Picture winner.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I Remembered It Wrong....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mark.waltz
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I first saw "Gigi" as a teenager, I was bewitched by its lavish costumes, sumptuous sets and delightful score, but in repeat viewings of it, I had to rank it as an overrated disappointment. Now some 25 years later, I watched it again, and while I don't consider it a perfect film (one worthy of a Best Picture Oscar), I do see it in a different light and appreciated it a bit more, taking my rating up from a 5 to an 8, **1/2 to ***1/2 on the Maltin scale. The days of living like Paris in the early 1900's are long gone, but it is certainly nice to re-visit them and the sweet duet between the aging Maurice Chevalier and Hermoine Gingold, the two scene-stealers of this film. Chevalier isn't the leading man he once was; In fact, Louis Jourdan, playing a part that Chevalier might have portrayed at Paramount during the early 1930's, doesn't seem quite up to the assignment, even if he is handsome, charming and well to do. Leslie Caron, however, does win in the title role, replacing Audrey Hepburn (from the stage productions) and being totally likable, especially when she sings "I Don't Understand the Parisians". Watching her grow from somewhat innocent teen to sophisticated young lady isn't quite like Hepburn going from guttersnipe to sophisticate in "My Fair Lady", even if the stories have a lot in common. The musical score has some bright moments, but some of the songs aren't as memorable as Lerner and Lowe's stage songs. The title song, in particular, suffers from some weak lyrics, and that defuses the dramatic impact of what it is trying to do. But when Chevalier and Gingold get together to reminisce in "I Remember It Well" and Gingold dances around with Jordan and Caron to "The Night They Invented Champagne", magic is made. Chevalier has a sly wink as the aging Honore, and in his relatively few scenes is the glue which holds the movie together. In smaller roles, Eva Gabor (as a two-timing lover of Jordan's) and Isabel Jeans (as the courtesan sister of Gingold) offer sophisticated bitchery. Gingold, a magic performer in everything she does, could be funny just looking around, and you wonder if her much later Broadway character of Madame Armfeldt in "A Little Night Music" could be a distant cousin of the family's. Superbly put together by the master of art in MGM musicals (Vincent Minnelli), "Gigi" can be appreciated more in repeat viewings as you get older, but some slow dramatic spots really cause it to drag a bit. That is minor, however, as this French creme pastry is lovely to look at, even though it may not entirely fill you up.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the most beautifully presented Musicals of all time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Koundinya
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The first time i watched the movie, i felt it was a "bore". The movie hardly has any running time of the character Gigi. The characters were melodramatic and their language was a butchered version of English. I never found the most vital element of Humor missing in the movie and was totally let down after having watched musicals like Singin' in the Rain and Wizard of Oz. Well, it was quite a long time back. I must agree i matured as a person who understands movie and appreciates it and not merely judge a movie based on its efficacy in entertaining. The movie is undoubtedly an entertainer. As the movie progressed, i started to understand the uniqueness of the movie and was enthralled by the songs and art setting. The movie is set in Paris at the turn of the century and the lifestyle, sartorial, marital and tonsorial preferences of the inhabitants is discreetly presented. The songs are brilliantly written and set to euphonious background music and when i paid heed to the lyrics, i realized what i greatly missed the first time i watched it- Humor. The movie also brings forth a message that no matter how rich and famous a man is, his heart remains vacant for a woman who remains herself and not be camouflaged with book-learned principles on satisfying a man.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    6.9?!?!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Gigi" won more Oscars than almost any other film in history. Yet, very oddly, it currently has an IMDb score of only 6.9! This makes no sense--especially since the film is magnificent throughout. The film is based on the story by Colette. It's about a sweet young lady, Gigi, and her family's insane intention of turning her into a very high-priced mistress to the rich and famous. However, because Gigi is so sweet, she just can't allow herself to have such a life and she insists on more--which causes problems with the man she loves (Louis Jourdan). While the plot is very simple (as it often is with musicals), the film works magnificently for several reasons. Most importantly, the Lerner and Lowe songs are among the best of any musical and are very memorable. In addition, the acting is so nice--and Leslie Caron is radiant and at her very best. Additionally, the film is just gorgeous--and replicates the grandeur of Paris circa 1900. Why this film has such a current mediocre score is beyond me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Curiously, no dancing...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dave from Ottawa
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Big Hollywood Musical genre in the 1950s was paved with ever more elaborate dance production numbers due to the popularity of stars like Gene Kelly, Fred Astaire and Cyd Charisse and yet rather curiously the ballet-trained Leslie Caron does not dance in this one and neither does anybody else. Still, 19th century Paris (the parks, the boulevards, Maxim's, the Follies etc.) is lavishly re-created, the costume designs are marvelous and the Lerner and Lowe songs are very good, if somewhat static in their presentation. The story is almost lighter than air, something about Caron reluctantly being groomed as a chic courtesan, but there is only enough to plot the keep things moving ahead as the camera tracks through or peeks into one gorgeously designed Parisian backdrop after another. The picture remains an old fashioned charmer thanks to million pretty things to look at and winning performances by Caron and especially Maurice Chevalier as an older rogue tutoring younger Louis Jourdan.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    At least I got 15 min sleep near the end
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    frankf-10
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I had seen this before years ago, but only could remember that it didn't impress me much. My wife selected the DVD via Netflix and 20 minutes into the film, all I could say to her was, "When is this movie going to start?" Slow moving hardly describes it. And Gaston repeating endlessly how boring things were for him hardly seems a way to entertain. I have never been much of a Maurice Chevalier fan and seeing him, as others have noted, oogling young girls in this flick is definitely weird now. Reading through reviews here, I was reminded how many Academy Awards it won - yikes! The Academy BS I can almost understand, but why IMDb reviewers found this leaden clunker so terrific is beyond me. Thank gawd I did get some shuteye toward the end.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Colourful character study which does remarkably well with two people crashing head first into a newfound state of thinking in regards to a chauvinistic lifestyle.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    johnnyboyz (j_l_h_m@yahoo.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gigi is a film about a young female protagonist asked to fall in with a highly specific male crowd; a crowd of whom carry with them the idea that something called "gender patriotism" consists of the wrecking of a woman's life, if she should ever leave you, by using your deep pockets of filthy wealth to buy off the man for whom she left you and convince him to leave town so that she is thus rendered totally heartbroken. If they suffer, why should't she? The men within this clique celebrate such an ideology, laughing and joking with one another; even taking time to indulge in speaking of the living by such rules with their barber, whom appears equally as enthused by such behaviour. On one occasion, it even led to the attempted suicide of one of those women  ah, well. But the film is not as it sounds, and will go on to cover this young female protagonist as well as her consequent frustrations out of trying to reject, or steer clear of, such an ill-gotten series of men and their livelihoods; the film eventually forming a piece about character we pray can find some sort of common-ground amidst what they exist - the film eventually an exuberant; careful piece treading along a fine line of bourgeoises indulgence and materialistic exploitation that comes together and actually works. The film unfolds in Paris; the year-clock in the French capital registering 1900. Leslie Caron plays the titular Gigi and that young protagonist slowly but surely being taught and groomed into falling in with a man to whom she may be able to act politely; overtly eloquently and essentially become the drone-wife that speaks when spoken to and laughs at her husband and his rich friend's anecdotes on prompt  after having brought out the tea for them, of course. But Gigi has an edge to her; a certain 'bite' and she is a faster and looser girl to that of what her contemporaries would like. In spite of being born into a fairly rich family, Gigi wishes not to head down a route of snobbery and such; instead, draws on inspiration from her mother - someone whom wanted more than what was offered, although someone, as her grandmother points out, whom chased a dream and failed to amount to what it was she desired when menial work at an opera house was the end product. In spite of this warning, as well as her grandmother's dismissive or hopeful tone that she will fail, we find it easy to get behind her. The man with whom she will come to interact a great deal more throughout is Louis Jourdan's Gaston Lachaille, the nephew of an elderly man named Honor&eacute; (Chevalier), whose attitudes towards women both now and throughout his life have been false and somewhat hate-filled although distilled through a filter of deft tones and extravagance. When we begin with him, he speaks to us on how he classifies his life profession as "lover" and we are drawn into a romanticised tone complimenting the sort of lifestyle in which a man like Honor&eacute; may waltz down a public street harbouring the opinions he has on the opposite sex. If we react as strongly as we ought to, our alignment with Gigi slips even easier into happening as she herself attempts to reject a kind of coercement director Vincente Minnelli attempts to relate onto that of the audience during the opening beats. Like Gigi, Gaston faces a seeping influence agonisingly trickling down from his peers and relations in regards to lifestyle choices and attitudes towards the other gender. Unlike most of his ilk, Gaston is fed up with the predominant items available and desires a change from socialite holidays to nations such as Italy and Spain, as well as the finer things on offer in Paris in the form of wines and such; something established through one of the film's many delightful musical numbers and a reoccurring quote throughout of "it's a bore" confirming this. Life for Gigi has reached a point in which honing skills in acting the socialite-come-snob for interactions should be the norm; the girl ambitious, and rather well off before this transitional phase, but her statements reiterating that she "doesn't understand Parisians" and that "there must be more to life than this" firmly establish her alienation to not only where she is, but the sorts of people with which she bonds. Primarily, these two characters coming together after seeking immense change from the patriarchal norm drives the film; Gaston's fondness for Gigi not equalled by her still prejudiced thinking when she deems him just as bad as anyone else in this messy cesspit of socialisation. One of the subtler moments of Jourdan's performance, going on neatly to project how he feels on what surrounds him, lies in the scene during which he loiters with his fellow men in that fatuous circle of elitism; a champagne toast to what they believe is carried out with a profound sense of glee evident on the faces of most of those present, but a wry peek at Gaston's facial expression amidst the extravagance and so-forth as everyone takes a sip reveals someone in deeper thought about this way of life than any of the others. In a film rich in colour; set decoration and faux-romanticism, best surmised when that wily rouge Honor&eacute; keeps getting his recollections shot down as he recalls decades-ago interludes with women now of his age, the film is deathly efficient in targeting people wanting out and away or something else anew. Many of the musical numbers work well, with one in which Gaston struggles with the coming to terms on how he feels for Gigi particularly standing out in memory, and the film generally pulls us in with its overlying juxtaposition of mise-en-scene with interior thematics; a deconstructing and retelling of stories of those within consummately seeing it home.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Enjoyable, but a wasted opportunity...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BlueEyes72
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gigi (Leslie Caron) is a young girl living in Paris in 1900, and being raised by her grandmother and great aunt to be a courtesan. Gaston (Louis Jourdan) is a rich Parisian playboy, who has become bored of his superficial lifestyle. He and Gigi have a platonic friendship, but as she becomes more sophisticated and grown up, the dynamic of their relationship starts to change This film, based on the novel by French author Colette, was not the last musical released by the MGM studios, but it was the last musical made by the Arthur Freed Unit at MGM (this unit was responsible for many of the classic musicals of the day, including Easter Parade, An American in Paris, and of course, Singin' In The Rain). The unit's swansong did very well, being nominated for nine Oscar awards, and winning all of them, breaking the then record of eight Oscars, held by Gone With The Wind. I thought the film was good, but not great. Some parts of it definitely worked  Leslie Caron was a delight as Gigi. I was not convinced by her performance in An American In Paris (although I l0ve An American In Paris and never get bored of watching it), but here she was great, and actually rather adorable. Audrey Hepburn was originally picked to play the part (having played Gigi on stage before she was famous), but due to other filming commitments, she was not available. Audrey is one of my favourite actresses, and I think she would have been perfect in the role, but Leslie Caron really worked well. Louis Jourdan was also great as the cynical and bored Gaston  making what could have been rather a dislikeable character into someone who the viewer liked a lot. Hermione Gingold and Isabel Jeans provided good support as Gigi's grandmother and great aunt. There were some lovely songs, in particular the title number sung by Louis Jourdan as he wanders throughout Paris, realising that his feelings for Gigi are changing; and the incredibly catchy The Night They Invented Champagne which I couldn't get out of my head after watching the film. Paris itself looks fabulous  most of the film was shot on location there, and it really is a lovely setting, very colourful and pretty. There were some parts that I didn't like  Maurice Chevalier's character Honore (the uncle of Gaston) seemed an unnecessary and distasteful character. This is no criticism of Chevalier's acting, which was fine, but the character was hard for me to warm to. In one scene Honore is highly delighted upon hearing that a former girlfriend of Gaston's has tried to kill herself after he ended her relationship. Honore toasts Gaston and says that he hopes this will be the first of many suicides. It may have been written flippantly, but this scene did not sit well with me. (Indeed the whole storyline of two women training their young relation to be a courtesan could be distasteful, although it was handled fairly well and with humour.) I was also slightly disappointed that there was no dancing in this film! I love to see fabulous dancing in musicals, and with Leslie Caron being an excellent ballet dancer, it feels like a missed opportunity not to show off her skills. Overall then, it's an enjoyable film, but ultimately a forgettable one. Worth watching for fans of musicals.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gee its grand to watch Gigi over and over, a film my sisters and I have adored from childhood
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Amy Adler
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In Paris, during the middle of the 19th century, handsome Gaston (Louis Jordan) is a sugar empire heir with a great deal of money. Like his father, Honore (Maurice Chevalier), he has shunned marriage in favor of having a succession of beautiful women. His present love, Lianne (Eva Gabor) is certainly pretty. But, as Gaston relates in song, he is truly bored with his lofty position in society, with women, and with parties. The only place he feels comfortable is at the home of an old friend (and former flame of Honore's), Mamita (Hermione Gingold). Odd it is, because the dear lady is rather poor and lives in an unfashionable neighborhood with her opera singing daughter AND her vivacious granddaughter, Gigi (Leslie Caron). Although she is in her middle teen years, Gigi is still treated by Gaston and her grandmama as a little girl and, in truth, she still acts as one, being very innocent and wide-eyed. Gaston loves eating Mamita's great cooking and playing cards with Gigi, away from the social scene. Unhappily, the sugar king soon finds that his "lady love" has been unfaithful and he makes a very publicized break with Lianne. To boost his spirits and pay off a card game debt to Gigi, Gaston, Mamita, and Gigi all go to the seashore for a vacation. They have a great time. But, Mamita's sister, also a former courtesan, wishes to change things when the trio returns to Paris. She sees that Gigi is really a young woman and, perhaps, they have a chance to offer her up as Gaston's next courtesan? She'd be well taken care of that's for certain. The only problem is that Gigi may not want to become the kind of woman who gets "passed around" but, rather, might want to be married and have children. What will the next season bring? Gee willikers is Gigi a pleasure to watch, as I and my sisters have done since our sixties' childhood. A musical, it nevertheless has enough non-musical action to satisfy those who don't particularly care for the genre. However, the songs are lovely and integral to the plot. Then, the acting is great, with Caron, Jordan, Chevalier, Ginggold and all of the others being near perfect in their respective roles. Also, the Paris setting, the terrific costumes, the lovely photography, and the superb direction by Vincente Minelli all contribute to the movie's enjoyment. It was awarded an Academy Award as best picture in 1958 and deservedly so. With that fact in mind, why not seek out Gigi ASAP?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "A gigantic, romantic clich&eacute;"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steffi_P
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There was a wave of stage-to-screen adaptations of hit musicals in the mid-1950s, translating the work of the two celebrated theatrical duos Rodgers and Hammerstein and Lerner and Loewe for a new audience. However this Arthur Freed production moves the other way, as Alan Jay Lerner and Frederick Loewe were hired by MGM to create a musical directly for the cinema, a sign perhaps that Broadway was beginning to take its rival more seriously. The result is in many ways an elaborately cinematic affair. Gigi takes advantage of the medium, having for example Maurice Chevalier break that pesky fourth wall and address the audience eye-to-eye, in reference to his screen musicals of the early 30s. We also have, in "She Is Not Thinking of Me", a song done in voice-over as an internal monologue  not, I believe, an original idea but certainly one that would be impossible (or at least very awkward) on the stage. As in their recent stage success My Fair Lady, Lerner and Loewe's songwriting is led by the lyrics, with a number like "It's a Bore" playing out like a musical conversation, with Loewe's melody skittering along to Lerner's vibrant wordplay. Their songs often serve to define character and relationships between characters. "It's a Bore" and "I Don't Understand the Parisians" are companion pieces as it were, and their similarities set up Gigi and Gaston as kindred spirits. Still, there are only a handful of really great numbers here ("The Night they Invented Champagne" being the standout), and one can't help getting the impression that Gigi is made up of cast-offs from the perfect My Fair Lady score. The lavishness of an Arthur Freed production ensured that his musicals were as much about look as they were sound. Gigi represents an astounding collaboration between cinematographer Joseph Ruttenberg, production designer Cecil Beaton and director Vincente Minnelli to reproduce the quality of fin-de-siecle painting, especially that of Auguste Renoir. The deliberate use of unfocused backgrounds in the opening scene is one of the best ever recreations of the impressionist style on screen. Minnelli (himself a keen painter) has a fine handling of perspective. Take the scene where Leslie Caron and Louis Jourdan are shelling peas. There is a chair in the foreground on the left-hand side, while on the right there is an open doorway into the kitchen. This contrast between closeness on one side and distance on the other not only adds real definition to the space, it allows the eye to be easily drawn from one end of the frame to the other, keeping Hermione Gingold highlighted even though she is in the background without having to resort to lots of obtrusive cutting. This is just one example, but it's a trick Minnelli pulls in almost every shot. The production is extremely lucky to have three genuine French stars for its principle parts, especially ones who were familiar enough with Hollywood to give an acceptable impression of Frenchness. Leslie Caron does a very credible job of playing a young girl on the verge of womanhood (she was in reality twenty-six) in a comically playful turn. Louis Jourdan is a little bland but by all means likable, and besides it suits him to look a little flat to all the better show off co-stars Caron and Chevalier. Ah oui, monsieur Chevalier, a man who is to an authentic portrayal of France what a crate of absinthe is to a light soiree. But for all his over-the-topness, he is great fun, slipping on the character of the ageing Lothario like an old glove. And those Lerner and Loewe songs like "I Remember It Well", where normal speech dovetails into singing, suit him very well. But while Gigi contains much to delight, as a whole it is lacking something. There just doesn't seem to be the heart or substance to the telling of the story that other Oscar-winning musicals have. Loewe in particular was reportedly reluctant to work in cinema, and both he and Lerner were overruled on a few decisions such as casting and inclusion of certain songs, so perhaps this explains the below-par score. Unsurprisingly it was a flop when adapted for the stage fifteen years later. Such is the care that has gone into those wonderful images, Gigi is far more a treat for the eyes than the ears, a coup were this purely a purely visual medium, but it falls some way short of being a superlative musical.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unintentionally creepy, with only one standout song
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Conrad
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A musical with only two memorable songs ("Thank Heaven for Little Girls" and "It's a Bore"), only one of which is good ("It's a Bore"), is not likely to be a good musical. Indeed, this is one of the most boring and poorly-acted in the history of the genre. The story ostensibly takes place in France, but it seems to unfold mainly in bland, claustrophobic drawing rooms. The title character's naive, youthful waifishness makes the relationship aspect of the film feel vaguely inappropriate, and this is only underscored by the aforementioned song about little girls, which is sung by a quintessentially creepy old man. This is a contender for worst Best Picture winner.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I Remembered It Wrong....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mark.waltz
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I first saw "Gigi" as a teenager, I was bewitched by its lavish costumes, sumptuous sets and delightful score, but in repeat viewings of it, I had to rank it as an overrated disappointment. Now some 25 years later, I watched it again, and while I don't consider it a perfect film (one worthy of a Best Picture Oscar), I do see it in a different light and appreciated it a bit more, taking my rating up from a 5 to an 8, **1/2 to ***1/2 on the Maltin scale. The days of living like Paris in the early 1900's are long gone, but it is certainly nice to re-visit them and the sweet duet between the aging Maurice Chevalier and Hermoine Gingold, the two scene-stealers of this film. Chevalier isn't the leading man he once was; In fact, Louis Jourdan, playing a part that Chevalier might have portrayed at Paramount during the early 1930's, doesn't seem quite up to the assignment, even if he is handsome, charming and well to do. Leslie Caron, however, does win in the title role, replacing Audrey Hepburn (from the stage productions) and being totally likable, especially when she sings "I Don't Understand the Parisians". Watching her grow from somewhat innocent teen to sophisticated young lady isn't quite like Hepburn going from guttersnipe to sophisticate in "My Fair Lady", even if the stories have a lot in common. The musical score has some bright moments, but some of the songs aren't as memorable as Lerner and Lowe's stage songs. The title song, in particular, suffers from some weak lyrics, and that defuses the dramatic impact of what it is trying to do. But when Chevalier and Gingold get together to reminisce in "I Remember It Well" and Gingold dances around with Jordan and Caron to "The Night They Invented Champagne", magic is made. Chevalier has a sly wink as the aging Honore, and in his relatively few scenes is the glue which holds the movie together. In smaller roles, Eva Gabor (as a two-timing lover of Jordan's) and Isabel Jeans (as the courtesan sister of Gingold) offer sophisticated bitchery. Gingold, a magic performer in everything she does, could be funny just looking around, and you wonder if her much later Broadway character of Madame Armfeldt in "A Little Night Music" could be a distant cousin of the family's. Superbly put together by the master of art in MGM musicals (Vincent Minnelli), "Gigi" can be appreciated more in repeat viewings as you get older, but some slow dramatic spots really cause it to drag a bit. That is minor, however, as this French creme pastry is lovely to look at, even though it may not entirely fill you up.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the most beautifully presented Musicals of all time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Koundinya
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The first time i watched the movie, i felt it was a "bore". The movie hardly has any running time of the character Gigi. The characters were melodramatic and their language was a butchered version of English. I never found the most vital element of Humor missing in the movie and was totally let down after having watched musicals like Singin' in the Rain and Wizard of Oz. Well, it was quite a long time back. I must agree i matured as a person who understands movie and appreciates it and not merely judge a movie based on its efficacy in entertaining. The movie is undoubtedly an entertainer. As the movie progressed, i started to understand the uniqueness of the movie and was enthralled by the songs and art setting. The movie is set in Paris at the turn of the century and the lifestyle, sartorial, marital and tonsorial preferences of the inhabitants is discreetly presented. The songs are brilliantly written and set to euphonious background music and when i paid heed to the lyrics, i realized what i greatly missed the first time i watched it- Humor. The movie also brings forth a message that no matter how rich and famous a man is, his heart remains vacant for a woman who remains herself and not be camouflaged with book-learned principles on satisfying a man.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    6.9?!?!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Gigi" won more Oscars than almost any other film in history. Yet, very oddly, it currently has an IMDb score of only 6.9! This makes no sense--especially since the film is magnificent throughout. The film is based on the story by Colette. It's about a sweet young lady, Gigi, and her family's insane intention of turning her into a very high-priced mistress to the rich and famous. However, because Gigi is so sweet, she just can't allow herself to have such a life and she insists on more--which causes problems with the man she loves (Louis Jourdan). While the plot is very simple (as it often is with musicals), the film works magnificently for several reasons. Most importantly, the Lerner and Lowe songs are among the best of any musical and are very memorable. In addition, the acting is so nice--and Leslie Caron is radiant and at her very best. Additionally, the film is just gorgeous--and replicates the grandeur of Paris circa 1900. Why this film has such a current mediocre score is beyond me.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Curiously, no dancing...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dave from Ottawa
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Big Hollywood Musical genre in the 1950s was paved with ever more elaborate dance production numbers due to the popularity of stars like Gene Kelly, Fred Astaire and Cyd Charisse and yet rather curiously the ballet-trained Leslie Caron does not dance in this one and neither does anybody else. Still, 19th century Paris (the parks, the boulevards, Maxim's, the Follies etc.) is lavishly re-created, the costume designs are marvelous and the Lerner and Lowe songs are very good, if somewhat static in their presentation. The story is almost lighter than air, something about Caron reluctantly being groomed as a chic courtesan, but there is only enough to plot the keep things moving ahead as the camera tracks through or peeks into one gorgeously designed Parisian backdrop after another. The picture remains an old fashioned charmer thanks to million pretty things to look at and winning performances by Caron and especially Maurice Chevalier as an older rogue tutoring younger Louis Jourdan.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    At least I got 15 min sleep near the end
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    frankf-10
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I had seen this before years ago, but only could remember that it didn't impress me much. My wife selected the DVD via Netflix and 20 minutes into the film, all I could say to her was, "When is this movie going to start?" Slow moving hardly describes it. And Gaston repeating endlessly how boring things were for him hardly seems a way to entertain. I have never been much of a Maurice Chevalier fan and seeing him, as others have noted, oogling young girls in this flick is definitely weird now. Reading through reviews here, I was reminded how many Academy Awards it won - yikes! The Academy BS I can almost understand, but why IMDb reviewers found this leaden clunker so terrific is beyond me. Thank gawd I did get some shuteye toward the end.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Colourful character study which does remarkably well with two people crashing head first into a newfound state of thinking in regards to a chauvinistic lifestyle.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    johnnyboyz (j_l_h_m@yahoo.co.uk)
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gigi is a film about a young female protagonist asked to fall in with a highly specific male crowd; a crowd of whom carry with them the idea that something called "gender patriotism" consists of the wrecking of a woman's life, if she should ever leave you, by using your deep pockets of filthy wealth to buy off the man for whom she left you and convince him to leave town so that she is thus rendered totally heartbroken. If they suffer, why should't she? The men within this clique celebrate such an ideology, laughing and joking with one another; even taking time to indulge in speaking of the living by such rules with their barber, whom appears equally as enthused by such behaviour. On one occasion, it even led to the attempted suicide of one of those women  ah, well. But the film is not as it sounds, and will go on to cover this young female protagonist as well as her consequent frustrations out of trying to reject, or steer clear of, such an ill-gotten series of men and their livelihoods; the film eventually forming a piece about character we pray can find some sort of common-ground amidst what they exist - the film eventually an exuberant; careful piece treading along a fine line of bourgeoises indulgence and materialistic exploitation that comes together and actually works. The film unfolds in Paris; the year-clock in the French capital registering 1900. Leslie Caron plays the titular Gigi and that young protagonist slowly but surely being taught and groomed into falling in with a man to whom she may be able to act politely; overtly eloquently and essentially become the drone-wife that speaks when spoken to and laughs at her husband and his rich friend's anecdotes on prompt  after having brought out the tea for them, of course. But Gigi has an edge to her; a certain 'bite' and she is a faster and looser girl to that of what her contemporaries would like. In spite of being born into a fairly rich family, Gigi wishes not to head down a route of snobbery and such; instead, draws on inspiration from her mother - someone whom wanted more than what was offered, although someone, as her grandmother points out, whom chased a dream and failed to amount to what it was she desired when menial work at an opera house was the end product. In spite of this warning, as well as her grandmother's dismissive or hopeful tone that she will fail, we find it easy to get behind her. The man with whom she will come to interact a great deal more throughout is Louis Jourdan's Gaston Lachaille, the nephew of an elderly man named Honor&eacute; (Chevalier), whose attitudes towards women both now and throughout his life have been false and somewhat hate-filled although distilled through a filter of deft tones and extravagance. When we begin with him, he speaks to us on how he classifies his life profession as "lover" and we are drawn into a romanticised tone complimenting the sort of lifestyle in which a man like Honor&eacute; may waltz down a public street harbouring the opinions he has on the opposite sex. If we react as strongly as we ought to, our alignment with Gigi slips even easier into happening as she herself attempts to reject a kind of coercement director Vincente Minnelli attempts to relate onto that of the audience during the opening beats. Like Gigi, Gaston faces a seeping influence agonisingly trickling down from his peers and relations in regards to lifestyle choices and attitudes towards the other gender. Unlike most of his ilk, Gaston is fed up with the predominant items available and desires a change from socialite holidays to nations such as Italy and Spain, as well as the finer things on offer in Paris in the form of wines and such; something established through one of the film's many delightful musical numbers and a reoccurring quote throughout of "it's a bore" confirming this. Life for Gigi has reached a point in which honing skills in acting the socialite-come-snob for interactions should be the norm; the girl ambitious, and rather well off before this transitional phase, but her statements reiterating that she "doesn't understand Parisians" and that "there must be more to life than this" firmly establish her alienation to not only where she is, but the sorts of people with which she bonds. Primarily, these two characters coming together after seeking immense change from the patriarchal norm drives the film; Gaston's fondness for Gigi not equalled by her still prejudiced thinking when she deems him just as bad as anyone else in this messy cesspit of socialisation. One of the subtler moments of Jourdan's performance, going on neatly to project how he feels on what surrounds him, lies in the scene during which he loiters with his fellow men in that fatuous circle of elitism; a champagne toast to what they believe is carried out with a profound sense of glee evident on the faces of most of those present, but a wry peek at Gaston's facial expression amidst the extravagance and so-forth as everyone takes a sip reveals someone in deeper thought about this way of life than any of the others. In a film rich in colour; set decoration and faux-romanticism, best surmised when that wily rouge Honor&eacute; keeps getting his recollections shot down as he recalls decades-ago interludes with women now of his age, the film is deathly efficient in targeting people wanting out and away or something else anew. Many of the musical numbers work well, with one in which Gaston struggles with the coming to terms on how he feels for Gigi particularly standing out in memory, and the film generally pulls us in with its overlying juxtaposition of mise-en-scene with interior thematics; a deconstructing and retelling of stories of those within consummately seeing it home.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Enjoyable, but a wasted opportunity...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    BlueEyes72
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gigi (Leslie Caron) is a young girl living in Paris in 1900, and being raised by her grandmother and great aunt to be a courtesan. Gaston (Louis Jourdan) is a rich Parisian playboy, who has become bored of his superficial lifestyle. He and Gigi have a platonic friendship, but as she becomes more sophisticated and grown up, the dynamic of their relationship starts to change This film, based on the novel by French author Colette, was not the last musical released by the MGM studios, but it was the last musical made by the Arthur Freed Unit at MGM (this unit was responsible for many of the classic musicals of the day, including Easter Parade, An American in Paris, and of course, Singin' In The Rain). The unit's swansong did very well, being nominated for nine Oscar awards, and winning all of them, breaking the then record of eight Oscars, held by Gone With The Wind. I thought the film was good, but not great. Some parts of it definitely worked  Leslie Caron was a delight as Gigi. I was not convinced by her performance in An American In Paris (although I l0ve An American In Paris and never get bored of watching it), but here she was great, and actually rather adorable. Audrey Hepburn was originally picked to play the part (having played Gigi on stage before she was famous), but due to other filming commitments, she was not available. Audrey is one of my favourite actresses, and I think she would have been perfect in the role, but Leslie Caron really worked well. Louis Jourdan was also great as the cynical and bored Gaston  making what could have been rather a dislikeable character into someone who the viewer liked a lot. Hermione Gingold and Isabel Jeans provided good support as Gigi's grandmother and great aunt. There were some lovely songs, in particular the title number sung by Louis Jourdan as he wanders throughout Paris, realising that his feelings for Gigi are changing; and the incredibly catchy The Night They Invented Champagne which I couldn't get out of my head after watching the film. Paris itself looks fabulous  most of the film was shot on location there, and it really is a lovely setting, very colourful and pretty. There were some parts that I didn't like  Maurice Chevalier's character Honore (the uncle of Gaston) seemed an unnecessary and distasteful character. This is no criticism of Chevalier's acting, which was fine, but the character was hard for me to warm to. In one scene Honore is highly delighted upon hearing that a former girlfriend of Gaston's has tried to kill herself after he ended her relationship. Honore toasts Gaston and says that he hopes this will be the first of many suicides. It may have been written flippantly, but this scene did not sit well with me. (Indeed the whole storyline of two women training their young relation to be a courtesan could be distasteful, although it was handled fairly well and with humour.) I was also slightly disappointed that there was no dancing in this film! I love to see fabulous dancing in musicals, and with Leslie Caron being an excellent ballet dancer, it feels like a missed opportunity not to show off her skills. Overall then, it's an enjoyable film, but ultimately a forgettable one. Worth watching for fans of musicals.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gee its grand to watch Gigi over and over, a film my sisters and I have adored from childhood
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Amy Adler
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In Paris, during the middle of the 19th century, handsome Gaston (Louis Jordan) is a sugar empire heir with a great deal of money. Like his father, Honore (Maurice Chevalier), he has shunned marriage in favor of having a succession of beautiful women. His present love, Lianne (Eva Gabor) is certainly pretty. But, as Gaston relates in song, he is truly bored with his lofty position in society, with women, and with parties. The only place he feels comfortable is at the home of an old friend (and former flame of Honore's), Mamita (Hermione Gingold). Odd it is, because the dear lady is rather poor and lives in an unfashionable neighborhood with her opera singing daughter AND her vivacious granddaughter, Gigi (Leslie Caron). Although she is in her middle teen years, Gigi is still treated by Gaston and her grandmama as a little girl and, in truth, she still acts as one, being very innocent and wide-eyed. Gaston loves eating Mamita's great cooking and playing cards with Gigi, away from the social scene. Unhappily, the sugar king soon finds that his "lady love" has been unfaithful and he makes a very publicized break with Lianne. To boost his spirits and pay off a card game debt to Gigi, Gaston, Mamita, and Gigi all go to the seashore for a vacation. They have a great time. But, Mamita's sister, also a former courtesan, wishes to change things when the trio returns to Paris. She sees that Gigi is really a young woman and, perhaps, they have a chance to offer her up as Gaston's next courtesan? She'd be well taken care of that's for certain. The only problem is that Gigi may not want to become the kind of woman who gets "passed around" but, rather, might want to be married and have children. What will the next season bring? Gee willikers is Gigi a pleasure to watch, as I and my sisters have done since our sixties' childhood. A musical, it nevertheless has enough non-musical action to satisfy those who don't particularly care for the genre. However, the songs are lovely and integral to the plot. Then, the acting is great, with Caron, Jordan, Chevalier, Ginggold and all of the others being near perfect in their respective roles. Also, the Paris setting, the terrific costumes, the lovely photography, and the superb direction by Vincente Minelli all contribute to the movie's enjoyment. It was awarded an Academy Award as best picture in 1958 and deservedly so. With that fact in mind, why not seek out Gigi ASAP?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "A gigantic, romantic clich&eacute;"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steffi_P
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There was a wave of stage-to-screen adaptations of hit musicals in the mid-1950s, translating the work of the two celebrated theatrical duos Rodgers and Hammerstein and Lerner and Loewe for a new audience. However this Arthur Freed production moves the other way, as Alan Jay Lerner and Frederick Loewe were hired by MGM to create a musical directly for the cinema, a sign perhaps that Broadway was beginning to take its rival more seriously. The result is in many ways an elaborately cinematic affair. Gigi takes advantage of the medium, having for example Maurice Chevalier break that pesky fourth wall and address the audience eye-to-eye, in reference to his screen musicals of the early 30s. We also have, in "She Is Not Thinking of Me", a song done in voice-over as an internal monologue  not, I believe, an original idea but certainly one that would be impossible (or at least very awkward) on the stage. As in their recent stage success My Fair Lady, Lerner and Loewe's songwriting is led by the lyrics, with a number like "It's a Bore" playing out like a musical conversation, with Loewe's melody skittering along to Lerner's vibrant wordplay. Their songs often serve to define character and relationships between characters. "It's a Bore" and "I Don't Understand the Parisians" are companion pieces as it were, and their similarities set up Gigi and Gaston as kindred spirits. Still, there are only a handful of really great numbers here ("The Night they Invented Champagne" being the standout), and one can't help getting the impression that Gigi is made up of cast-offs from the perfect My Fair Lady score. The lavishness of an Arthur Freed production ensured that his musicals were as much about look as they were sound. Gigi represents an astounding collaboration between cinematographer Joseph Ruttenberg, production designer Cecil Beaton and director Vincente Minnelli to reproduce the quality of fin-de-siecle painting, especially that of Auguste Renoir. The deliberate use of unfocused backgrounds in the opening scene is one of the best ever recreations of the impressionist style on screen. Minnelli (himself a keen painter) has a fine handling of perspective. Take the scene where Leslie Caron and Louis Jourdan are shelling peas. There is a chair in the foreground on the left-hand side, while on the right there is an open doorway into the kitchen. This contrast between closeness on one side and distance on the other not only adds real definition to the space, it allows the eye to be easily drawn from one end of the frame to the other, keeping Hermione Gingold highlighted even though she is in the background without having to resort to lots of obtrusive cutting. This is just one example, but it's a trick Minnelli pulls in almost every shot. The production is extremely lucky to have three genuine French stars for its principle parts, especially ones who were familiar enough with Hollywood to give an acceptable impression of Frenchness. Leslie Caron does a very credible job of playing a young girl on the verge of womanhood (she was in reality twenty-six) in a comically playful turn. Louis Jourdan is a little bland but by all means likable, and besides it suits him to look a little flat to all the better show off co-stars Caron and Chevalier. Ah oui, monsieur Chevalier, a man who is to an authentic portrayal of France what a crate of absinthe is to a light soiree. But for all his over-the-topness, he is great fun, slipping on the character of the ageing Lothario like an old glove. And those Lerner and Loewe songs like "I Remember It Well", where normal speech dovetails into singing, suit him very well. But while Gigi contains much to delight, as a whole it is lacking something. There just doesn't seem to be the heart or substance to the telling of the story that other Oscar-winning musicals have. Loewe in particular was reportedly reluctant to work in cinema, and both he and Lerner were overruled on a few decisions such as casting and inclusion of certain songs, so perhaps this explains the below-par score. Unsurprisingly it was a flop when adapted for the stage fifteen years later. Such is the care that has gone into those wonderful images, Gigi is far more a treat for the eyes than the ears, a coup were this purely a purely visual medium, but it falls some way short of being a superlative musical.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
