<filme>
 <id>
  616
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0063350
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1968
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  A Noite dos Mortos-Vivos
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  8.0
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  A group of people hide from bloodthirsty zombies in a farmhouse.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Barbra and her brother Johnny travel by car from Pittsburgh to the countryside to visit the gravestone of their father in the cemetery. Out of the blue, they are attacked by a strange man and Johnny is murdered. Barbra runs and releases the brake of Johnny's car since the keys are in his pocket, and flees to an isolated farmhouse, where she locks herself inside. Barbra is in shock and soon she finds a man, Ben, who is also escaping from the inhuman creatures and he reinforces the doors, windows and openings in the house. He also finds a shotgun and a radio and they learn that the radiation from a satellite that was returning from Venus has somehow reactivated the brain of the dead. Then they find five humans hidden in the basement: Harry Cooper, his wife Helen and their daughter Karen that is sick; and Tom and his girlfriend Judy. Harry has an argument with Ben, since he believes that the basement is the safest place for them and Harry goes not agree. Along the night, the tension ...
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Horror
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   farmhouse
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   grave
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   zombie
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   barricade
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   satellite
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   George A. Romero
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   John A. Russo
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   George A. Romero
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Duane Jones
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Judith O'Dea
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Karl Hardman
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wasn't too impressed by this horror classic, but it was an enjoyable film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bruno Youn
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A decent horror film overall, but I have to say it was a very uneven experience for me. While there are a few aspects I certainly enjoyed here, such as the effective scares, gruesome imagery and the shocking twist at the end, I thought the acting was stale at times and was pretty annoyed by the character of Helen. The film got too didactic and a bit tedious when they began to follow the announcements on TV. The explanation of the origins of the undead was very far-fetched for me and didn't really need to be here. Also, the zombies seemed to be inconsistent as some of them decide to chase people or kill them with objects when they have fresh meat to eat right beside them. Finally, I found many statements given by the characters to be quite obvious or even a bit ridiculous so that also took me out of the film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Grim & Influential.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    George Romero's infamous low budget horror film about the mysterious resurrection of hordes of the walking dead, who are compelled to kill, and consume, the living, became a huge underground hit that inspired a whole new sub genre of horror for those so inclined, not to mention a great many sequels, remakes, spin offs, etc. Though this is, on one level, a starkly effective shocker, the premise is so utterly preposterous, and tone so unmercifully grim and downbeat, with a horribly ironic ending, that it doesn't work for me. The acting is strong though, but film is dispiriting in the extreme, with little to recommend it, though it is a cult classic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This is where the long walk began...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MrGKB
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ...toward the contemporary zombie mythos of "The Walking Dead" and every cannibalistic living dead film in between. I first enjoyed "NotLD" on the big screen way back in the antediluvian days of college, pre- videotape/DVD/BluRay collections, pre-Internet, pre-Androids etal., when Romero's unassuming film was burning up the midnight film circuit and burrowing deep into the collective unconsciousness of horror fans and cinemaphiles everywhere. Little did I know at the time just how influential this little homegrown nightmare would prove to be, but there was no denying its raw power to shock and unsettle unsuspecting audiences, and all on a budget just somewhat above rock bottom. Imagine, if you will, several hundred Boomer college kids packed into a darkened auditorium, most of them likely intoxicated on one thing or another, all eager to see this scary movie that so far they'd only read about. They knew that Roger Ebert hated it, which only made it more alluring. They knew it pushed the boundaries of graphic depictions of murder, and that, too, made it all the more the forbidden fruit. And, perhaps most of all, they knew it wasn't a "Hollywood" movie, and that made its rising star all the brighter. Imagine now that very first viewing of that rough gem in all its lo-fi glory... Almost a half-century later, even the most forgiving retrospectives will admit to the film's flaws; only the most churlish could deny them. The acting is at times--to be polite--unpolished, and the make-up is simply crude by today's standards (one can only wonder how it might have looked had Tom Savini not be dragooned off to Vietnam). The camera-wrangling is well-informed by Romero's prior commercial experience, although eminently bolstered by darkly evocative lighting and editing; the choice to shoot in black-and-white was, of course, a financial one, but turned out to be the serendipitous one as well. I can't even conceive of this film being in color, and have steadfastly refused to ever watch the colorized version. "NotLD" remains a classic example of inspired (and inspiring) make-do indie film-making and quite rightfully deserves its many accolades and awards of honor. It's far from perfect--even the script is a let-down at times, what with its occasionally clunky dialog--but it hits all the right dramatic notes, tapping into a nervous zeitgeist in a way that still works even in a post-9/11 world, and perhaps even more so. If George A. Romero & Co. hadn't made "Night of the Living Dead," I have no doubt that someone else would have eventually come up with something similar. But, he did, and the face of horror and indie cinema in general is all the better for it. Long live the living dead!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Surprisingly good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheGreatAmericanNightmare
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I gave this a 6 considering that it was low budget and late 60's. The acting was really not too bad, all things considered. I don't usually go for "B" movies, but I would have to give this a B+. Definitely the beginning of genre. Glad I watched it. Sometimes just the fact that a movie is black and white is enough to keep me from watching it. I know I need to reexamine that policy. As much as I love movies, I need to give more black and white movies a chance. In the beginning, I thought, "Ooh I don't know if I can hang with this." It seemed a little dopey, but as it progressed I got into it and some of the dialog was actually decent. I've seen modern day low budget flicks that couldn't hold a candle to this one.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The first and still the best
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    usgator
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am not sure how to go about reviewing this movie since it is my favorite of all time. I watch it every Halloween, without fail, as well as several other of this type. We are talking about a 30 year span here and I still love it! As a MAJOR horror movie buff since the age of about 10, this is the ONLY one that ever terrified me. I saw it in an extremely cut version, as a Saturday afternoon TV movie, and it still left a big impression on me. Most of the "gory" scenes were cut but it still scared the heck out of me. Everything about this movie works: from the claustrophobic atmosphere to the black-and-white cinematography ... and everything in between. Director George Romero is, and always will be, the king of the flesh-eating zombie movies. This is the gold star of low budget horror flix. If you have not seen it, and are a horror movie fan, this is a MUST see. Do NOT hesitate, see it now, but remember this movie was made in 1968 and much of the shock value has faded as it has been done in 1000 movies since then. Keep in mind that THIS is the film the pushed the "gore" envelope and was the first modern zombie horror film and you can not help but be impressed. Once you see it you will also be compelled to see Romero's equally good sequels ... "Dawn of the Dead" (1978), "Day of the Dead" (1985) and "Land of the Dead" (2005). The other 2 ("Diary.." and "Survival ..") are not up to par, but still better than most of the other movies of this genre, no matter what the "critics" on IMDb say. In closing, I cannot recommend this film enough for the serious, and open minded, horror movie fan.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Great Accomplishment
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wfjohnston14
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Night of the Living Dead is a shocking film in many ways (not taken to be a pun) as it delivers good horror for a very low budget. When Barbara goes to deliver flowers to a grave, her brother is attacked by a zombie and she goes running to a nearby house where she is greeted by a black man named Ben. Then more people come to the house and are trapped inside the house as zombies start to come and attack the house. The group of people must out live the night and hopefully not die from the zombies or themselves. Night of the Living dead is a great accomplishment as it had a budget of $116,000 and made it count. There are so many big budget films that are wasted and this little budget film does not. It has some rather gross zombie scenes, not from the appearance of the zombies, but what they do as one scene they eat the body parts of one of the men and you watch as they tear of the flesh from the arm and chop it down. It's already cut of and now the appearance is rather gross, even for black and white film. The film has a very good climax as the zombies start to enter the house and the little girl finally transforms into a zombie and attacks her parents. Now Ben fights them off and kills the family as they all turn into zombies. Yay for the hero. But wait, it's not over as the police raid the area the next morning with zombie hunters and when Ben escapes the basement to get away from this place, is shot down as one of the hunters think he is a slow moving flesh eater and the happy ending turns tragic. Night of the Living Dead is a brilliant horror movie and does what so many other horrors films should do, be gross and fun. Grade: A
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    classic zombie fest or feast
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kai ringler
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It took me along time to watch this classic, I've seen more of the modern zombie movies over the past 20 years. and after each viewing of said movies I've always thought you know I should give the original masterpiece a try. I thoroughly enjoyed it, I didn't mind that the zombies were slow and hard to understand,, this movie was groundbreaking at the time so I didn't expect a lot of zombie attack action,, the opening scene is frightening to a point. especially in the graveyard. eventually our heroine makes it back to a farmhouse after seeing her brother be left for dead by a zombie, there she meets a black man who kinda runs the house,, together they try and board up all the doors and windows.. later on in the basement there is another family down there taking care of a sick child, and this is where things start to get interesting bickering , arguing amongst the men as to the best way to defend the house, and whether to stay on the top floor of the house or be in the basement,, watch and find out whose idea was better. i'm glad I've seen this movie and have watched it twice and will many more times.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Reality Bites
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tieman64
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "I was trying to come up with a concept about a new society, revolutionary...in political terms, that's taking over and devouring the old society."  George A. Romero George Romero's "Night Of The Living Dead" marked the implosion of the white, middle class, American nuclear family and portrayed the collapse of post-war patriarchal authority into a kind of mad hysteria. What followed - the sexual, political and social "revolutions" of the 1960s - were not so much rebellions against tyrannical paternal and political despots, or against the rigid repressions of suburban family life, as they were carnivalesque revelations that the emperor had no clothes. That 1950s suburbia offered nothing but hypocrisy and fake decor. As such, Romero has his nuclear family holed up in a farmhouse - the impotence of the father mirroring the clownishness and impotence of various authority figures on his television screen - until the unit collapses under the weight of its own stupidity and children-turned-zombies avidly consume their own parents. As is always the case with Romero, the zombies are actually the good guys, the new zombie order literally consuming the outmoded old. The zombie horde then become a darkly humorous vision of hippie communalism who are the preferred refuge of the children of the white middle class. But the rebellions of the 1960s went nowhere, hope fading and forgotten. Hippies and campus radicals from middle-class backgrounds grew up to be yuppies, and their influence on the larger culture was mostly a matter of an easily saleable "lifestyle." Once the social upheavals of the 60s had passed, consumerism turned out to be the real winner, so it's entirely appropriate that Romero's second zombie movie, "Dawn of the Dead", takes place in a shopping mall. Here our heroes live a fantasy of commodity abundance and unhinged consumption, whilst the zombies draw inexorably closer, the mall reminding them of their happiest pre-death moments. In this world there is no satisfaction, only lack, the zombie's unquenchable lust for flesh mocking the consumer's unquenchable desires. Then came "Day of the Dead", arguably the best film in the series. Here, 60s radicalism and 70s consumerism are shunted aside in favour for an assault on Reaganism and the military/scientific complex, where pathologically macho soldiers try to keep the zombies at bay whilst scientists try with futility to either "destroy the zombie plague" or "tame the zombies". The film is relentless in its deconstruction of military authoritarianism and scientific claims to supreme authority, but mostly it's the film's treatment of Freud's reality/pleasure principle and its thick fatalism which makes it so unique. Here, the zombies embody a kind of sympathetic, undeveloped and (pre-language, pre-entry-into-the-Symbolic) ego-less desire (they do not know why they want/desire), which contrasts with the libidinal economy and the twisted viciousness of the human characters (who bury the true motivations of their desires and hypocritically stand for social order). Each of Romero's zombie movies were intended to be a snapshot of the decade in which they was released; "Night" the 60s, "Dawn" the 70s and "Day" the 80s. "Land of the Dead", for financial reasons, was released in the 21st century, but it is actually a broad critique of 90s American society. Here, social class and warfare comes to the foreground, the film imagining America as a paranoid bastion of humanity and freedom, standing tall against the "foreign horde". In "Land of the Dead", the ruling class live lives of elegance and supreme wealth in the exclusive and gated high-rises of "Fiddler's Green", while the masses outside do their dirty bidding and scrape by on low incomes, distracting themselves from their worries with sex, drugs, gambling and violence. The leader of this late-capitalist America, a George Bush styled madman out to make the rich richer and who "refuses to negotiate with terrorists", subsists by sending into zombie territory teams of mercenaries who steal zombie loot (he achieves this by distracting the zombies with fireworks- a kind of metaphor for media spectacle and social brainwashing). The zombies themselves are, once again, the good guys, often linked with the rebelling humans who wish to rise up against their overlords. When the zombies break into the city - led by a black zombie of course - it's symbolic of the proletariat finally rising against their masters and demanding restitution and justice, though Romero knows this is but a futile, 1960s pipe dream. He ends the film with the zombies defeated, the humans infected, and the rebels disillusioned, the masses going their separate ways at the end of the film, wandering off into the horizon like so many disillusioned cinematic anti-heroes of cinema's golden age, specifically the existential road movies of the early 1970s. 8.5/10  "Day of the Dead" 8/10  "Land of the Dead", "Dawn of the Dead" 7.5/10  "Night of the Living Dead" Despite their tiny budgets and at times poor acting, these films still operate fairly well as popcorn movies. What elevates them, though, is the allegorical qualities of Romero's trashy plots.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's a fine zombie movie, but not good enough
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Conrad
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Did the perfect zombie (or "ghoul," as this film's antagonists are dubbed) movie spring forth from the head of George Romero fully-formed, or did subsequent iterations simply fail to build on his promising idea? You know the drill even if you are not a zombie connoisseur: the murderous undead are on the loose, and a diverse band of survivors must overcome their disagreements while staving off the hordes. Romero achieves his vision in "Night of the Living Dead" despite financial and technical limitations. Yet the vision itself is so limited that it hardly extends beyond the premise. In this movie, as in many later knock-offs, there is little character development, little consideration of the theological or scientific implications of the situation, and-- despite frequent claims to the contrary and the casting of a black lead actor--little social commentary. The ending is suggestive of the paranoia and pessimism that afflicted many in 1968, but the script's unironic portrayal of women as submissive and incompetent does not indicate a desire to engage with social issues of the day. "Night of the Living Dead" is decent as far as it goes, but it does not go far, and the genre has rarely aimed higher in the nearly 50 years since.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What could I add more?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    GUENOT PHILIPPE (philippe.guenot@dbmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    That's one of the best picture ever for me, overall, not only horror movies...What could I say more, that the other users have already told? I can't find enough words to describe this authentic gem that every movie buff - and not only - have already watched. I saw it a hundred times... A simple story, but so powerful, so efficient, and with no professional actors. No "hollywoodian" actors I mean. The very first scene, where we see an American flag put at the cemetery entry, which can be interpreted as the Vietnam mess - the film was shot in 1968 - is very meaningful for the rest of the film. And typical of this very period. The counter culture one. What I particularly like in this masterpiece is that there is not useless love interest between the characters, for instance Ben and Barbara's ones, as we could have expected. And I appreciate this. Yes, this movies describes the human behavior very well. After all, are the real human creatures better than the dead ones? That's the real question of the movie, that's my opinion. The characters fighting for their lives in the small house are shown in such an intense way...Films made now, in 20... are not so powerful. Sorry. And the final moral, where we finally find that the coward, nasty character - Cooper's one - was damn right, concerning the safety of the basement. All long the film, well almost, he told everyone that the basement was the safest way to stay. Ben, the lead, did not agree, so did the audience who loves this fighting character. And, at the end, that's this very basement that saved Ben. The bad guy was right at the end. That's very unusual. Yes I won't never be tired to watch this movie again and again.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wasn't too impressed by this horror classic, but it was an enjoyable film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bruno Youn
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A decent horror film overall, but I have to say it was a very uneven experience for me. While there are a few aspects I certainly enjoyed here, such as the effective scares, gruesome imagery and the shocking twist at the end, I thought the acting was stale at times and was pretty annoyed by the character of Helen. The film got too didactic and a bit tedious when they began to follow the announcements on TV. The explanation of the origins of the undead was very far-fetched for me and didn't really need to be here. Also, the zombies seemed to be inconsistent as some of them decide to chase people or kill them with objects when they have fresh meat to eat right beside them. Finally, I found many statements given by the characters to be quite obvious or even a bit ridiculous so that also took me out of the film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Grim & Influential.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    George Romero's infamous low budget horror film about the mysterious resurrection of hordes of the walking dead, who are compelled to kill, and consume, the living, became a huge underground hit that inspired a whole new sub genre of horror for those so inclined, not to mention a great many sequels, remakes, spin offs, etc. Though this is, on one level, a starkly effective shocker, the premise is so utterly preposterous, and tone so unmercifully grim and downbeat, with a horribly ironic ending, that it doesn't work for me. The acting is strong though, but film is dispiriting in the extreme, with little to recommend it, though it is a cult classic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This is where the long walk began...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MrGKB
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ...toward the contemporary zombie mythos of "The Walking Dead" and every cannibalistic living dead film in between. I first enjoyed "NotLD" on the big screen way back in the antediluvian days of college, pre- videotape/DVD/BluRay collections, pre-Internet, pre-Androids etal., when Romero's unassuming film was burning up the midnight film circuit and burrowing deep into the collective unconsciousness of horror fans and cinemaphiles everywhere. Little did I know at the time just how influential this little homegrown nightmare would prove to be, but there was no denying its raw power to shock and unsettle unsuspecting audiences, and all on a budget just somewhat above rock bottom. Imagine, if you will, several hundred Boomer college kids packed into a darkened auditorium, most of them likely intoxicated on one thing or another, all eager to see this scary movie that so far they'd only read about. They knew that Roger Ebert hated it, which only made it more alluring. They knew it pushed the boundaries of graphic depictions of murder, and that, too, made it all the more the forbidden fruit. And, perhaps most of all, they knew it wasn't a "Hollywood" movie, and that made its rising star all the brighter. Imagine now that very first viewing of that rough gem in all its lo-fi glory... Almost a half-century later, even the most forgiving retrospectives will admit to the film's flaws; only the most churlish could deny them. The acting is at times--to be polite--unpolished, and the make-up is simply crude by today's standards (one can only wonder how it might have looked had Tom Savini not be dragooned off to Vietnam). The camera-wrangling is well-informed by Romero's prior commercial experience, although eminently bolstered by darkly evocative lighting and editing; the choice to shoot in black-and-white was, of course, a financial one, but turned out to be the serendipitous one as well. I can't even conceive of this film being in color, and have steadfastly refused to ever watch the colorized version. "NotLD" remains a classic example of inspired (and inspiring) make-do indie film-making and quite rightfully deserves its many accolades and awards of honor. It's far from perfect--even the script is a let-down at times, what with its occasionally clunky dialog--but it hits all the right dramatic notes, tapping into a nervous zeitgeist in a way that still works even in a post-9/11 world, and perhaps even more so. If George A. Romero & Co. hadn't made "Night of the Living Dead," I have no doubt that someone else would have eventually come up with something similar. But, he did, and the face of horror and indie cinema in general is all the better for it. Long live the living dead!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Surprisingly good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheGreatAmericanNightmare
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I gave this a 6 considering that it was low budget and late 60's. The acting was really not too bad, all things considered. I don't usually go for "B" movies, but I would have to give this a B+. Definitely the beginning of genre. Glad I watched it. Sometimes just the fact that a movie is black and white is enough to keep me from watching it. I know I need to reexamine that policy. As much as I love movies, I need to give more black and white movies a chance. In the beginning, I thought, "Ooh I don't know if I can hang with this." It seemed a little dopey, but as it progressed I got into it and some of the dialog was actually decent. I've seen modern day low budget flicks that couldn't hold a candle to this one.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The first and still the best
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    usgator
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am not sure how to go about reviewing this movie since it is my favorite of all time. I watch it every Halloween, without fail, as well as several other of this type. We are talking about a 30 year span here and I still love it! As a MAJOR horror movie buff since the age of about 10, this is the ONLY one that ever terrified me. I saw it in an extremely cut version, as a Saturday afternoon TV movie, and it still left a big impression on me. Most of the "gory" scenes were cut but it still scared the heck out of me. Everything about this movie works: from the claustrophobic atmosphere to the black-and-white cinematography ... and everything in between. Director George Romero is, and always will be, the king of the flesh-eating zombie movies. This is the gold star of low budget horror flix. If you have not seen it, and are a horror movie fan, this is a MUST see. Do NOT hesitate, see it now, but remember this movie was made in 1968 and much of the shock value has faded as it has been done in 1000 movies since then. Keep in mind that THIS is the film the pushed the "gore" envelope and was the first modern zombie horror film and you can not help but be impressed. Once you see it you will also be compelled to see Romero's equally good sequels ... "Dawn of the Dead" (1978), "Day of the Dead" (1985) and "Land of the Dead" (2005). The other 2 ("Diary.." and "Survival ..") are not up to par, but still better than most of the other movies of this genre, no matter what the "critics" on IMDb say. In closing, I cannot recommend this film enough for the serious, and open minded, horror movie fan.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Great Accomplishment
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wfjohnston14
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Night of the Living Dead is a shocking film in many ways (not taken to be a pun) as it delivers good horror for a very low budget. When Barbara goes to deliver flowers to a grave, her brother is attacked by a zombie and she goes running to a nearby house where she is greeted by a black man named Ben. Then more people come to the house and are trapped inside the house as zombies start to come and attack the house. The group of people must out live the night and hopefully not die from the zombies or themselves. Night of the Living dead is a great accomplishment as it had a budget of $116,000 and made it count. There are so many big budget films that are wasted and this little budget film does not. It has some rather gross zombie scenes, not from the appearance of the zombies, but what they do as one scene they eat the body parts of one of the men and you watch as they tear of the flesh from the arm and chop it down. It's already cut of and now the appearance is rather gross, even for black and white film. The film has a very good climax as the zombies start to enter the house and the little girl finally transforms into a zombie and attacks her parents. Now Ben fights them off and kills the family as they all turn into zombies. Yay for the hero. But wait, it's not over as the police raid the area the next morning with zombie hunters and when Ben escapes the basement to get away from this place, is shot down as one of the hunters think he is a slow moving flesh eater and the happy ending turns tragic. Night of the Living Dead is a brilliant horror movie and does what so many other horrors films should do, be gross and fun. Grade: A
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    classic zombie fest or feast
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kai ringler
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It took me along time to watch this classic, I've seen more of the modern zombie movies over the past 20 years. and after each viewing of said movies I've always thought you know I should give the original masterpiece a try. I thoroughly enjoyed it, I didn't mind that the zombies were slow and hard to understand,, this movie was groundbreaking at the time so I didn't expect a lot of zombie attack action,, the opening scene is frightening to a point. especially in the graveyard. eventually our heroine makes it back to a farmhouse after seeing her brother be left for dead by a zombie, there she meets a black man who kinda runs the house,, together they try and board up all the doors and windows.. later on in the basement there is another family down there taking care of a sick child, and this is where things start to get interesting bickering , arguing amongst the men as to the best way to defend the house, and whether to stay on the top floor of the house or be in the basement,, watch and find out whose idea was better. i'm glad I've seen this movie and have watched it twice and will many more times.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Reality Bites
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tieman64
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "I was trying to come up with a concept about a new society, revolutionary...in political terms, that's taking over and devouring the old society."  George A. Romero George Romero's "Night Of The Living Dead" marked the implosion of the white, middle class, American nuclear family and portrayed the collapse of post-war patriarchal authority into a kind of mad hysteria. What followed - the sexual, political and social "revolutions" of the 1960s - were not so much rebellions against tyrannical paternal and political despots, or against the rigid repressions of suburban family life, as they were carnivalesque revelations that the emperor had no clothes. That 1950s suburbia offered nothing but hypocrisy and fake decor. As such, Romero has his nuclear family holed up in a farmhouse - the impotence of the father mirroring the clownishness and impotence of various authority figures on his television screen - until the unit collapses under the weight of its own stupidity and children-turned-zombies avidly consume their own parents. As is always the case with Romero, the zombies are actually the good guys, the new zombie order literally consuming the outmoded old. The zombie horde then become a darkly humorous vision of hippie communalism who are the preferred refuge of the children of the white middle class. But the rebellions of the 1960s went nowhere, hope fading and forgotten. Hippies and campus radicals from middle-class backgrounds grew up to be yuppies, and their influence on the larger culture was mostly a matter of an easily saleable "lifestyle." Once the social upheavals of the 60s had passed, consumerism turned out to be the real winner, so it's entirely appropriate that Romero's second zombie movie, "Dawn of the Dead", takes place in a shopping mall. Here our heroes live a fantasy of commodity abundance and unhinged consumption, whilst the zombies draw inexorably closer, the mall reminding them of their happiest pre-death moments. In this world there is no satisfaction, only lack, the zombie's unquenchable lust for flesh mocking the consumer's unquenchable desires. Then came "Day of the Dead", arguably the best film in the series. Here, 60s radicalism and 70s consumerism are shunted aside in favour for an assault on Reaganism and the military/scientific complex, where pathologically macho soldiers try to keep the zombies at bay whilst scientists try with futility to either "destroy the zombie plague" or "tame the zombies". The film is relentless in its deconstruction of military authoritarianism and scientific claims to supreme authority, but mostly it's the film's treatment of Freud's reality/pleasure principle and its thick fatalism which makes it so unique. Here, the zombies embody a kind of sympathetic, undeveloped and (pre-language, pre-entry-into-the-Symbolic) ego-less desire (they do not know why they want/desire), which contrasts with the libidinal economy and the twisted viciousness of the human characters (who bury the true motivations of their desires and hypocritically stand for social order). Each of Romero's zombie movies were intended to be a snapshot of the decade in which they was released; "Night" the 60s, "Dawn" the 70s and "Day" the 80s. "Land of the Dead", for financial reasons, was released in the 21st century, but it is actually a broad critique of 90s American society. Here, social class and warfare comes to the foreground, the film imagining America as a paranoid bastion of humanity and freedom, standing tall against the "foreign horde". In "Land of the Dead", the ruling class live lives of elegance and supreme wealth in the exclusive and gated high-rises of "Fiddler's Green", while the masses outside do their dirty bidding and scrape by on low incomes, distracting themselves from their worries with sex, drugs, gambling and violence. The leader of this late-capitalist America, a George Bush styled madman out to make the rich richer and who "refuses to negotiate with terrorists", subsists by sending into zombie territory teams of mercenaries who steal zombie loot (he achieves this by distracting the zombies with fireworks- a kind of metaphor for media spectacle and social brainwashing). The zombies themselves are, once again, the good guys, often linked with the rebelling humans who wish to rise up against their overlords. When the zombies break into the city - led by a black zombie of course - it's symbolic of the proletariat finally rising against their masters and demanding restitution and justice, though Romero knows this is but a futile, 1960s pipe dream. He ends the film with the zombies defeated, the humans infected, and the rebels disillusioned, the masses going their separate ways at the end of the film, wandering off into the horizon like so many disillusioned cinematic anti-heroes of cinema's golden age, specifically the existential road movies of the early 1970s. 8.5/10  "Day of the Dead" 8/10  "Land of the Dead", "Dawn of the Dead" 7.5/10  "Night of the Living Dead" Despite their tiny budgets and at times poor acting, these films still operate fairly well as popcorn movies. What elevates them, though, is the allegorical qualities of Romero's trashy plots.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's a fine zombie movie, but not good enough
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Conrad
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Did the perfect zombie (or "ghoul," as this film's antagonists are dubbed) movie spring forth from the head of George Romero fully-formed, or did subsequent iterations simply fail to build on his promising idea? You know the drill even if you are not a zombie connoisseur: the murderous undead are on the loose, and a diverse band of survivors must overcome their disagreements while staving off the hordes. Romero achieves his vision in "Night of the Living Dead" despite financial and technical limitations. Yet the vision itself is so limited that it hardly extends beyond the premise. In this movie, as in many later knock-offs, there is little character development, little consideration of the theological or scientific implications of the situation, and-- despite frequent claims to the contrary and the casting of a black lead actor--little social commentary. The ending is suggestive of the paranoia and pessimism that afflicted many in 1968, but the script's unironic portrayal of women as submissive and incompetent does not indicate a desire to engage with social issues of the day. "Night of the Living Dead" is decent as far as it goes, but it does not go far, and the genre has rarely aimed higher in the nearly 50 years since.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What could I add more?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    GUENOT PHILIPPE (philippe.guenot@dbmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    That's one of the best picture ever for me, overall, not only horror movies...What could I say more, that the other users have already told? I can't find enough words to describe this authentic gem that every movie buff - and not only - have already watched. I saw it a hundred times... A simple story, but so powerful, so efficient, and with no professional actors. No "hollywoodian" actors I mean. The very first scene, where we see an American flag put at the cemetery entry, which can be interpreted as the Vietnam mess - the film was shot in 1968 - is very meaningful for the rest of the film. And typical of this very period. The counter culture one. What I particularly like in this masterpiece is that there is not useless love interest between the characters, for instance Ben and Barbara's ones, as we could have expected. And I appreciate this. Yes, this movies describes the human behavior very well. After all, are the real human creatures better than the dead ones? That's the real question of the movie, that's my opinion. The characters fighting for their lives in the small house are shown in such an intense way...Films made now, in 20... are not so powerful. Sorry. And the final moral, where we finally find that the coward, nasty character - Cooper's one - was damn right, concerning the safety of the basement. All long the film, well almost, he told everyone that the basement was the safest way to stay. Ben, the lead, did not agree, so did the audience who loves this fighting character. And, at the end, that's this very basement that saved Ben. The bad guy was right at the end. That's very unusual. Yes I won't never be tired to watch this movie again and again.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wasn't too impressed by this horror classic, but it was an enjoyable film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bruno Youn
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A decent horror film overall, but I have to say it was a very uneven experience for me. While there are a few aspects I certainly enjoyed here, such as the effective scares, gruesome imagery and the shocking twist at the end, I thought the acting was stale at times and was pretty annoyed by the character of Helen. The film got too didactic and a bit tedious when they began to follow the announcements on TV. The explanation of the origins of the undead was very far-fetched for me and didn't really need to be here. Also, the zombies seemed to be inconsistent as some of them decide to chase people or kill them with objects when they have fresh meat to eat right beside them. Finally, I found many statements given by the characters to be quite obvious or even a bit ridiculous so that also took me out of the film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Grim & Influential.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    George Romero's infamous low budget horror film about the mysterious resurrection of hordes of the walking dead, who are compelled to kill, and consume, the living, became a huge underground hit that inspired a whole new sub genre of horror for those so inclined, not to mention a great many sequels, remakes, spin offs, etc. Though this is, on one level, a starkly effective shocker, the premise is so utterly preposterous, and tone so unmercifully grim and downbeat, with a horribly ironic ending, that it doesn't work for me. The acting is strong though, but film is dispiriting in the extreme, with little to recommend it, though it is a cult classic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This is where the long walk began...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MrGKB
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ...toward the contemporary zombie mythos of "The Walking Dead" and every cannibalistic living dead film in between. I first enjoyed "NotLD" on the big screen way back in the antediluvian days of college, pre- videotape/DVD/BluRay collections, pre-Internet, pre-Androids etal., when Romero's unassuming film was burning up the midnight film circuit and burrowing deep into the collective unconsciousness of horror fans and cinemaphiles everywhere. Little did I know at the time just how influential this little homegrown nightmare would prove to be, but there was no denying its raw power to shock and unsettle unsuspecting audiences, and all on a budget just somewhat above rock bottom. Imagine, if you will, several hundred Boomer college kids packed into a darkened auditorium, most of them likely intoxicated on one thing or another, all eager to see this scary movie that so far they'd only read about. They knew that Roger Ebert hated it, which only made it more alluring. They knew it pushed the boundaries of graphic depictions of murder, and that, too, made it all the more the forbidden fruit. And, perhaps most of all, they knew it wasn't a "Hollywood" movie, and that made its rising star all the brighter. Imagine now that very first viewing of that rough gem in all its lo-fi glory... Almost a half-century later, even the most forgiving retrospectives will admit to the film's flaws; only the most churlish could deny them. The acting is at times--to be polite--unpolished, and the make-up is simply crude by today's standards (one can only wonder how it might have looked had Tom Savini not be dragooned off to Vietnam). The camera-wrangling is well-informed by Romero's prior commercial experience, although eminently bolstered by darkly evocative lighting and editing; the choice to shoot in black-and-white was, of course, a financial one, but turned out to be the serendipitous one as well. I can't even conceive of this film being in color, and have steadfastly refused to ever watch the colorized version. "NotLD" remains a classic example of inspired (and inspiring) make-do indie film-making and quite rightfully deserves its many accolades and awards of honor. It's far from perfect--even the script is a let-down at times, what with its occasionally clunky dialog--but it hits all the right dramatic notes, tapping into a nervous zeitgeist in a way that still works even in a post-9/11 world, and perhaps even more so. If George A. Romero & Co. hadn't made "Night of the Living Dead," I have no doubt that someone else would have eventually come up with something similar. But, he did, and the face of horror and indie cinema in general is all the better for it. Long live the living dead!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Surprisingly good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheGreatAmericanNightmare
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I gave this a 6 considering that it was low budget and late 60's. The acting was really not too bad, all things considered. I don't usually go for "B" movies, but I would have to give this a B+. Definitely the beginning of genre. Glad I watched it. Sometimes just the fact that a movie is black and white is enough to keep me from watching it. I know I need to reexamine that policy. As much as I love movies, I need to give more black and white movies a chance. In the beginning, I thought, "Ooh I don't know if I can hang with this." It seemed a little dopey, but as it progressed I got into it and some of the dialog was actually decent. I've seen modern day low budget flicks that couldn't hold a candle to this one.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The first and still the best
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    usgator
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am not sure how to go about reviewing this movie since it is my favorite of all time. I watch it every Halloween, without fail, as well as several other of this type. We are talking about a 30 year span here and I still love it! As a MAJOR horror movie buff since the age of about 10, this is the ONLY one that ever terrified me. I saw it in an extremely cut version, as a Saturday afternoon TV movie, and it still left a big impression on me. Most of the "gory" scenes were cut but it still scared the heck out of me. Everything about this movie works: from the claustrophobic atmosphere to the black-and-white cinematography ... and everything in between. Director George Romero is, and always will be, the king of the flesh-eating zombie movies. This is the gold star of low budget horror flix. If you have not seen it, and are a horror movie fan, this is a MUST see. Do NOT hesitate, see it now, but remember this movie was made in 1968 and much of the shock value has faded as it has been done in 1000 movies since then. Keep in mind that THIS is the film the pushed the "gore" envelope and was the first modern zombie horror film and you can not help but be impressed. Once you see it you will also be compelled to see Romero's equally good sequels ... "Dawn of the Dead" (1978), "Day of the Dead" (1985) and "Land of the Dead" (2005). The other 2 ("Diary.." and "Survival ..") are not up to par, but still better than most of the other movies of this genre, no matter what the "critics" on IMDb say. In closing, I cannot recommend this film enough for the serious, and open minded, horror movie fan.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Great Accomplishment
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wfjohnston14
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Night of the Living Dead is a shocking film in many ways (not taken to be a pun) as it delivers good horror for a very low budget. When Barbara goes to deliver flowers to a grave, her brother is attacked by a zombie and she goes running to a nearby house where she is greeted by a black man named Ben. Then more people come to the house and are trapped inside the house as zombies start to come and attack the house. The group of people must out live the night and hopefully not die from the zombies or themselves. Night of the Living dead is a great accomplishment as it had a budget of $116,000 and made it count. There are so many big budget films that are wasted and this little budget film does not. It has some rather gross zombie scenes, not from the appearance of the zombies, but what they do as one scene they eat the body parts of one of the men and you watch as they tear of the flesh from the arm and chop it down. It's already cut of and now the appearance is rather gross, even for black and white film. The film has a very good climax as the zombies start to enter the house and the little girl finally transforms into a zombie and attacks her parents. Now Ben fights them off and kills the family as they all turn into zombies. Yay for the hero. But wait, it's not over as the police raid the area the next morning with zombie hunters and when Ben escapes the basement to get away from this place, is shot down as one of the hunters think he is a slow moving flesh eater and the happy ending turns tragic. Night of the Living Dead is a brilliant horror movie and does what so many other horrors films should do, be gross and fun. Grade: A
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    classic zombie fest or feast
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kai ringler
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It took me along time to watch this classic, I've seen more of the modern zombie movies over the past 20 years. and after each viewing of said movies I've always thought you know I should give the original masterpiece a try. I thoroughly enjoyed it, I didn't mind that the zombies were slow and hard to understand,, this movie was groundbreaking at the time so I didn't expect a lot of zombie attack action,, the opening scene is frightening to a point. especially in the graveyard. eventually our heroine makes it back to a farmhouse after seeing her brother be left for dead by a zombie, there she meets a black man who kinda runs the house,, together they try and board up all the doors and windows.. later on in the basement there is another family down there taking care of a sick child, and this is where things start to get interesting bickering , arguing amongst the men as to the best way to defend the house, and whether to stay on the top floor of the house or be in the basement,, watch and find out whose idea was better. i'm glad I've seen this movie and have watched it twice and will many more times.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Reality Bites
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tieman64
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "I was trying to come up with a concept about a new society, revolutionary...in political terms, that's taking over and devouring the old society."  George A. Romero George Romero's "Night Of The Living Dead" marked the implosion of the white, middle class, American nuclear family and portrayed the collapse of post-war patriarchal authority into a kind of mad hysteria. What followed - the sexual, political and social "revolutions" of the 1960s - were not so much rebellions against tyrannical paternal and political despots, or against the rigid repressions of suburban family life, as they were carnivalesque revelations that the emperor had no clothes. That 1950s suburbia offered nothing but hypocrisy and fake decor. As such, Romero has his nuclear family holed up in a farmhouse - the impotence of the father mirroring the clownishness and impotence of various authority figures on his television screen - until the unit collapses under the weight of its own stupidity and children-turned-zombies avidly consume their own parents. As is always the case with Romero, the zombies are actually the good guys, the new zombie order literally consuming the outmoded old. The zombie horde then become a darkly humorous vision of hippie communalism who are the preferred refuge of the children of the white middle class. But the rebellions of the 1960s went nowhere, hope fading and forgotten. Hippies and campus radicals from middle-class backgrounds grew up to be yuppies, and their influence on the larger culture was mostly a matter of an easily saleable "lifestyle." Once the social upheavals of the 60s had passed, consumerism turned out to be the real winner, so it's entirely appropriate that Romero's second zombie movie, "Dawn of the Dead", takes place in a shopping mall. Here our heroes live a fantasy of commodity abundance and unhinged consumption, whilst the zombies draw inexorably closer, the mall reminding them of their happiest pre-death moments. In this world there is no satisfaction, only lack, the zombie's unquenchable lust for flesh mocking the consumer's unquenchable desires. Then came "Day of the Dead", arguably the best film in the series. Here, 60s radicalism and 70s consumerism are shunted aside in favour for an assault on Reaganism and the military/scientific complex, where pathologically macho soldiers try to keep the zombies at bay whilst scientists try with futility to either "destroy the zombie plague" or "tame the zombies". The film is relentless in its deconstruction of military authoritarianism and scientific claims to supreme authority, but mostly it's the film's treatment of Freud's reality/pleasure principle and its thick fatalism which makes it so unique. Here, the zombies embody a kind of sympathetic, undeveloped and (pre-language, pre-entry-into-the-Symbolic) ego-less desire (they do not know why they want/desire), which contrasts with the libidinal economy and the twisted viciousness of the human characters (who bury the true motivations of their desires and hypocritically stand for social order). Each of Romero's zombie movies were intended to be a snapshot of the decade in which they was released; "Night" the 60s, "Dawn" the 70s and "Day" the 80s. "Land of the Dead", for financial reasons, was released in the 21st century, but it is actually a broad critique of 90s American society. Here, social class and warfare comes to the foreground, the film imagining America as a paranoid bastion of humanity and freedom, standing tall against the "foreign horde". In "Land of the Dead", the ruling class live lives of elegance and supreme wealth in the exclusive and gated high-rises of "Fiddler's Green", while the masses outside do their dirty bidding and scrape by on low incomes, distracting themselves from their worries with sex, drugs, gambling and violence. The leader of this late-capitalist America, a George Bush styled madman out to make the rich richer and who "refuses to negotiate with terrorists", subsists by sending into zombie territory teams of mercenaries who steal zombie loot (he achieves this by distracting the zombies with fireworks- a kind of metaphor for media spectacle and social brainwashing). The zombies themselves are, once again, the good guys, often linked with the rebelling humans who wish to rise up against their overlords. When the zombies break into the city - led by a black zombie of course - it's symbolic of the proletariat finally rising against their masters and demanding restitution and justice, though Romero knows this is but a futile, 1960s pipe dream. He ends the film with the zombies defeated, the humans infected, and the rebels disillusioned, the masses going their separate ways at the end of the film, wandering off into the horizon like so many disillusioned cinematic anti-heroes of cinema's golden age, specifically the existential road movies of the early 1970s. 8.5/10  "Day of the Dead" 8/10  "Land of the Dead", "Dawn of the Dead" 7.5/10  "Night of the Living Dead" Despite their tiny budgets and at times poor acting, these films still operate fairly well as popcorn movies. What elevates them, though, is the allegorical qualities of Romero's trashy plots.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's a fine zombie movie, but not good enough
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Conrad
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Did the perfect zombie (or "ghoul," as this film's antagonists are dubbed) movie spring forth from the head of George Romero fully-formed, or did subsequent iterations simply fail to build on his promising idea? You know the drill even if you are not a zombie connoisseur: the murderous undead are on the loose, and a diverse band of survivors must overcome their disagreements while staving off the hordes. Romero achieves his vision in "Night of the Living Dead" despite financial and technical limitations. Yet the vision itself is so limited that it hardly extends beyond the premise. In this movie, as in many later knock-offs, there is little character development, little consideration of the theological or scientific implications of the situation, and-- despite frequent claims to the contrary and the casting of a black lead actor--little social commentary. The ending is suggestive of the paranoia and pessimism that afflicted many in 1968, but the script's unironic portrayal of women as submissive and incompetent does not indicate a desire to engage with social issues of the day. "Night of the Living Dead" is decent as far as it goes, but it does not go far, and the genre has rarely aimed higher in the nearly 50 years since.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What could I add more?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    GUENOT PHILIPPE (philippe.guenot@dbmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    That's one of the best picture ever for me, overall, not only horror movies...What could I say more, that the other users have already told? I can't find enough words to describe this authentic gem that every movie buff - and not only - have already watched. I saw it a hundred times... A simple story, but so powerful, so efficient, and with no professional actors. No "hollywoodian" actors I mean. The very first scene, where we see an American flag put at the cemetery entry, which can be interpreted as the Vietnam mess - the film was shot in 1968 - is very meaningful for the rest of the film. And typical of this very period. The counter culture one. What I particularly like in this masterpiece is that there is not useless love interest between the characters, for instance Ben and Barbara's ones, as we could have expected. And I appreciate this. Yes, this movies describes the human behavior very well. After all, are the real human creatures better than the dead ones? That's the real question of the movie, that's my opinion. The characters fighting for their lives in the small house are shown in such an intense way...Films made now, in 20... are not so powerful. Sorry. And the final moral, where we finally find that the coward, nasty character - Cooper's one - was damn right, concerning the safety of the basement. All long the film, well almost, he told everyone that the basement was the safest way to stay. Ben, the lead, did not agree, so did the audience who loves this fighting character. And, at the end, that's this very basement that saved Ben. The bad guy was right at the end. That's very unusual. Yes I won't never be tired to watch this movie again and again.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wasn't too impressed by this horror classic, but it was an enjoyable film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bruno Youn
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A decent horror film overall, but I have to say it was a very uneven experience for me. While there are a few aspects I certainly enjoyed here, such as the effective scares, gruesome imagery and the shocking twist at the end, I thought the acting was stale at times and was pretty annoyed by the character of Helen. The film got too didactic and a bit tedious when they began to follow the announcements on TV. The explanation of the origins of the undead was very far-fetched for me and didn't really need to be here. Also, the zombies seemed to be inconsistent as some of them decide to chase people or kill them with objects when they have fresh meat to eat right beside them. Finally, I found many statements given by the characters to be quite obvious or even a bit ridiculous so that also took me out of the film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Grim & Influential.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    George Romero's infamous low budget horror film about the mysterious resurrection of hordes of the walking dead, who are compelled to kill, and consume, the living, became a huge underground hit that inspired a whole new sub genre of horror for those so inclined, not to mention a great many sequels, remakes, spin offs, etc. Though this is, on one level, a starkly effective shocker, the premise is so utterly preposterous, and tone so unmercifully grim and downbeat, with a horribly ironic ending, that it doesn't work for me. The acting is strong though, but film is dispiriting in the extreme, with little to recommend it, though it is a cult classic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This is where the long walk began...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MrGKB
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ...toward the contemporary zombie mythos of "The Walking Dead" and every cannibalistic living dead film in between. I first enjoyed "NotLD" on the big screen way back in the antediluvian days of college, pre- videotape/DVD/BluRay collections, pre-Internet, pre-Androids etal., when Romero's unassuming film was burning up the midnight film circuit and burrowing deep into the collective unconsciousness of horror fans and cinemaphiles everywhere. Little did I know at the time just how influential this little homegrown nightmare would prove to be, but there was no denying its raw power to shock and unsettle unsuspecting audiences, and all on a budget just somewhat above rock bottom. Imagine, if you will, several hundred Boomer college kids packed into a darkened auditorium, most of them likely intoxicated on one thing or another, all eager to see this scary movie that so far they'd only read about. They knew that Roger Ebert hated it, which only made it more alluring. They knew it pushed the boundaries of graphic depictions of murder, and that, too, made it all the more the forbidden fruit. And, perhaps most of all, they knew it wasn't a "Hollywood" movie, and that made its rising star all the brighter. Imagine now that very first viewing of that rough gem in all its lo-fi glory... Almost a half-century later, even the most forgiving retrospectives will admit to the film's flaws; only the most churlish could deny them. The acting is at times--to be polite--unpolished, and the make-up is simply crude by today's standards (one can only wonder how it might have looked had Tom Savini not be dragooned off to Vietnam). The camera-wrangling is well-informed by Romero's prior commercial experience, although eminently bolstered by darkly evocative lighting and editing; the choice to shoot in black-and-white was, of course, a financial one, but turned out to be the serendipitous one as well. I can't even conceive of this film being in color, and have steadfastly refused to ever watch the colorized version. "NotLD" remains a classic example of inspired (and inspiring) make-do indie film-making and quite rightfully deserves its many accolades and awards of honor. It's far from perfect--even the script is a let-down at times, what with its occasionally clunky dialog--but it hits all the right dramatic notes, tapping into a nervous zeitgeist in a way that still works even in a post-9/11 world, and perhaps even more so. If George A. Romero & Co. hadn't made "Night of the Living Dead," I have no doubt that someone else would have eventually come up with something similar. But, he did, and the face of horror and indie cinema in general is all the better for it. Long live the living dead!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Surprisingly good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheGreatAmericanNightmare
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I gave this a 6 considering that it was low budget and late 60's. The acting was really not too bad, all things considered. I don't usually go for "B" movies, but I would have to give this a B+. Definitely the beginning of genre. Glad I watched it. Sometimes just the fact that a movie is black and white is enough to keep me from watching it. I know I need to reexamine that policy. As much as I love movies, I need to give more black and white movies a chance. In the beginning, I thought, "Ooh I don't know if I can hang with this." It seemed a little dopey, but as it progressed I got into it and some of the dialog was actually decent. I've seen modern day low budget flicks that couldn't hold a candle to this one.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The first and still the best
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    usgator
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am not sure how to go about reviewing this movie since it is my favorite of all time. I watch it every Halloween, without fail, as well as several other of this type. We are talking about a 30 year span here and I still love it! As a MAJOR horror movie buff since the age of about 10, this is the ONLY one that ever terrified me. I saw it in an extremely cut version, as a Saturday afternoon TV movie, and it still left a big impression on me. Most of the "gory" scenes were cut but it still scared the heck out of me. Everything about this movie works: from the claustrophobic atmosphere to the black-and-white cinematography ... and everything in between. Director George Romero is, and always will be, the king of the flesh-eating zombie movies. This is the gold star of low budget horror flix. If you have not seen it, and are a horror movie fan, this is a MUST see. Do NOT hesitate, see it now, but remember this movie was made in 1968 and much of the shock value has faded as it has been done in 1000 movies since then. Keep in mind that THIS is the film the pushed the "gore" envelope and was the first modern zombie horror film and you can not help but be impressed. Once you see it you will also be compelled to see Romero's equally good sequels ... "Dawn of the Dead" (1978), "Day of the Dead" (1985) and "Land of the Dead" (2005). The other 2 ("Diary.." and "Survival ..") are not up to par, but still better than most of the other movies of this genre, no matter what the "critics" on IMDb say. In closing, I cannot recommend this film enough for the serious, and open minded, horror movie fan.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Great Accomplishment
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wfjohnston14
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Night of the Living Dead is a shocking film in many ways (not taken to be a pun) as it delivers good horror for a very low budget. When Barbara goes to deliver flowers to a grave, her brother is attacked by a zombie and she goes running to a nearby house where she is greeted by a black man named Ben. Then more people come to the house and are trapped inside the house as zombies start to come and attack the house. The group of people must out live the night and hopefully not die from the zombies or themselves. Night of the Living dead is a great accomplishment as it had a budget of $116,000 and made it count. There are so many big budget films that are wasted and this little budget film does not. It has some rather gross zombie scenes, not from the appearance of the zombies, but what they do as one scene they eat the body parts of one of the men and you watch as they tear of the flesh from the arm and chop it down. It's already cut of and now the appearance is rather gross, even for black and white film. The film has a very good climax as the zombies start to enter the house and the little girl finally transforms into a zombie and attacks her parents. Now Ben fights them off and kills the family as they all turn into zombies. Yay for the hero. But wait, it's not over as the police raid the area the next morning with zombie hunters and when Ben escapes the basement to get away from this place, is shot down as one of the hunters think he is a slow moving flesh eater and the happy ending turns tragic. Night of the Living Dead is a brilliant horror movie and does what so many other horrors films should do, be gross and fun. Grade: A
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    classic zombie fest or feast
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kai ringler
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It took me along time to watch this classic, I've seen more of the modern zombie movies over the past 20 years. and after each viewing of said movies I've always thought you know I should give the original masterpiece a try. I thoroughly enjoyed it, I didn't mind that the zombies were slow and hard to understand,, this movie was groundbreaking at the time so I didn't expect a lot of zombie attack action,, the opening scene is frightening to a point. especially in the graveyard. eventually our heroine makes it back to a farmhouse after seeing her brother be left for dead by a zombie, there she meets a black man who kinda runs the house,, together they try and board up all the doors and windows.. later on in the basement there is another family down there taking care of a sick child, and this is where things start to get interesting bickering , arguing amongst the men as to the best way to defend the house, and whether to stay on the top floor of the house or be in the basement,, watch and find out whose idea was better. i'm glad I've seen this movie and have watched it twice and will many more times.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Reality Bites
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tieman64
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "I was trying to come up with a concept about a new society, revolutionary...in political terms, that's taking over and devouring the old society."  George A. Romero George Romero's "Night Of The Living Dead" marked the implosion of the white, middle class, American nuclear family and portrayed the collapse of post-war patriarchal authority into a kind of mad hysteria. What followed - the sexual, political and social "revolutions" of the 1960s - were not so much rebellions against tyrannical paternal and political despots, or against the rigid repressions of suburban family life, as they were carnivalesque revelations that the emperor had no clothes. That 1950s suburbia offered nothing but hypocrisy and fake decor. As such, Romero has his nuclear family holed up in a farmhouse - the impotence of the father mirroring the clownishness and impotence of various authority figures on his television screen - until the unit collapses under the weight of its own stupidity and children-turned-zombies avidly consume their own parents. As is always the case with Romero, the zombies are actually the good guys, the new zombie order literally consuming the outmoded old. The zombie horde then become a darkly humorous vision of hippie communalism who are the preferred refuge of the children of the white middle class. But the rebellions of the 1960s went nowhere, hope fading and forgotten. Hippies and campus radicals from middle-class backgrounds grew up to be yuppies, and their influence on the larger culture was mostly a matter of an easily saleable "lifestyle." Once the social upheavals of the 60s had passed, consumerism turned out to be the real winner, so it's entirely appropriate that Romero's second zombie movie, "Dawn of the Dead", takes place in a shopping mall. Here our heroes live a fantasy of commodity abundance and unhinged consumption, whilst the zombies draw inexorably closer, the mall reminding them of their happiest pre-death moments. In this world there is no satisfaction, only lack, the zombie's unquenchable lust for flesh mocking the consumer's unquenchable desires. Then came "Day of the Dead", arguably the best film in the series. Here, 60s radicalism and 70s consumerism are shunted aside in favour for an assault on Reaganism and the military/scientific complex, where pathologically macho soldiers try to keep the zombies at bay whilst scientists try with futility to either "destroy the zombie plague" or "tame the zombies". The film is relentless in its deconstruction of military authoritarianism and scientific claims to supreme authority, but mostly it's the film's treatment of Freud's reality/pleasure principle and its thick fatalism which makes it so unique. Here, the zombies embody a kind of sympathetic, undeveloped and (pre-language, pre-entry-into-the-Symbolic) ego-less desire (they do not know why they want/desire), which contrasts with the libidinal economy and the twisted viciousness of the human characters (who bury the true motivations of their desires and hypocritically stand for social order). Each of Romero's zombie movies were intended to be a snapshot of the decade in which they was released; "Night" the 60s, "Dawn" the 70s and "Day" the 80s. "Land of the Dead", for financial reasons, was released in the 21st century, but it is actually a broad critique of 90s American society. Here, social class and warfare comes to the foreground, the film imagining America as a paranoid bastion of humanity and freedom, standing tall against the "foreign horde". In "Land of the Dead", the ruling class live lives of elegance and supreme wealth in the exclusive and gated high-rises of "Fiddler's Green", while the masses outside do their dirty bidding and scrape by on low incomes, distracting themselves from their worries with sex, drugs, gambling and violence. The leader of this late-capitalist America, a George Bush styled madman out to make the rich richer and who "refuses to negotiate with terrorists", subsists by sending into zombie territory teams of mercenaries who steal zombie loot (he achieves this by distracting the zombies with fireworks- a kind of metaphor for media spectacle and social brainwashing). The zombies themselves are, once again, the good guys, often linked with the rebelling humans who wish to rise up against their overlords. When the zombies break into the city - led by a black zombie of course - it's symbolic of the proletariat finally rising against their masters and demanding restitution and justice, though Romero knows this is but a futile, 1960s pipe dream. He ends the film with the zombies defeated, the humans infected, and the rebels disillusioned, the masses going their separate ways at the end of the film, wandering off into the horizon like so many disillusioned cinematic anti-heroes of cinema's golden age, specifically the existential road movies of the early 1970s. 8.5/10  "Day of the Dead" 8/10  "Land of the Dead", "Dawn of the Dead" 7.5/10  "Night of the Living Dead" Despite their tiny budgets and at times poor acting, these films still operate fairly well as popcorn movies. What elevates them, though, is the allegorical qualities of Romero's trashy plots.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's a fine zombie movie, but not good enough
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Conrad
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Did the perfect zombie (or "ghoul," as this film's antagonists are dubbed) movie spring forth from the head of George Romero fully-formed, or did subsequent iterations simply fail to build on his promising idea? You know the drill even if you are not a zombie connoisseur: the murderous undead are on the loose, and a diverse band of survivors must overcome their disagreements while staving off the hordes. Romero achieves his vision in "Night of the Living Dead" despite financial and technical limitations. Yet the vision itself is so limited that it hardly extends beyond the premise. In this movie, as in many later knock-offs, there is little character development, little consideration of the theological or scientific implications of the situation, and-- despite frequent claims to the contrary and the casting of a black lead actor--little social commentary. The ending is suggestive of the paranoia and pessimism that afflicted many in 1968, but the script's unironic portrayal of women as submissive and incompetent does not indicate a desire to engage with social issues of the day. "Night of the Living Dead" is decent as far as it goes, but it does not go far, and the genre has rarely aimed higher in the nearly 50 years since.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What could I add more?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    GUENOT PHILIPPE (philippe.guenot@dbmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    That's one of the best picture ever for me, overall, not only horror movies...What could I say more, that the other users have already told? I can't find enough words to describe this authentic gem that every movie buff - and not only - have already watched. I saw it a hundred times... A simple story, but so powerful, so efficient, and with no professional actors. No "hollywoodian" actors I mean. The very first scene, where we see an American flag put at the cemetery entry, which can be interpreted as the Vietnam mess - the film was shot in 1968 - is very meaningful for the rest of the film. And typical of this very period. The counter culture one. What I particularly like in this masterpiece is that there is not useless love interest between the characters, for instance Ben and Barbara's ones, as we could have expected. And I appreciate this. Yes, this movies describes the human behavior very well. After all, are the real human creatures better than the dead ones? That's the real question of the movie, that's my opinion. The characters fighting for their lives in the small house are shown in such an intense way...Films made now, in 20... are not so powerful. Sorry. And the final moral, where we finally find that the coward, nasty character - Cooper's one - was damn right, concerning the safety of the basement. All long the film, well almost, he told everyone that the basement was the safest way to stay. Ben, the lead, did not agree, so did the audience who loves this fighting character. And, at the end, that's this very basement that saved Ben. The bad guy was right at the end. That's very unusual. Yes I won't never be tired to watch this movie again and again.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wasn't too impressed by this horror classic, but it was an enjoyable film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bruno Youn
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A decent horror film overall, but I have to say it was a very uneven experience for me. While there are a few aspects I certainly enjoyed here, such as the effective scares, gruesome imagery and the shocking twist at the end, I thought the acting was stale at times and was pretty annoyed by the character of Helen. The film got too didactic and a bit tedious when they began to follow the announcements on TV. The explanation of the origins of the undead was very far-fetched for me and didn't really need to be here. Also, the zombies seemed to be inconsistent as some of them decide to chase people or kill them with objects when they have fresh meat to eat right beside them. Finally, I found many statements given by the characters to be quite obvious or even a bit ridiculous so that also took me out of the film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Grim & Influential.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    George Romero's infamous low budget horror film about the mysterious resurrection of hordes of the walking dead, who are compelled to kill, and consume, the living, became a huge underground hit that inspired a whole new sub genre of horror for those so inclined, not to mention a great many sequels, remakes, spin offs, etc. Though this is, on one level, a starkly effective shocker, the premise is so utterly preposterous, and tone so unmercifully grim and downbeat, with a horribly ironic ending, that it doesn't work for me. The acting is strong though, but film is dispiriting in the extreme, with little to recommend it, though it is a cult classic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This is where the long walk began...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MrGKB
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ...toward the contemporary zombie mythos of "The Walking Dead" and every cannibalistic living dead film in between. I first enjoyed "NotLD" on the big screen way back in the antediluvian days of college, pre- videotape/DVD/BluRay collections, pre-Internet, pre-Androids etal., when Romero's unassuming film was burning up the midnight film circuit and burrowing deep into the collective unconsciousness of horror fans and cinemaphiles everywhere. Little did I know at the time just how influential this little homegrown nightmare would prove to be, but there was no denying its raw power to shock and unsettle unsuspecting audiences, and all on a budget just somewhat above rock bottom. Imagine, if you will, several hundred Boomer college kids packed into a darkened auditorium, most of them likely intoxicated on one thing or another, all eager to see this scary movie that so far they'd only read about. They knew that Roger Ebert hated it, which only made it more alluring. They knew it pushed the boundaries of graphic depictions of murder, and that, too, made it all the more the forbidden fruit. And, perhaps most of all, they knew it wasn't a "Hollywood" movie, and that made its rising star all the brighter. Imagine now that very first viewing of that rough gem in all its lo-fi glory... Almost a half-century later, even the most forgiving retrospectives will admit to the film's flaws; only the most churlish could deny them. The acting is at times--to be polite--unpolished, and the make-up is simply crude by today's standards (one can only wonder how it might have looked had Tom Savini not be dragooned off to Vietnam). The camera-wrangling is well-informed by Romero's prior commercial experience, although eminently bolstered by darkly evocative lighting and editing; the choice to shoot in black-and-white was, of course, a financial one, but turned out to be the serendipitous one as well. I can't even conceive of this film being in color, and have steadfastly refused to ever watch the colorized version. "NotLD" remains a classic example of inspired (and inspiring) make-do indie film-making and quite rightfully deserves its many accolades and awards of honor. It's far from perfect--even the script is a let-down at times, what with its occasionally clunky dialog--but it hits all the right dramatic notes, tapping into a nervous zeitgeist in a way that still works even in a post-9/11 world, and perhaps even more so. If George A. Romero & Co. hadn't made "Night of the Living Dead," I have no doubt that someone else would have eventually come up with something similar. But, he did, and the face of horror and indie cinema in general is all the better for it. Long live the living dead!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Surprisingly good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheGreatAmericanNightmare
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I gave this a 6 considering that it was low budget and late 60's. The acting was really not too bad, all things considered. I don't usually go for "B" movies, but I would have to give this a B+. Definitely the beginning of genre. Glad I watched it. Sometimes just the fact that a movie is black and white is enough to keep me from watching it. I know I need to reexamine that policy. As much as I love movies, I need to give more black and white movies a chance. In the beginning, I thought, "Ooh I don't know if I can hang with this." It seemed a little dopey, but as it progressed I got into it and some of the dialog was actually decent. I've seen modern day low budget flicks that couldn't hold a candle to this one.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The first and still the best
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    usgator
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am not sure how to go about reviewing this movie since it is my favorite of all time. I watch it every Halloween, without fail, as well as several other of this type. We are talking about a 30 year span here and I still love it! As a MAJOR horror movie buff since the age of about 10, this is the ONLY one that ever terrified me. I saw it in an extremely cut version, as a Saturday afternoon TV movie, and it still left a big impression on me. Most of the "gory" scenes were cut but it still scared the heck out of me. Everything about this movie works: from the claustrophobic atmosphere to the black-and-white cinematography ... and everything in between. Director George Romero is, and always will be, the king of the flesh-eating zombie movies. This is the gold star of low budget horror flix. If you have not seen it, and are a horror movie fan, this is a MUST see. Do NOT hesitate, see it now, but remember this movie was made in 1968 and much of the shock value has faded as it has been done in 1000 movies since then. Keep in mind that THIS is the film the pushed the "gore" envelope and was the first modern zombie horror film and you can not help but be impressed. Once you see it you will also be compelled to see Romero's equally good sequels ... "Dawn of the Dead" (1978), "Day of the Dead" (1985) and "Land of the Dead" (2005). The other 2 ("Diary.." and "Survival ..") are not up to par, but still better than most of the other movies of this genre, no matter what the "critics" on IMDb say. In closing, I cannot recommend this film enough for the serious, and open minded, horror movie fan.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Great Accomplishment
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wfjohnston14
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Night of the Living Dead is a shocking film in many ways (not taken to be a pun) as it delivers good horror for a very low budget. When Barbara goes to deliver flowers to a grave, her brother is attacked by a zombie and she goes running to a nearby house where she is greeted by a black man named Ben. Then more people come to the house and are trapped inside the house as zombies start to come and attack the house. The group of people must out live the night and hopefully not die from the zombies or themselves. Night of the Living dead is a great accomplishment as it had a budget of $116,000 and made it count. There are so many big budget films that are wasted and this little budget film does not. It has some rather gross zombie scenes, not from the appearance of the zombies, but what they do as one scene they eat the body parts of one of the men and you watch as they tear of the flesh from the arm and chop it down. It's already cut of and now the appearance is rather gross, even for black and white film. The film has a very good climax as the zombies start to enter the house and the little girl finally transforms into a zombie and attacks her parents. Now Ben fights them off and kills the family as they all turn into zombies. Yay for the hero. But wait, it's not over as the police raid the area the next morning with zombie hunters and when Ben escapes the basement to get away from this place, is shot down as one of the hunters think he is a slow moving flesh eater and the happy ending turns tragic. Night of the Living Dead is a brilliant horror movie and does what so many other horrors films should do, be gross and fun. Grade: A
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    classic zombie fest or feast
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kai ringler
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It took me along time to watch this classic, I've seen more of the modern zombie movies over the past 20 years. and after each viewing of said movies I've always thought you know I should give the original masterpiece a try. I thoroughly enjoyed it, I didn't mind that the zombies were slow and hard to understand,, this movie was groundbreaking at the time so I didn't expect a lot of zombie attack action,, the opening scene is frightening to a point. especially in the graveyard. eventually our heroine makes it back to a farmhouse after seeing her brother be left for dead by a zombie, there she meets a black man who kinda runs the house,, together they try and board up all the doors and windows.. later on in the basement there is another family down there taking care of a sick child, and this is where things start to get interesting bickering , arguing amongst the men as to the best way to defend the house, and whether to stay on the top floor of the house or be in the basement,, watch and find out whose idea was better. i'm glad I've seen this movie and have watched it twice and will many more times.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Reality Bites
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tieman64
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "I was trying to come up with a concept about a new society, revolutionary...in political terms, that's taking over and devouring the old society."  George A. Romero George Romero's "Night Of The Living Dead" marked the implosion of the white, middle class, American nuclear family and portrayed the collapse of post-war patriarchal authority into a kind of mad hysteria. What followed - the sexual, political and social "revolutions" of the 1960s - were not so much rebellions against tyrannical paternal and political despots, or against the rigid repressions of suburban family life, as they were carnivalesque revelations that the emperor had no clothes. That 1950s suburbia offered nothing but hypocrisy and fake decor. As such, Romero has his nuclear family holed up in a farmhouse - the impotence of the father mirroring the clownishness and impotence of various authority figures on his television screen - until the unit collapses under the weight of its own stupidity and children-turned-zombies avidly consume their own parents. As is always the case with Romero, the zombies are actually the good guys, the new zombie order literally consuming the outmoded old. The zombie horde then become a darkly humorous vision of hippie communalism who are the preferred refuge of the children of the white middle class. But the rebellions of the 1960s went nowhere, hope fading and forgotten. Hippies and campus radicals from middle-class backgrounds grew up to be yuppies, and their influence on the larger culture was mostly a matter of an easily saleable "lifestyle." Once the social upheavals of the 60s had passed, consumerism turned out to be the real winner, so it's entirely appropriate that Romero's second zombie movie, "Dawn of the Dead", takes place in a shopping mall. Here our heroes live a fantasy of commodity abundance and unhinged consumption, whilst the zombies draw inexorably closer, the mall reminding them of their happiest pre-death moments. In this world there is no satisfaction, only lack, the zombie's unquenchable lust for flesh mocking the consumer's unquenchable desires. Then came "Day of the Dead", arguably the best film in the series. Here, 60s radicalism and 70s consumerism are shunted aside in favour for an assault on Reaganism and the military/scientific complex, where pathologically macho soldiers try to keep the zombies at bay whilst scientists try with futility to either "destroy the zombie plague" or "tame the zombies". The film is relentless in its deconstruction of military authoritarianism and scientific claims to supreme authority, but mostly it's the film's treatment of Freud's reality/pleasure principle and its thick fatalism which makes it so unique. Here, the zombies embody a kind of sympathetic, undeveloped and (pre-language, pre-entry-into-the-Symbolic) ego-less desire (they do not know why they want/desire), which contrasts with the libidinal economy and the twisted viciousness of the human characters (who bury the true motivations of their desires and hypocritically stand for social order). Each of Romero's zombie movies were intended to be a snapshot of the decade in which they was released; "Night" the 60s, "Dawn" the 70s and "Day" the 80s. "Land of the Dead", for financial reasons, was released in the 21st century, but it is actually a broad critique of 90s American society. Here, social class and warfare comes to the foreground, the film imagining America as a paranoid bastion of humanity and freedom, standing tall against the "foreign horde". In "Land of the Dead", the ruling class live lives of elegance and supreme wealth in the exclusive and gated high-rises of "Fiddler's Green", while the masses outside do their dirty bidding and scrape by on low incomes, distracting themselves from their worries with sex, drugs, gambling and violence. The leader of this late-capitalist America, a George Bush styled madman out to make the rich richer and who "refuses to negotiate with terrorists", subsists by sending into zombie territory teams of mercenaries who steal zombie loot (he achieves this by distracting the zombies with fireworks- a kind of metaphor for media spectacle and social brainwashing). The zombies themselves are, once again, the good guys, often linked with the rebelling humans who wish to rise up against their overlords. When the zombies break into the city - led by a black zombie of course - it's symbolic of the proletariat finally rising against their masters and demanding restitution and justice, though Romero knows this is but a futile, 1960s pipe dream. He ends the film with the zombies defeated, the humans infected, and the rebels disillusioned, the masses going their separate ways at the end of the film, wandering off into the horizon like so many disillusioned cinematic anti-heroes of cinema's golden age, specifically the existential road movies of the early 1970s. 8.5/10  "Day of the Dead" 8/10  "Land of the Dead", "Dawn of the Dead" 7.5/10  "Night of the Living Dead" Despite their tiny budgets and at times poor acting, these films still operate fairly well as popcorn movies. What elevates them, though, is the allegorical qualities of Romero's trashy plots.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's a fine zombie movie, but not good enough
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Conrad
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Did the perfect zombie (or "ghoul," as this film's antagonists are dubbed) movie spring forth from the head of George Romero fully-formed, or did subsequent iterations simply fail to build on his promising idea? You know the drill even if you are not a zombie connoisseur: the murderous undead are on the loose, and a diverse band of survivors must overcome their disagreements while staving off the hordes. Romero achieves his vision in "Night of the Living Dead" despite financial and technical limitations. Yet the vision itself is so limited that it hardly extends beyond the premise. In this movie, as in many later knock-offs, there is little character development, little consideration of the theological or scientific implications of the situation, and-- despite frequent claims to the contrary and the casting of a black lead actor--little social commentary. The ending is suggestive of the paranoia and pessimism that afflicted many in 1968, but the script's unironic portrayal of women as submissive and incompetent does not indicate a desire to engage with social issues of the day. "Night of the Living Dead" is decent as far as it goes, but it does not go far, and the genre has rarely aimed higher in the nearly 50 years since.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What could I add more?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    GUENOT PHILIPPE (philippe.guenot@dbmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    That's one of the best picture ever for me, overall, not only horror movies...What could I say more, that the other users have already told? I can't find enough words to describe this authentic gem that every movie buff - and not only - have already watched. I saw it a hundred times... A simple story, but so powerful, so efficient, and with no professional actors. No "hollywoodian" actors I mean. The very first scene, where we see an American flag put at the cemetery entry, which can be interpreted as the Vietnam mess - the film was shot in 1968 - is very meaningful for the rest of the film. And typical of this very period. The counter culture one. What I particularly like in this masterpiece is that there is not useless love interest between the characters, for instance Ben and Barbara's ones, as we could have expected. And I appreciate this. Yes, this movies describes the human behavior very well. After all, are the real human creatures better than the dead ones? That's the real question of the movie, that's my opinion. The characters fighting for their lives in the small house are shown in such an intense way...Films made now, in 20... are not so powerful. Sorry. And the final moral, where we finally find that the coward, nasty character - Cooper's one - was damn right, concerning the safety of the basement. All long the film, well almost, he told everyone that the basement was the safest way to stay. Ben, the lead, did not agree, so did the audience who loves this fighting character. And, at the end, that's this very basement that saved Ben. The bad guy was right at the end. That's very unusual. Yes I won't never be tired to watch this movie again and again.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wasn't too impressed by this horror classic, but it was an enjoyable film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bruno Youn
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A decent horror film overall, but I have to say it was a very uneven experience for me. While there are a few aspects I certainly enjoyed here, such as the effective scares, gruesome imagery and the shocking twist at the end, I thought the acting was stale at times and was pretty annoyed by the character of Helen. The film got too didactic and a bit tedious when they began to follow the announcements on TV. The explanation of the origins of the undead was very far-fetched for me and didn't really need to be here. Also, the zombies seemed to be inconsistent as some of them decide to chase people or kill them with objects when they have fresh meat to eat right beside them. Finally, I found many statements given by the characters to be quite obvious or even a bit ridiculous so that also took me out of the film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Grim & Influential.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    George Romero's infamous low budget horror film about the mysterious resurrection of hordes of the walking dead, who are compelled to kill, and consume, the living, became a huge underground hit that inspired a whole new sub genre of horror for those so inclined, not to mention a great many sequels, remakes, spin offs, etc. Though this is, on one level, a starkly effective shocker, the premise is so utterly preposterous, and tone so unmercifully grim and downbeat, with a horribly ironic ending, that it doesn't work for me. The acting is strong though, but film is dispiriting in the extreme, with little to recommend it, though it is a cult classic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This is where the long walk began...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MrGKB
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ...toward the contemporary zombie mythos of "The Walking Dead" and every cannibalistic living dead film in between. I first enjoyed "NotLD" on the big screen way back in the antediluvian days of college, pre- videotape/DVD/BluRay collections, pre-Internet, pre-Androids etal., when Romero's unassuming film was burning up the midnight film circuit and burrowing deep into the collective unconsciousness of horror fans and cinemaphiles everywhere. Little did I know at the time just how influential this little homegrown nightmare would prove to be, but there was no denying its raw power to shock and unsettle unsuspecting audiences, and all on a budget just somewhat above rock bottom. Imagine, if you will, several hundred Boomer college kids packed into a darkened auditorium, most of them likely intoxicated on one thing or another, all eager to see this scary movie that so far they'd only read about. They knew that Roger Ebert hated it, which only made it more alluring. They knew it pushed the boundaries of graphic depictions of murder, and that, too, made it all the more the forbidden fruit. And, perhaps most of all, they knew it wasn't a "Hollywood" movie, and that made its rising star all the brighter. Imagine now that very first viewing of that rough gem in all its lo-fi glory... Almost a half-century later, even the most forgiving retrospectives will admit to the film's flaws; only the most churlish could deny them. The acting is at times--to be polite--unpolished, and the make-up is simply crude by today's standards (one can only wonder how it might have looked had Tom Savini not be dragooned off to Vietnam). The camera-wrangling is well-informed by Romero's prior commercial experience, although eminently bolstered by darkly evocative lighting and editing; the choice to shoot in black-and-white was, of course, a financial one, but turned out to be the serendipitous one as well. I can't even conceive of this film being in color, and have steadfastly refused to ever watch the colorized version. "NotLD" remains a classic example of inspired (and inspiring) make-do indie film-making and quite rightfully deserves its many accolades and awards of honor. It's far from perfect--even the script is a let-down at times, what with its occasionally clunky dialog--but it hits all the right dramatic notes, tapping into a nervous zeitgeist in a way that still works even in a post-9/11 world, and perhaps even more so. If George A. Romero & Co. hadn't made "Night of the Living Dead," I have no doubt that someone else would have eventually come up with something similar. But, he did, and the face of horror and indie cinema in general is all the better for it. Long live the living dead!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Surprisingly good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheGreatAmericanNightmare
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I gave this a 6 considering that it was low budget and late 60's. The acting was really not too bad, all things considered. I don't usually go for "B" movies, but I would have to give this a B+. Definitely the beginning of genre. Glad I watched it. Sometimes just the fact that a movie is black and white is enough to keep me from watching it. I know I need to reexamine that policy. As much as I love movies, I need to give more black and white movies a chance. In the beginning, I thought, "Ooh I don't know if I can hang with this." It seemed a little dopey, but as it progressed I got into it and some of the dialog was actually decent. I've seen modern day low budget flicks that couldn't hold a candle to this one.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The first and still the best
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    usgator
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am not sure how to go about reviewing this movie since it is my favorite of all time. I watch it every Halloween, without fail, as well as several other of this type. We are talking about a 30 year span here and I still love it! As a MAJOR horror movie buff since the age of about 10, this is the ONLY one that ever terrified me. I saw it in an extremely cut version, as a Saturday afternoon TV movie, and it still left a big impression on me. Most of the "gory" scenes were cut but it still scared the heck out of me. Everything about this movie works: from the claustrophobic atmosphere to the black-and-white cinematography ... and everything in between. Director George Romero is, and always will be, the king of the flesh-eating zombie movies. This is the gold star of low budget horror flix. If you have not seen it, and are a horror movie fan, this is a MUST see. Do NOT hesitate, see it now, but remember this movie was made in 1968 and much of the shock value has faded as it has been done in 1000 movies since then. Keep in mind that THIS is the film the pushed the "gore" envelope and was the first modern zombie horror film and you can not help but be impressed. Once you see it you will also be compelled to see Romero's equally good sequels ... "Dawn of the Dead" (1978), "Day of the Dead" (1985) and "Land of the Dead" (2005). The other 2 ("Diary.." and "Survival ..") are not up to par, but still better than most of the other movies of this genre, no matter what the "critics" on IMDb say. In closing, I cannot recommend this film enough for the serious, and open minded, horror movie fan.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Great Accomplishment
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wfjohnston14
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Night of the Living Dead is a shocking film in many ways (not taken to be a pun) as it delivers good horror for a very low budget. When Barbara goes to deliver flowers to a grave, her brother is attacked by a zombie and she goes running to a nearby house where she is greeted by a black man named Ben. Then more people come to the house and are trapped inside the house as zombies start to come and attack the house. The group of people must out live the night and hopefully not die from the zombies or themselves. Night of the Living dead is a great accomplishment as it had a budget of $116,000 and made it count. There are so many big budget films that are wasted and this little budget film does not. It has some rather gross zombie scenes, not from the appearance of the zombies, but what they do as one scene they eat the body parts of one of the men and you watch as they tear of the flesh from the arm and chop it down. It's already cut of and now the appearance is rather gross, even for black and white film. The film has a very good climax as the zombies start to enter the house and the little girl finally transforms into a zombie and attacks her parents. Now Ben fights them off and kills the family as they all turn into zombies. Yay for the hero. But wait, it's not over as the police raid the area the next morning with zombie hunters and when Ben escapes the basement to get away from this place, is shot down as one of the hunters think he is a slow moving flesh eater and the happy ending turns tragic. Night of the Living Dead is a brilliant horror movie and does what so many other horrors films should do, be gross and fun. Grade: A
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    classic zombie fest or feast
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kai ringler
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It took me along time to watch this classic, I've seen more of the modern zombie movies over the past 20 years. and after each viewing of said movies I've always thought you know I should give the original masterpiece a try. I thoroughly enjoyed it, I didn't mind that the zombies were slow and hard to understand,, this movie was groundbreaking at the time so I didn't expect a lot of zombie attack action,, the opening scene is frightening to a point. especially in the graveyard. eventually our heroine makes it back to a farmhouse after seeing her brother be left for dead by a zombie, there she meets a black man who kinda runs the house,, together they try and board up all the doors and windows.. later on in the basement there is another family down there taking care of a sick child, and this is where things start to get interesting bickering , arguing amongst the men as to the best way to defend the house, and whether to stay on the top floor of the house or be in the basement,, watch and find out whose idea was better. i'm glad I've seen this movie and have watched it twice and will many more times.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Reality Bites
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tieman64
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "I was trying to come up with a concept about a new society, revolutionary...in political terms, that's taking over and devouring the old society."  George A. Romero George Romero's "Night Of The Living Dead" marked the implosion of the white, middle class, American nuclear family and portrayed the collapse of post-war patriarchal authority into a kind of mad hysteria. What followed - the sexual, political and social "revolutions" of the 1960s - were not so much rebellions against tyrannical paternal and political despots, or against the rigid repressions of suburban family life, as they were carnivalesque revelations that the emperor had no clothes. That 1950s suburbia offered nothing but hypocrisy and fake decor. As such, Romero has his nuclear family holed up in a farmhouse - the impotence of the father mirroring the clownishness and impotence of various authority figures on his television screen - until the unit collapses under the weight of its own stupidity and children-turned-zombies avidly consume their own parents. As is always the case with Romero, the zombies are actually the good guys, the new zombie order literally consuming the outmoded old. The zombie horde then become a darkly humorous vision of hippie communalism who are the preferred refuge of the children of the white middle class. But the rebellions of the 1960s went nowhere, hope fading and forgotten. Hippies and campus radicals from middle-class backgrounds grew up to be yuppies, and their influence on the larger culture was mostly a matter of an easily saleable "lifestyle." Once the social upheavals of the 60s had passed, consumerism turned out to be the real winner, so it's entirely appropriate that Romero's second zombie movie, "Dawn of the Dead", takes place in a shopping mall. Here our heroes live a fantasy of commodity abundance and unhinged consumption, whilst the zombies draw inexorably closer, the mall reminding them of their happiest pre-death moments. In this world there is no satisfaction, only lack, the zombie's unquenchable lust for flesh mocking the consumer's unquenchable desires. Then came "Day of the Dead", arguably the best film in the series. Here, 60s radicalism and 70s consumerism are shunted aside in favour for an assault on Reaganism and the military/scientific complex, where pathologically macho soldiers try to keep the zombies at bay whilst scientists try with futility to either "destroy the zombie plague" or "tame the zombies". The film is relentless in its deconstruction of military authoritarianism and scientific claims to supreme authority, but mostly it's the film's treatment of Freud's reality/pleasure principle and its thick fatalism which makes it so unique. Here, the zombies embody a kind of sympathetic, undeveloped and (pre-language, pre-entry-into-the-Symbolic) ego-less desire (they do not know why they want/desire), which contrasts with the libidinal economy and the twisted viciousness of the human characters (who bury the true motivations of their desires and hypocritically stand for social order). Each of Romero's zombie movies were intended to be a snapshot of the decade in which they was released; "Night" the 60s, "Dawn" the 70s and "Day" the 80s. "Land of the Dead", for financial reasons, was released in the 21st century, but it is actually a broad critique of 90s American society. Here, social class and warfare comes to the foreground, the film imagining America as a paranoid bastion of humanity and freedom, standing tall against the "foreign horde". In "Land of the Dead", the ruling class live lives of elegance and supreme wealth in the exclusive and gated high-rises of "Fiddler's Green", while the masses outside do their dirty bidding and scrape by on low incomes, distracting themselves from their worries with sex, drugs, gambling and violence. The leader of this late-capitalist America, a George Bush styled madman out to make the rich richer and who "refuses to negotiate with terrorists", subsists by sending into zombie territory teams of mercenaries who steal zombie loot (he achieves this by distracting the zombies with fireworks- a kind of metaphor for media spectacle and social brainwashing). The zombies themselves are, once again, the good guys, often linked with the rebelling humans who wish to rise up against their overlords. When the zombies break into the city - led by a black zombie of course - it's symbolic of the proletariat finally rising against their masters and demanding restitution and justice, though Romero knows this is but a futile, 1960s pipe dream. He ends the film with the zombies defeated, the humans infected, and the rebels disillusioned, the masses going their separate ways at the end of the film, wandering off into the horizon like so many disillusioned cinematic anti-heroes of cinema's golden age, specifically the existential road movies of the early 1970s. 8.5/10  "Day of the Dead" 8/10  "Land of the Dead", "Dawn of the Dead" 7.5/10  "Night of the Living Dead" Despite their tiny budgets and at times poor acting, these films still operate fairly well as popcorn movies. What elevates them, though, is the allegorical qualities of Romero's trashy plots.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's a fine zombie movie, but not good enough
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Conrad
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Did the perfect zombie (or "ghoul," as this film's antagonists are dubbed) movie spring forth from the head of George Romero fully-formed, or did subsequent iterations simply fail to build on his promising idea? You know the drill even if you are not a zombie connoisseur: the murderous undead are on the loose, and a diverse band of survivors must overcome their disagreements while staving off the hordes. Romero achieves his vision in "Night of the Living Dead" despite financial and technical limitations. Yet the vision itself is so limited that it hardly extends beyond the premise. In this movie, as in many later knock-offs, there is little character development, little consideration of the theological or scientific implications of the situation, and-- despite frequent claims to the contrary and the casting of a black lead actor--little social commentary. The ending is suggestive of the paranoia and pessimism that afflicted many in 1968, but the script's unironic portrayal of women as submissive and incompetent does not indicate a desire to engage with social issues of the day. "Night of the Living Dead" is decent as far as it goes, but it does not go far, and the genre has rarely aimed higher in the nearly 50 years since.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What could I add more?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    GUENOT PHILIPPE (philippe.guenot@dbmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    That's one of the best picture ever for me, overall, not only horror movies...What could I say more, that the other users have already told? I can't find enough words to describe this authentic gem that every movie buff - and not only - have already watched. I saw it a hundred times... A simple story, but so powerful, so efficient, and with no professional actors. No "hollywoodian" actors I mean. The very first scene, where we see an American flag put at the cemetery entry, which can be interpreted as the Vietnam mess - the film was shot in 1968 - is very meaningful for the rest of the film. And typical of this very period. The counter culture one. What I particularly like in this masterpiece is that there is not useless love interest between the characters, for instance Ben and Barbara's ones, as we could have expected. And I appreciate this. Yes, this movies describes the human behavior very well. After all, are the real human creatures better than the dead ones? That's the real question of the movie, that's my opinion. The characters fighting for their lives in the small house are shown in such an intense way...Films made now, in 20... are not so powerful. Sorry. And the final moral, where we finally find that the coward, nasty character - Cooper's one - was damn right, concerning the safety of the basement. All long the film, well almost, he told everyone that the basement was the safest way to stay. Ben, the lead, did not agree, so did the audience who loves this fighting character. And, at the end, that's this very basement that saved Ben. The bad guy was right at the end. That's very unusual. Yes I won't never be tired to watch this movie again and again.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wasn't too impressed by this horror classic, but it was an enjoyable film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bruno Youn
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A decent horror film overall, but I have to say it was a very uneven experience for me. While there are a few aspects I certainly enjoyed here, such as the effective scares, gruesome imagery and the shocking twist at the end, I thought the acting was stale at times and was pretty annoyed by the character of Helen. The film got too didactic and a bit tedious when they began to follow the announcements on TV. The explanation of the origins of the undead was very far-fetched for me and didn't really need to be here. Also, the zombies seemed to be inconsistent as some of them decide to chase people or kill them with objects when they have fresh meat to eat right beside them. Finally, I found many statements given by the characters to be quite obvious or even a bit ridiculous so that also took me out of the film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Grim & Influential.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    George Romero's infamous low budget horror film about the mysterious resurrection of hordes of the walking dead, who are compelled to kill, and consume, the living, became a huge underground hit that inspired a whole new sub genre of horror for those so inclined, not to mention a great many sequels, remakes, spin offs, etc. Though this is, on one level, a starkly effective shocker, the premise is so utterly preposterous, and tone so unmercifully grim and downbeat, with a horribly ironic ending, that it doesn't work for me. The acting is strong though, but film is dispiriting in the extreme, with little to recommend it, though it is a cult classic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This is where the long walk began...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MrGKB
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ...toward the contemporary zombie mythos of "The Walking Dead" and every cannibalistic living dead film in between. I first enjoyed "NotLD" on the big screen way back in the antediluvian days of college, pre- videotape/DVD/BluRay collections, pre-Internet, pre-Androids etal., when Romero's unassuming film was burning up the midnight film circuit and burrowing deep into the collective unconsciousness of horror fans and cinemaphiles everywhere. Little did I know at the time just how influential this little homegrown nightmare would prove to be, but there was no denying its raw power to shock and unsettle unsuspecting audiences, and all on a budget just somewhat above rock bottom. Imagine, if you will, several hundred Boomer college kids packed into a darkened auditorium, most of them likely intoxicated on one thing or another, all eager to see this scary movie that so far they'd only read about. They knew that Roger Ebert hated it, which only made it more alluring. They knew it pushed the boundaries of graphic depictions of murder, and that, too, made it all the more the forbidden fruit. And, perhaps most of all, they knew it wasn't a "Hollywood" movie, and that made its rising star all the brighter. Imagine now that very first viewing of that rough gem in all its lo-fi glory... Almost a half-century later, even the most forgiving retrospectives will admit to the film's flaws; only the most churlish could deny them. The acting is at times--to be polite--unpolished, and the make-up is simply crude by today's standards (one can only wonder how it might have looked had Tom Savini not be dragooned off to Vietnam). The camera-wrangling is well-informed by Romero's prior commercial experience, although eminently bolstered by darkly evocative lighting and editing; the choice to shoot in black-and-white was, of course, a financial one, but turned out to be the serendipitous one as well. I can't even conceive of this film being in color, and have steadfastly refused to ever watch the colorized version. "NotLD" remains a classic example of inspired (and inspiring) make-do indie film-making and quite rightfully deserves its many accolades and awards of honor. It's far from perfect--even the script is a let-down at times, what with its occasionally clunky dialog--but it hits all the right dramatic notes, tapping into a nervous zeitgeist in a way that still works even in a post-9/11 world, and perhaps even more so. If George A. Romero & Co. hadn't made "Night of the Living Dead," I have no doubt that someone else would have eventually come up with something similar. But, he did, and the face of horror and indie cinema in general is all the better for it. Long live the living dead!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Surprisingly good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheGreatAmericanNightmare
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I gave this a 6 considering that it was low budget and late 60's. The acting was really not too bad, all things considered. I don't usually go for "B" movies, but I would have to give this a B+. Definitely the beginning of genre. Glad I watched it. Sometimes just the fact that a movie is black and white is enough to keep me from watching it. I know I need to reexamine that policy. As much as I love movies, I need to give more black and white movies a chance. In the beginning, I thought, "Ooh I don't know if I can hang with this." It seemed a little dopey, but as it progressed I got into it and some of the dialog was actually decent. I've seen modern day low budget flicks that couldn't hold a candle to this one.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The first and still the best
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    usgator
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am not sure how to go about reviewing this movie since it is my favorite of all time. I watch it every Halloween, without fail, as well as several other of this type. We are talking about a 30 year span here and I still love it! As a MAJOR horror movie buff since the age of about 10, this is the ONLY one that ever terrified me. I saw it in an extremely cut version, as a Saturday afternoon TV movie, and it still left a big impression on me. Most of the "gory" scenes were cut but it still scared the heck out of me. Everything about this movie works: from the claustrophobic atmosphere to the black-and-white cinematography ... and everything in between. Director George Romero is, and always will be, the king of the flesh-eating zombie movies. This is the gold star of low budget horror flix. If you have not seen it, and are a horror movie fan, this is a MUST see. Do NOT hesitate, see it now, but remember this movie was made in 1968 and much of the shock value has faded as it has been done in 1000 movies since then. Keep in mind that THIS is the film the pushed the "gore" envelope and was the first modern zombie horror film and you can not help but be impressed. Once you see it you will also be compelled to see Romero's equally good sequels ... "Dawn of the Dead" (1978), "Day of the Dead" (1985) and "Land of the Dead" (2005). The other 2 ("Diary.." and "Survival ..") are not up to par, but still better than most of the other movies of this genre, no matter what the "critics" on IMDb say. In closing, I cannot recommend this film enough for the serious, and open minded, horror movie fan.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Great Accomplishment
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wfjohnston14
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Night of the Living Dead is a shocking film in many ways (not taken to be a pun) as it delivers good horror for a very low budget. When Barbara goes to deliver flowers to a grave, her brother is attacked by a zombie and she goes running to a nearby house where she is greeted by a black man named Ben. Then more people come to the house and are trapped inside the house as zombies start to come and attack the house. The group of people must out live the night and hopefully not die from the zombies or themselves. Night of the Living dead is a great accomplishment as it had a budget of $116,000 and made it count. There are so many big budget films that are wasted and this little budget film does not. It has some rather gross zombie scenes, not from the appearance of the zombies, but what they do as one scene they eat the body parts of one of the men and you watch as they tear of the flesh from the arm and chop it down. It's already cut of and now the appearance is rather gross, even for black and white film. The film has a very good climax as the zombies start to enter the house and the little girl finally transforms into a zombie and attacks her parents. Now Ben fights them off and kills the family as they all turn into zombies. Yay for the hero. But wait, it's not over as the police raid the area the next morning with zombie hunters and when Ben escapes the basement to get away from this place, is shot down as one of the hunters think he is a slow moving flesh eater and the happy ending turns tragic. Night of the Living Dead is a brilliant horror movie and does what so many other horrors films should do, be gross and fun. Grade: A
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    classic zombie fest or feast
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kai ringler
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It took me along time to watch this classic, I've seen more of the modern zombie movies over the past 20 years. and after each viewing of said movies I've always thought you know I should give the original masterpiece a try. I thoroughly enjoyed it, I didn't mind that the zombies were slow and hard to understand,, this movie was groundbreaking at the time so I didn't expect a lot of zombie attack action,, the opening scene is frightening to a point. especially in the graveyard. eventually our heroine makes it back to a farmhouse after seeing her brother be left for dead by a zombie, there she meets a black man who kinda runs the house,, together they try and board up all the doors and windows.. later on in the basement there is another family down there taking care of a sick child, and this is where things start to get interesting bickering , arguing amongst the men as to the best way to defend the house, and whether to stay on the top floor of the house or be in the basement,, watch and find out whose idea was better. i'm glad I've seen this movie and have watched it twice and will many more times.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Reality Bites
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tieman64
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "I was trying to come up with a concept about a new society, revolutionary...in political terms, that's taking over and devouring the old society."  George A. Romero George Romero's "Night Of The Living Dead" marked the implosion of the white, middle class, American nuclear family and portrayed the collapse of post-war patriarchal authority into a kind of mad hysteria. What followed - the sexual, political and social "revolutions" of the 1960s - were not so much rebellions against tyrannical paternal and political despots, or against the rigid repressions of suburban family life, as they were carnivalesque revelations that the emperor had no clothes. That 1950s suburbia offered nothing but hypocrisy and fake decor. As such, Romero has his nuclear family holed up in a farmhouse - the impotence of the father mirroring the clownishness and impotence of various authority figures on his television screen - until the unit collapses under the weight of its own stupidity and children-turned-zombies avidly consume their own parents. As is always the case with Romero, the zombies are actually the good guys, the new zombie order literally consuming the outmoded old. The zombie horde then become a darkly humorous vision of hippie communalism who are the preferred refuge of the children of the white middle class. But the rebellions of the 1960s went nowhere, hope fading and forgotten. Hippies and campus radicals from middle-class backgrounds grew up to be yuppies, and their influence on the larger culture was mostly a matter of an easily saleable "lifestyle." Once the social upheavals of the 60s had passed, consumerism turned out to be the real winner, so it's entirely appropriate that Romero's second zombie movie, "Dawn of the Dead", takes place in a shopping mall. Here our heroes live a fantasy of commodity abundance and unhinged consumption, whilst the zombies draw inexorably closer, the mall reminding them of their happiest pre-death moments. In this world there is no satisfaction, only lack, the zombie's unquenchable lust for flesh mocking the consumer's unquenchable desires. Then came "Day of the Dead", arguably the best film in the series. Here, 60s radicalism and 70s consumerism are shunted aside in favour for an assault on Reaganism and the military/scientific complex, where pathologically macho soldiers try to keep the zombies at bay whilst scientists try with futility to either "destroy the zombie plague" or "tame the zombies". The film is relentless in its deconstruction of military authoritarianism and scientific claims to supreme authority, but mostly it's the film's treatment of Freud's reality/pleasure principle and its thick fatalism which makes it so unique. Here, the zombies embody a kind of sympathetic, undeveloped and (pre-language, pre-entry-into-the-Symbolic) ego-less desire (they do not know why they want/desire), which contrasts with the libidinal economy and the twisted viciousness of the human characters (who bury the true motivations of their desires and hypocritically stand for social order). Each of Romero's zombie movies were intended to be a snapshot of the decade in which they was released; "Night" the 60s, "Dawn" the 70s and "Day" the 80s. "Land of the Dead", for financial reasons, was released in the 21st century, but it is actually a broad critique of 90s American society. Here, social class and warfare comes to the foreground, the film imagining America as a paranoid bastion of humanity and freedom, standing tall against the "foreign horde". In "Land of the Dead", the ruling class live lives of elegance and supreme wealth in the exclusive and gated high-rises of "Fiddler's Green", while the masses outside do their dirty bidding and scrape by on low incomes, distracting themselves from their worries with sex, drugs, gambling and violence. The leader of this late-capitalist America, a George Bush styled madman out to make the rich richer and who "refuses to negotiate with terrorists", subsists by sending into zombie territory teams of mercenaries who steal zombie loot (he achieves this by distracting the zombies with fireworks- a kind of metaphor for media spectacle and social brainwashing). The zombies themselves are, once again, the good guys, often linked with the rebelling humans who wish to rise up against their overlords. When the zombies break into the city - led by a black zombie of course - it's symbolic of the proletariat finally rising against their masters and demanding restitution and justice, though Romero knows this is but a futile, 1960s pipe dream. He ends the film with the zombies defeated, the humans infected, and the rebels disillusioned, the masses going their separate ways at the end of the film, wandering off into the horizon like so many disillusioned cinematic anti-heroes of cinema's golden age, specifically the existential road movies of the early 1970s. 8.5/10  "Day of the Dead" 8/10  "Land of the Dead", "Dawn of the Dead" 7.5/10  "Night of the Living Dead" Despite their tiny budgets and at times poor acting, these films still operate fairly well as popcorn movies. What elevates them, though, is the allegorical qualities of Romero's trashy plots.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's a fine zombie movie, but not good enough
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Conrad
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Did the perfect zombie (or "ghoul," as this film's antagonists are dubbed) movie spring forth from the head of George Romero fully-formed, or did subsequent iterations simply fail to build on his promising idea? You know the drill even if you are not a zombie connoisseur: the murderous undead are on the loose, and a diverse band of survivors must overcome their disagreements while staving off the hordes. Romero achieves his vision in "Night of the Living Dead" despite financial and technical limitations. Yet the vision itself is so limited that it hardly extends beyond the premise. In this movie, as in many later knock-offs, there is little character development, little consideration of the theological or scientific implications of the situation, and-- despite frequent claims to the contrary and the casting of a black lead actor--little social commentary. The ending is suggestive of the paranoia and pessimism that afflicted many in 1968, but the script's unironic portrayal of women as submissive and incompetent does not indicate a desire to engage with social issues of the day. "Night of the Living Dead" is decent as far as it goes, but it does not go far, and the genre has rarely aimed higher in the nearly 50 years since.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What could I add more?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    GUENOT PHILIPPE (philippe.guenot@dbmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    That's one of the best picture ever for me, overall, not only horror movies...What could I say more, that the other users have already told? I can't find enough words to describe this authentic gem that every movie buff - and not only - have already watched. I saw it a hundred times... A simple story, but so powerful, so efficient, and with no professional actors. No "hollywoodian" actors I mean. The very first scene, where we see an American flag put at the cemetery entry, which can be interpreted as the Vietnam mess - the film was shot in 1968 - is very meaningful for the rest of the film. And typical of this very period. The counter culture one. What I particularly like in this masterpiece is that there is not useless love interest between the characters, for instance Ben and Barbara's ones, as we could have expected. And I appreciate this. Yes, this movies describes the human behavior very well. After all, are the real human creatures better than the dead ones? That's the real question of the movie, that's my opinion. The characters fighting for their lives in the small house are shown in such an intense way...Films made now, in 20... are not so powerful. Sorry. And the final moral, where we finally find that the coward, nasty character - Cooper's one - was damn right, concerning the safety of the basement. All long the film, well almost, he told everyone that the basement was the safest way to stay. Ben, the lead, did not agree, so did the audience who loves this fighting character. And, at the end, that's this very basement that saved Ben. The bad guy was right at the end. That's very unusual. Yes I won't never be tired to watch this movie again and again.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wasn't too impressed by this horror classic, but it was an enjoyable film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bruno Youn
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A decent horror film overall, but I have to say it was a very uneven experience for me. While there are a few aspects I certainly enjoyed here, such as the effective scares, gruesome imagery and the shocking twist at the end, I thought the acting was stale at times and was pretty annoyed by the character of Helen. The film got too didactic and a bit tedious when they began to follow the announcements on TV. The explanation of the origins of the undead was very far-fetched for me and didn't really need to be here. Also, the zombies seemed to be inconsistent as some of them decide to chase people or kill them with objects when they have fresh meat to eat right beside them. Finally, I found many statements given by the characters to be quite obvious or even a bit ridiculous so that also took me out of the film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Grim & Influential.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    George Romero's infamous low budget horror film about the mysterious resurrection of hordes of the walking dead, who are compelled to kill, and consume, the living, became a huge underground hit that inspired a whole new sub genre of horror for those so inclined, not to mention a great many sequels, remakes, spin offs, etc. Though this is, on one level, a starkly effective shocker, the premise is so utterly preposterous, and tone so unmercifully grim and downbeat, with a horribly ironic ending, that it doesn't work for me. The acting is strong though, but film is dispiriting in the extreme, with little to recommend it, though it is a cult classic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This is where the long walk began...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MrGKB
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ...toward the contemporary zombie mythos of "The Walking Dead" and every cannibalistic living dead film in between. I first enjoyed "NotLD" on the big screen way back in the antediluvian days of college, pre- videotape/DVD/BluRay collections, pre-Internet, pre-Androids etal., when Romero's unassuming film was burning up the midnight film circuit and burrowing deep into the collective unconsciousness of horror fans and cinemaphiles everywhere. Little did I know at the time just how influential this little homegrown nightmare would prove to be, but there was no denying its raw power to shock and unsettle unsuspecting audiences, and all on a budget just somewhat above rock bottom. Imagine, if you will, several hundred Boomer college kids packed into a darkened auditorium, most of them likely intoxicated on one thing or another, all eager to see this scary movie that so far they'd only read about. They knew that Roger Ebert hated it, which only made it more alluring. They knew it pushed the boundaries of graphic depictions of murder, and that, too, made it all the more the forbidden fruit. And, perhaps most of all, they knew it wasn't a "Hollywood" movie, and that made its rising star all the brighter. Imagine now that very first viewing of that rough gem in all its lo-fi glory... Almost a half-century later, even the most forgiving retrospectives will admit to the film's flaws; only the most churlish could deny them. The acting is at times--to be polite--unpolished, and the make-up is simply crude by today's standards (one can only wonder how it might have looked had Tom Savini not be dragooned off to Vietnam). The camera-wrangling is well-informed by Romero's prior commercial experience, although eminently bolstered by darkly evocative lighting and editing; the choice to shoot in black-and-white was, of course, a financial one, but turned out to be the serendipitous one as well. I can't even conceive of this film being in color, and have steadfastly refused to ever watch the colorized version. "NotLD" remains a classic example of inspired (and inspiring) make-do indie film-making and quite rightfully deserves its many accolades and awards of honor. It's far from perfect--even the script is a let-down at times, what with its occasionally clunky dialog--but it hits all the right dramatic notes, tapping into a nervous zeitgeist in a way that still works even in a post-9/11 world, and perhaps even more so. If George A. Romero & Co. hadn't made "Night of the Living Dead," I have no doubt that someone else would have eventually come up with something similar. But, he did, and the face of horror and indie cinema in general is all the better for it. Long live the living dead!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Surprisingly good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheGreatAmericanNightmare
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I gave this a 6 considering that it was low budget and late 60's. The acting was really not too bad, all things considered. I don't usually go for "B" movies, but I would have to give this a B+. Definitely the beginning of genre. Glad I watched it. Sometimes just the fact that a movie is black and white is enough to keep me from watching it. I know I need to reexamine that policy. As much as I love movies, I need to give more black and white movies a chance. In the beginning, I thought, "Ooh I don't know if I can hang with this." It seemed a little dopey, but as it progressed I got into it and some of the dialog was actually decent. I've seen modern day low budget flicks that couldn't hold a candle to this one.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The first and still the best
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    usgator
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am not sure how to go about reviewing this movie since it is my favorite of all time. I watch it every Halloween, without fail, as well as several other of this type. We are talking about a 30 year span here and I still love it! As a MAJOR horror movie buff since the age of about 10, this is the ONLY one that ever terrified me. I saw it in an extremely cut version, as a Saturday afternoon TV movie, and it still left a big impression on me. Most of the "gory" scenes were cut but it still scared the heck out of me. Everything about this movie works: from the claustrophobic atmosphere to the black-and-white cinematography ... and everything in between. Director George Romero is, and always will be, the king of the flesh-eating zombie movies. This is the gold star of low budget horror flix. If you have not seen it, and are a horror movie fan, this is a MUST see. Do NOT hesitate, see it now, but remember this movie was made in 1968 and much of the shock value has faded as it has been done in 1000 movies since then. Keep in mind that THIS is the film the pushed the "gore" envelope and was the first modern zombie horror film and you can not help but be impressed. Once you see it you will also be compelled to see Romero's equally good sequels ... "Dawn of the Dead" (1978), "Day of the Dead" (1985) and "Land of the Dead" (2005). The other 2 ("Diary.." and "Survival ..") are not up to par, but still better than most of the other movies of this genre, no matter what the "critics" on IMDb say. In closing, I cannot recommend this film enough for the serious, and open minded, horror movie fan.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Great Accomplishment
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wfjohnston14
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Night of the Living Dead is a shocking film in many ways (not taken to be a pun) as it delivers good horror for a very low budget. When Barbara goes to deliver flowers to a grave, her brother is attacked by a zombie and she goes running to a nearby house where she is greeted by a black man named Ben. Then more people come to the house and are trapped inside the house as zombies start to come and attack the house. The group of people must out live the night and hopefully not die from the zombies or themselves. Night of the Living dead is a great accomplishment as it had a budget of $116,000 and made it count. There are so many big budget films that are wasted and this little budget film does not. It has some rather gross zombie scenes, not from the appearance of the zombies, but what they do as one scene they eat the body parts of one of the men and you watch as they tear of the flesh from the arm and chop it down. It's already cut of and now the appearance is rather gross, even for black and white film. The film has a very good climax as the zombies start to enter the house and the little girl finally transforms into a zombie and attacks her parents. Now Ben fights them off and kills the family as they all turn into zombies. Yay for the hero. But wait, it's not over as the police raid the area the next morning with zombie hunters and when Ben escapes the basement to get away from this place, is shot down as one of the hunters think he is a slow moving flesh eater and the happy ending turns tragic. Night of the Living Dead is a brilliant horror movie and does what so many other horrors films should do, be gross and fun. Grade: A
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    classic zombie fest or feast
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kai ringler
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It took me along time to watch this classic, I've seen more of the modern zombie movies over the past 20 years. and after each viewing of said movies I've always thought you know I should give the original masterpiece a try. I thoroughly enjoyed it, I didn't mind that the zombies were slow and hard to understand,, this movie was groundbreaking at the time so I didn't expect a lot of zombie attack action,, the opening scene is frightening to a point. especially in the graveyard. eventually our heroine makes it back to a farmhouse after seeing her brother be left for dead by a zombie, there she meets a black man who kinda runs the house,, together they try and board up all the doors and windows.. later on in the basement there is another family down there taking care of a sick child, and this is where things start to get interesting bickering , arguing amongst the men as to the best way to defend the house, and whether to stay on the top floor of the house or be in the basement,, watch and find out whose idea was better. i'm glad I've seen this movie and have watched it twice and will many more times.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Reality Bites
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tieman64
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "I was trying to come up with a concept about a new society, revolutionary...in political terms, that's taking over and devouring the old society."  George A. Romero George Romero's "Night Of The Living Dead" marked the implosion of the white, middle class, American nuclear family and portrayed the collapse of post-war patriarchal authority into a kind of mad hysteria. What followed - the sexual, political and social "revolutions" of the 1960s - were not so much rebellions against tyrannical paternal and political despots, or against the rigid repressions of suburban family life, as they were carnivalesque revelations that the emperor had no clothes. That 1950s suburbia offered nothing but hypocrisy and fake decor. As such, Romero has his nuclear family holed up in a farmhouse - the impotence of the father mirroring the clownishness and impotence of various authority figures on his television screen - until the unit collapses under the weight of its own stupidity and children-turned-zombies avidly consume their own parents. As is always the case with Romero, the zombies are actually the good guys, the new zombie order literally consuming the outmoded old. The zombie horde then become a darkly humorous vision of hippie communalism who are the preferred refuge of the children of the white middle class. But the rebellions of the 1960s went nowhere, hope fading and forgotten. Hippies and campus radicals from middle-class backgrounds grew up to be yuppies, and their influence on the larger culture was mostly a matter of an easily saleable "lifestyle." Once the social upheavals of the 60s had passed, consumerism turned out to be the real winner, so it's entirely appropriate that Romero's second zombie movie, "Dawn of the Dead", takes place in a shopping mall. Here our heroes live a fantasy of commodity abundance and unhinged consumption, whilst the zombies draw inexorably closer, the mall reminding them of their happiest pre-death moments. In this world there is no satisfaction, only lack, the zombie's unquenchable lust for flesh mocking the consumer's unquenchable desires. Then came "Day of the Dead", arguably the best film in the series. Here, 60s radicalism and 70s consumerism are shunted aside in favour for an assault on Reaganism and the military/scientific complex, where pathologically macho soldiers try to keep the zombies at bay whilst scientists try with futility to either "destroy the zombie plague" or "tame the zombies". The film is relentless in its deconstruction of military authoritarianism and scientific claims to supreme authority, but mostly it's the film's treatment of Freud's reality/pleasure principle and its thick fatalism which makes it so unique. Here, the zombies embody a kind of sympathetic, undeveloped and (pre-language, pre-entry-into-the-Symbolic) ego-less desire (they do not know why they want/desire), which contrasts with the libidinal economy and the twisted viciousness of the human characters (who bury the true motivations of their desires and hypocritically stand for social order). Each of Romero's zombie movies were intended to be a snapshot of the decade in which they was released; "Night" the 60s, "Dawn" the 70s and "Day" the 80s. "Land of the Dead", for financial reasons, was released in the 21st century, but it is actually a broad critique of 90s American society. Here, social class and warfare comes to the foreground, the film imagining America as a paranoid bastion of humanity and freedom, standing tall against the "foreign horde". In "Land of the Dead", the ruling class live lives of elegance and supreme wealth in the exclusive and gated high-rises of "Fiddler's Green", while the masses outside do their dirty bidding and scrape by on low incomes, distracting themselves from their worries with sex, drugs, gambling and violence. The leader of this late-capitalist America, a George Bush styled madman out to make the rich richer and who "refuses to negotiate with terrorists", subsists by sending into zombie territory teams of mercenaries who steal zombie loot (he achieves this by distracting the zombies with fireworks- a kind of metaphor for media spectacle and social brainwashing). The zombies themselves are, once again, the good guys, often linked with the rebelling humans who wish to rise up against their overlords. When the zombies break into the city - led by a black zombie of course - it's symbolic of the proletariat finally rising against their masters and demanding restitution and justice, though Romero knows this is but a futile, 1960s pipe dream. He ends the film with the zombies defeated, the humans infected, and the rebels disillusioned, the masses going their separate ways at the end of the film, wandering off into the horizon like so many disillusioned cinematic anti-heroes of cinema's golden age, specifically the existential road movies of the early 1970s. 8.5/10  "Day of the Dead" 8/10  "Land of the Dead", "Dawn of the Dead" 7.5/10  "Night of the Living Dead" Despite their tiny budgets and at times poor acting, these films still operate fairly well as popcorn movies. What elevates them, though, is the allegorical qualities of Romero's trashy plots.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's a fine zombie movie, but not good enough
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Conrad
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Did the perfect zombie (or "ghoul," as this film's antagonists are dubbed) movie spring forth from the head of George Romero fully-formed, or did subsequent iterations simply fail to build on his promising idea? You know the drill even if you are not a zombie connoisseur: the murderous undead are on the loose, and a diverse band of survivors must overcome their disagreements while staving off the hordes. Romero achieves his vision in "Night of the Living Dead" despite financial and technical limitations. Yet the vision itself is so limited that it hardly extends beyond the premise. In this movie, as in many later knock-offs, there is little character development, little consideration of the theological or scientific implications of the situation, and-- despite frequent claims to the contrary and the casting of a black lead actor--little social commentary. The ending is suggestive of the paranoia and pessimism that afflicted many in 1968, but the script's unironic portrayal of women as submissive and incompetent does not indicate a desire to engage with social issues of the day. "Night of the Living Dead" is decent as far as it goes, but it does not go far, and the genre has rarely aimed higher in the nearly 50 years since.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What could I add more?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    GUENOT PHILIPPE (philippe.guenot@dbmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    That's one of the best picture ever for me, overall, not only horror movies...What could I say more, that the other users have already told? I can't find enough words to describe this authentic gem that every movie buff - and not only - have already watched. I saw it a hundred times... A simple story, but so powerful, so efficient, and with no professional actors. No "hollywoodian" actors I mean. The very first scene, where we see an American flag put at the cemetery entry, which can be interpreted as the Vietnam mess - the film was shot in 1968 - is very meaningful for the rest of the film. And typical of this very period. The counter culture one. What I particularly like in this masterpiece is that there is not useless love interest between the characters, for instance Ben and Barbara's ones, as we could have expected. And I appreciate this. Yes, this movies describes the human behavior very well. After all, are the real human creatures better than the dead ones? That's the real question of the movie, that's my opinion. The characters fighting for their lives in the small house are shown in such an intense way...Films made now, in 20... are not so powerful. Sorry. And the final moral, where we finally find that the coward, nasty character - Cooper's one - was damn right, concerning the safety of the basement. All long the film, well almost, he told everyone that the basement was the safest way to stay. Ben, the lead, did not agree, so did the audience who loves this fighting character. And, at the end, that's this very basement that saved Ben. The bad guy was right at the end. That's very unusual. Yes I won't never be tired to watch this movie again and again.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wasn't too impressed by this horror classic, but it was an enjoyable film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bruno Youn
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A decent horror film overall, but I have to say it was a very uneven experience for me. While there are a few aspects I certainly enjoyed here, such as the effective scares, gruesome imagery and the shocking twist at the end, I thought the acting was stale at times and was pretty annoyed by the character of Helen. The film got too didactic and a bit tedious when they began to follow the announcements on TV. The explanation of the origins of the undead was very far-fetched for me and didn't really need to be here. Also, the zombies seemed to be inconsistent as some of them decide to chase people or kill them with objects when they have fresh meat to eat right beside them. Finally, I found many statements given by the characters to be quite obvious or even a bit ridiculous so that also took me out of the film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Grim & Influential.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    George Romero's infamous low budget horror film about the mysterious resurrection of hordes of the walking dead, who are compelled to kill, and consume, the living, became a huge underground hit that inspired a whole new sub genre of horror for those so inclined, not to mention a great many sequels, remakes, spin offs, etc. Though this is, on one level, a starkly effective shocker, the premise is so utterly preposterous, and tone so unmercifully grim and downbeat, with a horribly ironic ending, that it doesn't work for me. The acting is strong though, but film is dispiriting in the extreme, with little to recommend it, though it is a cult classic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This is where the long walk began...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MrGKB
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ...toward the contemporary zombie mythos of "The Walking Dead" and every cannibalistic living dead film in between. I first enjoyed "NotLD" on the big screen way back in the antediluvian days of college, pre- videotape/DVD/BluRay collections, pre-Internet, pre-Androids etal., when Romero's unassuming film was burning up the midnight film circuit and burrowing deep into the collective unconsciousness of horror fans and cinemaphiles everywhere. Little did I know at the time just how influential this little homegrown nightmare would prove to be, but there was no denying its raw power to shock and unsettle unsuspecting audiences, and all on a budget just somewhat above rock bottom. Imagine, if you will, several hundred Boomer college kids packed into a darkened auditorium, most of them likely intoxicated on one thing or another, all eager to see this scary movie that so far they'd only read about. They knew that Roger Ebert hated it, which only made it more alluring. They knew it pushed the boundaries of graphic depictions of murder, and that, too, made it all the more the forbidden fruit. And, perhaps most of all, they knew it wasn't a "Hollywood" movie, and that made its rising star all the brighter. Imagine now that very first viewing of that rough gem in all its lo-fi glory... Almost a half-century later, even the most forgiving retrospectives will admit to the film's flaws; only the most churlish could deny them. The acting is at times--to be polite--unpolished, and the make-up is simply crude by today's standards (one can only wonder how it might have looked had Tom Savini not be dragooned off to Vietnam). The camera-wrangling is well-informed by Romero's prior commercial experience, although eminently bolstered by darkly evocative lighting and editing; the choice to shoot in black-and-white was, of course, a financial one, but turned out to be the serendipitous one as well. I can't even conceive of this film being in color, and have steadfastly refused to ever watch the colorized version. "NotLD" remains a classic example of inspired (and inspiring) make-do indie film-making and quite rightfully deserves its many accolades and awards of honor. It's far from perfect--even the script is a let-down at times, what with its occasionally clunky dialog--but it hits all the right dramatic notes, tapping into a nervous zeitgeist in a way that still works even in a post-9/11 world, and perhaps even more so. If George A. Romero & Co. hadn't made "Night of the Living Dead," I have no doubt that someone else would have eventually come up with something similar. But, he did, and the face of horror and indie cinema in general is all the better for it. Long live the living dead!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Surprisingly good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheGreatAmericanNightmare
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I gave this a 6 considering that it was low budget and late 60's. The acting was really not too bad, all things considered. I don't usually go for "B" movies, but I would have to give this a B+. Definitely the beginning of genre. Glad I watched it. Sometimes just the fact that a movie is black and white is enough to keep me from watching it. I know I need to reexamine that policy. As much as I love movies, I need to give more black and white movies a chance. In the beginning, I thought, "Ooh I don't know if I can hang with this." It seemed a little dopey, but as it progressed I got into it and some of the dialog was actually decent. I've seen modern day low budget flicks that couldn't hold a candle to this one.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The first and still the best
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    usgator
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am not sure how to go about reviewing this movie since it is my favorite of all time. I watch it every Halloween, without fail, as well as several other of this type. We are talking about a 30 year span here and I still love it! As a MAJOR horror movie buff since the age of about 10, this is the ONLY one that ever terrified me. I saw it in an extremely cut version, as a Saturday afternoon TV movie, and it still left a big impression on me. Most of the "gory" scenes were cut but it still scared the heck out of me. Everything about this movie works: from the claustrophobic atmosphere to the black-and-white cinematography ... and everything in between. Director George Romero is, and always will be, the king of the flesh-eating zombie movies. This is the gold star of low budget horror flix. If you have not seen it, and are a horror movie fan, this is a MUST see. Do NOT hesitate, see it now, but remember this movie was made in 1968 and much of the shock value has faded as it has been done in 1000 movies since then. Keep in mind that THIS is the film the pushed the "gore" envelope and was the first modern zombie horror film and you can not help but be impressed. Once you see it you will also be compelled to see Romero's equally good sequels ... "Dawn of the Dead" (1978), "Day of the Dead" (1985) and "Land of the Dead" (2005). The other 2 ("Diary.." and "Survival ..") are not up to par, but still better than most of the other movies of this genre, no matter what the "critics" on IMDb say. In closing, I cannot recommend this film enough for the serious, and open minded, horror movie fan.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Great Accomplishment
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wfjohnston14
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Night of the Living Dead is a shocking film in many ways (not taken to be a pun) as it delivers good horror for a very low budget. When Barbara goes to deliver flowers to a grave, her brother is attacked by a zombie and she goes running to a nearby house where she is greeted by a black man named Ben. Then more people come to the house and are trapped inside the house as zombies start to come and attack the house. The group of people must out live the night and hopefully not die from the zombies or themselves. Night of the Living dead is a great accomplishment as it had a budget of $116,000 and made it count. There are so many big budget films that are wasted and this little budget film does not. It has some rather gross zombie scenes, not from the appearance of the zombies, but what they do as one scene they eat the body parts of one of the men and you watch as they tear of the flesh from the arm and chop it down. It's already cut of and now the appearance is rather gross, even for black and white film. The film has a very good climax as the zombies start to enter the house and the little girl finally transforms into a zombie and attacks her parents. Now Ben fights them off and kills the family as they all turn into zombies. Yay for the hero. But wait, it's not over as the police raid the area the next morning with zombie hunters and when Ben escapes the basement to get away from this place, is shot down as one of the hunters think he is a slow moving flesh eater and the happy ending turns tragic. Night of the Living Dead is a brilliant horror movie and does what so many other horrors films should do, be gross and fun. Grade: A
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    classic zombie fest or feast
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kai ringler
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It took me along time to watch this classic, I've seen more of the modern zombie movies over the past 20 years. and after each viewing of said movies I've always thought you know I should give the original masterpiece a try. I thoroughly enjoyed it, I didn't mind that the zombies were slow and hard to understand,, this movie was groundbreaking at the time so I didn't expect a lot of zombie attack action,, the opening scene is frightening to a point. especially in the graveyard. eventually our heroine makes it back to a farmhouse after seeing her brother be left for dead by a zombie, there she meets a black man who kinda runs the house,, together they try and board up all the doors and windows.. later on in the basement there is another family down there taking care of a sick child, and this is where things start to get interesting bickering , arguing amongst the men as to the best way to defend the house, and whether to stay on the top floor of the house or be in the basement,, watch and find out whose idea was better. i'm glad I've seen this movie and have watched it twice and will many more times.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Reality Bites
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tieman64
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "I was trying to come up with a concept about a new society, revolutionary...in political terms, that's taking over and devouring the old society."  George A. Romero George Romero's "Night Of The Living Dead" marked the implosion of the white, middle class, American nuclear family and portrayed the collapse of post-war patriarchal authority into a kind of mad hysteria. What followed - the sexual, political and social "revolutions" of the 1960s - were not so much rebellions against tyrannical paternal and political despots, or against the rigid repressions of suburban family life, as they were carnivalesque revelations that the emperor had no clothes. That 1950s suburbia offered nothing but hypocrisy and fake decor. As such, Romero has his nuclear family holed up in a farmhouse - the impotence of the father mirroring the clownishness and impotence of various authority figures on his television screen - until the unit collapses under the weight of its own stupidity and children-turned-zombies avidly consume their own parents. As is always the case with Romero, the zombies are actually the good guys, the new zombie order literally consuming the outmoded old. The zombie horde then become a darkly humorous vision of hippie communalism who are the preferred refuge of the children of the white middle class. But the rebellions of the 1960s went nowhere, hope fading and forgotten. Hippies and campus radicals from middle-class backgrounds grew up to be yuppies, and their influence on the larger culture was mostly a matter of an easily saleable "lifestyle." Once the social upheavals of the 60s had passed, consumerism turned out to be the real winner, so it's entirely appropriate that Romero's second zombie movie, "Dawn of the Dead", takes place in a shopping mall. Here our heroes live a fantasy of commodity abundance and unhinged consumption, whilst the zombies draw inexorably closer, the mall reminding them of their happiest pre-death moments. In this world there is no satisfaction, only lack, the zombie's unquenchable lust for flesh mocking the consumer's unquenchable desires. Then came "Day of the Dead", arguably the best film in the series. Here, 60s radicalism and 70s consumerism are shunted aside in favour for an assault on Reaganism and the military/scientific complex, where pathologically macho soldiers try to keep the zombies at bay whilst scientists try with futility to either "destroy the zombie plague" or "tame the zombies". The film is relentless in its deconstruction of military authoritarianism and scientific claims to supreme authority, but mostly it's the film's treatment of Freud's reality/pleasure principle and its thick fatalism which makes it so unique. Here, the zombies embody a kind of sympathetic, undeveloped and (pre-language, pre-entry-into-the-Symbolic) ego-less desire (they do not know why they want/desire), which contrasts with the libidinal economy and the twisted viciousness of the human characters (who bury the true motivations of their desires and hypocritically stand for social order). Each of Romero's zombie movies were intended to be a snapshot of the decade in which they was released; "Night" the 60s, "Dawn" the 70s and "Day" the 80s. "Land of the Dead", for financial reasons, was released in the 21st century, but it is actually a broad critique of 90s American society. Here, social class and warfare comes to the foreground, the film imagining America as a paranoid bastion of humanity and freedom, standing tall against the "foreign horde". In "Land of the Dead", the ruling class live lives of elegance and supreme wealth in the exclusive and gated high-rises of "Fiddler's Green", while the masses outside do their dirty bidding and scrape by on low incomes, distracting themselves from their worries with sex, drugs, gambling and violence. The leader of this late-capitalist America, a George Bush styled madman out to make the rich richer and who "refuses to negotiate with terrorists", subsists by sending into zombie territory teams of mercenaries who steal zombie loot (he achieves this by distracting the zombies with fireworks- a kind of metaphor for media spectacle and social brainwashing). The zombies themselves are, once again, the good guys, often linked with the rebelling humans who wish to rise up against their overlords. When the zombies break into the city - led by a black zombie of course - it's symbolic of the proletariat finally rising against their masters and demanding restitution and justice, though Romero knows this is but a futile, 1960s pipe dream. He ends the film with the zombies defeated, the humans infected, and the rebels disillusioned, the masses going their separate ways at the end of the film, wandering off into the horizon like so many disillusioned cinematic anti-heroes of cinema's golden age, specifically the existential road movies of the early 1970s. 8.5/10  "Day of the Dead" 8/10  "Land of the Dead", "Dawn of the Dead" 7.5/10  "Night of the Living Dead" Despite their tiny budgets and at times poor acting, these films still operate fairly well as popcorn movies. What elevates them, though, is the allegorical qualities of Romero's trashy plots.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's a fine zombie movie, but not good enough
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Conrad
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Did the perfect zombie (or "ghoul," as this film's antagonists are dubbed) movie spring forth from the head of George Romero fully-formed, or did subsequent iterations simply fail to build on his promising idea? You know the drill even if you are not a zombie connoisseur: the murderous undead are on the loose, and a diverse band of survivors must overcome their disagreements while staving off the hordes. Romero achieves his vision in "Night of the Living Dead" despite financial and technical limitations. Yet the vision itself is so limited that it hardly extends beyond the premise. In this movie, as in many later knock-offs, there is little character development, little consideration of the theological or scientific implications of the situation, and-- despite frequent claims to the contrary and the casting of a black lead actor--little social commentary. The ending is suggestive of the paranoia and pessimism that afflicted many in 1968, but the script's unironic portrayal of women as submissive and incompetent does not indicate a desire to engage with social issues of the day. "Night of the Living Dead" is decent as far as it goes, but it does not go far, and the genre has rarely aimed higher in the nearly 50 years since.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What could I add more?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    GUENOT PHILIPPE (philippe.guenot@dbmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    That's one of the best picture ever for me, overall, not only horror movies...What could I say more, that the other users have already told? I can't find enough words to describe this authentic gem that every movie buff - and not only - have already watched. I saw it a hundred times... A simple story, but so powerful, so efficient, and with no professional actors. No "hollywoodian" actors I mean. The very first scene, where we see an American flag put at the cemetery entry, which can be interpreted as the Vietnam mess - the film was shot in 1968 - is very meaningful for the rest of the film. And typical of this very period. The counter culture one. What I particularly like in this masterpiece is that there is not useless love interest between the characters, for instance Ben and Barbara's ones, as we could have expected. And I appreciate this. Yes, this movies describes the human behavior very well. After all, are the real human creatures better than the dead ones? That's the real question of the movie, that's my opinion. The characters fighting for their lives in the small house are shown in such an intense way...Films made now, in 20... are not so powerful. Sorry. And the final moral, where we finally find that the coward, nasty character - Cooper's one - was damn right, concerning the safety of the basement. All long the film, well almost, he told everyone that the basement was the safest way to stay. Ben, the lead, did not agree, so did the audience who loves this fighting character. And, at the end, that's this very basement that saved Ben. The bad guy was right at the end. That's very unusual. Yes I won't never be tired to watch this movie again and again.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wasn't too impressed by this horror classic, but it was an enjoyable film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bruno Youn
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A decent horror film overall, but I have to say it was a very uneven experience for me. While there are a few aspects I certainly enjoyed here, such as the effective scares, gruesome imagery and the shocking twist at the end, I thought the acting was stale at times and was pretty annoyed by the character of Helen. The film got too didactic and a bit tedious when they began to follow the announcements on TV. The explanation of the origins of the undead was very far-fetched for me and didn't really need to be here. Also, the zombies seemed to be inconsistent as some of them decide to chase people or kill them with objects when they have fresh meat to eat right beside them. Finally, I found many statements given by the characters to be quite obvious or even a bit ridiculous so that also took me out of the film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Grim & Influential.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    George Romero's infamous low budget horror film about the mysterious resurrection of hordes of the walking dead, who are compelled to kill, and consume, the living, became a huge underground hit that inspired a whole new sub genre of horror for those so inclined, not to mention a great many sequels, remakes, spin offs, etc. Though this is, on one level, a starkly effective shocker, the premise is so utterly preposterous, and tone so unmercifully grim and downbeat, with a horribly ironic ending, that it doesn't work for me. The acting is strong though, but film is dispiriting in the extreme, with little to recommend it, though it is a cult classic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This is where the long walk began...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MrGKB
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ...toward the contemporary zombie mythos of "The Walking Dead" and every cannibalistic living dead film in between. I first enjoyed "NotLD" on the big screen way back in the antediluvian days of college, pre- videotape/DVD/BluRay collections, pre-Internet, pre-Androids etal., when Romero's unassuming film was burning up the midnight film circuit and burrowing deep into the collective unconsciousness of horror fans and cinemaphiles everywhere. Little did I know at the time just how influential this little homegrown nightmare would prove to be, but there was no denying its raw power to shock and unsettle unsuspecting audiences, and all on a budget just somewhat above rock bottom. Imagine, if you will, several hundred Boomer college kids packed into a darkened auditorium, most of them likely intoxicated on one thing or another, all eager to see this scary movie that so far they'd only read about. They knew that Roger Ebert hated it, which only made it more alluring. They knew it pushed the boundaries of graphic depictions of murder, and that, too, made it all the more the forbidden fruit. And, perhaps most of all, they knew it wasn't a "Hollywood" movie, and that made its rising star all the brighter. Imagine now that very first viewing of that rough gem in all its lo-fi glory... Almost a half-century later, even the most forgiving retrospectives will admit to the film's flaws; only the most churlish could deny them. The acting is at times--to be polite--unpolished, and the make-up is simply crude by today's standards (one can only wonder how it might have looked had Tom Savini not be dragooned off to Vietnam). The camera-wrangling is well-informed by Romero's prior commercial experience, although eminently bolstered by darkly evocative lighting and editing; the choice to shoot in black-and-white was, of course, a financial one, but turned out to be the serendipitous one as well. I can't even conceive of this film being in color, and have steadfastly refused to ever watch the colorized version. "NotLD" remains a classic example of inspired (and inspiring) make-do indie film-making and quite rightfully deserves its many accolades and awards of honor. It's far from perfect--even the script is a let-down at times, what with its occasionally clunky dialog--but it hits all the right dramatic notes, tapping into a nervous zeitgeist in a way that still works even in a post-9/11 world, and perhaps even more so. If George A. Romero & Co. hadn't made "Night of the Living Dead," I have no doubt that someone else would have eventually come up with something similar. But, he did, and the face of horror and indie cinema in general is all the better for it. Long live the living dead!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Surprisingly good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheGreatAmericanNightmare
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I gave this a 6 considering that it was low budget and late 60's. The acting was really not too bad, all things considered. I don't usually go for "B" movies, but I would have to give this a B+. Definitely the beginning of genre. Glad I watched it. Sometimes just the fact that a movie is black and white is enough to keep me from watching it. I know I need to reexamine that policy. As much as I love movies, I need to give more black and white movies a chance. In the beginning, I thought, "Ooh I don't know if I can hang with this." It seemed a little dopey, but as it progressed I got into it and some of the dialog was actually decent. I've seen modern day low budget flicks that couldn't hold a candle to this one.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The first and still the best
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    usgator
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am not sure how to go about reviewing this movie since it is my favorite of all time. I watch it every Halloween, without fail, as well as several other of this type. We are talking about a 30 year span here and I still love it! As a MAJOR horror movie buff since the age of about 10, this is the ONLY one that ever terrified me. I saw it in an extremely cut version, as a Saturday afternoon TV movie, and it still left a big impression on me. Most of the "gory" scenes were cut but it still scared the heck out of me. Everything about this movie works: from the claustrophobic atmosphere to the black-and-white cinematography ... and everything in between. Director George Romero is, and always will be, the king of the flesh-eating zombie movies. This is the gold star of low budget horror flix. If you have not seen it, and are a horror movie fan, this is a MUST see. Do NOT hesitate, see it now, but remember this movie was made in 1968 and much of the shock value has faded as it has been done in 1000 movies since then. Keep in mind that THIS is the film the pushed the "gore" envelope and was the first modern zombie horror film and you can not help but be impressed. Once you see it you will also be compelled to see Romero's equally good sequels ... "Dawn of the Dead" (1978), "Day of the Dead" (1985) and "Land of the Dead" (2005). The other 2 ("Diary.." and "Survival ..") are not up to par, but still better than most of the other movies of this genre, no matter what the "critics" on IMDb say. In closing, I cannot recommend this film enough for the serious, and open minded, horror movie fan.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Great Accomplishment
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wfjohnston14
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Night of the Living Dead is a shocking film in many ways (not taken to be a pun) as it delivers good horror for a very low budget. When Barbara goes to deliver flowers to a grave, her brother is attacked by a zombie and she goes running to a nearby house where she is greeted by a black man named Ben. Then more people come to the house and are trapped inside the house as zombies start to come and attack the house. The group of people must out live the night and hopefully not die from the zombies or themselves. Night of the Living dead is a great accomplishment as it had a budget of $116,000 and made it count. There are so many big budget films that are wasted and this little budget film does not. It has some rather gross zombie scenes, not from the appearance of the zombies, but what they do as one scene they eat the body parts of one of the men and you watch as they tear of the flesh from the arm and chop it down. It's already cut of and now the appearance is rather gross, even for black and white film. The film has a very good climax as the zombies start to enter the house and the little girl finally transforms into a zombie and attacks her parents. Now Ben fights them off and kills the family as they all turn into zombies. Yay for the hero. But wait, it's not over as the police raid the area the next morning with zombie hunters and when Ben escapes the basement to get away from this place, is shot down as one of the hunters think he is a slow moving flesh eater and the happy ending turns tragic. Night of the Living Dead is a brilliant horror movie and does what so many other horrors films should do, be gross and fun. Grade: A
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    classic zombie fest or feast
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kai ringler
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It took me along time to watch this classic, I've seen more of the modern zombie movies over the past 20 years. and after each viewing of said movies I've always thought you know I should give the original masterpiece a try. I thoroughly enjoyed it, I didn't mind that the zombies were slow and hard to understand,, this movie was groundbreaking at the time so I didn't expect a lot of zombie attack action,, the opening scene is frightening to a point. especially in the graveyard. eventually our heroine makes it back to a farmhouse after seeing her brother be left for dead by a zombie, there she meets a black man who kinda runs the house,, together they try and board up all the doors and windows.. later on in the basement there is another family down there taking care of a sick child, and this is where things start to get interesting bickering , arguing amongst the men as to the best way to defend the house, and whether to stay on the top floor of the house or be in the basement,, watch and find out whose idea was better. i'm glad I've seen this movie and have watched it twice and will many more times.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Reality Bites
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tieman64
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "I was trying to come up with a concept about a new society, revolutionary...in political terms, that's taking over and devouring the old society."  George A. Romero George Romero's "Night Of The Living Dead" marked the implosion of the white, middle class, American nuclear family and portrayed the collapse of post-war patriarchal authority into a kind of mad hysteria. What followed - the sexual, political and social "revolutions" of the 1960s - were not so much rebellions against tyrannical paternal and political despots, or against the rigid repressions of suburban family life, as they were carnivalesque revelations that the emperor had no clothes. That 1950s suburbia offered nothing but hypocrisy and fake decor. As such, Romero has his nuclear family holed up in a farmhouse - the impotence of the father mirroring the clownishness and impotence of various authority figures on his television screen - until the unit collapses under the weight of its own stupidity and children-turned-zombies avidly consume their own parents. As is always the case with Romero, the zombies are actually the good guys, the new zombie order literally consuming the outmoded old. The zombie horde then become a darkly humorous vision of hippie communalism who are the preferred refuge of the children of the white middle class. But the rebellions of the 1960s went nowhere, hope fading and forgotten. Hippies and campus radicals from middle-class backgrounds grew up to be yuppies, and their influence on the larger culture was mostly a matter of an easily saleable "lifestyle." Once the social upheavals of the 60s had passed, consumerism turned out to be the real winner, so it's entirely appropriate that Romero's second zombie movie, "Dawn of the Dead", takes place in a shopping mall. Here our heroes live a fantasy of commodity abundance and unhinged consumption, whilst the zombies draw inexorably closer, the mall reminding them of their happiest pre-death moments. In this world there is no satisfaction, only lack, the zombie's unquenchable lust for flesh mocking the consumer's unquenchable desires. Then came "Day of the Dead", arguably the best film in the series. Here, 60s radicalism and 70s consumerism are shunted aside in favour for an assault on Reaganism and the military/scientific complex, where pathologically macho soldiers try to keep the zombies at bay whilst scientists try with futility to either "destroy the zombie plague" or "tame the zombies". The film is relentless in its deconstruction of military authoritarianism and scientific claims to supreme authority, but mostly it's the film's treatment of Freud's reality/pleasure principle and its thick fatalism which makes it so unique. Here, the zombies embody a kind of sympathetic, undeveloped and (pre-language, pre-entry-into-the-Symbolic) ego-less desire (they do not know why they want/desire), which contrasts with the libidinal economy and the twisted viciousness of the human characters (who bury the true motivations of their desires and hypocritically stand for social order). Each of Romero's zombie movies were intended to be a snapshot of the decade in which they was released; "Night" the 60s, "Dawn" the 70s and "Day" the 80s. "Land of the Dead", for financial reasons, was released in the 21st century, but it is actually a broad critique of 90s American society. Here, social class and warfare comes to the foreground, the film imagining America as a paranoid bastion of humanity and freedom, standing tall against the "foreign horde". In "Land of the Dead", the ruling class live lives of elegance and supreme wealth in the exclusive and gated high-rises of "Fiddler's Green", while the masses outside do their dirty bidding and scrape by on low incomes, distracting themselves from their worries with sex, drugs, gambling and violence. The leader of this late-capitalist America, a George Bush styled madman out to make the rich richer and who "refuses to negotiate with terrorists", subsists by sending into zombie territory teams of mercenaries who steal zombie loot (he achieves this by distracting the zombies with fireworks- a kind of metaphor for media spectacle and social brainwashing). The zombies themselves are, once again, the good guys, often linked with the rebelling humans who wish to rise up against their overlords. When the zombies break into the city - led by a black zombie of course - it's symbolic of the proletariat finally rising against their masters and demanding restitution and justice, though Romero knows this is but a futile, 1960s pipe dream. He ends the film with the zombies defeated, the humans infected, and the rebels disillusioned, the masses going their separate ways at the end of the film, wandering off into the horizon like so many disillusioned cinematic anti-heroes of cinema's golden age, specifically the existential road movies of the early 1970s. 8.5/10  "Day of the Dead" 8/10  "Land of the Dead", "Dawn of the Dead" 7.5/10  "Night of the Living Dead" Despite their tiny budgets and at times poor acting, these films still operate fairly well as popcorn movies. What elevates them, though, is the allegorical qualities of Romero's trashy plots.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's a fine zombie movie, but not good enough
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Conrad
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Did the perfect zombie (or "ghoul," as this film's antagonists are dubbed) movie spring forth from the head of George Romero fully-formed, or did subsequent iterations simply fail to build on his promising idea? You know the drill even if you are not a zombie connoisseur: the murderous undead are on the loose, and a diverse band of survivors must overcome their disagreements while staving off the hordes. Romero achieves his vision in "Night of the Living Dead" despite financial and technical limitations. Yet the vision itself is so limited that it hardly extends beyond the premise. In this movie, as in many later knock-offs, there is little character development, little consideration of the theological or scientific implications of the situation, and-- despite frequent claims to the contrary and the casting of a black lead actor--little social commentary. The ending is suggestive of the paranoia and pessimism that afflicted many in 1968, but the script's unironic portrayal of women as submissive and incompetent does not indicate a desire to engage with social issues of the day. "Night of the Living Dead" is decent as far as it goes, but it does not go far, and the genre has rarely aimed higher in the nearly 50 years since.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What could I add more?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    GUENOT PHILIPPE (philippe.guenot@dbmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    That's one of the best picture ever for me, overall, not only horror movies...What could I say more, that the other users have already told? I can't find enough words to describe this authentic gem that every movie buff - and not only - have already watched. I saw it a hundred times... A simple story, but so powerful, so efficient, and with no professional actors. No "hollywoodian" actors I mean. The very first scene, where we see an American flag put at the cemetery entry, which can be interpreted as the Vietnam mess - the film was shot in 1968 - is very meaningful for the rest of the film. And typical of this very period. The counter culture one. What I particularly like in this masterpiece is that there is not useless love interest between the characters, for instance Ben and Barbara's ones, as we could have expected. And I appreciate this. Yes, this movies describes the human behavior very well. After all, are the real human creatures better than the dead ones? That's the real question of the movie, that's my opinion. The characters fighting for their lives in the small house are shown in such an intense way...Films made now, in 20... are not so powerful. Sorry. And the final moral, where we finally find that the coward, nasty character - Cooper's one - was damn right, concerning the safety of the basement. All long the film, well almost, he told everyone that the basement was the safest way to stay. Ben, the lead, did not agree, so did the audience who loves this fighting character. And, at the end, that's this very basement that saved Ben. The bad guy was right at the end. That's very unusual. Yes I won't never be tired to watch this movie again and again.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
