<filme>
 <id>
  617
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0020697
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1930
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  O Anjo Azul
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  7.8
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  An elderly professor's ordered life spins dangerously out of control when he falls for a nightclub singer.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Immanuel Rath, an old bachelor, is a professor at the town's university. When he discovers that some of his pupils often go into a speakeasy, The Blue Angel, to visit a dancer, Lola Lola, he comes there to confront them. But he is attracted to Lola. The next night he comes again--and does not sleep at home. This causes trouble at work and his life takes a downward spiral.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Music
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   professor
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   singer
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   nightclub
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   obsession
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   police
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Josef von Sternberg
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Heinrich Mann
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Carl Zuckmayer
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Emil Jannings
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Marlene Dietrich
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Kurt Gerron
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Perhaps it was startling at its time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    funkyfry
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I can't say much about this film, having just seen it for the first time, but while I was impressed with Von Sternberg's direction, as usual, I felt that this film lacked substance and drive. The story is too predictable; maybe at its time, it had some novelty. I hoped that the road would twist in some unpredictable direction, but it simply loped along to its predictably depressing conclusion. Jannings and Dietrich are wonderfully cast and carry off their roles with perfection. Less convincing is Kurt Gerron's magician -- he seems like he would belong more as a bar-tender than as an impresario. The touches of humor are odd.... I found myself uncertain at times whether it was a comedy or a drama. Certainly, the film makes Jannings' imperious school professor a subject of so much ridicule that his fall from grace comes more as a relief than a tragedy. One would hope to find minor characters with some flash to add some interest to a simple story, but only Hans Albers' strongman can really make much of an impression next to Jannings and Dietrich. It's a pleasing film to watch, I enjoyed much of the atmosphere and so forth, but it didn't make much of a lasting impression on me I'm afraid.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Succulent, Mellifluous
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Antti Keisala
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Von Sternberg's film is a wonderfully constructed piece of succulent and mellifluous tragicomedy. The fluently moving camera offers a beautiful sense of place, and especially the crooked pebble-stoned streets and leaning houses are the unforgettable epitomes of this film in my memory. Just as with Vigo's "L'Atalante" (1934), much of the film's power depends on us, as the audience, being able to fall in love with the lead actress. It certainly helps that the director did, and for once some knowledge of production enhances the experience: Umrat/Jennings as the jealous and passionate star, Dietrich as the object of desire not only of the boys but of the camera. I also really like the use of stairs, which clearly separate the differing worlds. I could definitely see this influencing "Z&eacute;ro de conduite" (1933) and "Hets" (1944). The slow movement of the camera in the empty classroom after the crucial confrontation reveals one of the most touching visual moments I can think of (this is repeated later in an equally heart-breaking scene). I remember I was very young when I saw this for the first time. It made a lasting impression then, and I count it as one of the three films that ultimately made me fall in love with films to the extent that my thirst will never be quenched.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Blue Angel
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    They released this film filmed in two versions, they acted all the scenes in both German and English, but when I decided to watch this film from the 1001 Movies You Must See Before You Die book, I was going to watch the original German language version. Basically Professor Immanuel Rath (Emil Jannings) is the esteemed college preparatory high school educator who has punished many of his male students for spreading around the image of beautiful stage performer Lola Lola (Destry Rides Again's Marlene Dietrich). He hopes to catch the school boys in the cabaret club The Blue Angel, where she is the headlining act, and after her for himself he grows slowly passionate for her, and with a pair of panties snatched by a student he has a good reason to return there the following night. Having had a night of desire and such, Rath returns to class next day, with the Principal (Eduard Von Winterstein) furious to see the students running riot, and he is aware of the teacher's behaviour recently as well. He decides it is best to retire from the school, and with his newfound freedom he can marry Lola, but they cannot stay happy for long as their money problems grow, and to earn he is forced to become a stage clown in the cabaret troupe. Rath is often filled with jealousy and lust for his wife and her profession, she leaves herself open as a "shared woman", and he is being ridiculed for his past while performing as a clown. He performs his last act at The Blue Angel, and he is shocked to see Lola kissing her new love interest strongman Mazeppa (Hans Albers), and his rage turns into insanity, where he starts strangles his wife and is forced into a straitjacket. In the end, having been released from prison, Rath is not able to resolve his position as a school teacher, and he has obviously lost wife Lola, so he dies from extreme self pity clutching the school desks that once sat his loyal students. Also starring Kurt Gerron as Kiepert the Magician, Rosa Valetti as Guste the Magician's Wife, Reinhold Bernt as The Clown, Hans Roth as Beadle the Caretaker of the Secondary School, Rolf M&uuml;ller as Pupil Angst and Robert Klein-L&ouml;rk as Pupil Goldstaub. Jannings - in his first talking picture - gives a mixed but equally interesting performance as the teacher turned performer with a troubled passion, and Dietrich is wonderful in her iconic top hat and black stockings as the seductive stage performer with a cruel streak, it is a film with some memorable sequences and moments that stand out, especially of course the cabaret stuff, making it a most watchable drama. Very good!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Falling From Grace Over "Show Girl" or There's No Fool Like An Old Fool!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    John T. Ryan (redryan64@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    WE CAN WELL recall viewing this film for the very first time on a PBS Friday evening show. This was circa 1971 and we needed to go to such Public Television stations as our own WTTW, Channel 11 in Chicago in order to see many films which weren't shown on commercial TV Statiobs. WELL, HOW THINGS have changed. Just this passed Monday (2 days ago), Turner Classic Movies ran THE BLUE ANGEL in prime-time. It had been about 40 years (yes, count 'em, folks!) since our initial contact with Herr Josef Von Sternberg's dark, tragic drama. We had seen it once or twice during that period, but had never given it my undivided attention. ALTHOUGH IT IS a German language film, there was at least one of these showings was in a recently rediscovered English language version. We also remember a showing which was in German; but featured Miss Dietrich's performance of "Falling In Lov Again" in English. VIEWING A FILM SUCH as this very talky drama, while at the same time being compelled to read Subtutles, in order to follow the story can really prove to be a pain right where one sits. Yet, it does seem to become easier as the story progresses; as we become engrossed with the scenario unfolding, the dark yet starkly penetrating images, moody and highly atmospheric songs & music and the virtuoso acting performances. THE STORY MAY seem somewhat complex; yet it is probably the very universal themes and connection with the lives and needs of all people that make this such a powerful and compelling of a story with such a long life as an all time favourite. IN SHORT, WE have a story of loneliness, the need to love and be loved, the falling from grace of a highly regarded and most straight laced of a member of academia. From perhaps a most distinguished position and and outstanding of a reputation as a Professor of Literature at the unnamed university, the professor (Mr. Emil Jannings) falls in love with a common, vulgar cabaret singer and exponent of sex, Lola Lola (Miss Marlena Dietrich). THE STORY COVERS a period of over five years, in which the middle aged, clearly un-handsome man discovers that he has fallen to such a degree of degradation as to not only being a minor entertainer; but also participating in selling his own wife. During appearances following Lola's doing her song, professor Roth's duties included peddling some rather pornographic type of postcards to the bawdy male patrons of the show. WE MUST CONFESS that even being a grown man, married with two children, there was an awful lot of obvious seedy goings on that I missed on previous viewings. Certainly, there were no examples of explicit on screen sex (such as have become so commonplace); and yet, with all of the occurrences we surely are forced to ask a few questions. IN ADDITION TO the setting of a night club with rather risqu&eacute; programming, what is it that all of these college boys find so fascinating? Why do the young men hide from the Professor in secret rooms that are below the floors? What is the purpose of these rooms? Why does the proprietor worry about the presence of a police officer; for, isn't this a legal and licensed establishment? Do you think that there is sex for sale here? We do. THE AMAZING FEAT that is accomplished here is making such an interesting story out of such a sordid and low life segment of society. WE GIVE THIS five stars as our rating.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unforgettable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jacabiya
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let me join the ranks that herald this film as one of the great ones, an unforgettable all-time world cinema masterpiece that should be way higher in the IMDb scores, still relevant, powerful, not dated, with not one but two landmark performances. In the first half the film is very funny, but when Lola Lola starts clucking in the wedding reception the horror begins. This is my favorite Marlene Dietrich role, and for my taste the only sexy one, with baby fat and a rounder, younger, nubile face and body(before she turned into the more stern and severe deep-voiced German femme fatale). I find it amazing that her character in this 1930 film still turns me on. Jannings overacts grandiosely to match the extremely melodramatic, denigrating, tragic story, and gives one of the great acting performances of movie history (along with his performance in the silent The Last Laugh). The magician is perfectly sleazy yet human in his ignorance. The film piles it up towards its cringing climax, culminating in action not actually shown, an extremely intelligent move on Sternberg's part. And I dare anyone to come up with more horrible and painful sounds in film history than the professor's.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Downfall of an Arrogant Academic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Le Sage
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Blue Angel features a simple but effective narrative, showing the fall of a man into degradation and squalor. As such, it echoes the themes in early Weimar cinema such as Pandora's Box. The narrative is, indeed, so simple, that this early "talkie" could just as easily have been a silent film. Only rarely is the new sound technology explored to good effect, such as when songs can be heard when the doors from Lola's room to the stage are periodically opened and closed by characters. There is also, of course, the use of song, with Dietrich's voice showcased to good affect. Emil Jannings portrays the stereotype of an academic perfectly: arrogant, insular and with some minor eccentricities, he is unable to cope with life in the "real world" and this leads to his fall from grace. Initially, we in the audience, like his students, see him as a clown, a laughable, pompous yet bumbling figure. His ultimate fate is to be exposed to the whole town as a fool when, stripped of his power, he literally becomes a clown before seeking to return to the insularity of his old post. However, the Professor is not the only loathsome character in this film. The attitude of the students is as despicable as that of their tutor: with their arrogant and bullying behaviour, whilst they are his nemesis, they are also his mirror. They are growing into his image and, with his growing captivation with Lola, he is growing into theirs. Lola is an equally unlikable character and perhaps, once again, reflects concern amongst conservatives in Weimar society about the growing power of women. She is far smarter than the "learned" professor in terms of her ability to understand and manipulate people. Going out on the stage each night is the opposite to his insular world yet it his "act" of appearing respectable in society that this actress is able to quickly pull apart, exposing the shallow man inside. The bird motif used throughout the film is strikingly effective. At the start, the bird who can no longer sing is callously discarded by the housekeeper, just as the worn-out, useless Professor will be discarded, first by the school and then by society. The doomed bird motif is also prefigured by the birds near the clock as the procession of ghoulish statues marches past with each hour. Finally, the Professor himself is humiliated during the clown and magician routine, forced to have doves fly out from under his top hat and to crow like a rooster. Ultimately, this is a brilliant film and, like much late Weimar cinema, reflects themes of moral decline and degradation. This time, however, the character is deeply unlikable from the outset and his humiliation is really an increasing expose to the world of his pre-existing inner nature. He does not grow or transform as a character; rather, as his power is stripped, his true nature is revealed. The learned academic is the biggest fool of all. Stripped of his position and prestige, the academic is nothing more than a clown.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Only angels have wings
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    chaos-rampant
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Films that revolve around performance are essentially about cinema, I'm always on the lookout for these. But unlike the more traditional films about the making of films - Day for Night, Contempt, The Stunt Man, Shadow of the Vampire, etc - those about performance have the extra allure that we have to participate in staging the illusion; it falls on us to imagine the cinematic scenario, and thus complete the notion, actually see in our minds how it completes. It is the best kind of in-sight into creative life - which is every life on the planet, a long series of invention, deception, connection. In The Red Shoes for example, it was a dance between us from the position of the camera and the stage where the story is being danced out. A more intriguing vision we find in the silent Dr. Mabuse, with us looking to apprehend the criminal mastermind who under various guises manipulates the narrative we see. Or the continuation of this in The American Friend, another German film; a 'frame' artist who becomes framed in an illusion that unfolds, this is the film within, as gangster stuff around Europe. This second group is more competent because the film-within, in whatever form, is better integrated inside the outer film. But in all these cases the main subject remains the same; the effort to discern boundaries between a life we control, and so a narrative we are free to improvise as best we can, and a life that is framed, scripted and storyboarded around us from outside. (the truly wise filmmakers understand how these are the same; how, in other terms, the best actors in life are those who are completely clueless about the narrative and therefore effortlessly natural, and those who have studied it and can exercise volition to reshape themselves into what the role requires). Sternberg had made a film about film before this, a more explicit but astounding vision of a filmed reality that prophesied New Wave thirty years before. This is more inconspicuous, less singlemindedly about self-reference, with interesting crowds and rooms around the stage that we can loose ourselves into. It is just endearing to watch on a very basic level, occasionally pretty funny; and in the end thoroughly gut-wrenching. Yet it is still very much about a man losing himself into a performance. What entices him and us is the woman; in fact, we are made to share the male point-of-view so adeptly, the camera always strategically placed where it can be teased and seduced by long legs in stockings, by large eye-lashes making promises, that it is not just the professor, but us as well, more importantly us, that want to let go and be absorbed in the sexual fantasy. It's no wonder she is so captivating, we know after all how Sternberg would grow to worship her, and bind, fully devote his craft to images of her. The second part is where it's truly grueling to watch, where the professor, a pillar of morals and ethos at the start, is completely subsumed inside the fantasy and loses all. Again Emil Jannings puts on a costume. So many fascinating things then happen so quickly, I was left with jaw open. We revisit the cabaret stage from before, only now, quite literally, from inside the mirror looking out; now we are the spectacle, the show being looked on, with being made to perform as the price exacted for having fully invested in the feverish, sultry dream in the first place. Now we are what is being dreamed - this trope is what Lynch has worked and innovated from. And again the distinction between the performance as perceived from outside, with jeers and catcalls, and the human being inside as we know it to suffer. As with all those silent films before about clowns suffering from behind painted smiles, it is a tragic sight of humiliation and despair. When he bellows inordinately, the audience laughs, but we know it's the sound of a soul being torn apart. My only minor gripe, is with how forceful is this part, how emotional. Then again it makes sense; we are again so adeptly placed inside the character, and made to feel as broken as he is. The film ends with the woman performing again her number that captivated the audience so much, only now we understand what's behind the notes. "I'm programmed for love" sings Dietrich, the femme fatale - and so desire, sexual danger personified - who operated the performance from behind the stage. We have mostly come to know film noir from American film. But it was born in Germany, between Dr. Mabuse and this. It's a compelling moral, as in noir later: we are reminded again how dangerous it is to indulge the chimeras of the mind, ego and desire, and how the social fabric has its ways of eventually restoring us in the common, harmless delusions. It's okay to watch, anything more is at our spiritual peril.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The "Carmen" who got away
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    evening1
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Having just caught the Metropolitan's 2010 production of "Carmen" on film during the opera company's outdoor HD Live festival, I expected this film would end with Lola's comeuppance, if not murder. It was a little chilling, and, I have to admit, disappointing, to see her sitting pretty on-stage as her discarded, humiliated husband shuffles away into hopeless oblivion. This film, which I had taped from the City University of New York's excellent TV channel, suffered from horrible visual and sound quality but it managed to keep my attention throughout. It seems a case study in the follies of trying to live without the benefit of self-knowledge. Professor Rath -- was he supposed to be Jewish in this film made as Naziism was on the rise in Germany? -- was a misfit and a clod, a man who found his place in life through his book knowledge. What was missing in him was any sense of who he was as a man. Rath demonstrated his ineptness outside of the ivory tower by blundering into Lola's dressing room, a fateful breaking of social boundaries. Lola treats Rath as one might an old teddy bear. When he proposes marriage, gorgeous Lola cackles hysterically, but it wouldn't occur to Rath to wonder what this might mean. Lola accepts the offer, though one would have to assume the union will never be consummated. (Rather than gaining a love partner, she takes in the father she probably never knew.) Rath's eventual rejection is inevitable. The only surprise here is Lola's getting off scot free. Maybe she thinks about her actions a little; she does seem to darken somewhat during the course of the film. However, she's ultimately left pretty much unscathed by the final credits. Interestingly, Dietrich goes on from this film to become a success in Hollywood, whereas the actor who played Rath remained in Germany to participate in Nazi-propaganda films from which which his career never recovered -- an outcome that pretty much parallels the movie's plot line.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Naughty, naughty..."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moonspinner55
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A stuffy, lonely German college professor, laughed at by his immature pupils, ventures out to a cabaret in the village to berate his students for ogling the female entertainment; instead, he becomes infatuated with the star of the show, chanteuse Lola Lola, and apparently she to him. After marrying the flashy girl, the teacher leaves his profession to travel with the theatrical troupe, but life on the road immediately wears him down. An ugly little story, adapted from Heinrich Mann's novel "Professor Unrath", has a winking-nudging overlay of sexual byplay and was released to great acclaim in both German and English-language versions (this review pertains to the German version with subtitles). Director Josef von Sternberg was already a 15-year veteran of Hollywood movie-making by the time "The Blue Angel" arrived, and yet several sequences (most notably in the first reel and the last) are sloppily constructed and uncertainly paced. Emil Jannings is wonderful as the unloved professor who initially blossoms in the company of streetwise Marlene Dietrich, but his emotional unraveling is awfully quick in coming. Josef von Sternberg is far too sluggish in the beginning, but by the midway point he rushes the narrative...and the audience isn't allowed to get their bearings. As a result, the plot feels like a sadistic series of screw-turns, with no hope (or heart) in sight. **1/2 from ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Humbert Humbert's predecessor
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watching "Der blaue Engel" ("The Blue Angel" in English), I got the feeling that it was sort of a precursor to "Lolita". When you look at how Prof. Immanuel Rath (Emil Jannings) lets his infatuation with nightclub singer Lola Lola (Marlene Dietrich) come to dominate his life, it seems very much like what happens to Humbert Humbert. Of course, the movie is best known for Dietrich's sexy performance as the liberated chanteuse (on which Madeline Kahn's character in "Blazing Saddles" was based). Dietrich must have been every man's dream after the movie came out. Still, the change in Prof. Rath's life caused by his obsession with her certainly stands out as well. All in all, Josef von Sternberg created a real masterpiece.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Perhaps it was startling at its time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    funkyfry
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I can't say much about this film, having just seen it for the first time, but while I was impressed with Von Sternberg's direction, as usual, I felt that this film lacked substance and drive. The story is too predictable; maybe at its time, it had some novelty. I hoped that the road would twist in some unpredictable direction, but it simply loped along to its predictably depressing conclusion. Jannings and Dietrich are wonderfully cast and carry off their roles with perfection. Less convincing is Kurt Gerron's magician -- he seems like he would belong more as a bar-tender than as an impresario. The touches of humor are odd.... I found myself uncertain at times whether it was a comedy or a drama. Certainly, the film makes Jannings' imperious school professor a subject of so much ridicule that his fall from grace comes more as a relief than a tragedy. One would hope to find minor characters with some flash to add some interest to a simple story, but only Hans Albers' strongman can really make much of an impression next to Jannings and Dietrich. It's a pleasing film to watch, I enjoyed much of the atmosphere and so forth, but it didn't make much of a lasting impression on me I'm afraid.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Succulent, Mellifluous
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Antti Keisala
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Von Sternberg's film is a wonderfully constructed piece of succulent and mellifluous tragicomedy. The fluently moving camera offers a beautiful sense of place, and especially the crooked pebble-stoned streets and leaning houses are the unforgettable epitomes of this film in my memory. Just as with Vigo's "L'Atalante" (1934), much of the film's power depends on us, as the audience, being able to fall in love with the lead actress. It certainly helps that the director did, and for once some knowledge of production enhances the experience: Umrat/Jennings as the jealous and passionate star, Dietrich as the object of desire not only of the boys but of the camera. I also really like the use of stairs, which clearly separate the differing worlds. I could definitely see this influencing "Z&eacute;ro de conduite" (1933) and "Hets" (1944). The slow movement of the camera in the empty classroom after the crucial confrontation reveals one of the most touching visual moments I can think of (this is repeated later in an equally heart-breaking scene). I remember I was very young when I saw this for the first time. It made a lasting impression then, and I count it as one of the three films that ultimately made me fall in love with films to the extent that my thirst will never be quenched.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Blue Angel
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    They released this film filmed in two versions, they acted all the scenes in both German and English, but when I decided to watch this film from the 1001 Movies You Must See Before You Die book, I was going to watch the original German language version. Basically Professor Immanuel Rath (Emil Jannings) is the esteemed college preparatory high school educator who has punished many of his male students for spreading around the image of beautiful stage performer Lola Lola (Destry Rides Again's Marlene Dietrich). He hopes to catch the school boys in the cabaret club The Blue Angel, where she is the headlining act, and after her for himself he grows slowly passionate for her, and with a pair of panties snatched by a student he has a good reason to return there the following night. Having had a night of desire and such, Rath returns to class next day, with the Principal (Eduard Von Winterstein) furious to see the students running riot, and he is aware of the teacher's behaviour recently as well. He decides it is best to retire from the school, and with his newfound freedom he can marry Lola, but they cannot stay happy for long as their money problems grow, and to earn he is forced to become a stage clown in the cabaret troupe. Rath is often filled with jealousy and lust for his wife and her profession, she leaves herself open as a "shared woman", and he is being ridiculed for his past while performing as a clown. He performs his last act at The Blue Angel, and he is shocked to see Lola kissing her new love interest strongman Mazeppa (Hans Albers), and his rage turns into insanity, where he starts strangles his wife and is forced into a straitjacket. In the end, having been released from prison, Rath is not able to resolve his position as a school teacher, and he has obviously lost wife Lola, so he dies from extreme self pity clutching the school desks that once sat his loyal students. Also starring Kurt Gerron as Kiepert the Magician, Rosa Valetti as Guste the Magician's Wife, Reinhold Bernt as The Clown, Hans Roth as Beadle the Caretaker of the Secondary School, Rolf M&uuml;ller as Pupil Angst and Robert Klein-L&ouml;rk as Pupil Goldstaub. Jannings - in his first talking picture - gives a mixed but equally interesting performance as the teacher turned performer with a troubled passion, and Dietrich is wonderful in her iconic top hat and black stockings as the seductive stage performer with a cruel streak, it is a film with some memorable sequences and moments that stand out, especially of course the cabaret stuff, making it a most watchable drama. Very good!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Falling From Grace Over "Show Girl" or There's No Fool Like An Old Fool!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    John T. Ryan (redryan64@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    WE CAN WELL recall viewing this film for the very first time on a PBS Friday evening show. This was circa 1971 and we needed to go to such Public Television stations as our own WTTW, Channel 11 in Chicago in order to see many films which weren't shown on commercial TV Statiobs. WELL, HOW THINGS have changed. Just this passed Monday (2 days ago), Turner Classic Movies ran THE BLUE ANGEL in prime-time. It had been about 40 years (yes, count 'em, folks!) since our initial contact with Herr Josef Von Sternberg's dark, tragic drama. We had seen it once or twice during that period, but had never given it my undivided attention. ALTHOUGH IT IS a German language film, there was at least one of these showings was in a recently rediscovered English language version. We also remember a showing which was in German; but featured Miss Dietrich's performance of "Falling In Lov Again" in English. VIEWING A FILM SUCH as this very talky drama, while at the same time being compelled to read Subtutles, in order to follow the story can really prove to be a pain right where one sits. Yet, it does seem to become easier as the story progresses; as we become engrossed with the scenario unfolding, the dark yet starkly penetrating images, moody and highly atmospheric songs & music and the virtuoso acting performances. THE STORY MAY seem somewhat complex; yet it is probably the very universal themes and connection with the lives and needs of all people that make this such a powerful and compelling of a story with such a long life as an all time favourite. IN SHORT, WE have a story of loneliness, the need to love and be loved, the falling from grace of a highly regarded and most straight laced of a member of academia. From perhaps a most distinguished position and and outstanding of a reputation as a Professor of Literature at the unnamed university, the professor (Mr. Emil Jannings) falls in love with a common, vulgar cabaret singer and exponent of sex, Lola Lola (Miss Marlena Dietrich). THE STORY COVERS a period of over five years, in which the middle aged, clearly un-handsome man discovers that he has fallen to such a degree of degradation as to not only being a minor entertainer; but also participating in selling his own wife. During appearances following Lola's doing her song, professor Roth's duties included peddling some rather pornographic type of postcards to the bawdy male patrons of the show. WE MUST CONFESS that even being a grown man, married with two children, there was an awful lot of obvious seedy goings on that I missed on previous viewings. Certainly, there were no examples of explicit on screen sex (such as have become so commonplace); and yet, with all of the occurrences we surely are forced to ask a few questions. IN ADDITION TO the setting of a night club with rather risqu&eacute; programming, what is it that all of these college boys find so fascinating? Why do the young men hide from the Professor in secret rooms that are below the floors? What is the purpose of these rooms? Why does the proprietor worry about the presence of a police officer; for, isn't this a legal and licensed establishment? Do you think that there is sex for sale here? We do. THE AMAZING FEAT that is accomplished here is making such an interesting story out of such a sordid and low life segment of society. WE GIVE THIS five stars as our rating.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unforgettable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jacabiya
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let me join the ranks that herald this film as one of the great ones, an unforgettable all-time world cinema masterpiece that should be way higher in the IMDb scores, still relevant, powerful, not dated, with not one but two landmark performances. In the first half the film is very funny, but when Lola Lola starts clucking in the wedding reception the horror begins. This is my favorite Marlene Dietrich role, and for my taste the only sexy one, with baby fat and a rounder, younger, nubile face and body(before she turned into the more stern and severe deep-voiced German femme fatale). I find it amazing that her character in this 1930 film still turns me on. Jannings overacts grandiosely to match the extremely melodramatic, denigrating, tragic story, and gives one of the great acting performances of movie history (along with his performance in the silent The Last Laugh). The magician is perfectly sleazy yet human in his ignorance. The film piles it up towards its cringing climax, culminating in action not actually shown, an extremely intelligent move on Sternberg's part. And I dare anyone to come up with more horrible and painful sounds in film history than the professor's.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Downfall of an Arrogant Academic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Le Sage
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Blue Angel features a simple but effective narrative, showing the fall of a man into degradation and squalor. As such, it echoes the themes in early Weimar cinema such as Pandora's Box. The narrative is, indeed, so simple, that this early "talkie" could just as easily have been a silent film. Only rarely is the new sound technology explored to good effect, such as when songs can be heard when the doors from Lola's room to the stage are periodically opened and closed by characters. There is also, of course, the use of song, with Dietrich's voice showcased to good affect. Emil Jannings portrays the stereotype of an academic perfectly: arrogant, insular and with some minor eccentricities, he is unable to cope with life in the "real world" and this leads to his fall from grace. Initially, we in the audience, like his students, see him as a clown, a laughable, pompous yet bumbling figure. His ultimate fate is to be exposed to the whole town as a fool when, stripped of his power, he literally becomes a clown before seeking to return to the insularity of his old post. However, the Professor is not the only loathsome character in this film. The attitude of the students is as despicable as that of their tutor: with their arrogant and bullying behaviour, whilst they are his nemesis, they are also his mirror. They are growing into his image and, with his growing captivation with Lola, he is growing into theirs. Lola is an equally unlikable character and perhaps, once again, reflects concern amongst conservatives in Weimar society about the growing power of women. She is far smarter than the "learned" professor in terms of her ability to understand and manipulate people. Going out on the stage each night is the opposite to his insular world yet it his "act" of appearing respectable in society that this actress is able to quickly pull apart, exposing the shallow man inside. The bird motif used throughout the film is strikingly effective. At the start, the bird who can no longer sing is callously discarded by the housekeeper, just as the worn-out, useless Professor will be discarded, first by the school and then by society. The doomed bird motif is also prefigured by the birds near the clock as the procession of ghoulish statues marches past with each hour. Finally, the Professor himself is humiliated during the clown and magician routine, forced to have doves fly out from under his top hat and to crow like a rooster. Ultimately, this is a brilliant film and, like much late Weimar cinema, reflects themes of moral decline and degradation. This time, however, the character is deeply unlikable from the outset and his humiliation is really an increasing expose to the world of his pre-existing inner nature. He does not grow or transform as a character; rather, as his power is stripped, his true nature is revealed. The learned academic is the biggest fool of all. Stripped of his position and prestige, the academic is nothing more than a clown.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Only angels have wings
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    chaos-rampant
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Films that revolve around performance are essentially about cinema, I'm always on the lookout for these. But unlike the more traditional films about the making of films - Day for Night, Contempt, The Stunt Man, Shadow of the Vampire, etc - those about performance have the extra allure that we have to participate in staging the illusion; it falls on us to imagine the cinematic scenario, and thus complete the notion, actually see in our minds how it completes. It is the best kind of in-sight into creative life - which is every life on the planet, a long series of invention, deception, connection. In The Red Shoes for example, it was a dance between us from the position of the camera and the stage where the story is being danced out. A more intriguing vision we find in the silent Dr. Mabuse, with us looking to apprehend the criminal mastermind who under various guises manipulates the narrative we see. Or the continuation of this in The American Friend, another German film; a 'frame' artist who becomes framed in an illusion that unfolds, this is the film within, as gangster stuff around Europe. This second group is more competent because the film-within, in whatever form, is better integrated inside the outer film. But in all these cases the main subject remains the same; the effort to discern boundaries between a life we control, and so a narrative we are free to improvise as best we can, and a life that is framed, scripted and storyboarded around us from outside. (the truly wise filmmakers understand how these are the same; how, in other terms, the best actors in life are those who are completely clueless about the narrative and therefore effortlessly natural, and those who have studied it and can exercise volition to reshape themselves into what the role requires). Sternberg had made a film about film before this, a more explicit but astounding vision of a filmed reality that prophesied New Wave thirty years before. This is more inconspicuous, less singlemindedly about self-reference, with interesting crowds and rooms around the stage that we can loose ourselves into. It is just endearing to watch on a very basic level, occasionally pretty funny; and in the end thoroughly gut-wrenching. Yet it is still very much about a man losing himself into a performance. What entices him and us is the woman; in fact, we are made to share the male point-of-view so adeptly, the camera always strategically placed where it can be teased and seduced by long legs in stockings, by large eye-lashes making promises, that it is not just the professor, but us as well, more importantly us, that want to let go and be absorbed in the sexual fantasy. It's no wonder she is so captivating, we know after all how Sternberg would grow to worship her, and bind, fully devote his craft to images of her. The second part is where it's truly grueling to watch, where the professor, a pillar of morals and ethos at the start, is completely subsumed inside the fantasy and loses all. Again Emil Jannings puts on a costume. So many fascinating things then happen so quickly, I was left with jaw open. We revisit the cabaret stage from before, only now, quite literally, from inside the mirror looking out; now we are the spectacle, the show being looked on, with being made to perform as the price exacted for having fully invested in the feverish, sultry dream in the first place. Now we are what is being dreamed - this trope is what Lynch has worked and innovated from. And again the distinction between the performance as perceived from outside, with jeers and catcalls, and the human being inside as we know it to suffer. As with all those silent films before about clowns suffering from behind painted smiles, it is a tragic sight of humiliation and despair. When he bellows inordinately, the audience laughs, but we know it's the sound of a soul being torn apart. My only minor gripe, is with how forceful is this part, how emotional. Then again it makes sense; we are again so adeptly placed inside the character, and made to feel as broken as he is. The film ends with the woman performing again her number that captivated the audience so much, only now we understand what's behind the notes. "I'm programmed for love" sings Dietrich, the femme fatale - and so desire, sexual danger personified - who operated the performance from behind the stage. We have mostly come to know film noir from American film. But it was born in Germany, between Dr. Mabuse and this. It's a compelling moral, as in noir later: we are reminded again how dangerous it is to indulge the chimeras of the mind, ego and desire, and how the social fabric has its ways of eventually restoring us in the common, harmless delusions. It's okay to watch, anything more is at our spiritual peril.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The "Carmen" who got away
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    evening1
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Having just caught the Metropolitan's 2010 production of "Carmen" on film during the opera company's outdoor HD Live festival, I expected this film would end with Lola's comeuppance, if not murder. It was a little chilling, and, I have to admit, disappointing, to see her sitting pretty on-stage as her discarded, humiliated husband shuffles away into hopeless oblivion. This film, which I had taped from the City University of New York's excellent TV channel, suffered from horrible visual and sound quality but it managed to keep my attention throughout. It seems a case study in the follies of trying to live without the benefit of self-knowledge. Professor Rath -- was he supposed to be Jewish in this film made as Naziism was on the rise in Germany? -- was a misfit and a clod, a man who found his place in life through his book knowledge. What was missing in him was any sense of who he was as a man. Rath demonstrated his ineptness outside of the ivory tower by blundering into Lola's dressing room, a fateful breaking of social boundaries. Lola treats Rath as one might an old teddy bear. When he proposes marriage, gorgeous Lola cackles hysterically, but it wouldn't occur to Rath to wonder what this might mean. Lola accepts the offer, though one would have to assume the union will never be consummated. (Rather than gaining a love partner, she takes in the father she probably never knew.) Rath's eventual rejection is inevitable. The only surprise here is Lola's getting off scot free. Maybe she thinks about her actions a little; she does seem to darken somewhat during the course of the film. However, she's ultimately left pretty much unscathed by the final credits. Interestingly, Dietrich goes on from this film to become a success in Hollywood, whereas the actor who played Rath remained in Germany to participate in Nazi-propaganda films from which which his career never recovered -- an outcome that pretty much parallels the movie's plot line.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Naughty, naughty..."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moonspinner55
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A stuffy, lonely German college professor, laughed at by his immature pupils, ventures out to a cabaret in the village to berate his students for ogling the female entertainment; instead, he becomes infatuated with the star of the show, chanteuse Lola Lola, and apparently she to him. After marrying the flashy girl, the teacher leaves his profession to travel with the theatrical troupe, but life on the road immediately wears him down. An ugly little story, adapted from Heinrich Mann's novel "Professor Unrath", has a winking-nudging overlay of sexual byplay and was released to great acclaim in both German and English-language versions (this review pertains to the German version with subtitles). Director Josef von Sternberg was already a 15-year veteran of Hollywood movie-making by the time "The Blue Angel" arrived, and yet several sequences (most notably in the first reel and the last) are sloppily constructed and uncertainly paced. Emil Jannings is wonderful as the unloved professor who initially blossoms in the company of streetwise Marlene Dietrich, but his emotional unraveling is awfully quick in coming. Josef von Sternberg is far too sluggish in the beginning, but by the midway point he rushes the narrative...and the audience isn't allowed to get their bearings. As a result, the plot feels like a sadistic series of screw-turns, with no hope (or heart) in sight. **1/2 from ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Humbert Humbert's predecessor
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watching "Der blaue Engel" ("The Blue Angel" in English), I got the feeling that it was sort of a precursor to "Lolita". When you look at how Prof. Immanuel Rath (Emil Jannings) lets his infatuation with nightclub singer Lola Lola (Marlene Dietrich) come to dominate his life, it seems very much like what happens to Humbert Humbert. Of course, the movie is best known for Dietrich's sexy performance as the liberated chanteuse (on which Madeline Kahn's character in "Blazing Saddles" was based). Dietrich must have been every man's dream after the movie came out. Still, the change in Prof. Rath's life caused by his obsession with her certainly stands out as well. All in all, Josef von Sternberg created a real masterpiece.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Perhaps it was startling at its time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    funkyfry
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I can't say much about this film, having just seen it for the first time, but while I was impressed with Von Sternberg's direction, as usual, I felt that this film lacked substance and drive. The story is too predictable; maybe at its time, it had some novelty. I hoped that the road would twist in some unpredictable direction, but it simply loped along to its predictably depressing conclusion. Jannings and Dietrich are wonderfully cast and carry off their roles with perfection. Less convincing is Kurt Gerron's magician -- he seems like he would belong more as a bar-tender than as an impresario. The touches of humor are odd.... I found myself uncertain at times whether it was a comedy or a drama. Certainly, the film makes Jannings' imperious school professor a subject of so much ridicule that his fall from grace comes more as a relief than a tragedy. One would hope to find minor characters with some flash to add some interest to a simple story, but only Hans Albers' strongman can really make much of an impression next to Jannings and Dietrich. It's a pleasing film to watch, I enjoyed much of the atmosphere and so forth, but it didn't make much of a lasting impression on me I'm afraid.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Succulent, Mellifluous
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Antti Keisala
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Von Sternberg's film is a wonderfully constructed piece of succulent and mellifluous tragicomedy. The fluently moving camera offers a beautiful sense of place, and especially the crooked pebble-stoned streets and leaning houses are the unforgettable epitomes of this film in my memory. Just as with Vigo's "L'Atalante" (1934), much of the film's power depends on us, as the audience, being able to fall in love with the lead actress. It certainly helps that the director did, and for once some knowledge of production enhances the experience: Umrat/Jennings as the jealous and passionate star, Dietrich as the object of desire not only of the boys but of the camera. I also really like the use of stairs, which clearly separate the differing worlds. I could definitely see this influencing "Z&eacute;ro de conduite" (1933) and "Hets" (1944). The slow movement of the camera in the empty classroom after the crucial confrontation reveals one of the most touching visual moments I can think of (this is repeated later in an equally heart-breaking scene). I remember I was very young when I saw this for the first time. It made a lasting impression then, and I count it as one of the three films that ultimately made me fall in love with films to the extent that my thirst will never be quenched.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Blue Angel
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    They released this film filmed in two versions, they acted all the scenes in both German and English, but when I decided to watch this film from the 1001 Movies You Must See Before You Die book, I was going to watch the original German language version. Basically Professor Immanuel Rath (Emil Jannings) is the esteemed college preparatory high school educator who has punished many of his male students for spreading around the image of beautiful stage performer Lola Lola (Destry Rides Again's Marlene Dietrich). He hopes to catch the school boys in the cabaret club The Blue Angel, where she is the headlining act, and after her for himself he grows slowly passionate for her, and with a pair of panties snatched by a student he has a good reason to return there the following night. Having had a night of desire and such, Rath returns to class next day, with the Principal (Eduard Von Winterstein) furious to see the students running riot, and he is aware of the teacher's behaviour recently as well. He decides it is best to retire from the school, and with his newfound freedom he can marry Lola, but they cannot stay happy for long as their money problems grow, and to earn he is forced to become a stage clown in the cabaret troupe. Rath is often filled with jealousy and lust for his wife and her profession, she leaves herself open as a "shared woman", and he is being ridiculed for his past while performing as a clown. He performs his last act at The Blue Angel, and he is shocked to see Lola kissing her new love interest strongman Mazeppa (Hans Albers), and his rage turns into insanity, where he starts strangles his wife and is forced into a straitjacket. In the end, having been released from prison, Rath is not able to resolve his position as a school teacher, and he has obviously lost wife Lola, so he dies from extreme self pity clutching the school desks that once sat his loyal students. Also starring Kurt Gerron as Kiepert the Magician, Rosa Valetti as Guste the Magician's Wife, Reinhold Bernt as The Clown, Hans Roth as Beadle the Caretaker of the Secondary School, Rolf M&uuml;ller as Pupil Angst and Robert Klein-L&ouml;rk as Pupil Goldstaub. Jannings - in his first talking picture - gives a mixed but equally interesting performance as the teacher turned performer with a troubled passion, and Dietrich is wonderful in her iconic top hat and black stockings as the seductive stage performer with a cruel streak, it is a film with some memorable sequences and moments that stand out, especially of course the cabaret stuff, making it a most watchable drama. Very good!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Falling From Grace Over "Show Girl" or There's No Fool Like An Old Fool!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    John T. Ryan (redryan64@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    WE CAN WELL recall viewing this film for the very first time on a PBS Friday evening show. This was circa 1971 and we needed to go to such Public Television stations as our own WTTW, Channel 11 in Chicago in order to see many films which weren't shown on commercial TV Statiobs. WELL, HOW THINGS have changed. Just this passed Monday (2 days ago), Turner Classic Movies ran THE BLUE ANGEL in prime-time. It had been about 40 years (yes, count 'em, folks!) since our initial contact with Herr Josef Von Sternberg's dark, tragic drama. We had seen it once or twice during that period, but had never given it my undivided attention. ALTHOUGH IT IS a German language film, there was at least one of these showings was in a recently rediscovered English language version. We also remember a showing which was in German; but featured Miss Dietrich's performance of "Falling In Lov Again" in English. VIEWING A FILM SUCH as this very talky drama, while at the same time being compelled to read Subtutles, in order to follow the story can really prove to be a pain right where one sits. Yet, it does seem to become easier as the story progresses; as we become engrossed with the scenario unfolding, the dark yet starkly penetrating images, moody and highly atmospheric songs & music and the virtuoso acting performances. THE STORY MAY seem somewhat complex; yet it is probably the very universal themes and connection with the lives and needs of all people that make this such a powerful and compelling of a story with such a long life as an all time favourite. IN SHORT, WE have a story of loneliness, the need to love and be loved, the falling from grace of a highly regarded and most straight laced of a member of academia. From perhaps a most distinguished position and and outstanding of a reputation as a Professor of Literature at the unnamed university, the professor (Mr. Emil Jannings) falls in love with a common, vulgar cabaret singer and exponent of sex, Lola Lola (Miss Marlena Dietrich). THE STORY COVERS a period of over five years, in which the middle aged, clearly un-handsome man discovers that he has fallen to such a degree of degradation as to not only being a minor entertainer; but also participating in selling his own wife. During appearances following Lola's doing her song, professor Roth's duties included peddling some rather pornographic type of postcards to the bawdy male patrons of the show. WE MUST CONFESS that even being a grown man, married with two children, there was an awful lot of obvious seedy goings on that I missed on previous viewings. Certainly, there were no examples of explicit on screen sex (such as have become so commonplace); and yet, with all of the occurrences we surely are forced to ask a few questions. IN ADDITION TO the setting of a night club with rather risqu&eacute; programming, what is it that all of these college boys find so fascinating? Why do the young men hide from the Professor in secret rooms that are below the floors? What is the purpose of these rooms? Why does the proprietor worry about the presence of a police officer; for, isn't this a legal and licensed establishment? Do you think that there is sex for sale here? We do. THE AMAZING FEAT that is accomplished here is making such an interesting story out of such a sordid and low life segment of society. WE GIVE THIS five stars as our rating.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unforgettable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jacabiya
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let me join the ranks that herald this film as one of the great ones, an unforgettable all-time world cinema masterpiece that should be way higher in the IMDb scores, still relevant, powerful, not dated, with not one but two landmark performances. In the first half the film is very funny, but when Lola Lola starts clucking in the wedding reception the horror begins. This is my favorite Marlene Dietrich role, and for my taste the only sexy one, with baby fat and a rounder, younger, nubile face and body(before she turned into the more stern and severe deep-voiced German femme fatale). I find it amazing that her character in this 1930 film still turns me on. Jannings overacts grandiosely to match the extremely melodramatic, denigrating, tragic story, and gives one of the great acting performances of movie history (along with his performance in the silent The Last Laugh). The magician is perfectly sleazy yet human in his ignorance. The film piles it up towards its cringing climax, culminating in action not actually shown, an extremely intelligent move on Sternberg's part. And I dare anyone to come up with more horrible and painful sounds in film history than the professor's.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Downfall of an Arrogant Academic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Le Sage
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Blue Angel features a simple but effective narrative, showing the fall of a man into degradation and squalor. As such, it echoes the themes in early Weimar cinema such as Pandora's Box. The narrative is, indeed, so simple, that this early "talkie" could just as easily have been a silent film. Only rarely is the new sound technology explored to good effect, such as when songs can be heard when the doors from Lola's room to the stage are periodically opened and closed by characters. There is also, of course, the use of song, with Dietrich's voice showcased to good affect. Emil Jannings portrays the stereotype of an academic perfectly: arrogant, insular and with some minor eccentricities, he is unable to cope with life in the "real world" and this leads to his fall from grace. Initially, we in the audience, like his students, see him as a clown, a laughable, pompous yet bumbling figure. His ultimate fate is to be exposed to the whole town as a fool when, stripped of his power, he literally becomes a clown before seeking to return to the insularity of his old post. However, the Professor is not the only loathsome character in this film. The attitude of the students is as despicable as that of their tutor: with their arrogant and bullying behaviour, whilst they are his nemesis, they are also his mirror. They are growing into his image and, with his growing captivation with Lola, he is growing into theirs. Lola is an equally unlikable character and perhaps, once again, reflects concern amongst conservatives in Weimar society about the growing power of women. She is far smarter than the "learned" professor in terms of her ability to understand and manipulate people. Going out on the stage each night is the opposite to his insular world yet it his "act" of appearing respectable in society that this actress is able to quickly pull apart, exposing the shallow man inside. The bird motif used throughout the film is strikingly effective. At the start, the bird who can no longer sing is callously discarded by the housekeeper, just as the worn-out, useless Professor will be discarded, first by the school and then by society. The doomed bird motif is also prefigured by the birds near the clock as the procession of ghoulish statues marches past with each hour. Finally, the Professor himself is humiliated during the clown and magician routine, forced to have doves fly out from under his top hat and to crow like a rooster. Ultimately, this is a brilliant film and, like much late Weimar cinema, reflects themes of moral decline and degradation. This time, however, the character is deeply unlikable from the outset and his humiliation is really an increasing expose to the world of his pre-existing inner nature. He does not grow or transform as a character; rather, as his power is stripped, his true nature is revealed. The learned academic is the biggest fool of all. Stripped of his position and prestige, the academic is nothing more than a clown.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Only angels have wings
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    chaos-rampant
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Films that revolve around performance are essentially about cinema, I'm always on the lookout for these. But unlike the more traditional films about the making of films - Day for Night, Contempt, The Stunt Man, Shadow of the Vampire, etc - those about performance have the extra allure that we have to participate in staging the illusion; it falls on us to imagine the cinematic scenario, and thus complete the notion, actually see in our minds how it completes. It is the best kind of in-sight into creative life - which is every life on the planet, a long series of invention, deception, connection. In The Red Shoes for example, it was a dance between us from the position of the camera and the stage where the story is being danced out. A more intriguing vision we find in the silent Dr. Mabuse, with us looking to apprehend the criminal mastermind who under various guises manipulates the narrative we see. Or the continuation of this in The American Friend, another German film; a 'frame' artist who becomes framed in an illusion that unfolds, this is the film within, as gangster stuff around Europe. This second group is more competent because the film-within, in whatever form, is better integrated inside the outer film. But in all these cases the main subject remains the same; the effort to discern boundaries between a life we control, and so a narrative we are free to improvise as best we can, and a life that is framed, scripted and storyboarded around us from outside. (the truly wise filmmakers understand how these are the same; how, in other terms, the best actors in life are those who are completely clueless about the narrative and therefore effortlessly natural, and those who have studied it and can exercise volition to reshape themselves into what the role requires). Sternberg had made a film about film before this, a more explicit but astounding vision of a filmed reality that prophesied New Wave thirty years before. This is more inconspicuous, less singlemindedly about self-reference, with interesting crowds and rooms around the stage that we can loose ourselves into. It is just endearing to watch on a very basic level, occasionally pretty funny; and in the end thoroughly gut-wrenching. Yet it is still very much about a man losing himself into a performance. What entices him and us is the woman; in fact, we are made to share the male point-of-view so adeptly, the camera always strategically placed where it can be teased and seduced by long legs in stockings, by large eye-lashes making promises, that it is not just the professor, but us as well, more importantly us, that want to let go and be absorbed in the sexual fantasy. It's no wonder she is so captivating, we know after all how Sternberg would grow to worship her, and bind, fully devote his craft to images of her. The second part is where it's truly grueling to watch, where the professor, a pillar of morals and ethos at the start, is completely subsumed inside the fantasy and loses all. Again Emil Jannings puts on a costume. So many fascinating things then happen so quickly, I was left with jaw open. We revisit the cabaret stage from before, only now, quite literally, from inside the mirror looking out; now we are the spectacle, the show being looked on, with being made to perform as the price exacted for having fully invested in the feverish, sultry dream in the first place. Now we are what is being dreamed - this trope is what Lynch has worked and innovated from. And again the distinction between the performance as perceived from outside, with jeers and catcalls, and the human being inside as we know it to suffer. As with all those silent films before about clowns suffering from behind painted smiles, it is a tragic sight of humiliation and despair. When he bellows inordinately, the audience laughs, but we know it's the sound of a soul being torn apart. My only minor gripe, is with how forceful is this part, how emotional. Then again it makes sense; we are again so adeptly placed inside the character, and made to feel as broken as he is. The film ends with the woman performing again her number that captivated the audience so much, only now we understand what's behind the notes. "I'm programmed for love" sings Dietrich, the femme fatale - and so desire, sexual danger personified - who operated the performance from behind the stage. We have mostly come to know film noir from American film. But it was born in Germany, between Dr. Mabuse and this. It's a compelling moral, as in noir later: we are reminded again how dangerous it is to indulge the chimeras of the mind, ego and desire, and how the social fabric has its ways of eventually restoring us in the common, harmless delusions. It's okay to watch, anything more is at our spiritual peril.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The "Carmen" who got away
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    evening1
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Having just caught the Metropolitan's 2010 production of "Carmen" on film during the opera company's outdoor HD Live festival, I expected this film would end with Lola's comeuppance, if not murder. It was a little chilling, and, I have to admit, disappointing, to see her sitting pretty on-stage as her discarded, humiliated husband shuffles away into hopeless oblivion. This film, which I had taped from the City University of New York's excellent TV channel, suffered from horrible visual and sound quality but it managed to keep my attention throughout. It seems a case study in the follies of trying to live without the benefit of self-knowledge. Professor Rath -- was he supposed to be Jewish in this film made as Naziism was on the rise in Germany? -- was a misfit and a clod, a man who found his place in life through his book knowledge. What was missing in him was any sense of who he was as a man. Rath demonstrated his ineptness outside of the ivory tower by blundering into Lola's dressing room, a fateful breaking of social boundaries. Lola treats Rath as one might an old teddy bear. When he proposes marriage, gorgeous Lola cackles hysterically, but it wouldn't occur to Rath to wonder what this might mean. Lola accepts the offer, though one would have to assume the union will never be consummated. (Rather than gaining a love partner, she takes in the father she probably never knew.) Rath's eventual rejection is inevitable. The only surprise here is Lola's getting off scot free. Maybe she thinks about her actions a little; she does seem to darken somewhat during the course of the film. However, she's ultimately left pretty much unscathed by the final credits. Interestingly, Dietrich goes on from this film to become a success in Hollywood, whereas the actor who played Rath remained in Germany to participate in Nazi-propaganda films from which which his career never recovered -- an outcome that pretty much parallels the movie's plot line.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Naughty, naughty..."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moonspinner55
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A stuffy, lonely German college professor, laughed at by his immature pupils, ventures out to a cabaret in the village to berate his students for ogling the female entertainment; instead, he becomes infatuated with the star of the show, chanteuse Lola Lola, and apparently she to him. After marrying the flashy girl, the teacher leaves his profession to travel with the theatrical troupe, but life on the road immediately wears him down. An ugly little story, adapted from Heinrich Mann's novel "Professor Unrath", has a winking-nudging overlay of sexual byplay and was released to great acclaim in both German and English-language versions (this review pertains to the German version with subtitles). Director Josef von Sternberg was already a 15-year veteran of Hollywood movie-making by the time "The Blue Angel" arrived, and yet several sequences (most notably in the first reel and the last) are sloppily constructed and uncertainly paced. Emil Jannings is wonderful as the unloved professor who initially blossoms in the company of streetwise Marlene Dietrich, but his emotional unraveling is awfully quick in coming. Josef von Sternberg is far too sluggish in the beginning, but by the midway point he rushes the narrative...and the audience isn't allowed to get their bearings. As a result, the plot feels like a sadistic series of screw-turns, with no hope (or heart) in sight. **1/2 from ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Humbert Humbert's predecessor
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watching "Der blaue Engel" ("The Blue Angel" in English), I got the feeling that it was sort of a precursor to "Lolita". When you look at how Prof. Immanuel Rath (Emil Jannings) lets his infatuation with nightclub singer Lola Lola (Marlene Dietrich) come to dominate his life, it seems very much like what happens to Humbert Humbert. Of course, the movie is best known for Dietrich's sexy performance as the liberated chanteuse (on which Madeline Kahn's character in "Blazing Saddles" was based). Dietrich must have been every man's dream after the movie came out. Still, the change in Prof. Rath's life caused by his obsession with her certainly stands out as well. All in all, Josef von Sternberg created a real masterpiece.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Perhaps it was startling at its time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    funkyfry
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I can't say much about this film, having just seen it for the first time, but while I was impressed with Von Sternberg's direction, as usual, I felt that this film lacked substance and drive. The story is too predictable; maybe at its time, it had some novelty. I hoped that the road would twist in some unpredictable direction, but it simply loped along to its predictably depressing conclusion. Jannings and Dietrich are wonderfully cast and carry off their roles with perfection. Less convincing is Kurt Gerron's magician -- he seems like he would belong more as a bar-tender than as an impresario. The touches of humor are odd.... I found myself uncertain at times whether it was a comedy or a drama. Certainly, the film makes Jannings' imperious school professor a subject of so much ridicule that his fall from grace comes more as a relief than a tragedy. One would hope to find minor characters with some flash to add some interest to a simple story, but only Hans Albers' strongman can really make much of an impression next to Jannings and Dietrich. It's a pleasing film to watch, I enjoyed much of the atmosphere and so forth, but it didn't make much of a lasting impression on me I'm afraid.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Succulent, Mellifluous
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Antti Keisala
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Von Sternberg's film is a wonderfully constructed piece of succulent and mellifluous tragicomedy. The fluently moving camera offers a beautiful sense of place, and especially the crooked pebble-stoned streets and leaning houses are the unforgettable epitomes of this film in my memory. Just as with Vigo's "L'Atalante" (1934), much of the film's power depends on us, as the audience, being able to fall in love with the lead actress. It certainly helps that the director did, and for once some knowledge of production enhances the experience: Umrat/Jennings as the jealous and passionate star, Dietrich as the object of desire not only of the boys but of the camera. I also really like the use of stairs, which clearly separate the differing worlds. I could definitely see this influencing "Z&eacute;ro de conduite" (1933) and "Hets" (1944). The slow movement of the camera in the empty classroom after the crucial confrontation reveals one of the most touching visual moments I can think of (this is repeated later in an equally heart-breaking scene). I remember I was very young when I saw this for the first time. It made a lasting impression then, and I count it as one of the three films that ultimately made me fall in love with films to the extent that my thirst will never be quenched.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Blue Angel
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    They released this film filmed in two versions, they acted all the scenes in both German and English, but when I decided to watch this film from the 1001 Movies You Must See Before You Die book, I was going to watch the original German language version. Basically Professor Immanuel Rath (Emil Jannings) is the esteemed college preparatory high school educator who has punished many of his male students for spreading around the image of beautiful stage performer Lola Lola (Destry Rides Again's Marlene Dietrich). He hopes to catch the school boys in the cabaret club The Blue Angel, where she is the headlining act, and after her for himself he grows slowly passionate for her, and with a pair of panties snatched by a student he has a good reason to return there the following night. Having had a night of desire and such, Rath returns to class next day, with the Principal (Eduard Von Winterstein) furious to see the students running riot, and he is aware of the teacher's behaviour recently as well. He decides it is best to retire from the school, and with his newfound freedom he can marry Lola, but they cannot stay happy for long as their money problems grow, and to earn he is forced to become a stage clown in the cabaret troupe. Rath is often filled with jealousy and lust for his wife and her profession, she leaves herself open as a "shared woman", and he is being ridiculed for his past while performing as a clown. He performs his last act at The Blue Angel, and he is shocked to see Lola kissing her new love interest strongman Mazeppa (Hans Albers), and his rage turns into insanity, where he starts strangles his wife and is forced into a straitjacket. In the end, having been released from prison, Rath is not able to resolve his position as a school teacher, and he has obviously lost wife Lola, so he dies from extreme self pity clutching the school desks that once sat his loyal students. Also starring Kurt Gerron as Kiepert the Magician, Rosa Valetti as Guste the Magician's Wife, Reinhold Bernt as The Clown, Hans Roth as Beadle the Caretaker of the Secondary School, Rolf M&uuml;ller as Pupil Angst and Robert Klein-L&ouml;rk as Pupil Goldstaub. Jannings - in his first talking picture - gives a mixed but equally interesting performance as the teacher turned performer with a troubled passion, and Dietrich is wonderful in her iconic top hat and black stockings as the seductive stage performer with a cruel streak, it is a film with some memorable sequences and moments that stand out, especially of course the cabaret stuff, making it a most watchable drama. Very good!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Falling From Grace Over "Show Girl" or There's No Fool Like An Old Fool!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    John T. Ryan (redryan64@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    WE CAN WELL recall viewing this film for the very first time on a PBS Friday evening show. This was circa 1971 and we needed to go to such Public Television stations as our own WTTW, Channel 11 in Chicago in order to see many films which weren't shown on commercial TV Statiobs. WELL, HOW THINGS have changed. Just this passed Monday (2 days ago), Turner Classic Movies ran THE BLUE ANGEL in prime-time. It had been about 40 years (yes, count 'em, folks!) since our initial contact with Herr Josef Von Sternberg's dark, tragic drama. We had seen it once or twice during that period, but had never given it my undivided attention. ALTHOUGH IT IS a German language film, there was at least one of these showings was in a recently rediscovered English language version. We also remember a showing which was in German; but featured Miss Dietrich's performance of "Falling In Lov Again" in English. VIEWING A FILM SUCH as this very talky drama, while at the same time being compelled to read Subtutles, in order to follow the story can really prove to be a pain right where one sits. Yet, it does seem to become easier as the story progresses; as we become engrossed with the scenario unfolding, the dark yet starkly penetrating images, moody and highly atmospheric songs & music and the virtuoso acting performances. THE STORY MAY seem somewhat complex; yet it is probably the very universal themes and connection with the lives and needs of all people that make this such a powerful and compelling of a story with such a long life as an all time favourite. IN SHORT, WE have a story of loneliness, the need to love and be loved, the falling from grace of a highly regarded and most straight laced of a member of academia. From perhaps a most distinguished position and and outstanding of a reputation as a Professor of Literature at the unnamed university, the professor (Mr. Emil Jannings) falls in love with a common, vulgar cabaret singer and exponent of sex, Lola Lola (Miss Marlena Dietrich). THE STORY COVERS a period of over five years, in which the middle aged, clearly un-handsome man discovers that he has fallen to such a degree of degradation as to not only being a minor entertainer; but also participating in selling his own wife. During appearances following Lola's doing her song, professor Roth's duties included peddling some rather pornographic type of postcards to the bawdy male patrons of the show. WE MUST CONFESS that even being a grown man, married with two children, there was an awful lot of obvious seedy goings on that I missed on previous viewings. Certainly, there were no examples of explicit on screen sex (such as have become so commonplace); and yet, with all of the occurrences we surely are forced to ask a few questions. IN ADDITION TO the setting of a night club with rather risqu&eacute; programming, what is it that all of these college boys find so fascinating? Why do the young men hide from the Professor in secret rooms that are below the floors? What is the purpose of these rooms? Why does the proprietor worry about the presence of a police officer; for, isn't this a legal and licensed establishment? Do you think that there is sex for sale here? We do. THE AMAZING FEAT that is accomplished here is making such an interesting story out of such a sordid and low life segment of society. WE GIVE THIS five stars as our rating.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unforgettable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jacabiya
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let me join the ranks that herald this film as one of the great ones, an unforgettable all-time world cinema masterpiece that should be way higher in the IMDb scores, still relevant, powerful, not dated, with not one but two landmark performances. In the first half the film is very funny, but when Lola Lola starts clucking in the wedding reception the horror begins. This is my favorite Marlene Dietrich role, and for my taste the only sexy one, with baby fat and a rounder, younger, nubile face and body(before she turned into the more stern and severe deep-voiced German femme fatale). I find it amazing that her character in this 1930 film still turns me on. Jannings overacts grandiosely to match the extremely melodramatic, denigrating, tragic story, and gives one of the great acting performances of movie history (along with his performance in the silent The Last Laugh). The magician is perfectly sleazy yet human in his ignorance. The film piles it up towards its cringing climax, culminating in action not actually shown, an extremely intelligent move on Sternberg's part. And I dare anyone to come up with more horrible and painful sounds in film history than the professor's.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Downfall of an Arrogant Academic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Le Sage
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Blue Angel features a simple but effective narrative, showing the fall of a man into degradation and squalor. As such, it echoes the themes in early Weimar cinema such as Pandora's Box. The narrative is, indeed, so simple, that this early "talkie" could just as easily have been a silent film. Only rarely is the new sound technology explored to good effect, such as when songs can be heard when the doors from Lola's room to the stage are periodically opened and closed by characters. There is also, of course, the use of song, with Dietrich's voice showcased to good affect. Emil Jannings portrays the stereotype of an academic perfectly: arrogant, insular and with some minor eccentricities, he is unable to cope with life in the "real world" and this leads to his fall from grace. Initially, we in the audience, like his students, see him as a clown, a laughable, pompous yet bumbling figure. His ultimate fate is to be exposed to the whole town as a fool when, stripped of his power, he literally becomes a clown before seeking to return to the insularity of his old post. However, the Professor is not the only loathsome character in this film. The attitude of the students is as despicable as that of their tutor: with their arrogant and bullying behaviour, whilst they are his nemesis, they are also his mirror. They are growing into his image and, with his growing captivation with Lola, he is growing into theirs. Lola is an equally unlikable character and perhaps, once again, reflects concern amongst conservatives in Weimar society about the growing power of women. She is far smarter than the "learned" professor in terms of her ability to understand and manipulate people. Going out on the stage each night is the opposite to his insular world yet it his "act" of appearing respectable in society that this actress is able to quickly pull apart, exposing the shallow man inside. The bird motif used throughout the film is strikingly effective. At the start, the bird who can no longer sing is callously discarded by the housekeeper, just as the worn-out, useless Professor will be discarded, first by the school and then by society. The doomed bird motif is also prefigured by the birds near the clock as the procession of ghoulish statues marches past with each hour. Finally, the Professor himself is humiliated during the clown and magician routine, forced to have doves fly out from under his top hat and to crow like a rooster. Ultimately, this is a brilliant film and, like much late Weimar cinema, reflects themes of moral decline and degradation. This time, however, the character is deeply unlikable from the outset and his humiliation is really an increasing expose to the world of his pre-existing inner nature. He does not grow or transform as a character; rather, as his power is stripped, his true nature is revealed. The learned academic is the biggest fool of all. Stripped of his position and prestige, the academic is nothing more than a clown.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Only angels have wings
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    chaos-rampant
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Films that revolve around performance are essentially about cinema, I'm always on the lookout for these. But unlike the more traditional films about the making of films - Day for Night, Contempt, The Stunt Man, Shadow of the Vampire, etc - those about performance have the extra allure that we have to participate in staging the illusion; it falls on us to imagine the cinematic scenario, and thus complete the notion, actually see in our minds how it completes. It is the best kind of in-sight into creative life - which is every life on the planet, a long series of invention, deception, connection. In The Red Shoes for example, it was a dance between us from the position of the camera and the stage where the story is being danced out. A more intriguing vision we find in the silent Dr. Mabuse, with us looking to apprehend the criminal mastermind who under various guises manipulates the narrative we see. Or the continuation of this in The American Friend, another German film; a 'frame' artist who becomes framed in an illusion that unfolds, this is the film within, as gangster stuff around Europe. This second group is more competent because the film-within, in whatever form, is better integrated inside the outer film. But in all these cases the main subject remains the same; the effort to discern boundaries between a life we control, and so a narrative we are free to improvise as best we can, and a life that is framed, scripted and storyboarded around us from outside. (the truly wise filmmakers understand how these are the same; how, in other terms, the best actors in life are those who are completely clueless about the narrative and therefore effortlessly natural, and those who have studied it and can exercise volition to reshape themselves into what the role requires). Sternberg had made a film about film before this, a more explicit but astounding vision of a filmed reality that prophesied New Wave thirty years before. This is more inconspicuous, less singlemindedly about self-reference, with interesting crowds and rooms around the stage that we can loose ourselves into. It is just endearing to watch on a very basic level, occasionally pretty funny; and in the end thoroughly gut-wrenching. Yet it is still very much about a man losing himself into a performance. What entices him and us is the woman; in fact, we are made to share the male point-of-view so adeptly, the camera always strategically placed where it can be teased and seduced by long legs in stockings, by large eye-lashes making promises, that it is not just the professor, but us as well, more importantly us, that want to let go and be absorbed in the sexual fantasy. It's no wonder she is so captivating, we know after all how Sternberg would grow to worship her, and bind, fully devote his craft to images of her. The second part is where it's truly grueling to watch, where the professor, a pillar of morals and ethos at the start, is completely subsumed inside the fantasy and loses all. Again Emil Jannings puts on a costume. So many fascinating things then happen so quickly, I was left with jaw open. We revisit the cabaret stage from before, only now, quite literally, from inside the mirror looking out; now we are the spectacle, the show being looked on, with being made to perform as the price exacted for having fully invested in the feverish, sultry dream in the first place. Now we are what is being dreamed - this trope is what Lynch has worked and innovated from. And again the distinction between the performance as perceived from outside, with jeers and catcalls, and the human being inside as we know it to suffer. As with all those silent films before about clowns suffering from behind painted smiles, it is a tragic sight of humiliation and despair. When he bellows inordinately, the audience laughs, but we know it's the sound of a soul being torn apart. My only minor gripe, is with how forceful is this part, how emotional. Then again it makes sense; we are again so adeptly placed inside the character, and made to feel as broken as he is. The film ends with the woman performing again her number that captivated the audience so much, only now we understand what's behind the notes. "I'm programmed for love" sings Dietrich, the femme fatale - and so desire, sexual danger personified - who operated the performance from behind the stage. We have mostly come to know film noir from American film. But it was born in Germany, between Dr. Mabuse and this. It's a compelling moral, as in noir later: we are reminded again how dangerous it is to indulge the chimeras of the mind, ego and desire, and how the social fabric has its ways of eventually restoring us in the common, harmless delusions. It's okay to watch, anything more is at our spiritual peril.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The "Carmen" who got away
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    evening1
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Having just caught the Metropolitan's 2010 production of "Carmen" on film during the opera company's outdoor HD Live festival, I expected this film would end with Lola's comeuppance, if not murder. It was a little chilling, and, I have to admit, disappointing, to see her sitting pretty on-stage as her discarded, humiliated husband shuffles away into hopeless oblivion. This film, which I had taped from the City University of New York's excellent TV channel, suffered from horrible visual and sound quality but it managed to keep my attention throughout. It seems a case study in the follies of trying to live without the benefit of self-knowledge. Professor Rath -- was he supposed to be Jewish in this film made as Naziism was on the rise in Germany? -- was a misfit and a clod, a man who found his place in life through his book knowledge. What was missing in him was any sense of who he was as a man. Rath demonstrated his ineptness outside of the ivory tower by blundering into Lola's dressing room, a fateful breaking of social boundaries. Lola treats Rath as one might an old teddy bear. When he proposes marriage, gorgeous Lola cackles hysterically, but it wouldn't occur to Rath to wonder what this might mean. Lola accepts the offer, though one would have to assume the union will never be consummated. (Rather than gaining a love partner, she takes in the father she probably never knew.) Rath's eventual rejection is inevitable. The only surprise here is Lola's getting off scot free. Maybe she thinks about her actions a little; she does seem to darken somewhat during the course of the film. However, she's ultimately left pretty much unscathed by the final credits. Interestingly, Dietrich goes on from this film to become a success in Hollywood, whereas the actor who played Rath remained in Germany to participate in Nazi-propaganda films from which which his career never recovered -- an outcome that pretty much parallels the movie's plot line.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Naughty, naughty..."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moonspinner55
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A stuffy, lonely German college professor, laughed at by his immature pupils, ventures out to a cabaret in the village to berate his students for ogling the female entertainment; instead, he becomes infatuated with the star of the show, chanteuse Lola Lola, and apparently she to him. After marrying the flashy girl, the teacher leaves his profession to travel with the theatrical troupe, but life on the road immediately wears him down. An ugly little story, adapted from Heinrich Mann's novel "Professor Unrath", has a winking-nudging overlay of sexual byplay and was released to great acclaim in both German and English-language versions (this review pertains to the German version with subtitles). Director Josef von Sternberg was already a 15-year veteran of Hollywood movie-making by the time "The Blue Angel" arrived, and yet several sequences (most notably in the first reel and the last) are sloppily constructed and uncertainly paced. Emil Jannings is wonderful as the unloved professor who initially blossoms in the company of streetwise Marlene Dietrich, but his emotional unraveling is awfully quick in coming. Josef von Sternberg is far too sluggish in the beginning, but by the midway point he rushes the narrative...and the audience isn't allowed to get their bearings. As a result, the plot feels like a sadistic series of screw-turns, with no hope (or heart) in sight. **1/2 from ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Humbert Humbert's predecessor
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watching "Der blaue Engel" ("The Blue Angel" in English), I got the feeling that it was sort of a precursor to "Lolita". When you look at how Prof. Immanuel Rath (Emil Jannings) lets his infatuation with nightclub singer Lola Lola (Marlene Dietrich) come to dominate his life, it seems very much like what happens to Humbert Humbert. Of course, the movie is best known for Dietrich's sexy performance as the liberated chanteuse (on which Madeline Kahn's character in "Blazing Saddles" was based). Dietrich must have been every man's dream after the movie came out. Still, the change in Prof. Rath's life caused by his obsession with her certainly stands out as well. All in all, Josef von Sternberg created a real masterpiece.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Perhaps it was startling at its time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    funkyfry
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I can't say much about this film, having just seen it for the first time, but while I was impressed with Von Sternberg's direction, as usual, I felt that this film lacked substance and drive. The story is too predictable; maybe at its time, it had some novelty. I hoped that the road would twist in some unpredictable direction, but it simply loped along to its predictably depressing conclusion. Jannings and Dietrich are wonderfully cast and carry off their roles with perfection. Less convincing is Kurt Gerron's magician -- he seems like he would belong more as a bar-tender than as an impresario. The touches of humor are odd.... I found myself uncertain at times whether it was a comedy or a drama. Certainly, the film makes Jannings' imperious school professor a subject of so much ridicule that his fall from grace comes more as a relief than a tragedy. One would hope to find minor characters with some flash to add some interest to a simple story, but only Hans Albers' strongman can really make much of an impression next to Jannings and Dietrich. It's a pleasing film to watch, I enjoyed much of the atmosphere and so forth, but it didn't make much of a lasting impression on me I'm afraid.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Succulent, Mellifluous
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Antti Keisala
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Von Sternberg's film is a wonderfully constructed piece of succulent and mellifluous tragicomedy. The fluently moving camera offers a beautiful sense of place, and especially the crooked pebble-stoned streets and leaning houses are the unforgettable epitomes of this film in my memory. Just as with Vigo's "L'Atalante" (1934), much of the film's power depends on us, as the audience, being able to fall in love with the lead actress. It certainly helps that the director did, and for once some knowledge of production enhances the experience: Umrat/Jennings as the jealous and passionate star, Dietrich as the object of desire not only of the boys but of the camera. I also really like the use of stairs, which clearly separate the differing worlds. I could definitely see this influencing "Z&eacute;ro de conduite" (1933) and "Hets" (1944). The slow movement of the camera in the empty classroom after the crucial confrontation reveals one of the most touching visual moments I can think of (this is repeated later in an equally heart-breaking scene). I remember I was very young when I saw this for the first time. It made a lasting impression then, and I count it as one of the three films that ultimately made me fall in love with films to the extent that my thirst will never be quenched.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Blue Angel
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    They released this film filmed in two versions, they acted all the scenes in both German and English, but when I decided to watch this film from the 1001 Movies You Must See Before You Die book, I was going to watch the original German language version. Basically Professor Immanuel Rath (Emil Jannings) is the esteemed college preparatory high school educator who has punished many of his male students for spreading around the image of beautiful stage performer Lola Lola (Destry Rides Again's Marlene Dietrich). He hopes to catch the school boys in the cabaret club The Blue Angel, where she is the headlining act, and after her for himself he grows slowly passionate for her, and with a pair of panties snatched by a student he has a good reason to return there the following night. Having had a night of desire and such, Rath returns to class next day, with the Principal (Eduard Von Winterstein) furious to see the students running riot, and he is aware of the teacher's behaviour recently as well. He decides it is best to retire from the school, and with his newfound freedom he can marry Lola, but they cannot stay happy for long as their money problems grow, and to earn he is forced to become a stage clown in the cabaret troupe. Rath is often filled with jealousy and lust for his wife and her profession, she leaves herself open as a "shared woman", and he is being ridiculed for his past while performing as a clown. He performs his last act at The Blue Angel, and he is shocked to see Lola kissing her new love interest strongman Mazeppa (Hans Albers), and his rage turns into insanity, where he starts strangles his wife and is forced into a straitjacket. In the end, having been released from prison, Rath is not able to resolve his position as a school teacher, and he has obviously lost wife Lola, so he dies from extreme self pity clutching the school desks that once sat his loyal students. Also starring Kurt Gerron as Kiepert the Magician, Rosa Valetti as Guste the Magician's Wife, Reinhold Bernt as The Clown, Hans Roth as Beadle the Caretaker of the Secondary School, Rolf M&uuml;ller as Pupil Angst and Robert Klein-L&ouml;rk as Pupil Goldstaub. Jannings - in his first talking picture - gives a mixed but equally interesting performance as the teacher turned performer with a troubled passion, and Dietrich is wonderful in her iconic top hat and black stockings as the seductive stage performer with a cruel streak, it is a film with some memorable sequences and moments that stand out, especially of course the cabaret stuff, making it a most watchable drama. Very good!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Falling From Grace Over "Show Girl" or There's No Fool Like An Old Fool!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    John T. Ryan (redryan64@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    WE CAN WELL recall viewing this film for the very first time on a PBS Friday evening show. This was circa 1971 and we needed to go to such Public Television stations as our own WTTW, Channel 11 in Chicago in order to see many films which weren't shown on commercial TV Statiobs. WELL, HOW THINGS have changed. Just this passed Monday (2 days ago), Turner Classic Movies ran THE BLUE ANGEL in prime-time. It had been about 40 years (yes, count 'em, folks!) since our initial contact with Herr Josef Von Sternberg's dark, tragic drama. We had seen it once or twice during that period, but had never given it my undivided attention. ALTHOUGH IT IS a German language film, there was at least one of these showings was in a recently rediscovered English language version. We also remember a showing which was in German; but featured Miss Dietrich's performance of "Falling In Lov Again" in English. VIEWING A FILM SUCH as this very talky drama, while at the same time being compelled to read Subtutles, in order to follow the story can really prove to be a pain right where one sits. Yet, it does seem to become easier as the story progresses; as we become engrossed with the scenario unfolding, the dark yet starkly penetrating images, moody and highly atmospheric songs & music and the virtuoso acting performances. THE STORY MAY seem somewhat complex; yet it is probably the very universal themes and connection with the lives and needs of all people that make this such a powerful and compelling of a story with such a long life as an all time favourite. IN SHORT, WE have a story of loneliness, the need to love and be loved, the falling from grace of a highly regarded and most straight laced of a member of academia. From perhaps a most distinguished position and and outstanding of a reputation as a Professor of Literature at the unnamed university, the professor (Mr. Emil Jannings) falls in love with a common, vulgar cabaret singer and exponent of sex, Lola Lola (Miss Marlena Dietrich). THE STORY COVERS a period of over five years, in which the middle aged, clearly un-handsome man discovers that he has fallen to such a degree of degradation as to not only being a minor entertainer; but also participating in selling his own wife. During appearances following Lola's doing her song, professor Roth's duties included peddling some rather pornographic type of postcards to the bawdy male patrons of the show. WE MUST CONFESS that even being a grown man, married with two children, there was an awful lot of obvious seedy goings on that I missed on previous viewings. Certainly, there were no examples of explicit on screen sex (such as have become so commonplace); and yet, with all of the occurrences we surely are forced to ask a few questions. IN ADDITION TO the setting of a night club with rather risqu&eacute; programming, what is it that all of these college boys find so fascinating? Why do the young men hide from the Professor in secret rooms that are below the floors? What is the purpose of these rooms? Why does the proprietor worry about the presence of a police officer; for, isn't this a legal and licensed establishment? Do you think that there is sex for sale here? We do. THE AMAZING FEAT that is accomplished here is making such an interesting story out of such a sordid and low life segment of society. WE GIVE THIS five stars as our rating.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unforgettable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jacabiya
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let me join the ranks that herald this film as one of the great ones, an unforgettable all-time world cinema masterpiece that should be way higher in the IMDb scores, still relevant, powerful, not dated, with not one but two landmark performances. In the first half the film is very funny, but when Lola Lola starts clucking in the wedding reception the horror begins. This is my favorite Marlene Dietrich role, and for my taste the only sexy one, with baby fat and a rounder, younger, nubile face and body(before she turned into the more stern and severe deep-voiced German femme fatale). I find it amazing that her character in this 1930 film still turns me on. Jannings overacts grandiosely to match the extremely melodramatic, denigrating, tragic story, and gives one of the great acting performances of movie history (along with his performance in the silent The Last Laugh). The magician is perfectly sleazy yet human in his ignorance. The film piles it up towards its cringing climax, culminating in action not actually shown, an extremely intelligent move on Sternberg's part. And I dare anyone to come up with more horrible and painful sounds in film history than the professor's.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Downfall of an Arrogant Academic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Le Sage
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Blue Angel features a simple but effective narrative, showing the fall of a man into degradation and squalor. As such, it echoes the themes in early Weimar cinema such as Pandora's Box. The narrative is, indeed, so simple, that this early "talkie" could just as easily have been a silent film. Only rarely is the new sound technology explored to good effect, such as when songs can be heard when the doors from Lola's room to the stage are periodically opened and closed by characters. There is also, of course, the use of song, with Dietrich's voice showcased to good affect. Emil Jannings portrays the stereotype of an academic perfectly: arrogant, insular and with some minor eccentricities, he is unable to cope with life in the "real world" and this leads to his fall from grace. Initially, we in the audience, like his students, see him as a clown, a laughable, pompous yet bumbling figure. His ultimate fate is to be exposed to the whole town as a fool when, stripped of his power, he literally becomes a clown before seeking to return to the insularity of his old post. However, the Professor is not the only loathsome character in this film. The attitude of the students is as despicable as that of their tutor: with their arrogant and bullying behaviour, whilst they are his nemesis, they are also his mirror. They are growing into his image and, with his growing captivation with Lola, he is growing into theirs. Lola is an equally unlikable character and perhaps, once again, reflects concern amongst conservatives in Weimar society about the growing power of women. She is far smarter than the "learned" professor in terms of her ability to understand and manipulate people. Going out on the stage each night is the opposite to his insular world yet it his "act" of appearing respectable in society that this actress is able to quickly pull apart, exposing the shallow man inside. The bird motif used throughout the film is strikingly effective. At the start, the bird who can no longer sing is callously discarded by the housekeeper, just as the worn-out, useless Professor will be discarded, first by the school and then by society. The doomed bird motif is also prefigured by the birds near the clock as the procession of ghoulish statues marches past with each hour. Finally, the Professor himself is humiliated during the clown and magician routine, forced to have doves fly out from under his top hat and to crow like a rooster. Ultimately, this is a brilliant film and, like much late Weimar cinema, reflects themes of moral decline and degradation. This time, however, the character is deeply unlikable from the outset and his humiliation is really an increasing expose to the world of his pre-existing inner nature. He does not grow or transform as a character; rather, as his power is stripped, his true nature is revealed. The learned academic is the biggest fool of all. Stripped of his position and prestige, the academic is nothing more than a clown.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Only angels have wings
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    chaos-rampant
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Films that revolve around performance are essentially about cinema, I'm always on the lookout for these. But unlike the more traditional films about the making of films - Day for Night, Contempt, The Stunt Man, Shadow of the Vampire, etc - those about performance have the extra allure that we have to participate in staging the illusion; it falls on us to imagine the cinematic scenario, and thus complete the notion, actually see in our minds how it completes. It is the best kind of in-sight into creative life - which is every life on the planet, a long series of invention, deception, connection. In The Red Shoes for example, it was a dance between us from the position of the camera and the stage where the story is being danced out. A more intriguing vision we find in the silent Dr. Mabuse, with us looking to apprehend the criminal mastermind who under various guises manipulates the narrative we see. Or the continuation of this in The American Friend, another German film; a 'frame' artist who becomes framed in an illusion that unfolds, this is the film within, as gangster stuff around Europe. This second group is more competent because the film-within, in whatever form, is better integrated inside the outer film. But in all these cases the main subject remains the same; the effort to discern boundaries between a life we control, and so a narrative we are free to improvise as best we can, and a life that is framed, scripted and storyboarded around us from outside. (the truly wise filmmakers understand how these are the same; how, in other terms, the best actors in life are those who are completely clueless about the narrative and therefore effortlessly natural, and those who have studied it and can exercise volition to reshape themselves into what the role requires). Sternberg had made a film about film before this, a more explicit but astounding vision of a filmed reality that prophesied New Wave thirty years before. This is more inconspicuous, less singlemindedly about self-reference, with interesting crowds and rooms around the stage that we can loose ourselves into. It is just endearing to watch on a very basic level, occasionally pretty funny; and in the end thoroughly gut-wrenching. Yet it is still very much about a man losing himself into a performance. What entices him and us is the woman; in fact, we are made to share the male point-of-view so adeptly, the camera always strategically placed where it can be teased and seduced by long legs in stockings, by large eye-lashes making promises, that it is not just the professor, but us as well, more importantly us, that want to let go and be absorbed in the sexual fantasy. It's no wonder she is so captivating, we know after all how Sternberg would grow to worship her, and bind, fully devote his craft to images of her. The second part is where it's truly grueling to watch, where the professor, a pillar of morals and ethos at the start, is completely subsumed inside the fantasy and loses all. Again Emil Jannings puts on a costume. So many fascinating things then happen so quickly, I was left with jaw open. We revisit the cabaret stage from before, only now, quite literally, from inside the mirror looking out; now we are the spectacle, the show being looked on, with being made to perform as the price exacted for having fully invested in the feverish, sultry dream in the first place. Now we are what is being dreamed - this trope is what Lynch has worked and innovated from. And again the distinction between the performance as perceived from outside, with jeers and catcalls, and the human being inside as we know it to suffer. As with all those silent films before about clowns suffering from behind painted smiles, it is a tragic sight of humiliation and despair. When he bellows inordinately, the audience laughs, but we know it's the sound of a soul being torn apart. My only minor gripe, is with how forceful is this part, how emotional. Then again it makes sense; we are again so adeptly placed inside the character, and made to feel as broken as he is. The film ends with the woman performing again her number that captivated the audience so much, only now we understand what's behind the notes. "I'm programmed for love" sings Dietrich, the femme fatale - and so desire, sexual danger personified - who operated the performance from behind the stage. We have mostly come to know film noir from American film. But it was born in Germany, between Dr. Mabuse and this. It's a compelling moral, as in noir later: we are reminded again how dangerous it is to indulge the chimeras of the mind, ego and desire, and how the social fabric has its ways of eventually restoring us in the common, harmless delusions. It's okay to watch, anything more is at our spiritual peril.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The "Carmen" who got away
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    evening1
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Having just caught the Metropolitan's 2010 production of "Carmen" on film during the opera company's outdoor HD Live festival, I expected this film would end with Lola's comeuppance, if not murder. It was a little chilling, and, I have to admit, disappointing, to see her sitting pretty on-stage as her discarded, humiliated husband shuffles away into hopeless oblivion. This film, which I had taped from the City University of New York's excellent TV channel, suffered from horrible visual and sound quality but it managed to keep my attention throughout. It seems a case study in the follies of trying to live without the benefit of self-knowledge. Professor Rath -- was he supposed to be Jewish in this film made as Naziism was on the rise in Germany? -- was a misfit and a clod, a man who found his place in life through his book knowledge. What was missing in him was any sense of who he was as a man. Rath demonstrated his ineptness outside of the ivory tower by blundering into Lola's dressing room, a fateful breaking of social boundaries. Lola treats Rath as one might an old teddy bear. When he proposes marriage, gorgeous Lola cackles hysterically, but it wouldn't occur to Rath to wonder what this might mean. Lola accepts the offer, though one would have to assume the union will never be consummated. (Rather than gaining a love partner, she takes in the father she probably never knew.) Rath's eventual rejection is inevitable. The only surprise here is Lola's getting off scot free. Maybe she thinks about her actions a little; she does seem to darken somewhat during the course of the film. However, she's ultimately left pretty much unscathed by the final credits. Interestingly, Dietrich goes on from this film to become a success in Hollywood, whereas the actor who played Rath remained in Germany to participate in Nazi-propaganda films from which which his career never recovered -- an outcome that pretty much parallels the movie's plot line.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Naughty, naughty..."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moonspinner55
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A stuffy, lonely German college professor, laughed at by his immature pupils, ventures out to a cabaret in the village to berate his students for ogling the female entertainment; instead, he becomes infatuated with the star of the show, chanteuse Lola Lola, and apparently she to him. After marrying the flashy girl, the teacher leaves his profession to travel with the theatrical troupe, but life on the road immediately wears him down. An ugly little story, adapted from Heinrich Mann's novel "Professor Unrath", has a winking-nudging overlay of sexual byplay and was released to great acclaim in both German and English-language versions (this review pertains to the German version with subtitles). Director Josef von Sternberg was already a 15-year veteran of Hollywood movie-making by the time "The Blue Angel" arrived, and yet several sequences (most notably in the first reel and the last) are sloppily constructed and uncertainly paced. Emil Jannings is wonderful as the unloved professor who initially blossoms in the company of streetwise Marlene Dietrich, but his emotional unraveling is awfully quick in coming. Josef von Sternberg is far too sluggish in the beginning, but by the midway point he rushes the narrative...and the audience isn't allowed to get their bearings. As a result, the plot feels like a sadistic series of screw-turns, with no hope (or heart) in sight. **1/2 from ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Humbert Humbert's predecessor
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watching "Der blaue Engel" ("The Blue Angel" in English), I got the feeling that it was sort of a precursor to "Lolita". When you look at how Prof. Immanuel Rath (Emil Jannings) lets his infatuation with nightclub singer Lola Lola (Marlene Dietrich) come to dominate his life, it seems very much like what happens to Humbert Humbert. Of course, the movie is best known for Dietrich's sexy performance as the liberated chanteuse (on which Madeline Kahn's character in "Blazing Saddles" was based). Dietrich must have been every man's dream after the movie came out. Still, the change in Prof. Rath's life caused by his obsession with her certainly stands out as well. All in all, Josef von Sternberg created a real masterpiece.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Perhaps it was startling at its time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    funkyfry
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I can't say much about this film, having just seen it for the first time, but while I was impressed with Von Sternberg's direction, as usual, I felt that this film lacked substance and drive. The story is too predictable; maybe at its time, it had some novelty. I hoped that the road would twist in some unpredictable direction, but it simply loped along to its predictably depressing conclusion. Jannings and Dietrich are wonderfully cast and carry off their roles with perfection. Less convincing is Kurt Gerron's magician -- he seems like he would belong more as a bar-tender than as an impresario. The touches of humor are odd.... I found myself uncertain at times whether it was a comedy or a drama. Certainly, the film makes Jannings' imperious school professor a subject of so much ridicule that his fall from grace comes more as a relief than a tragedy. One would hope to find minor characters with some flash to add some interest to a simple story, but only Hans Albers' strongman can really make much of an impression next to Jannings and Dietrich. It's a pleasing film to watch, I enjoyed much of the atmosphere and so forth, but it didn't make much of a lasting impression on me I'm afraid.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Succulent, Mellifluous
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Antti Keisala
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Von Sternberg's film is a wonderfully constructed piece of succulent and mellifluous tragicomedy. The fluently moving camera offers a beautiful sense of place, and especially the crooked pebble-stoned streets and leaning houses are the unforgettable epitomes of this film in my memory. Just as with Vigo's "L'Atalante" (1934), much of the film's power depends on us, as the audience, being able to fall in love with the lead actress. It certainly helps that the director did, and for once some knowledge of production enhances the experience: Umrat/Jennings as the jealous and passionate star, Dietrich as the object of desire not only of the boys but of the camera. I also really like the use of stairs, which clearly separate the differing worlds. I could definitely see this influencing "Z&eacute;ro de conduite" (1933) and "Hets" (1944). The slow movement of the camera in the empty classroom after the crucial confrontation reveals one of the most touching visual moments I can think of (this is repeated later in an equally heart-breaking scene). I remember I was very young when I saw this for the first time. It made a lasting impression then, and I count it as one of the three films that ultimately made me fall in love with films to the extent that my thirst will never be quenched.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Blue Angel
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    They released this film filmed in two versions, they acted all the scenes in both German and English, but when I decided to watch this film from the 1001 Movies You Must See Before You Die book, I was going to watch the original German language version. Basically Professor Immanuel Rath (Emil Jannings) is the esteemed college preparatory high school educator who has punished many of his male students for spreading around the image of beautiful stage performer Lola Lola (Destry Rides Again's Marlene Dietrich). He hopes to catch the school boys in the cabaret club The Blue Angel, where she is the headlining act, and after her for himself he grows slowly passionate for her, and with a pair of panties snatched by a student he has a good reason to return there the following night. Having had a night of desire and such, Rath returns to class next day, with the Principal (Eduard Von Winterstein) furious to see the students running riot, and he is aware of the teacher's behaviour recently as well. He decides it is best to retire from the school, and with his newfound freedom he can marry Lola, but they cannot stay happy for long as their money problems grow, and to earn he is forced to become a stage clown in the cabaret troupe. Rath is often filled with jealousy and lust for his wife and her profession, she leaves herself open as a "shared woman", and he is being ridiculed for his past while performing as a clown. He performs his last act at The Blue Angel, and he is shocked to see Lola kissing her new love interest strongman Mazeppa (Hans Albers), and his rage turns into insanity, where he starts strangles his wife and is forced into a straitjacket. In the end, having been released from prison, Rath is not able to resolve his position as a school teacher, and he has obviously lost wife Lola, so he dies from extreme self pity clutching the school desks that once sat his loyal students. Also starring Kurt Gerron as Kiepert the Magician, Rosa Valetti as Guste the Magician's Wife, Reinhold Bernt as The Clown, Hans Roth as Beadle the Caretaker of the Secondary School, Rolf M&uuml;ller as Pupil Angst and Robert Klein-L&ouml;rk as Pupil Goldstaub. Jannings - in his first talking picture - gives a mixed but equally interesting performance as the teacher turned performer with a troubled passion, and Dietrich is wonderful in her iconic top hat and black stockings as the seductive stage performer with a cruel streak, it is a film with some memorable sequences and moments that stand out, especially of course the cabaret stuff, making it a most watchable drama. Very good!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Falling From Grace Over "Show Girl" or There's No Fool Like An Old Fool!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    John T. Ryan (redryan64@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    WE CAN WELL recall viewing this film for the very first time on a PBS Friday evening show. This was circa 1971 and we needed to go to such Public Television stations as our own WTTW, Channel 11 in Chicago in order to see many films which weren't shown on commercial TV Statiobs. WELL, HOW THINGS have changed. Just this passed Monday (2 days ago), Turner Classic Movies ran THE BLUE ANGEL in prime-time. It had been about 40 years (yes, count 'em, folks!) since our initial contact with Herr Josef Von Sternberg's dark, tragic drama. We had seen it once or twice during that period, but had never given it my undivided attention. ALTHOUGH IT IS a German language film, there was at least one of these showings was in a recently rediscovered English language version. We also remember a showing which was in German; but featured Miss Dietrich's performance of "Falling In Lov Again" in English. VIEWING A FILM SUCH as this very talky drama, while at the same time being compelled to read Subtutles, in order to follow the story can really prove to be a pain right where one sits. Yet, it does seem to become easier as the story progresses; as we become engrossed with the scenario unfolding, the dark yet starkly penetrating images, moody and highly atmospheric songs & music and the virtuoso acting performances. THE STORY MAY seem somewhat complex; yet it is probably the very universal themes and connection with the lives and needs of all people that make this such a powerful and compelling of a story with such a long life as an all time favourite. IN SHORT, WE have a story of loneliness, the need to love and be loved, the falling from grace of a highly regarded and most straight laced of a member of academia. From perhaps a most distinguished position and and outstanding of a reputation as a Professor of Literature at the unnamed university, the professor (Mr. Emil Jannings) falls in love with a common, vulgar cabaret singer and exponent of sex, Lola Lola (Miss Marlena Dietrich). THE STORY COVERS a period of over five years, in which the middle aged, clearly un-handsome man discovers that he has fallen to such a degree of degradation as to not only being a minor entertainer; but also participating in selling his own wife. During appearances following Lola's doing her song, professor Roth's duties included peddling some rather pornographic type of postcards to the bawdy male patrons of the show. WE MUST CONFESS that even being a grown man, married with two children, there was an awful lot of obvious seedy goings on that I missed on previous viewings. Certainly, there were no examples of explicit on screen sex (such as have become so commonplace); and yet, with all of the occurrences we surely are forced to ask a few questions. IN ADDITION TO the setting of a night club with rather risqu&eacute; programming, what is it that all of these college boys find so fascinating? Why do the young men hide from the Professor in secret rooms that are below the floors? What is the purpose of these rooms? Why does the proprietor worry about the presence of a police officer; for, isn't this a legal and licensed establishment? Do you think that there is sex for sale here? We do. THE AMAZING FEAT that is accomplished here is making such an interesting story out of such a sordid and low life segment of society. WE GIVE THIS five stars as our rating.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unforgettable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jacabiya
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let me join the ranks that herald this film as one of the great ones, an unforgettable all-time world cinema masterpiece that should be way higher in the IMDb scores, still relevant, powerful, not dated, with not one but two landmark performances. In the first half the film is very funny, but when Lola Lola starts clucking in the wedding reception the horror begins. This is my favorite Marlene Dietrich role, and for my taste the only sexy one, with baby fat and a rounder, younger, nubile face and body(before she turned into the more stern and severe deep-voiced German femme fatale). I find it amazing that her character in this 1930 film still turns me on. Jannings overacts grandiosely to match the extremely melodramatic, denigrating, tragic story, and gives one of the great acting performances of movie history (along with his performance in the silent The Last Laugh). The magician is perfectly sleazy yet human in his ignorance. The film piles it up towards its cringing climax, culminating in action not actually shown, an extremely intelligent move on Sternberg's part. And I dare anyone to come up with more horrible and painful sounds in film history than the professor's.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Downfall of an Arrogant Academic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Le Sage
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Blue Angel features a simple but effective narrative, showing the fall of a man into degradation and squalor. As such, it echoes the themes in early Weimar cinema such as Pandora's Box. The narrative is, indeed, so simple, that this early "talkie" could just as easily have been a silent film. Only rarely is the new sound technology explored to good effect, such as when songs can be heard when the doors from Lola's room to the stage are periodically opened and closed by characters. There is also, of course, the use of song, with Dietrich's voice showcased to good affect. Emil Jannings portrays the stereotype of an academic perfectly: arrogant, insular and with some minor eccentricities, he is unable to cope with life in the "real world" and this leads to his fall from grace. Initially, we in the audience, like his students, see him as a clown, a laughable, pompous yet bumbling figure. His ultimate fate is to be exposed to the whole town as a fool when, stripped of his power, he literally becomes a clown before seeking to return to the insularity of his old post. However, the Professor is not the only loathsome character in this film. The attitude of the students is as despicable as that of their tutor: with their arrogant and bullying behaviour, whilst they are his nemesis, they are also his mirror. They are growing into his image and, with his growing captivation with Lola, he is growing into theirs. Lola is an equally unlikable character and perhaps, once again, reflects concern amongst conservatives in Weimar society about the growing power of women. She is far smarter than the "learned" professor in terms of her ability to understand and manipulate people. Going out on the stage each night is the opposite to his insular world yet it his "act" of appearing respectable in society that this actress is able to quickly pull apart, exposing the shallow man inside. The bird motif used throughout the film is strikingly effective. At the start, the bird who can no longer sing is callously discarded by the housekeeper, just as the worn-out, useless Professor will be discarded, first by the school and then by society. The doomed bird motif is also prefigured by the birds near the clock as the procession of ghoulish statues marches past with each hour. Finally, the Professor himself is humiliated during the clown and magician routine, forced to have doves fly out from under his top hat and to crow like a rooster. Ultimately, this is a brilliant film and, like much late Weimar cinema, reflects themes of moral decline and degradation. This time, however, the character is deeply unlikable from the outset and his humiliation is really an increasing expose to the world of his pre-existing inner nature. He does not grow or transform as a character; rather, as his power is stripped, his true nature is revealed. The learned academic is the biggest fool of all. Stripped of his position and prestige, the academic is nothing more than a clown.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Only angels have wings
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    chaos-rampant
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Films that revolve around performance are essentially about cinema, I'm always on the lookout for these. But unlike the more traditional films about the making of films - Day for Night, Contempt, The Stunt Man, Shadow of the Vampire, etc - those about performance have the extra allure that we have to participate in staging the illusion; it falls on us to imagine the cinematic scenario, and thus complete the notion, actually see in our minds how it completes. It is the best kind of in-sight into creative life - which is every life on the planet, a long series of invention, deception, connection. In The Red Shoes for example, it was a dance between us from the position of the camera and the stage where the story is being danced out. A more intriguing vision we find in the silent Dr. Mabuse, with us looking to apprehend the criminal mastermind who under various guises manipulates the narrative we see. Or the continuation of this in The American Friend, another German film; a 'frame' artist who becomes framed in an illusion that unfolds, this is the film within, as gangster stuff around Europe. This second group is more competent because the film-within, in whatever form, is better integrated inside the outer film. But in all these cases the main subject remains the same; the effort to discern boundaries between a life we control, and so a narrative we are free to improvise as best we can, and a life that is framed, scripted and storyboarded around us from outside. (the truly wise filmmakers understand how these are the same; how, in other terms, the best actors in life are those who are completely clueless about the narrative and therefore effortlessly natural, and those who have studied it and can exercise volition to reshape themselves into what the role requires). Sternberg had made a film about film before this, a more explicit but astounding vision of a filmed reality that prophesied New Wave thirty years before. This is more inconspicuous, less singlemindedly about self-reference, with interesting crowds and rooms around the stage that we can loose ourselves into. It is just endearing to watch on a very basic level, occasionally pretty funny; and in the end thoroughly gut-wrenching. Yet it is still very much about a man losing himself into a performance. What entices him and us is the woman; in fact, we are made to share the male point-of-view so adeptly, the camera always strategically placed where it can be teased and seduced by long legs in stockings, by large eye-lashes making promises, that it is not just the professor, but us as well, more importantly us, that want to let go and be absorbed in the sexual fantasy. It's no wonder she is so captivating, we know after all how Sternberg would grow to worship her, and bind, fully devote his craft to images of her. The second part is where it's truly grueling to watch, where the professor, a pillar of morals and ethos at the start, is completely subsumed inside the fantasy and loses all. Again Emil Jannings puts on a costume. So many fascinating things then happen so quickly, I was left with jaw open. We revisit the cabaret stage from before, only now, quite literally, from inside the mirror looking out; now we are the spectacle, the show being looked on, with being made to perform as the price exacted for having fully invested in the feverish, sultry dream in the first place. Now we are what is being dreamed - this trope is what Lynch has worked and innovated from. And again the distinction between the performance as perceived from outside, with jeers and catcalls, and the human being inside as we know it to suffer. As with all those silent films before about clowns suffering from behind painted smiles, it is a tragic sight of humiliation and despair. When he bellows inordinately, the audience laughs, but we know it's the sound of a soul being torn apart. My only minor gripe, is with how forceful is this part, how emotional. Then again it makes sense; we are again so adeptly placed inside the character, and made to feel as broken as he is. The film ends with the woman performing again her number that captivated the audience so much, only now we understand what's behind the notes. "I'm programmed for love" sings Dietrich, the femme fatale - and so desire, sexual danger personified - who operated the performance from behind the stage. We have mostly come to know film noir from American film. But it was born in Germany, between Dr. Mabuse and this. It's a compelling moral, as in noir later: we are reminded again how dangerous it is to indulge the chimeras of the mind, ego and desire, and how the social fabric has its ways of eventually restoring us in the common, harmless delusions. It's okay to watch, anything more is at our spiritual peril.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The "Carmen" who got away
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    evening1
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Having just caught the Metropolitan's 2010 production of "Carmen" on film during the opera company's outdoor HD Live festival, I expected this film would end with Lola's comeuppance, if not murder. It was a little chilling, and, I have to admit, disappointing, to see her sitting pretty on-stage as her discarded, humiliated husband shuffles away into hopeless oblivion. This film, which I had taped from the City University of New York's excellent TV channel, suffered from horrible visual and sound quality but it managed to keep my attention throughout. It seems a case study in the follies of trying to live without the benefit of self-knowledge. Professor Rath -- was he supposed to be Jewish in this film made as Naziism was on the rise in Germany? -- was a misfit and a clod, a man who found his place in life through his book knowledge. What was missing in him was any sense of who he was as a man. Rath demonstrated his ineptness outside of the ivory tower by blundering into Lola's dressing room, a fateful breaking of social boundaries. Lola treats Rath as one might an old teddy bear. When he proposes marriage, gorgeous Lola cackles hysterically, but it wouldn't occur to Rath to wonder what this might mean. Lola accepts the offer, though one would have to assume the union will never be consummated. (Rather than gaining a love partner, she takes in the father she probably never knew.) Rath's eventual rejection is inevitable. The only surprise here is Lola's getting off scot free. Maybe she thinks about her actions a little; she does seem to darken somewhat during the course of the film. However, she's ultimately left pretty much unscathed by the final credits. Interestingly, Dietrich goes on from this film to become a success in Hollywood, whereas the actor who played Rath remained in Germany to participate in Nazi-propaganda films from which which his career never recovered -- an outcome that pretty much parallels the movie's plot line.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Naughty, naughty..."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moonspinner55
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A stuffy, lonely German college professor, laughed at by his immature pupils, ventures out to a cabaret in the village to berate his students for ogling the female entertainment; instead, he becomes infatuated with the star of the show, chanteuse Lola Lola, and apparently she to him. After marrying the flashy girl, the teacher leaves his profession to travel with the theatrical troupe, but life on the road immediately wears him down. An ugly little story, adapted from Heinrich Mann's novel "Professor Unrath", has a winking-nudging overlay of sexual byplay and was released to great acclaim in both German and English-language versions (this review pertains to the German version with subtitles). Director Josef von Sternberg was already a 15-year veteran of Hollywood movie-making by the time "The Blue Angel" arrived, and yet several sequences (most notably in the first reel and the last) are sloppily constructed and uncertainly paced. Emil Jannings is wonderful as the unloved professor who initially blossoms in the company of streetwise Marlene Dietrich, but his emotional unraveling is awfully quick in coming. Josef von Sternberg is far too sluggish in the beginning, but by the midway point he rushes the narrative...and the audience isn't allowed to get their bearings. As a result, the plot feels like a sadistic series of screw-turns, with no hope (or heart) in sight. **1/2 from ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Humbert Humbert's predecessor
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watching "Der blaue Engel" ("The Blue Angel" in English), I got the feeling that it was sort of a precursor to "Lolita". When you look at how Prof. Immanuel Rath (Emil Jannings) lets his infatuation with nightclub singer Lola Lola (Marlene Dietrich) come to dominate his life, it seems very much like what happens to Humbert Humbert. Of course, the movie is best known for Dietrich's sexy performance as the liberated chanteuse (on which Madeline Kahn's character in "Blazing Saddles" was based). Dietrich must have been every man's dream after the movie came out. Still, the change in Prof. Rath's life caused by his obsession with her certainly stands out as well. All in all, Josef von Sternberg created a real masterpiece.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Perhaps it was startling at its time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    funkyfry
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I can't say much about this film, having just seen it for the first time, but while I was impressed with Von Sternberg's direction, as usual, I felt that this film lacked substance and drive. The story is too predictable; maybe at its time, it had some novelty. I hoped that the road would twist in some unpredictable direction, but it simply loped along to its predictably depressing conclusion. Jannings and Dietrich are wonderfully cast and carry off their roles with perfection. Less convincing is Kurt Gerron's magician -- he seems like he would belong more as a bar-tender than as an impresario. The touches of humor are odd.... I found myself uncertain at times whether it was a comedy or a drama. Certainly, the film makes Jannings' imperious school professor a subject of so much ridicule that his fall from grace comes more as a relief than a tragedy. One would hope to find minor characters with some flash to add some interest to a simple story, but only Hans Albers' strongman can really make much of an impression next to Jannings and Dietrich. It's a pleasing film to watch, I enjoyed much of the atmosphere and so forth, but it didn't make much of a lasting impression on me I'm afraid.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Succulent, Mellifluous
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Antti Keisala
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Von Sternberg's film is a wonderfully constructed piece of succulent and mellifluous tragicomedy. The fluently moving camera offers a beautiful sense of place, and especially the crooked pebble-stoned streets and leaning houses are the unforgettable epitomes of this film in my memory. Just as with Vigo's "L'Atalante" (1934), much of the film's power depends on us, as the audience, being able to fall in love with the lead actress. It certainly helps that the director did, and for once some knowledge of production enhances the experience: Umrat/Jennings as the jealous and passionate star, Dietrich as the object of desire not only of the boys but of the camera. I also really like the use of stairs, which clearly separate the differing worlds. I could definitely see this influencing "Z&eacute;ro de conduite" (1933) and "Hets" (1944). The slow movement of the camera in the empty classroom after the crucial confrontation reveals one of the most touching visual moments I can think of (this is repeated later in an equally heart-breaking scene). I remember I was very young when I saw this for the first time. It made a lasting impression then, and I count it as one of the three films that ultimately made me fall in love with films to the extent that my thirst will never be quenched.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Blue Angel
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    They released this film filmed in two versions, they acted all the scenes in both German and English, but when I decided to watch this film from the 1001 Movies You Must See Before You Die book, I was going to watch the original German language version. Basically Professor Immanuel Rath (Emil Jannings) is the esteemed college preparatory high school educator who has punished many of his male students for spreading around the image of beautiful stage performer Lola Lola (Destry Rides Again's Marlene Dietrich). He hopes to catch the school boys in the cabaret club The Blue Angel, where she is the headlining act, and after her for himself he grows slowly passionate for her, and with a pair of panties snatched by a student he has a good reason to return there the following night. Having had a night of desire and such, Rath returns to class next day, with the Principal (Eduard Von Winterstein) furious to see the students running riot, and he is aware of the teacher's behaviour recently as well. He decides it is best to retire from the school, and with his newfound freedom he can marry Lola, but they cannot stay happy for long as their money problems grow, and to earn he is forced to become a stage clown in the cabaret troupe. Rath is often filled with jealousy and lust for his wife and her profession, she leaves herself open as a "shared woman", and he is being ridiculed for his past while performing as a clown. He performs his last act at The Blue Angel, and he is shocked to see Lola kissing her new love interest strongman Mazeppa (Hans Albers), and his rage turns into insanity, where he starts strangles his wife and is forced into a straitjacket. In the end, having been released from prison, Rath is not able to resolve his position as a school teacher, and he has obviously lost wife Lola, so he dies from extreme self pity clutching the school desks that once sat his loyal students. Also starring Kurt Gerron as Kiepert the Magician, Rosa Valetti as Guste the Magician's Wife, Reinhold Bernt as The Clown, Hans Roth as Beadle the Caretaker of the Secondary School, Rolf M&uuml;ller as Pupil Angst and Robert Klein-L&ouml;rk as Pupil Goldstaub. Jannings - in his first talking picture - gives a mixed but equally interesting performance as the teacher turned performer with a troubled passion, and Dietrich is wonderful in her iconic top hat and black stockings as the seductive stage performer with a cruel streak, it is a film with some memorable sequences and moments that stand out, especially of course the cabaret stuff, making it a most watchable drama. Very good!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Falling From Grace Over "Show Girl" or There's No Fool Like An Old Fool!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    John T. Ryan (redryan64@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    WE CAN WELL recall viewing this film for the very first time on a PBS Friday evening show. This was circa 1971 and we needed to go to such Public Television stations as our own WTTW, Channel 11 in Chicago in order to see many films which weren't shown on commercial TV Statiobs. WELL, HOW THINGS have changed. Just this passed Monday (2 days ago), Turner Classic Movies ran THE BLUE ANGEL in prime-time. It had been about 40 years (yes, count 'em, folks!) since our initial contact with Herr Josef Von Sternberg's dark, tragic drama. We had seen it once or twice during that period, but had never given it my undivided attention. ALTHOUGH IT IS a German language film, there was at least one of these showings was in a recently rediscovered English language version. We also remember a showing which was in German; but featured Miss Dietrich's performance of "Falling In Lov Again" in English. VIEWING A FILM SUCH as this very talky drama, while at the same time being compelled to read Subtutles, in order to follow the story can really prove to be a pain right where one sits. Yet, it does seem to become easier as the story progresses; as we become engrossed with the scenario unfolding, the dark yet starkly penetrating images, moody and highly atmospheric songs & music and the virtuoso acting performances. THE STORY MAY seem somewhat complex; yet it is probably the very universal themes and connection with the lives and needs of all people that make this such a powerful and compelling of a story with such a long life as an all time favourite. IN SHORT, WE have a story of loneliness, the need to love and be loved, the falling from grace of a highly regarded and most straight laced of a member of academia. From perhaps a most distinguished position and and outstanding of a reputation as a Professor of Literature at the unnamed university, the professor (Mr. Emil Jannings) falls in love with a common, vulgar cabaret singer and exponent of sex, Lola Lola (Miss Marlena Dietrich). THE STORY COVERS a period of over five years, in which the middle aged, clearly un-handsome man discovers that he has fallen to such a degree of degradation as to not only being a minor entertainer; but also participating in selling his own wife. During appearances following Lola's doing her song, professor Roth's duties included peddling some rather pornographic type of postcards to the bawdy male patrons of the show. WE MUST CONFESS that even being a grown man, married with two children, there was an awful lot of obvious seedy goings on that I missed on previous viewings. Certainly, there were no examples of explicit on screen sex (such as have become so commonplace); and yet, with all of the occurrences we surely are forced to ask a few questions. IN ADDITION TO the setting of a night club with rather risqu&eacute; programming, what is it that all of these college boys find so fascinating? Why do the young men hide from the Professor in secret rooms that are below the floors? What is the purpose of these rooms? Why does the proprietor worry about the presence of a police officer; for, isn't this a legal and licensed establishment? Do you think that there is sex for sale here? We do. THE AMAZING FEAT that is accomplished here is making such an interesting story out of such a sordid and low life segment of society. WE GIVE THIS five stars as our rating.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unforgettable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jacabiya
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let me join the ranks that herald this film as one of the great ones, an unforgettable all-time world cinema masterpiece that should be way higher in the IMDb scores, still relevant, powerful, not dated, with not one but two landmark performances. In the first half the film is very funny, but when Lola Lola starts clucking in the wedding reception the horror begins. This is my favorite Marlene Dietrich role, and for my taste the only sexy one, with baby fat and a rounder, younger, nubile face and body(before she turned into the more stern and severe deep-voiced German femme fatale). I find it amazing that her character in this 1930 film still turns me on. Jannings overacts grandiosely to match the extremely melodramatic, denigrating, tragic story, and gives one of the great acting performances of movie history (along with his performance in the silent The Last Laugh). The magician is perfectly sleazy yet human in his ignorance. The film piles it up towards its cringing climax, culminating in action not actually shown, an extremely intelligent move on Sternberg's part. And I dare anyone to come up with more horrible and painful sounds in film history than the professor's.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Downfall of an Arrogant Academic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Le Sage
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Blue Angel features a simple but effective narrative, showing the fall of a man into degradation and squalor. As such, it echoes the themes in early Weimar cinema such as Pandora's Box. The narrative is, indeed, so simple, that this early "talkie" could just as easily have been a silent film. Only rarely is the new sound technology explored to good effect, such as when songs can be heard when the doors from Lola's room to the stage are periodically opened and closed by characters. There is also, of course, the use of song, with Dietrich's voice showcased to good affect. Emil Jannings portrays the stereotype of an academic perfectly: arrogant, insular and with some minor eccentricities, he is unable to cope with life in the "real world" and this leads to his fall from grace. Initially, we in the audience, like his students, see him as a clown, a laughable, pompous yet bumbling figure. His ultimate fate is to be exposed to the whole town as a fool when, stripped of his power, he literally becomes a clown before seeking to return to the insularity of his old post. However, the Professor is not the only loathsome character in this film. The attitude of the students is as despicable as that of their tutor: with their arrogant and bullying behaviour, whilst they are his nemesis, they are also his mirror. They are growing into his image and, with his growing captivation with Lola, he is growing into theirs. Lola is an equally unlikable character and perhaps, once again, reflects concern amongst conservatives in Weimar society about the growing power of women. She is far smarter than the "learned" professor in terms of her ability to understand and manipulate people. Going out on the stage each night is the opposite to his insular world yet it his "act" of appearing respectable in society that this actress is able to quickly pull apart, exposing the shallow man inside. The bird motif used throughout the film is strikingly effective. At the start, the bird who can no longer sing is callously discarded by the housekeeper, just as the worn-out, useless Professor will be discarded, first by the school and then by society. The doomed bird motif is also prefigured by the birds near the clock as the procession of ghoulish statues marches past with each hour. Finally, the Professor himself is humiliated during the clown and magician routine, forced to have doves fly out from under his top hat and to crow like a rooster. Ultimately, this is a brilliant film and, like much late Weimar cinema, reflects themes of moral decline and degradation. This time, however, the character is deeply unlikable from the outset and his humiliation is really an increasing expose to the world of his pre-existing inner nature. He does not grow or transform as a character; rather, as his power is stripped, his true nature is revealed. The learned academic is the biggest fool of all. Stripped of his position and prestige, the academic is nothing more than a clown.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Only angels have wings
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    chaos-rampant
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Films that revolve around performance are essentially about cinema, I'm always on the lookout for these. But unlike the more traditional films about the making of films - Day for Night, Contempt, The Stunt Man, Shadow of the Vampire, etc - those about performance have the extra allure that we have to participate in staging the illusion; it falls on us to imagine the cinematic scenario, and thus complete the notion, actually see in our minds how it completes. It is the best kind of in-sight into creative life - which is every life on the planet, a long series of invention, deception, connection. In The Red Shoes for example, it was a dance between us from the position of the camera and the stage where the story is being danced out. A more intriguing vision we find in the silent Dr. Mabuse, with us looking to apprehend the criminal mastermind who under various guises manipulates the narrative we see. Or the continuation of this in The American Friend, another German film; a 'frame' artist who becomes framed in an illusion that unfolds, this is the film within, as gangster stuff around Europe. This second group is more competent because the film-within, in whatever form, is better integrated inside the outer film. But in all these cases the main subject remains the same; the effort to discern boundaries between a life we control, and so a narrative we are free to improvise as best we can, and a life that is framed, scripted and storyboarded around us from outside. (the truly wise filmmakers understand how these are the same; how, in other terms, the best actors in life are those who are completely clueless about the narrative and therefore effortlessly natural, and those who have studied it and can exercise volition to reshape themselves into what the role requires). Sternberg had made a film about film before this, a more explicit but astounding vision of a filmed reality that prophesied New Wave thirty years before. This is more inconspicuous, less singlemindedly about self-reference, with interesting crowds and rooms around the stage that we can loose ourselves into. It is just endearing to watch on a very basic level, occasionally pretty funny; and in the end thoroughly gut-wrenching. Yet it is still very much about a man losing himself into a performance. What entices him and us is the woman; in fact, we are made to share the male point-of-view so adeptly, the camera always strategically placed where it can be teased and seduced by long legs in stockings, by large eye-lashes making promises, that it is not just the professor, but us as well, more importantly us, that want to let go and be absorbed in the sexual fantasy. It's no wonder she is so captivating, we know after all how Sternberg would grow to worship her, and bind, fully devote his craft to images of her. The second part is where it's truly grueling to watch, where the professor, a pillar of morals and ethos at the start, is completely subsumed inside the fantasy and loses all. Again Emil Jannings puts on a costume. So many fascinating things then happen so quickly, I was left with jaw open. We revisit the cabaret stage from before, only now, quite literally, from inside the mirror looking out; now we are the spectacle, the show being looked on, with being made to perform as the price exacted for having fully invested in the feverish, sultry dream in the first place. Now we are what is being dreamed - this trope is what Lynch has worked and innovated from. And again the distinction between the performance as perceived from outside, with jeers and catcalls, and the human being inside as we know it to suffer. As with all those silent films before about clowns suffering from behind painted smiles, it is a tragic sight of humiliation and despair. When he bellows inordinately, the audience laughs, but we know it's the sound of a soul being torn apart. My only minor gripe, is with how forceful is this part, how emotional. Then again it makes sense; we are again so adeptly placed inside the character, and made to feel as broken as he is. The film ends with the woman performing again her number that captivated the audience so much, only now we understand what's behind the notes. "I'm programmed for love" sings Dietrich, the femme fatale - and so desire, sexual danger personified - who operated the performance from behind the stage. We have mostly come to know film noir from American film. But it was born in Germany, between Dr. Mabuse and this. It's a compelling moral, as in noir later: we are reminded again how dangerous it is to indulge the chimeras of the mind, ego and desire, and how the social fabric has its ways of eventually restoring us in the common, harmless delusions. It's okay to watch, anything more is at our spiritual peril.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The "Carmen" who got away
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    evening1
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Having just caught the Metropolitan's 2010 production of "Carmen" on film during the opera company's outdoor HD Live festival, I expected this film would end with Lola's comeuppance, if not murder. It was a little chilling, and, I have to admit, disappointing, to see her sitting pretty on-stage as her discarded, humiliated husband shuffles away into hopeless oblivion. This film, which I had taped from the City University of New York's excellent TV channel, suffered from horrible visual and sound quality but it managed to keep my attention throughout. It seems a case study in the follies of trying to live without the benefit of self-knowledge. Professor Rath -- was he supposed to be Jewish in this film made as Naziism was on the rise in Germany? -- was a misfit and a clod, a man who found his place in life through his book knowledge. What was missing in him was any sense of who he was as a man. Rath demonstrated his ineptness outside of the ivory tower by blundering into Lola's dressing room, a fateful breaking of social boundaries. Lola treats Rath as one might an old teddy bear. When he proposes marriage, gorgeous Lola cackles hysterically, but it wouldn't occur to Rath to wonder what this might mean. Lola accepts the offer, though one would have to assume the union will never be consummated. (Rather than gaining a love partner, she takes in the father she probably never knew.) Rath's eventual rejection is inevitable. The only surprise here is Lola's getting off scot free. Maybe she thinks about her actions a little; she does seem to darken somewhat during the course of the film. However, she's ultimately left pretty much unscathed by the final credits. Interestingly, Dietrich goes on from this film to become a success in Hollywood, whereas the actor who played Rath remained in Germany to participate in Nazi-propaganda films from which which his career never recovered -- an outcome that pretty much parallels the movie's plot line.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Naughty, naughty..."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moonspinner55
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A stuffy, lonely German college professor, laughed at by his immature pupils, ventures out to a cabaret in the village to berate his students for ogling the female entertainment; instead, he becomes infatuated with the star of the show, chanteuse Lola Lola, and apparently she to him. After marrying the flashy girl, the teacher leaves his profession to travel with the theatrical troupe, but life on the road immediately wears him down. An ugly little story, adapted from Heinrich Mann's novel "Professor Unrath", has a winking-nudging overlay of sexual byplay and was released to great acclaim in both German and English-language versions (this review pertains to the German version with subtitles). Director Josef von Sternberg was already a 15-year veteran of Hollywood movie-making by the time "The Blue Angel" arrived, and yet several sequences (most notably in the first reel and the last) are sloppily constructed and uncertainly paced. Emil Jannings is wonderful as the unloved professor who initially blossoms in the company of streetwise Marlene Dietrich, but his emotional unraveling is awfully quick in coming. Josef von Sternberg is far too sluggish in the beginning, but by the midway point he rushes the narrative...and the audience isn't allowed to get their bearings. As a result, the plot feels like a sadistic series of screw-turns, with no hope (or heart) in sight. **1/2 from ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Humbert Humbert's predecessor
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watching "Der blaue Engel" ("The Blue Angel" in English), I got the feeling that it was sort of a precursor to "Lolita". When you look at how Prof. Immanuel Rath (Emil Jannings) lets his infatuation with nightclub singer Lola Lola (Marlene Dietrich) come to dominate his life, it seems very much like what happens to Humbert Humbert. Of course, the movie is best known for Dietrich's sexy performance as the liberated chanteuse (on which Madeline Kahn's character in "Blazing Saddles" was based). Dietrich must have been every man's dream after the movie came out. Still, the change in Prof. Rath's life caused by his obsession with her certainly stands out as well. All in all, Josef von Sternberg created a real masterpiece.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Perhaps it was startling at its time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    funkyfry
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I can't say much about this film, having just seen it for the first time, but while I was impressed with Von Sternberg's direction, as usual, I felt that this film lacked substance and drive. The story is too predictable; maybe at its time, it had some novelty. I hoped that the road would twist in some unpredictable direction, but it simply loped along to its predictably depressing conclusion. Jannings and Dietrich are wonderfully cast and carry off their roles with perfection. Less convincing is Kurt Gerron's magician -- he seems like he would belong more as a bar-tender than as an impresario. The touches of humor are odd.... I found myself uncertain at times whether it was a comedy or a drama. Certainly, the film makes Jannings' imperious school professor a subject of so much ridicule that his fall from grace comes more as a relief than a tragedy. One would hope to find minor characters with some flash to add some interest to a simple story, but only Hans Albers' strongman can really make much of an impression next to Jannings and Dietrich. It's a pleasing film to watch, I enjoyed much of the atmosphere and so forth, but it didn't make much of a lasting impression on me I'm afraid.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Succulent, Mellifluous
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Antti Keisala
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Von Sternberg's film is a wonderfully constructed piece of succulent and mellifluous tragicomedy. The fluently moving camera offers a beautiful sense of place, and especially the crooked pebble-stoned streets and leaning houses are the unforgettable epitomes of this film in my memory. Just as with Vigo's "L'Atalante" (1934), much of the film's power depends on us, as the audience, being able to fall in love with the lead actress. It certainly helps that the director did, and for once some knowledge of production enhances the experience: Umrat/Jennings as the jealous and passionate star, Dietrich as the object of desire not only of the boys but of the camera. I also really like the use of stairs, which clearly separate the differing worlds. I could definitely see this influencing "Z&eacute;ro de conduite" (1933) and "Hets" (1944). The slow movement of the camera in the empty classroom after the crucial confrontation reveals one of the most touching visual moments I can think of (this is repeated later in an equally heart-breaking scene). I remember I was very young when I saw this for the first time. It made a lasting impression then, and I count it as one of the three films that ultimately made me fall in love with films to the extent that my thirst will never be quenched.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Blue Angel
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    They released this film filmed in two versions, they acted all the scenes in both German and English, but when I decided to watch this film from the 1001 Movies You Must See Before You Die book, I was going to watch the original German language version. Basically Professor Immanuel Rath (Emil Jannings) is the esteemed college preparatory high school educator who has punished many of his male students for spreading around the image of beautiful stage performer Lola Lola (Destry Rides Again's Marlene Dietrich). He hopes to catch the school boys in the cabaret club The Blue Angel, where she is the headlining act, and after her for himself he grows slowly passionate for her, and with a pair of panties snatched by a student he has a good reason to return there the following night. Having had a night of desire and such, Rath returns to class next day, with the Principal (Eduard Von Winterstein) furious to see the students running riot, and he is aware of the teacher's behaviour recently as well. He decides it is best to retire from the school, and with his newfound freedom he can marry Lola, but they cannot stay happy for long as their money problems grow, and to earn he is forced to become a stage clown in the cabaret troupe. Rath is often filled with jealousy and lust for his wife and her profession, she leaves herself open as a "shared woman", and he is being ridiculed for his past while performing as a clown. He performs his last act at The Blue Angel, and he is shocked to see Lola kissing her new love interest strongman Mazeppa (Hans Albers), and his rage turns into insanity, where he starts strangles his wife and is forced into a straitjacket. In the end, having been released from prison, Rath is not able to resolve his position as a school teacher, and he has obviously lost wife Lola, so he dies from extreme self pity clutching the school desks that once sat his loyal students. Also starring Kurt Gerron as Kiepert the Magician, Rosa Valetti as Guste the Magician's Wife, Reinhold Bernt as The Clown, Hans Roth as Beadle the Caretaker of the Secondary School, Rolf M&uuml;ller as Pupil Angst and Robert Klein-L&ouml;rk as Pupil Goldstaub. Jannings - in his first talking picture - gives a mixed but equally interesting performance as the teacher turned performer with a troubled passion, and Dietrich is wonderful in her iconic top hat and black stockings as the seductive stage performer with a cruel streak, it is a film with some memorable sequences and moments that stand out, especially of course the cabaret stuff, making it a most watchable drama. Very good!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Falling From Grace Over "Show Girl" or There's No Fool Like An Old Fool!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    John T. Ryan (redryan64@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    WE CAN WELL recall viewing this film for the very first time on a PBS Friday evening show. This was circa 1971 and we needed to go to such Public Television stations as our own WTTW, Channel 11 in Chicago in order to see many films which weren't shown on commercial TV Statiobs. WELL, HOW THINGS have changed. Just this passed Monday (2 days ago), Turner Classic Movies ran THE BLUE ANGEL in prime-time. It had been about 40 years (yes, count 'em, folks!) since our initial contact with Herr Josef Von Sternberg's dark, tragic drama. We had seen it once or twice during that period, but had never given it my undivided attention. ALTHOUGH IT IS a German language film, there was at least one of these showings was in a recently rediscovered English language version. We also remember a showing which was in German; but featured Miss Dietrich's performance of "Falling In Lov Again" in English. VIEWING A FILM SUCH as this very talky drama, while at the same time being compelled to read Subtutles, in order to follow the story can really prove to be a pain right where one sits. Yet, it does seem to become easier as the story progresses; as we become engrossed with the scenario unfolding, the dark yet starkly penetrating images, moody and highly atmospheric songs & music and the virtuoso acting performances. THE STORY MAY seem somewhat complex; yet it is probably the very universal themes and connection with the lives and needs of all people that make this such a powerful and compelling of a story with such a long life as an all time favourite. IN SHORT, WE have a story of loneliness, the need to love and be loved, the falling from grace of a highly regarded and most straight laced of a member of academia. From perhaps a most distinguished position and and outstanding of a reputation as a Professor of Literature at the unnamed university, the professor (Mr. Emil Jannings) falls in love with a common, vulgar cabaret singer and exponent of sex, Lola Lola (Miss Marlena Dietrich). THE STORY COVERS a period of over five years, in which the middle aged, clearly un-handsome man discovers that he has fallen to such a degree of degradation as to not only being a minor entertainer; but also participating in selling his own wife. During appearances following Lola's doing her song, professor Roth's duties included peddling some rather pornographic type of postcards to the bawdy male patrons of the show. WE MUST CONFESS that even being a grown man, married with two children, there was an awful lot of obvious seedy goings on that I missed on previous viewings. Certainly, there were no examples of explicit on screen sex (such as have become so commonplace); and yet, with all of the occurrences we surely are forced to ask a few questions. IN ADDITION TO the setting of a night club with rather risqu&eacute; programming, what is it that all of these college boys find so fascinating? Why do the young men hide from the Professor in secret rooms that are below the floors? What is the purpose of these rooms? Why does the proprietor worry about the presence of a police officer; for, isn't this a legal and licensed establishment? Do you think that there is sex for sale here? We do. THE AMAZING FEAT that is accomplished here is making such an interesting story out of such a sordid and low life segment of society. WE GIVE THIS five stars as our rating.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unforgettable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jacabiya
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let me join the ranks that herald this film as one of the great ones, an unforgettable all-time world cinema masterpiece that should be way higher in the IMDb scores, still relevant, powerful, not dated, with not one but two landmark performances. In the first half the film is very funny, but when Lola Lola starts clucking in the wedding reception the horror begins. This is my favorite Marlene Dietrich role, and for my taste the only sexy one, with baby fat and a rounder, younger, nubile face and body(before she turned into the more stern and severe deep-voiced German femme fatale). I find it amazing that her character in this 1930 film still turns me on. Jannings overacts grandiosely to match the extremely melodramatic, denigrating, tragic story, and gives one of the great acting performances of movie history (along with his performance in the silent The Last Laugh). The magician is perfectly sleazy yet human in his ignorance. The film piles it up towards its cringing climax, culminating in action not actually shown, an extremely intelligent move on Sternberg's part. And I dare anyone to come up with more horrible and painful sounds in film history than the professor's.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Downfall of an Arrogant Academic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Le Sage
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Blue Angel features a simple but effective narrative, showing the fall of a man into degradation and squalor. As such, it echoes the themes in early Weimar cinema such as Pandora's Box. The narrative is, indeed, so simple, that this early "talkie" could just as easily have been a silent film. Only rarely is the new sound technology explored to good effect, such as when songs can be heard when the doors from Lola's room to the stage are periodically opened and closed by characters. There is also, of course, the use of song, with Dietrich's voice showcased to good affect. Emil Jannings portrays the stereotype of an academic perfectly: arrogant, insular and with some minor eccentricities, he is unable to cope with life in the "real world" and this leads to his fall from grace. Initially, we in the audience, like his students, see him as a clown, a laughable, pompous yet bumbling figure. His ultimate fate is to be exposed to the whole town as a fool when, stripped of his power, he literally becomes a clown before seeking to return to the insularity of his old post. However, the Professor is not the only loathsome character in this film. The attitude of the students is as despicable as that of their tutor: with their arrogant and bullying behaviour, whilst they are his nemesis, they are also his mirror. They are growing into his image and, with his growing captivation with Lola, he is growing into theirs. Lola is an equally unlikable character and perhaps, once again, reflects concern amongst conservatives in Weimar society about the growing power of women. She is far smarter than the "learned" professor in terms of her ability to understand and manipulate people. Going out on the stage each night is the opposite to his insular world yet it his "act" of appearing respectable in society that this actress is able to quickly pull apart, exposing the shallow man inside. The bird motif used throughout the film is strikingly effective. At the start, the bird who can no longer sing is callously discarded by the housekeeper, just as the worn-out, useless Professor will be discarded, first by the school and then by society. The doomed bird motif is also prefigured by the birds near the clock as the procession of ghoulish statues marches past with each hour. Finally, the Professor himself is humiliated during the clown and magician routine, forced to have doves fly out from under his top hat and to crow like a rooster. Ultimately, this is a brilliant film and, like much late Weimar cinema, reflects themes of moral decline and degradation. This time, however, the character is deeply unlikable from the outset and his humiliation is really an increasing expose to the world of his pre-existing inner nature. He does not grow or transform as a character; rather, as his power is stripped, his true nature is revealed. The learned academic is the biggest fool of all. Stripped of his position and prestige, the academic is nothing more than a clown.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Only angels have wings
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    chaos-rampant
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Films that revolve around performance are essentially about cinema, I'm always on the lookout for these. But unlike the more traditional films about the making of films - Day for Night, Contempt, The Stunt Man, Shadow of the Vampire, etc - those about performance have the extra allure that we have to participate in staging the illusion; it falls on us to imagine the cinematic scenario, and thus complete the notion, actually see in our minds how it completes. It is the best kind of in-sight into creative life - which is every life on the planet, a long series of invention, deception, connection. In The Red Shoes for example, it was a dance between us from the position of the camera and the stage where the story is being danced out. A more intriguing vision we find in the silent Dr. Mabuse, with us looking to apprehend the criminal mastermind who under various guises manipulates the narrative we see. Or the continuation of this in The American Friend, another German film; a 'frame' artist who becomes framed in an illusion that unfolds, this is the film within, as gangster stuff around Europe. This second group is more competent because the film-within, in whatever form, is better integrated inside the outer film. But in all these cases the main subject remains the same; the effort to discern boundaries between a life we control, and so a narrative we are free to improvise as best we can, and a life that is framed, scripted and storyboarded around us from outside. (the truly wise filmmakers understand how these are the same; how, in other terms, the best actors in life are those who are completely clueless about the narrative and therefore effortlessly natural, and those who have studied it and can exercise volition to reshape themselves into what the role requires). Sternberg had made a film about film before this, a more explicit but astounding vision of a filmed reality that prophesied New Wave thirty years before. This is more inconspicuous, less singlemindedly about self-reference, with interesting crowds and rooms around the stage that we can loose ourselves into. It is just endearing to watch on a very basic level, occasionally pretty funny; and in the end thoroughly gut-wrenching. Yet it is still very much about a man losing himself into a performance. What entices him and us is the woman; in fact, we are made to share the male point-of-view so adeptly, the camera always strategically placed where it can be teased and seduced by long legs in stockings, by large eye-lashes making promises, that it is not just the professor, but us as well, more importantly us, that want to let go and be absorbed in the sexual fantasy. It's no wonder she is so captivating, we know after all how Sternberg would grow to worship her, and bind, fully devote his craft to images of her. The second part is where it's truly grueling to watch, where the professor, a pillar of morals and ethos at the start, is completely subsumed inside the fantasy and loses all. Again Emil Jannings puts on a costume. So many fascinating things then happen so quickly, I was left with jaw open. We revisit the cabaret stage from before, only now, quite literally, from inside the mirror looking out; now we are the spectacle, the show being looked on, with being made to perform as the price exacted for having fully invested in the feverish, sultry dream in the first place. Now we are what is being dreamed - this trope is what Lynch has worked and innovated from. And again the distinction between the performance as perceived from outside, with jeers and catcalls, and the human being inside as we know it to suffer. As with all those silent films before about clowns suffering from behind painted smiles, it is a tragic sight of humiliation and despair. When he bellows inordinately, the audience laughs, but we know it's the sound of a soul being torn apart. My only minor gripe, is with how forceful is this part, how emotional. Then again it makes sense; we are again so adeptly placed inside the character, and made to feel as broken as he is. The film ends with the woman performing again her number that captivated the audience so much, only now we understand what's behind the notes. "I'm programmed for love" sings Dietrich, the femme fatale - and so desire, sexual danger personified - who operated the performance from behind the stage. We have mostly come to know film noir from American film. But it was born in Germany, between Dr. Mabuse and this. It's a compelling moral, as in noir later: we are reminded again how dangerous it is to indulge the chimeras of the mind, ego and desire, and how the social fabric has its ways of eventually restoring us in the common, harmless delusions. It's okay to watch, anything more is at our spiritual peril.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The "Carmen" who got away
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    evening1
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Having just caught the Metropolitan's 2010 production of "Carmen" on film during the opera company's outdoor HD Live festival, I expected this film would end with Lola's comeuppance, if not murder. It was a little chilling, and, I have to admit, disappointing, to see her sitting pretty on-stage as her discarded, humiliated husband shuffles away into hopeless oblivion. This film, which I had taped from the City University of New York's excellent TV channel, suffered from horrible visual and sound quality but it managed to keep my attention throughout. It seems a case study in the follies of trying to live without the benefit of self-knowledge. Professor Rath -- was he supposed to be Jewish in this film made as Naziism was on the rise in Germany? -- was a misfit and a clod, a man who found his place in life through his book knowledge. What was missing in him was any sense of who he was as a man. Rath demonstrated his ineptness outside of the ivory tower by blundering into Lola's dressing room, a fateful breaking of social boundaries. Lola treats Rath as one might an old teddy bear. When he proposes marriage, gorgeous Lola cackles hysterically, but it wouldn't occur to Rath to wonder what this might mean. Lola accepts the offer, though one would have to assume the union will never be consummated. (Rather than gaining a love partner, she takes in the father she probably never knew.) Rath's eventual rejection is inevitable. The only surprise here is Lola's getting off scot free. Maybe she thinks about her actions a little; she does seem to darken somewhat during the course of the film. However, she's ultimately left pretty much unscathed by the final credits. Interestingly, Dietrich goes on from this film to become a success in Hollywood, whereas the actor who played Rath remained in Germany to participate in Nazi-propaganda films from which which his career never recovered -- an outcome that pretty much parallels the movie's plot line.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Naughty, naughty..."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moonspinner55
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A stuffy, lonely German college professor, laughed at by his immature pupils, ventures out to a cabaret in the village to berate his students for ogling the female entertainment; instead, he becomes infatuated with the star of the show, chanteuse Lola Lola, and apparently she to him. After marrying the flashy girl, the teacher leaves his profession to travel with the theatrical troupe, but life on the road immediately wears him down. An ugly little story, adapted from Heinrich Mann's novel "Professor Unrath", has a winking-nudging overlay of sexual byplay and was released to great acclaim in both German and English-language versions (this review pertains to the German version with subtitles). Director Josef von Sternberg was already a 15-year veteran of Hollywood movie-making by the time "The Blue Angel" arrived, and yet several sequences (most notably in the first reel and the last) are sloppily constructed and uncertainly paced. Emil Jannings is wonderful as the unloved professor who initially blossoms in the company of streetwise Marlene Dietrich, but his emotional unraveling is awfully quick in coming. Josef von Sternberg is far too sluggish in the beginning, but by the midway point he rushes the narrative...and the audience isn't allowed to get their bearings. As a result, the plot feels like a sadistic series of screw-turns, with no hope (or heart) in sight. **1/2 from ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Humbert Humbert's predecessor
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watching "Der blaue Engel" ("The Blue Angel" in English), I got the feeling that it was sort of a precursor to "Lolita". When you look at how Prof. Immanuel Rath (Emil Jannings) lets his infatuation with nightclub singer Lola Lola (Marlene Dietrich) come to dominate his life, it seems very much like what happens to Humbert Humbert. Of course, the movie is best known for Dietrich's sexy performance as the liberated chanteuse (on which Madeline Kahn's character in "Blazing Saddles" was based). Dietrich must have been every man's dream after the movie came out. Still, the change in Prof. Rath's life caused by his obsession with her certainly stands out as well. All in all, Josef von Sternberg created a real masterpiece.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
