<filme>
 <id>
  62
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0111282
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1994
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Stargate - A Chave para o Futuro da Humanidade
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.9
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  An interstellar teleportation device, found in Egypt, leads to a planet with humans resembling ancient Egyptians who worship the god Ra.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  A small group of US troups and an Egyptologist use an ancient device found in 1920s Egypt to transport themselves to a distant planet. There they discover .. err, well any more plot would be considered a spoiler.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Action
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Adventure
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Sci-Fi
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   stargate
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   alien
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   egypt
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   teleportation
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   military
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Roland Emmerich
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Dean Devlin
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Roland Emmerich
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Kurt Russell
  </ator>
  <ator>
   James Spader
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Alexis Cruz
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Led To The TV Franchise.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Roland Emmerich directed this Sci-Fi action film as Kurt Russell plays Col. Jack O'Neil, who, along with Dr. Daniel Jackson(played by James Spader) lead a team of scientists and military personnel as they explore a time/space portal that was found in Egypt, and has only recently been figured out, unlocking its teleporting ability, and sending them to a desert world where an advanced race of human-like beings still practice ancient Egyptian culture, only with modern technology. They are a warlike people, who want to use the re-opened portal for invasion, so of course they must be stopped. Good premise is strangely squandered in this spectacular looking but dramatically flat and unoriginal film. Good cast tries their best, but overlong film never comes close to the 'Star Wars" level of epic storytelling it clearly aspires to.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Almost Twenty Years Later and after Watching at Least Six Times, the Timeless "Stargate" is still a Fantastic Sci-Fi
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Claudio Carvalho
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In 1928, in Egypt, a strange device is found by an expedition. In the present days, the outcast linguist Dr. Daniel Jackson (James Spader) is invited by a mysterious woman to decipher an ancient hieroglyph in a military facility. Soon he finds that the device was developed by an advanced civilization and opens a portal to teletransport to another planet. Dr. Jackson is invited to join a military team under the command of Colonel Jonathan 'Jack' O'Neil (Kurt Russell) that will explore the new world. They find a land that recalls Egypt and humans in a primitive culture that worship and are slaves to Ra, the God of the Sun. But soon they discover the secret of the mysterious "stargate". "Stargate" is still a fantastic sci-fi after almost twenty years and watching it at least six times. The story is intriguing and entwines action with humor and romance. The cast is excellent, with Kurt Russell and James Spade in the top of their careers. The special effects are still great after almost twenty years. And the haunting music score completes this timeless classic sci-fi with a touch of class. My vote is nine. Title (Brazil): "Stargate - A Chave para o Futuro da Humanidade" ("Stargate  The Key for the Future of Mankind")
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nice science-fiction entertainment
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Avid Climber
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Stargate is, as far as I'm concerned, better than the original TV series, which I've watched a couple of time without really getting interested, but then I'm not a fan. The good. Very imaginative settings and alien technology. Beautiful photography. Nicely paced scenario. Interesting story with a solid background. The actors. Kurt Russell is right in his element, and didn't need to show the limits of his short acting range. James Spader is the most interesting character, and plays it well. Mili Avital is pretty, innocent, and plays her sweet role really nicely. Erick Avari, though, is my favorite of the cast and offers us a very convincing performance as the primitive priest-leader faced with powerful strangers. And finally, you can see some of the antics of French Stewart. The bad. Very low army credibility. The intro village miniature is of poor quality. The special effects are getting a bit old, but they were done in such a way as to minimize the aging and still be well received these days. The ugly. That desert beast puppet is just terrible. The chevrons are flimsy. The result. Good entertainment, recommended to sci-fi fans.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Terrific sci-fi adventure
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Progressive-Element
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's had a lot of stick over the years, but Stargate makes for a terrific thrill ride, conveying some of the excitement of Star Wars, Indiana Jones, and Flash Gordon. And perhaps even the John Carter books too. It takes awhile for it to build up, but the set-up is enthralling, a neat spin on the Chariots of the Gods stuff about ancient astronauts and the like. Once Kurt and James are on 'Planet X', they and the team eventually discover humans living a nomadic existence, kept subservient by the sun-god Ra - who turns out to be a powerful despotic alien, but no God. Ra's henchmen too are simply big strong men, who happen to be kitted out with high-tech weapons and equipment. Things take a turn for the worse when Ra shows up, alerted to the activation of the Stargate, and Spader, Kurt and his men eventually find themselves leading a revolt, while at the same time racing against time from stopping Ra sending an explosive present through the Stargate to Earth. Not perfect, a little plodding at times, but fun undemanding entertainment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a classic but not for me, too much talking
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    trashgang
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Having just bought the full stargate collection I had to start with the original one. Having seen it I had my doubts about starting the series. The flick doesn't blow me away. The effects were good and no that much of CGI was used but it was the story itself that wasn't my cup of tea. It starts rather good going back to 8000 years before Christ to see some kind of space ship landing on earth. Flash forward to early 1920's to see the discovery in Egypt of some weird objects. Flash forward to nowadays were Dr. Daniel Jackson(James Spader) is brought in into the army to help solving a two year problem, what are the symbols standing on the objects found in Egypt, in comes Col. Jonathan 'Jack' O'Neil (Kurt Russell with a weird haircut) to solve the problem once they see that the object is some kind of Stargate. Off they go into the stargate to another galaxy and from here things go wrong for me. Here we move away from a science-fiction to a story were the white people are the superiors of the black coloured. They need the whites to help them against the Egyptian looking aliens with a god called Ra. Anyone. In comes also a bit of a love story with Dr. Jackosn. Even when the aliens attack it's a bit low on everything. It's a bit of how humanity started and what went wrong with a lot of blah blah and no action. Still, for some it's a classic that spawned a new flick Children Of The Gods (1997) with a whole new cast which leads to the series for ten years long. As I said, the effects were rather good and luckily the monsters and original alien were not done in CGI but there are better SF's out from that era. Gore 0/5 Nudity 0/5 Effects 3/5 Story 2,5/5 Comedy 0/5
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Absolutely brilliant Sci-Fi.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    domino365
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An excellent movie with great cast, original idea and great story. The Cast. Kurt Russell is great as Jonathan 'Jack' O'Neil. He comes across as a great hero during the action scenes but plays the emotional parts well when they arise. James Spader is great as Dr Daniel Jackson and really comes across as the kind of person you'd expect to be teaching students in a university. His character and Kurt Russell's bump heads a few times and you really believe that they're two really different people. Jackson wants to read every piece of righting, discover every little fossil and meet every local which is a contrast to O'Neil who wants to get on with the mission, shoot first ask questions later and perceive everything as a possible threat. The main cast is back by a stellar supporting cast notable Jaye Davidson as the evil Egyptian god, Ra. The concept. Most mainstream Sci-Fi is set on a spaceship, in the future but this movie takes a completely different direction. The StarGate is a ring with thirty six symbols on it which act as an address to a different planet. It creates a wormhole which instantly transports you to another planet. That is a departure in itself but here's the best part, the main villain is an alien who kidnapped humans from ancient Egypt and brought them to this planet. He took over a young boys body and poses as Ra, the sun god in order to enslave the captured humans. Rather than being set in the future where a big bad alien race tries to invade Earth, there is a heavy focus on the past and takes mythology we know about and says 'what if?' which is a really interesting concept. The story. It's a fairly generic story. It's about a team of special forces commandos who go through the Stargate and find the citizens on the planet are being enslaved by an alien in the body of a boy who is pretending to be the Egyptian sun god, Ra. The team set out to overthrow Ra and get home before they're all killed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    amazing 90s Sci-Fi cult classic that spawned SG1, Atlantis and Universe
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    HelenMary
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Love this film. It's aged well, and is the opener for a massive TV series franchise. Basically, Dr Daniel Jackson (James Spader) is called into a military research station to decipher hieroglyphs and other symbols on a large artifact found at Giza in 1928, which is of course the first Stargate and was built by the alien civilisation that created the Ancient Egyptian way of life here on Earth, which have since gone on another planet, where our intrepid explorers go and find a similar civilisation to what the Egyptians might have been two thousand plus years ago on Earth. Their language is similar enough to what Dr Jackson, an archaeological linguist, can reasonably and not-improbably understand, after a few false starts. The film is of epic proportions set against sweeping sand dune vistas and huge sets, reminiscent of the big studio classics, with hundreds of extras who are real people not painted in later. It has an iconic soundtrack that is almost operatic in places, and the costumes, ancient Egyptian similarities and the special effects are just brilliant even nearly twenty years on, and without the prolific CGI we have today! It is visually very impressive, and original. The script isn't great and is really the only thing that lets the film down a point. It's all a bit rushed and staccato at the beginning - the bit on Earth is the least convincing actually. The film manages some humour as well as having you on the edge of your seat for a climactic finale, which is also a little emotive. James Spader is always a good bet, known most prominently for rather seedy, smutty, awkward or fast talking characters (Oh! How I love Boston Legal), he is superb as the academic PhD here; his calm, measured and quiet delivery are perfect against Kurt Russell's buzz-cut macho all-guns-blazing military man on a mission. Jaye Davidson gives a rather scary performance as Ra ("the Sun god") with control and an almost sexual element and effeminacy but also a violence and temper that are only partially helped by special effects. I really loved the acting - possibly the stand out character - of Alexis Cruz as the smart and brave village boy Skaara who makes first contact and is the plucky comic relief! Erick Avari, the village leader Kasuf, is a familiar face now (but perhaps wasn't so much back in the early 90s as this was his first major film role) as is French Stewart, one of the soldiers (3rd Rock from the Sun) and also Djimon Hounsou in an early in his acting career small though perfectly formed role as Horus. A brilliant film, well worth watching for sci-fi, Egyptian, alien, anthropology, archaeology, action adventure interests. It is worth noting that the beginning of the film is in German with subtitles and your DVD language and subtitle options aren't playing up (I stupidly forgot that last time I watched as it had been such a long time since I'd seen it), and also there are subtitles for the plot-important Egyptian dialect conversations too.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fairly typical
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Leofwine_draca
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    STARGATE should be the perfect movie for me: an interesting premise, grounded in real-life theory (I've been reading Graham Hancock's FINGERPRINTS OF THE GODS recently, and am familiar with Von Daniken's writings) and made with a high enough budget to do the special effects justice. And watching it, it's hard to fault the production. The performances are pretty good, from Kurt Russell's hard-ass soldier to James Spader's nerdy Egyptologist, and the aforementioned SFX are decent. It's just that the film ends up feeling relatively mundane given the extensive set-up; it all turns into an entirely typical good guys vs. the bad guys type film, with little of the intelligence or thought-provoking questions I was hoping for. I'll lay the blame squarely at the door of Roland Emmerich, who has quite the habit of dumbing down his source material (INDEPENDENCE DAY, GODZILLA, need I go on?). Imagine if this had been made by somebody with more interest in the questions raised instead of the size of the guns!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A bit standard, but a very decent concept to a great movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin-thelordofthefu-48-460297
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well, I just want to say that I had never heard of this film before... until the past summer when I was at summer camp when I watched it on a VHS copy. I also heard that this was made the same year I was born and this was made by the same guy who directed Independence Day, Godzilla, and the later film 2012. I watched it because I wanted to see if it would keep me very interested. It did after my first viewing and I personally like it as much as those who gave it a positive feedback. Sure, some of the characters may be unengaging and the story, despite it's decent concept, does have some plot holes and I would've like to see more of the romance between the two characters. Those flaws didn't really bother me at all and I think that this is Roland Emmerich's best film next to Independence Day and The Patriot. The acting on the whole is pretty good especially Kurt Russell and James Spader who had great chemistry together throughout the film. The directing from Roland Emmerich is pretty good and focused, the pacing moves along very nicely, but would've been fifteen minutes longer at the end of the film. The strongest aspects, however, goes to it's compelling visuals and it's epic music score from David Arnold. The look of the Egyptian world along with some nice costume designs is fabulous. David Arnold's music score doesn't have a sci-fi tone to it, but it does have a memorable tune which gives the movie an epic sweep to it. It also has some good dialog especially it's nice moments with the main character and the villain who is quite menacing. Stargate does have a hokey concept, but I don't understand why some people hated it because I think that this is an interesting film and I simply understood that it got a cult following over the years. It isn't perfect, but it's completely watchable to those who haven't seen it yet. So, in my opinion, this deserves a 4/5.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ancient Astronaut Theorists and Fans are Still Waiting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Ancient Astronaut thesis definitively started in the late 60's with Erich Von Daniken, was matured and intellectualized by Zecharia Sitchin starting in 1976, and is here today in a plethora of TV shows, documentaries and extensions of previous works. It is a fascinating and totally believable subject that has limited, if any big screen incarnations. Thus speaks Stargate. The movie starts off great with the whole thing collapsing under its own weight of misunderstanding the concept and turning it into a good looking but incredibly inept military exercise with dull action scenes and unbelievably uninteresting cultural exchanges. The Alien look is outstanding as are the sets, but it shamelessly uses a deep concept and ridicules its insights. It has no taste for the intellect and the cartoonish presentation of the Marines is clich&eacute;d and dated. There is still a great movie to be made with this subject matter and if it is handled in a respectful manner it could be the biggest brainy blockbuster of all time. Ever since 2001: A Space Odyssey (which had undertones of the theme) fans of the Ancient Astronaut theory have been waiting and one hopes that Hollywood is listening.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Led To The TV Franchise.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Roland Emmerich directed this Sci-Fi action film as Kurt Russell plays Col. Jack O'Neil, who, along with Dr. Daniel Jackson(played by James Spader) lead a team of scientists and military personnel as they explore a time/space portal that was found in Egypt, and has only recently been figured out, unlocking its teleporting ability, and sending them to a desert world where an advanced race of human-like beings still practice ancient Egyptian culture, only with modern technology. They are a warlike people, who want to use the re-opened portal for invasion, so of course they must be stopped. Good premise is strangely squandered in this spectacular looking but dramatically flat and unoriginal film. Good cast tries their best, but overlong film never comes close to the 'Star Wars" level of epic storytelling it clearly aspires to.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Almost Twenty Years Later and after Watching at Least Six Times, the Timeless "Stargate" is still a Fantastic Sci-Fi
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Claudio Carvalho
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In 1928, in Egypt, a strange device is found by an expedition. In the present days, the outcast linguist Dr. Daniel Jackson (James Spader) is invited by a mysterious woman to decipher an ancient hieroglyph in a military facility. Soon he finds that the device was developed by an advanced civilization and opens a portal to teletransport to another planet. Dr. Jackson is invited to join a military team under the command of Colonel Jonathan 'Jack' O'Neil (Kurt Russell) that will explore the new world. They find a land that recalls Egypt and humans in a primitive culture that worship and are slaves to Ra, the God of the Sun. But soon they discover the secret of the mysterious "stargate". "Stargate" is still a fantastic sci-fi after almost twenty years and watching it at least six times. The story is intriguing and entwines action with humor and romance. The cast is excellent, with Kurt Russell and James Spade in the top of their careers. The special effects are still great after almost twenty years. And the haunting music score completes this timeless classic sci-fi with a touch of class. My vote is nine. Title (Brazil): "Stargate - A Chave para o Futuro da Humanidade" ("Stargate  The Key for the Future of Mankind")
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nice science-fiction entertainment
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Avid Climber
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Stargate is, as far as I'm concerned, better than the original TV series, which I've watched a couple of time without really getting interested, but then I'm not a fan. The good. Very imaginative settings and alien technology. Beautiful photography. Nicely paced scenario. Interesting story with a solid background. The actors. Kurt Russell is right in his element, and didn't need to show the limits of his short acting range. James Spader is the most interesting character, and plays it well. Mili Avital is pretty, innocent, and plays her sweet role really nicely. Erick Avari, though, is my favorite of the cast and offers us a very convincing performance as the primitive priest-leader faced with powerful strangers. And finally, you can see some of the antics of French Stewart. The bad. Very low army credibility. The intro village miniature is of poor quality. The special effects are getting a bit old, but they were done in such a way as to minimize the aging and still be well received these days. The ugly. That desert beast puppet is just terrible. The chevrons are flimsy. The result. Good entertainment, recommended to sci-fi fans.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Terrific sci-fi adventure
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Progressive-Element
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's had a lot of stick over the years, but Stargate makes for a terrific thrill ride, conveying some of the excitement of Star Wars, Indiana Jones, and Flash Gordon. And perhaps even the John Carter books too. It takes awhile for it to build up, but the set-up is enthralling, a neat spin on the Chariots of the Gods stuff about ancient astronauts and the like. Once Kurt and James are on 'Planet X', they and the team eventually discover humans living a nomadic existence, kept subservient by the sun-god Ra - who turns out to be a powerful despotic alien, but no God. Ra's henchmen too are simply big strong men, who happen to be kitted out with high-tech weapons and equipment. Things take a turn for the worse when Ra shows up, alerted to the activation of the Stargate, and Spader, Kurt and his men eventually find themselves leading a revolt, while at the same time racing against time from stopping Ra sending an explosive present through the Stargate to Earth. Not perfect, a little plodding at times, but fun undemanding entertainment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a classic but not for me, too much talking
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    trashgang
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Having just bought the full stargate collection I had to start with the original one. Having seen it I had my doubts about starting the series. The flick doesn't blow me away. The effects were good and no that much of CGI was used but it was the story itself that wasn't my cup of tea. It starts rather good going back to 8000 years before Christ to see some kind of space ship landing on earth. Flash forward to early 1920's to see the discovery in Egypt of some weird objects. Flash forward to nowadays were Dr. Daniel Jackson(James Spader) is brought in into the army to help solving a two year problem, what are the symbols standing on the objects found in Egypt, in comes Col. Jonathan 'Jack' O'Neil (Kurt Russell with a weird haircut) to solve the problem once they see that the object is some kind of Stargate. Off they go into the stargate to another galaxy and from here things go wrong for me. Here we move away from a science-fiction to a story were the white people are the superiors of the black coloured. They need the whites to help them against the Egyptian looking aliens with a god called Ra. Anyone. In comes also a bit of a love story with Dr. Jackosn. Even when the aliens attack it's a bit low on everything. It's a bit of how humanity started and what went wrong with a lot of blah blah and no action. Still, for some it's a classic that spawned a new flick Children Of The Gods (1997) with a whole new cast which leads to the series for ten years long. As I said, the effects were rather good and luckily the monsters and original alien were not done in CGI but there are better SF's out from that era. Gore 0/5 Nudity 0/5 Effects 3/5 Story 2,5/5 Comedy 0/5
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Absolutely brilliant Sci-Fi.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    domino365
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An excellent movie with great cast, original idea and great story. The Cast. Kurt Russell is great as Jonathan 'Jack' O'Neil. He comes across as a great hero during the action scenes but plays the emotional parts well when they arise. James Spader is great as Dr Daniel Jackson and really comes across as the kind of person you'd expect to be teaching students in a university. His character and Kurt Russell's bump heads a few times and you really believe that they're two really different people. Jackson wants to read every piece of righting, discover every little fossil and meet every local which is a contrast to O'Neil who wants to get on with the mission, shoot first ask questions later and perceive everything as a possible threat. The main cast is back by a stellar supporting cast notable Jaye Davidson as the evil Egyptian god, Ra. The concept. Most mainstream Sci-Fi is set on a spaceship, in the future but this movie takes a completely different direction. The StarGate is a ring with thirty six symbols on it which act as an address to a different planet. It creates a wormhole which instantly transports you to another planet. That is a departure in itself but here's the best part, the main villain is an alien who kidnapped humans from ancient Egypt and brought them to this planet. He took over a young boys body and poses as Ra, the sun god in order to enslave the captured humans. Rather than being set in the future where a big bad alien race tries to invade Earth, there is a heavy focus on the past and takes mythology we know about and says 'what if?' which is a really interesting concept. The story. It's a fairly generic story. It's about a team of special forces commandos who go through the Stargate and find the citizens on the planet are being enslaved by an alien in the body of a boy who is pretending to be the Egyptian sun god, Ra. The team set out to overthrow Ra and get home before they're all killed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    amazing 90s Sci-Fi cult classic that spawned SG1, Atlantis and Universe
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    HelenMary
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Love this film. It's aged well, and is the opener for a massive TV series franchise. Basically, Dr Daniel Jackson (James Spader) is called into a military research station to decipher hieroglyphs and other symbols on a large artifact found at Giza in 1928, which is of course the first Stargate and was built by the alien civilisation that created the Ancient Egyptian way of life here on Earth, which have since gone on another planet, where our intrepid explorers go and find a similar civilisation to what the Egyptians might have been two thousand plus years ago on Earth. Their language is similar enough to what Dr Jackson, an archaeological linguist, can reasonably and not-improbably understand, after a few false starts. The film is of epic proportions set against sweeping sand dune vistas and huge sets, reminiscent of the big studio classics, with hundreds of extras who are real people not painted in later. It has an iconic soundtrack that is almost operatic in places, and the costumes, ancient Egyptian similarities and the special effects are just brilliant even nearly twenty years on, and without the prolific CGI we have today! It is visually very impressive, and original. The script isn't great and is really the only thing that lets the film down a point. It's all a bit rushed and staccato at the beginning - the bit on Earth is the least convincing actually. The film manages some humour as well as having you on the edge of your seat for a climactic finale, which is also a little emotive. James Spader is always a good bet, known most prominently for rather seedy, smutty, awkward or fast talking characters (Oh! How I love Boston Legal), he is superb as the academic PhD here; his calm, measured and quiet delivery are perfect against Kurt Russell's buzz-cut macho all-guns-blazing military man on a mission. Jaye Davidson gives a rather scary performance as Ra ("the Sun god") with control and an almost sexual element and effeminacy but also a violence and temper that are only partially helped by special effects. I really loved the acting - possibly the stand out character - of Alexis Cruz as the smart and brave village boy Skaara who makes first contact and is the plucky comic relief! Erick Avari, the village leader Kasuf, is a familiar face now (but perhaps wasn't so much back in the early 90s as this was his first major film role) as is French Stewart, one of the soldiers (3rd Rock from the Sun) and also Djimon Hounsou in an early in his acting career small though perfectly formed role as Horus. A brilliant film, well worth watching for sci-fi, Egyptian, alien, anthropology, archaeology, action adventure interests. It is worth noting that the beginning of the film is in German with subtitles and your DVD language and subtitle options aren't playing up (I stupidly forgot that last time I watched as it had been such a long time since I'd seen it), and also there are subtitles for the plot-important Egyptian dialect conversations too.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fairly typical
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Leofwine_draca
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    STARGATE should be the perfect movie for me: an interesting premise, grounded in real-life theory (I've been reading Graham Hancock's FINGERPRINTS OF THE GODS recently, and am familiar with Von Daniken's writings) and made with a high enough budget to do the special effects justice. And watching it, it's hard to fault the production. The performances are pretty good, from Kurt Russell's hard-ass soldier to James Spader's nerdy Egyptologist, and the aforementioned SFX are decent. It's just that the film ends up feeling relatively mundane given the extensive set-up; it all turns into an entirely typical good guys vs. the bad guys type film, with little of the intelligence or thought-provoking questions I was hoping for. I'll lay the blame squarely at the door of Roland Emmerich, who has quite the habit of dumbing down his source material (INDEPENDENCE DAY, GODZILLA, need I go on?). Imagine if this had been made by somebody with more interest in the questions raised instead of the size of the guns!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A bit standard, but a very decent concept to a great movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin-thelordofthefu-48-460297
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well, I just want to say that I had never heard of this film before... until the past summer when I was at summer camp when I watched it on a VHS copy. I also heard that this was made the same year I was born and this was made by the same guy who directed Independence Day, Godzilla, and the later film 2012. I watched it because I wanted to see if it would keep me very interested. It did after my first viewing and I personally like it as much as those who gave it a positive feedback. Sure, some of the characters may be unengaging and the story, despite it's decent concept, does have some plot holes and I would've like to see more of the romance between the two characters. Those flaws didn't really bother me at all and I think that this is Roland Emmerich's best film next to Independence Day and The Patriot. The acting on the whole is pretty good especially Kurt Russell and James Spader who had great chemistry together throughout the film. The directing from Roland Emmerich is pretty good and focused, the pacing moves along very nicely, but would've been fifteen minutes longer at the end of the film. The strongest aspects, however, goes to it's compelling visuals and it's epic music score from David Arnold. The look of the Egyptian world along with some nice costume designs is fabulous. David Arnold's music score doesn't have a sci-fi tone to it, but it does have a memorable tune which gives the movie an epic sweep to it. It also has some good dialog especially it's nice moments with the main character and the villain who is quite menacing. Stargate does have a hokey concept, but I don't understand why some people hated it because I think that this is an interesting film and I simply understood that it got a cult following over the years. It isn't perfect, but it's completely watchable to those who haven't seen it yet. So, in my opinion, this deserves a 4/5.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ancient Astronaut Theorists and Fans are Still Waiting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Ancient Astronaut thesis definitively started in the late 60's with Erich Von Daniken, was matured and intellectualized by Zecharia Sitchin starting in 1976, and is here today in a plethora of TV shows, documentaries and extensions of previous works. It is a fascinating and totally believable subject that has limited, if any big screen incarnations. Thus speaks Stargate. The movie starts off great with the whole thing collapsing under its own weight of misunderstanding the concept and turning it into a good looking but incredibly inept military exercise with dull action scenes and unbelievably uninteresting cultural exchanges. The Alien look is outstanding as are the sets, but it shamelessly uses a deep concept and ridicules its insights. It has no taste for the intellect and the cartoonish presentation of the Marines is clich&eacute;d and dated. There is still a great movie to be made with this subject matter and if it is handled in a respectful manner it could be the biggest brainy blockbuster of all time. Ever since 2001: A Space Odyssey (which had undertones of the theme) fans of the Ancient Astronaut theory have been waiting and one hopes that Hollywood is listening.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Led To The TV Franchise.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Roland Emmerich directed this Sci-Fi action film as Kurt Russell plays Col. Jack O'Neil, who, along with Dr. Daniel Jackson(played by James Spader) lead a team of scientists and military personnel as they explore a time/space portal that was found in Egypt, and has only recently been figured out, unlocking its teleporting ability, and sending them to a desert world where an advanced race of human-like beings still practice ancient Egyptian culture, only with modern technology. They are a warlike people, who want to use the re-opened portal for invasion, so of course they must be stopped. Good premise is strangely squandered in this spectacular looking but dramatically flat and unoriginal film. Good cast tries their best, but overlong film never comes close to the 'Star Wars" level of epic storytelling it clearly aspires to.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Almost Twenty Years Later and after Watching at Least Six Times, the Timeless "Stargate" is still a Fantastic Sci-Fi
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Claudio Carvalho
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In 1928, in Egypt, a strange device is found by an expedition. In the present days, the outcast linguist Dr. Daniel Jackson (James Spader) is invited by a mysterious woman to decipher an ancient hieroglyph in a military facility. Soon he finds that the device was developed by an advanced civilization and opens a portal to teletransport to another planet. Dr. Jackson is invited to join a military team under the command of Colonel Jonathan 'Jack' O'Neil (Kurt Russell) that will explore the new world. They find a land that recalls Egypt and humans in a primitive culture that worship and are slaves to Ra, the God of the Sun. But soon they discover the secret of the mysterious "stargate". "Stargate" is still a fantastic sci-fi after almost twenty years and watching it at least six times. The story is intriguing and entwines action with humor and romance. The cast is excellent, with Kurt Russell and James Spade in the top of their careers. The special effects are still great after almost twenty years. And the haunting music score completes this timeless classic sci-fi with a touch of class. My vote is nine. Title (Brazil): "Stargate - A Chave para o Futuro da Humanidade" ("Stargate  The Key for the Future of Mankind")
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nice science-fiction entertainment
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Avid Climber
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Stargate is, as far as I'm concerned, better than the original TV series, which I've watched a couple of time without really getting interested, but then I'm not a fan. The good. Very imaginative settings and alien technology. Beautiful photography. Nicely paced scenario. Interesting story with a solid background. The actors. Kurt Russell is right in his element, and didn't need to show the limits of his short acting range. James Spader is the most interesting character, and plays it well. Mili Avital is pretty, innocent, and plays her sweet role really nicely. Erick Avari, though, is my favorite of the cast and offers us a very convincing performance as the primitive priest-leader faced with powerful strangers. And finally, you can see some of the antics of French Stewart. The bad. Very low army credibility. The intro village miniature is of poor quality. The special effects are getting a bit old, but they were done in such a way as to minimize the aging and still be well received these days. The ugly. That desert beast puppet is just terrible. The chevrons are flimsy. The result. Good entertainment, recommended to sci-fi fans.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Terrific sci-fi adventure
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Progressive-Element
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's had a lot of stick over the years, but Stargate makes for a terrific thrill ride, conveying some of the excitement of Star Wars, Indiana Jones, and Flash Gordon. And perhaps even the John Carter books too. It takes awhile for it to build up, but the set-up is enthralling, a neat spin on the Chariots of the Gods stuff about ancient astronauts and the like. Once Kurt and James are on 'Planet X', they and the team eventually discover humans living a nomadic existence, kept subservient by the sun-god Ra - who turns out to be a powerful despotic alien, but no God. Ra's henchmen too are simply big strong men, who happen to be kitted out with high-tech weapons and equipment. Things take a turn for the worse when Ra shows up, alerted to the activation of the Stargate, and Spader, Kurt and his men eventually find themselves leading a revolt, while at the same time racing against time from stopping Ra sending an explosive present through the Stargate to Earth. Not perfect, a little plodding at times, but fun undemanding entertainment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a classic but not for me, too much talking
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    trashgang
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Having just bought the full stargate collection I had to start with the original one. Having seen it I had my doubts about starting the series. The flick doesn't blow me away. The effects were good and no that much of CGI was used but it was the story itself that wasn't my cup of tea. It starts rather good going back to 8000 years before Christ to see some kind of space ship landing on earth. Flash forward to early 1920's to see the discovery in Egypt of some weird objects. Flash forward to nowadays were Dr. Daniel Jackson(James Spader) is brought in into the army to help solving a two year problem, what are the symbols standing on the objects found in Egypt, in comes Col. Jonathan 'Jack' O'Neil (Kurt Russell with a weird haircut) to solve the problem once they see that the object is some kind of Stargate. Off they go into the stargate to another galaxy and from here things go wrong for me. Here we move away from a science-fiction to a story were the white people are the superiors of the black coloured. They need the whites to help them against the Egyptian looking aliens with a god called Ra. Anyone. In comes also a bit of a love story with Dr. Jackosn. Even when the aliens attack it's a bit low on everything. It's a bit of how humanity started and what went wrong with a lot of blah blah and no action. Still, for some it's a classic that spawned a new flick Children Of The Gods (1997) with a whole new cast which leads to the series for ten years long. As I said, the effects were rather good and luckily the monsters and original alien were not done in CGI but there are better SF's out from that era. Gore 0/5 Nudity 0/5 Effects 3/5 Story 2,5/5 Comedy 0/5
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Absolutely brilliant Sci-Fi.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    domino365
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An excellent movie with great cast, original idea and great story. The Cast. Kurt Russell is great as Jonathan 'Jack' O'Neil. He comes across as a great hero during the action scenes but plays the emotional parts well when they arise. James Spader is great as Dr Daniel Jackson and really comes across as the kind of person you'd expect to be teaching students in a university. His character and Kurt Russell's bump heads a few times and you really believe that they're two really different people. Jackson wants to read every piece of righting, discover every little fossil and meet every local which is a contrast to O'Neil who wants to get on with the mission, shoot first ask questions later and perceive everything as a possible threat. The main cast is back by a stellar supporting cast notable Jaye Davidson as the evil Egyptian god, Ra. The concept. Most mainstream Sci-Fi is set on a spaceship, in the future but this movie takes a completely different direction. The StarGate is a ring with thirty six symbols on it which act as an address to a different planet. It creates a wormhole which instantly transports you to another planet. That is a departure in itself but here's the best part, the main villain is an alien who kidnapped humans from ancient Egypt and brought them to this planet. He took over a young boys body and poses as Ra, the sun god in order to enslave the captured humans. Rather than being set in the future where a big bad alien race tries to invade Earth, there is a heavy focus on the past and takes mythology we know about and says 'what if?' which is a really interesting concept. The story. It's a fairly generic story. It's about a team of special forces commandos who go through the Stargate and find the citizens on the planet are being enslaved by an alien in the body of a boy who is pretending to be the Egyptian sun god, Ra. The team set out to overthrow Ra and get home before they're all killed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    amazing 90s Sci-Fi cult classic that spawned SG1, Atlantis and Universe
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    HelenMary
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Love this film. It's aged well, and is the opener for a massive TV series franchise. Basically, Dr Daniel Jackson (James Spader) is called into a military research station to decipher hieroglyphs and other symbols on a large artifact found at Giza in 1928, which is of course the first Stargate and was built by the alien civilisation that created the Ancient Egyptian way of life here on Earth, which have since gone on another planet, where our intrepid explorers go and find a similar civilisation to what the Egyptians might have been two thousand plus years ago on Earth. Their language is similar enough to what Dr Jackson, an archaeological linguist, can reasonably and not-improbably understand, after a few false starts. The film is of epic proportions set against sweeping sand dune vistas and huge sets, reminiscent of the big studio classics, with hundreds of extras who are real people not painted in later. It has an iconic soundtrack that is almost operatic in places, and the costumes, ancient Egyptian similarities and the special effects are just brilliant even nearly twenty years on, and without the prolific CGI we have today! It is visually very impressive, and original. The script isn't great and is really the only thing that lets the film down a point. It's all a bit rushed and staccato at the beginning - the bit on Earth is the least convincing actually. The film manages some humour as well as having you on the edge of your seat for a climactic finale, which is also a little emotive. James Spader is always a good bet, known most prominently for rather seedy, smutty, awkward or fast talking characters (Oh! How I love Boston Legal), he is superb as the academic PhD here; his calm, measured and quiet delivery are perfect against Kurt Russell's buzz-cut macho all-guns-blazing military man on a mission. Jaye Davidson gives a rather scary performance as Ra ("the Sun god") with control and an almost sexual element and effeminacy but also a violence and temper that are only partially helped by special effects. I really loved the acting - possibly the stand out character - of Alexis Cruz as the smart and brave village boy Skaara who makes first contact and is the plucky comic relief! Erick Avari, the village leader Kasuf, is a familiar face now (but perhaps wasn't so much back in the early 90s as this was his first major film role) as is French Stewart, one of the soldiers (3rd Rock from the Sun) and also Djimon Hounsou in an early in his acting career small though perfectly formed role as Horus. A brilliant film, well worth watching for sci-fi, Egyptian, alien, anthropology, archaeology, action adventure interests. It is worth noting that the beginning of the film is in German with subtitles and your DVD language and subtitle options aren't playing up (I stupidly forgot that last time I watched as it had been such a long time since I'd seen it), and also there are subtitles for the plot-important Egyptian dialect conversations too.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fairly typical
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Leofwine_draca
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    STARGATE should be the perfect movie for me: an interesting premise, grounded in real-life theory (I've been reading Graham Hancock's FINGERPRINTS OF THE GODS recently, and am familiar with Von Daniken's writings) and made with a high enough budget to do the special effects justice. And watching it, it's hard to fault the production. The performances are pretty good, from Kurt Russell's hard-ass soldier to James Spader's nerdy Egyptologist, and the aforementioned SFX are decent. It's just that the film ends up feeling relatively mundane given the extensive set-up; it all turns into an entirely typical good guys vs. the bad guys type film, with little of the intelligence or thought-provoking questions I was hoping for. I'll lay the blame squarely at the door of Roland Emmerich, who has quite the habit of dumbing down his source material (INDEPENDENCE DAY, GODZILLA, need I go on?). Imagine if this had been made by somebody with more interest in the questions raised instead of the size of the guns!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A bit standard, but a very decent concept to a great movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin-thelordofthefu-48-460297
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well, I just want to say that I had never heard of this film before... until the past summer when I was at summer camp when I watched it on a VHS copy. I also heard that this was made the same year I was born and this was made by the same guy who directed Independence Day, Godzilla, and the later film 2012. I watched it because I wanted to see if it would keep me very interested. It did after my first viewing and I personally like it as much as those who gave it a positive feedback. Sure, some of the characters may be unengaging and the story, despite it's decent concept, does have some plot holes and I would've like to see more of the romance between the two characters. Those flaws didn't really bother me at all and I think that this is Roland Emmerich's best film next to Independence Day and The Patriot. The acting on the whole is pretty good especially Kurt Russell and James Spader who had great chemistry together throughout the film. The directing from Roland Emmerich is pretty good and focused, the pacing moves along very nicely, but would've been fifteen minutes longer at the end of the film. The strongest aspects, however, goes to it's compelling visuals and it's epic music score from David Arnold. The look of the Egyptian world along with some nice costume designs is fabulous. David Arnold's music score doesn't have a sci-fi tone to it, but it does have a memorable tune which gives the movie an epic sweep to it. It also has some good dialog especially it's nice moments with the main character and the villain who is quite menacing. Stargate does have a hokey concept, but I don't understand why some people hated it because I think that this is an interesting film and I simply understood that it got a cult following over the years. It isn't perfect, but it's completely watchable to those who haven't seen it yet. So, in my opinion, this deserves a 4/5.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ancient Astronaut Theorists and Fans are Still Waiting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Ancient Astronaut thesis definitively started in the late 60's with Erich Von Daniken, was matured and intellectualized by Zecharia Sitchin starting in 1976, and is here today in a plethora of TV shows, documentaries and extensions of previous works. It is a fascinating and totally believable subject that has limited, if any big screen incarnations. Thus speaks Stargate. The movie starts off great with the whole thing collapsing under its own weight of misunderstanding the concept and turning it into a good looking but incredibly inept military exercise with dull action scenes and unbelievably uninteresting cultural exchanges. The Alien look is outstanding as are the sets, but it shamelessly uses a deep concept and ridicules its insights. It has no taste for the intellect and the cartoonish presentation of the Marines is clich&eacute;d and dated. There is still a great movie to be made with this subject matter and if it is handled in a respectful manner it could be the biggest brainy blockbuster of all time. Ever since 2001: A Space Odyssey (which had undertones of the theme) fans of the Ancient Astronaut theory have been waiting and one hopes that Hollywood is listening.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Led To The TV Franchise.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Roland Emmerich directed this Sci-Fi action film as Kurt Russell plays Col. Jack O'Neil, who, along with Dr. Daniel Jackson(played by James Spader) lead a team of scientists and military personnel as they explore a time/space portal that was found in Egypt, and has only recently been figured out, unlocking its teleporting ability, and sending them to a desert world where an advanced race of human-like beings still practice ancient Egyptian culture, only with modern technology. They are a warlike people, who want to use the re-opened portal for invasion, so of course they must be stopped. Good premise is strangely squandered in this spectacular looking but dramatically flat and unoriginal film. Good cast tries their best, but overlong film never comes close to the 'Star Wars" level of epic storytelling it clearly aspires to.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Almost Twenty Years Later and after Watching at Least Six Times, the Timeless "Stargate" is still a Fantastic Sci-Fi
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Claudio Carvalho
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In 1928, in Egypt, a strange device is found by an expedition. In the present days, the outcast linguist Dr. Daniel Jackson (James Spader) is invited by a mysterious woman to decipher an ancient hieroglyph in a military facility. Soon he finds that the device was developed by an advanced civilization and opens a portal to teletransport to another planet. Dr. Jackson is invited to join a military team under the command of Colonel Jonathan 'Jack' O'Neil (Kurt Russell) that will explore the new world. They find a land that recalls Egypt and humans in a primitive culture that worship and are slaves to Ra, the God of the Sun. But soon they discover the secret of the mysterious "stargate". "Stargate" is still a fantastic sci-fi after almost twenty years and watching it at least six times. The story is intriguing and entwines action with humor and romance. The cast is excellent, with Kurt Russell and James Spade in the top of their careers. The special effects are still great after almost twenty years. And the haunting music score completes this timeless classic sci-fi with a touch of class. My vote is nine. Title (Brazil): "Stargate - A Chave para o Futuro da Humanidade" ("Stargate  The Key for the Future of Mankind")
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nice science-fiction entertainment
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Avid Climber
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Stargate is, as far as I'm concerned, better than the original TV series, which I've watched a couple of time without really getting interested, but then I'm not a fan. The good. Very imaginative settings and alien technology. Beautiful photography. Nicely paced scenario. Interesting story with a solid background. The actors. Kurt Russell is right in his element, and didn't need to show the limits of his short acting range. James Spader is the most interesting character, and plays it well. Mili Avital is pretty, innocent, and plays her sweet role really nicely. Erick Avari, though, is my favorite of the cast and offers us a very convincing performance as the primitive priest-leader faced with powerful strangers. And finally, you can see some of the antics of French Stewart. The bad. Very low army credibility. The intro village miniature is of poor quality. The special effects are getting a bit old, but they were done in such a way as to minimize the aging and still be well received these days. The ugly. That desert beast puppet is just terrible. The chevrons are flimsy. The result. Good entertainment, recommended to sci-fi fans.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Terrific sci-fi adventure
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Progressive-Element
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's had a lot of stick over the years, but Stargate makes for a terrific thrill ride, conveying some of the excitement of Star Wars, Indiana Jones, and Flash Gordon. And perhaps even the John Carter books too. It takes awhile for it to build up, but the set-up is enthralling, a neat spin on the Chariots of the Gods stuff about ancient astronauts and the like. Once Kurt and James are on 'Planet X', they and the team eventually discover humans living a nomadic existence, kept subservient by the sun-god Ra - who turns out to be a powerful despotic alien, but no God. Ra's henchmen too are simply big strong men, who happen to be kitted out with high-tech weapons and equipment. Things take a turn for the worse when Ra shows up, alerted to the activation of the Stargate, and Spader, Kurt and his men eventually find themselves leading a revolt, while at the same time racing against time from stopping Ra sending an explosive present through the Stargate to Earth. Not perfect, a little plodding at times, but fun undemanding entertainment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a classic but not for me, too much talking
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    trashgang
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Having just bought the full stargate collection I had to start with the original one. Having seen it I had my doubts about starting the series. The flick doesn't blow me away. The effects were good and no that much of CGI was used but it was the story itself that wasn't my cup of tea. It starts rather good going back to 8000 years before Christ to see some kind of space ship landing on earth. Flash forward to early 1920's to see the discovery in Egypt of some weird objects. Flash forward to nowadays were Dr. Daniel Jackson(James Spader) is brought in into the army to help solving a two year problem, what are the symbols standing on the objects found in Egypt, in comes Col. Jonathan 'Jack' O'Neil (Kurt Russell with a weird haircut) to solve the problem once they see that the object is some kind of Stargate. Off they go into the stargate to another galaxy and from here things go wrong for me. Here we move away from a science-fiction to a story were the white people are the superiors of the black coloured. They need the whites to help them against the Egyptian looking aliens with a god called Ra. Anyone. In comes also a bit of a love story with Dr. Jackosn. Even when the aliens attack it's a bit low on everything. It's a bit of how humanity started and what went wrong with a lot of blah blah and no action. Still, for some it's a classic that spawned a new flick Children Of The Gods (1997) with a whole new cast which leads to the series for ten years long. As I said, the effects were rather good and luckily the monsters and original alien were not done in CGI but there are better SF's out from that era. Gore 0/5 Nudity 0/5 Effects 3/5 Story 2,5/5 Comedy 0/5
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Absolutely brilliant Sci-Fi.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    domino365
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An excellent movie with great cast, original idea and great story. The Cast. Kurt Russell is great as Jonathan 'Jack' O'Neil. He comes across as a great hero during the action scenes but plays the emotional parts well when they arise. James Spader is great as Dr Daniel Jackson and really comes across as the kind of person you'd expect to be teaching students in a university. His character and Kurt Russell's bump heads a few times and you really believe that they're two really different people. Jackson wants to read every piece of righting, discover every little fossil and meet every local which is a contrast to O'Neil who wants to get on with the mission, shoot first ask questions later and perceive everything as a possible threat. The main cast is back by a stellar supporting cast notable Jaye Davidson as the evil Egyptian god, Ra. The concept. Most mainstream Sci-Fi is set on a spaceship, in the future but this movie takes a completely different direction. The StarGate is a ring with thirty six symbols on it which act as an address to a different planet. It creates a wormhole which instantly transports you to another planet. That is a departure in itself but here's the best part, the main villain is an alien who kidnapped humans from ancient Egypt and brought them to this planet. He took over a young boys body and poses as Ra, the sun god in order to enslave the captured humans. Rather than being set in the future where a big bad alien race tries to invade Earth, there is a heavy focus on the past and takes mythology we know about and says 'what if?' which is a really interesting concept. The story. It's a fairly generic story. It's about a team of special forces commandos who go through the Stargate and find the citizens on the planet are being enslaved by an alien in the body of a boy who is pretending to be the Egyptian sun god, Ra. The team set out to overthrow Ra and get home before they're all killed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    amazing 90s Sci-Fi cult classic that spawned SG1, Atlantis and Universe
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    HelenMary
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Love this film. It's aged well, and is the opener for a massive TV series franchise. Basically, Dr Daniel Jackson (James Spader) is called into a military research station to decipher hieroglyphs and other symbols on a large artifact found at Giza in 1928, which is of course the first Stargate and was built by the alien civilisation that created the Ancient Egyptian way of life here on Earth, which have since gone on another planet, where our intrepid explorers go and find a similar civilisation to what the Egyptians might have been two thousand plus years ago on Earth. Their language is similar enough to what Dr Jackson, an archaeological linguist, can reasonably and not-improbably understand, after a few false starts. The film is of epic proportions set against sweeping sand dune vistas and huge sets, reminiscent of the big studio classics, with hundreds of extras who are real people not painted in later. It has an iconic soundtrack that is almost operatic in places, and the costumes, ancient Egyptian similarities and the special effects are just brilliant even nearly twenty years on, and without the prolific CGI we have today! It is visually very impressive, and original. The script isn't great and is really the only thing that lets the film down a point. It's all a bit rushed and staccato at the beginning - the bit on Earth is the least convincing actually. The film manages some humour as well as having you on the edge of your seat for a climactic finale, which is also a little emotive. James Spader is always a good bet, known most prominently for rather seedy, smutty, awkward or fast talking characters (Oh! How I love Boston Legal), he is superb as the academic PhD here; his calm, measured and quiet delivery are perfect against Kurt Russell's buzz-cut macho all-guns-blazing military man on a mission. Jaye Davidson gives a rather scary performance as Ra ("the Sun god") with control and an almost sexual element and effeminacy but also a violence and temper that are only partially helped by special effects. I really loved the acting - possibly the stand out character - of Alexis Cruz as the smart and brave village boy Skaara who makes first contact and is the plucky comic relief! Erick Avari, the village leader Kasuf, is a familiar face now (but perhaps wasn't so much back in the early 90s as this was his first major film role) as is French Stewart, one of the soldiers (3rd Rock from the Sun) and also Djimon Hounsou in an early in his acting career small though perfectly formed role as Horus. A brilliant film, well worth watching for sci-fi, Egyptian, alien, anthropology, archaeology, action adventure interests. It is worth noting that the beginning of the film is in German with subtitles and your DVD language and subtitle options aren't playing up (I stupidly forgot that last time I watched as it had been such a long time since I'd seen it), and also there are subtitles for the plot-important Egyptian dialect conversations too.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fairly typical
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Leofwine_draca
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    STARGATE should be the perfect movie for me: an interesting premise, grounded in real-life theory (I've been reading Graham Hancock's FINGERPRINTS OF THE GODS recently, and am familiar with Von Daniken's writings) and made with a high enough budget to do the special effects justice. And watching it, it's hard to fault the production. The performances are pretty good, from Kurt Russell's hard-ass soldier to James Spader's nerdy Egyptologist, and the aforementioned SFX are decent. It's just that the film ends up feeling relatively mundane given the extensive set-up; it all turns into an entirely typical good guys vs. the bad guys type film, with little of the intelligence or thought-provoking questions I was hoping for. I'll lay the blame squarely at the door of Roland Emmerich, who has quite the habit of dumbing down his source material (INDEPENDENCE DAY, GODZILLA, need I go on?). Imagine if this had been made by somebody with more interest in the questions raised instead of the size of the guns!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A bit standard, but a very decent concept to a great movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin-thelordofthefu-48-460297
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well, I just want to say that I had never heard of this film before... until the past summer when I was at summer camp when I watched it on a VHS copy. I also heard that this was made the same year I was born and this was made by the same guy who directed Independence Day, Godzilla, and the later film 2012. I watched it because I wanted to see if it would keep me very interested. It did after my first viewing and I personally like it as much as those who gave it a positive feedback. Sure, some of the characters may be unengaging and the story, despite it's decent concept, does have some plot holes and I would've like to see more of the romance between the two characters. Those flaws didn't really bother me at all and I think that this is Roland Emmerich's best film next to Independence Day and The Patriot. The acting on the whole is pretty good especially Kurt Russell and James Spader who had great chemistry together throughout the film. The directing from Roland Emmerich is pretty good and focused, the pacing moves along very nicely, but would've been fifteen minutes longer at the end of the film. The strongest aspects, however, goes to it's compelling visuals and it's epic music score from David Arnold. The look of the Egyptian world along with some nice costume designs is fabulous. David Arnold's music score doesn't have a sci-fi tone to it, but it does have a memorable tune which gives the movie an epic sweep to it. It also has some good dialog especially it's nice moments with the main character and the villain who is quite menacing. Stargate does have a hokey concept, but I don't understand why some people hated it because I think that this is an interesting film and I simply understood that it got a cult following over the years. It isn't perfect, but it's completely watchable to those who haven't seen it yet. So, in my opinion, this deserves a 4/5.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ancient Astronaut Theorists and Fans are Still Waiting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Ancient Astronaut thesis definitively started in the late 60's with Erich Von Daniken, was matured and intellectualized by Zecharia Sitchin starting in 1976, and is here today in a plethora of TV shows, documentaries and extensions of previous works. It is a fascinating and totally believable subject that has limited, if any big screen incarnations. Thus speaks Stargate. The movie starts off great with the whole thing collapsing under its own weight of misunderstanding the concept and turning it into a good looking but incredibly inept military exercise with dull action scenes and unbelievably uninteresting cultural exchanges. The Alien look is outstanding as are the sets, but it shamelessly uses a deep concept and ridicules its insights. It has no taste for the intellect and the cartoonish presentation of the Marines is clich&eacute;d and dated. There is still a great movie to be made with this subject matter and if it is handled in a respectful manner it could be the biggest brainy blockbuster of all time. Ever since 2001: A Space Odyssey (which had undertones of the theme) fans of the Ancient Astronaut theory have been waiting and one hopes that Hollywood is listening.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Led To The TV Franchise.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Roland Emmerich directed this Sci-Fi action film as Kurt Russell plays Col. Jack O'Neil, who, along with Dr. Daniel Jackson(played by James Spader) lead a team of scientists and military personnel as they explore a time/space portal that was found in Egypt, and has only recently been figured out, unlocking its teleporting ability, and sending them to a desert world where an advanced race of human-like beings still practice ancient Egyptian culture, only with modern technology. They are a warlike people, who want to use the re-opened portal for invasion, so of course they must be stopped. Good premise is strangely squandered in this spectacular looking but dramatically flat and unoriginal film. Good cast tries their best, but overlong film never comes close to the 'Star Wars" level of epic storytelling it clearly aspires to.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Almost Twenty Years Later and after Watching at Least Six Times, the Timeless "Stargate" is still a Fantastic Sci-Fi
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Claudio Carvalho
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In 1928, in Egypt, a strange device is found by an expedition. In the present days, the outcast linguist Dr. Daniel Jackson (James Spader) is invited by a mysterious woman to decipher an ancient hieroglyph in a military facility. Soon he finds that the device was developed by an advanced civilization and opens a portal to teletransport to another planet. Dr. Jackson is invited to join a military team under the command of Colonel Jonathan 'Jack' O'Neil (Kurt Russell) that will explore the new world. They find a land that recalls Egypt and humans in a primitive culture that worship and are slaves to Ra, the God of the Sun. But soon they discover the secret of the mysterious "stargate". "Stargate" is still a fantastic sci-fi after almost twenty years and watching it at least six times. The story is intriguing and entwines action with humor and romance. The cast is excellent, with Kurt Russell and James Spade in the top of their careers. The special effects are still great after almost twenty years. And the haunting music score completes this timeless classic sci-fi with a touch of class. My vote is nine. Title (Brazil): "Stargate - A Chave para o Futuro da Humanidade" ("Stargate  The Key for the Future of Mankind")
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nice science-fiction entertainment
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Avid Climber
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Stargate is, as far as I'm concerned, better than the original TV series, which I've watched a couple of time without really getting interested, but then I'm not a fan. The good. Very imaginative settings and alien technology. Beautiful photography. Nicely paced scenario. Interesting story with a solid background. The actors. Kurt Russell is right in his element, and didn't need to show the limits of his short acting range. James Spader is the most interesting character, and plays it well. Mili Avital is pretty, innocent, and plays her sweet role really nicely. Erick Avari, though, is my favorite of the cast and offers us a very convincing performance as the primitive priest-leader faced with powerful strangers. And finally, you can see some of the antics of French Stewart. The bad. Very low army credibility. The intro village miniature is of poor quality. The special effects are getting a bit old, but they were done in such a way as to minimize the aging and still be well received these days. The ugly. That desert beast puppet is just terrible. The chevrons are flimsy. The result. Good entertainment, recommended to sci-fi fans.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Terrific sci-fi adventure
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Progressive-Element
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's had a lot of stick over the years, but Stargate makes for a terrific thrill ride, conveying some of the excitement of Star Wars, Indiana Jones, and Flash Gordon. And perhaps even the John Carter books too. It takes awhile for it to build up, but the set-up is enthralling, a neat spin on the Chariots of the Gods stuff about ancient astronauts and the like. Once Kurt and James are on 'Planet X', they and the team eventually discover humans living a nomadic existence, kept subservient by the sun-god Ra - who turns out to be a powerful despotic alien, but no God. Ra's henchmen too are simply big strong men, who happen to be kitted out with high-tech weapons and equipment. Things take a turn for the worse when Ra shows up, alerted to the activation of the Stargate, and Spader, Kurt and his men eventually find themselves leading a revolt, while at the same time racing against time from stopping Ra sending an explosive present through the Stargate to Earth. Not perfect, a little plodding at times, but fun undemanding entertainment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a classic but not for me, too much talking
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    trashgang
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Having just bought the full stargate collection I had to start with the original one. Having seen it I had my doubts about starting the series. The flick doesn't blow me away. The effects were good and no that much of CGI was used but it was the story itself that wasn't my cup of tea. It starts rather good going back to 8000 years before Christ to see some kind of space ship landing on earth. Flash forward to early 1920's to see the discovery in Egypt of some weird objects. Flash forward to nowadays were Dr. Daniel Jackson(James Spader) is brought in into the army to help solving a two year problem, what are the symbols standing on the objects found in Egypt, in comes Col. Jonathan 'Jack' O'Neil (Kurt Russell with a weird haircut) to solve the problem once they see that the object is some kind of Stargate. Off they go into the stargate to another galaxy and from here things go wrong for me. Here we move away from a science-fiction to a story were the white people are the superiors of the black coloured. They need the whites to help them against the Egyptian looking aliens with a god called Ra. Anyone. In comes also a bit of a love story with Dr. Jackosn. Even when the aliens attack it's a bit low on everything. It's a bit of how humanity started and what went wrong with a lot of blah blah and no action. Still, for some it's a classic that spawned a new flick Children Of The Gods (1997) with a whole new cast which leads to the series for ten years long. As I said, the effects were rather good and luckily the monsters and original alien were not done in CGI but there are better SF's out from that era. Gore 0/5 Nudity 0/5 Effects 3/5 Story 2,5/5 Comedy 0/5
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Absolutely brilliant Sci-Fi.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    domino365
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An excellent movie with great cast, original idea and great story. The Cast. Kurt Russell is great as Jonathan 'Jack' O'Neil. He comes across as a great hero during the action scenes but plays the emotional parts well when they arise. James Spader is great as Dr Daniel Jackson and really comes across as the kind of person you'd expect to be teaching students in a university. His character and Kurt Russell's bump heads a few times and you really believe that they're two really different people. Jackson wants to read every piece of righting, discover every little fossil and meet every local which is a contrast to O'Neil who wants to get on with the mission, shoot first ask questions later and perceive everything as a possible threat. The main cast is back by a stellar supporting cast notable Jaye Davidson as the evil Egyptian god, Ra. The concept. Most mainstream Sci-Fi is set on a spaceship, in the future but this movie takes a completely different direction. The StarGate is a ring with thirty six symbols on it which act as an address to a different planet. It creates a wormhole which instantly transports you to another planet. That is a departure in itself but here's the best part, the main villain is an alien who kidnapped humans from ancient Egypt and brought them to this planet. He took over a young boys body and poses as Ra, the sun god in order to enslave the captured humans. Rather than being set in the future where a big bad alien race tries to invade Earth, there is a heavy focus on the past and takes mythology we know about and says 'what if?' which is a really interesting concept. The story. It's a fairly generic story. It's about a team of special forces commandos who go through the Stargate and find the citizens on the planet are being enslaved by an alien in the body of a boy who is pretending to be the Egyptian sun god, Ra. The team set out to overthrow Ra and get home before they're all killed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    amazing 90s Sci-Fi cult classic that spawned SG1, Atlantis and Universe
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    HelenMary
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Love this film. It's aged well, and is the opener for a massive TV series franchise. Basically, Dr Daniel Jackson (James Spader) is called into a military research station to decipher hieroglyphs and other symbols on a large artifact found at Giza in 1928, which is of course the first Stargate and was built by the alien civilisation that created the Ancient Egyptian way of life here on Earth, which have since gone on another planet, where our intrepid explorers go and find a similar civilisation to what the Egyptians might have been two thousand plus years ago on Earth. Their language is similar enough to what Dr Jackson, an archaeological linguist, can reasonably and not-improbably understand, after a few false starts. The film is of epic proportions set against sweeping sand dune vistas and huge sets, reminiscent of the big studio classics, with hundreds of extras who are real people not painted in later. It has an iconic soundtrack that is almost operatic in places, and the costumes, ancient Egyptian similarities and the special effects are just brilliant even nearly twenty years on, and without the prolific CGI we have today! It is visually very impressive, and original. The script isn't great and is really the only thing that lets the film down a point. It's all a bit rushed and staccato at the beginning - the bit on Earth is the least convincing actually. The film manages some humour as well as having you on the edge of your seat for a climactic finale, which is also a little emotive. James Spader is always a good bet, known most prominently for rather seedy, smutty, awkward or fast talking characters (Oh! How I love Boston Legal), he is superb as the academic PhD here; his calm, measured and quiet delivery are perfect against Kurt Russell's buzz-cut macho all-guns-blazing military man on a mission. Jaye Davidson gives a rather scary performance as Ra ("the Sun god") with control and an almost sexual element and effeminacy but also a violence and temper that are only partially helped by special effects. I really loved the acting - possibly the stand out character - of Alexis Cruz as the smart and brave village boy Skaara who makes first contact and is the plucky comic relief! Erick Avari, the village leader Kasuf, is a familiar face now (but perhaps wasn't so much back in the early 90s as this was his first major film role) as is French Stewart, one of the soldiers (3rd Rock from the Sun) and also Djimon Hounsou in an early in his acting career small though perfectly formed role as Horus. A brilliant film, well worth watching for sci-fi, Egyptian, alien, anthropology, archaeology, action adventure interests. It is worth noting that the beginning of the film is in German with subtitles and your DVD language and subtitle options aren't playing up (I stupidly forgot that last time I watched as it had been such a long time since I'd seen it), and also there are subtitles for the plot-important Egyptian dialect conversations too.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fairly typical
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Leofwine_draca
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    STARGATE should be the perfect movie for me: an interesting premise, grounded in real-life theory (I've been reading Graham Hancock's FINGERPRINTS OF THE GODS recently, and am familiar with Von Daniken's writings) and made with a high enough budget to do the special effects justice. And watching it, it's hard to fault the production. The performances are pretty good, from Kurt Russell's hard-ass soldier to James Spader's nerdy Egyptologist, and the aforementioned SFX are decent. It's just that the film ends up feeling relatively mundane given the extensive set-up; it all turns into an entirely typical good guys vs. the bad guys type film, with little of the intelligence or thought-provoking questions I was hoping for. I'll lay the blame squarely at the door of Roland Emmerich, who has quite the habit of dumbing down his source material (INDEPENDENCE DAY, GODZILLA, need I go on?). Imagine if this had been made by somebody with more interest in the questions raised instead of the size of the guns!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A bit standard, but a very decent concept to a great movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin-thelordofthefu-48-460297
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well, I just want to say that I had never heard of this film before... until the past summer when I was at summer camp when I watched it on a VHS copy. I also heard that this was made the same year I was born and this was made by the same guy who directed Independence Day, Godzilla, and the later film 2012. I watched it because I wanted to see if it would keep me very interested. It did after my first viewing and I personally like it as much as those who gave it a positive feedback. Sure, some of the characters may be unengaging and the story, despite it's decent concept, does have some plot holes and I would've like to see more of the romance between the two characters. Those flaws didn't really bother me at all and I think that this is Roland Emmerich's best film next to Independence Day and The Patriot. The acting on the whole is pretty good especially Kurt Russell and James Spader who had great chemistry together throughout the film. The directing from Roland Emmerich is pretty good and focused, the pacing moves along very nicely, but would've been fifteen minutes longer at the end of the film. The strongest aspects, however, goes to it's compelling visuals and it's epic music score from David Arnold. The look of the Egyptian world along with some nice costume designs is fabulous. David Arnold's music score doesn't have a sci-fi tone to it, but it does have a memorable tune which gives the movie an epic sweep to it. It also has some good dialog especially it's nice moments with the main character and the villain who is quite menacing. Stargate does have a hokey concept, but I don't understand why some people hated it because I think that this is an interesting film and I simply understood that it got a cult following over the years. It isn't perfect, but it's completely watchable to those who haven't seen it yet. So, in my opinion, this deserves a 4/5.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ancient Astronaut Theorists and Fans are Still Waiting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Ancient Astronaut thesis definitively started in the late 60's with Erich Von Daniken, was matured and intellectualized by Zecharia Sitchin starting in 1976, and is here today in a plethora of TV shows, documentaries and extensions of previous works. It is a fascinating and totally believable subject that has limited, if any big screen incarnations. Thus speaks Stargate. The movie starts off great with the whole thing collapsing under its own weight of misunderstanding the concept and turning it into a good looking but incredibly inept military exercise with dull action scenes and unbelievably uninteresting cultural exchanges. The Alien look is outstanding as are the sets, but it shamelessly uses a deep concept and ridicules its insights. It has no taste for the intellect and the cartoonish presentation of the Marines is clich&eacute;d and dated. There is still a great movie to be made with this subject matter and if it is handled in a respectful manner it could be the biggest brainy blockbuster of all time. Ever since 2001: A Space Odyssey (which had undertones of the theme) fans of the Ancient Astronaut theory have been waiting and one hopes that Hollywood is listening.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Led To The TV Franchise.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Roland Emmerich directed this Sci-Fi action film as Kurt Russell plays Col. Jack O'Neil, who, along with Dr. Daniel Jackson(played by James Spader) lead a team of scientists and military personnel as they explore a time/space portal that was found in Egypt, and has only recently been figured out, unlocking its teleporting ability, and sending them to a desert world where an advanced race of human-like beings still practice ancient Egyptian culture, only with modern technology. They are a warlike people, who want to use the re-opened portal for invasion, so of course they must be stopped. Good premise is strangely squandered in this spectacular looking but dramatically flat and unoriginal film. Good cast tries their best, but overlong film never comes close to the 'Star Wars" level of epic storytelling it clearly aspires to.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Almost Twenty Years Later and after Watching at Least Six Times, the Timeless "Stargate" is still a Fantastic Sci-Fi
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Claudio Carvalho
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In 1928, in Egypt, a strange device is found by an expedition. In the present days, the outcast linguist Dr. Daniel Jackson (James Spader) is invited by a mysterious woman to decipher an ancient hieroglyph in a military facility. Soon he finds that the device was developed by an advanced civilization and opens a portal to teletransport to another planet. Dr. Jackson is invited to join a military team under the command of Colonel Jonathan 'Jack' O'Neil (Kurt Russell) that will explore the new world. They find a land that recalls Egypt and humans in a primitive culture that worship and are slaves to Ra, the God of the Sun. But soon they discover the secret of the mysterious "stargate". "Stargate" is still a fantastic sci-fi after almost twenty years and watching it at least six times. The story is intriguing and entwines action with humor and romance. The cast is excellent, with Kurt Russell and James Spade in the top of their careers. The special effects are still great after almost twenty years. And the haunting music score completes this timeless classic sci-fi with a touch of class. My vote is nine. Title (Brazil): "Stargate - A Chave para o Futuro da Humanidade" ("Stargate  The Key for the Future of Mankind")
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nice science-fiction entertainment
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Avid Climber
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Stargate is, as far as I'm concerned, better than the original TV series, which I've watched a couple of time without really getting interested, but then I'm not a fan. The good. Very imaginative settings and alien technology. Beautiful photography. Nicely paced scenario. Interesting story with a solid background. The actors. Kurt Russell is right in his element, and didn't need to show the limits of his short acting range. James Spader is the most interesting character, and plays it well. Mili Avital is pretty, innocent, and plays her sweet role really nicely. Erick Avari, though, is my favorite of the cast and offers us a very convincing performance as the primitive priest-leader faced with powerful strangers. And finally, you can see some of the antics of French Stewart. The bad. Very low army credibility. The intro village miniature is of poor quality. The special effects are getting a bit old, but they were done in such a way as to minimize the aging and still be well received these days. The ugly. That desert beast puppet is just terrible. The chevrons are flimsy. The result. Good entertainment, recommended to sci-fi fans.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Terrific sci-fi adventure
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Progressive-Element
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's had a lot of stick over the years, but Stargate makes for a terrific thrill ride, conveying some of the excitement of Star Wars, Indiana Jones, and Flash Gordon. And perhaps even the John Carter books too. It takes awhile for it to build up, but the set-up is enthralling, a neat spin on the Chariots of the Gods stuff about ancient astronauts and the like. Once Kurt and James are on 'Planet X', they and the team eventually discover humans living a nomadic existence, kept subservient by the sun-god Ra - who turns out to be a powerful despotic alien, but no God. Ra's henchmen too are simply big strong men, who happen to be kitted out with high-tech weapons and equipment. Things take a turn for the worse when Ra shows up, alerted to the activation of the Stargate, and Spader, Kurt and his men eventually find themselves leading a revolt, while at the same time racing against time from stopping Ra sending an explosive present through the Stargate to Earth. Not perfect, a little plodding at times, but fun undemanding entertainment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a classic but not for me, too much talking
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    trashgang
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Having just bought the full stargate collection I had to start with the original one. Having seen it I had my doubts about starting the series. The flick doesn't blow me away. The effects were good and no that much of CGI was used but it was the story itself that wasn't my cup of tea. It starts rather good going back to 8000 years before Christ to see some kind of space ship landing on earth. Flash forward to early 1920's to see the discovery in Egypt of some weird objects. Flash forward to nowadays were Dr. Daniel Jackson(James Spader) is brought in into the army to help solving a two year problem, what are the symbols standing on the objects found in Egypt, in comes Col. Jonathan 'Jack' O'Neil (Kurt Russell with a weird haircut) to solve the problem once they see that the object is some kind of Stargate. Off they go into the stargate to another galaxy and from here things go wrong for me. Here we move away from a science-fiction to a story were the white people are the superiors of the black coloured. They need the whites to help them against the Egyptian looking aliens with a god called Ra. Anyone. In comes also a bit of a love story with Dr. Jackosn. Even when the aliens attack it's a bit low on everything. It's a bit of how humanity started and what went wrong with a lot of blah blah and no action. Still, for some it's a classic that spawned a new flick Children Of The Gods (1997) with a whole new cast which leads to the series for ten years long. As I said, the effects were rather good and luckily the monsters and original alien were not done in CGI but there are better SF's out from that era. Gore 0/5 Nudity 0/5 Effects 3/5 Story 2,5/5 Comedy 0/5
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Absolutely brilliant Sci-Fi.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    domino365
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An excellent movie with great cast, original idea and great story. The Cast. Kurt Russell is great as Jonathan 'Jack' O'Neil. He comes across as a great hero during the action scenes but plays the emotional parts well when they arise. James Spader is great as Dr Daniel Jackson and really comes across as the kind of person you'd expect to be teaching students in a university. His character and Kurt Russell's bump heads a few times and you really believe that they're two really different people. Jackson wants to read every piece of righting, discover every little fossil and meet every local which is a contrast to O'Neil who wants to get on with the mission, shoot first ask questions later and perceive everything as a possible threat. The main cast is back by a stellar supporting cast notable Jaye Davidson as the evil Egyptian god, Ra. The concept. Most mainstream Sci-Fi is set on a spaceship, in the future but this movie takes a completely different direction. The StarGate is a ring with thirty six symbols on it which act as an address to a different planet. It creates a wormhole which instantly transports you to another planet. That is a departure in itself but here's the best part, the main villain is an alien who kidnapped humans from ancient Egypt and brought them to this planet. He took over a young boys body and poses as Ra, the sun god in order to enslave the captured humans. Rather than being set in the future where a big bad alien race tries to invade Earth, there is a heavy focus on the past and takes mythology we know about and says 'what if?' which is a really interesting concept. The story. It's a fairly generic story. It's about a team of special forces commandos who go through the Stargate and find the citizens on the planet are being enslaved by an alien in the body of a boy who is pretending to be the Egyptian sun god, Ra. The team set out to overthrow Ra and get home before they're all killed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    amazing 90s Sci-Fi cult classic that spawned SG1, Atlantis and Universe
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    HelenMary
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Love this film. It's aged well, and is the opener for a massive TV series franchise. Basically, Dr Daniel Jackson (James Spader) is called into a military research station to decipher hieroglyphs and other symbols on a large artifact found at Giza in 1928, which is of course the first Stargate and was built by the alien civilisation that created the Ancient Egyptian way of life here on Earth, which have since gone on another planet, where our intrepid explorers go and find a similar civilisation to what the Egyptians might have been two thousand plus years ago on Earth. Their language is similar enough to what Dr Jackson, an archaeological linguist, can reasonably and not-improbably understand, after a few false starts. The film is of epic proportions set against sweeping sand dune vistas and huge sets, reminiscent of the big studio classics, with hundreds of extras who are real people not painted in later. It has an iconic soundtrack that is almost operatic in places, and the costumes, ancient Egyptian similarities and the special effects are just brilliant even nearly twenty years on, and without the prolific CGI we have today! It is visually very impressive, and original. The script isn't great and is really the only thing that lets the film down a point. It's all a bit rushed and staccato at the beginning - the bit on Earth is the least convincing actually. The film manages some humour as well as having you on the edge of your seat for a climactic finale, which is also a little emotive. James Spader is always a good bet, known most prominently for rather seedy, smutty, awkward or fast talking characters (Oh! How I love Boston Legal), he is superb as the academic PhD here; his calm, measured and quiet delivery are perfect against Kurt Russell's buzz-cut macho all-guns-blazing military man on a mission. Jaye Davidson gives a rather scary performance as Ra ("the Sun god") with control and an almost sexual element and effeminacy but also a violence and temper that are only partially helped by special effects. I really loved the acting - possibly the stand out character - of Alexis Cruz as the smart and brave village boy Skaara who makes first contact and is the plucky comic relief! Erick Avari, the village leader Kasuf, is a familiar face now (but perhaps wasn't so much back in the early 90s as this was his first major film role) as is French Stewart, one of the soldiers (3rd Rock from the Sun) and also Djimon Hounsou in an early in his acting career small though perfectly formed role as Horus. A brilliant film, well worth watching for sci-fi, Egyptian, alien, anthropology, archaeology, action adventure interests. It is worth noting that the beginning of the film is in German with subtitles and your DVD language and subtitle options aren't playing up (I stupidly forgot that last time I watched as it had been such a long time since I'd seen it), and also there are subtitles for the plot-important Egyptian dialect conversations too.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fairly typical
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Leofwine_draca
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    STARGATE should be the perfect movie for me: an interesting premise, grounded in real-life theory (I've been reading Graham Hancock's FINGERPRINTS OF THE GODS recently, and am familiar with Von Daniken's writings) and made with a high enough budget to do the special effects justice. And watching it, it's hard to fault the production. The performances are pretty good, from Kurt Russell's hard-ass soldier to James Spader's nerdy Egyptologist, and the aforementioned SFX are decent. It's just that the film ends up feeling relatively mundane given the extensive set-up; it all turns into an entirely typical good guys vs. the bad guys type film, with little of the intelligence or thought-provoking questions I was hoping for. I'll lay the blame squarely at the door of Roland Emmerich, who has quite the habit of dumbing down his source material (INDEPENDENCE DAY, GODZILLA, need I go on?). Imagine if this had been made by somebody with more interest in the questions raised instead of the size of the guns!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A bit standard, but a very decent concept to a great movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin-thelordofthefu-48-460297
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well, I just want to say that I had never heard of this film before... until the past summer when I was at summer camp when I watched it on a VHS copy. I also heard that this was made the same year I was born and this was made by the same guy who directed Independence Day, Godzilla, and the later film 2012. I watched it because I wanted to see if it would keep me very interested. It did after my first viewing and I personally like it as much as those who gave it a positive feedback. Sure, some of the characters may be unengaging and the story, despite it's decent concept, does have some plot holes and I would've like to see more of the romance between the two characters. Those flaws didn't really bother me at all and I think that this is Roland Emmerich's best film next to Independence Day and The Patriot. The acting on the whole is pretty good especially Kurt Russell and James Spader who had great chemistry together throughout the film. The directing from Roland Emmerich is pretty good and focused, the pacing moves along very nicely, but would've been fifteen minutes longer at the end of the film. The strongest aspects, however, goes to it's compelling visuals and it's epic music score from David Arnold. The look of the Egyptian world along with some nice costume designs is fabulous. David Arnold's music score doesn't have a sci-fi tone to it, but it does have a memorable tune which gives the movie an epic sweep to it. It also has some good dialog especially it's nice moments with the main character and the villain who is quite menacing. Stargate does have a hokey concept, but I don't understand why some people hated it because I think that this is an interesting film and I simply understood that it got a cult following over the years. It isn't perfect, but it's completely watchable to those who haven't seen it yet. So, in my opinion, this deserves a 4/5.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ancient Astronaut Theorists and Fans are Still Waiting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Ancient Astronaut thesis definitively started in the late 60's with Erich Von Daniken, was matured and intellectualized by Zecharia Sitchin starting in 1976, and is here today in a plethora of TV shows, documentaries and extensions of previous works. It is a fascinating and totally believable subject that has limited, if any big screen incarnations. Thus speaks Stargate. The movie starts off great with the whole thing collapsing under its own weight of misunderstanding the concept and turning it into a good looking but incredibly inept military exercise with dull action scenes and unbelievably uninteresting cultural exchanges. The Alien look is outstanding as are the sets, but it shamelessly uses a deep concept and ridicules its insights. It has no taste for the intellect and the cartoonish presentation of the Marines is clich&eacute;d and dated. There is still a great movie to be made with this subject matter and if it is handled in a respectful manner it could be the biggest brainy blockbuster of all time. Ever since 2001: A Space Odyssey (which had undertones of the theme) fans of the Ancient Astronaut theory have been waiting and one hopes that Hollywood is listening.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Led To The TV Franchise.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Roland Emmerich directed this Sci-Fi action film as Kurt Russell plays Col. Jack O'Neil, who, along with Dr. Daniel Jackson(played by James Spader) lead a team of scientists and military personnel as they explore a time/space portal that was found in Egypt, and has only recently been figured out, unlocking its teleporting ability, and sending them to a desert world where an advanced race of human-like beings still practice ancient Egyptian culture, only with modern technology. They are a warlike people, who want to use the re-opened portal for invasion, so of course they must be stopped. Good premise is strangely squandered in this spectacular looking but dramatically flat and unoriginal film. Good cast tries their best, but overlong film never comes close to the 'Star Wars" level of epic storytelling it clearly aspires to.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Almost Twenty Years Later and after Watching at Least Six Times, the Timeless "Stargate" is still a Fantastic Sci-Fi
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Claudio Carvalho
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In 1928, in Egypt, a strange device is found by an expedition. In the present days, the outcast linguist Dr. Daniel Jackson (James Spader) is invited by a mysterious woman to decipher an ancient hieroglyph in a military facility. Soon he finds that the device was developed by an advanced civilization and opens a portal to teletransport to another planet. Dr. Jackson is invited to join a military team under the command of Colonel Jonathan 'Jack' O'Neil (Kurt Russell) that will explore the new world. They find a land that recalls Egypt and humans in a primitive culture that worship and are slaves to Ra, the God of the Sun. But soon they discover the secret of the mysterious "stargate". "Stargate" is still a fantastic sci-fi after almost twenty years and watching it at least six times. The story is intriguing and entwines action with humor and romance. The cast is excellent, with Kurt Russell and James Spade in the top of their careers. The special effects are still great after almost twenty years. And the haunting music score completes this timeless classic sci-fi with a touch of class. My vote is nine. Title (Brazil): "Stargate - A Chave para o Futuro da Humanidade" ("Stargate  The Key for the Future of Mankind")
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nice science-fiction entertainment
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Avid Climber
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Stargate is, as far as I'm concerned, better than the original TV series, which I've watched a couple of time without really getting interested, but then I'm not a fan. The good. Very imaginative settings and alien technology. Beautiful photography. Nicely paced scenario. Interesting story with a solid background. The actors. Kurt Russell is right in his element, and didn't need to show the limits of his short acting range. James Spader is the most interesting character, and plays it well. Mili Avital is pretty, innocent, and plays her sweet role really nicely. Erick Avari, though, is my favorite of the cast and offers us a very convincing performance as the primitive priest-leader faced with powerful strangers. And finally, you can see some of the antics of French Stewart. The bad. Very low army credibility. The intro village miniature is of poor quality. The special effects are getting a bit old, but they were done in such a way as to minimize the aging and still be well received these days. The ugly. That desert beast puppet is just terrible. The chevrons are flimsy. The result. Good entertainment, recommended to sci-fi fans.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Terrific sci-fi adventure
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Progressive-Element
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's had a lot of stick over the years, but Stargate makes for a terrific thrill ride, conveying some of the excitement of Star Wars, Indiana Jones, and Flash Gordon. And perhaps even the John Carter books too. It takes awhile for it to build up, but the set-up is enthralling, a neat spin on the Chariots of the Gods stuff about ancient astronauts and the like. Once Kurt and James are on 'Planet X', they and the team eventually discover humans living a nomadic existence, kept subservient by the sun-god Ra - who turns out to be a powerful despotic alien, but no God. Ra's henchmen too are simply big strong men, who happen to be kitted out with high-tech weapons and equipment. Things take a turn for the worse when Ra shows up, alerted to the activation of the Stargate, and Spader, Kurt and his men eventually find themselves leading a revolt, while at the same time racing against time from stopping Ra sending an explosive present through the Stargate to Earth. Not perfect, a little plodding at times, but fun undemanding entertainment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a classic but not for me, too much talking
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    trashgang
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Having just bought the full stargate collection I had to start with the original one. Having seen it I had my doubts about starting the series. The flick doesn't blow me away. The effects were good and no that much of CGI was used but it was the story itself that wasn't my cup of tea. It starts rather good going back to 8000 years before Christ to see some kind of space ship landing on earth. Flash forward to early 1920's to see the discovery in Egypt of some weird objects. Flash forward to nowadays were Dr. Daniel Jackson(James Spader) is brought in into the army to help solving a two year problem, what are the symbols standing on the objects found in Egypt, in comes Col. Jonathan 'Jack' O'Neil (Kurt Russell with a weird haircut) to solve the problem once they see that the object is some kind of Stargate. Off they go into the stargate to another galaxy and from here things go wrong for me. Here we move away from a science-fiction to a story were the white people are the superiors of the black coloured. They need the whites to help them against the Egyptian looking aliens with a god called Ra. Anyone. In comes also a bit of a love story with Dr. Jackosn. Even when the aliens attack it's a bit low on everything. It's a bit of how humanity started and what went wrong with a lot of blah blah and no action. Still, for some it's a classic that spawned a new flick Children Of The Gods (1997) with a whole new cast which leads to the series for ten years long. As I said, the effects were rather good and luckily the monsters and original alien were not done in CGI but there are better SF's out from that era. Gore 0/5 Nudity 0/5 Effects 3/5 Story 2,5/5 Comedy 0/5
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Absolutely brilliant Sci-Fi.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    domino365
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An excellent movie with great cast, original idea and great story. The Cast. Kurt Russell is great as Jonathan 'Jack' O'Neil. He comes across as a great hero during the action scenes but plays the emotional parts well when they arise. James Spader is great as Dr Daniel Jackson and really comes across as the kind of person you'd expect to be teaching students in a university. His character and Kurt Russell's bump heads a few times and you really believe that they're two really different people. Jackson wants to read every piece of righting, discover every little fossil and meet every local which is a contrast to O'Neil who wants to get on with the mission, shoot first ask questions later and perceive everything as a possible threat. The main cast is back by a stellar supporting cast notable Jaye Davidson as the evil Egyptian god, Ra. The concept. Most mainstream Sci-Fi is set on a spaceship, in the future but this movie takes a completely different direction. The StarGate is a ring with thirty six symbols on it which act as an address to a different planet. It creates a wormhole which instantly transports you to another planet. That is a departure in itself but here's the best part, the main villain is an alien who kidnapped humans from ancient Egypt and brought them to this planet. He took over a young boys body and poses as Ra, the sun god in order to enslave the captured humans. Rather than being set in the future where a big bad alien race tries to invade Earth, there is a heavy focus on the past and takes mythology we know about and says 'what if?' which is a really interesting concept. The story. It's a fairly generic story. It's about a team of special forces commandos who go through the Stargate and find the citizens on the planet are being enslaved by an alien in the body of a boy who is pretending to be the Egyptian sun god, Ra. The team set out to overthrow Ra and get home before they're all killed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    amazing 90s Sci-Fi cult classic that spawned SG1, Atlantis and Universe
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    HelenMary
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Love this film. It's aged well, and is the opener for a massive TV series franchise. Basically, Dr Daniel Jackson (James Spader) is called into a military research station to decipher hieroglyphs and other symbols on a large artifact found at Giza in 1928, which is of course the first Stargate and was built by the alien civilisation that created the Ancient Egyptian way of life here on Earth, which have since gone on another planet, where our intrepid explorers go and find a similar civilisation to what the Egyptians might have been two thousand plus years ago on Earth. Their language is similar enough to what Dr Jackson, an archaeological linguist, can reasonably and not-improbably understand, after a few false starts. The film is of epic proportions set against sweeping sand dune vistas and huge sets, reminiscent of the big studio classics, with hundreds of extras who are real people not painted in later. It has an iconic soundtrack that is almost operatic in places, and the costumes, ancient Egyptian similarities and the special effects are just brilliant even nearly twenty years on, and without the prolific CGI we have today! It is visually very impressive, and original. The script isn't great and is really the only thing that lets the film down a point. It's all a bit rushed and staccato at the beginning - the bit on Earth is the least convincing actually. The film manages some humour as well as having you on the edge of your seat for a climactic finale, which is also a little emotive. James Spader is always a good bet, known most prominently for rather seedy, smutty, awkward or fast talking characters (Oh! How I love Boston Legal), he is superb as the academic PhD here; his calm, measured and quiet delivery are perfect against Kurt Russell's buzz-cut macho all-guns-blazing military man on a mission. Jaye Davidson gives a rather scary performance as Ra ("the Sun god") with control and an almost sexual element and effeminacy but also a violence and temper that are only partially helped by special effects. I really loved the acting - possibly the stand out character - of Alexis Cruz as the smart and brave village boy Skaara who makes first contact and is the plucky comic relief! Erick Avari, the village leader Kasuf, is a familiar face now (but perhaps wasn't so much back in the early 90s as this was his first major film role) as is French Stewart, one of the soldiers (3rd Rock from the Sun) and also Djimon Hounsou in an early in his acting career small though perfectly formed role as Horus. A brilliant film, well worth watching for sci-fi, Egyptian, alien, anthropology, archaeology, action adventure interests. It is worth noting that the beginning of the film is in German with subtitles and your DVD language and subtitle options aren't playing up (I stupidly forgot that last time I watched as it had been such a long time since I'd seen it), and also there are subtitles for the plot-important Egyptian dialect conversations too.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fairly typical
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Leofwine_draca
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    STARGATE should be the perfect movie for me: an interesting premise, grounded in real-life theory (I've been reading Graham Hancock's FINGERPRINTS OF THE GODS recently, and am familiar with Von Daniken's writings) and made with a high enough budget to do the special effects justice. And watching it, it's hard to fault the production. The performances are pretty good, from Kurt Russell's hard-ass soldier to James Spader's nerdy Egyptologist, and the aforementioned SFX are decent. It's just that the film ends up feeling relatively mundane given the extensive set-up; it all turns into an entirely typical good guys vs. the bad guys type film, with little of the intelligence or thought-provoking questions I was hoping for. I'll lay the blame squarely at the door of Roland Emmerich, who has quite the habit of dumbing down his source material (INDEPENDENCE DAY, GODZILLA, need I go on?). Imagine if this had been made by somebody with more interest in the questions raised instead of the size of the guns!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A bit standard, but a very decent concept to a great movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin-thelordofthefu-48-460297
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well, I just want to say that I had never heard of this film before... until the past summer when I was at summer camp when I watched it on a VHS copy. I also heard that this was made the same year I was born and this was made by the same guy who directed Independence Day, Godzilla, and the later film 2012. I watched it because I wanted to see if it would keep me very interested. It did after my first viewing and I personally like it as much as those who gave it a positive feedback. Sure, some of the characters may be unengaging and the story, despite it's decent concept, does have some plot holes and I would've like to see more of the romance between the two characters. Those flaws didn't really bother me at all and I think that this is Roland Emmerich's best film next to Independence Day and The Patriot. The acting on the whole is pretty good especially Kurt Russell and James Spader who had great chemistry together throughout the film. The directing from Roland Emmerich is pretty good and focused, the pacing moves along very nicely, but would've been fifteen minutes longer at the end of the film. The strongest aspects, however, goes to it's compelling visuals and it's epic music score from David Arnold. The look of the Egyptian world along with some nice costume designs is fabulous. David Arnold's music score doesn't have a sci-fi tone to it, but it does have a memorable tune which gives the movie an epic sweep to it. It also has some good dialog especially it's nice moments with the main character and the villain who is quite menacing. Stargate does have a hokey concept, but I don't understand why some people hated it because I think that this is an interesting film and I simply understood that it got a cult following over the years. It isn't perfect, but it's completely watchable to those who haven't seen it yet. So, in my opinion, this deserves a 4/5.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ancient Astronaut Theorists and Fans are Still Waiting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Ancient Astronaut thesis definitively started in the late 60's with Erich Von Daniken, was matured and intellectualized by Zecharia Sitchin starting in 1976, and is here today in a plethora of TV shows, documentaries and extensions of previous works. It is a fascinating and totally believable subject that has limited, if any big screen incarnations. Thus speaks Stargate. The movie starts off great with the whole thing collapsing under its own weight of misunderstanding the concept and turning it into a good looking but incredibly inept military exercise with dull action scenes and unbelievably uninteresting cultural exchanges. The Alien look is outstanding as are the sets, but it shamelessly uses a deep concept and ridicules its insights. It has no taste for the intellect and the cartoonish presentation of the Marines is clich&eacute;d and dated. There is still a great movie to be made with this subject matter and if it is handled in a respectful manner it could be the biggest brainy blockbuster of all time. Ever since 2001: A Space Odyssey (which had undertones of the theme) fans of the Ancient Astronaut theory have been waiting and one hopes that Hollywood is listening.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Led To The TV Franchise.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Roland Emmerich directed this Sci-Fi action film as Kurt Russell plays Col. Jack O'Neil, who, along with Dr. Daniel Jackson(played by James Spader) lead a team of scientists and military personnel as they explore a time/space portal that was found in Egypt, and has only recently been figured out, unlocking its teleporting ability, and sending them to a desert world where an advanced race of human-like beings still practice ancient Egyptian culture, only with modern technology. They are a warlike people, who want to use the re-opened portal for invasion, so of course they must be stopped. Good premise is strangely squandered in this spectacular looking but dramatically flat and unoriginal film. Good cast tries their best, but overlong film never comes close to the 'Star Wars" level of epic storytelling it clearly aspires to.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Almost Twenty Years Later and after Watching at Least Six Times, the Timeless "Stargate" is still a Fantastic Sci-Fi
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Claudio Carvalho
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In 1928, in Egypt, a strange device is found by an expedition. In the present days, the outcast linguist Dr. Daniel Jackson (James Spader) is invited by a mysterious woman to decipher an ancient hieroglyph in a military facility. Soon he finds that the device was developed by an advanced civilization and opens a portal to teletransport to another planet. Dr. Jackson is invited to join a military team under the command of Colonel Jonathan 'Jack' O'Neil (Kurt Russell) that will explore the new world. They find a land that recalls Egypt and humans in a primitive culture that worship and are slaves to Ra, the God of the Sun. But soon they discover the secret of the mysterious "stargate". "Stargate" is still a fantastic sci-fi after almost twenty years and watching it at least six times. The story is intriguing and entwines action with humor and romance. The cast is excellent, with Kurt Russell and James Spade in the top of their careers. The special effects are still great after almost twenty years. And the haunting music score completes this timeless classic sci-fi with a touch of class. My vote is nine. Title (Brazil): "Stargate - A Chave para o Futuro da Humanidade" ("Stargate  The Key for the Future of Mankind")
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nice science-fiction entertainment
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Avid Climber
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Stargate is, as far as I'm concerned, better than the original TV series, which I've watched a couple of time without really getting interested, but then I'm not a fan. The good. Very imaginative settings and alien technology. Beautiful photography. Nicely paced scenario. Interesting story with a solid background. The actors. Kurt Russell is right in his element, and didn't need to show the limits of his short acting range. James Spader is the most interesting character, and plays it well. Mili Avital is pretty, innocent, and plays her sweet role really nicely. Erick Avari, though, is my favorite of the cast and offers us a very convincing performance as the primitive priest-leader faced with powerful strangers. And finally, you can see some of the antics of French Stewart. The bad. Very low army credibility. The intro village miniature is of poor quality. The special effects are getting a bit old, but they were done in such a way as to minimize the aging and still be well received these days. The ugly. That desert beast puppet is just terrible. The chevrons are flimsy. The result. Good entertainment, recommended to sci-fi fans.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Terrific sci-fi adventure
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Progressive-Element
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's had a lot of stick over the years, but Stargate makes for a terrific thrill ride, conveying some of the excitement of Star Wars, Indiana Jones, and Flash Gordon. And perhaps even the John Carter books too. It takes awhile for it to build up, but the set-up is enthralling, a neat spin on the Chariots of the Gods stuff about ancient astronauts and the like. Once Kurt and James are on 'Planet X', they and the team eventually discover humans living a nomadic existence, kept subservient by the sun-god Ra - who turns out to be a powerful despotic alien, but no God. Ra's henchmen too are simply big strong men, who happen to be kitted out with high-tech weapons and equipment. Things take a turn for the worse when Ra shows up, alerted to the activation of the Stargate, and Spader, Kurt and his men eventually find themselves leading a revolt, while at the same time racing against time from stopping Ra sending an explosive present through the Stargate to Earth. Not perfect, a little plodding at times, but fun undemanding entertainment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a classic but not for me, too much talking
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    trashgang
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Having just bought the full stargate collection I had to start with the original one. Having seen it I had my doubts about starting the series. The flick doesn't blow me away. The effects were good and no that much of CGI was used but it was the story itself that wasn't my cup of tea. It starts rather good going back to 8000 years before Christ to see some kind of space ship landing on earth. Flash forward to early 1920's to see the discovery in Egypt of some weird objects. Flash forward to nowadays were Dr. Daniel Jackson(James Spader) is brought in into the army to help solving a two year problem, what are the symbols standing on the objects found in Egypt, in comes Col. Jonathan 'Jack' O'Neil (Kurt Russell with a weird haircut) to solve the problem once they see that the object is some kind of Stargate. Off they go into the stargate to another galaxy and from here things go wrong for me. Here we move away from a science-fiction to a story were the white people are the superiors of the black coloured. They need the whites to help them against the Egyptian looking aliens with a god called Ra. Anyone. In comes also a bit of a love story with Dr. Jackosn. Even when the aliens attack it's a bit low on everything. It's a bit of how humanity started and what went wrong with a lot of blah blah and no action. Still, for some it's a classic that spawned a new flick Children Of The Gods (1997) with a whole new cast which leads to the series for ten years long. As I said, the effects were rather good and luckily the monsters and original alien were not done in CGI but there are better SF's out from that era. Gore 0/5 Nudity 0/5 Effects 3/5 Story 2,5/5 Comedy 0/5
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Absolutely brilliant Sci-Fi.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    domino365
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An excellent movie with great cast, original idea and great story. The Cast. Kurt Russell is great as Jonathan 'Jack' O'Neil. He comes across as a great hero during the action scenes but plays the emotional parts well when they arise. James Spader is great as Dr Daniel Jackson and really comes across as the kind of person you'd expect to be teaching students in a university. His character and Kurt Russell's bump heads a few times and you really believe that they're two really different people. Jackson wants to read every piece of righting, discover every little fossil and meet every local which is a contrast to O'Neil who wants to get on with the mission, shoot first ask questions later and perceive everything as a possible threat. The main cast is back by a stellar supporting cast notable Jaye Davidson as the evil Egyptian god, Ra. The concept. Most mainstream Sci-Fi is set on a spaceship, in the future but this movie takes a completely different direction. The StarGate is a ring with thirty six symbols on it which act as an address to a different planet. It creates a wormhole which instantly transports you to another planet. That is a departure in itself but here's the best part, the main villain is an alien who kidnapped humans from ancient Egypt and brought them to this planet. He took over a young boys body and poses as Ra, the sun god in order to enslave the captured humans. Rather than being set in the future where a big bad alien race tries to invade Earth, there is a heavy focus on the past and takes mythology we know about and says 'what if?' which is a really interesting concept. The story. It's a fairly generic story. It's about a team of special forces commandos who go through the Stargate and find the citizens on the planet are being enslaved by an alien in the body of a boy who is pretending to be the Egyptian sun god, Ra. The team set out to overthrow Ra and get home before they're all killed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    amazing 90s Sci-Fi cult classic that spawned SG1, Atlantis and Universe
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    HelenMary
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Love this film. It's aged well, and is the opener for a massive TV series franchise. Basically, Dr Daniel Jackson (James Spader) is called into a military research station to decipher hieroglyphs and other symbols on a large artifact found at Giza in 1928, which is of course the first Stargate and was built by the alien civilisation that created the Ancient Egyptian way of life here on Earth, which have since gone on another planet, where our intrepid explorers go and find a similar civilisation to what the Egyptians might have been two thousand plus years ago on Earth. Their language is similar enough to what Dr Jackson, an archaeological linguist, can reasonably and not-improbably understand, after a few false starts. The film is of epic proportions set against sweeping sand dune vistas and huge sets, reminiscent of the big studio classics, with hundreds of extras who are real people not painted in later. It has an iconic soundtrack that is almost operatic in places, and the costumes, ancient Egyptian similarities and the special effects are just brilliant even nearly twenty years on, and without the prolific CGI we have today! It is visually very impressive, and original. The script isn't great and is really the only thing that lets the film down a point. It's all a bit rushed and staccato at the beginning - the bit on Earth is the least convincing actually. The film manages some humour as well as having you on the edge of your seat for a climactic finale, which is also a little emotive. James Spader is always a good bet, known most prominently for rather seedy, smutty, awkward or fast talking characters (Oh! How I love Boston Legal), he is superb as the academic PhD here; his calm, measured and quiet delivery are perfect against Kurt Russell's buzz-cut macho all-guns-blazing military man on a mission. Jaye Davidson gives a rather scary performance as Ra ("the Sun god") with control and an almost sexual element and effeminacy but also a violence and temper that are only partially helped by special effects. I really loved the acting - possibly the stand out character - of Alexis Cruz as the smart and brave village boy Skaara who makes first contact and is the plucky comic relief! Erick Avari, the village leader Kasuf, is a familiar face now (but perhaps wasn't so much back in the early 90s as this was his first major film role) as is French Stewart, one of the soldiers (3rd Rock from the Sun) and also Djimon Hounsou in an early in his acting career small though perfectly formed role as Horus. A brilliant film, well worth watching for sci-fi, Egyptian, alien, anthropology, archaeology, action adventure interests. It is worth noting that the beginning of the film is in German with subtitles and your DVD language and subtitle options aren't playing up (I stupidly forgot that last time I watched as it had been such a long time since I'd seen it), and also there are subtitles for the plot-important Egyptian dialect conversations too.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fairly typical
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Leofwine_draca
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    STARGATE should be the perfect movie for me: an interesting premise, grounded in real-life theory (I've been reading Graham Hancock's FINGERPRINTS OF THE GODS recently, and am familiar with Von Daniken's writings) and made with a high enough budget to do the special effects justice. And watching it, it's hard to fault the production. The performances are pretty good, from Kurt Russell's hard-ass soldier to James Spader's nerdy Egyptologist, and the aforementioned SFX are decent. It's just that the film ends up feeling relatively mundane given the extensive set-up; it all turns into an entirely typical good guys vs. the bad guys type film, with little of the intelligence or thought-provoking questions I was hoping for. I'll lay the blame squarely at the door of Roland Emmerich, who has quite the habit of dumbing down his source material (INDEPENDENCE DAY, GODZILLA, need I go on?). Imagine if this had been made by somebody with more interest in the questions raised instead of the size of the guns!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A bit standard, but a very decent concept to a great movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin-thelordofthefu-48-460297
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well, I just want to say that I had never heard of this film before... until the past summer when I was at summer camp when I watched it on a VHS copy. I also heard that this was made the same year I was born and this was made by the same guy who directed Independence Day, Godzilla, and the later film 2012. I watched it because I wanted to see if it would keep me very interested. It did after my first viewing and I personally like it as much as those who gave it a positive feedback. Sure, some of the characters may be unengaging and the story, despite it's decent concept, does have some plot holes and I would've like to see more of the romance between the two characters. Those flaws didn't really bother me at all and I think that this is Roland Emmerich's best film next to Independence Day and The Patriot. The acting on the whole is pretty good especially Kurt Russell and James Spader who had great chemistry together throughout the film. The directing from Roland Emmerich is pretty good and focused, the pacing moves along very nicely, but would've been fifteen minutes longer at the end of the film. The strongest aspects, however, goes to it's compelling visuals and it's epic music score from David Arnold. The look of the Egyptian world along with some nice costume designs is fabulous. David Arnold's music score doesn't have a sci-fi tone to it, but it does have a memorable tune which gives the movie an epic sweep to it. It also has some good dialog especially it's nice moments with the main character and the villain who is quite menacing. Stargate does have a hokey concept, but I don't understand why some people hated it because I think that this is an interesting film and I simply understood that it got a cult following over the years. It isn't perfect, but it's completely watchable to those who haven't seen it yet. So, in my opinion, this deserves a 4/5.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ancient Astronaut Theorists and Fans are Still Waiting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Ancient Astronaut thesis definitively started in the late 60's with Erich Von Daniken, was matured and intellectualized by Zecharia Sitchin starting in 1976, and is here today in a plethora of TV shows, documentaries and extensions of previous works. It is a fascinating and totally believable subject that has limited, if any big screen incarnations. Thus speaks Stargate. The movie starts off great with the whole thing collapsing under its own weight of misunderstanding the concept and turning it into a good looking but incredibly inept military exercise with dull action scenes and unbelievably uninteresting cultural exchanges. The Alien look is outstanding as are the sets, but it shamelessly uses a deep concept and ridicules its insights. It has no taste for the intellect and the cartoonish presentation of the Marines is clich&eacute;d and dated. There is still a great movie to be made with this subject matter and if it is handled in a respectful manner it could be the biggest brainy blockbuster of all time. Ever since 2001: A Space Odyssey (which had undertones of the theme) fans of the Ancient Astronaut theory have been waiting and one hopes that Hollywood is listening.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Led To The TV Franchise.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Roland Emmerich directed this Sci-Fi action film as Kurt Russell plays Col. Jack O'Neil, who, along with Dr. Daniel Jackson(played by James Spader) lead a team of scientists and military personnel as they explore a time/space portal that was found in Egypt, and has only recently been figured out, unlocking its teleporting ability, and sending them to a desert world where an advanced race of human-like beings still practice ancient Egyptian culture, only with modern technology. They are a warlike people, who want to use the re-opened portal for invasion, so of course they must be stopped. Good premise is strangely squandered in this spectacular looking but dramatically flat and unoriginal film. Good cast tries their best, but overlong film never comes close to the 'Star Wars" level of epic storytelling it clearly aspires to.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Almost Twenty Years Later and after Watching at Least Six Times, the Timeless "Stargate" is still a Fantastic Sci-Fi
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Claudio Carvalho
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In 1928, in Egypt, a strange device is found by an expedition. In the present days, the outcast linguist Dr. Daniel Jackson (James Spader) is invited by a mysterious woman to decipher an ancient hieroglyph in a military facility. Soon he finds that the device was developed by an advanced civilization and opens a portal to teletransport to another planet. Dr. Jackson is invited to join a military team under the command of Colonel Jonathan 'Jack' O'Neil (Kurt Russell) that will explore the new world. They find a land that recalls Egypt and humans in a primitive culture that worship and are slaves to Ra, the God of the Sun. But soon they discover the secret of the mysterious "stargate". "Stargate" is still a fantastic sci-fi after almost twenty years and watching it at least six times. The story is intriguing and entwines action with humor and romance. The cast is excellent, with Kurt Russell and James Spade in the top of their careers. The special effects are still great after almost twenty years. And the haunting music score completes this timeless classic sci-fi with a touch of class. My vote is nine. Title (Brazil): "Stargate - A Chave para o Futuro da Humanidade" ("Stargate  The Key for the Future of Mankind")
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nice science-fiction entertainment
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Avid Climber
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Stargate is, as far as I'm concerned, better than the original TV series, which I've watched a couple of time without really getting interested, but then I'm not a fan. The good. Very imaginative settings and alien technology. Beautiful photography. Nicely paced scenario. Interesting story with a solid background. The actors. Kurt Russell is right in his element, and didn't need to show the limits of his short acting range. James Spader is the most interesting character, and plays it well. Mili Avital is pretty, innocent, and plays her sweet role really nicely. Erick Avari, though, is my favorite of the cast and offers us a very convincing performance as the primitive priest-leader faced with powerful strangers. And finally, you can see some of the antics of French Stewart. The bad. Very low army credibility. The intro village miniature is of poor quality. The special effects are getting a bit old, but they were done in such a way as to minimize the aging and still be well received these days. The ugly. That desert beast puppet is just terrible. The chevrons are flimsy. The result. Good entertainment, recommended to sci-fi fans.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Terrific sci-fi adventure
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Progressive-Element
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's had a lot of stick over the years, but Stargate makes for a terrific thrill ride, conveying some of the excitement of Star Wars, Indiana Jones, and Flash Gordon. And perhaps even the John Carter books too. It takes awhile for it to build up, but the set-up is enthralling, a neat spin on the Chariots of the Gods stuff about ancient astronauts and the like. Once Kurt and James are on 'Planet X', they and the team eventually discover humans living a nomadic existence, kept subservient by the sun-god Ra - who turns out to be a powerful despotic alien, but no God. Ra's henchmen too are simply big strong men, who happen to be kitted out with high-tech weapons and equipment. Things take a turn for the worse when Ra shows up, alerted to the activation of the Stargate, and Spader, Kurt and his men eventually find themselves leading a revolt, while at the same time racing against time from stopping Ra sending an explosive present through the Stargate to Earth. Not perfect, a little plodding at times, but fun undemanding entertainment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a classic but not for me, too much talking
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    trashgang
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Having just bought the full stargate collection I had to start with the original one. Having seen it I had my doubts about starting the series. The flick doesn't blow me away. The effects were good and no that much of CGI was used but it was the story itself that wasn't my cup of tea. It starts rather good going back to 8000 years before Christ to see some kind of space ship landing on earth. Flash forward to early 1920's to see the discovery in Egypt of some weird objects. Flash forward to nowadays were Dr. Daniel Jackson(James Spader) is brought in into the army to help solving a two year problem, what are the symbols standing on the objects found in Egypt, in comes Col. Jonathan 'Jack' O'Neil (Kurt Russell with a weird haircut) to solve the problem once they see that the object is some kind of Stargate. Off they go into the stargate to another galaxy and from here things go wrong for me. Here we move away from a science-fiction to a story were the white people are the superiors of the black coloured. They need the whites to help them against the Egyptian looking aliens with a god called Ra. Anyone. In comes also a bit of a love story with Dr. Jackosn. Even when the aliens attack it's a bit low on everything. It's a bit of how humanity started and what went wrong with a lot of blah blah and no action. Still, for some it's a classic that spawned a new flick Children Of The Gods (1997) with a whole new cast which leads to the series for ten years long. As I said, the effects were rather good and luckily the monsters and original alien were not done in CGI but there are better SF's out from that era. Gore 0/5 Nudity 0/5 Effects 3/5 Story 2,5/5 Comedy 0/5
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Absolutely brilliant Sci-Fi.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    domino365
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An excellent movie with great cast, original idea and great story. The Cast. Kurt Russell is great as Jonathan 'Jack' O'Neil. He comes across as a great hero during the action scenes but plays the emotional parts well when they arise. James Spader is great as Dr Daniel Jackson and really comes across as the kind of person you'd expect to be teaching students in a university. His character and Kurt Russell's bump heads a few times and you really believe that they're two really different people. Jackson wants to read every piece of righting, discover every little fossil and meet every local which is a contrast to O'Neil who wants to get on with the mission, shoot first ask questions later and perceive everything as a possible threat. The main cast is back by a stellar supporting cast notable Jaye Davidson as the evil Egyptian god, Ra. The concept. Most mainstream Sci-Fi is set on a spaceship, in the future but this movie takes a completely different direction. The StarGate is a ring with thirty six symbols on it which act as an address to a different planet. It creates a wormhole which instantly transports you to another planet. That is a departure in itself but here's the best part, the main villain is an alien who kidnapped humans from ancient Egypt and brought them to this planet. He took over a young boys body and poses as Ra, the sun god in order to enslave the captured humans. Rather than being set in the future where a big bad alien race tries to invade Earth, there is a heavy focus on the past and takes mythology we know about and says 'what if?' which is a really interesting concept. The story. It's a fairly generic story. It's about a team of special forces commandos who go through the Stargate and find the citizens on the planet are being enslaved by an alien in the body of a boy who is pretending to be the Egyptian sun god, Ra. The team set out to overthrow Ra and get home before they're all killed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    amazing 90s Sci-Fi cult classic that spawned SG1, Atlantis and Universe
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    HelenMary
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Love this film. It's aged well, and is the opener for a massive TV series franchise. Basically, Dr Daniel Jackson (James Spader) is called into a military research station to decipher hieroglyphs and other symbols on a large artifact found at Giza in 1928, which is of course the first Stargate and was built by the alien civilisation that created the Ancient Egyptian way of life here on Earth, which have since gone on another planet, where our intrepid explorers go and find a similar civilisation to what the Egyptians might have been two thousand plus years ago on Earth. Their language is similar enough to what Dr Jackson, an archaeological linguist, can reasonably and not-improbably understand, after a few false starts. The film is of epic proportions set against sweeping sand dune vistas and huge sets, reminiscent of the big studio classics, with hundreds of extras who are real people not painted in later. It has an iconic soundtrack that is almost operatic in places, and the costumes, ancient Egyptian similarities and the special effects are just brilliant even nearly twenty years on, and without the prolific CGI we have today! It is visually very impressive, and original. The script isn't great and is really the only thing that lets the film down a point. It's all a bit rushed and staccato at the beginning - the bit on Earth is the least convincing actually. The film manages some humour as well as having you on the edge of your seat for a climactic finale, which is also a little emotive. James Spader is always a good bet, known most prominently for rather seedy, smutty, awkward or fast talking characters (Oh! How I love Boston Legal), he is superb as the academic PhD here; his calm, measured and quiet delivery are perfect against Kurt Russell's buzz-cut macho all-guns-blazing military man on a mission. Jaye Davidson gives a rather scary performance as Ra ("the Sun god") with control and an almost sexual element and effeminacy but also a violence and temper that are only partially helped by special effects. I really loved the acting - possibly the stand out character - of Alexis Cruz as the smart and brave village boy Skaara who makes first contact and is the plucky comic relief! Erick Avari, the village leader Kasuf, is a familiar face now (but perhaps wasn't so much back in the early 90s as this was his first major film role) as is French Stewart, one of the soldiers (3rd Rock from the Sun) and also Djimon Hounsou in an early in his acting career small though perfectly formed role as Horus. A brilliant film, well worth watching for sci-fi, Egyptian, alien, anthropology, archaeology, action adventure interests. It is worth noting that the beginning of the film is in German with subtitles and your DVD language and subtitle options aren't playing up (I stupidly forgot that last time I watched as it had been such a long time since I'd seen it), and also there are subtitles for the plot-important Egyptian dialect conversations too.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fairly typical
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Leofwine_draca
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    STARGATE should be the perfect movie for me: an interesting premise, grounded in real-life theory (I've been reading Graham Hancock's FINGERPRINTS OF THE GODS recently, and am familiar with Von Daniken's writings) and made with a high enough budget to do the special effects justice. And watching it, it's hard to fault the production. The performances are pretty good, from Kurt Russell's hard-ass soldier to James Spader's nerdy Egyptologist, and the aforementioned SFX are decent. It's just that the film ends up feeling relatively mundane given the extensive set-up; it all turns into an entirely typical good guys vs. the bad guys type film, with little of the intelligence or thought-provoking questions I was hoping for. I'll lay the blame squarely at the door of Roland Emmerich, who has quite the habit of dumbing down his source material (INDEPENDENCE DAY, GODZILLA, need I go on?). Imagine if this had been made by somebody with more interest in the questions raised instead of the size of the guns!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A bit standard, but a very decent concept to a great movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin-thelordofthefu-48-460297
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well, I just want to say that I had never heard of this film before... until the past summer when I was at summer camp when I watched it on a VHS copy. I also heard that this was made the same year I was born and this was made by the same guy who directed Independence Day, Godzilla, and the later film 2012. I watched it because I wanted to see if it would keep me very interested. It did after my first viewing and I personally like it as much as those who gave it a positive feedback. Sure, some of the characters may be unengaging and the story, despite it's decent concept, does have some plot holes and I would've like to see more of the romance between the two characters. Those flaws didn't really bother me at all and I think that this is Roland Emmerich's best film next to Independence Day and The Patriot. The acting on the whole is pretty good especially Kurt Russell and James Spader who had great chemistry together throughout the film. The directing from Roland Emmerich is pretty good and focused, the pacing moves along very nicely, but would've been fifteen minutes longer at the end of the film. The strongest aspects, however, goes to it's compelling visuals and it's epic music score from David Arnold. The look of the Egyptian world along with some nice costume designs is fabulous. David Arnold's music score doesn't have a sci-fi tone to it, but it does have a memorable tune which gives the movie an epic sweep to it. It also has some good dialog especially it's nice moments with the main character and the villain who is quite menacing. Stargate does have a hokey concept, but I don't understand why some people hated it because I think that this is an interesting film and I simply understood that it got a cult following over the years. It isn't perfect, but it's completely watchable to those who haven't seen it yet. So, in my opinion, this deserves a 4/5.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ancient Astronaut Theorists and Fans are Still Waiting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Ancient Astronaut thesis definitively started in the late 60's with Erich Von Daniken, was matured and intellectualized by Zecharia Sitchin starting in 1976, and is here today in a plethora of TV shows, documentaries and extensions of previous works. It is a fascinating and totally believable subject that has limited, if any big screen incarnations. Thus speaks Stargate. The movie starts off great with the whole thing collapsing under its own weight of misunderstanding the concept and turning it into a good looking but incredibly inept military exercise with dull action scenes and unbelievably uninteresting cultural exchanges. The Alien look is outstanding as are the sets, but it shamelessly uses a deep concept and ridicules its insights. It has no taste for the intellect and the cartoonish presentation of the Marines is clich&eacute;d and dated. There is still a great movie to be made with this subject matter and if it is handled in a respectful manner it could be the biggest brainy blockbuster of all time. Ever since 2001: A Space Odyssey (which had undertones of the theme) fans of the Ancient Astronaut theory have been waiting and one hopes that Hollywood is listening.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Led To The TV Franchise.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Roland Emmerich directed this Sci-Fi action film as Kurt Russell plays Col. Jack O'Neil, who, along with Dr. Daniel Jackson(played by James Spader) lead a team of scientists and military personnel as they explore a time/space portal that was found in Egypt, and has only recently been figured out, unlocking its teleporting ability, and sending them to a desert world where an advanced race of human-like beings still practice ancient Egyptian culture, only with modern technology. They are a warlike people, who want to use the re-opened portal for invasion, so of course they must be stopped. Good premise is strangely squandered in this spectacular looking but dramatically flat and unoriginal film. Good cast tries their best, but overlong film never comes close to the 'Star Wars" level of epic storytelling it clearly aspires to.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Almost Twenty Years Later and after Watching at Least Six Times, the Timeless "Stargate" is still a Fantastic Sci-Fi
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Claudio Carvalho
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In 1928, in Egypt, a strange device is found by an expedition. In the present days, the outcast linguist Dr. Daniel Jackson (James Spader) is invited by a mysterious woman to decipher an ancient hieroglyph in a military facility. Soon he finds that the device was developed by an advanced civilization and opens a portal to teletransport to another planet. Dr. Jackson is invited to join a military team under the command of Colonel Jonathan 'Jack' O'Neil (Kurt Russell) that will explore the new world. They find a land that recalls Egypt and humans in a primitive culture that worship and are slaves to Ra, the God of the Sun. But soon they discover the secret of the mysterious "stargate". "Stargate" is still a fantastic sci-fi after almost twenty years and watching it at least six times. The story is intriguing and entwines action with humor and romance. The cast is excellent, with Kurt Russell and James Spade in the top of their careers. The special effects are still great after almost twenty years. And the haunting music score completes this timeless classic sci-fi with a touch of class. My vote is nine. Title (Brazil): "Stargate - A Chave para o Futuro da Humanidade" ("Stargate  The Key for the Future of Mankind")
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nice science-fiction entertainment
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Avid Climber
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Stargate is, as far as I'm concerned, better than the original TV series, which I've watched a couple of time without really getting interested, but then I'm not a fan. The good. Very imaginative settings and alien technology. Beautiful photography. Nicely paced scenario. Interesting story with a solid background. The actors. Kurt Russell is right in his element, and didn't need to show the limits of his short acting range. James Spader is the most interesting character, and plays it well. Mili Avital is pretty, innocent, and plays her sweet role really nicely. Erick Avari, though, is my favorite of the cast and offers us a very convincing performance as the primitive priest-leader faced with powerful strangers. And finally, you can see some of the antics of French Stewart. The bad. Very low army credibility. The intro village miniature is of poor quality. The special effects are getting a bit old, but they were done in such a way as to minimize the aging and still be well received these days. The ugly. That desert beast puppet is just terrible. The chevrons are flimsy. The result. Good entertainment, recommended to sci-fi fans.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Terrific sci-fi adventure
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Progressive-Element
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's had a lot of stick over the years, but Stargate makes for a terrific thrill ride, conveying some of the excitement of Star Wars, Indiana Jones, and Flash Gordon. And perhaps even the John Carter books too. It takes awhile for it to build up, but the set-up is enthralling, a neat spin on the Chariots of the Gods stuff about ancient astronauts and the like. Once Kurt and James are on 'Planet X', they and the team eventually discover humans living a nomadic existence, kept subservient by the sun-god Ra - who turns out to be a powerful despotic alien, but no God. Ra's henchmen too are simply big strong men, who happen to be kitted out with high-tech weapons and equipment. Things take a turn for the worse when Ra shows up, alerted to the activation of the Stargate, and Spader, Kurt and his men eventually find themselves leading a revolt, while at the same time racing against time from stopping Ra sending an explosive present through the Stargate to Earth. Not perfect, a little plodding at times, but fun undemanding entertainment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a classic but not for me, too much talking
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    trashgang
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Having just bought the full stargate collection I had to start with the original one. Having seen it I had my doubts about starting the series. The flick doesn't blow me away. The effects were good and no that much of CGI was used but it was the story itself that wasn't my cup of tea. It starts rather good going back to 8000 years before Christ to see some kind of space ship landing on earth. Flash forward to early 1920's to see the discovery in Egypt of some weird objects. Flash forward to nowadays were Dr. Daniel Jackson(James Spader) is brought in into the army to help solving a two year problem, what are the symbols standing on the objects found in Egypt, in comes Col. Jonathan 'Jack' O'Neil (Kurt Russell with a weird haircut) to solve the problem once they see that the object is some kind of Stargate. Off they go into the stargate to another galaxy and from here things go wrong for me. Here we move away from a science-fiction to a story were the white people are the superiors of the black coloured. They need the whites to help them against the Egyptian looking aliens with a god called Ra. Anyone. In comes also a bit of a love story with Dr. Jackosn. Even when the aliens attack it's a bit low on everything. It's a bit of how humanity started and what went wrong with a lot of blah blah and no action. Still, for some it's a classic that spawned a new flick Children Of The Gods (1997) with a whole new cast which leads to the series for ten years long. As I said, the effects were rather good and luckily the monsters and original alien were not done in CGI but there are better SF's out from that era. Gore 0/5 Nudity 0/5 Effects 3/5 Story 2,5/5 Comedy 0/5
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Absolutely brilliant Sci-Fi.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    domino365
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An excellent movie with great cast, original idea and great story. The Cast. Kurt Russell is great as Jonathan 'Jack' O'Neil. He comes across as a great hero during the action scenes but plays the emotional parts well when they arise. James Spader is great as Dr Daniel Jackson and really comes across as the kind of person you'd expect to be teaching students in a university. His character and Kurt Russell's bump heads a few times and you really believe that they're two really different people. Jackson wants to read every piece of righting, discover every little fossil and meet every local which is a contrast to O'Neil who wants to get on with the mission, shoot first ask questions later and perceive everything as a possible threat. The main cast is back by a stellar supporting cast notable Jaye Davidson as the evil Egyptian god, Ra. The concept. Most mainstream Sci-Fi is set on a spaceship, in the future but this movie takes a completely different direction. The StarGate is a ring with thirty six symbols on it which act as an address to a different planet. It creates a wormhole which instantly transports you to another planet. That is a departure in itself but here's the best part, the main villain is an alien who kidnapped humans from ancient Egypt and brought them to this planet. He took over a young boys body and poses as Ra, the sun god in order to enslave the captured humans. Rather than being set in the future where a big bad alien race tries to invade Earth, there is a heavy focus on the past and takes mythology we know about and says 'what if?' which is a really interesting concept. The story. It's a fairly generic story. It's about a team of special forces commandos who go through the Stargate and find the citizens on the planet are being enslaved by an alien in the body of a boy who is pretending to be the Egyptian sun god, Ra. The team set out to overthrow Ra and get home before they're all killed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    amazing 90s Sci-Fi cult classic that spawned SG1, Atlantis and Universe
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    HelenMary
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Love this film. It's aged well, and is the opener for a massive TV series franchise. Basically, Dr Daniel Jackson (James Spader) is called into a military research station to decipher hieroglyphs and other symbols on a large artifact found at Giza in 1928, which is of course the first Stargate and was built by the alien civilisation that created the Ancient Egyptian way of life here on Earth, which have since gone on another planet, where our intrepid explorers go and find a similar civilisation to what the Egyptians might have been two thousand plus years ago on Earth. Their language is similar enough to what Dr Jackson, an archaeological linguist, can reasonably and not-improbably understand, after a few false starts. The film is of epic proportions set against sweeping sand dune vistas and huge sets, reminiscent of the big studio classics, with hundreds of extras who are real people not painted in later. It has an iconic soundtrack that is almost operatic in places, and the costumes, ancient Egyptian similarities and the special effects are just brilliant even nearly twenty years on, and without the prolific CGI we have today! It is visually very impressive, and original. The script isn't great and is really the only thing that lets the film down a point. It's all a bit rushed and staccato at the beginning - the bit on Earth is the least convincing actually. The film manages some humour as well as having you on the edge of your seat for a climactic finale, which is also a little emotive. James Spader is always a good bet, known most prominently for rather seedy, smutty, awkward or fast talking characters (Oh! How I love Boston Legal), he is superb as the academic PhD here; his calm, measured and quiet delivery are perfect against Kurt Russell's buzz-cut macho all-guns-blazing military man on a mission. Jaye Davidson gives a rather scary performance as Ra ("the Sun god") with control and an almost sexual element and effeminacy but also a violence and temper that are only partially helped by special effects. I really loved the acting - possibly the stand out character - of Alexis Cruz as the smart and brave village boy Skaara who makes first contact and is the plucky comic relief! Erick Avari, the village leader Kasuf, is a familiar face now (but perhaps wasn't so much back in the early 90s as this was his first major film role) as is French Stewart, one of the soldiers (3rd Rock from the Sun) and also Djimon Hounsou in an early in his acting career small though perfectly formed role as Horus. A brilliant film, well worth watching for sci-fi, Egyptian, alien, anthropology, archaeology, action adventure interests. It is worth noting that the beginning of the film is in German with subtitles and your DVD language and subtitle options aren't playing up (I stupidly forgot that last time I watched as it had been such a long time since I'd seen it), and also there are subtitles for the plot-important Egyptian dialect conversations too.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fairly typical
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Leofwine_draca
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    STARGATE should be the perfect movie for me: an interesting premise, grounded in real-life theory (I've been reading Graham Hancock's FINGERPRINTS OF THE GODS recently, and am familiar with Von Daniken's writings) and made with a high enough budget to do the special effects justice. And watching it, it's hard to fault the production. The performances are pretty good, from Kurt Russell's hard-ass soldier to James Spader's nerdy Egyptologist, and the aforementioned SFX are decent. It's just that the film ends up feeling relatively mundane given the extensive set-up; it all turns into an entirely typical good guys vs. the bad guys type film, with little of the intelligence or thought-provoking questions I was hoping for. I'll lay the blame squarely at the door of Roland Emmerich, who has quite the habit of dumbing down his source material (INDEPENDENCE DAY, GODZILLA, need I go on?). Imagine if this had been made by somebody with more interest in the questions raised instead of the size of the guns!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A bit standard, but a very decent concept to a great movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin-thelordofthefu-48-460297
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well, I just want to say that I had never heard of this film before... until the past summer when I was at summer camp when I watched it on a VHS copy. I also heard that this was made the same year I was born and this was made by the same guy who directed Independence Day, Godzilla, and the later film 2012. I watched it because I wanted to see if it would keep me very interested. It did after my first viewing and I personally like it as much as those who gave it a positive feedback. Sure, some of the characters may be unengaging and the story, despite it's decent concept, does have some plot holes and I would've like to see more of the romance between the two characters. Those flaws didn't really bother me at all and I think that this is Roland Emmerich's best film next to Independence Day and The Patriot. The acting on the whole is pretty good especially Kurt Russell and James Spader who had great chemistry together throughout the film. The directing from Roland Emmerich is pretty good and focused, the pacing moves along very nicely, but would've been fifteen minutes longer at the end of the film. The strongest aspects, however, goes to it's compelling visuals and it's epic music score from David Arnold. The look of the Egyptian world along with some nice costume designs is fabulous. David Arnold's music score doesn't have a sci-fi tone to it, but it does have a memorable tune which gives the movie an epic sweep to it. It also has some good dialog especially it's nice moments with the main character and the villain who is quite menacing. Stargate does have a hokey concept, but I don't understand why some people hated it because I think that this is an interesting film and I simply understood that it got a cult following over the years. It isn't perfect, but it's completely watchable to those who haven't seen it yet. So, in my opinion, this deserves a 4/5.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ancient Astronaut Theorists and Fans are Still Waiting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Ancient Astronaut thesis definitively started in the late 60's with Erich Von Daniken, was matured and intellectualized by Zecharia Sitchin starting in 1976, and is here today in a plethora of TV shows, documentaries and extensions of previous works. It is a fascinating and totally believable subject that has limited, if any big screen incarnations. Thus speaks Stargate. The movie starts off great with the whole thing collapsing under its own weight of misunderstanding the concept and turning it into a good looking but incredibly inept military exercise with dull action scenes and unbelievably uninteresting cultural exchanges. The Alien look is outstanding as are the sets, but it shamelessly uses a deep concept and ridicules its insights. It has no taste for the intellect and the cartoonish presentation of the Marines is clich&eacute;d and dated. There is still a great movie to be made with this subject matter and if it is handled in a respectful manner it could be the biggest brainy blockbuster of all time. Ever since 2001: A Space Odyssey (which had undertones of the theme) fans of the Ancient Astronaut theory have been waiting and one hopes that Hollywood is listening.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
