<filme>
 <id>
  625
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0057546
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1963
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  A Espada Era a Lei
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  7.1
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Merlin the Magician teaches a young boy who is destined to be King Arthur.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Arthur (aka Wart) is a young boy who aspires to be a knight's squire. On a hunting trip he falls in on Merlin, a powerful but amnesiac wizard who has plans for Wart beyond mere squiredom. He starts by trying to give Wart an education (whatever that is), believing that once one has an education, one can go anywhere. Needless to say, it doesn't quite work out that way.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Animation
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Adventure
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   squire
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   owl
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   wizard
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   sword
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   castle
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Wolfgang Reitherman
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Bill Peet
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   T.H. White
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Rickie Sorensen
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Sebastian Cabot
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Karl Swenson
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Kid-friendly King Arthur tale
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ersinkdotcom
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A young orphan named "Wart" wants nothing more than to be the squire to his older foster brother. Merlin the Magician sees more potential in the boy and begins training him for a greater destiny. "Wart" accompanies his brother to a tournament in London, where he will discover his true fate as Merlin's visions of greatness unfold. We all know how it feels when you remember a movie one way from childhood and realize as an adult it's not quite as it seemed. That was my feeling as I watched Disney's "The Sword in the Stone." Far be it for me to start slinging mud at what is considered to be a classic in the eyes of many. However, it became tedious watching Merlin the Magician teach "Wart" life lessons through turning himself and the boy into one animal after another and breaking into song. I've never been a big fan of any musicals. I'm sure this factor has everything to do with my lack of enthusiasm for "The Sword in the Stone." My preferred version of the Arthur story would lean more towards the adventurous "Excalibur." "The Sword in the Stone" does contain quite a bit of magic. Some people with certain religious convictions will find this a good reason to steer clear of the movie. I would have to say that anyone who watches "The Lord of the Rings" films has no right to throw rocks at this one. My 7-year old loved "The Sword in the Stone," so maybe I've just outgrown it. He's watched it twice already, where I found it near impossible to sit through once. If children like it, does it really matter what this old reviewer thinks about it anyway? It's been proved time and time again that Disney movies are critic-proof.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A triumph of fun and intelligence over animation 
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ElMaruecan82
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
     just like brain over brawn, Merlin's eternal motto. The initial reactions to "The Sword in the Stone" left me astonished. How could such a merry and original piece of animation get such negative criticism? From what I've read, nothing was spared: the animation didn't match the quality of previous Disney's works, the episodic structure lead to a conclusion disappointing because of the lack of a memorable plot line or a clearly defined antagonist  in this list of flaws, where I only concede the issue with Wart's voice, nothing seemed enjoyable enough to redeem the film: not Merlin's eccentric personality, not the humor made of unusual anachronistic references, not even the scene- stealing exuberance of Madame Mim. Well, since reviewing is about giving opinions, I'll give you mine: "The Sword in the Stone" was victim of an unfair bias constantly leaning on Disney's 'Golden Age' standards, while for one thing, it was a respectable attempt to take some distance from the usual formulas (and I'm pretty sure viewers enjoyed the new storytelling format, since the film ended-up being one of the highest grossing of 1963). And now that these fifty years of existence did justice to "Sword in the Stone", now that there are enough Disney animated features to make a clear distinction between the indisputable classics, the underrated gems, and the forgettable ones, I think we can all agree that "The Sword in the Stone" is in the same league than "The Jungle Book" or "Robin Hood", all contained in that entertaining parenthesis of the 60's-70's. And it's precisely the sketchy animation so typical of that period that elevates "The Sword in the Stone" to more interesting level of appreciation, more focused on the story, as the counterpart of such ambitious projects like "Sleeping Beauty", a film of dazzling imagery but certainly poorer story-wise. "The Sword in the Stone" is an educational journey guided by Merlin the wizard, whose long beard, blue pointed hat and long robe belong to the best of Disney iconography. His disciple is Wart, a twelve-year old boy, whose destiny is to become the future legendary King Arthur. The mentorship goes through different stages, using magic as an accessory but never as the crucial tool, in order to make Wart learn from practice, the values of the driving forces of our universe: physics, gravity or survival, all the stuff that makes 'things go round' and the greatest lesson of all being that brains always triumph on brawn. This 'brains over brawn' dichotomy is the pattern that forged human civilization and Merlin's divinatory power allowed him to check the validity of his point, what Wart would only see through experience. The film is made of many vignettes during which Arthur is turned into an animal. As a fish, he's victim of a bullying bull-frog before confronting a pike, as a squirrel, a female gets infatuated with him, turning the lesson on gravity into one about a much greater force. The third lesson involves Arthur as a sparrow learning to fly with Merlin's owl Archimedes, but his abrupt encounter with the witch Madame Mim, Merlin's archenemy, leads to one of Disney's greatest moments: the wizardry duel. The sequence is a triumph of imagination and animation combined, having both characters turning into various animals while conserving their defining traits is a delight to the eyes, and it concludes perfectly with Mim finally "catching" Merlin' but not the way she intended. Again, Merlin always proves his point. The secret of "The Sword in the Stone" lies essentially on its relative absence of a plot, and the episodic structure, which constitutes the basis of Merlin's mentorship. Each sequence is not only full of educational and philosophical value but stands alone as a great moment of animation. The fish part involves Arthur's first confrontation with a giant predator and the first opportunity to use his brains by turning his smaller size to his advantage. In the process, it also unveils an heroic facet in Archimedes' grouchy personality. The squirrel part, after a series of laughs driven by Merlin's misadventure with a fat beaver-like creature, finally illustrates Disney's formula that for every laugh, there should be a tear. And even if it's not 'Bambi' or 'Lion King', there's something extremely poignant and heart-breaking in the squirrel part's conclusion, even more because it's unexpected. But there are laughs in the film, and quite a lot, "The Sword in the Stone" is full of anachronisms, of priceless interactions between Merlin and Archimedes, who make a great pair of "Grumpy Old Men", and some hilarious scenes involving a wolf that have an irresistible Warner Bros cartoon feeling. And the few songs are so catchy we end up inevitably humming them while enjoying the animation.Who can resist to the sight of Merlin's furniture lined-up with a hot-tempered sugar pot on the lead, and being reduced over and over again to fit in a ridiculously small bag, or to the dishes washing by themselves motivated by all these "Hockity-Pockity" or "Higites-Figitus", which sound like improvement on "Cinderella"'s 'Bobbidi-Bibbidi"? The film isn't flawless, the irony that the more you like it, the more you watch it and discover some bits of repetitive or lazy animations. But "The Sword in the Stone" works thanks to its independence from a plot line's tyranny. Granted the film doesn't feature all the Disney archetypes, Mim is the main antagonist but not the larger-than-life villain with a heart- pounding demise. Even Arthur's foster father Ector has heart and his son Kay is more of a dim-witted comic relief. No abundance of songs, no memorable climax either except from the wizardry duel and the magical sword moment, but despite all these missing elements, "The Sword in the Stone", through its difference, marks itself among the most memorable work from Disney studios with an undeniable educational, intellectual and philosophical value.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nothing like the great book by T.H. White, and nowhere near the quality of other Disney classics
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Conrad
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The book "The Sword in the Stone" by T.H. White is a trove of wisdom for children and adults, and a paean of love to medieval England, but virtually none of the best material from the novel finds its way to the screen in this soulless adaptation. Most Disney classics are like stepping into a fantasy storybook, but this is little more than a cheap cartoon. Something meaningful could have been made of Arthur's encounter with an amorous squirrel (this occurs while he himself is in the body of a squirrel), something akin to the beautiful and literary swan episode in White's book, but while there is a hint of real emotion in the film's squirrel scene it is largely overshadowed by meaningless back-and-forths between Merlin's own squirrel avatar and a husky female of the species. This is a representative example of the movie's many missed opportunities.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    7th out of 8 in the Silver Era
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Centaurus3
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After the success of 101 Dalmatians, The Sword in The Stone was released in December of 1963, and the last animated film Walt Disney would see completed and released. The story is about a Wizard named Merlin, who teaches Arthur about life lessons and how to use his brain, as Merlin knows that Arthur is going to be something big. Arthur pulls out the sword, making him king. Most of the characters in this film are extremely boring, except for Madame Mim and Merlin. Mim is the bad wizard who appears in the last 15 minutes of the film, and is a bit bubbly despite being evil. Merlin is the original Genie with all the modern day references, and is the comic relief; he is a cool guy. Arthur does not warrant any interest at all, and the fact that he is voiced by 3 VOICE ACTORS is probably the only thing that stands out about him. All of the other characters (the deadhead father and son, etc) are extremely forgettable. This movie only has a few songs. "Higitus Figitus" is a Bibidi Bobidi Bo type song, but played down, and "Madame Mim" is just alright. The introduction song is pretty neat though. The soundtrack is just alright. The animation is not up to par with the previous films, and the Xerography in this movie makes it even more bland and forgettable than it is; they should have used the animation from the 50s, but that was too expensive. Here is where the reused animation in Disney films start to become obvious, as you would see the same animation sketches in the next few movies. The character designs are alright, but the animation is good when Merlin is using magic. With the weak plot, mostly weak characters, and everything else average, this movie is where the magic in Disney films start to wane away. This film is not very memorable, but there is some good and entertaining parts in the movie (Merlin vs Mim, squirrel scene). If you want to watch a Disney film that you have not watched in a while, this may be the movie. Give it a watch, you will find some moments you like, but don't expect it to be a great movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Sword in the Stone That Will Destine One For The Throne.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dawalk-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I remember seeing this among other Disney films I saw in elementary school (at least part of them anyway) and those that aired on non-cable t.v. Some years later, I viewed this on Youtube a while back and for some time afterward, I'd been considering and wanting to buy a copy of the 45th Anniversary edition of it. I finally did last month and it's great seeing it once again. I never really thought or paid attention to it as much as some, certain other Disney animated features, but now I think I have to concur that it's one of the more underrated ones. A boy named Arthur (a.k.a. Wart) has the dream of one day becoming a squire. But little does he know that he's destined for something much greater, which is being the new English king, which is the position he takes over later from his late father (although being new at this and not knowing much about a ruler's duties, Wart isn't so sure he's up to it). This occurs once he successfully pulls out the enchanted sword from the stone. That makes sense, considering he's his son and he eventually inherits his place on the throne. But before that, while going off to retrieve another sword in the woods for his foster brother Kay, he comes across a cottage where he meets the grand wizard, Merlin, and his highly intellectual owl, Archimedes. Merlin appoints himself as Wart's tutor and emphasizes brains used as associated with an education being more important than brawn. This movie has a lot of thrilling moments, such as Wart getting a feel of what it's like to be different animals through the help of Merlin's magic, Merlin's talks about what are yet to come from his time travels (which leaves anyone from his time he tries to explain to about them puzzled or perplexed) and what's one of the most renowned moments, if not the most renowned moment, the Wizard's Duel between Merlin and the witch Mad Madam Mim. I never read the initial source that inspired Disney's take, but I read a little there was mentioned about it in the difference between this and T.H. White's book, which is this version being more comical. Aside from the fact that again I never read the original source, I don't mind nor do I think I would even if I did. I recommend this to anyone who's into adventure. Because it has plenty of it, making it still outstanding nonetheless of other things.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What it lacks in plot, is mostly made up by humor
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Joshua Mitchell
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Sword In The Stone is a major disappointment. It's by no means a bad film, it's just disappointing. What I expected to be an origin film was really just a silly film about a boy with a wizard for a teacher. Don't let the title deceive you, this is not a movie about a sword in a stone, it's about a skinny young boy named Arthur- whom everyone calls Wart- who has a rather ruthless and obnoxious father and older brother. While hunting with his older brother, Kay, Wart discovers a wizard named Merlin and his frumpy owl, Archimedes. Merlin is convinced that it is his job to tutor the boy, and that's all there is to it. There's not nearly enough plot to last even the short 79 minute run time. This might've worked as a 15 minute short film, but as a feature length film, The Sword In The Stone feels padded and tedious. There's just not enough material. Which is a shame because The Sword In The Stone has so much potential. This could've been a marvelous rags-to-riches story, but alas, it's just a Ben Kneobi, Luke Skywalker tale. The Sword In The Stone does have some bright spots though, make no mistake. While a majority of the characters are dull and forgettable, Archimedes is at least slightly amusing, and Merlin is the real main character, and he steals all the scenes anyhow. The protagonist, Wart, is likable, if mostly forgettable. The animation is shockingly bland. Despite a beautiful underwater segment, The Sword In The Stone has little visual sparkle. There are songs too, but like many of the characters, they're forgettable. They're not bad by any means, just forgettable. At the minimum, they're not dull and that's good enough for me. The score, by recurring Disney composer George Bruns, is disappointingly mediocre. However, there's a wonderful jazz piece utilizing the piano during a scene in which Merlin uses magic to wash dishes. This is the only part of the score I can recommend, unfortunately. Some of the scenes are funny, if somewhat pointless to the actual story. The quarrels between Merlin and Archimedes are particularly amusing. There's also one scene towards the end, where Merlin battles a witch in a fun, yet completely illogical duel of magic. While The Sword In The Stone lacks a real plot, and ultimately has nothing to do with the sword in the stone, it's an occasionally fun ride with enough humor to be a mildly enjoyable diversion.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My favorite Disney film!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ravsten428
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I don't know exactly why many people don't praise this movie more. I absolutely love this film. There are not many songs in the movie but the ones that are in it are enjoyable. Merlin who is a wizard that can see centuries into the future and lives with his annoying but lovable owl Archimedes predicts that a young boy of around 11 or 12 will drop into his house and sure enough he's dead on. Merlin takes the young Wart who is the future King of England, on many adventures and tries to teach Wart that knowledge is power. Somewhere along the way Wart is appointed to be Kay's squire at a jousting competition. Merlin is upset by this and says "Blow me to Bermuda!" Merlin takes off and Wart and Archimedes are left alone. Here is where we find that Wart goes to pull out the sword in the stone because he forgot Kay's sword. He tells Sir Ector that he got the sword from the stone yet nobody believes him at first but they go back and find that he was really the one who pulled it and is therefore dubbed King Arthur, King of all England. I love the wizard's duel between Merlin and the evil Madam Mim. One of the best parts of the movie. And also the part where Merlin is being chased by the fat girl squirrel who takes a fancy to him. Love this film!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A lot of fun, but not among Disney's best
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RokurotaMakabe
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is Disney's version of the legend of King Arthur and it represents an adaptation of T.H. White's children's story. Here, Arthur is a young boy who is unaware of his great destiny. He meets and befriends the great wizard Merlin who decides to give him a proper instruction and education in order to prepare him for his future. The film has some great characters: Merlin the wizard and his intellectually trained owl Archimedes are particularly funny. The animation is very good, but this is Disney after all, so you would expect it to be like that. The film is definitely entertaining, but there are a few drawbacks as well. There are moments when it feels a little too similar to Disney's other animated features from that period. The film also incorporates a lot of plot elements from other Disney movies and the film is very predictable at times. In comparison to another Disney classic, "Sleeping Beauty", this film looks more like a secondary project. "The Sword in the Stone" is nevertheless a good film and it is superior to many of Disney's modern efforts ("Hercules", "The Hunchback of Notre Dame" or "Pocahontas" to name a few). It is very entertaining and definitely worth watching. My rating: 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Disney film not to be missed!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Kristine (kristinedrama14@msn.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I cannot believe I never wrote a comment on The Sword in the Stone, my friends always joke how I'm the ultimate Mickey Mouse since I'm such a fan and I own every Disney movie on DVD. I wanted to watch one of my movies last night and I picked The Sword in the Stone and rediscovered how much I loved this movie when I was a kid and still love it today. I went on IMDb to see if I gave the appropriate rating, but I was surprised to see that I never did write about it, but I guess better late then never. Sword in the Stone is just a classic treasure that no family should be without but also the film lovers. A wonderful classic story told Disney style and filled with great songs and beautiful animation, how could anyone not fall in love with The Sword in the Stone. The "Sword in the Stone" appears in London, with an inscription proclaiming that "Who so Pulleth Out This Sword of this Stone and Anvil, is Rightwise King Born of England." None succeed in removing the sword, which is soon forgotten, leaving England in a Dark Age. Some years later, Arthur aka "Wart", a 12-year-old orphan training to be a squire. While accompanying his older foster brother Kay on a hunting trip. He falls into Merlin's cottage, Merlin declares himself Wart's tutor and the two return to Wart's home, a castle run by Sir Ector, Arthur's foster father. There Merlin stays with Arthur to teach him the ways of the world and the magic as well as the intelligence and strength he will need for his true destiny. I think my favorite moment of this film is definitely the battle between Merlin and Mim, since this is one of the rare Disney movies that doesn't have a definitive villain, but I think Mim was a close as you could get. Their battle was epic and absolutely amazing to watch, plus I love the classic sound effects with good old slap stick humor. Also I loved the story when Merlin turned Arthur and himself into squirrels and they were attacked by the lady squirrels was just too cute for words. I know the animation isn't up to par with today's standards, but this is the exact animation that I loved growing up with because the animators seemed to have a love for the film they were making. The Sword in the Stone is a classic Disney film that should never be missed and I can't wait to show my children one day. Disney always had a way of taking classic stories that may not interest a small child and puts action, adventure, romance and wonderful animation into it and made it come to life. I can't believe I hadn't watched this movie since I was a kid, because no film lover should be without this treasure, it's just so excellent and magical, takes you back to a simpler time where we were destined for greatness and the world was at our fingertips. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stone cold
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jc-osms
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Pleasant Disney animation, without being a classic. It has its moments, particularly the magic-fight between Merlin and Mim, but is light on characterisation and especially good songs. The soundtrack tunes are very simplistic both melodically and especially lyrically and resolutely refuse to stay in your brain. The narrative itself is unusual, introducing the sword in the stone legend immediately and then dispensing with it until the last five minutes or so, concentrating its energies instead on young Arthur (read Wort) and his upbringing by the kindly Merlin and his obstinate talking owl Archimedes. I kept seeing recollections of past Disney (and other) cartoon forebears, everything from, naturally enough the Sorcerer's Apprentice from "Fantasia" and "Cinderella" while the chasing wolf early on is a blatant lift of Wile E Coyote in the "Road Runner" shorts. The old Disney trick of an experienced elder mentoring a young innocent had of course been done before in "Pinocchio" and "The Jungle Book" although I could also see some ideas which were adapted in future projects, the animated crockery anticipates "Beauty and the Beast" for instance. Disney never did return to the Arthurian Legnd in future animations as was hinted might happen here which is a pity but for me there's far too much diversion from the legend itself so that I was willing young Arthur to hurry up and give the sword the required pull long before the ending, which when it does arrive seems far too rushed in any case. No, not the best Disney by a long way and certainly not in the vanguard of the studio's work.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Kid-friendly King Arthur tale
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ersinkdotcom
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A young orphan named "Wart" wants nothing more than to be the squire to his older foster brother. Merlin the Magician sees more potential in the boy and begins training him for a greater destiny. "Wart" accompanies his brother to a tournament in London, where he will discover his true fate as Merlin's visions of greatness unfold. We all know how it feels when you remember a movie one way from childhood and realize as an adult it's not quite as it seemed. That was my feeling as I watched Disney's "The Sword in the Stone." Far be it for me to start slinging mud at what is considered to be a classic in the eyes of many. However, it became tedious watching Merlin the Magician teach "Wart" life lessons through turning himself and the boy into one animal after another and breaking into song. I've never been a big fan of any musicals. I'm sure this factor has everything to do with my lack of enthusiasm for "The Sword in the Stone." My preferred version of the Arthur story would lean more towards the adventurous "Excalibur." "The Sword in the Stone" does contain quite a bit of magic. Some people with certain religious convictions will find this a good reason to steer clear of the movie. I would have to say that anyone who watches "The Lord of the Rings" films has no right to throw rocks at this one. My 7-year old loved "The Sword in the Stone," so maybe I've just outgrown it. He's watched it twice already, where I found it near impossible to sit through once. If children like it, does it really matter what this old reviewer thinks about it anyway? It's been proved time and time again that Disney movies are critic-proof.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A triumph of fun and intelligence over animation 
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ElMaruecan82
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
     just like brain over brawn, Merlin's eternal motto. The initial reactions to "The Sword in the Stone" left me astonished. How could such a merry and original piece of animation get such negative criticism? From what I've read, nothing was spared: the animation didn't match the quality of previous Disney's works, the episodic structure lead to a conclusion disappointing because of the lack of a memorable plot line or a clearly defined antagonist  in this list of flaws, where I only concede the issue with Wart's voice, nothing seemed enjoyable enough to redeem the film: not Merlin's eccentric personality, not the humor made of unusual anachronistic references, not even the scene- stealing exuberance of Madame Mim. Well, since reviewing is about giving opinions, I'll give you mine: "The Sword in the Stone" was victim of an unfair bias constantly leaning on Disney's 'Golden Age' standards, while for one thing, it was a respectable attempt to take some distance from the usual formulas (and I'm pretty sure viewers enjoyed the new storytelling format, since the film ended-up being one of the highest grossing of 1963). And now that these fifty years of existence did justice to "Sword in the Stone", now that there are enough Disney animated features to make a clear distinction between the indisputable classics, the underrated gems, and the forgettable ones, I think we can all agree that "The Sword in the Stone" is in the same league than "The Jungle Book" or "Robin Hood", all contained in that entertaining parenthesis of the 60's-70's. And it's precisely the sketchy animation so typical of that period that elevates "The Sword in the Stone" to more interesting level of appreciation, more focused on the story, as the counterpart of such ambitious projects like "Sleeping Beauty", a film of dazzling imagery but certainly poorer story-wise. "The Sword in the Stone" is an educational journey guided by Merlin the wizard, whose long beard, blue pointed hat and long robe belong to the best of Disney iconography. His disciple is Wart, a twelve-year old boy, whose destiny is to become the future legendary King Arthur. The mentorship goes through different stages, using magic as an accessory but never as the crucial tool, in order to make Wart learn from practice, the values of the driving forces of our universe: physics, gravity or survival, all the stuff that makes 'things go round' and the greatest lesson of all being that brains always triumph on brawn. This 'brains over brawn' dichotomy is the pattern that forged human civilization and Merlin's divinatory power allowed him to check the validity of his point, what Wart would only see through experience. The film is made of many vignettes during which Arthur is turned into an animal. As a fish, he's victim of a bullying bull-frog before confronting a pike, as a squirrel, a female gets infatuated with him, turning the lesson on gravity into one about a much greater force. The third lesson involves Arthur as a sparrow learning to fly with Merlin's owl Archimedes, but his abrupt encounter with the witch Madame Mim, Merlin's archenemy, leads to one of Disney's greatest moments: the wizardry duel. The sequence is a triumph of imagination and animation combined, having both characters turning into various animals while conserving their defining traits is a delight to the eyes, and it concludes perfectly with Mim finally "catching" Merlin' but not the way she intended. Again, Merlin always proves his point. The secret of "The Sword in the Stone" lies essentially on its relative absence of a plot, and the episodic structure, which constitutes the basis of Merlin's mentorship. Each sequence is not only full of educational and philosophical value but stands alone as a great moment of animation. The fish part involves Arthur's first confrontation with a giant predator and the first opportunity to use his brains by turning his smaller size to his advantage. In the process, it also unveils an heroic facet in Archimedes' grouchy personality. The squirrel part, after a series of laughs driven by Merlin's misadventure with a fat beaver-like creature, finally illustrates Disney's formula that for every laugh, there should be a tear. And even if it's not 'Bambi' or 'Lion King', there's something extremely poignant and heart-breaking in the squirrel part's conclusion, even more because it's unexpected. But there are laughs in the film, and quite a lot, "The Sword in the Stone" is full of anachronisms, of priceless interactions between Merlin and Archimedes, who make a great pair of "Grumpy Old Men", and some hilarious scenes involving a wolf that have an irresistible Warner Bros cartoon feeling. And the few songs are so catchy we end up inevitably humming them while enjoying the animation.Who can resist to the sight of Merlin's furniture lined-up with a hot-tempered sugar pot on the lead, and being reduced over and over again to fit in a ridiculously small bag, or to the dishes washing by themselves motivated by all these "Hockity-Pockity" or "Higites-Figitus", which sound like improvement on "Cinderella"'s 'Bobbidi-Bibbidi"? The film isn't flawless, the irony that the more you like it, the more you watch it and discover some bits of repetitive or lazy animations. But "The Sword in the Stone" works thanks to its independence from a plot line's tyranny. Granted the film doesn't feature all the Disney archetypes, Mim is the main antagonist but not the larger-than-life villain with a heart- pounding demise. Even Arthur's foster father Ector has heart and his son Kay is more of a dim-witted comic relief. No abundance of songs, no memorable climax either except from the wizardry duel and the magical sword moment, but despite all these missing elements, "The Sword in the Stone", through its difference, marks itself among the most memorable work from Disney studios with an undeniable educational, intellectual and philosophical value.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nothing like the great book by T.H. White, and nowhere near the quality of other Disney classics
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Conrad
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The book "The Sword in the Stone" by T.H. White is a trove of wisdom for children and adults, and a paean of love to medieval England, but virtually none of the best material from the novel finds its way to the screen in this soulless adaptation. Most Disney classics are like stepping into a fantasy storybook, but this is little more than a cheap cartoon. Something meaningful could have been made of Arthur's encounter with an amorous squirrel (this occurs while he himself is in the body of a squirrel), something akin to the beautiful and literary swan episode in White's book, but while there is a hint of real emotion in the film's squirrel scene it is largely overshadowed by meaningless back-and-forths between Merlin's own squirrel avatar and a husky female of the species. This is a representative example of the movie's many missed opportunities.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    7th out of 8 in the Silver Era
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Centaurus3
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After the success of 101 Dalmatians, The Sword in The Stone was released in December of 1963, and the last animated film Walt Disney would see completed and released. The story is about a Wizard named Merlin, who teaches Arthur about life lessons and how to use his brain, as Merlin knows that Arthur is going to be something big. Arthur pulls out the sword, making him king. Most of the characters in this film are extremely boring, except for Madame Mim and Merlin. Mim is the bad wizard who appears in the last 15 minutes of the film, and is a bit bubbly despite being evil. Merlin is the original Genie with all the modern day references, and is the comic relief; he is a cool guy. Arthur does not warrant any interest at all, and the fact that he is voiced by 3 VOICE ACTORS is probably the only thing that stands out about him. All of the other characters (the deadhead father and son, etc) are extremely forgettable. This movie only has a few songs. "Higitus Figitus" is a Bibidi Bobidi Bo type song, but played down, and "Madame Mim" is just alright. The introduction song is pretty neat though. The soundtrack is just alright. The animation is not up to par with the previous films, and the Xerography in this movie makes it even more bland and forgettable than it is; they should have used the animation from the 50s, but that was too expensive. Here is where the reused animation in Disney films start to become obvious, as you would see the same animation sketches in the next few movies. The character designs are alright, but the animation is good when Merlin is using magic. With the weak plot, mostly weak characters, and everything else average, this movie is where the magic in Disney films start to wane away. This film is not very memorable, but there is some good and entertaining parts in the movie (Merlin vs Mim, squirrel scene). If you want to watch a Disney film that you have not watched in a while, this may be the movie. Give it a watch, you will find some moments you like, but don't expect it to be a great movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Sword in the Stone That Will Destine One For The Throne.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dawalk-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I remember seeing this among other Disney films I saw in elementary school (at least part of them anyway) and those that aired on non-cable t.v. Some years later, I viewed this on Youtube a while back and for some time afterward, I'd been considering and wanting to buy a copy of the 45th Anniversary edition of it. I finally did last month and it's great seeing it once again. I never really thought or paid attention to it as much as some, certain other Disney animated features, but now I think I have to concur that it's one of the more underrated ones. A boy named Arthur (a.k.a. Wart) has the dream of one day becoming a squire. But little does he know that he's destined for something much greater, which is being the new English king, which is the position he takes over later from his late father (although being new at this and not knowing much about a ruler's duties, Wart isn't so sure he's up to it). This occurs once he successfully pulls out the enchanted sword from the stone. That makes sense, considering he's his son and he eventually inherits his place on the throne. But before that, while going off to retrieve another sword in the woods for his foster brother Kay, he comes across a cottage where he meets the grand wizard, Merlin, and his highly intellectual owl, Archimedes. Merlin appoints himself as Wart's tutor and emphasizes brains used as associated with an education being more important than brawn. This movie has a lot of thrilling moments, such as Wart getting a feel of what it's like to be different animals through the help of Merlin's magic, Merlin's talks about what are yet to come from his time travels (which leaves anyone from his time he tries to explain to about them puzzled or perplexed) and what's one of the most renowned moments, if not the most renowned moment, the Wizard's Duel between Merlin and the witch Mad Madam Mim. I never read the initial source that inspired Disney's take, but I read a little there was mentioned about it in the difference between this and T.H. White's book, which is this version being more comical. Aside from the fact that again I never read the original source, I don't mind nor do I think I would even if I did. I recommend this to anyone who's into adventure. Because it has plenty of it, making it still outstanding nonetheless of other things.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What it lacks in plot, is mostly made up by humor
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Joshua Mitchell
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Sword In The Stone is a major disappointment. It's by no means a bad film, it's just disappointing. What I expected to be an origin film was really just a silly film about a boy with a wizard for a teacher. Don't let the title deceive you, this is not a movie about a sword in a stone, it's about a skinny young boy named Arthur- whom everyone calls Wart- who has a rather ruthless and obnoxious father and older brother. While hunting with his older brother, Kay, Wart discovers a wizard named Merlin and his frumpy owl, Archimedes. Merlin is convinced that it is his job to tutor the boy, and that's all there is to it. There's not nearly enough plot to last even the short 79 minute run time. This might've worked as a 15 minute short film, but as a feature length film, The Sword In The Stone feels padded and tedious. There's just not enough material. Which is a shame because The Sword In The Stone has so much potential. This could've been a marvelous rags-to-riches story, but alas, it's just a Ben Kneobi, Luke Skywalker tale. The Sword In The Stone does have some bright spots though, make no mistake. While a majority of the characters are dull and forgettable, Archimedes is at least slightly amusing, and Merlin is the real main character, and he steals all the scenes anyhow. The protagonist, Wart, is likable, if mostly forgettable. The animation is shockingly bland. Despite a beautiful underwater segment, The Sword In The Stone has little visual sparkle. There are songs too, but like many of the characters, they're forgettable. They're not bad by any means, just forgettable. At the minimum, they're not dull and that's good enough for me. The score, by recurring Disney composer George Bruns, is disappointingly mediocre. However, there's a wonderful jazz piece utilizing the piano during a scene in which Merlin uses magic to wash dishes. This is the only part of the score I can recommend, unfortunately. Some of the scenes are funny, if somewhat pointless to the actual story. The quarrels between Merlin and Archimedes are particularly amusing. There's also one scene towards the end, where Merlin battles a witch in a fun, yet completely illogical duel of magic. While The Sword In The Stone lacks a real plot, and ultimately has nothing to do with the sword in the stone, it's an occasionally fun ride with enough humor to be a mildly enjoyable diversion.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My favorite Disney film!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ravsten428
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I don't know exactly why many people don't praise this movie more. I absolutely love this film. There are not many songs in the movie but the ones that are in it are enjoyable. Merlin who is a wizard that can see centuries into the future and lives with his annoying but lovable owl Archimedes predicts that a young boy of around 11 or 12 will drop into his house and sure enough he's dead on. Merlin takes the young Wart who is the future King of England, on many adventures and tries to teach Wart that knowledge is power. Somewhere along the way Wart is appointed to be Kay's squire at a jousting competition. Merlin is upset by this and says "Blow me to Bermuda!" Merlin takes off and Wart and Archimedes are left alone. Here is where we find that Wart goes to pull out the sword in the stone because he forgot Kay's sword. He tells Sir Ector that he got the sword from the stone yet nobody believes him at first but they go back and find that he was really the one who pulled it and is therefore dubbed King Arthur, King of all England. I love the wizard's duel between Merlin and the evil Madam Mim. One of the best parts of the movie. And also the part where Merlin is being chased by the fat girl squirrel who takes a fancy to him. Love this film!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A lot of fun, but not among Disney's best
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RokurotaMakabe
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is Disney's version of the legend of King Arthur and it represents an adaptation of T.H. White's children's story. Here, Arthur is a young boy who is unaware of his great destiny. He meets and befriends the great wizard Merlin who decides to give him a proper instruction and education in order to prepare him for his future. The film has some great characters: Merlin the wizard and his intellectually trained owl Archimedes are particularly funny. The animation is very good, but this is Disney after all, so you would expect it to be like that. The film is definitely entertaining, but there are a few drawbacks as well. There are moments when it feels a little too similar to Disney's other animated features from that period. The film also incorporates a lot of plot elements from other Disney movies and the film is very predictable at times. In comparison to another Disney classic, "Sleeping Beauty", this film looks more like a secondary project. "The Sword in the Stone" is nevertheless a good film and it is superior to many of Disney's modern efforts ("Hercules", "The Hunchback of Notre Dame" or "Pocahontas" to name a few). It is very entertaining and definitely worth watching. My rating: 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Disney film not to be missed!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Kristine (kristinedrama14@msn.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I cannot believe I never wrote a comment on The Sword in the Stone, my friends always joke how I'm the ultimate Mickey Mouse since I'm such a fan and I own every Disney movie on DVD. I wanted to watch one of my movies last night and I picked The Sword in the Stone and rediscovered how much I loved this movie when I was a kid and still love it today. I went on IMDb to see if I gave the appropriate rating, but I was surprised to see that I never did write about it, but I guess better late then never. Sword in the Stone is just a classic treasure that no family should be without but also the film lovers. A wonderful classic story told Disney style and filled with great songs and beautiful animation, how could anyone not fall in love with The Sword in the Stone. The "Sword in the Stone" appears in London, with an inscription proclaiming that "Who so Pulleth Out This Sword of this Stone and Anvil, is Rightwise King Born of England." None succeed in removing the sword, which is soon forgotten, leaving England in a Dark Age. Some years later, Arthur aka "Wart", a 12-year-old orphan training to be a squire. While accompanying his older foster brother Kay on a hunting trip. He falls into Merlin's cottage, Merlin declares himself Wart's tutor and the two return to Wart's home, a castle run by Sir Ector, Arthur's foster father. There Merlin stays with Arthur to teach him the ways of the world and the magic as well as the intelligence and strength he will need for his true destiny. I think my favorite moment of this film is definitely the battle between Merlin and Mim, since this is one of the rare Disney movies that doesn't have a definitive villain, but I think Mim was a close as you could get. Their battle was epic and absolutely amazing to watch, plus I love the classic sound effects with good old slap stick humor. Also I loved the story when Merlin turned Arthur and himself into squirrels and they were attacked by the lady squirrels was just too cute for words. I know the animation isn't up to par with today's standards, but this is the exact animation that I loved growing up with because the animators seemed to have a love for the film they were making. The Sword in the Stone is a classic Disney film that should never be missed and I can't wait to show my children one day. Disney always had a way of taking classic stories that may not interest a small child and puts action, adventure, romance and wonderful animation into it and made it come to life. I can't believe I hadn't watched this movie since I was a kid, because no film lover should be without this treasure, it's just so excellent and magical, takes you back to a simpler time where we were destined for greatness and the world was at our fingertips. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stone cold
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jc-osms
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Pleasant Disney animation, without being a classic. It has its moments, particularly the magic-fight between Merlin and Mim, but is light on characterisation and especially good songs. The soundtrack tunes are very simplistic both melodically and especially lyrically and resolutely refuse to stay in your brain. The narrative itself is unusual, introducing the sword in the stone legend immediately and then dispensing with it until the last five minutes or so, concentrating its energies instead on young Arthur (read Wort) and his upbringing by the kindly Merlin and his obstinate talking owl Archimedes. I kept seeing recollections of past Disney (and other) cartoon forebears, everything from, naturally enough the Sorcerer's Apprentice from "Fantasia" and "Cinderella" while the chasing wolf early on is a blatant lift of Wile E Coyote in the "Road Runner" shorts. The old Disney trick of an experienced elder mentoring a young innocent had of course been done before in "Pinocchio" and "The Jungle Book" although I could also see some ideas which were adapted in future projects, the animated crockery anticipates "Beauty and the Beast" for instance. Disney never did return to the Arthurian Legnd in future animations as was hinted might happen here which is a pity but for me there's far too much diversion from the legend itself so that I was willing young Arthur to hurry up and give the sword the required pull long before the ending, which when it does arrive seems far too rushed in any case. No, not the best Disney by a long way and certainly not in the vanguard of the studio's work.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Kid-friendly King Arthur tale
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ersinkdotcom
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A young orphan named "Wart" wants nothing more than to be the squire to his older foster brother. Merlin the Magician sees more potential in the boy and begins training him for a greater destiny. "Wart" accompanies his brother to a tournament in London, where he will discover his true fate as Merlin's visions of greatness unfold. We all know how it feels when you remember a movie one way from childhood and realize as an adult it's not quite as it seemed. That was my feeling as I watched Disney's "The Sword in the Stone." Far be it for me to start slinging mud at what is considered to be a classic in the eyes of many. However, it became tedious watching Merlin the Magician teach "Wart" life lessons through turning himself and the boy into one animal after another and breaking into song. I've never been a big fan of any musicals. I'm sure this factor has everything to do with my lack of enthusiasm for "The Sword in the Stone." My preferred version of the Arthur story would lean more towards the adventurous "Excalibur." "The Sword in the Stone" does contain quite a bit of magic. Some people with certain religious convictions will find this a good reason to steer clear of the movie. I would have to say that anyone who watches "The Lord of the Rings" films has no right to throw rocks at this one. My 7-year old loved "The Sword in the Stone," so maybe I've just outgrown it. He's watched it twice already, where I found it near impossible to sit through once. If children like it, does it really matter what this old reviewer thinks about it anyway? It's been proved time and time again that Disney movies are critic-proof.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A triumph of fun and intelligence over animation 
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ElMaruecan82
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
     just like brain over brawn, Merlin's eternal motto. The initial reactions to "The Sword in the Stone" left me astonished. How could such a merry and original piece of animation get such negative criticism? From what I've read, nothing was spared: the animation didn't match the quality of previous Disney's works, the episodic structure lead to a conclusion disappointing because of the lack of a memorable plot line or a clearly defined antagonist  in this list of flaws, where I only concede the issue with Wart's voice, nothing seemed enjoyable enough to redeem the film: not Merlin's eccentric personality, not the humor made of unusual anachronistic references, not even the scene- stealing exuberance of Madame Mim. Well, since reviewing is about giving opinions, I'll give you mine: "The Sword in the Stone" was victim of an unfair bias constantly leaning on Disney's 'Golden Age' standards, while for one thing, it was a respectable attempt to take some distance from the usual formulas (and I'm pretty sure viewers enjoyed the new storytelling format, since the film ended-up being one of the highest grossing of 1963). And now that these fifty years of existence did justice to "Sword in the Stone", now that there are enough Disney animated features to make a clear distinction between the indisputable classics, the underrated gems, and the forgettable ones, I think we can all agree that "The Sword in the Stone" is in the same league than "The Jungle Book" or "Robin Hood", all contained in that entertaining parenthesis of the 60's-70's. And it's precisely the sketchy animation so typical of that period that elevates "The Sword in the Stone" to more interesting level of appreciation, more focused on the story, as the counterpart of such ambitious projects like "Sleeping Beauty", a film of dazzling imagery but certainly poorer story-wise. "The Sword in the Stone" is an educational journey guided by Merlin the wizard, whose long beard, blue pointed hat and long robe belong to the best of Disney iconography. His disciple is Wart, a twelve-year old boy, whose destiny is to become the future legendary King Arthur. The mentorship goes through different stages, using magic as an accessory but never as the crucial tool, in order to make Wart learn from practice, the values of the driving forces of our universe: physics, gravity or survival, all the stuff that makes 'things go round' and the greatest lesson of all being that brains always triumph on brawn. This 'brains over brawn' dichotomy is the pattern that forged human civilization and Merlin's divinatory power allowed him to check the validity of his point, what Wart would only see through experience. The film is made of many vignettes during which Arthur is turned into an animal. As a fish, he's victim of a bullying bull-frog before confronting a pike, as a squirrel, a female gets infatuated with him, turning the lesson on gravity into one about a much greater force. The third lesson involves Arthur as a sparrow learning to fly with Merlin's owl Archimedes, but his abrupt encounter with the witch Madame Mim, Merlin's archenemy, leads to one of Disney's greatest moments: the wizardry duel. The sequence is a triumph of imagination and animation combined, having both characters turning into various animals while conserving their defining traits is a delight to the eyes, and it concludes perfectly with Mim finally "catching" Merlin' but not the way she intended. Again, Merlin always proves his point. The secret of "The Sword in the Stone" lies essentially on its relative absence of a plot, and the episodic structure, which constitutes the basis of Merlin's mentorship. Each sequence is not only full of educational and philosophical value but stands alone as a great moment of animation. The fish part involves Arthur's first confrontation with a giant predator and the first opportunity to use his brains by turning his smaller size to his advantage. In the process, it also unveils an heroic facet in Archimedes' grouchy personality. The squirrel part, after a series of laughs driven by Merlin's misadventure with a fat beaver-like creature, finally illustrates Disney's formula that for every laugh, there should be a tear. And even if it's not 'Bambi' or 'Lion King', there's something extremely poignant and heart-breaking in the squirrel part's conclusion, even more because it's unexpected. But there are laughs in the film, and quite a lot, "The Sword in the Stone" is full of anachronisms, of priceless interactions between Merlin and Archimedes, who make a great pair of "Grumpy Old Men", and some hilarious scenes involving a wolf that have an irresistible Warner Bros cartoon feeling. And the few songs are so catchy we end up inevitably humming them while enjoying the animation.Who can resist to the sight of Merlin's furniture lined-up with a hot-tempered sugar pot on the lead, and being reduced over and over again to fit in a ridiculously small bag, or to the dishes washing by themselves motivated by all these "Hockity-Pockity" or "Higites-Figitus", which sound like improvement on "Cinderella"'s 'Bobbidi-Bibbidi"? The film isn't flawless, the irony that the more you like it, the more you watch it and discover some bits of repetitive or lazy animations. But "The Sword in the Stone" works thanks to its independence from a plot line's tyranny. Granted the film doesn't feature all the Disney archetypes, Mim is the main antagonist but not the larger-than-life villain with a heart- pounding demise. Even Arthur's foster father Ector has heart and his son Kay is more of a dim-witted comic relief. No abundance of songs, no memorable climax either except from the wizardry duel and the magical sword moment, but despite all these missing elements, "The Sword in the Stone", through its difference, marks itself among the most memorable work from Disney studios with an undeniable educational, intellectual and philosophical value.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nothing like the great book by T.H. White, and nowhere near the quality of other Disney classics
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Conrad
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The book "The Sword in the Stone" by T.H. White is a trove of wisdom for children and adults, and a paean of love to medieval England, but virtually none of the best material from the novel finds its way to the screen in this soulless adaptation. Most Disney classics are like stepping into a fantasy storybook, but this is little more than a cheap cartoon. Something meaningful could have been made of Arthur's encounter with an amorous squirrel (this occurs while he himself is in the body of a squirrel), something akin to the beautiful and literary swan episode in White's book, but while there is a hint of real emotion in the film's squirrel scene it is largely overshadowed by meaningless back-and-forths between Merlin's own squirrel avatar and a husky female of the species. This is a representative example of the movie's many missed opportunities.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    7th out of 8 in the Silver Era
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Centaurus3
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After the success of 101 Dalmatians, The Sword in The Stone was released in December of 1963, and the last animated film Walt Disney would see completed and released. The story is about a Wizard named Merlin, who teaches Arthur about life lessons and how to use his brain, as Merlin knows that Arthur is going to be something big. Arthur pulls out the sword, making him king. Most of the characters in this film are extremely boring, except for Madame Mim and Merlin. Mim is the bad wizard who appears in the last 15 minutes of the film, and is a bit bubbly despite being evil. Merlin is the original Genie with all the modern day references, and is the comic relief; he is a cool guy. Arthur does not warrant any interest at all, and the fact that he is voiced by 3 VOICE ACTORS is probably the only thing that stands out about him. All of the other characters (the deadhead father and son, etc) are extremely forgettable. This movie only has a few songs. "Higitus Figitus" is a Bibidi Bobidi Bo type song, but played down, and "Madame Mim" is just alright. The introduction song is pretty neat though. The soundtrack is just alright. The animation is not up to par with the previous films, and the Xerography in this movie makes it even more bland and forgettable than it is; they should have used the animation from the 50s, but that was too expensive. Here is where the reused animation in Disney films start to become obvious, as you would see the same animation sketches in the next few movies. The character designs are alright, but the animation is good when Merlin is using magic. With the weak plot, mostly weak characters, and everything else average, this movie is where the magic in Disney films start to wane away. This film is not very memorable, but there is some good and entertaining parts in the movie (Merlin vs Mim, squirrel scene). If you want to watch a Disney film that you have not watched in a while, this may be the movie. Give it a watch, you will find some moments you like, but don't expect it to be a great movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Sword in the Stone That Will Destine One For The Throne.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dawalk-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I remember seeing this among other Disney films I saw in elementary school (at least part of them anyway) and those that aired on non-cable t.v. Some years later, I viewed this on Youtube a while back and for some time afterward, I'd been considering and wanting to buy a copy of the 45th Anniversary edition of it. I finally did last month and it's great seeing it once again. I never really thought or paid attention to it as much as some, certain other Disney animated features, but now I think I have to concur that it's one of the more underrated ones. A boy named Arthur (a.k.a. Wart) has the dream of one day becoming a squire. But little does he know that he's destined for something much greater, which is being the new English king, which is the position he takes over later from his late father (although being new at this and not knowing much about a ruler's duties, Wart isn't so sure he's up to it). This occurs once he successfully pulls out the enchanted sword from the stone. That makes sense, considering he's his son and he eventually inherits his place on the throne. But before that, while going off to retrieve another sword in the woods for his foster brother Kay, he comes across a cottage where he meets the grand wizard, Merlin, and his highly intellectual owl, Archimedes. Merlin appoints himself as Wart's tutor and emphasizes brains used as associated with an education being more important than brawn. This movie has a lot of thrilling moments, such as Wart getting a feel of what it's like to be different animals through the help of Merlin's magic, Merlin's talks about what are yet to come from his time travels (which leaves anyone from his time he tries to explain to about them puzzled or perplexed) and what's one of the most renowned moments, if not the most renowned moment, the Wizard's Duel between Merlin and the witch Mad Madam Mim. I never read the initial source that inspired Disney's take, but I read a little there was mentioned about it in the difference between this and T.H. White's book, which is this version being more comical. Aside from the fact that again I never read the original source, I don't mind nor do I think I would even if I did. I recommend this to anyone who's into adventure. Because it has plenty of it, making it still outstanding nonetheless of other things.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What it lacks in plot, is mostly made up by humor
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Joshua Mitchell
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Sword In The Stone is a major disappointment. It's by no means a bad film, it's just disappointing. What I expected to be an origin film was really just a silly film about a boy with a wizard for a teacher. Don't let the title deceive you, this is not a movie about a sword in a stone, it's about a skinny young boy named Arthur- whom everyone calls Wart- who has a rather ruthless and obnoxious father and older brother. While hunting with his older brother, Kay, Wart discovers a wizard named Merlin and his frumpy owl, Archimedes. Merlin is convinced that it is his job to tutor the boy, and that's all there is to it. There's not nearly enough plot to last even the short 79 minute run time. This might've worked as a 15 minute short film, but as a feature length film, The Sword In The Stone feels padded and tedious. There's just not enough material. Which is a shame because The Sword In The Stone has so much potential. This could've been a marvelous rags-to-riches story, but alas, it's just a Ben Kneobi, Luke Skywalker tale. The Sword In The Stone does have some bright spots though, make no mistake. While a majority of the characters are dull and forgettable, Archimedes is at least slightly amusing, and Merlin is the real main character, and he steals all the scenes anyhow. The protagonist, Wart, is likable, if mostly forgettable. The animation is shockingly bland. Despite a beautiful underwater segment, The Sword In The Stone has little visual sparkle. There are songs too, but like many of the characters, they're forgettable. They're not bad by any means, just forgettable. At the minimum, they're not dull and that's good enough for me. The score, by recurring Disney composer George Bruns, is disappointingly mediocre. However, there's a wonderful jazz piece utilizing the piano during a scene in which Merlin uses magic to wash dishes. This is the only part of the score I can recommend, unfortunately. Some of the scenes are funny, if somewhat pointless to the actual story. The quarrels between Merlin and Archimedes are particularly amusing. There's also one scene towards the end, where Merlin battles a witch in a fun, yet completely illogical duel of magic. While The Sword In The Stone lacks a real plot, and ultimately has nothing to do with the sword in the stone, it's an occasionally fun ride with enough humor to be a mildly enjoyable diversion.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My favorite Disney film!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ravsten428
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I don't know exactly why many people don't praise this movie more. I absolutely love this film. There are not many songs in the movie but the ones that are in it are enjoyable. Merlin who is a wizard that can see centuries into the future and lives with his annoying but lovable owl Archimedes predicts that a young boy of around 11 or 12 will drop into his house and sure enough he's dead on. Merlin takes the young Wart who is the future King of England, on many adventures and tries to teach Wart that knowledge is power. Somewhere along the way Wart is appointed to be Kay's squire at a jousting competition. Merlin is upset by this and says "Blow me to Bermuda!" Merlin takes off and Wart and Archimedes are left alone. Here is where we find that Wart goes to pull out the sword in the stone because he forgot Kay's sword. He tells Sir Ector that he got the sword from the stone yet nobody believes him at first but they go back and find that he was really the one who pulled it and is therefore dubbed King Arthur, King of all England. I love the wizard's duel between Merlin and the evil Madam Mim. One of the best parts of the movie. And also the part where Merlin is being chased by the fat girl squirrel who takes a fancy to him. Love this film!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A lot of fun, but not among Disney's best
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RokurotaMakabe
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is Disney's version of the legend of King Arthur and it represents an adaptation of T.H. White's children's story. Here, Arthur is a young boy who is unaware of his great destiny. He meets and befriends the great wizard Merlin who decides to give him a proper instruction and education in order to prepare him for his future. The film has some great characters: Merlin the wizard and his intellectually trained owl Archimedes are particularly funny. The animation is very good, but this is Disney after all, so you would expect it to be like that. The film is definitely entertaining, but there are a few drawbacks as well. There are moments when it feels a little too similar to Disney's other animated features from that period. The film also incorporates a lot of plot elements from other Disney movies and the film is very predictable at times. In comparison to another Disney classic, "Sleeping Beauty", this film looks more like a secondary project. "The Sword in the Stone" is nevertheless a good film and it is superior to many of Disney's modern efforts ("Hercules", "The Hunchback of Notre Dame" or "Pocahontas" to name a few). It is very entertaining and definitely worth watching. My rating: 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Disney film not to be missed!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Kristine (kristinedrama14@msn.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I cannot believe I never wrote a comment on The Sword in the Stone, my friends always joke how I'm the ultimate Mickey Mouse since I'm such a fan and I own every Disney movie on DVD. I wanted to watch one of my movies last night and I picked The Sword in the Stone and rediscovered how much I loved this movie when I was a kid and still love it today. I went on IMDb to see if I gave the appropriate rating, but I was surprised to see that I never did write about it, but I guess better late then never. Sword in the Stone is just a classic treasure that no family should be without but also the film lovers. A wonderful classic story told Disney style and filled with great songs and beautiful animation, how could anyone not fall in love with The Sword in the Stone. The "Sword in the Stone" appears in London, with an inscription proclaiming that "Who so Pulleth Out This Sword of this Stone and Anvil, is Rightwise King Born of England." None succeed in removing the sword, which is soon forgotten, leaving England in a Dark Age. Some years later, Arthur aka "Wart", a 12-year-old orphan training to be a squire. While accompanying his older foster brother Kay on a hunting trip. He falls into Merlin's cottage, Merlin declares himself Wart's tutor and the two return to Wart's home, a castle run by Sir Ector, Arthur's foster father. There Merlin stays with Arthur to teach him the ways of the world and the magic as well as the intelligence and strength he will need for his true destiny. I think my favorite moment of this film is definitely the battle between Merlin and Mim, since this is one of the rare Disney movies that doesn't have a definitive villain, but I think Mim was a close as you could get. Their battle was epic and absolutely amazing to watch, plus I love the classic sound effects with good old slap stick humor. Also I loved the story when Merlin turned Arthur and himself into squirrels and they were attacked by the lady squirrels was just too cute for words. I know the animation isn't up to par with today's standards, but this is the exact animation that I loved growing up with because the animators seemed to have a love for the film they were making. The Sword in the Stone is a classic Disney film that should never be missed and I can't wait to show my children one day. Disney always had a way of taking classic stories that may not interest a small child and puts action, adventure, romance and wonderful animation into it and made it come to life. I can't believe I hadn't watched this movie since I was a kid, because no film lover should be without this treasure, it's just so excellent and magical, takes you back to a simpler time where we were destined for greatness and the world was at our fingertips. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stone cold
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jc-osms
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Pleasant Disney animation, without being a classic. It has its moments, particularly the magic-fight between Merlin and Mim, but is light on characterisation and especially good songs. The soundtrack tunes are very simplistic both melodically and especially lyrically and resolutely refuse to stay in your brain. The narrative itself is unusual, introducing the sword in the stone legend immediately and then dispensing with it until the last five minutes or so, concentrating its energies instead on young Arthur (read Wort) and his upbringing by the kindly Merlin and his obstinate talking owl Archimedes. I kept seeing recollections of past Disney (and other) cartoon forebears, everything from, naturally enough the Sorcerer's Apprentice from "Fantasia" and "Cinderella" while the chasing wolf early on is a blatant lift of Wile E Coyote in the "Road Runner" shorts. The old Disney trick of an experienced elder mentoring a young innocent had of course been done before in "Pinocchio" and "The Jungle Book" although I could also see some ideas which were adapted in future projects, the animated crockery anticipates "Beauty and the Beast" for instance. Disney never did return to the Arthurian Legnd in future animations as was hinted might happen here which is a pity but for me there's far too much diversion from the legend itself so that I was willing young Arthur to hurry up and give the sword the required pull long before the ending, which when it does arrive seems far too rushed in any case. No, not the best Disney by a long way and certainly not in the vanguard of the studio's work.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Kid-friendly King Arthur tale
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ersinkdotcom
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A young orphan named "Wart" wants nothing more than to be the squire to his older foster brother. Merlin the Magician sees more potential in the boy and begins training him for a greater destiny. "Wart" accompanies his brother to a tournament in London, where he will discover his true fate as Merlin's visions of greatness unfold. We all know how it feels when you remember a movie one way from childhood and realize as an adult it's not quite as it seemed. That was my feeling as I watched Disney's "The Sword in the Stone." Far be it for me to start slinging mud at what is considered to be a classic in the eyes of many. However, it became tedious watching Merlin the Magician teach "Wart" life lessons through turning himself and the boy into one animal after another and breaking into song. I've never been a big fan of any musicals. I'm sure this factor has everything to do with my lack of enthusiasm for "The Sword in the Stone." My preferred version of the Arthur story would lean more towards the adventurous "Excalibur." "The Sword in the Stone" does contain quite a bit of magic. Some people with certain religious convictions will find this a good reason to steer clear of the movie. I would have to say that anyone who watches "The Lord of the Rings" films has no right to throw rocks at this one. My 7-year old loved "The Sword in the Stone," so maybe I've just outgrown it. He's watched it twice already, where I found it near impossible to sit through once. If children like it, does it really matter what this old reviewer thinks about it anyway? It's been proved time and time again that Disney movies are critic-proof.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A triumph of fun and intelligence over animation 
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ElMaruecan82
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
     just like brain over brawn, Merlin's eternal motto. The initial reactions to "The Sword in the Stone" left me astonished. How could such a merry and original piece of animation get such negative criticism? From what I've read, nothing was spared: the animation didn't match the quality of previous Disney's works, the episodic structure lead to a conclusion disappointing because of the lack of a memorable plot line or a clearly defined antagonist  in this list of flaws, where I only concede the issue with Wart's voice, nothing seemed enjoyable enough to redeem the film: not Merlin's eccentric personality, not the humor made of unusual anachronistic references, not even the scene- stealing exuberance of Madame Mim. Well, since reviewing is about giving opinions, I'll give you mine: "The Sword in the Stone" was victim of an unfair bias constantly leaning on Disney's 'Golden Age' standards, while for one thing, it was a respectable attempt to take some distance from the usual formulas (and I'm pretty sure viewers enjoyed the new storytelling format, since the film ended-up being one of the highest grossing of 1963). And now that these fifty years of existence did justice to "Sword in the Stone", now that there are enough Disney animated features to make a clear distinction between the indisputable classics, the underrated gems, and the forgettable ones, I think we can all agree that "The Sword in the Stone" is in the same league than "The Jungle Book" or "Robin Hood", all contained in that entertaining parenthesis of the 60's-70's. And it's precisely the sketchy animation so typical of that period that elevates "The Sword in the Stone" to more interesting level of appreciation, more focused on the story, as the counterpart of such ambitious projects like "Sleeping Beauty", a film of dazzling imagery but certainly poorer story-wise. "The Sword in the Stone" is an educational journey guided by Merlin the wizard, whose long beard, blue pointed hat and long robe belong to the best of Disney iconography. His disciple is Wart, a twelve-year old boy, whose destiny is to become the future legendary King Arthur. The mentorship goes through different stages, using magic as an accessory but never as the crucial tool, in order to make Wart learn from practice, the values of the driving forces of our universe: physics, gravity or survival, all the stuff that makes 'things go round' and the greatest lesson of all being that brains always triumph on brawn. This 'brains over brawn' dichotomy is the pattern that forged human civilization and Merlin's divinatory power allowed him to check the validity of his point, what Wart would only see through experience. The film is made of many vignettes during which Arthur is turned into an animal. As a fish, he's victim of a bullying bull-frog before confronting a pike, as a squirrel, a female gets infatuated with him, turning the lesson on gravity into one about a much greater force. The third lesson involves Arthur as a sparrow learning to fly with Merlin's owl Archimedes, but his abrupt encounter with the witch Madame Mim, Merlin's archenemy, leads to one of Disney's greatest moments: the wizardry duel. The sequence is a triumph of imagination and animation combined, having both characters turning into various animals while conserving their defining traits is a delight to the eyes, and it concludes perfectly with Mim finally "catching" Merlin' but not the way she intended. Again, Merlin always proves his point. The secret of "The Sword in the Stone" lies essentially on its relative absence of a plot, and the episodic structure, which constitutes the basis of Merlin's mentorship. Each sequence is not only full of educational and philosophical value but stands alone as a great moment of animation. The fish part involves Arthur's first confrontation with a giant predator and the first opportunity to use his brains by turning his smaller size to his advantage. In the process, it also unveils an heroic facet in Archimedes' grouchy personality. The squirrel part, after a series of laughs driven by Merlin's misadventure with a fat beaver-like creature, finally illustrates Disney's formula that for every laugh, there should be a tear. And even if it's not 'Bambi' or 'Lion King', there's something extremely poignant and heart-breaking in the squirrel part's conclusion, even more because it's unexpected. But there are laughs in the film, and quite a lot, "The Sword in the Stone" is full of anachronisms, of priceless interactions between Merlin and Archimedes, who make a great pair of "Grumpy Old Men", and some hilarious scenes involving a wolf that have an irresistible Warner Bros cartoon feeling. And the few songs are so catchy we end up inevitably humming them while enjoying the animation.Who can resist to the sight of Merlin's furniture lined-up with a hot-tempered sugar pot on the lead, and being reduced over and over again to fit in a ridiculously small bag, or to the dishes washing by themselves motivated by all these "Hockity-Pockity" or "Higites-Figitus", which sound like improvement on "Cinderella"'s 'Bobbidi-Bibbidi"? The film isn't flawless, the irony that the more you like it, the more you watch it and discover some bits of repetitive or lazy animations. But "The Sword in the Stone" works thanks to its independence from a plot line's tyranny. Granted the film doesn't feature all the Disney archetypes, Mim is the main antagonist but not the larger-than-life villain with a heart- pounding demise. Even Arthur's foster father Ector has heart and his son Kay is more of a dim-witted comic relief. No abundance of songs, no memorable climax either except from the wizardry duel and the magical sword moment, but despite all these missing elements, "The Sword in the Stone", through its difference, marks itself among the most memorable work from Disney studios with an undeniable educational, intellectual and philosophical value.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nothing like the great book by T.H. White, and nowhere near the quality of other Disney classics
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Conrad
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The book "The Sword in the Stone" by T.H. White is a trove of wisdom for children and adults, and a paean of love to medieval England, but virtually none of the best material from the novel finds its way to the screen in this soulless adaptation. Most Disney classics are like stepping into a fantasy storybook, but this is little more than a cheap cartoon. Something meaningful could have been made of Arthur's encounter with an amorous squirrel (this occurs while he himself is in the body of a squirrel), something akin to the beautiful and literary swan episode in White's book, but while there is a hint of real emotion in the film's squirrel scene it is largely overshadowed by meaningless back-and-forths between Merlin's own squirrel avatar and a husky female of the species. This is a representative example of the movie's many missed opportunities.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    7th out of 8 in the Silver Era
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Centaurus3
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After the success of 101 Dalmatians, The Sword in The Stone was released in December of 1963, and the last animated film Walt Disney would see completed and released. The story is about a Wizard named Merlin, who teaches Arthur about life lessons and how to use his brain, as Merlin knows that Arthur is going to be something big. Arthur pulls out the sword, making him king. Most of the characters in this film are extremely boring, except for Madame Mim and Merlin. Mim is the bad wizard who appears in the last 15 minutes of the film, and is a bit bubbly despite being evil. Merlin is the original Genie with all the modern day references, and is the comic relief; he is a cool guy. Arthur does not warrant any interest at all, and the fact that he is voiced by 3 VOICE ACTORS is probably the only thing that stands out about him. All of the other characters (the deadhead father and son, etc) are extremely forgettable. This movie only has a few songs. "Higitus Figitus" is a Bibidi Bobidi Bo type song, but played down, and "Madame Mim" is just alright. The introduction song is pretty neat though. The soundtrack is just alright. The animation is not up to par with the previous films, and the Xerography in this movie makes it even more bland and forgettable than it is; they should have used the animation from the 50s, but that was too expensive. Here is where the reused animation in Disney films start to become obvious, as you would see the same animation sketches in the next few movies. The character designs are alright, but the animation is good when Merlin is using magic. With the weak plot, mostly weak characters, and everything else average, this movie is where the magic in Disney films start to wane away. This film is not very memorable, but there is some good and entertaining parts in the movie (Merlin vs Mim, squirrel scene). If you want to watch a Disney film that you have not watched in a while, this may be the movie. Give it a watch, you will find some moments you like, but don't expect it to be a great movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Sword in the Stone That Will Destine One For The Throne.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dawalk-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I remember seeing this among other Disney films I saw in elementary school (at least part of them anyway) and those that aired on non-cable t.v. Some years later, I viewed this on Youtube a while back and for some time afterward, I'd been considering and wanting to buy a copy of the 45th Anniversary edition of it. I finally did last month and it's great seeing it once again. I never really thought or paid attention to it as much as some, certain other Disney animated features, but now I think I have to concur that it's one of the more underrated ones. A boy named Arthur (a.k.a. Wart) has the dream of one day becoming a squire. But little does he know that he's destined for something much greater, which is being the new English king, which is the position he takes over later from his late father (although being new at this and not knowing much about a ruler's duties, Wart isn't so sure he's up to it). This occurs once he successfully pulls out the enchanted sword from the stone. That makes sense, considering he's his son and he eventually inherits his place on the throne. But before that, while going off to retrieve another sword in the woods for his foster brother Kay, he comes across a cottage where he meets the grand wizard, Merlin, and his highly intellectual owl, Archimedes. Merlin appoints himself as Wart's tutor and emphasizes brains used as associated with an education being more important than brawn. This movie has a lot of thrilling moments, such as Wart getting a feel of what it's like to be different animals through the help of Merlin's magic, Merlin's talks about what are yet to come from his time travels (which leaves anyone from his time he tries to explain to about them puzzled or perplexed) and what's one of the most renowned moments, if not the most renowned moment, the Wizard's Duel between Merlin and the witch Mad Madam Mim. I never read the initial source that inspired Disney's take, but I read a little there was mentioned about it in the difference between this and T.H. White's book, which is this version being more comical. Aside from the fact that again I never read the original source, I don't mind nor do I think I would even if I did. I recommend this to anyone who's into adventure. Because it has plenty of it, making it still outstanding nonetheless of other things.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What it lacks in plot, is mostly made up by humor
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Joshua Mitchell
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Sword In The Stone is a major disappointment. It's by no means a bad film, it's just disappointing. What I expected to be an origin film was really just a silly film about a boy with a wizard for a teacher. Don't let the title deceive you, this is not a movie about a sword in a stone, it's about a skinny young boy named Arthur- whom everyone calls Wart- who has a rather ruthless and obnoxious father and older brother. While hunting with his older brother, Kay, Wart discovers a wizard named Merlin and his frumpy owl, Archimedes. Merlin is convinced that it is his job to tutor the boy, and that's all there is to it. There's not nearly enough plot to last even the short 79 minute run time. This might've worked as a 15 minute short film, but as a feature length film, The Sword In The Stone feels padded and tedious. There's just not enough material. Which is a shame because The Sword In The Stone has so much potential. This could've been a marvelous rags-to-riches story, but alas, it's just a Ben Kneobi, Luke Skywalker tale. The Sword In The Stone does have some bright spots though, make no mistake. While a majority of the characters are dull and forgettable, Archimedes is at least slightly amusing, and Merlin is the real main character, and he steals all the scenes anyhow. The protagonist, Wart, is likable, if mostly forgettable. The animation is shockingly bland. Despite a beautiful underwater segment, The Sword In The Stone has little visual sparkle. There are songs too, but like many of the characters, they're forgettable. They're not bad by any means, just forgettable. At the minimum, they're not dull and that's good enough for me. The score, by recurring Disney composer George Bruns, is disappointingly mediocre. However, there's a wonderful jazz piece utilizing the piano during a scene in which Merlin uses magic to wash dishes. This is the only part of the score I can recommend, unfortunately. Some of the scenes are funny, if somewhat pointless to the actual story. The quarrels between Merlin and Archimedes are particularly amusing. There's also one scene towards the end, where Merlin battles a witch in a fun, yet completely illogical duel of magic. While The Sword In The Stone lacks a real plot, and ultimately has nothing to do with the sword in the stone, it's an occasionally fun ride with enough humor to be a mildly enjoyable diversion.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My favorite Disney film!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ravsten428
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I don't know exactly why many people don't praise this movie more. I absolutely love this film. There are not many songs in the movie but the ones that are in it are enjoyable. Merlin who is a wizard that can see centuries into the future and lives with his annoying but lovable owl Archimedes predicts that a young boy of around 11 or 12 will drop into his house and sure enough he's dead on. Merlin takes the young Wart who is the future King of England, on many adventures and tries to teach Wart that knowledge is power. Somewhere along the way Wart is appointed to be Kay's squire at a jousting competition. Merlin is upset by this and says "Blow me to Bermuda!" Merlin takes off and Wart and Archimedes are left alone. Here is where we find that Wart goes to pull out the sword in the stone because he forgot Kay's sword. He tells Sir Ector that he got the sword from the stone yet nobody believes him at first but they go back and find that he was really the one who pulled it and is therefore dubbed King Arthur, King of all England. I love the wizard's duel between Merlin and the evil Madam Mim. One of the best parts of the movie. And also the part where Merlin is being chased by the fat girl squirrel who takes a fancy to him. Love this film!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A lot of fun, but not among Disney's best
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RokurotaMakabe
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is Disney's version of the legend of King Arthur and it represents an adaptation of T.H. White's children's story. Here, Arthur is a young boy who is unaware of his great destiny. He meets and befriends the great wizard Merlin who decides to give him a proper instruction and education in order to prepare him for his future. The film has some great characters: Merlin the wizard and his intellectually trained owl Archimedes are particularly funny. The animation is very good, but this is Disney after all, so you would expect it to be like that. The film is definitely entertaining, but there are a few drawbacks as well. There are moments when it feels a little too similar to Disney's other animated features from that period. The film also incorporates a lot of plot elements from other Disney movies and the film is very predictable at times. In comparison to another Disney classic, "Sleeping Beauty", this film looks more like a secondary project. "The Sword in the Stone" is nevertheless a good film and it is superior to many of Disney's modern efforts ("Hercules", "The Hunchback of Notre Dame" or "Pocahontas" to name a few). It is very entertaining and definitely worth watching. My rating: 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Disney film not to be missed!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Kristine (kristinedrama14@msn.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I cannot believe I never wrote a comment on The Sword in the Stone, my friends always joke how I'm the ultimate Mickey Mouse since I'm such a fan and I own every Disney movie on DVD. I wanted to watch one of my movies last night and I picked The Sword in the Stone and rediscovered how much I loved this movie when I was a kid and still love it today. I went on IMDb to see if I gave the appropriate rating, but I was surprised to see that I never did write about it, but I guess better late then never. Sword in the Stone is just a classic treasure that no family should be without but also the film lovers. A wonderful classic story told Disney style and filled with great songs and beautiful animation, how could anyone not fall in love with The Sword in the Stone. The "Sword in the Stone" appears in London, with an inscription proclaiming that "Who so Pulleth Out This Sword of this Stone and Anvil, is Rightwise King Born of England." None succeed in removing the sword, which is soon forgotten, leaving England in a Dark Age. Some years later, Arthur aka "Wart", a 12-year-old orphan training to be a squire. While accompanying his older foster brother Kay on a hunting trip. He falls into Merlin's cottage, Merlin declares himself Wart's tutor and the two return to Wart's home, a castle run by Sir Ector, Arthur's foster father. There Merlin stays with Arthur to teach him the ways of the world and the magic as well as the intelligence and strength he will need for his true destiny. I think my favorite moment of this film is definitely the battle between Merlin and Mim, since this is one of the rare Disney movies that doesn't have a definitive villain, but I think Mim was a close as you could get. Their battle was epic and absolutely amazing to watch, plus I love the classic sound effects with good old slap stick humor. Also I loved the story when Merlin turned Arthur and himself into squirrels and they were attacked by the lady squirrels was just too cute for words. I know the animation isn't up to par with today's standards, but this is the exact animation that I loved growing up with because the animators seemed to have a love for the film they were making. The Sword in the Stone is a classic Disney film that should never be missed and I can't wait to show my children one day. Disney always had a way of taking classic stories that may not interest a small child and puts action, adventure, romance and wonderful animation into it and made it come to life. I can't believe I hadn't watched this movie since I was a kid, because no film lover should be without this treasure, it's just so excellent and magical, takes you back to a simpler time where we were destined for greatness and the world was at our fingertips. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stone cold
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jc-osms
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Pleasant Disney animation, without being a classic. It has its moments, particularly the magic-fight between Merlin and Mim, but is light on characterisation and especially good songs. The soundtrack tunes are very simplistic both melodically and especially lyrically and resolutely refuse to stay in your brain. The narrative itself is unusual, introducing the sword in the stone legend immediately and then dispensing with it until the last five minutes or so, concentrating its energies instead on young Arthur (read Wort) and his upbringing by the kindly Merlin and his obstinate talking owl Archimedes. I kept seeing recollections of past Disney (and other) cartoon forebears, everything from, naturally enough the Sorcerer's Apprentice from "Fantasia" and "Cinderella" while the chasing wolf early on is a blatant lift of Wile E Coyote in the "Road Runner" shorts. The old Disney trick of an experienced elder mentoring a young innocent had of course been done before in "Pinocchio" and "The Jungle Book" although I could also see some ideas which were adapted in future projects, the animated crockery anticipates "Beauty and the Beast" for instance. Disney never did return to the Arthurian Legnd in future animations as was hinted might happen here which is a pity but for me there's far too much diversion from the legend itself so that I was willing young Arthur to hurry up and give the sword the required pull long before the ending, which when it does arrive seems far too rushed in any case. No, not the best Disney by a long way and certainly not in the vanguard of the studio's work.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Kid-friendly King Arthur tale
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ersinkdotcom
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A young orphan named "Wart" wants nothing more than to be the squire to his older foster brother. Merlin the Magician sees more potential in the boy and begins training him for a greater destiny. "Wart" accompanies his brother to a tournament in London, where he will discover his true fate as Merlin's visions of greatness unfold. We all know how it feels when you remember a movie one way from childhood and realize as an adult it's not quite as it seemed. That was my feeling as I watched Disney's "The Sword in the Stone." Far be it for me to start slinging mud at what is considered to be a classic in the eyes of many. However, it became tedious watching Merlin the Magician teach "Wart" life lessons through turning himself and the boy into one animal after another and breaking into song. I've never been a big fan of any musicals. I'm sure this factor has everything to do with my lack of enthusiasm for "The Sword in the Stone." My preferred version of the Arthur story would lean more towards the adventurous "Excalibur." "The Sword in the Stone" does contain quite a bit of magic. Some people with certain religious convictions will find this a good reason to steer clear of the movie. I would have to say that anyone who watches "The Lord of the Rings" films has no right to throw rocks at this one. My 7-year old loved "The Sword in the Stone," so maybe I've just outgrown it. He's watched it twice already, where I found it near impossible to sit through once. If children like it, does it really matter what this old reviewer thinks about it anyway? It's been proved time and time again that Disney movies are critic-proof.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A triumph of fun and intelligence over animation 
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ElMaruecan82
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
     just like brain over brawn, Merlin's eternal motto. The initial reactions to "The Sword in the Stone" left me astonished. How could such a merry and original piece of animation get such negative criticism? From what I've read, nothing was spared: the animation didn't match the quality of previous Disney's works, the episodic structure lead to a conclusion disappointing because of the lack of a memorable plot line or a clearly defined antagonist  in this list of flaws, where I only concede the issue with Wart's voice, nothing seemed enjoyable enough to redeem the film: not Merlin's eccentric personality, not the humor made of unusual anachronistic references, not even the scene- stealing exuberance of Madame Mim. Well, since reviewing is about giving opinions, I'll give you mine: "The Sword in the Stone" was victim of an unfair bias constantly leaning on Disney's 'Golden Age' standards, while for one thing, it was a respectable attempt to take some distance from the usual formulas (and I'm pretty sure viewers enjoyed the new storytelling format, since the film ended-up being one of the highest grossing of 1963). And now that these fifty years of existence did justice to "Sword in the Stone", now that there are enough Disney animated features to make a clear distinction between the indisputable classics, the underrated gems, and the forgettable ones, I think we can all agree that "The Sword in the Stone" is in the same league than "The Jungle Book" or "Robin Hood", all contained in that entertaining parenthesis of the 60's-70's. And it's precisely the sketchy animation so typical of that period that elevates "The Sword in the Stone" to more interesting level of appreciation, more focused on the story, as the counterpart of such ambitious projects like "Sleeping Beauty", a film of dazzling imagery but certainly poorer story-wise. "The Sword in the Stone" is an educational journey guided by Merlin the wizard, whose long beard, blue pointed hat and long robe belong to the best of Disney iconography. His disciple is Wart, a twelve-year old boy, whose destiny is to become the future legendary King Arthur. The mentorship goes through different stages, using magic as an accessory but never as the crucial tool, in order to make Wart learn from practice, the values of the driving forces of our universe: physics, gravity or survival, all the stuff that makes 'things go round' and the greatest lesson of all being that brains always triumph on brawn. This 'brains over brawn' dichotomy is the pattern that forged human civilization and Merlin's divinatory power allowed him to check the validity of his point, what Wart would only see through experience. The film is made of many vignettes during which Arthur is turned into an animal. As a fish, he's victim of a bullying bull-frog before confronting a pike, as a squirrel, a female gets infatuated with him, turning the lesson on gravity into one about a much greater force. The third lesson involves Arthur as a sparrow learning to fly with Merlin's owl Archimedes, but his abrupt encounter with the witch Madame Mim, Merlin's archenemy, leads to one of Disney's greatest moments: the wizardry duel. The sequence is a triumph of imagination and animation combined, having both characters turning into various animals while conserving their defining traits is a delight to the eyes, and it concludes perfectly with Mim finally "catching" Merlin' but not the way she intended. Again, Merlin always proves his point. The secret of "The Sword in the Stone" lies essentially on its relative absence of a plot, and the episodic structure, which constitutes the basis of Merlin's mentorship. Each sequence is not only full of educational and philosophical value but stands alone as a great moment of animation. The fish part involves Arthur's first confrontation with a giant predator and the first opportunity to use his brains by turning his smaller size to his advantage. In the process, it also unveils an heroic facet in Archimedes' grouchy personality. The squirrel part, after a series of laughs driven by Merlin's misadventure with a fat beaver-like creature, finally illustrates Disney's formula that for every laugh, there should be a tear. And even if it's not 'Bambi' or 'Lion King', there's something extremely poignant and heart-breaking in the squirrel part's conclusion, even more because it's unexpected. But there are laughs in the film, and quite a lot, "The Sword in the Stone" is full of anachronisms, of priceless interactions between Merlin and Archimedes, who make a great pair of "Grumpy Old Men", and some hilarious scenes involving a wolf that have an irresistible Warner Bros cartoon feeling. And the few songs are so catchy we end up inevitably humming them while enjoying the animation.Who can resist to the sight of Merlin's furniture lined-up with a hot-tempered sugar pot on the lead, and being reduced over and over again to fit in a ridiculously small bag, or to the dishes washing by themselves motivated by all these "Hockity-Pockity" or "Higites-Figitus", which sound like improvement on "Cinderella"'s 'Bobbidi-Bibbidi"? The film isn't flawless, the irony that the more you like it, the more you watch it and discover some bits of repetitive or lazy animations. But "The Sword in the Stone" works thanks to its independence from a plot line's tyranny. Granted the film doesn't feature all the Disney archetypes, Mim is the main antagonist but not the larger-than-life villain with a heart- pounding demise. Even Arthur's foster father Ector has heart and his son Kay is more of a dim-witted comic relief. No abundance of songs, no memorable climax either except from the wizardry duel and the magical sword moment, but despite all these missing elements, "The Sword in the Stone", through its difference, marks itself among the most memorable work from Disney studios with an undeniable educational, intellectual and philosophical value.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nothing like the great book by T.H. White, and nowhere near the quality of other Disney classics
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Conrad
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The book "The Sword in the Stone" by T.H. White is a trove of wisdom for children and adults, and a paean of love to medieval England, but virtually none of the best material from the novel finds its way to the screen in this soulless adaptation. Most Disney classics are like stepping into a fantasy storybook, but this is little more than a cheap cartoon. Something meaningful could have been made of Arthur's encounter with an amorous squirrel (this occurs while he himself is in the body of a squirrel), something akin to the beautiful and literary swan episode in White's book, but while there is a hint of real emotion in the film's squirrel scene it is largely overshadowed by meaningless back-and-forths between Merlin's own squirrel avatar and a husky female of the species. This is a representative example of the movie's many missed opportunities.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    7th out of 8 in the Silver Era
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Centaurus3
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After the success of 101 Dalmatians, The Sword in The Stone was released in December of 1963, and the last animated film Walt Disney would see completed and released. The story is about a Wizard named Merlin, who teaches Arthur about life lessons and how to use his brain, as Merlin knows that Arthur is going to be something big. Arthur pulls out the sword, making him king. Most of the characters in this film are extremely boring, except for Madame Mim and Merlin. Mim is the bad wizard who appears in the last 15 minutes of the film, and is a bit bubbly despite being evil. Merlin is the original Genie with all the modern day references, and is the comic relief; he is a cool guy. Arthur does not warrant any interest at all, and the fact that he is voiced by 3 VOICE ACTORS is probably the only thing that stands out about him. All of the other characters (the deadhead father and son, etc) are extremely forgettable. This movie only has a few songs. "Higitus Figitus" is a Bibidi Bobidi Bo type song, but played down, and "Madame Mim" is just alright. The introduction song is pretty neat though. The soundtrack is just alright. The animation is not up to par with the previous films, and the Xerography in this movie makes it even more bland and forgettable than it is; they should have used the animation from the 50s, but that was too expensive. Here is where the reused animation in Disney films start to become obvious, as you would see the same animation sketches in the next few movies. The character designs are alright, but the animation is good when Merlin is using magic. With the weak plot, mostly weak characters, and everything else average, this movie is where the magic in Disney films start to wane away. This film is not very memorable, but there is some good and entertaining parts in the movie (Merlin vs Mim, squirrel scene). If you want to watch a Disney film that you have not watched in a while, this may be the movie. Give it a watch, you will find some moments you like, but don't expect it to be a great movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Sword in the Stone That Will Destine One For The Throne.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dawalk-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I remember seeing this among other Disney films I saw in elementary school (at least part of them anyway) and those that aired on non-cable t.v. Some years later, I viewed this on Youtube a while back and for some time afterward, I'd been considering and wanting to buy a copy of the 45th Anniversary edition of it. I finally did last month and it's great seeing it once again. I never really thought or paid attention to it as much as some, certain other Disney animated features, but now I think I have to concur that it's one of the more underrated ones. A boy named Arthur (a.k.a. Wart) has the dream of one day becoming a squire. But little does he know that he's destined for something much greater, which is being the new English king, which is the position he takes over later from his late father (although being new at this and not knowing much about a ruler's duties, Wart isn't so sure he's up to it). This occurs once he successfully pulls out the enchanted sword from the stone. That makes sense, considering he's his son and he eventually inherits his place on the throne. But before that, while going off to retrieve another sword in the woods for his foster brother Kay, he comes across a cottage where he meets the grand wizard, Merlin, and his highly intellectual owl, Archimedes. Merlin appoints himself as Wart's tutor and emphasizes brains used as associated with an education being more important than brawn. This movie has a lot of thrilling moments, such as Wart getting a feel of what it's like to be different animals through the help of Merlin's magic, Merlin's talks about what are yet to come from his time travels (which leaves anyone from his time he tries to explain to about them puzzled or perplexed) and what's one of the most renowned moments, if not the most renowned moment, the Wizard's Duel between Merlin and the witch Mad Madam Mim. I never read the initial source that inspired Disney's take, but I read a little there was mentioned about it in the difference between this and T.H. White's book, which is this version being more comical. Aside from the fact that again I never read the original source, I don't mind nor do I think I would even if I did. I recommend this to anyone who's into adventure. Because it has plenty of it, making it still outstanding nonetheless of other things.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What it lacks in plot, is mostly made up by humor
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Joshua Mitchell
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Sword In The Stone is a major disappointment. It's by no means a bad film, it's just disappointing. What I expected to be an origin film was really just a silly film about a boy with a wizard for a teacher. Don't let the title deceive you, this is not a movie about a sword in a stone, it's about a skinny young boy named Arthur- whom everyone calls Wart- who has a rather ruthless and obnoxious father and older brother. While hunting with his older brother, Kay, Wart discovers a wizard named Merlin and his frumpy owl, Archimedes. Merlin is convinced that it is his job to tutor the boy, and that's all there is to it. There's not nearly enough plot to last even the short 79 minute run time. This might've worked as a 15 minute short film, but as a feature length film, The Sword In The Stone feels padded and tedious. There's just not enough material. Which is a shame because The Sword In The Stone has so much potential. This could've been a marvelous rags-to-riches story, but alas, it's just a Ben Kneobi, Luke Skywalker tale. The Sword In The Stone does have some bright spots though, make no mistake. While a majority of the characters are dull and forgettable, Archimedes is at least slightly amusing, and Merlin is the real main character, and he steals all the scenes anyhow. The protagonist, Wart, is likable, if mostly forgettable. The animation is shockingly bland. Despite a beautiful underwater segment, The Sword In The Stone has little visual sparkle. There are songs too, but like many of the characters, they're forgettable. They're not bad by any means, just forgettable. At the minimum, they're not dull and that's good enough for me. The score, by recurring Disney composer George Bruns, is disappointingly mediocre. However, there's a wonderful jazz piece utilizing the piano during a scene in which Merlin uses magic to wash dishes. This is the only part of the score I can recommend, unfortunately. Some of the scenes are funny, if somewhat pointless to the actual story. The quarrels between Merlin and Archimedes are particularly amusing. There's also one scene towards the end, where Merlin battles a witch in a fun, yet completely illogical duel of magic. While The Sword In The Stone lacks a real plot, and ultimately has nothing to do with the sword in the stone, it's an occasionally fun ride with enough humor to be a mildly enjoyable diversion.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My favorite Disney film!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ravsten428
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I don't know exactly why many people don't praise this movie more. I absolutely love this film. There are not many songs in the movie but the ones that are in it are enjoyable. Merlin who is a wizard that can see centuries into the future and lives with his annoying but lovable owl Archimedes predicts that a young boy of around 11 or 12 will drop into his house and sure enough he's dead on. Merlin takes the young Wart who is the future King of England, on many adventures and tries to teach Wart that knowledge is power. Somewhere along the way Wart is appointed to be Kay's squire at a jousting competition. Merlin is upset by this and says "Blow me to Bermuda!" Merlin takes off and Wart and Archimedes are left alone. Here is where we find that Wart goes to pull out the sword in the stone because he forgot Kay's sword. He tells Sir Ector that he got the sword from the stone yet nobody believes him at first but they go back and find that he was really the one who pulled it and is therefore dubbed King Arthur, King of all England. I love the wizard's duel between Merlin and the evil Madam Mim. One of the best parts of the movie. And also the part where Merlin is being chased by the fat girl squirrel who takes a fancy to him. Love this film!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A lot of fun, but not among Disney's best
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RokurotaMakabe
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is Disney's version of the legend of King Arthur and it represents an adaptation of T.H. White's children's story. Here, Arthur is a young boy who is unaware of his great destiny. He meets and befriends the great wizard Merlin who decides to give him a proper instruction and education in order to prepare him for his future. The film has some great characters: Merlin the wizard and his intellectually trained owl Archimedes are particularly funny. The animation is very good, but this is Disney after all, so you would expect it to be like that. The film is definitely entertaining, but there are a few drawbacks as well. There are moments when it feels a little too similar to Disney's other animated features from that period. The film also incorporates a lot of plot elements from other Disney movies and the film is very predictable at times. In comparison to another Disney classic, "Sleeping Beauty", this film looks more like a secondary project. "The Sword in the Stone" is nevertheless a good film and it is superior to many of Disney's modern efforts ("Hercules", "The Hunchback of Notre Dame" or "Pocahontas" to name a few). It is very entertaining and definitely worth watching. My rating: 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Disney film not to be missed!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Kristine (kristinedrama14@msn.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I cannot believe I never wrote a comment on The Sword in the Stone, my friends always joke how I'm the ultimate Mickey Mouse since I'm such a fan and I own every Disney movie on DVD. I wanted to watch one of my movies last night and I picked The Sword in the Stone and rediscovered how much I loved this movie when I was a kid and still love it today. I went on IMDb to see if I gave the appropriate rating, but I was surprised to see that I never did write about it, but I guess better late then never. Sword in the Stone is just a classic treasure that no family should be without but also the film lovers. A wonderful classic story told Disney style and filled with great songs and beautiful animation, how could anyone not fall in love with The Sword in the Stone. The "Sword in the Stone" appears in London, with an inscription proclaiming that "Who so Pulleth Out This Sword of this Stone and Anvil, is Rightwise King Born of England." None succeed in removing the sword, which is soon forgotten, leaving England in a Dark Age. Some years later, Arthur aka "Wart", a 12-year-old orphan training to be a squire. While accompanying his older foster brother Kay on a hunting trip. He falls into Merlin's cottage, Merlin declares himself Wart's tutor and the two return to Wart's home, a castle run by Sir Ector, Arthur's foster father. There Merlin stays with Arthur to teach him the ways of the world and the magic as well as the intelligence and strength he will need for his true destiny. I think my favorite moment of this film is definitely the battle between Merlin and Mim, since this is one of the rare Disney movies that doesn't have a definitive villain, but I think Mim was a close as you could get. Their battle was epic and absolutely amazing to watch, plus I love the classic sound effects with good old slap stick humor. Also I loved the story when Merlin turned Arthur and himself into squirrels and they were attacked by the lady squirrels was just too cute for words. I know the animation isn't up to par with today's standards, but this is the exact animation that I loved growing up with because the animators seemed to have a love for the film they were making. The Sword in the Stone is a classic Disney film that should never be missed and I can't wait to show my children one day. Disney always had a way of taking classic stories that may not interest a small child and puts action, adventure, romance and wonderful animation into it and made it come to life. I can't believe I hadn't watched this movie since I was a kid, because no film lover should be without this treasure, it's just so excellent and magical, takes you back to a simpler time where we were destined for greatness and the world was at our fingertips. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stone cold
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jc-osms
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Pleasant Disney animation, without being a classic. It has its moments, particularly the magic-fight between Merlin and Mim, but is light on characterisation and especially good songs. The soundtrack tunes are very simplistic both melodically and especially lyrically and resolutely refuse to stay in your brain. The narrative itself is unusual, introducing the sword in the stone legend immediately and then dispensing with it until the last five minutes or so, concentrating its energies instead on young Arthur (read Wort) and his upbringing by the kindly Merlin and his obstinate talking owl Archimedes. I kept seeing recollections of past Disney (and other) cartoon forebears, everything from, naturally enough the Sorcerer's Apprentice from "Fantasia" and "Cinderella" while the chasing wolf early on is a blatant lift of Wile E Coyote in the "Road Runner" shorts. The old Disney trick of an experienced elder mentoring a young innocent had of course been done before in "Pinocchio" and "The Jungle Book" although I could also see some ideas which were adapted in future projects, the animated crockery anticipates "Beauty and the Beast" for instance. Disney never did return to the Arthurian Legnd in future animations as was hinted might happen here which is a pity but for me there's far too much diversion from the legend itself so that I was willing young Arthur to hurry up and give the sword the required pull long before the ending, which when it does arrive seems far too rushed in any case. No, not the best Disney by a long way and certainly not in the vanguard of the studio's work.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Kid-friendly King Arthur tale
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ersinkdotcom
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A young orphan named "Wart" wants nothing more than to be the squire to his older foster brother. Merlin the Magician sees more potential in the boy and begins training him for a greater destiny. "Wart" accompanies his brother to a tournament in London, where he will discover his true fate as Merlin's visions of greatness unfold. We all know how it feels when you remember a movie one way from childhood and realize as an adult it's not quite as it seemed. That was my feeling as I watched Disney's "The Sword in the Stone." Far be it for me to start slinging mud at what is considered to be a classic in the eyes of many. However, it became tedious watching Merlin the Magician teach "Wart" life lessons through turning himself and the boy into one animal after another and breaking into song. I've never been a big fan of any musicals. I'm sure this factor has everything to do with my lack of enthusiasm for "The Sword in the Stone." My preferred version of the Arthur story would lean more towards the adventurous "Excalibur." "The Sword in the Stone" does contain quite a bit of magic. Some people with certain religious convictions will find this a good reason to steer clear of the movie. I would have to say that anyone who watches "The Lord of the Rings" films has no right to throw rocks at this one. My 7-year old loved "The Sword in the Stone," so maybe I've just outgrown it. He's watched it twice already, where I found it near impossible to sit through once. If children like it, does it really matter what this old reviewer thinks about it anyway? It's been proved time and time again that Disney movies are critic-proof.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A triumph of fun and intelligence over animation 
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ElMaruecan82
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
     just like brain over brawn, Merlin's eternal motto. The initial reactions to "The Sword in the Stone" left me astonished. How could such a merry and original piece of animation get such negative criticism? From what I've read, nothing was spared: the animation didn't match the quality of previous Disney's works, the episodic structure lead to a conclusion disappointing because of the lack of a memorable plot line or a clearly defined antagonist  in this list of flaws, where I only concede the issue with Wart's voice, nothing seemed enjoyable enough to redeem the film: not Merlin's eccentric personality, not the humor made of unusual anachronistic references, not even the scene- stealing exuberance of Madame Mim. Well, since reviewing is about giving opinions, I'll give you mine: "The Sword in the Stone" was victim of an unfair bias constantly leaning on Disney's 'Golden Age' standards, while for one thing, it was a respectable attempt to take some distance from the usual formulas (and I'm pretty sure viewers enjoyed the new storytelling format, since the film ended-up being one of the highest grossing of 1963). And now that these fifty years of existence did justice to "Sword in the Stone", now that there are enough Disney animated features to make a clear distinction between the indisputable classics, the underrated gems, and the forgettable ones, I think we can all agree that "The Sword in the Stone" is in the same league than "The Jungle Book" or "Robin Hood", all contained in that entertaining parenthesis of the 60's-70's. And it's precisely the sketchy animation so typical of that period that elevates "The Sword in the Stone" to more interesting level of appreciation, more focused on the story, as the counterpart of such ambitious projects like "Sleeping Beauty", a film of dazzling imagery but certainly poorer story-wise. "The Sword in the Stone" is an educational journey guided by Merlin the wizard, whose long beard, blue pointed hat and long robe belong to the best of Disney iconography. His disciple is Wart, a twelve-year old boy, whose destiny is to become the future legendary King Arthur. The mentorship goes through different stages, using magic as an accessory but never as the crucial tool, in order to make Wart learn from practice, the values of the driving forces of our universe: physics, gravity or survival, all the stuff that makes 'things go round' and the greatest lesson of all being that brains always triumph on brawn. This 'brains over brawn' dichotomy is the pattern that forged human civilization and Merlin's divinatory power allowed him to check the validity of his point, what Wart would only see through experience. The film is made of many vignettes during which Arthur is turned into an animal. As a fish, he's victim of a bullying bull-frog before confronting a pike, as a squirrel, a female gets infatuated with him, turning the lesson on gravity into one about a much greater force. The third lesson involves Arthur as a sparrow learning to fly with Merlin's owl Archimedes, but his abrupt encounter with the witch Madame Mim, Merlin's archenemy, leads to one of Disney's greatest moments: the wizardry duel. The sequence is a triumph of imagination and animation combined, having both characters turning into various animals while conserving their defining traits is a delight to the eyes, and it concludes perfectly with Mim finally "catching" Merlin' but not the way she intended. Again, Merlin always proves his point. The secret of "The Sword in the Stone" lies essentially on its relative absence of a plot, and the episodic structure, which constitutes the basis of Merlin's mentorship. Each sequence is not only full of educational and philosophical value but stands alone as a great moment of animation. The fish part involves Arthur's first confrontation with a giant predator and the first opportunity to use his brains by turning his smaller size to his advantage. In the process, it also unveils an heroic facet in Archimedes' grouchy personality. The squirrel part, after a series of laughs driven by Merlin's misadventure with a fat beaver-like creature, finally illustrates Disney's formula that for every laugh, there should be a tear. And even if it's not 'Bambi' or 'Lion King', there's something extremely poignant and heart-breaking in the squirrel part's conclusion, even more because it's unexpected. But there are laughs in the film, and quite a lot, "The Sword in the Stone" is full of anachronisms, of priceless interactions between Merlin and Archimedes, who make a great pair of "Grumpy Old Men", and some hilarious scenes involving a wolf that have an irresistible Warner Bros cartoon feeling. And the few songs are so catchy we end up inevitably humming them while enjoying the animation.Who can resist to the sight of Merlin's furniture lined-up with a hot-tempered sugar pot on the lead, and being reduced over and over again to fit in a ridiculously small bag, or to the dishes washing by themselves motivated by all these "Hockity-Pockity" or "Higites-Figitus", which sound like improvement on "Cinderella"'s 'Bobbidi-Bibbidi"? The film isn't flawless, the irony that the more you like it, the more you watch it and discover some bits of repetitive or lazy animations. But "The Sword in the Stone" works thanks to its independence from a plot line's tyranny. Granted the film doesn't feature all the Disney archetypes, Mim is the main antagonist but not the larger-than-life villain with a heart- pounding demise. Even Arthur's foster father Ector has heart and his son Kay is more of a dim-witted comic relief. No abundance of songs, no memorable climax either except from the wizardry duel and the magical sword moment, but despite all these missing elements, "The Sword in the Stone", through its difference, marks itself among the most memorable work from Disney studios with an undeniable educational, intellectual and philosophical value.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nothing like the great book by T.H. White, and nowhere near the quality of other Disney classics
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Conrad
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The book "The Sword in the Stone" by T.H. White is a trove of wisdom for children and adults, and a paean of love to medieval England, but virtually none of the best material from the novel finds its way to the screen in this soulless adaptation. Most Disney classics are like stepping into a fantasy storybook, but this is little more than a cheap cartoon. Something meaningful could have been made of Arthur's encounter with an amorous squirrel (this occurs while he himself is in the body of a squirrel), something akin to the beautiful and literary swan episode in White's book, but while there is a hint of real emotion in the film's squirrel scene it is largely overshadowed by meaningless back-and-forths between Merlin's own squirrel avatar and a husky female of the species. This is a representative example of the movie's many missed opportunities.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    7th out of 8 in the Silver Era
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Centaurus3
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After the success of 101 Dalmatians, The Sword in The Stone was released in December of 1963, and the last animated film Walt Disney would see completed and released. The story is about a Wizard named Merlin, who teaches Arthur about life lessons and how to use his brain, as Merlin knows that Arthur is going to be something big. Arthur pulls out the sword, making him king. Most of the characters in this film are extremely boring, except for Madame Mim and Merlin. Mim is the bad wizard who appears in the last 15 minutes of the film, and is a bit bubbly despite being evil. Merlin is the original Genie with all the modern day references, and is the comic relief; he is a cool guy. Arthur does not warrant any interest at all, and the fact that he is voiced by 3 VOICE ACTORS is probably the only thing that stands out about him. All of the other characters (the deadhead father and son, etc) are extremely forgettable. This movie only has a few songs. "Higitus Figitus" is a Bibidi Bobidi Bo type song, but played down, and "Madame Mim" is just alright. The introduction song is pretty neat though. The soundtrack is just alright. The animation is not up to par with the previous films, and the Xerography in this movie makes it even more bland and forgettable than it is; they should have used the animation from the 50s, but that was too expensive. Here is where the reused animation in Disney films start to become obvious, as you would see the same animation sketches in the next few movies. The character designs are alright, but the animation is good when Merlin is using magic. With the weak plot, mostly weak characters, and everything else average, this movie is where the magic in Disney films start to wane away. This film is not very memorable, but there is some good and entertaining parts in the movie (Merlin vs Mim, squirrel scene). If you want to watch a Disney film that you have not watched in a while, this may be the movie. Give it a watch, you will find some moments you like, but don't expect it to be a great movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Sword in the Stone That Will Destine One For The Throne.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dawalk-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I remember seeing this among other Disney films I saw in elementary school (at least part of them anyway) and those that aired on non-cable t.v. Some years later, I viewed this on Youtube a while back and for some time afterward, I'd been considering and wanting to buy a copy of the 45th Anniversary edition of it. I finally did last month and it's great seeing it once again. I never really thought or paid attention to it as much as some, certain other Disney animated features, but now I think I have to concur that it's one of the more underrated ones. A boy named Arthur (a.k.a. Wart) has the dream of one day becoming a squire. But little does he know that he's destined for something much greater, which is being the new English king, which is the position he takes over later from his late father (although being new at this and not knowing much about a ruler's duties, Wart isn't so sure he's up to it). This occurs once he successfully pulls out the enchanted sword from the stone. That makes sense, considering he's his son and he eventually inherits his place on the throne. But before that, while going off to retrieve another sword in the woods for his foster brother Kay, he comes across a cottage where he meets the grand wizard, Merlin, and his highly intellectual owl, Archimedes. Merlin appoints himself as Wart's tutor and emphasizes brains used as associated with an education being more important than brawn. This movie has a lot of thrilling moments, such as Wart getting a feel of what it's like to be different animals through the help of Merlin's magic, Merlin's talks about what are yet to come from his time travels (which leaves anyone from his time he tries to explain to about them puzzled or perplexed) and what's one of the most renowned moments, if not the most renowned moment, the Wizard's Duel between Merlin and the witch Mad Madam Mim. I never read the initial source that inspired Disney's take, but I read a little there was mentioned about it in the difference between this and T.H. White's book, which is this version being more comical. Aside from the fact that again I never read the original source, I don't mind nor do I think I would even if I did. I recommend this to anyone who's into adventure. Because it has plenty of it, making it still outstanding nonetheless of other things.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What it lacks in plot, is mostly made up by humor
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Joshua Mitchell
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Sword In The Stone is a major disappointment. It's by no means a bad film, it's just disappointing. What I expected to be an origin film was really just a silly film about a boy with a wizard for a teacher. Don't let the title deceive you, this is not a movie about a sword in a stone, it's about a skinny young boy named Arthur- whom everyone calls Wart- who has a rather ruthless and obnoxious father and older brother. While hunting with his older brother, Kay, Wart discovers a wizard named Merlin and his frumpy owl, Archimedes. Merlin is convinced that it is his job to tutor the boy, and that's all there is to it. There's not nearly enough plot to last even the short 79 minute run time. This might've worked as a 15 minute short film, but as a feature length film, The Sword In The Stone feels padded and tedious. There's just not enough material. Which is a shame because The Sword In The Stone has so much potential. This could've been a marvelous rags-to-riches story, but alas, it's just a Ben Kneobi, Luke Skywalker tale. The Sword In The Stone does have some bright spots though, make no mistake. While a majority of the characters are dull and forgettable, Archimedes is at least slightly amusing, and Merlin is the real main character, and he steals all the scenes anyhow. The protagonist, Wart, is likable, if mostly forgettable. The animation is shockingly bland. Despite a beautiful underwater segment, The Sword In The Stone has little visual sparkle. There are songs too, but like many of the characters, they're forgettable. They're not bad by any means, just forgettable. At the minimum, they're not dull and that's good enough for me. The score, by recurring Disney composer George Bruns, is disappointingly mediocre. However, there's a wonderful jazz piece utilizing the piano during a scene in which Merlin uses magic to wash dishes. This is the only part of the score I can recommend, unfortunately. Some of the scenes are funny, if somewhat pointless to the actual story. The quarrels between Merlin and Archimedes are particularly amusing. There's also one scene towards the end, where Merlin battles a witch in a fun, yet completely illogical duel of magic. While The Sword In The Stone lacks a real plot, and ultimately has nothing to do with the sword in the stone, it's an occasionally fun ride with enough humor to be a mildly enjoyable diversion.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My favorite Disney film!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ravsten428
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I don't know exactly why many people don't praise this movie more. I absolutely love this film. There are not many songs in the movie but the ones that are in it are enjoyable. Merlin who is a wizard that can see centuries into the future and lives with his annoying but lovable owl Archimedes predicts that a young boy of around 11 or 12 will drop into his house and sure enough he's dead on. Merlin takes the young Wart who is the future King of England, on many adventures and tries to teach Wart that knowledge is power. Somewhere along the way Wart is appointed to be Kay's squire at a jousting competition. Merlin is upset by this and says "Blow me to Bermuda!" Merlin takes off and Wart and Archimedes are left alone. Here is where we find that Wart goes to pull out the sword in the stone because he forgot Kay's sword. He tells Sir Ector that he got the sword from the stone yet nobody believes him at first but they go back and find that he was really the one who pulled it and is therefore dubbed King Arthur, King of all England. I love the wizard's duel between Merlin and the evil Madam Mim. One of the best parts of the movie. And also the part where Merlin is being chased by the fat girl squirrel who takes a fancy to him. Love this film!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A lot of fun, but not among Disney's best
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RokurotaMakabe
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is Disney's version of the legend of King Arthur and it represents an adaptation of T.H. White's children's story. Here, Arthur is a young boy who is unaware of his great destiny. He meets and befriends the great wizard Merlin who decides to give him a proper instruction and education in order to prepare him for his future. The film has some great characters: Merlin the wizard and his intellectually trained owl Archimedes are particularly funny. The animation is very good, but this is Disney after all, so you would expect it to be like that. The film is definitely entertaining, but there are a few drawbacks as well. There are moments when it feels a little too similar to Disney's other animated features from that period. The film also incorporates a lot of plot elements from other Disney movies and the film is very predictable at times. In comparison to another Disney classic, "Sleeping Beauty", this film looks more like a secondary project. "The Sword in the Stone" is nevertheless a good film and it is superior to many of Disney's modern efforts ("Hercules", "The Hunchback of Notre Dame" or "Pocahontas" to name a few). It is very entertaining and definitely worth watching. My rating: 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Disney film not to be missed!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Kristine (kristinedrama14@msn.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I cannot believe I never wrote a comment on The Sword in the Stone, my friends always joke how I'm the ultimate Mickey Mouse since I'm such a fan and I own every Disney movie on DVD. I wanted to watch one of my movies last night and I picked The Sword in the Stone and rediscovered how much I loved this movie when I was a kid and still love it today. I went on IMDb to see if I gave the appropriate rating, but I was surprised to see that I never did write about it, but I guess better late then never. Sword in the Stone is just a classic treasure that no family should be without but also the film lovers. A wonderful classic story told Disney style and filled with great songs and beautiful animation, how could anyone not fall in love with The Sword in the Stone. The "Sword in the Stone" appears in London, with an inscription proclaiming that "Who so Pulleth Out This Sword of this Stone and Anvil, is Rightwise King Born of England." None succeed in removing the sword, which is soon forgotten, leaving England in a Dark Age. Some years later, Arthur aka "Wart", a 12-year-old orphan training to be a squire. While accompanying his older foster brother Kay on a hunting trip. He falls into Merlin's cottage, Merlin declares himself Wart's tutor and the two return to Wart's home, a castle run by Sir Ector, Arthur's foster father. There Merlin stays with Arthur to teach him the ways of the world and the magic as well as the intelligence and strength he will need for his true destiny. I think my favorite moment of this film is definitely the battle between Merlin and Mim, since this is one of the rare Disney movies that doesn't have a definitive villain, but I think Mim was a close as you could get. Their battle was epic and absolutely amazing to watch, plus I love the classic sound effects with good old slap stick humor. Also I loved the story when Merlin turned Arthur and himself into squirrels and they were attacked by the lady squirrels was just too cute for words. I know the animation isn't up to par with today's standards, but this is the exact animation that I loved growing up with because the animators seemed to have a love for the film they were making. The Sword in the Stone is a classic Disney film that should never be missed and I can't wait to show my children one day. Disney always had a way of taking classic stories that may not interest a small child and puts action, adventure, romance and wonderful animation into it and made it come to life. I can't believe I hadn't watched this movie since I was a kid, because no film lover should be without this treasure, it's just so excellent and magical, takes you back to a simpler time where we were destined for greatness and the world was at our fingertips. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stone cold
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jc-osms
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Pleasant Disney animation, without being a classic. It has its moments, particularly the magic-fight between Merlin and Mim, but is light on characterisation and especially good songs. The soundtrack tunes are very simplistic both melodically and especially lyrically and resolutely refuse to stay in your brain. The narrative itself is unusual, introducing the sword in the stone legend immediately and then dispensing with it until the last five minutes or so, concentrating its energies instead on young Arthur (read Wort) and his upbringing by the kindly Merlin and his obstinate talking owl Archimedes. I kept seeing recollections of past Disney (and other) cartoon forebears, everything from, naturally enough the Sorcerer's Apprentice from "Fantasia" and "Cinderella" while the chasing wolf early on is a blatant lift of Wile E Coyote in the "Road Runner" shorts. The old Disney trick of an experienced elder mentoring a young innocent had of course been done before in "Pinocchio" and "The Jungle Book" although I could also see some ideas which were adapted in future projects, the animated crockery anticipates "Beauty and the Beast" for instance. Disney never did return to the Arthurian Legnd in future animations as was hinted might happen here which is a pity but for me there's far too much diversion from the legend itself so that I was willing young Arthur to hurry up and give the sword the required pull long before the ending, which when it does arrive seems far too rushed in any case. No, not the best Disney by a long way and certainly not in the vanguard of the studio's work.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Kid-friendly King Arthur tale
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ersinkdotcom
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A young orphan named "Wart" wants nothing more than to be the squire to his older foster brother. Merlin the Magician sees more potential in the boy and begins training him for a greater destiny. "Wart" accompanies his brother to a tournament in London, where he will discover his true fate as Merlin's visions of greatness unfold. We all know how it feels when you remember a movie one way from childhood and realize as an adult it's not quite as it seemed. That was my feeling as I watched Disney's "The Sword in the Stone." Far be it for me to start slinging mud at what is considered to be a classic in the eyes of many. However, it became tedious watching Merlin the Magician teach "Wart" life lessons through turning himself and the boy into one animal after another and breaking into song. I've never been a big fan of any musicals. I'm sure this factor has everything to do with my lack of enthusiasm for "The Sword in the Stone." My preferred version of the Arthur story would lean more towards the adventurous "Excalibur." "The Sword in the Stone" does contain quite a bit of magic. Some people with certain religious convictions will find this a good reason to steer clear of the movie. I would have to say that anyone who watches "The Lord of the Rings" films has no right to throw rocks at this one. My 7-year old loved "The Sword in the Stone," so maybe I've just outgrown it. He's watched it twice already, where I found it near impossible to sit through once. If children like it, does it really matter what this old reviewer thinks about it anyway? It's been proved time and time again that Disney movies are critic-proof.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A triumph of fun and intelligence over animation 
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ElMaruecan82
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
     just like brain over brawn, Merlin's eternal motto. The initial reactions to "The Sword in the Stone" left me astonished. How could such a merry and original piece of animation get such negative criticism? From what I've read, nothing was spared: the animation didn't match the quality of previous Disney's works, the episodic structure lead to a conclusion disappointing because of the lack of a memorable plot line or a clearly defined antagonist  in this list of flaws, where I only concede the issue with Wart's voice, nothing seemed enjoyable enough to redeem the film: not Merlin's eccentric personality, not the humor made of unusual anachronistic references, not even the scene- stealing exuberance of Madame Mim. Well, since reviewing is about giving opinions, I'll give you mine: "The Sword in the Stone" was victim of an unfair bias constantly leaning on Disney's 'Golden Age' standards, while for one thing, it was a respectable attempt to take some distance from the usual formulas (and I'm pretty sure viewers enjoyed the new storytelling format, since the film ended-up being one of the highest grossing of 1963). And now that these fifty years of existence did justice to "Sword in the Stone", now that there are enough Disney animated features to make a clear distinction between the indisputable classics, the underrated gems, and the forgettable ones, I think we can all agree that "The Sword in the Stone" is in the same league than "The Jungle Book" or "Robin Hood", all contained in that entertaining parenthesis of the 60's-70's. And it's precisely the sketchy animation so typical of that period that elevates "The Sword in the Stone" to more interesting level of appreciation, more focused on the story, as the counterpart of such ambitious projects like "Sleeping Beauty", a film of dazzling imagery but certainly poorer story-wise. "The Sword in the Stone" is an educational journey guided by Merlin the wizard, whose long beard, blue pointed hat and long robe belong to the best of Disney iconography. His disciple is Wart, a twelve-year old boy, whose destiny is to become the future legendary King Arthur. The mentorship goes through different stages, using magic as an accessory but never as the crucial tool, in order to make Wart learn from practice, the values of the driving forces of our universe: physics, gravity or survival, all the stuff that makes 'things go round' and the greatest lesson of all being that brains always triumph on brawn. This 'brains over brawn' dichotomy is the pattern that forged human civilization and Merlin's divinatory power allowed him to check the validity of his point, what Wart would only see through experience. The film is made of many vignettes during which Arthur is turned into an animal. As a fish, he's victim of a bullying bull-frog before confronting a pike, as a squirrel, a female gets infatuated with him, turning the lesson on gravity into one about a much greater force. The third lesson involves Arthur as a sparrow learning to fly with Merlin's owl Archimedes, but his abrupt encounter with the witch Madame Mim, Merlin's archenemy, leads to one of Disney's greatest moments: the wizardry duel. The sequence is a triumph of imagination and animation combined, having both characters turning into various animals while conserving their defining traits is a delight to the eyes, and it concludes perfectly with Mim finally "catching" Merlin' but not the way she intended. Again, Merlin always proves his point. The secret of "The Sword in the Stone" lies essentially on its relative absence of a plot, and the episodic structure, which constitutes the basis of Merlin's mentorship. Each sequence is not only full of educational and philosophical value but stands alone as a great moment of animation. The fish part involves Arthur's first confrontation with a giant predator and the first opportunity to use his brains by turning his smaller size to his advantage. In the process, it also unveils an heroic facet in Archimedes' grouchy personality. The squirrel part, after a series of laughs driven by Merlin's misadventure with a fat beaver-like creature, finally illustrates Disney's formula that for every laugh, there should be a tear. And even if it's not 'Bambi' or 'Lion King', there's something extremely poignant and heart-breaking in the squirrel part's conclusion, even more because it's unexpected. But there are laughs in the film, and quite a lot, "The Sword in the Stone" is full of anachronisms, of priceless interactions between Merlin and Archimedes, who make a great pair of "Grumpy Old Men", and some hilarious scenes involving a wolf that have an irresistible Warner Bros cartoon feeling. And the few songs are so catchy we end up inevitably humming them while enjoying the animation.Who can resist to the sight of Merlin's furniture lined-up with a hot-tempered sugar pot on the lead, and being reduced over and over again to fit in a ridiculously small bag, or to the dishes washing by themselves motivated by all these "Hockity-Pockity" or "Higites-Figitus", which sound like improvement on "Cinderella"'s 'Bobbidi-Bibbidi"? The film isn't flawless, the irony that the more you like it, the more you watch it and discover some bits of repetitive or lazy animations. But "The Sword in the Stone" works thanks to its independence from a plot line's tyranny. Granted the film doesn't feature all the Disney archetypes, Mim is the main antagonist but not the larger-than-life villain with a heart- pounding demise. Even Arthur's foster father Ector has heart and his son Kay is more of a dim-witted comic relief. No abundance of songs, no memorable climax either except from the wizardry duel and the magical sword moment, but despite all these missing elements, "The Sword in the Stone", through its difference, marks itself among the most memorable work from Disney studios with an undeniable educational, intellectual and philosophical value.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nothing like the great book by T.H. White, and nowhere near the quality of other Disney classics
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Conrad
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The book "The Sword in the Stone" by T.H. White is a trove of wisdom for children and adults, and a paean of love to medieval England, but virtually none of the best material from the novel finds its way to the screen in this soulless adaptation. Most Disney classics are like stepping into a fantasy storybook, but this is little more than a cheap cartoon. Something meaningful could have been made of Arthur's encounter with an amorous squirrel (this occurs while he himself is in the body of a squirrel), something akin to the beautiful and literary swan episode in White's book, but while there is a hint of real emotion in the film's squirrel scene it is largely overshadowed by meaningless back-and-forths between Merlin's own squirrel avatar and a husky female of the species. This is a representative example of the movie's many missed opportunities.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    7th out of 8 in the Silver Era
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Centaurus3
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After the success of 101 Dalmatians, The Sword in The Stone was released in December of 1963, and the last animated film Walt Disney would see completed and released. The story is about a Wizard named Merlin, who teaches Arthur about life lessons and how to use his brain, as Merlin knows that Arthur is going to be something big. Arthur pulls out the sword, making him king. Most of the characters in this film are extremely boring, except for Madame Mim and Merlin. Mim is the bad wizard who appears in the last 15 minutes of the film, and is a bit bubbly despite being evil. Merlin is the original Genie with all the modern day references, and is the comic relief; he is a cool guy. Arthur does not warrant any interest at all, and the fact that he is voiced by 3 VOICE ACTORS is probably the only thing that stands out about him. All of the other characters (the deadhead father and son, etc) are extremely forgettable. This movie only has a few songs. "Higitus Figitus" is a Bibidi Bobidi Bo type song, but played down, and "Madame Mim" is just alright. The introduction song is pretty neat though. The soundtrack is just alright. The animation is not up to par with the previous films, and the Xerography in this movie makes it even more bland and forgettable than it is; they should have used the animation from the 50s, but that was too expensive. Here is where the reused animation in Disney films start to become obvious, as you would see the same animation sketches in the next few movies. The character designs are alright, but the animation is good when Merlin is using magic. With the weak plot, mostly weak characters, and everything else average, this movie is where the magic in Disney films start to wane away. This film is not very memorable, but there is some good and entertaining parts in the movie (Merlin vs Mim, squirrel scene). If you want to watch a Disney film that you have not watched in a while, this may be the movie. Give it a watch, you will find some moments you like, but don't expect it to be a great movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Sword in the Stone That Will Destine One For The Throne.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dawalk-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I remember seeing this among other Disney films I saw in elementary school (at least part of them anyway) and those that aired on non-cable t.v. Some years later, I viewed this on Youtube a while back and for some time afterward, I'd been considering and wanting to buy a copy of the 45th Anniversary edition of it. I finally did last month and it's great seeing it once again. I never really thought or paid attention to it as much as some, certain other Disney animated features, but now I think I have to concur that it's one of the more underrated ones. A boy named Arthur (a.k.a. Wart) has the dream of one day becoming a squire. But little does he know that he's destined for something much greater, which is being the new English king, which is the position he takes over later from his late father (although being new at this and not knowing much about a ruler's duties, Wart isn't so sure he's up to it). This occurs once he successfully pulls out the enchanted sword from the stone. That makes sense, considering he's his son and he eventually inherits his place on the throne. But before that, while going off to retrieve another sword in the woods for his foster brother Kay, he comes across a cottage where he meets the grand wizard, Merlin, and his highly intellectual owl, Archimedes. Merlin appoints himself as Wart's tutor and emphasizes brains used as associated with an education being more important than brawn. This movie has a lot of thrilling moments, such as Wart getting a feel of what it's like to be different animals through the help of Merlin's magic, Merlin's talks about what are yet to come from his time travels (which leaves anyone from his time he tries to explain to about them puzzled or perplexed) and what's one of the most renowned moments, if not the most renowned moment, the Wizard's Duel between Merlin and the witch Mad Madam Mim. I never read the initial source that inspired Disney's take, but I read a little there was mentioned about it in the difference between this and T.H. White's book, which is this version being more comical. Aside from the fact that again I never read the original source, I don't mind nor do I think I would even if I did. I recommend this to anyone who's into adventure. Because it has plenty of it, making it still outstanding nonetheless of other things.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What it lacks in plot, is mostly made up by humor
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Joshua Mitchell
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Sword In The Stone is a major disappointment. It's by no means a bad film, it's just disappointing. What I expected to be an origin film was really just a silly film about a boy with a wizard for a teacher. Don't let the title deceive you, this is not a movie about a sword in a stone, it's about a skinny young boy named Arthur- whom everyone calls Wart- who has a rather ruthless and obnoxious father and older brother. While hunting with his older brother, Kay, Wart discovers a wizard named Merlin and his frumpy owl, Archimedes. Merlin is convinced that it is his job to tutor the boy, and that's all there is to it. There's not nearly enough plot to last even the short 79 minute run time. This might've worked as a 15 minute short film, but as a feature length film, The Sword In The Stone feels padded and tedious. There's just not enough material. Which is a shame because The Sword In The Stone has so much potential. This could've been a marvelous rags-to-riches story, but alas, it's just a Ben Kneobi, Luke Skywalker tale. The Sword In The Stone does have some bright spots though, make no mistake. While a majority of the characters are dull and forgettable, Archimedes is at least slightly amusing, and Merlin is the real main character, and he steals all the scenes anyhow. The protagonist, Wart, is likable, if mostly forgettable. The animation is shockingly bland. Despite a beautiful underwater segment, The Sword In The Stone has little visual sparkle. There are songs too, but like many of the characters, they're forgettable. They're not bad by any means, just forgettable. At the minimum, they're not dull and that's good enough for me. The score, by recurring Disney composer George Bruns, is disappointingly mediocre. However, there's a wonderful jazz piece utilizing the piano during a scene in which Merlin uses magic to wash dishes. This is the only part of the score I can recommend, unfortunately. Some of the scenes are funny, if somewhat pointless to the actual story. The quarrels between Merlin and Archimedes are particularly amusing. There's also one scene towards the end, where Merlin battles a witch in a fun, yet completely illogical duel of magic. While The Sword In The Stone lacks a real plot, and ultimately has nothing to do with the sword in the stone, it's an occasionally fun ride with enough humor to be a mildly enjoyable diversion.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My favorite Disney film!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ravsten428
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I don't know exactly why many people don't praise this movie more. I absolutely love this film. There are not many songs in the movie but the ones that are in it are enjoyable. Merlin who is a wizard that can see centuries into the future and lives with his annoying but lovable owl Archimedes predicts that a young boy of around 11 or 12 will drop into his house and sure enough he's dead on. Merlin takes the young Wart who is the future King of England, on many adventures and tries to teach Wart that knowledge is power. Somewhere along the way Wart is appointed to be Kay's squire at a jousting competition. Merlin is upset by this and says "Blow me to Bermuda!" Merlin takes off and Wart and Archimedes are left alone. Here is where we find that Wart goes to pull out the sword in the stone because he forgot Kay's sword. He tells Sir Ector that he got the sword from the stone yet nobody believes him at first but they go back and find that he was really the one who pulled it and is therefore dubbed King Arthur, King of all England. I love the wizard's duel between Merlin and the evil Madam Mim. One of the best parts of the movie. And also the part where Merlin is being chased by the fat girl squirrel who takes a fancy to him. Love this film!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A lot of fun, but not among Disney's best
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RokurotaMakabe
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is Disney's version of the legend of King Arthur and it represents an adaptation of T.H. White's children's story. Here, Arthur is a young boy who is unaware of his great destiny. He meets and befriends the great wizard Merlin who decides to give him a proper instruction and education in order to prepare him for his future. The film has some great characters: Merlin the wizard and his intellectually trained owl Archimedes are particularly funny. The animation is very good, but this is Disney after all, so you would expect it to be like that. The film is definitely entertaining, but there are a few drawbacks as well. There are moments when it feels a little too similar to Disney's other animated features from that period. The film also incorporates a lot of plot elements from other Disney movies and the film is very predictable at times. In comparison to another Disney classic, "Sleeping Beauty", this film looks more like a secondary project. "The Sword in the Stone" is nevertheless a good film and it is superior to many of Disney's modern efforts ("Hercules", "The Hunchback of Notre Dame" or "Pocahontas" to name a few). It is very entertaining and definitely worth watching. My rating: 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Disney film not to be missed!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Kristine (kristinedrama14@msn.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I cannot believe I never wrote a comment on The Sword in the Stone, my friends always joke how I'm the ultimate Mickey Mouse since I'm such a fan and I own every Disney movie on DVD. I wanted to watch one of my movies last night and I picked The Sword in the Stone and rediscovered how much I loved this movie when I was a kid and still love it today. I went on IMDb to see if I gave the appropriate rating, but I was surprised to see that I never did write about it, but I guess better late then never. Sword in the Stone is just a classic treasure that no family should be without but also the film lovers. A wonderful classic story told Disney style and filled with great songs and beautiful animation, how could anyone not fall in love with The Sword in the Stone. The "Sword in the Stone" appears in London, with an inscription proclaiming that "Who so Pulleth Out This Sword of this Stone and Anvil, is Rightwise King Born of England." None succeed in removing the sword, which is soon forgotten, leaving England in a Dark Age. Some years later, Arthur aka "Wart", a 12-year-old orphan training to be a squire. While accompanying his older foster brother Kay on a hunting trip. He falls into Merlin's cottage, Merlin declares himself Wart's tutor and the two return to Wart's home, a castle run by Sir Ector, Arthur's foster father. There Merlin stays with Arthur to teach him the ways of the world and the magic as well as the intelligence and strength he will need for his true destiny. I think my favorite moment of this film is definitely the battle between Merlin and Mim, since this is one of the rare Disney movies that doesn't have a definitive villain, but I think Mim was a close as you could get. Their battle was epic and absolutely amazing to watch, plus I love the classic sound effects with good old slap stick humor. Also I loved the story when Merlin turned Arthur and himself into squirrels and they were attacked by the lady squirrels was just too cute for words. I know the animation isn't up to par with today's standards, but this is the exact animation that I loved growing up with because the animators seemed to have a love for the film they were making. The Sword in the Stone is a classic Disney film that should never be missed and I can't wait to show my children one day. Disney always had a way of taking classic stories that may not interest a small child and puts action, adventure, romance and wonderful animation into it and made it come to life. I can't believe I hadn't watched this movie since I was a kid, because no film lover should be without this treasure, it's just so excellent and magical, takes you back to a simpler time where we were destined for greatness and the world was at our fingertips. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stone cold
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jc-osms
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Pleasant Disney animation, without being a classic. It has its moments, particularly the magic-fight between Merlin and Mim, but is light on characterisation and especially good songs. The soundtrack tunes are very simplistic both melodically and especially lyrically and resolutely refuse to stay in your brain. The narrative itself is unusual, introducing the sword in the stone legend immediately and then dispensing with it until the last five minutes or so, concentrating its energies instead on young Arthur (read Wort) and his upbringing by the kindly Merlin and his obstinate talking owl Archimedes. I kept seeing recollections of past Disney (and other) cartoon forebears, everything from, naturally enough the Sorcerer's Apprentice from "Fantasia" and "Cinderella" while the chasing wolf early on is a blatant lift of Wile E Coyote in the "Road Runner" shorts. The old Disney trick of an experienced elder mentoring a young innocent had of course been done before in "Pinocchio" and "The Jungle Book" although I could also see some ideas which were adapted in future projects, the animated crockery anticipates "Beauty and the Beast" for instance. Disney never did return to the Arthurian Legnd in future animations as was hinted might happen here which is a pity but for me there's far too much diversion from the legend itself so that I was willing young Arthur to hurry up and give the sword the required pull long before the ending, which when it does arrive seems far too rushed in any case. No, not the best Disney by a long way and certainly not in the vanguard of the studio's work.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
