<filme>
 <id>
  629
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0084865
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1982
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Victor ou Victoria
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  7.4
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  A struggling female soprano finds work playing a male female impersonator, but it complicates her personal life.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  In 1934 Paris, trained coloratura soprano Victoria Grant, a native Brit, can't get a job as a singer and is having trouble making ends meet. She doesn't even have enough money for the basics of food and shelter. Gay cabaret singer Carole 'Toddy' Todd may befall the same fate as Victoria as he was just fired from his singing gig at a second rate club named Chez Lui. To solve both their problems, Toddy comes up with what he considers an inspired idea: with Toddy as her manager, Victoria, pretending to be a man, get a job singing as a female impersonator. If they pull this scheme off, Toddy vows Victoria, as her male alter ego, will be the toast of Paris and as such be extremely wealthy. That alter ego they decide is Polish Count Victor Grazinski, Toddy's ex-lover who was disowned by his family when they found out he was gay. The Count auditions for the city's leading agent, Andre Cassell, who, impressed, gets him a gig performing in the city's best nightclub. In the audience on the ...
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Music
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Musical
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   singer
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   nightclub
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   cabaret
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   1930s
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   opera
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Blake Edwards
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Blake Edwards
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Hans Hoemburg
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Julie Andrews
  </ator>
  <ator>
   James Garner
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Robert Preston
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    May I Review the First Half?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Ezell
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I think of the word "uneven" this film comes to mind. The first half is a wonderful funny film about the rise of a starving artist in the right place at the correct time. And the performances, wow! Julie Andrews vocal and comedic talents put to use, Leslie Ann Warren in an amazing performance as the ultimate Depression-era floozie and Robert Preston in what is probably his best film performance after The Music Man. All this flows perfectly for about an hour and then the second half, how shall I put this, stinks. I have frequently commented Hollywood would benefit from learning to make shorter, better films--a concept I wish Blake Edwards had considered when putting this film together.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Movie Ahead of It's Time!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ShelbyTMItchell
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Movie was way ahead of it's time as first saw it as a eight-year old back in Fla at the time. As it showed Julie Andrews being directed by her husband, the late and great Blake Edwards. He helped revive her career after Mary Popppins was typecasting her. As this proved to really help her shake that image. As she plays a poor female singer who is struggling to make ends meet. As she meets a gay singer who would become her manager, played by the great and late, Robert Preston. As after an argument with Preston's lover and Andrews punching him out, they make up her being a man pretending to be a woman singer. In order to make ends meet and it helps along the way winning both of them, fame and fortune. But Andrews finds out her personal life will clash when she meets the handsome James Gardner, who's bodyguard is also gay, played by the late great Alex Karras and his nagging girlfriend, Leslie Ann Warren. Gardner sees right through Andrews and the two fall in love as Andrews must maintain this image despite a snooping PI wanting to expose her. The film really helped out her career in the 1980s with Edwards. Seen this movie thousands of times, as it was ahead of it's time for the taboo 1980s. RIP Alex Karras, Blake Edwards, and Robert Edwards!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Okay....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Julie Andrews plays an out of work starving artist. However, when she meets a gay man (Robert Preston), he convinces her to fake being a cross-dresser and then she'll hit it big. This turns out to be true but also creates serious problems in regard to her love life. I read through the many very positive reviews for "Victor Victoria" and felt a bit lost. In some ways I wondered exactly what they saw in this film. I mean that "Victor Victoria" was kind of cute and enjoyable--but not much more. Perhaps the earlier versions would might have been a bit better. Although the film is set in France in the 1930s, you might no know that by listening to everyone. James Garner, Julie Andrews and Robert Preston are the leads....and are not exactly French. No one sounded or looked French. I wonder what French folks think when they see films like this... Also, while I know that the film is about a cross-dressing cabaret singer, I STILL felt that there were too many musical numbers. They tended to slow the film down and deflected the comedy. However, overall it's still an enjoyable little comedy that is a bit better than a time-passer. I know I am the odd reviewer here, but I just didn't see this as a really funny film nor did it seem all that special--especially with it coming out the same time as a better cross-dressing film, "Tootsie".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a 1980 movie; not 1982...but I digress. Simply one of the best movies!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    englishtnscones
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Blake Edwards was a genius! I agree with other reviewers that if you have a problem with THIS movie, then you have issues with your own sexuality that are no one else's problem but your own. I could watch this movie 1000 times (and I think I may have) and still belly laugh all the way through! I've let my kids watch it and all of the 'adult' jokes go right over their heads, like they did mine when I was only 13 (that's how I remember when this movie was released). Blake Edwards, who was not only Julie Andrew's husband but also the director of all the Pink Panther movies, was a brilliant director that more young movie makers should model their craft after. Physical comedy, not necessarily script lines, will always get a huge laugh if filmed properly with proper comedic timing (something that is next-to-impossible to teach). Knowing HOW to shoot a comedy scene is the key to getting those big laughs (watch the cockroach- restaurant scene to the end and note the change in audience perspective; that's what makes that scene a cinematic classic!) Get some popcorn, a glass of good French wine and prepare yourself for an evening of laughs and feel-good entertainment! Great for the whole family...as long as you're not "uptight". Life's too short to go through it uptight anyway so LEARN to be less selfish, LEARN to respect other people's way of thinking (even if it differs from your own beliefs)and LEARN how to be TOLERANT!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I still prefer Mary and Maria.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SmileysWorld
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Not unlike many men my age,I developed a huge crush on Julie Andrews as a kid somewhere between Mary Poppins and Maria Von Trapp.Over the years,Ms.Andrews has made it plain that she while she did enjoy working on the two films that produced these characters,she has not enjoyed the stereotyped image it produced for her.So,she set out to prove that she was indeed not the goody two shoes type that she has often been perceived to be.If that was her quest,she more than conquered it with her performance in this film.While I understand her position,I'm not one of those people that needed to see a film like this in order to understand that she isn't at all like those first two characters she played.It's all fantasy and I get that.All of that being said,I still prefer Mary and Maria vs. what she gives us here.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An absolute hoot!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I can't believe how much I loved Victor/Victoria. It is charming, witty and a lot of fun, and you can tell everybody involved with it had a ball. To be honest, I wasn't sure whether I would like this movie. I thought it would be a vehicle for Julie Andrews like Star! was and little more, and the story at first I wasn't sure about and I can't quite put my finger on why. I am so glad though that I saw it, because it was an absolute hoot and infinitely better than expected. This is so much more than a Julie Andrews vehicle, while it is not her best film it is one of her more enjoyable ones. As for Andrews she is wonderful. Here she does play an atypical role on the surface, looking at Mary Poppins and Sound of Music you would never guess Andrews would play a bloke. But she does play the role with wit and charm, and to be doubly sure she was comfortable she is even given some fun songs to show off her very angelic voice, she is especially impressive in the show-stopper that is Le Jazz Hot with very clever execution of the fiendishly difficult two-octave slide. That's not all. Andrews is supported by an equally impressive cast. James Garner is dashing and immensely likable as the heterosexual troubled by his attraction to Andrews' character. Robert Preston is also outrageously camp but in a good way- Shady Dame from Seville is hilarious-, while Lesley Ann Warren(very funny and very sexy), John Rhys Davies and especially Alex Karras give stellar supporting turns as well. The songs are just great, especially the moving Crazy World. The melodies are memorable and fun and the lyrics are deliciously witty, and I have to say the cast did great justice to those songs not just in the performances but in making them their own too. Just as good is the choreography, which manages to be sprightly and energetic. Blake Edwards also deserves a lot of credit for two things, one is his funny and witty script, the other is his affectionate and tender direction while never being too showy. The production values are top drawer, the sets and scenery are very elegant and pleasing on the eyes, the lighting is never dull and the costumes especially the drag costumes are colourful arrays. The story and romance is interesting with very rare a false or dull note even with the lengthy length. All in all, a delightful movie and a must see for fans of Julie Andrews, Blake Edwards, musicals or James Garner. 10/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Go ahead, laugh!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ptb-8
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I always had a struggle with VICTOR VICTORIA and only recently saw the 1935 Brit original FIRST A BOY with Jesse Matthews which itself was a remake of the identical German version called VIKTOR VIKTORIA from 1933. It is the German version that now in 2011 might just be the most fascinating of the two originals... however 30 years on from 1982, I possibly can appreciate VICTOR VICTORIA for the hilarious MGM musical farce others claim it is and see it up there with SINGIN IN THE RAIN and MY FAVOURITE YEAR. What I dislike about VV is that it is too long and too ramshackle in plot. Also I just get tired of it. Yes sacrilege I know but if it was tighter and not as meandering (it is half an hour longer than SINGIN IN THE RAIN and most other glorious musicals equally applauded) I would find it a better film. the ending just runs on and on with Robert Preston doing his lady Of Seville number. Every component of VV is terrific, Julie Andrews is as gorgeous as she was in STAR! (which I love yes even at 3 hours) and the sets and costumes are terrific. There is a lot of Pink Panther gag humor from director Blake Edwards and a perfect supporting cast. Robert Preston has had an incredible career and I equally admire him in MAME as in MUSIC MAN and here ... three massive musicals hits in the 60s 70s and 80s... almost a match for Julie! I love the parts of VV but I just don't love the film as a whole.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You and Me
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (albertoveronese)
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film grows in your heart a little stronger each time you watch it; it is like a genuinely good friend returning to visit you. Blake Edwards directed Victor Victoria with such an affection and tenderness that I think no one can help but be moved. You'll never find yourself tired watching it again and again because more you know the characters the more you love them, the funnier the situations and dialogs become, the more you enjoy the story. 'You and Me' which is sung by Julie Andrew and Robert Preston before the audience reminds us that you can be strong and free only if you know who you are and if you are true to who you are. Julie Andrews' song Crazy World calls us to keep loving others no matter what. Costumed or disguised you'll find Blake Edwards' comedy Victor Victoria to be bright, funny and thriving.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    That's what homosexuality was like in the 1980ies, folks
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Karl Self
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/9/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is "Tootsie" the other way round. A struggling female singer takes to impersonating a transvestite in order to make ends meet. This way, she doesn't have to impersonate anything and comes across as surprisingly convincing. A butch underworld king falls in love with her and is troubled that he's taken in by what he thinks is a man in drag. Although I personally don't care all that much for stories about gender crossing, Victor Victoria is simply a great film with a number of very impressive and creative vari&eacute;t&eacute; numbers. Director Blake Edwards used a ca. 1930ies German plot and recreated it around his wife Julie Edwards. He went out of his way to promote homosexuals as not-second-rate human beings, although he softened the original plot where the very masculine King Marchand falls in love with what he thinks is a man in drag -- in the film, King first finds out that Victor is really Victoria before he pursues her. Personally, I found the Toddy character, a middle-aged and very queer- acting man, annoying and somewhat dated.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I like this movie more every time I watch it
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    enkelien-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The first time I saw it, I thought it was "pretty good." Amusing, but I didn't expect to find myself watching it again. It's unpretentious. It doesn't have Big Ideas or profound themes that you have to watch it twice to get. But it's got lovable characters and a kickin' plot, and I happen to have a huge crush on the 1930s. I love the friendship between Victoria and Toddy because it feels so genuine and it's rare to see a friendship (particularly between men and women) portrayed so well in movies. I love the romance between Victoria and King, because they're well-matched, but at the same time the problems in their relationship are so realistic. Fundamental inability to compromise? I think everyone knows what that's like.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    May I Review the First Half?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Ezell
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I think of the word "uneven" this film comes to mind. The first half is a wonderful funny film about the rise of a starving artist in the right place at the correct time. And the performances, wow! Julie Andrews vocal and comedic talents put to use, Leslie Ann Warren in an amazing performance as the ultimate Depression-era floozie and Robert Preston in what is probably his best film performance after The Music Man. All this flows perfectly for about an hour and then the second half, how shall I put this, stinks. I have frequently commented Hollywood would benefit from learning to make shorter, better films--a concept I wish Blake Edwards had considered when putting this film together.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Movie Ahead of It's Time!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ShelbyTMItchell
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Movie was way ahead of it's time as first saw it as a eight-year old back in Fla at the time. As it showed Julie Andrews being directed by her husband, the late and great Blake Edwards. He helped revive her career after Mary Popppins was typecasting her. As this proved to really help her shake that image. As she plays a poor female singer who is struggling to make ends meet. As she meets a gay singer who would become her manager, played by the great and late, Robert Preston. As after an argument with Preston's lover and Andrews punching him out, they make up her being a man pretending to be a woman singer. In order to make ends meet and it helps along the way winning both of them, fame and fortune. But Andrews finds out her personal life will clash when she meets the handsome James Gardner, who's bodyguard is also gay, played by the late great Alex Karras and his nagging girlfriend, Leslie Ann Warren. Gardner sees right through Andrews and the two fall in love as Andrews must maintain this image despite a snooping PI wanting to expose her. The film really helped out her career in the 1980s with Edwards. Seen this movie thousands of times, as it was ahead of it's time for the taboo 1980s. RIP Alex Karras, Blake Edwards, and Robert Edwards!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Okay....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Julie Andrews plays an out of work starving artist. However, when she meets a gay man (Robert Preston), he convinces her to fake being a cross-dresser and then she'll hit it big. This turns out to be true but also creates serious problems in regard to her love life. I read through the many very positive reviews for "Victor Victoria" and felt a bit lost. In some ways I wondered exactly what they saw in this film. I mean that "Victor Victoria" was kind of cute and enjoyable--but not much more. Perhaps the earlier versions would might have been a bit better. Although the film is set in France in the 1930s, you might no know that by listening to everyone. James Garner, Julie Andrews and Robert Preston are the leads....and are not exactly French. No one sounded or looked French. I wonder what French folks think when they see films like this... Also, while I know that the film is about a cross-dressing cabaret singer, I STILL felt that there were too many musical numbers. They tended to slow the film down and deflected the comedy. However, overall it's still an enjoyable little comedy that is a bit better than a time-passer. I know I am the odd reviewer here, but I just didn't see this as a really funny film nor did it seem all that special--especially with it coming out the same time as a better cross-dressing film, "Tootsie".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a 1980 movie; not 1982...but I digress. Simply one of the best movies!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    englishtnscones
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Blake Edwards was a genius! I agree with other reviewers that if you have a problem with THIS movie, then you have issues with your own sexuality that are no one else's problem but your own. I could watch this movie 1000 times (and I think I may have) and still belly laugh all the way through! I've let my kids watch it and all of the 'adult' jokes go right over their heads, like they did mine when I was only 13 (that's how I remember when this movie was released). Blake Edwards, who was not only Julie Andrew's husband but also the director of all the Pink Panther movies, was a brilliant director that more young movie makers should model their craft after. Physical comedy, not necessarily script lines, will always get a huge laugh if filmed properly with proper comedic timing (something that is next-to-impossible to teach). Knowing HOW to shoot a comedy scene is the key to getting those big laughs (watch the cockroach- restaurant scene to the end and note the change in audience perspective; that's what makes that scene a cinematic classic!) Get some popcorn, a glass of good French wine and prepare yourself for an evening of laughs and feel-good entertainment! Great for the whole family...as long as you're not "uptight". Life's too short to go through it uptight anyway so LEARN to be less selfish, LEARN to respect other people's way of thinking (even if it differs from your own beliefs)and LEARN how to be TOLERANT!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I still prefer Mary and Maria.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SmileysWorld
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Not unlike many men my age,I developed a huge crush on Julie Andrews as a kid somewhere between Mary Poppins and Maria Von Trapp.Over the years,Ms.Andrews has made it plain that she while she did enjoy working on the two films that produced these characters,she has not enjoyed the stereotyped image it produced for her.So,she set out to prove that she was indeed not the goody two shoes type that she has often been perceived to be.If that was her quest,she more than conquered it with her performance in this film.While I understand her position,I'm not one of those people that needed to see a film like this in order to understand that she isn't at all like those first two characters she played.It's all fantasy and I get that.All of that being said,I still prefer Mary and Maria vs. what she gives us here.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An absolute hoot!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I can't believe how much I loved Victor/Victoria. It is charming, witty and a lot of fun, and you can tell everybody involved with it had a ball. To be honest, I wasn't sure whether I would like this movie. I thought it would be a vehicle for Julie Andrews like Star! was and little more, and the story at first I wasn't sure about and I can't quite put my finger on why. I am so glad though that I saw it, because it was an absolute hoot and infinitely better than expected. This is so much more than a Julie Andrews vehicle, while it is not her best film it is one of her more enjoyable ones. As for Andrews she is wonderful. Here she does play an atypical role on the surface, looking at Mary Poppins and Sound of Music you would never guess Andrews would play a bloke. But she does play the role with wit and charm, and to be doubly sure she was comfortable she is even given some fun songs to show off her very angelic voice, she is especially impressive in the show-stopper that is Le Jazz Hot with very clever execution of the fiendishly difficult two-octave slide. That's not all. Andrews is supported by an equally impressive cast. James Garner is dashing and immensely likable as the heterosexual troubled by his attraction to Andrews' character. Robert Preston is also outrageously camp but in a good way- Shady Dame from Seville is hilarious-, while Lesley Ann Warren(very funny and very sexy), John Rhys Davies and especially Alex Karras give stellar supporting turns as well. The songs are just great, especially the moving Crazy World. The melodies are memorable and fun and the lyrics are deliciously witty, and I have to say the cast did great justice to those songs not just in the performances but in making them their own too. Just as good is the choreography, which manages to be sprightly and energetic. Blake Edwards also deserves a lot of credit for two things, one is his funny and witty script, the other is his affectionate and tender direction while never being too showy. The production values are top drawer, the sets and scenery are very elegant and pleasing on the eyes, the lighting is never dull and the costumes especially the drag costumes are colourful arrays. The story and romance is interesting with very rare a false or dull note even with the lengthy length. All in all, a delightful movie and a must see for fans of Julie Andrews, Blake Edwards, musicals or James Garner. 10/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Go ahead, laugh!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ptb-8
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I always had a struggle with VICTOR VICTORIA and only recently saw the 1935 Brit original FIRST A BOY with Jesse Matthews which itself was a remake of the identical German version called VIKTOR VIKTORIA from 1933. It is the German version that now in 2011 might just be the most fascinating of the two originals... however 30 years on from 1982, I possibly can appreciate VICTOR VICTORIA for the hilarious MGM musical farce others claim it is and see it up there with SINGIN IN THE RAIN and MY FAVOURITE YEAR. What I dislike about VV is that it is too long and too ramshackle in plot. Also I just get tired of it. Yes sacrilege I know but if it was tighter and not as meandering (it is half an hour longer than SINGIN IN THE RAIN and most other glorious musicals equally applauded) I would find it a better film. the ending just runs on and on with Robert Preston doing his lady Of Seville number. Every component of VV is terrific, Julie Andrews is as gorgeous as she was in STAR! (which I love yes even at 3 hours) and the sets and costumes are terrific. There is a lot of Pink Panther gag humor from director Blake Edwards and a perfect supporting cast. Robert Preston has had an incredible career and I equally admire him in MAME as in MUSIC MAN and here ... three massive musicals hits in the 60s 70s and 80s... almost a match for Julie! I love the parts of VV but I just don't love the film as a whole.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You and Me
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (albertoveronese)
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film grows in your heart a little stronger each time you watch it; it is like a genuinely good friend returning to visit you. Blake Edwards directed Victor Victoria with such an affection and tenderness that I think no one can help but be moved. You'll never find yourself tired watching it again and again because more you know the characters the more you love them, the funnier the situations and dialogs become, the more you enjoy the story. 'You and Me' which is sung by Julie Andrew and Robert Preston before the audience reminds us that you can be strong and free only if you know who you are and if you are true to who you are. Julie Andrews' song Crazy World calls us to keep loving others no matter what. Costumed or disguised you'll find Blake Edwards' comedy Victor Victoria to be bright, funny and thriving.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    That's what homosexuality was like in the 1980ies, folks
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Karl Self
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/9/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is "Tootsie" the other way round. A struggling female singer takes to impersonating a transvestite in order to make ends meet. This way, she doesn't have to impersonate anything and comes across as surprisingly convincing. A butch underworld king falls in love with her and is troubled that he's taken in by what he thinks is a man in drag. Although I personally don't care all that much for stories about gender crossing, Victor Victoria is simply a great film with a number of very impressive and creative vari&eacute;t&eacute; numbers. Director Blake Edwards used a ca. 1930ies German plot and recreated it around his wife Julie Edwards. He went out of his way to promote homosexuals as not-second-rate human beings, although he softened the original plot where the very masculine King Marchand falls in love with what he thinks is a man in drag -- in the film, King first finds out that Victor is really Victoria before he pursues her. Personally, I found the Toddy character, a middle-aged and very queer- acting man, annoying and somewhat dated.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I like this movie more every time I watch it
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    enkelien-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The first time I saw it, I thought it was "pretty good." Amusing, but I didn't expect to find myself watching it again. It's unpretentious. It doesn't have Big Ideas or profound themes that you have to watch it twice to get. But it's got lovable characters and a kickin' plot, and I happen to have a huge crush on the 1930s. I love the friendship between Victoria and Toddy because it feels so genuine and it's rare to see a friendship (particularly between men and women) portrayed so well in movies. I love the romance between Victoria and King, because they're well-matched, but at the same time the problems in their relationship are so realistic. Fundamental inability to compromise? I think everyone knows what that's like.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    May I Review the First Half?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Ezell
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I think of the word "uneven" this film comes to mind. The first half is a wonderful funny film about the rise of a starving artist in the right place at the correct time. And the performances, wow! Julie Andrews vocal and comedic talents put to use, Leslie Ann Warren in an amazing performance as the ultimate Depression-era floozie and Robert Preston in what is probably his best film performance after The Music Man. All this flows perfectly for about an hour and then the second half, how shall I put this, stinks. I have frequently commented Hollywood would benefit from learning to make shorter, better films--a concept I wish Blake Edwards had considered when putting this film together.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Movie Ahead of It's Time!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ShelbyTMItchell
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Movie was way ahead of it's time as first saw it as a eight-year old back in Fla at the time. As it showed Julie Andrews being directed by her husband, the late and great Blake Edwards. He helped revive her career after Mary Popppins was typecasting her. As this proved to really help her shake that image. As she plays a poor female singer who is struggling to make ends meet. As she meets a gay singer who would become her manager, played by the great and late, Robert Preston. As after an argument with Preston's lover and Andrews punching him out, they make up her being a man pretending to be a woman singer. In order to make ends meet and it helps along the way winning both of them, fame and fortune. But Andrews finds out her personal life will clash when she meets the handsome James Gardner, who's bodyguard is also gay, played by the late great Alex Karras and his nagging girlfriend, Leslie Ann Warren. Gardner sees right through Andrews and the two fall in love as Andrews must maintain this image despite a snooping PI wanting to expose her. The film really helped out her career in the 1980s with Edwards. Seen this movie thousands of times, as it was ahead of it's time for the taboo 1980s. RIP Alex Karras, Blake Edwards, and Robert Edwards!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Okay....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Julie Andrews plays an out of work starving artist. However, when she meets a gay man (Robert Preston), he convinces her to fake being a cross-dresser and then she'll hit it big. This turns out to be true but also creates serious problems in regard to her love life. I read through the many very positive reviews for "Victor Victoria" and felt a bit lost. In some ways I wondered exactly what they saw in this film. I mean that "Victor Victoria" was kind of cute and enjoyable--but not much more. Perhaps the earlier versions would might have been a bit better. Although the film is set in France in the 1930s, you might no know that by listening to everyone. James Garner, Julie Andrews and Robert Preston are the leads....and are not exactly French. No one sounded or looked French. I wonder what French folks think when they see films like this... Also, while I know that the film is about a cross-dressing cabaret singer, I STILL felt that there were too many musical numbers. They tended to slow the film down and deflected the comedy. However, overall it's still an enjoyable little comedy that is a bit better than a time-passer. I know I am the odd reviewer here, but I just didn't see this as a really funny film nor did it seem all that special--especially with it coming out the same time as a better cross-dressing film, "Tootsie".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a 1980 movie; not 1982...but I digress. Simply one of the best movies!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    englishtnscones
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Blake Edwards was a genius! I agree with other reviewers that if you have a problem with THIS movie, then you have issues with your own sexuality that are no one else's problem but your own. I could watch this movie 1000 times (and I think I may have) and still belly laugh all the way through! I've let my kids watch it and all of the 'adult' jokes go right over their heads, like they did mine when I was only 13 (that's how I remember when this movie was released). Blake Edwards, who was not only Julie Andrew's husband but also the director of all the Pink Panther movies, was a brilliant director that more young movie makers should model their craft after. Physical comedy, not necessarily script lines, will always get a huge laugh if filmed properly with proper comedic timing (something that is next-to-impossible to teach). Knowing HOW to shoot a comedy scene is the key to getting those big laughs (watch the cockroach- restaurant scene to the end and note the change in audience perspective; that's what makes that scene a cinematic classic!) Get some popcorn, a glass of good French wine and prepare yourself for an evening of laughs and feel-good entertainment! Great for the whole family...as long as you're not "uptight". Life's too short to go through it uptight anyway so LEARN to be less selfish, LEARN to respect other people's way of thinking (even if it differs from your own beliefs)and LEARN how to be TOLERANT!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I still prefer Mary and Maria.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SmileysWorld
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Not unlike many men my age,I developed a huge crush on Julie Andrews as a kid somewhere between Mary Poppins and Maria Von Trapp.Over the years,Ms.Andrews has made it plain that she while she did enjoy working on the two films that produced these characters,she has not enjoyed the stereotyped image it produced for her.So,she set out to prove that she was indeed not the goody two shoes type that she has often been perceived to be.If that was her quest,she more than conquered it with her performance in this film.While I understand her position,I'm not one of those people that needed to see a film like this in order to understand that she isn't at all like those first two characters she played.It's all fantasy and I get that.All of that being said,I still prefer Mary and Maria vs. what she gives us here.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An absolute hoot!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I can't believe how much I loved Victor/Victoria. It is charming, witty and a lot of fun, and you can tell everybody involved with it had a ball. To be honest, I wasn't sure whether I would like this movie. I thought it would be a vehicle for Julie Andrews like Star! was and little more, and the story at first I wasn't sure about and I can't quite put my finger on why. I am so glad though that I saw it, because it was an absolute hoot and infinitely better than expected. This is so much more than a Julie Andrews vehicle, while it is not her best film it is one of her more enjoyable ones. As for Andrews she is wonderful. Here she does play an atypical role on the surface, looking at Mary Poppins and Sound of Music you would never guess Andrews would play a bloke. But she does play the role with wit and charm, and to be doubly sure she was comfortable she is even given some fun songs to show off her very angelic voice, she is especially impressive in the show-stopper that is Le Jazz Hot with very clever execution of the fiendishly difficult two-octave slide. That's not all. Andrews is supported by an equally impressive cast. James Garner is dashing and immensely likable as the heterosexual troubled by his attraction to Andrews' character. Robert Preston is also outrageously camp but in a good way- Shady Dame from Seville is hilarious-, while Lesley Ann Warren(very funny and very sexy), John Rhys Davies and especially Alex Karras give stellar supporting turns as well. The songs are just great, especially the moving Crazy World. The melodies are memorable and fun and the lyrics are deliciously witty, and I have to say the cast did great justice to those songs not just in the performances but in making them their own too. Just as good is the choreography, which manages to be sprightly and energetic. Blake Edwards also deserves a lot of credit for two things, one is his funny and witty script, the other is his affectionate and tender direction while never being too showy. The production values are top drawer, the sets and scenery are very elegant and pleasing on the eyes, the lighting is never dull and the costumes especially the drag costumes are colourful arrays. The story and romance is interesting with very rare a false or dull note even with the lengthy length. All in all, a delightful movie and a must see for fans of Julie Andrews, Blake Edwards, musicals or James Garner. 10/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Go ahead, laugh!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ptb-8
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I always had a struggle with VICTOR VICTORIA and only recently saw the 1935 Brit original FIRST A BOY with Jesse Matthews which itself was a remake of the identical German version called VIKTOR VIKTORIA from 1933. It is the German version that now in 2011 might just be the most fascinating of the two originals... however 30 years on from 1982, I possibly can appreciate VICTOR VICTORIA for the hilarious MGM musical farce others claim it is and see it up there with SINGIN IN THE RAIN and MY FAVOURITE YEAR. What I dislike about VV is that it is too long and too ramshackle in plot. Also I just get tired of it. Yes sacrilege I know but if it was tighter and not as meandering (it is half an hour longer than SINGIN IN THE RAIN and most other glorious musicals equally applauded) I would find it a better film. the ending just runs on and on with Robert Preston doing his lady Of Seville number. Every component of VV is terrific, Julie Andrews is as gorgeous as she was in STAR! (which I love yes even at 3 hours) and the sets and costumes are terrific. There is a lot of Pink Panther gag humor from director Blake Edwards and a perfect supporting cast. Robert Preston has had an incredible career and I equally admire him in MAME as in MUSIC MAN and here ... three massive musicals hits in the 60s 70s and 80s... almost a match for Julie! I love the parts of VV but I just don't love the film as a whole.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You and Me
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (albertoveronese)
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film grows in your heart a little stronger each time you watch it; it is like a genuinely good friend returning to visit you. Blake Edwards directed Victor Victoria with such an affection and tenderness that I think no one can help but be moved. You'll never find yourself tired watching it again and again because more you know the characters the more you love them, the funnier the situations and dialogs become, the more you enjoy the story. 'You and Me' which is sung by Julie Andrew and Robert Preston before the audience reminds us that you can be strong and free only if you know who you are and if you are true to who you are. Julie Andrews' song Crazy World calls us to keep loving others no matter what. Costumed or disguised you'll find Blake Edwards' comedy Victor Victoria to be bright, funny and thriving.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    That's what homosexuality was like in the 1980ies, folks
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Karl Self
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/9/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is "Tootsie" the other way round. A struggling female singer takes to impersonating a transvestite in order to make ends meet. This way, she doesn't have to impersonate anything and comes across as surprisingly convincing. A butch underworld king falls in love with her and is troubled that he's taken in by what he thinks is a man in drag. Although I personally don't care all that much for stories about gender crossing, Victor Victoria is simply a great film with a number of very impressive and creative vari&eacute;t&eacute; numbers. Director Blake Edwards used a ca. 1930ies German plot and recreated it around his wife Julie Edwards. He went out of his way to promote homosexuals as not-second-rate human beings, although he softened the original plot where the very masculine King Marchand falls in love with what he thinks is a man in drag -- in the film, King first finds out that Victor is really Victoria before he pursues her. Personally, I found the Toddy character, a middle-aged and very queer- acting man, annoying and somewhat dated.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I like this movie more every time I watch it
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    enkelien-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The first time I saw it, I thought it was "pretty good." Amusing, but I didn't expect to find myself watching it again. It's unpretentious. It doesn't have Big Ideas or profound themes that you have to watch it twice to get. But it's got lovable characters and a kickin' plot, and I happen to have a huge crush on the 1930s. I love the friendship between Victoria and Toddy because it feels so genuine and it's rare to see a friendship (particularly between men and women) portrayed so well in movies. I love the romance between Victoria and King, because they're well-matched, but at the same time the problems in their relationship are so realistic. Fundamental inability to compromise? I think everyone knows what that's like.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    May I Review the First Half?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Ezell
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I think of the word "uneven" this film comes to mind. The first half is a wonderful funny film about the rise of a starving artist in the right place at the correct time. And the performances, wow! Julie Andrews vocal and comedic talents put to use, Leslie Ann Warren in an amazing performance as the ultimate Depression-era floozie and Robert Preston in what is probably his best film performance after The Music Man. All this flows perfectly for about an hour and then the second half, how shall I put this, stinks. I have frequently commented Hollywood would benefit from learning to make shorter, better films--a concept I wish Blake Edwards had considered when putting this film together.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Movie Ahead of It's Time!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ShelbyTMItchell
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Movie was way ahead of it's time as first saw it as a eight-year old back in Fla at the time. As it showed Julie Andrews being directed by her husband, the late and great Blake Edwards. He helped revive her career after Mary Popppins was typecasting her. As this proved to really help her shake that image. As she plays a poor female singer who is struggling to make ends meet. As she meets a gay singer who would become her manager, played by the great and late, Robert Preston. As after an argument with Preston's lover and Andrews punching him out, they make up her being a man pretending to be a woman singer. In order to make ends meet and it helps along the way winning both of them, fame and fortune. But Andrews finds out her personal life will clash when she meets the handsome James Gardner, who's bodyguard is also gay, played by the late great Alex Karras and his nagging girlfriend, Leslie Ann Warren. Gardner sees right through Andrews and the two fall in love as Andrews must maintain this image despite a snooping PI wanting to expose her. The film really helped out her career in the 1980s with Edwards. Seen this movie thousands of times, as it was ahead of it's time for the taboo 1980s. RIP Alex Karras, Blake Edwards, and Robert Edwards!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Okay....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Julie Andrews plays an out of work starving artist. However, when she meets a gay man (Robert Preston), he convinces her to fake being a cross-dresser and then she'll hit it big. This turns out to be true but also creates serious problems in regard to her love life. I read through the many very positive reviews for "Victor Victoria" and felt a bit lost. In some ways I wondered exactly what they saw in this film. I mean that "Victor Victoria" was kind of cute and enjoyable--but not much more. Perhaps the earlier versions would might have been a bit better. Although the film is set in France in the 1930s, you might no know that by listening to everyone. James Garner, Julie Andrews and Robert Preston are the leads....and are not exactly French. No one sounded or looked French. I wonder what French folks think when they see films like this... Also, while I know that the film is about a cross-dressing cabaret singer, I STILL felt that there were too many musical numbers. They tended to slow the film down and deflected the comedy. However, overall it's still an enjoyable little comedy that is a bit better than a time-passer. I know I am the odd reviewer here, but I just didn't see this as a really funny film nor did it seem all that special--especially with it coming out the same time as a better cross-dressing film, "Tootsie".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a 1980 movie; not 1982...but I digress. Simply one of the best movies!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    englishtnscones
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Blake Edwards was a genius! I agree with other reviewers that if you have a problem with THIS movie, then you have issues with your own sexuality that are no one else's problem but your own. I could watch this movie 1000 times (and I think I may have) and still belly laugh all the way through! I've let my kids watch it and all of the 'adult' jokes go right over their heads, like they did mine when I was only 13 (that's how I remember when this movie was released). Blake Edwards, who was not only Julie Andrew's husband but also the director of all the Pink Panther movies, was a brilliant director that more young movie makers should model their craft after. Physical comedy, not necessarily script lines, will always get a huge laugh if filmed properly with proper comedic timing (something that is next-to-impossible to teach). Knowing HOW to shoot a comedy scene is the key to getting those big laughs (watch the cockroach- restaurant scene to the end and note the change in audience perspective; that's what makes that scene a cinematic classic!) Get some popcorn, a glass of good French wine and prepare yourself for an evening of laughs and feel-good entertainment! Great for the whole family...as long as you're not "uptight". Life's too short to go through it uptight anyway so LEARN to be less selfish, LEARN to respect other people's way of thinking (even if it differs from your own beliefs)and LEARN how to be TOLERANT!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I still prefer Mary and Maria.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SmileysWorld
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Not unlike many men my age,I developed a huge crush on Julie Andrews as a kid somewhere between Mary Poppins and Maria Von Trapp.Over the years,Ms.Andrews has made it plain that she while she did enjoy working on the two films that produced these characters,she has not enjoyed the stereotyped image it produced for her.So,she set out to prove that she was indeed not the goody two shoes type that she has often been perceived to be.If that was her quest,she more than conquered it with her performance in this film.While I understand her position,I'm not one of those people that needed to see a film like this in order to understand that she isn't at all like those first two characters she played.It's all fantasy and I get that.All of that being said,I still prefer Mary and Maria vs. what she gives us here.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An absolute hoot!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I can't believe how much I loved Victor/Victoria. It is charming, witty and a lot of fun, and you can tell everybody involved with it had a ball. To be honest, I wasn't sure whether I would like this movie. I thought it would be a vehicle for Julie Andrews like Star! was and little more, and the story at first I wasn't sure about and I can't quite put my finger on why. I am so glad though that I saw it, because it was an absolute hoot and infinitely better than expected. This is so much more than a Julie Andrews vehicle, while it is not her best film it is one of her more enjoyable ones. As for Andrews she is wonderful. Here she does play an atypical role on the surface, looking at Mary Poppins and Sound of Music you would never guess Andrews would play a bloke. But she does play the role with wit and charm, and to be doubly sure she was comfortable she is even given some fun songs to show off her very angelic voice, she is especially impressive in the show-stopper that is Le Jazz Hot with very clever execution of the fiendishly difficult two-octave slide. That's not all. Andrews is supported by an equally impressive cast. James Garner is dashing and immensely likable as the heterosexual troubled by his attraction to Andrews' character. Robert Preston is also outrageously camp but in a good way- Shady Dame from Seville is hilarious-, while Lesley Ann Warren(very funny and very sexy), John Rhys Davies and especially Alex Karras give stellar supporting turns as well. The songs are just great, especially the moving Crazy World. The melodies are memorable and fun and the lyrics are deliciously witty, and I have to say the cast did great justice to those songs not just in the performances but in making them their own too. Just as good is the choreography, which manages to be sprightly and energetic. Blake Edwards also deserves a lot of credit for two things, one is his funny and witty script, the other is his affectionate and tender direction while never being too showy. The production values are top drawer, the sets and scenery are very elegant and pleasing on the eyes, the lighting is never dull and the costumes especially the drag costumes are colourful arrays. The story and romance is interesting with very rare a false or dull note even with the lengthy length. All in all, a delightful movie and a must see for fans of Julie Andrews, Blake Edwards, musicals or James Garner. 10/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Go ahead, laugh!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ptb-8
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I always had a struggle with VICTOR VICTORIA and only recently saw the 1935 Brit original FIRST A BOY with Jesse Matthews which itself was a remake of the identical German version called VIKTOR VIKTORIA from 1933. It is the German version that now in 2011 might just be the most fascinating of the two originals... however 30 years on from 1982, I possibly can appreciate VICTOR VICTORIA for the hilarious MGM musical farce others claim it is and see it up there with SINGIN IN THE RAIN and MY FAVOURITE YEAR. What I dislike about VV is that it is too long and too ramshackle in plot. Also I just get tired of it. Yes sacrilege I know but if it was tighter and not as meandering (it is half an hour longer than SINGIN IN THE RAIN and most other glorious musicals equally applauded) I would find it a better film. the ending just runs on and on with Robert Preston doing his lady Of Seville number. Every component of VV is terrific, Julie Andrews is as gorgeous as she was in STAR! (which I love yes even at 3 hours) and the sets and costumes are terrific. There is a lot of Pink Panther gag humor from director Blake Edwards and a perfect supporting cast. Robert Preston has had an incredible career and I equally admire him in MAME as in MUSIC MAN and here ... three massive musicals hits in the 60s 70s and 80s... almost a match for Julie! I love the parts of VV but I just don't love the film as a whole.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You and Me
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (albertoveronese)
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film grows in your heart a little stronger each time you watch it; it is like a genuinely good friend returning to visit you. Blake Edwards directed Victor Victoria with such an affection and tenderness that I think no one can help but be moved. You'll never find yourself tired watching it again and again because more you know the characters the more you love them, the funnier the situations and dialogs become, the more you enjoy the story. 'You and Me' which is sung by Julie Andrew and Robert Preston before the audience reminds us that you can be strong and free only if you know who you are and if you are true to who you are. Julie Andrews' song Crazy World calls us to keep loving others no matter what. Costumed or disguised you'll find Blake Edwards' comedy Victor Victoria to be bright, funny and thriving.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    That's what homosexuality was like in the 1980ies, folks
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Karl Self
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/9/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is "Tootsie" the other way round. A struggling female singer takes to impersonating a transvestite in order to make ends meet. This way, she doesn't have to impersonate anything and comes across as surprisingly convincing. A butch underworld king falls in love with her and is troubled that he's taken in by what he thinks is a man in drag. Although I personally don't care all that much for stories about gender crossing, Victor Victoria is simply a great film with a number of very impressive and creative vari&eacute;t&eacute; numbers. Director Blake Edwards used a ca. 1930ies German plot and recreated it around his wife Julie Edwards. He went out of his way to promote homosexuals as not-second-rate human beings, although he softened the original plot where the very masculine King Marchand falls in love with what he thinks is a man in drag -- in the film, King first finds out that Victor is really Victoria before he pursues her. Personally, I found the Toddy character, a middle-aged and very queer- acting man, annoying and somewhat dated.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I like this movie more every time I watch it
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    enkelien-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The first time I saw it, I thought it was "pretty good." Amusing, but I didn't expect to find myself watching it again. It's unpretentious. It doesn't have Big Ideas or profound themes that you have to watch it twice to get. But it's got lovable characters and a kickin' plot, and I happen to have a huge crush on the 1930s. I love the friendship between Victoria and Toddy because it feels so genuine and it's rare to see a friendship (particularly between men and women) portrayed so well in movies. I love the romance between Victoria and King, because they're well-matched, but at the same time the problems in their relationship are so realistic. Fundamental inability to compromise? I think everyone knows what that's like.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    May I Review the First Half?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Ezell
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I think of the word "uneven" this film comes to mind. The first half is a wonderful funny film about the rise of a starving artist in the right place at the correct time. And the performances, wow! Julie Andrews vocal and comedic talents put to use, Leslie Ann Warren in an amazing performance as the ultimate Depression-era floozie and Robert Preston in what is probably his best film performance after The Music Man. All this flows perfectly for about an hour and then the second half, how shall I put this, stinks. I have frequently commented Hollywood would benefit from learning to make shorter, better films--a concept I wish Blake Edwards had considered when putting this film together.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Movie Ahead of It's Time!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ShelbyTMItchell
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Movie was way ahead of it's time as first saw it as a eight-year old back in Fla at the time. As it showed Julie Andrews being directed by her husband, the late and great Blake Edwards. He helped revive her career after Mary Popppins was typecasting her. As this proved to really help her shake that image. As she plays a poor female singer who is struggling to make ends meet. As she meets a gay singer who would become her manager, played by the great and late, Robert Preston. As after an argument with Preston's lover and Andrews punching him out, they make up her being a man pretending to be a woman singer. In order to make ends meet and it helps along the way winning both of them, fame and fortune. But Andrews finds out her personal life will clash when she meets the handsome James Gardner, who's bodyguard is also gay, played by the late great Alex Karras and his nagging girlfriend, Leslie Ann Warren. Gardner sees right through Andrews and the two fall in love as Andrews must maintain this image despite a snooping PI wanting to expose her. The film really helped out her career in the 1980s with Edwards. Seen this movie thousands of times, as it was ahead of it's time for the taboo 1980s. RIP Alex Karras, Blake Edwards, and Robert Edwards!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Okay....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Julie Andrews plays an out of work starving artist. However, when she meets a gay man (Robert Preston), he convinces her to fake being a cross-dresser and then she'll hit it big. This turns out to be true but also creates serious problems in regard to her love life. I read through the many very positive reviews for "Victor Victoria" and felt a bit lost. In some ways I wondered exactly what they saw in this film. I mean that "Victor Victoria" was kind of cute and enjoyable--but not much more. Perhaps the earlier versions would might have been a bit better. Although the film is set in France in the 1930s, you might no know that by listening to everyone. James Garner, Julie Andrews and Robert Preston are the leads....and are not exactly French. No one sounded or looked French. I wonder what French folks think when they see films like this... Also, while I know that the film is about a cross-dressing cabaret singer, I STILL felt that there were too many musical numbers. They tended to slow the film down and deflected the comedy. However, overall it's still an enjoyable little comedy that is a bit better than a time-passer. I know I am the odd reviewer here, but I just didn't see this as a really funny film nor did it seem all that special--especially with it coming out the same time as a better cross-dressing film, "Tootsie".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a 1980 movie; not 1982...but I digress. Simply one of the best movies!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    englishtnscones
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Blake Edwards was a genius! I agree with other reviewers that if you have a problem with THIS movie, then you have issues with your own sexuality that are no one else's problem but your own. I could watch this movie 1000 times (and I think I may have) and still belly laugh all the way through! I've let my kids watch it and all of the 'adult' jokes go right over their heads, like they did mine when I was only 13 (that's how I remember when this movie was released). Blake Edwards, who was not only Julie Andrew's husband but also the director of all the Pink Panther movies, was a brilliant director that more young movie makers should model their craft after. Physical comedy, not necessarily script lines, will always get a huge laugh if filmed properly with proper comedic timing (something that is next-to-impossible to teach). Knowing HOW to shoot a comedy scene is the key to getting those big laughs (watch the cockroach- restaurant scene to the end and note the change in audience perspective; that's what makes that scene a cinematic classic!) Get some popcorn, a glass of good French wine and prepare yourself for an evening of laughs and feel-good entertainment! Great for the whole family...as long as you're not "uptight". Life's too short to go through it uptight anyway so LEARN to be less selfish, LEARN to respect other people's way of thinking (even if it differs from your own beliefs)and LEARN how to be TOLERANT!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I still prefer Mary and Maria.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SmileysWorld
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Not unlike many men my age,I developed a huge crush on Julie Andrews as a kid somewhere between Mary Poppins and Maria Von Trapp.Over the years,Ms.Andrews has made it plain that she while she did enjoy working on the two films that produced these characters,she has not enjoyed the stereotyped image it produced for her.So,she set out to prove that she was indeed not the goody two shoes type that she has often been perceived to be.If that was her quest,she more than conquered it with her performance in this film.While I understand her position,I'm not one of those people that needed to see a film like this in order to understand that she isn't at all like those first two characters she played.It's all fantasy and I get that.All of that being said,I still prefer Mary and Maria vs. what she gives us here.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An absolute hoot!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I can't believe how much I loved Victor/Victoria. It is charming, witty and a lot of fun, and you can tell everybody involved with it had a ball. To be honest, I wasn't sure whether I would like this movie. I thought it would be a vehicle for Julie Andrews like Star! was and little more, and the story at first I wasn't sure about and I can't quite put my finger on why. I am so glad though that I saw it, because it was an absolute hoot and infinitely better than expected. This is so much more than a Julie Andrews vehicle, while it is not her best film it is one of her more enjoyable ones. As for Andrews she is wonderful. Here she does play an atypical role on the surface, looking at Mary Poppins and Sound of Music you would never guess Andrews would play a bloke. But she does play the role with wit and charm, and to be doubly sure she was comfortable she is even given some fun songs to show off her very angelic voice, she is especially impressive in the show-stopper that is Le Jazz Hot with very clever execution of the fiendishly difficult two-octave slide. That's not all. Andrews is supported by an equally impressive cast. James Garner is dashing and immensely likable as the heterosexual troubled by his attraction to Andrews' character. Robert Preston is also outrageously camp but in a good way- Shady Dame from Seville is hilarious-, while Lesley Ann Warren(very funny and very sexy), John Rhys Davies and especially Alex Karras give stellar supporting turns as well. The songs are just great, especially the moving Crazy World. The melodies are memorable and fun and the lyrics are deliciously witty, and I have to say the cast did great justice to those songs not just in the performances but in making them their own too. Just as good is the choreography, which manages to be sprightly and energetic. Blake Edwards also deserves a lot of credit for two things, one is his funny and witty script, the other is his affectionate and tender direction while never being too showy. The production values are top drawer, the sets and scenery are very elegant and pleasing on the eyes, the lighting is never dull and the costumes especially the drag costumes are colourful arrays. The story and romance is interesting with very rare a false or dull note even with the lengthy length. All in all, a delightful movie and a must see for fans of Julie Andrews, Blake Edwards, musicals or James Garner. 10/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Go ahead, laugh!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ptb-8
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I always had a struggle with VICTOR VICTORIA and only recently saw the 1935 Brit original FIRST A BOY with Jesse Matthews which itself was a remake of the identical German version called VIKTOR VIKTORIA from 1933. It is the German version that now in 2011 might just be the most fascinating of the two originals... however 30 years on from 1982, I possibly can appreciate VICTOR VICTORIA for the hilarious MGM musical farce others claim it is and see it up there with SINGIN IN THE RAIN and MY FAVOURITE YEAR. What I dislike about VV is that it is too long and too ramshackle in plot. Also I just get tired of it. Yes sacrilege I know but if it was tighter and not as meandering (it is half an hour longer than SINGIN IN THE RAIN and most other glorious musicals equally applauded) I would find it a better film. the ending just runs on and on with Robert Preston doing his lady Of Seville number. Every component of VV is terrific, Julie Andrews is as gorgeous as she was in STAR! (which I love yes even at 3 hours) and the sets and costumes are terrific. There is a lot of Pink Panther gag humor from director Blake Edwards and a perfect supporting cast. Robert Preston has had an incredible career and I equally admire him in MAME as in MUSIC MAN and here ... three massive musicals hits in the 60s 70s and 80s... almost a match for Julie! I love the parts of VV but I just don't love the film as a whole.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You and Me
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (albertoveronese)
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film grows in your heart a little stronger each time you watch it; it is like a genuinely good friend returning to visit you. Blake Edwards directed Victor Victoria with such an affection and tenderness that I think no one can help but be moved. You'll never find yourself tired watching it again and again because more you know the characters the more you love them, the funnier the situations and dialogs become, the more you enjoy the story. 'You and Me' which is sung by Julie Andrew and Robert Preston before the audience reminds us that you can be strong and free only if you know who you are and if you are true to who you are. Julie Andrews' song Crazy World calls us to keep loving others no matter what. Costumed or disguised you'll find Blake Edwards' comedy Victor Victoria to be bright, funny and thriving.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    That's what homosexuality was like in the 1980ies, folks
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Karl Self
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/9/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is "Tootsie" the other way round. A struggling female singer takes to impersonating a transvestite in order to make ends meet. This way, she doesn't have to impersonate anything and comes across as surprisingly convincing. A butch underworld king falls in love with her and is troubled that he's taken in by what he thinks is a man in drag. Although I personally don't care all that much for stories about gender crossing, Victor Victoria is simply a great film with a number of very impressive and creative vari&eacute;t&eacute; numbers. Director Blake Edwards used a ca. 1930ies German plot and recreated it around his wife Julie Edwards. He went out of his way to promote homosexuals as not-second-rate human beings, although he softened the original plot where the very masculine King Marchand falls in love with what he thinks is a man in drag -- in the film, King first finds out that Victor is really Victoria before he pursues her. Personally, I found the Toddy character, a middle-aged and very queer- acting man, annoying and somewhat dated.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I like this movie more every time I watch it
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    enkelien-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The first time I saw it, I thought it was "pretty good." Amusing, but I didn't expect to find myself watching it again. It's unpretentious. It doesn't have Big Ideas or profound themes that you have to watch it twice to get. But it's got lovable characters and a kickin' plot, and I happen to have a huge crush on the 1930s. I love the friendship between Victoria and Toddy because it feels so genuine and it's rare to see a friendship (particularly between men and women) portrayed so well in movies. I love the romance between Victoria and King, because they're well-matched, but at the same time the problems in their relationship are so realistic. Fundamental inability to compromise? I think everyone knows what that's like.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    May I Review the First Half?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Ezell
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I think of the word "uneven" this film comes to mind. The first half is a wonderful funny film about the rise of a starving artist in the right place at the correct time. And the performances, wow! Julie Andrews vocal and comedic talents put to use, Leslie Ann Warren in an amazing performance as the ultimate Depression-era floozie and Robert Preston in what is probably his best film performance after The Music Man. All this flows perfectly for about an hour and then the second half, how shall I put this, stinks. I have frequently commented Hollywood would benefit from learning to make shorter, better films--a concept I wish Blake Edwards had considered when putting this film together.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Movie Ahead of It's Time!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ShelbyTMItchell
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Movie was way ahead of it's time as first saw it as a eight-year old back in Fla at the time. As it showed Julie Andrews being directed by her husband, the late and great Blake Edwards. He helped revive her career after Mary Popppins was typecasting her. As this proved to really help her shake that image. As she plays a poor female singer who is struggling to make ends meet. As she meets a gay singer who would become her manager, played by the great and late, Robert Preston. As after an argument with Preston's lover and Andrews punching him out, they make up her being a man pretending to be a woman singer. In order to make ends meet and it helps along the way winning both of them, fame and fortune. But Andrews finds out her personal life will clash when she meets the handsome James Gardner, who's bodyguard is also gay, played by the late great Alex Karras and his nagging girlfriend, Leslie Ann Warren. Gardner sees right through Andrews and the two fall in love as Andrews must maintain this image despite a snooping PI wanting to expose her. The film really helped out her career in the 1980s with Edwards. Seen this movie thousands of times, as it was ahead of it's time for the taboo 1980s. RIP Alex Karras, Blake Edwards, and Robert Edwards!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Okay....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Julie Andrews plays an out of work starving artist. However, when she meets a gay man (Robert Preston), he convinces her to fake being a cross-dresser and then she'll hit it big. This turns out to be true but also creates serious problems in regard to her love life. I read through the many very positive reviews for "Victor Victoria" and felt a bit lost. In some ways I wondered exactly what they saw in this film. I mean that "Victor Victoria" was kind of cute and enjoyable--but not much more. Perhaps the earlier versions would might have been a bit better. Although the film is set in France in the 1930s, you might no know that by listening to everyone. James Garner, Julie Andrews and Robert Preston are the leads....and are not exactly French. No one sounded or looked French. I wonder what French folks think when they see films like this... Also, while I know that the film is about a cross-dressing cabaret singer, I STILL felt that there were too many musical numbers. They tended to slow the film down and deflected the comedy. However, overall it's still an enjoyable little comedy that is a bit better than a time-passer. I know I am the odd reviewer here, but I just didn't see this as a really funny film nor did it seem all that special--especially with it coming out the same time as a better cross-dressing film, "Tootsie".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a 1980 movie; not 1982...but I digress. Simply one of the best movies!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    englishtnscones
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Blake Edwards was a genius! I agree with other reviewers that if you have a problem with THIS movie, then you have issues with your own sexuality that are no one else's problem but your own. I could watch this movie 1000 times (and I think I may have) and still belly laugh all the way through! I've let my kids watch it and all of the 'adult' jokes go right over their heads, like they did mine when I was only 13 (that's how I remember when this movie was released). Blake Edwards, who was not only Julie Andrew's husband but also the director of all the Pink Panther movies, was a brilliant director that more young movie makers should model their craft after. Physical comedy, not necessarily script lines, will always get a huge laugh if filmed properly with proper comedic timing (something that is next-to-impossible to teach). Knowing HOW to shoot a comedy scene is the key to getting those big laughs (watch the cockroach- restaurant scene to the end and note the change in audience perspective; that's what makes that scene a cinematic classic!) Get some popcorn, a glass of good French wine and prepare yourself for an evening of laughs and feel-good entertainment! Great for the whole family...as long as you're not "uptight". Life's too short to go through it uptight anyway so LEARN to be less selfish, LEARN to respect other people's way of thinking (even if it differs from your own beliefs)and LEARN how to be TOLERANT!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I still prefer Mary and Maria.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SmileysWorld
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Not unlike many men my age,I developed a huge crush on Julie Andrews as a kid somewhere between Mary Poppins and Maria Von Trapp.Over the years,Ms.Andrews has made it plain that she while she did enjoy working on the two films that produced these characters,she has not enjoyed the stereotyped image it produced for her.So,she set out to prove that she was indeed not the goody two shoes type that she has often been perceived to be.If that was her quest,she more than conquered it with her performance in this film.While I understand her position,I'm not one of those people that needed to see a film like this in order to understand that she isn't at all like those first two characters she played.It's all fantasy and I get that.All of that being said,I still prefer Mary and Maria vs. what she gives us here.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An absolute hoot!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I can't believe how much I loved Victor/Victoria. It is charming, witty and a lot of fun, and you can tell everybody involved with it had a ball. To be honest, I wasn't sure whether I would like this movie. I thought it would be a vehicle for Julie Andrews like Star! was and little more, and the story at first I wasn't sure about and I can't quite put my finger on why. I am so glad though that I saw it, because it was an absolute hoot and infinitely better than expected. This is so much more than a Julie Andrews vehicle, while it is not her best film it is one of her more enjoyable ones. As for Andrews she is wonderful. Here she does play an atypical role on the surface, looking at Mary Poppins and Sound of Music you would never guess Andrews would play a bloke. But she does play the role with wit and charm, and to be doubly sure she was comfortable she is even given some fun songs to show off her very angelic voice, she is especially impressive in the show-stopper that is Le Jazz Hot with very clever execution of the fiendishly difficult two-octave slide. That's not all. Andrews is supported by an equally impressive cast. James Garner is dashing and immensely likable as the heterosexual troubled by his attraction to Andrews' character. Robert Preston is also outrageously camp but in a good way- Shady Dame from Seville is hilarious-, while Lesley Ann Warren(very funny and very sexy), John Rhys Davies and especially Alex Karras give stellar supporting turns as well. The songs are just great, especially the moving Crazy World. The melodies are memorable and fun and the lyrics are deliciously witty, and I have to say the cast did great justice to those songs not just in the performances but in making them their own too. Just as good is the choreography, which manages to be sprightly and energetic. Blake Edwards also deserves a lot of credit for two things, one is his funny and witty script, the other is his affectionate and tender direction while never being too showy. The production values are top drawer, the sets and scenery are very elegant and pleasing on the eyes, the lighting is never dull and the costumes especially the drag costumes are colourful arrays. The story and romance is interesting with very rare a false or dull note even with the lengthy length. All in all, a delightful movie and a must see for fans of Julie Andrews, Blake Edwards, musicals or James Garner. 10/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Go ahead, laugh!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ptb-8
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I always had a struggle with VICTOR VICTORIA and only recently saw the 1935 Brit original FIRST A BOY with Jesse Matthews which itself was a remake of the identical German version called VIKTOR VIKTORIA from 1933. It is the German version that now in 2011 might just be the most fascinating of the two originals... however 30 years on from 1982, I possibly can appreciate VICTOR VICTORIA for the hilarious MGM musical farce others claim it is and see it up there with SINGIN IN THE RAIN and MY FAVOURITE YEAR. What I dislike about VV is that it is too long and too ramshackle in plot. Also I just get tired of it. Yes sacrilege I know but if it was tighter and not as meandering (it is half an hour longer than SINGIN IN THE RAIN and most other glorious musicals equally applauded) I would find it a better film. the ending just runs on and on with Robert Preston doing his lady Of Seville number. Every component of VV is terrific, Julie Andrews is as gorgeous as she was in STAR! (which I love yes even at 3 hours) and the sets and costumes are terrific. There is a lot of Pink Panther gag humor from director Blake Edwards and a perfect supporting cast. Robert Preston has had an incredible career and I equally admire him in MAME as in MUSIC MAN and here ... three massive musicals hits in the 60s 70s and 80s... almost a match for Julie! I love the parts of VV but I just don't love the film as a whole.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You and Me
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (albertoveronese)
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film grows in your heart a little stronger each time you watch it; it is like a genuinely good friend returning to visit you. Blake Edwards directed Victor Victoria with such an affection and tenderness that I think no one can help but be moved. You'll never find yourself tired watching it again and again because more you know the characters the more you love them, the funnier the situations and dialogs become, the more you enjoy the story. 'You and Me' which is sung by Julie Andrew and Robert Preston before the audience reminds us that you can be strong and free only if you know who you are and if you are true to who you are. Julie Andrews' song Crazy World calls us to keep loving others no matter what. Costumed or disguised you'll find Blake Edwards' comedy Victor Victoria to be bright, funny and thriving.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    That's what homosexuality was like in the 1980ies, folks
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Karl Self
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/9/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is "Tootsie" the other way round. A struggling female singer takes to impersonating a transvestite in order to make ends meet. This way, she doesn't have to impersonate anything and comes across as surprisingly convincing. A butch underworld king falls in love with her and is troubled that he's taken in by what he thinks is a man in drag. Although I personally don't care all that much for stories about gender crossing, Victor Victoria is simply a great film with a number of very impressive and creative vari&eacute;t&eacute; numbers. Director Blake Edwards used a ca. 1930ies German plot and recreated it around his wife Julie Edwards. He went out of his way to promote homosexuals as not-second-rate human beings, although he softened the original plot where the very masculine King Marchand falls in love with what he thinks is a man in drag -- in the film, King first finds out that Victor is really Victoria before he pursues her. Personally, I found the Toddy character, a middle-aged and very queer- acting man, annoying and somewhat dated.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I like this movie more every time I watch it
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    enkelien-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The first time I saw it, I thought it was "pretty good." Amusing, but I didn't expect to find myself watching it again. It's unpretentious. It doesn't have Big Ideas or profound themes that you have to watch it twice to get. But it's got lovable characters and a kickin' plot, and I happen to have a huge crush on the 1930s. I love the friendship between Victoria and Toddy because it feels so genuine and it's rare to see a friendship (particularly between men and women) portrayed so well in movies. I love the romance between Victoria and King, because they're well-matched, but at the same time the problems in their relationship are so realistic. Fundamental inability to compromise? I think everyone knows what that's like.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    May I Review the First Half?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Ezell
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I think of the word "uneven" this film comes to mind. The first half is a wonderful funny film about the rise of a starving artist in the right place at the correct time. And the performances, wow! Julie Andrews vocal and comedic talents put to use, Leslie Ann Warren in an amazing performance as the ultimate Depression-era floozie and Robert Preston in what is probably his best film performance after The Music Man. All this flows perfectly for about an hour and then the second half, how shall I put this, stinks. I have frequently commented Hollywood would benefit from learning to make shorter, better films--a concept I wish Blake Edwards had considered when putting this film together.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Movie Ahead of It's Time!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ShelbyTMItchell
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Movie was way ahead of it's time as first saw it as a eight-year old back in Fla at the time. As it showed Julie Andrews being directed by her husband, the late and great Blake Edwards. He helped revive her career after Mary Popppins was typecasting her. As this proved to really help her shake that image. As she plays a poor female singer who is struggling to make ends meet. As she meets a gay singer who would become her manager, played by the great and late, Robert Preston. As after an argument with Preston's lover and Andrews punching him out, they make up her being a man pretending to be a woman singer. In order to make ends meet and it helps along the way winning both of them, fame and fortune. But Andrews finds out her personal life will clash when she meets the handsome James Gardner, who's bodyguard is also gay, played by the late great Alex Karras and his nagging girlfriend, Leslie Ann Warren. Gardner sees right through Andrews and the two fall in love as Andrews must maintain this image despite a snooping PI wanting to expose her. The film really helped out her career in the 1980s with Edwards. Seen this movie thousands of times, as it was ahead of it's time for the taboo 1980s. RIP Alex Karras, Blake Edwards, and Robert Edwards!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Okay....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Julie Andrews plays an out of work starving artist. However, when she meets a gay man (Robert Preston), he convinces her to fake being a cross-dresser and then she'll hit it big. This turns out to be true but also creates serious problems in regard to her love life. I read through the many very positive reviews for "Victor Victoria" and felt a bit lost. In some ways I wondered exactly what they saw in this film. I mean that "Victor Victoria" was kind of cute and enjoyable--but not much more. Perhaps the earlier versions would might have been a bit better. Although the film is set in France in the 1930s, you might no know that by listening to everyone. James Garner, Julie Andrews and Robert Preston are the leads....and are not exactly French. No one sounded or looked French. I wonder what French folks think when they see films like this... Also, while I know that the film is about a cross-dressing cabaret singer, I STILL felt that there were too many musical numbers. They tended to slow the film down and deflected the comedy. However, overall it's still an enjoyable little comedy that is a bit better than a time-passer. I know I am the odd reviewer here, but I just didn't see this as a really funny film nor did it seem all that special--especially with it coming out the same time as a better cross-dressing film, "Tootsie".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a 1980 movie; not 1982...but I digress. Simply one of the best movies!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    englishtnscones
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Blake Edwards was a genius! I agree with other reviewers that if you have a problem with THIS movie, then you have issues with your own sexuality that are no one else's problem but your own. I could watch this movie 1000 times (and I think I may have) and still belly laugh all the way through! I've let my kids watch it and all of the 'adult' jokes go right over their heads, like they did mine when I was only 13 (that's how I remember when this movie was released). Blake Edwards, who was not only Julie Andrew's husband but also the director of all the Pink Panther movies, was a brilliant director that more young movie makers should model their craft after. Physical comedy, not necessarily script lines, will always get a huge laugh if filmed properly with proper comedic timing (something that is next-to-impossible to teach). Knowing HOW to shoot a comedy scene is the key to getting those big laughs (watch the cockroach- restaurant scene to the end and note the change in audience perspective; that's what makes that scene a cinematic classic!) Get some popcorn, a glass of good French wine and prepare yourself for an evening of laughs and feel-good entertainment! Great for the whole family...as long as you're not "uptight". Life's too short to go through it uptight anyway so LEARN to be less selfish, LEARN to respect other people's way of thinking (even if it differs from your own beliefs)and LEARN how to be TOLERANT!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I still prefer Mary and Maria.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SmileysWorld
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Not unlike many men my age,I developed a huge crush on Julie Andrews as a kid somewhere between Mary Poppins and Maria Von Trapp.Over the years,Ms.Andrews has made it plain that she while she did enjoy working on the two films that produced these characters,she has not enjoyed the stereotyped image it produced for her.So,she set out to prove that she was indeed not the goody two shoes type that she has often been perceived to be.If that was her quest,she more than conquered it with her performance in this film.While I understand her position,I'm not one of those people that needed to see a film like this in order to understand that she isn't at all like those first two characters she played.It's all fantasy and I get that.All of that being said,I still prefer Mary and Maria vs. what she gives us here.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An absolute hoot!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I can't believe how much I loved Victor/Victoria. It is charming, witty and a lot of fun, and you can tell everybody involved with it had a ball. To be honest, I wasn't sure whether I would like this movie. I thought it would be a vehicle for Julie Andrews like Star! was and little more, and the story at first I wasn't sure about and I can't quite put my finger on why. I am so glad though that I saw it, because it was an absolute hoot and infinitely better than expected. This is so much more than a Julie Andrews vehicle, while it is not her best film it is one of her more enjoyable ones. As for Andrews she is wonderful. Here she does play an atypical role on the surface, looking at Mary Poppins and Sound of Music you would never guess Andrews would play a bloke. But she does play the role with wit and charm, and to be doubly sure she was comfortable she is even given some fun songs to show off her very angelic voice, she is especially impressive in the show-stopper that is Le Jazz Hot with very clever execution of the fiendishly difficult two-octave slide. That's not all. Andrews is supported by an equally impressive cast. James Garner is dashing and immensely likable as the heterosexual troubled by his attraction to Andrews' character. Robert Preston is also outrageously camp but in a good way- Shady Dame from Seville is hilarious-, while Lesley Ann Warren(very funny and very sexy), John Rhys Davies and especially Alex Karras give stellar supporting turns as well. The songs are just great, especially the moving Crazy World. The melodies are memorable and fun and the lyrics are deliciously witty, and I have to say the cast did great justice to those songs not just in the performances but in making them their own too. Just as good is the choreography, which manages to be sprightly and energetic. Blake Edwards also deserves a lot of credit for two things, one is his funny and witty script, the other is his affectionate and tender direction while never being too showy. The production values are top drawer, the sets and scenery are very elegant and pleasing on the eyes, the lighting is never dull and the costumes especially the drag costumes are colourful arrays. The story and romance is interesting with very rare a false or dull note even with the lengthy length. All in all, a delightful movie and a must see for fans of Julie Andrews, Blake Edwards, musicals or James Garner. 10/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Go ahead, laugh!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ptb-8
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I always had a struggle with VICTOR VICTORIA and only recently saw the 1935 Brit original FIRST A BOY with Jesse Matthews which itself was a remake of the identical German version called VIKTOR VIKTORIA from 1933. It is the German version that now in 2011 might just be the most fascinating of the two originals... however 30 years on from 1982, I possibly can appreciate VICTOR VICTORIA for the hilarious MGM musical farce others claim it is and see it up there with SINGIN IN THE RAIN and MY FAVOURITE YEAR. What I dislike about VV is that it is too long and too ramshackle in plot. Also I just get tired of it. Yes sacrilege I know but if it was tighter and not as meandering (it is half an hour longer than SINGIN IN THE RAIN and most other glorious musicals equally applauded) I would find it a better film. the ending just runs on and on with Robert Preston doing his lady Of Seville number. Every component of VV is terrific, Julie Andrews is as gorgeous as she was in STAR! (which I love yes even at 3 hours) and the sets and costumes are terrific. There is a lot of Pink Panther gag humor from director Blake Edwards and a perfect supporting cast. Robert Preston has had an incredible career and I equally admire him in MAME as in MUSIC MAN and here ... three massive musicals hits in the 60s 70s and 80s... almost a match for Julie! I love the parts of VV but I just don't love the film as a whole.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You and Me
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (albertoveronese)
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film grows in your heart a little stronger each time you watch it; it is like a genuinely good friend returning to visit you. Blake Edwards directed Victor Victoria with such an affection and tenderness that I think no one can help but be moved. You'll never find yourself tired watching it again and again because more you know the characters the more you love them, the funnier the situations and dialogs become, the more you enjoy the story. 'You and Me' which is sung by Julie Andrew and Robert Preston before the audience reminds us that you can be strong and free only if you know who you are and if you are true to who you are. Julie Andrews' song Crazy World calls us to keep loving others no matter what. Costumed or disguised you'll find Blake Edwards' comedy Victor Victoria to be bright, funny and thriving.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    That's what homosexuality was like in the 1980ies, folks
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Karl Self
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/9/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is "Tootsie" the other way round. A struggling female singer takes to impersonating a transvestite in order to make ends meet. This way, she doesn't have to impersonate anything and comes across as surprisingly convincing. A butch underworld king falls in love with her and is troubled that he's taken in by what he thinks is a man in drag. Although I personally don't care all that much for stories about gender crossing, Victor Victoria is simply a great film with a number of very impressive and creative vari&eacute;t&eacute; numbers. Director Blake Edwards used a ca. 1930ies German plot and recreated it around his wife Julie Edwards. He went out of his way to promote homosexuals as not-second-rate human beings, although he softened the original plot where the very masculine King Marchand falls in love with what he thinks is a man in drag -- in the film, King first finds out that Victor is really Victoria before he pursues her. Personally, I found the Toddy character, a middle-aged and very queer- acting man, annoying and somewhat dated.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I like this movie more every time I watch it
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    enkelien-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The first time I saw it, I thought it was "pretty good." Amusing, but I didn't expect to find myself watching it again. It's unpretentious. It doesn't have Big Ideas or profound themes that you have to watch it twice to get. But it's got lovable characters and a kickin' plot, and I happen to have a huge crush on the 1930s. I love the friendship between Victoria and Toddy because it feels so genuine and it's rare to see a friendship (particularly between men and women) portrayed so well in movies. I love the romance between Victoria and King, because they're well-matched, but at the same time the problems in their relationship are so realistic. Fundamental inability to compromise? I think everyone knows what that's like.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    May I Review the First Half?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Ezell
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I think of the word "uneven" this film comes to mind. The first half is a wonderful funny film about the rise of a starving artist in the right place at the correct time. And the performances, wow! Julie Andrews vocal and comedic talents put to use, Leslie Ann Warren in an amazing performance as the ultimate Depression-era floozie and Robert Preston in what is probably his best film performance after The Music Man. All this flows perfectly for about an hour and then the second half, how shall I put this, stinks. I have frequently commented Hollywood would benefit from learning to make shorter, better films--a concept I wish Blake Edwards had considered when putting this film together.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Movie Ahead of It's Time!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ShelbyTMItchell
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Movie was way ahead of it's time as first saw it as a eight-year old back in Fla at the time. As it showed Julie Andrews being directed by her husband, the late and great Blake Edwards. He helped revive her career after Mary Popppins was typecasting her. As this proved to really help her shake that image. As she plays a poor female singer who is struggling to make ends meet. As she meets a gay singer who would become her manager, played by the great and late, Robert Preston. As after an argument with Preston's lover and Andrews punching him out, they make up her being a man pretending to be a woman singer. In order to make ends meet and it helps along the way winning both of them, fame and fortune. But Andrews finds out her personal life will clash when she meets the handsome James Gardner, who's bodyguard is also gay, played by the late great Alex Karras and his nagging girlfriend, Leslie Ann Warren. Gardner sees right through Andrews and the two fall in love as Andrews must maintain this image despite a snooping PI wanting to expose her. The film really helped out her career in the 1980s with Edwards. Seen this movie thousands of times, as it was ahead of it's time for the taboo 1980s. RIP Alex Karras, Blake Edwards, and Robert Edwards!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Okay....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Julie Andrews plays an out of work starving artist. However, when she meets a gay man (Robert Preston), he convinces her to fake being a cross-dresser and then she'll hit it big. This turns out to be true but also creates serious problems in regard to her love life. I read through the many very positive reviews for "Victor Victoria" and felt a bit lost. In some ways I wondered exactly what they saw in this film. I mean that "Victor Victoria" was kind of cute and enjoyable--but not much more. Perhaps the earlier versions would might have been a bit better. Although the film is set in France in the 1930s, you might no know that by listening to everyone. James Garner, Julie Andrews and Robert Preston are the leads....and are not exactly French. No one sounded or looked French. I wonder what French folks think when they see films like this... Also, while I know that the film is about a cross-dressing cabaret singer, I STILL felt that there were too many musical numbers. They tended to slow the film down and deflected the comedy. However, overall it's still an enjoyable little comedy that is a bit better than a time-passer. I know I am the odd reviewer here, but I just didn't see this as a really funny film nor did it seem all that special--especially with it coming out the same time as a better cross-dressing film, "Tootsie".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a 1980 movie; not 1982...but I digress. Simply one of the best movies!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    englishtnscones
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Blake Edwards was a genius! I agree with other reviewers that if you have a problem with THIS movie, then you have issues with your own sexuality that are no one else's problem but your own. I could watch this movie 1000 times (and I think I may have) and still belly laugh all the way through! I've let my kids watch it and all of the 'adult' jokes go right over their heads, like they did mine when I was only 13 (that's how I remember when this movie was released). Blake Edwards, who was not only Julie Andrew's husband but also the director of all the Pink Panther movies, was a brilliant director that more young movie makers should model their craft after. Physical comedy, not necessarily script lines, will always get a huge laugh if filmed properly with proper comedic timing (something that is next-to-impossible to teach). Knowing HOW to shoot a comedy scene is the key to getting those big laughs (watch the cockroach- restaurant scene to the end and note the change in audience perspective; that's what makes that scene a cinematic classic!) Get some popcorn, a glass of good French wine and prepare yourself for an evening of laughs and feel-good entertainment! Great for the whole family...as long as you're not "uptight". Life's too short to go through it uptight anyway so LEARN to be less selfish, LEARN to respect other people's way of thinking (even if it differs from your own beliefs)and LEARN how to be TOLERANT!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I still prefer Mary and Maria.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SmileysWorld
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Not unlike many men my age,I developed a huge crush on Julie Andrews as a kid somewhere between Mary Poppins and Maria Von Trapp.Over the years,Ms.Andrews has made it plain that she while she did enjoy working on the two films that produced these characters,she has not enjoyed the stereotyped image it produced for her.So,she set out to prove that she was indeed not the goody two shoes type that she has often been perceived to be.If that was her quest,she more than conquered it with her performance in this film.While I understand her position,I'm not one of those people that needed to see a film like this in order to understand that she isn't at all like those first two characters she played.It's all fantasy and I get that.All of that being said,I still prefer Mary and Maria vs. what she gives us here.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An absolute hoot!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I can't believe how much I loved Victor/Victoria. It is charming, witty and a lot of fun, and you can tell everybody involved with it had a ball. To be honest, I wasn't sure whether I would like this movie. I thought it would be a vehicle for Julie Andrews like Star! was and little more, and the story at first I wasn't sure about and I can't quite put my finger on why. I am so glad though that I saw it, because it was an absolute hoot and infinitely better than expected. This is so much more than a Julie Andrews vehicle, while it is not her best film it is one of her more enjoyable ones. As for Andrews she is wonderful. Here she does play an atypical role on the surface, looking at Mary Poppins and Sound of Music you would never guess Andrews would play a bloke. But she does play the role with wit and charm, and to be doubly sure she was comfortable she is even given some fun songs to show off her very angelic voice, she is especially impressive in the show-stopper that is Le Jazz Hot with very clever execution of the fiendishly difficult two-octave slide. That's not all. Andrews is supported by an equally impressive cast. James Garner is dashing and immensely likable as the heterosexual troubled by his attraction to Andrews' character. Robert Preston is also outrageously camp but in a good way- Shady Dame from Seville is hilarious-, while Lesley Ann Warren(very funny and very sexy), John Rhys Davies and especially Alex Karras give stellar supporting turns as well. The songs are just great, especially the moving Crazy World. The melodies are memorable and fun and the lyrics are deliciously witty, and I have to say the cast did great justice to those songs not just in the performances but in making them their own too. Just as good is the choreography, which manages to be sprightly and energetic. Blake Edwards also deserves a lot of credit for two things, one is his funny and witty script, the other is his affectionate and tender direction while never being too showy. The production values are top drawer, the sets and scenery are very elegant and pleasing on the eyes, the lighting is never dull and the costumes especially the drag costumes are colourful arrays. The story and romance is interesting with very rare a false or dull note even with the lengthy length. All in all, a delightful movie and a must see for fans of Julie Andrews, Blake Edwards, musicals or James Garner. 10/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Go ahead, laugh!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ptb-8
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I always had a struggle with VICTOR VICTORIA and only recently saw the 1935 Brit original FIRST A BOY with Jesse Matthews which itself was a remake of the identical German version called VIKTOR VIKTORIA from 1933. It is the German version that now in 2011 might just be the most fascinating of the two originals... however 30 years on from 1982, I possibly can appreciate VICTOR VICTORIA for the hilarious MGM musical farce others claim it is and see it up there with SINGIN IN THE RAIN and MY FAVOURITE YEAR. What I dislike about VV is that it is too long and too ramshackle in plot. Also I just get tired of it. Yes sacrilege I know but if it was tighter and not as meandering (it is half an hour longer than SINGIN IN THE RAIN and most other glorious musicals equally applauded) I would find it a better film. the ending just runs on and on with Robert Preston doing his lady Of Seville number. Every component of VV is terrific, Julie Andrews is as gorgeous as she was in STAR! (which I love yes even at 3 hours) and the sets and costumes are terrific. There is a lot of Pink Panther gag humor from director Blake Edwards and a perfect supporting cast. Robert Preston has had an incredible career and I equally admire him in MAME as in MUSIC MAN and here ... three massive musicals hits in the 60s 70s and 80s... almost a match for Julie! I love the parts of VV but I just don't love the film as a whole.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You and Me
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (albertoveronese)
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film grows in your heart a little stronger each time you watch it; it is like a genuinely good friend returning to visit you. Blake Edwards directed Victor Victoria with such an affection and tenderness that I think no one can help but be moved. You'll never find yourself tired watching it again and again because more you know the characters the more you love them, the funnier the situations and dialogs become, the more you enjoy the story. 'You and Me' which is sung by Julie Andrew and Robert Preston before the audience reminds us that you can be strong and free only if you know who you are and if you are true to who you are. Julie Andrews' song Crazy World calls us to keep loving others no matter what. Costumed or disguised you'll find Blake Edwards' comedy Victor Victoria to be bright, funny and thriving.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    That's what homosexuality was like in the 1980ies, folks
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Karl Self
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/9/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is "Tootsie" the other way round. A struggling female singer takes to impersonating a transvestite in order to make ends meet. This way, she doesn't have to impersonate anything and comes across as surprisingly convincing. A butch underworld king falls in love with her and is troubled that he's taken in by what he thinks is a man in drag. Although I personally don't care all that much for stories about gender crossing, Victor Victoria is simply a great film with a number of very impressive and creative vari&eacute;t&eacute; numbers. Director Blake Edwards used a ca. 1930ies German plot and recreated it around his wife Julie Edwards. He went out of his way to promote homosexuals as not-second-rate human beings, although he softened the original plot where the very masculine King Marchand falls in love with what he thinks is a man in drag -- in the film, King first finds out that Victor is really Victoria before he pursues her. Personally, I found the Toddy character, a middle-aged and very queer- acting man, annoying and somewhat dated.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I like this movie more every time I watch it
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    enkelien-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The first time I saw it, I thought it was "pretty good." Amusing, but I didn't expect to find myself watching it again. It's unpretentious. It doesn't have Big Ideas or profound themes that you have to watch it twice to get. But it's got lovable characters and a kickin' plot, and I happen to have a huge crush on the 1930s. I love the friendship between Victoria and Toddy because it feels so genuine and it's rare to see a friendship (particularly between men and women) portrayed so well in movies. I love the romance between Victoria and King, because they're well-matched, but at the same time the problems in their relationship are so realistic. Fundamental inability to compromise? I think everyone knows what that's like.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    May I Review the First Half?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Ezell
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I think of the word "uneven" this film comes to mind. The first half is a wonderful funny film about the rise of a starving artist in the right place at the correct time. And the performances, wow! Julie Andrews vocal and comedic talents put to use, Leslie Ann Warren in an amazing performance as the ultimate Depression-era floozie and Robert Preston in what is probably his best film performance after The Music Man. All this flows perfectly for about an hour and then the second half, how shall I put this, stinks. I have frequently commented Hollywood would benefit from learning to make shorter, better films--a concept I wish Blake Edwards had considered when putting this film together.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Movie Ahead of It's Time!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ShelbyTMItchell
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Movie was way ahead of it's time as first saw it as a eight-year old back in Fla at the time. As it showed Julie Andrews being directed by her husband, the late and great Blake Edwards. He helped revive her career after Mary Popppins was typecasting her. As this proved to really help her shake that image. As she plays a poor female singer who is struggling to make ends meet. As she meets a gay singer who would become her manager, played by the great and late, Robert Preston. As after an argument with Preston's lover and Andrews punching him out, they make up her being a man pretending to be a woman singer. In order to make ends meet and it helps along the way winning both of them, fame and fortune. But Andrews finds out her personal life will clash when she meets the handsome James Gardner, who's bodyguard is also gay, played by the late great Alex Karras and his nagging girlfriend, Leslie Ann Warren. Gardner sees right through Andrews and the two fall in love as Andrews must maintain this image despite a snooping PI wanting to expose her. The film really helped out her career in the 1980s with Edwards. Seen this movie thousands of times, as it was ahead of it's time for the taboo 1980s. RIP Alex Karras, Blake Edwards, and Robert Edwards!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Okay....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Julie Andrews plays an out of work starving artist. However, when she meets a gay man (Robert Preston), he convinces her to fake being a cross-dresser and then she'll hit it big. This turns out to be true but also creates serious problems in regard to her love life. I read through the many very positive reviews for "Victor Victoria" and felt a bit lost. In some ways I wondered exactly what they saw in this film. I mean that "Victor Victoria" was kind of cute and enjoyable--but not much more. Perhaps the earlier versions would might have been a bit better. Although the film is set in France in the 1930s, you might no know that by listening to everyone. James Garner, Julie Andrews and Robert Preston are the leads....and are not exactly French. No one sounded or looked French. I wonder what French folks think when they see films like this... Also, while I know that the film is about a cross-dressing cabaret singer, I STILL felt that there were too many musical numbers. They tended to slow the film down and deflected the comedy. However, overall it's still an enjoyable little comedy that is a bit better than a time-passer. I know I am the odd reviewer here, but I just didn't see this as a really funny film nor did it seem all that special--especially with it coming out the same time as a better cross-dressing film, "Tootsie".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a 1980 movie; not 1982...but I digress. Simply one of the best movies!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    englishtnscones
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Blake Edwards was a genius! I agree with other reviewers that if you have a problem with THIS movie, then you have issues with your own sexuality that are no one else's problem but your own. I could watch this movie 1000 times (and I think I may have) and still belly laugh all the way through! I've let my kids watch it and all of the 'adult' jokes go right over their heads, like they did mine when I was only 13 (that's how I remember when this movie was released). Blake Edwards, who was not only Julie Andrew's husband but also the director of all the Pink Panther movies, was a brilliant director that more young movie makers should model their craft after. Physical comedy, not necessarily script lines, will always get a huge laugh if filmed properly with proper comedic timing (something that is next-to-impossible to teach). Knowing HOW to shoot a comedy scene is the key to getting those big laughs (watch the cockroach- restaurant scene to the end and note the change in audience perspective; that's what makes that scene a cinematic classic!) Get some popcorn, a glass of good French wine and prepare yourself for an evening of laughs and feel-good entertainment! Great for the whole family...as long as you're not "uptight". Life's too short to go through it uptight anyway so LEARN to be less selfish, LEARN to respect other people's way of thinking (even if it differs from your own beliefs)and LEARN how to be TOLERANT!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I still prefer Mary and Maria.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SmileysWorld
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Not unlike many men my age,I developed a huge crush on Julie Andrews as a kid somewhere between Mary Poppins and Maria Von Trapp.Over the years,Ms.Andrews has made it plain that she while she did enjoy working on the two films that produced these characters,she has not enjoyed the stereotyped image it produced for her.So,she set out to prove that she was indeed not the goody two shoes type that she has often been perceived to be.If that was her quest,she more than conquered it with her performance in this film.While I understand her position,I'm not one of those people that needed to see a film like this in order to understand that she isn't at all like those first two characters she played.It's all fantasy and I get that.All of that being said,I still prefer Mary and Maria vs. what she gives us here.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An absolute hoot!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I can't believe how much I loved Victor/Victoria. It is charming, witty and a lot of fun, and you can tell everybody involved with it had a ball. To be honest, I wasn't sure whether I would like this movie. I thought it would be a vehicle for Julie Andrews like Star! was and little more, and the story at first I wasn't sure about and I can't quite put my finger on why. I am so glad though that I saw it, because it was an absolute hoot and infinitely better than expected. This is so much more than a Julie Andrews vehicle, while it is not her best film it is one of her more enjoyable ones. As for Andrews she is wonderful. Here she does play an atypical role on the surface, looking at Mary Poppins and Sound of Music you would never guess Andrews would play a bloke. But she does play the role with wit and charm, and to be doubly sure she was comfortable she is even given some fun songs to show off her very angelic voice, she is especially impressive in the show-stopper that is Le Jazz Hot with very clever execution of the fiendishly difficult two-octave slide. That's not all. Andrews is supported by an equally impressive cast. James Garner is dashing and immensely likable as the heterosexual troubled by his attraction to Andrews' character. Robert Preston is also outrageously camp but in a good way- Shady Dame from Seville is hilarious-, while Lesley Ann Warren(very funny and very sexy), John Rhys Davies and especially Alex Karras give stellar supporting turns as well. The songs are just great, especially the moving Crazy World. The melodies are memorable and fun and the lyrics are deliciously witty, and I have to say the cast did great justice to those songs not just in the performances but in making them their own too. Just as good is the choreography, which manages to be sprightly and energetic. Blake Edwards also deserves a lot of credit for two things, one is his funny and witty script, the other is his affectionate and tender direction while never being too showy. The production values are top drawer, the sets and scenery are very elegant and pleasing on the eyes, the lighting is never dull and the costumes especially the drag costumes are colourful arrays. The story and romance is interesting with very rare a false or dull note even with the lengthy length. All in all, a delightful movie and a must see for fans of Julie Andrews, Blake Edwards, musicals or James Garner. 10/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Go ahead, laugh!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ptb-8
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I always had a struggle with VICTOR VICTORIA and only recently saw the 1935 Brit original FIRST A BOY with Jesse Matthews which itself was a remake of the identical German version called VIKTOR VIKTORIA from 1933. It is the German version that now in 2011 might just be the most fascinating of the two originals... however 30 years on from 1982, I possibly can appreciate VICTOR VICTORIA for the hilarious MGM musical farce others claim it is and see it up there with SINGIN IN THE RAIN and MY FAVOURITE YEAR. What I dislike about VV is that it is too long and too ramshackle in plot. Also I just get tired of it. Yes sacrilege I know but if it was tighter and not as meandering (it is half an hour longer than SINGIN IN THE RAIN and most other glorious musicals equally applauded) I would find it a better film. the ending just runs on and on with Robert Preston doing his lady Of Seville number. Every component of VV is terrific, Julie Andrews is as gorgeous as she was in STAR! (which I love yes even at 3 hours) and the sets and costumes are terrific. There is a lot of Pink Panther gag humor from director Blake Edwards and a perfect supporting cast. Robert Preston has had an incredible career and I equally admire him in MAME as in MUSIC MAN and here ... three massive musicals hits in the 60s 70s and 80s... almost a match for Julie! I love the parts of VV but I just don't love the film as a whole.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You and Me
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (albertoveronese)
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film grows in your heart a little stronger each time you watch it; it is like a genuinely good friend returning to visit you. Blake Edwards directed Victor Victoria with such an affection and tenderness that I think no one can help but be moved. You'll never find yourself tired watching it again and again because more you know the characters the more you love them, the funnier the situations and dialogs become, the more you enjoy the story. 'You and Me' which is sung by Julie Andrew and Robert Preston before the audience reminds us that you can be strong and free only if you know who you are and if you are true to who you are. Julie Andrews' song Crazy World calls us to keep loving others no matter what. Costumed or disguised you'll find Blake Edwards' comedy Victor Victoria to be bright, funny and thriving.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    That's what homosexuality was like in the 1980ies, folks
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Karl Self
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/9/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is "Tootsie" the other way round. A struggling female singer takes to impersonating a transvestite in order to make ends meet. This way, she doesn't have to impersonate anything and comes across as surprisingly convincing. A butch underworld king falls in love with her and is troubled that he's taken in by what he thinks is a man in drag. Although I personally don't care all that much for stories about gender crossing, Victor Victoria is simply a great film with a number of very impressive and creative vari&eacute;t&eacute; numbers. Director Blake Edwards used a ca. 1930ies German plot and recreated it around his wife Julie Edwards. He went out of his way to promote homosexuals as not-second-rate human beings, although he softened the original plot where the very masculine King Marchand falls in love with what he thinks is a man in drag -- in the film, King first finds out that Victor is really Victoria before he pursues her. Personally, I found the Toddy character, a middle-aged and very queer- acting man, annoying and somewhat dated.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I like this movie more every time I watch it
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    enkelien-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The first time I saw it, I thought it was "pretty good." Amusing, but I didn't expect to find myself watching it again. It's unpretentious. It doesn't have Big Ideas or profound themes that you have to watch it twice to get. But it's got lovable characters and a kickin' plot, and I happen to have a huge crush on the 1930s. I love the friendship between Victoria and Toddy because it feels so genuine and it's rare to see a friendship (particularly between men and women) portrayed so well in movies. I love the romance between Victoria and King, because they're well-matched, but at the same time the problems in their relationship are so realistic. Fundamental inability to compromise? I think everyone knows what that's like.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    May I Review the First Half?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David Ezell
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I think of the word "uneven" this film comes to mind. The first half is a wonderful funny film about the rise of a starving artist in the right place at the correct time. And the performances, wow! Julie Andrews vocal and comedic talents put to use, Leslie Ann Warren in an amazing performance as the ultimate Depression-era floozie and Robert Preston in what is probably his best film performance after The Music Man. All this flows perfectly for about an hour and then the second half, how shall I put this, stinks. I have frequently commented Hollywood would benefit from learning to make shorter, better films--a concept I wish Blake Edwards had considered when putting this film together.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Movie Ahead of It's Time!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ShelbyTMItchell
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Movie was way ahead of it's time as first saw it as a eight-year old back in Fla at the time. As it showed Julie Andrews being directed by her husband, the late and great Blake Edwards. He helped revive her career after Mary Popppins was typecasting her. As this proved to really help her shake that image. As she plays a poor female singer who is struggling to make ends meet. As she meets a gay singer who would become her manager, played by the great and late, Robert Preston. As after an argument with Preston's lover and Andrews punching him out, they make up her being a man pretending to be a woman singer. In order to make ends meet and it helps along the way winning both of them, fame and fortune. But Andrews finds out her personal life will clash when she meets the handsome James Gardner, who's bodyguard is also gay, played by the late great Alex Karras and his nagging girlfriend, Leslie Ann Warren. Gardner sees right through Andrews and the two fall in love as Andrews must maintain this image despite a snooping PI wanting to expose her. The film really helped out her career in the 1980s with Edwards. Seen this movie thousands of times, as it was ahead of it's time for the taboo 1980s. RIP Alex Karras, Blake Edwards, and Robert Edwards!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Okay....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Julie Andrews plays an out of work starving artist. However, when she meets a gay man (Robert Preston), he convinces her to fake being a cross-dresser and then she'll hit it big. This turns out to be true but also creates serious problems in regard to her love life. I read through the many very positive reviews for "Victor Victoria" and felt a bit lost. In some ways I wondered exactly what they saw in this film. I mean that "Victor Victoria" was kind of cute and enjoyable--but not much more. Perhaps the earlier versions would might have been a bit better. Although the film is set in France in the 1930s, you might no know that by listening to everyone. James Garner, Julie Andrews and Robert Preston are the leads....and are not exactly French. No one sounded or looked French. I wonder what French folks think when they see films like this... Also, while I know that the film is about a cross-dressing cabaret singer, I STILL felt that there were too many musical numbers. They tended to slow the film down and deflected the comedy. However, overall it's still an enjoyable little comedy that is a bit better than a time-passer. I know I am the odd reviewer here, but I just didn't see this as a really funny film nor did it seem all that special--especially with it coming out the same time as a better cross-dressing film, "Tootsie".
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a 1980 movie; not 1982...but I digress. Simply one of the best movies!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    englishtnscones
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Blake Edwards was a genius! I agree with other reviewers that if you have a problem with THIS movie, then you have issues with your own sexuality that are no one else's problem but your own. I could watch this movie 1000 times (and I think I may have) and still belly laugh all the way through! I've let my kids watch it and all of the 'adult' jokes go right over their heads, like they did mine when I was only 13 (that's how I remember when this movie was released). Blake Edwards, who was not only Julie Andrew's husband but also the director of all the Pink Panther movies, was a brilliant director that more young movie makers should model their craft after. Physical comedy, not necessarily script lines, will always get a huge laugh if filmed properly with proper comedic timing (something that is next-to-impossible to teach). Knowing HOW to shoot a comedy scene is the key to getting those big laughs (watch the cockroach- restaurant scene to the end and note the change in audience perspective; that's what makes that scene a cinematic classic!) Get some popcorn, a glass of good French wine and prepare yourself for an evening of laughs and feel-good entertainment! Great for the whole family...as long as you're not "uptight". Life's too short to go through it uptight anyway so LEARN to be less selfish, LEARN to respect other people's way of thinking (even if it differs from your own beliefs)and LEARN how to be TOLERANT!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I still prefer Mary and Maria.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SmileysWorld
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Not unlike many men my age,I developed a huge crush on Julie Andrews as a kid somewhere between Mary Poppins and Maria Von Trapp.Over the years,Ms.Andrews has made it plain that she while she did enjoy working on the two films that produced these characters,she has not enjoyed the stereotyped image it produced for her.So,she set out to prove that she was indeed not the goody two shoes type that she has often been perceived to be.If that was her quest,she more than conquered it with her performance in this film.While I understand her position,I'm not one of those people that needed to see a film like this in order to understand that she isn't at all like those first two characters she played.It's all fantasy and I get that.All of that being said,I still prefer Mary and Maria vs. what she gives us here.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An absolute hoot!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I can't believe how much I loved Victor/Victoria. It is charming, witty and a lot of fun, and you can tell everybody involved with it had a ball. To be honest, I wasn't sure whether I would like this movie. I thought it would be a vehicle for Julie Andrews like Star! was and little more, and the story at first I wasn't sure about and I can't quite put my finger on why. I am so glad though that I saw it, because it was an absolute hoot and infinitely better than expected. This is so much more than a Julie Andrews vehicle, while it is not her best film it is one of her more enjoyable ones. As for Andrews she is wonderful. Here she does play an atypical role on the surface, looking at Mary Poppins and Sound of Music you would never guess Andrews would play a bloke. But she does play the role with wit and charm, and to be doubly sure she was comfortable she is even given some fun songs to show off her very angelic voice, she is especially impressive in the show-stopper that is Le Jazz Hot with very clever execution of the fiendishly difficult two-octave slide. That's not all. Andrews is supported by an equally impressive cast. James Garner is dashing and immensely likable as the heterosexual troubled by his attraction to Andrews' character. Robert Preston is also outrageously camp but in a good way- Shady Dame from Seville is hilarious-, while Lesley Ann Warren(very funny and very sexy), John Rhys Davies and especially Alex Karras give stellar supporting turns as well. The songs are just great, especially the moving Crazy World. The melodies are memorable and fun and the lyrics are deliciously witty, and I have to say the cast did great justice to those songs not just in the performances but in making them their own too. Just as good is the choreography, which manages to be sprightly and energetic. Blake Edwards also deserves a lot of credit for two things, one is his funny and witty script, the other is his affectionate and tender direction while never being too showy. The production values are top drawer, the sets and scenery are very elegant and pleasing on the eyes, the lighting is never dull and the costumes especially the drag costumes are colourful arrays. The story and romance is interesting with very rare a false or dull note even with the lengthy length. All in all, a delightful movie and a must see for fans of Julie Andrews, Blake Edwards, musicals or James Garner. 10/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Go ahead, laugh!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ptb-8
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I always had a struggle with VICTOR VICTORIA and only recently saw the 1935 Brit original FIRST A BOY with Jesse Matthews which itself was a remake of the identical German version called VIKTOR VIKTORIA from 1933. It is the German version that now in 2011 might just be the most fascinating of the two originals... however 30 years on from 1982, I possibly can appreciate VICTOR VICTORIA for the hilarious MGM musical farce others claim it is and see it up there with SINGIN IN THE RAIN and MY FAVOURITE YEAR. What I dislike about VV is that it is too long and too ramshackle in plot. Also I just get tired of it. Yes sacrilege I know but if it was tighter and not as meandering (it is half an hour longer than SINGIN IN THE RAIN and most other glorious musicals equally applauded) I would find it a better film. the ending just runs on and on with Robert Preston doing his lady Of Seville number. Every component of VV is terrific, Julie Andrews is as gorgeous as she was in STAR! (which I love yes even at 3 hours) and the sets and costumes are terrific. There is a lot of Pink Panther gag humor from director Blake Edwards and a perfect supporting cast. Robert Preston has had an incredible career and I equally admire him in MAME as in MUSIC MAN and here ... three massive musicals hits in the 60s 70s and 80s... almost a match for Julie! I love the parts of VV but I just don't love the film as a whole.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You and Me
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (albertoveronese)
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film grows in your heart a little stronger each time you watch it; it is like a genuinely good friend returning to visit you. Blake Edwards directed Victor Victoria with such an affection and tenderness that I think no one can help but be moved. You'll never find yourself tired watching it again and again because more you know the characters the more you love them, the funnier the situations and dialogs become, the more you enjoy the story. 'You and Me' which is sung by Julie Andrew and Robert Preston before the audience reminds us that you can be strong and free only if you know who you are and if you are true to who you are. Julie Andrews' song Crazy World calls us to keep loving others no matter what. Costumed or disguised you'll find Blake Edwards' comedy Victor Victoria to be bright, funny and thriving.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    That's what homosexuality was like in the 1980ies, folks
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Karl Self
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/9/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is "Tootsie" the other way round. A struggling female singer takes to impersonating a transvestite in order to make ends meet. This way, she doesn't have to impersonate anything and comes across as surprisingly convincing. A butch underworld king falls in love with her and is troubled that he's taken in by what he thinks is a man in drag. Although I personally don't care all that much for stories about gender crossing, Victor Victoria is simply a great film with a number of very impressive and creative vari&eacute;t&eacute; numbers. Director Blake Edwards used a ca. 1930ies German plot and recreated it around his wife Julie Edwards. He went out of his way to promote homosexuals as not-second-rate human beings, although he softened the original plot where the very masculine King Marchand falls in love with what he thinks is a man in drag -- in the film, King first finds out that Victor is really Victoria before he pursues her. Personally, I found the Toddy character, a middle-aged and very queer- acting man, annoying and somewhat dated.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I like this movie more every time I watch it
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    enkelien-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The first time I saw it, I thought it was "pretty good." Amusing, but I didn't expect to find myself watching it again. It's unpretentious. It doesn't have Big Ideas or profound themes that you have to watch it twice to get. But it's got lovable characters and a kickin' plot, and I happen to have a huge crush on the 1930s. I love the friendship between Victoria and Toddy because it feels so genuine and it's rare to see a friendship (particularly between men and women) portrayed so well in movies. I love the romance between Victoria and King, because they're well-matched, but at the same time the problems in their relationship are so realistic. Fundamental inability to compromise? I think everyone knows what that's like.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
