<filme>
 <id>
  631
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0104036
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1992
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Tra&iacute;dos pelo Desejo
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  7.3
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  A British soldier is kidnapped by IRA terrorists. He befriends one of his captors, who is drawn into the soldier's world.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  An unlikely kind of friendship develops between Fergus, an Irish Republican Army volunteer, and Jody, a kidnapped British soldier lured into an IRA trap by Jude, another IRA member. When the hostage-taking ends up going horribly wrong, Fergus escapes and heads to London, where he seeks out Jody's lover, a hairdresser named Dil. Fergus adopts the name "Jimmy" and gets a job as a day laborer. He also starts seeing Dil, who knows nothing about Fergus' IRA background. But there are some things about Dil that Fergus doesn't know, either...
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Crime
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Romance
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   soldier
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   hairdresser
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   escape
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   friendship
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   irish republican army
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Neil Jordan
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Neil Jordan
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Stephen Rea
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Jaye Davidson
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Forest Whitaker
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Prominently atmospheric, incisively humorous..."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sindre Kaspersen
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Irish screenwriter, producer and director Neil Jordan's seventh feature film which he wrote, premiered at the 49th Venice Film Festival in 1992, was screened at the 17th Toronto International Film Festival in 1992, was shot on location in England and Ireland and is a UK-Japan co- production which was produced by producer Stephen Woolley. It tells the story about an Irish Volunteer in the IRA named Fergus Clegg who whilst staying with a small group of other IRA terrorists in Belfast, Northern Ireland kidnaps an English soldier named Jody whom a woman named Jude has lured into a trap. Whilst guarding the soldier who believes that it is only a matter of time before he will be killed, Fergus becomes acquainted with him an learns about his girlfriend named Dil who works at a hair salon in the capital city of England, but as Fergus begins to appreciate Jody's company and regard him as his friend he is assigned to assassinate him by his superior named Peter. Distinctly and precisely directed by Irish filmmaker Neil Jordan, this finely tuned fictional tale which is narrated mostly from the two main characters' viewpoints, draws an intriguing and multifaceted portrayal of an Irishman who travels to London, England to honor a friend's last wish and to get away from his associations with the Irish Republican Army. While notable for it's variegated and naturalistic milieu depictions, sterling cinematography by English cinematographer Ian Wilson, production design by production designer Jim Clay and use of colors and light, this character-driven and narrative-driven story about deception, attraction and overcoming one's preconceptions where a hairdresser and singer whom has just left her boyfriend one day gets a new customer who introduces himself as a Scottish native and later shows up at the bar where she sings, depicts two interrelated and charming studies of character and contains a great score by English composer Anne Dudley. This somewhat political, conversational and eloquently romantic psychological thriller from the early 1990s which is set in Belfast, Northern Ireland and London, England during the Troubles in Northern Ireland in the late 20th century and where a man presents himself with another name than his own to a stranger he only knows from a picture, is impelled and reinforced by it's cogent narrative structure, substantial character development, subtle continuity, endearing and colorful characters, brilliant dialog, merging of themes and genres, timely use of music and remarkable acting performances by Irish actor Stephen Rea, American actor Jaye Davidson in his debut feature film role, English actress Miranda Richardson and American actor, producer and director Forest Whitaker. A prominently atmospheric, incisively humorous and memorable love-story which gained, among numerous other awards, the Alexander Korda Award for Best British Film at the 46th BAFTA Awards in 1993.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Crying Game- Good Noir Cinema (1992)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ashish sood (ashistrong@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "The Crying Game" is one of those films that you see and would like even more in retrospect. The film was huge in 1992 and earned a Best Picture nomination from the Academy, with director It is a complicated puzzle that involves an IRA (Provisional Irish Republican Army) volunteer Fergus(Stephen Rea) befriending with Dil (Jaye Davidson) girlfriend of an English soldier Jody(Forest Whitaker) whom he had kidnapped. The twists and turns of "The Crying Game" are what make the film work. The movie although has flaws in several areas, but overall ranks real high on the list of other great films of the 1990s. Director Neil Jordan creates a modern-day noir, and the film scores on both the levels of plot and character evident with the fact that he won Academy Award for Best Writing, Screenplay Written Directly for the Screen along with 5 other nominations for his movie. MY RATING: 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If It Wasn't For That Twist It Would Have Been Totally Obscure
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Theo Robertson
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A British soldier called Jody is kidnapped by the IRA and held hostage . Given the task of guarding him Fergus listens to Jody discuss his life . Showing Fergus a photograph of his girlfriend Dil and Fergus starts a strange obsession for Dil In 1992 this came and went in the blink of an eye at the British box office . Hardly surprising because the British box office appetite for Brit movies was still three or four years away . A British film in those days was basically a TV play with slightly better production values and this one is little different . When it was released in the rest of the world it became the film to see especially in America . Cynical Brits who hadn't seen the film would sneer that showing the IRA is a good light might have everything to do with it but then critics and marketing started making reference to the film's twist so much that when the film started picking up nominations at the big awards ceremonies people would jokingly ask if Jaye Davidson would be Oscar nominated as best supporting actor or best supporting actress This of course lets the cat out of the bag for everyone who hadn't seen the film . THE CRYING GAME exists mainly to set up this plot twist . If it was a conventional love story it would have headed straight to video and obscurity . Great suspension of disbelief is needed and the disbelief is a bit too difficult to suspend . Dil might look very feminine on celluloid but I can tell you in real life ladyboy wannabes are not so convincing . I remember one time in Pokhara in Nepal the town opened its gates to a ladyboy convention and I guarantee you not even Stevie Wonder would be fooled . There's a mannerism and a metaphysical aura to a transsexual impersonating a woman that fails to convince and knowing this you'd have severe doubts that Fergus would be taken in . The screenplay itself is very contrived with Jody having to become conveniently deaf which seals his fate and Fergus having to bump in to old friends That said I did find myself not exactly enjoying the film after first seeing it after a gap of nearly twenty years but respecting it more . This is certainly almost down to the hype surrounding the film on its release in America where the critics gave the impression this was the greatest film ever made . It's not but is a well acted well made drama . Forest Whittaker makes a mess of his accent which while rarely slipping in to American doesn't sound like a London accent . Stephen Rea manages to make his character likable even though he playing the long clich&eacute;d role of a " good " IRA man . Miranda Richardson who seemed to appear in every British film from the period does well enough enough to exorcise memories of her singularly awful performances as Queen Ezlibath in BLACKADDER 2 but the film quite rightly belongs to Jaye Davidson as Dil after appearing in this also gave an equally good performance in STARGATE then promptly disappeared as quickly arrived In summary THE CRYING GAME is a film that probably suffered from its own hype after becoming a sleeper hit in the States . It's never as deep as it tries try to be fusing issues of sexuality and identity . It's a love story with a difference but apart from the shock plot twist it's a film that would have appeared on channel 4 one Thursday night without causing a ripple
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I wish more scripts were written like this.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sergeant_Tibbs
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Continuing my quest to see all the Oscar screenplay nominees and currently knocking down the winners, I move onto The Crying Game, a film I've been intending to see for a few years now even though I knew its twist. It has a fantastic script. Very real characters and a sharp wit gives it a great edge. It's quite small scale with two distinct halves, both a slow burn to big payoffs. Forget the context and content, this is how scripts should be written. Although Stephen Rea is great, I did find myself having problems with Forest Whitaker and Jaye Davidson in their awkward and forced line deliveries to the point where I thought there was something wrong with the sound. They may have taken me out of the moment sometimes during the long stretches of emotional brooding, but it's the film's thrilling moments that makes the film such a treat. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very twisted early 90's Irish thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    delenn7
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie come out when I was 8. But I only saw it last week but still powerful to this day. Themes of trans phobia, Irish revolution on the English, kidnapping and Fergus/Jimmy caught between morals and Honor. The scorpion and the frog would fit "the title" well. Jaye Davidson was in only one other known movie Stargate as Ra the space villain which started the Staragate TV Shows. Shame he isn't acting today. The song-title of the movie the Crying game is a catchy song. Weird how Fergus "kidnaps" the "boyfriend" of transgendered "girlfriend" and becomes her "new boyfriend". Of course Jody the bad chick in the film adds zest. I recommend Breakfast in Pluto for a similar Irish LGBT film. Rated R FOR Sexuality scenes, language and violence.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Masterpiece!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'The Crying Game' is A Masterpiece in filmmaking! A Hard-Hitting, Engrossing Film, that also offers marvelous Direction, top-class Cinematography & flawless Performances! 'The Crying Game' Synopsis: A British soldier is kidnapped by IRA terrorists. He befriends one of his captors, who is drawn into the soldier's world. 'The Crying Game' explores themes of race, gender, nationality, and sexuality against the backdrop of the Irish Troubles. Neil Jordan's Oscar-Winning Screenplay is Hard-Hitting & Engrossing. Its so brave, that it doesn't let you move from your seat. Its raises questions on humanity & seeks for answers. Its amongst The Most Amazing Screenplays Ever Written! Neil Jordan's Direction, on the other-hand, is marvelous. He has executed the film with flourish. Ian Wilson's Cinematography is top-class. Each & Every Frame has Clarity! Editing is good. Art Design is appropriate. Make-Up is fabulously done. Performance-Wise: Stephen Rea is astonishing. He plays a guilt-driven man with utter brilliance. Jaye Davidson embodies the part & delivers in high regard. The Sequences Between Rea & Davidson are magnificent. Forest Whitaker is extra-ordinary. Miranda Richardson is haunting, while Adrian Dunbar is convincing. Jim Broadbent is charming. On the whole, 'The Crying Game' is not to be missed!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Twilight: The Movie of a young black man
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Blackman TheBlackMan
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have never seen such a great movie, it was STUNNING and beautiful in all aspects, I am honestly wondering why this is not top 10 yet, the scene where the girl was crying and the boy went up to her and slapped her was great. y friend thought this movie was bad at first but then he thought it was awesome, so did I. so Basically we win and you don't, we would like to buy a cheeseburger. Thank you. Also, if you prefer horror movies, watch this because I think you will get a hair of stuff if you continue to rise beyond the many colors of reduntant colors and reluctant decisions of your succinct thoughts. Even though you are the prime-minister you will enjoy this movie, I would personally give this a 9.5/10, this is really an upcoming film. Christopher Nolan, move out of the way! i have cancer please hep me.. i like it when the black man is afraid of trains and stop by die in everyone
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One Story Two Many
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This well known Film and its equally well known and at the time unexpected, explicit, and shocking scene, tries to be a dual Drama. It has a "split personality". It has both humanistic and political concerns. The double story combines uneasily and probably would have been better concentrating on the trans-looking and trans-spirited nature and the uncomfortable, but warm, relationship of the two very sensitive characters that are at the heart of this gallant effort. The opening scenes are the least affecting and the intertwining of both "soldiers" back-story commitment is uneasy, if not forced into the narrative. The best parts are some creative dialog and the "lovers" interplay. The result is a not so great film with an attraction of aspects that do move things along, but with uneven results. It is the compelling and quite different coupling that works the best and the other part seems to belong in another Film with another agenda. To geminate the two story lines appears to be the biggest failing and in the end it is very good by a half.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's all about the subtle details in "The Crying Game" (1992)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dee.reid
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Writer-director Neil Jordan's "The Crying Game" caused a huge sensation in 1992 before and after the time of its release that year. I myself have a strange history with this movie. I had a very strong idea about this film's "big plot twist" long before I actually sat down and watched it; a documentary on slasher movies also clued me in to the little detail that this film had hiding within its complex story structures. I have to say that upon having completely watched "The Crying Game" in its entirety, the "big twist" is still pretty shocking - even if it is to be expected. The film begins as an intense political thriller: IRA terrorist Fergus (Stephen Rea) is part of a plot to kidnap a black British soldier named Jody (Forest Whitaker, sporting his best British accent ever) in exchange for the freedom of several IRA members being held captive by the British military. The two strike up an unexpected, albeit tragic friendship: Jody knows that Fergus is no killer at heart, but instead extracts a promise from Fergus that in the event of his inevitable execution, he go to London to track down and protect his exotic lover Dil (Jaye Davidson). As expected, the two strike up a casual friendship that eventually blossoms into a tentative romantic relationship. And soon, even after the Big Twist, elements from Fergus's past as an IRA terrorist come back to haunt him. "The Crying Game" is a film that often explores the complexities of human nature (both the sordid histories of both Fergus and Dil come to the forefront for them both to deal with), against a backdrop of complex political intrigue, nationality, sexuality, race, and gender. These details, in addition to the subtle body language and nuances of the performers, make "The Crying Game" a complex and highly involving psychological thriller. It's a boldly acted, written, and directed little film with big-time ambitions. "The Crying Game" was undoubtedly one of the best films of 1992 and for plenty of good reason. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I just couldn't get myself to like this movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lagudafuad
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Crying game has critical acclaim but I still found it hard to rate it above 5; to me it is something that is not for everybody. The acting delivered by the trio of Forest Whitaker, Stephen Rea and Jaye Davidson is the only thing this movie runs on, a triumphant entry into a world of perfect acting is what this movie delivers from the first scene. The movie's plot is also strong enough to keep you watching if you are that interested. The surprise that Fergus got when he found out that his new love is not exactly what he think she is, is the eye opener in the movie. Getting 6 Academy Award nominations and wining one for Best Original Screenplay, The Crying Game was released in 1992 to a favorable review holding a 100% approval rating from critics in Rotten Tomatoes. This psychological thriller drama was written and directed by filmmaker Neil Jordan (who is also a novelist on the side) who was behind the 1994 movie Interview with the Vampire: The Vampire Chronicles and the 2007 movie The Brave One with Jodie Foster. Interview with the Vampire also had Stephen Rea as one of the cast with Tom Cruise and Brad Pitt. The movie went into production with the name The Soldier's Wife but the late Stanley Kubrick a good friend of Neil advised him against it, saying with a name like that people will expect a war film. The name of the movie is actually a song Dil (Jaye Davidson) sang at the club where she met Fergus (Stephen Rea). The Crying Game is a song by Boy George. The movies strong point is the plot, it thickens as the movie goes on; the plot has an IRA soldier named Fergus (Stephen Rea) and his unit, including a woman named Jude (Miranda Richardson) who was the bait to help kidnap Jody (Forest Whitaker). The IRA kidnapped Jody so as to use him as a bargain chip as they demand the release of other jailed IRA members, threatening to execute Jody if their demands are not met. While Fergus guards Jody, they develop a bond during which, Jody tells Fergus the story about the Scorpion and the Frog, which teaches the lesson that something's are natural to some people regardless of the circumstances in which they find themselves. Jody gets killed and Fergus has to keep a promise that he made to him to help take care of Dil. I won't want to rob you of the few thrills I got from the movie, but at least I can say it is not as grand as they all say, but I will let you be the judge of that. www.lagsreviews.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Prominently atmospheric, incisively humorous..."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sindre Kaspersen
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Irish screenwriter, producer and director Neil Jordan's seventh feature film which he wrote, premiered at the 49th Venice Film Festival in 1992, was screened at the 17th Toronto International Film Festival in 1992, was shot on location in England and Ireland and is a UK-Japan co- production which was produced by producer Stephen Woolley. It tells the story about an Irish Volunteer in the IRA named Fergus Clegg who whilst staying with a small group of other IRA terrorists in Belfast, Northern Ireland kidnaps an English soldier named Jody whom a woman named Jude has lured into a trap. Whilst guarding the soldier who believes that it is only a matter of time before he will be killed, Fergus becomes acquainted with him an learns about his girlfriend named Dil who works at a hair salon in the capital city of England, but as Fergus begins to appreciate Jody's company and regard him as his friend he is assigned to assassinate him by his superior named Peter. Distinctly and precisely directed by Irish filmmaker Neil Jordan, this finely tuned fictional tale which is narrated mostly from the two main characters' viewpoints, draws an intriguing and multifaceted portrayal of an Irishman who travels to London, England to honor a friend's last wish and to get away from his associations with the Irish Republican Army. While notable for it's variegated and naturalistic milieu depictions, sterling cinematography by English cinematographer Ian Wilson, production design by production designer Jim Clay and use of colors and light, this character-driven and narrative-driven story about deception, attraction and overcoming one's preconceptions where a hairdresser and singer whom has just left her boyfriend one day gets a new customer who introduces himself as a Scottish native and later shows up at the bar where she sings, depicts two interrelated and charming studies of character and contains a great score by English composer Anne Dudley. This somewhat political, conversational and eloquently romantic psychological thriller from the early 1990s which is set in Belfast, Northern Ireland and London, England during the Troubles in Northern Ireland in the late 20th century and where a man presents himself with another name than his own to a stranger he only knows from a picture, is impelled and reinforced by it's cogent narrative structure, substantial character development, subtle continuity, endearing and colorful characters, brilliant dialog, merging of themes and genres, timely use of music and remarkable acting performances by Irish actor Stephen Rea, American actor Jaye Davidson in his debut feature film role, English actress Miranda Richardson and American actor, producer and director Forest Whitaker. A prominently atmospheric, incisively humorous and memorable love-story which gained, among numerous other awards, the Alexander Korda Award for Best British Film at the 46th BAFTA Awards in 1993.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Crying Game- Good Noir Cinema (1992)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ashish sood (ashistrong@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "The Crying Game" is one of those films that you see and would like even more in retrospect. The film was huge in 1992 and earned a Best Picture nomination from the Academy, with director It is a complicated puzzle that involves an IRA (Provisional Irish Republican Army) volunteer Fergus(Stephen Rea) befriending with Dil (Jaye Davidson) girlfriend of an English soldier Jody(Forest Whitaker) whom he had kidnapped. The twists and turns of "The Crying Game" are what make the film work. The movie although has flaws in several areas, but overall ranks real high on the list of other great films of the 1990s. Director Neil Jordan creates a modern-day noir, and the film scores on both the levels of plot and character evident with the fact that he won Academy Award for Best Writing, Screenplay Written Directly for the Screen along with 5 other nominations for his movie. MY RATING: 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If It Wasn't For That Twist It Would Have Been Totally Obscure
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Theo Robertson
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A British soldier called Jody is kidnapped by the IRA and held hostage . Given the task of guarding him Fergus listens to Jody discuss his life . Showing Fergus a photograph of his girlfriend Dil and Fergus starts a strange obsession for Dil In 1992 this came and went in the blink of an eye at the British box office . Hardly surprising because the British box office appetite for Brit movies was still three or four years away . A British film in those days was basically a TV play with slightly better production values and this one is little different . When it was released in the rest of the world it became the film to see especially in America . Cynical Brits who hadn't seen the film would sneer that showing the IRA is a good light might have everything to do with it but then critics and marketing started making reference to the film's twist so much that when the film started picking up nominations at the big awards ceremonies people would jokingly ask if Jaye Davidson would be Oscar nominated as best supporting actor or best supporting actress This of course lets the cat out of the bag for everyone who hadn't seen the film . THE CRYING GAME exists mainly to set up this plot twist . If it was a conventional love story it would have headed straight to video and obscurity . Great suspension of disbelief is needed and the disbelief is a bit too difficult to suspend . Dil might look very feminine on celluloid but I can tell you in real life ladyboy wannabes are not so convincing . I remember one time in Pokhara in Nepal the town opened its gates to a ladyboy convention and I guarantee you not even Stevie Wonder would be fooled . There's a mannerism and a metaphysical aura to a transsexual impersonating a woman that fails to convince and knowing this you'd have severe doubts that Fergus would be taken in . The screenplay itself is very contrived with Jody having to become conveniently deaf which seals his fate and Fergus having to bump in to old friends That said I did find myself not exactly enjoying the film after first seeing it after a gap of nearly twenty years but respecting it more . This is certainly almost down to the hype surrounding the film on its release in America where the critics gave the impression this was the greatest film ever made . It's not but is a well acted well made drama . Forest Whittaker makes a mess of his accent which while rarely slipping in to American doesn't sound like a London accent . Stephen Rea manages to make his character likable even though he playing the long clich&eacute;d role of a " good " IRA man . Miranda Richardson who seemed to appear in every British film from the period does well enough enough to exorcise memories of her singularly awful performances as Queen Ezlibath in BLACKADDER 2 but the film quite rightly belongs to Jaye Davidson as Dil after appearing in this also gave an equally good performance in STARGATE then promptly disappeared as quickly arrived In summary THE CRYING GAME is a film that probably suffered from its own hype after becoming a sleeper hit in the States . It's never as deep as it tries try to be fusing issues of sexuality and identity . It's a love story with a difference but apart from the shock plot twist it's a film that would have appeared on channel 4 one Thursday night without causing a ripple
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I wish more scripts were written like this.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sergeant_Tibbs
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Continuing my quest to see all the Oscar screenplay nominees and currently knocking down the winners, I move onto The Crying Game, a film I've been intending to see for a few years now even though I knew its twist. It has a fantastic script. Very real characters and a sharp wit gives it a great edge. It's quite small scale with two distinct halves, both a slow burn to big payoffs. Forget the context and content, this is how scripts should be written. Although Stephen Rea is great, I did find myself having problems with Forest Whitaker and Jaye Davidson in their awkward and forced line deliveries to the point where I thought there was something wrong with the sound. They may have taken me out of the moment sometimes during the long stretches of emotional brooding, but it's the film's thrilling moments that makes the film such a treat. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very twisted early 90's Irish thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    delenn7
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie come out when I was 8. But I only saw it last week but still powerful to this day. Themes of trans phobia, Irish revolution on the English, kidnapping and Fergus/Jimmy caught between morals and Honor. The scorpion and the frog would fit "the title" well. Jaye Davidson was in only one other known movie Stargate as Ra the space villain which started the Staragate TV Shows. Shame he isn't acting today. The song-title of the movie the Crying game is a catchy song. Weird how Fergus "kidnaps" the "boyfriend" of transgendered "girlfriend" and becomes her "new boyfriend". Of course Jody the bad chick in the film adds zest. I recommend Breakfast in Pluto for a similar Irish LGBT film. Rated R FOR Sexuality scenes, language and violence.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Masterpiece!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'The Crying Game' is A Masterpiece in filmmaking! A Hard-Hitting, Engrossing Film, that also offers marvelous Direction, top-class Cinematography & flawless Performances! 'The Crying Game' Synopsis: A British soldier is kidnapped by IRA terrorists. He befriends one of his captors, who is drawn into the soldier's world. 'The Crying Game' explores themes of race, gender, nationality, and sexuality against the backdrop of the Irish Troubles. Neil Jordan's Oscar-Winning Screenplay is Hard-Hitting & Engrossing. Its so brave, that it doesn't let you move from your seat. Its raises questions on humanity & seeks for answers. Its amongst The Most Amazing Screenplays Ever Written! Neil Jordan's Direction, on the other-hand, is marvelous. He has executed the film with flourish. Ian Wilson's Cinematography is top-class. Each & Every Frame has Clarity! Editing is good. Art Design is appropriate. Make-Up is fabulously done. Performance-Wise: Stephen Rea is astonishing. He plays a guilt-driven man with utter brilliance. Jaye Davidson embodies the part & delivers in high regard. The Sequences Between Rea & Davidson are magnificent. Forest Whitaker is extra-ordinary. Miranda Richardson is haunting, while Adrian Dunbar is convincing. Jim Broadbent is charming. On the whole, 'The Crying Game' is not to be missed!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Twilight: The Movie of a young black man
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Blackman TheBlackMan
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have never seen such a great movie, it was STUNNING and beautiful in all aspects, I am honestly wondering why this is not top 10 yet, the scene where the girl was crying and the boy went up to her and slapped her was great. y friend thought this movie was bad at first but then he thought it was awesome, so did I. so Basically we win and you don't, we would like to buy a cheeseburger. Thank you. Also, if you prefer horror movies, watch this because I think you will get a hair of stuff if you continue to rise beyond the many colors of reduntant colors and reluctant decisions of your succinct thoughts. Even though you are the prime-minister you will enjoy this movie, I would personally give this a 9.5/10, this is really an upcoming film. Christopher Nolan, move out of the way! i have cancer please hep me.. i like it when the black man is afraid of trains and stop by die in everyone
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One Story Two Many
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This well known Film and its equally well known and at the time unexpected, explicit, and shocking scene, tries to be a dual Drama. It has a "split personality". It has both humanistic and political concerns. The double story combines uneasily and probably would have been better concentrating on the trans-looking and trans-spirited nature and the uncomfortable, but warm, relationship of the two very sensitive characters that are at the heart of this gallant effort. The opening scenes are the least affecting and the intertwining of both "soldiers" back-story commitment is uneasy, if not forced into the narrative. The best parts are some creative dialog and the "lovers" interplay. The result is a not so great film with an attraction of aspects that do move things along, but with uneven results. It is the compelling and quite different coupling that works the best and the other part seems to belong in another Film with another agenda. To geminate the two story lines appears to be the biggest failing and in the end it is very good by a half.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's all about the subtle details in "The Crying Game" (1992)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dee.reid
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Writer-director Neil Jordan's "The Crying Game" caused a huge sensation in 1992 before and after the time of its release that year. I myself have a strange history with this movie. I had a very strong idea about this film's "big plot twist" long before I actually sat down and watched it; a documentary on slasher movies also clued me in to the little detail that this film had hiding within its complex story structures. I have to say that upon having completely watched "The Crying Game" in its entirety, the "big twist" is still pretty shocking - even if it is to be expected. The film begins as an intense political thriller: IRA terrorist Fergus (Stephen Rea) is part of a plot to kidnap a black British soldier named Jody (Forest Whitaker, sporting his best British accent ever) in exchange for the freedom of several IRA members being held captive by the British military. The two strike up an unexpected, albeit tragic friendship: Jody knows that Fergus is no killer at heart, but instead extracts a promise from Fergus that in the event of his inevitable execution, he go to London to track down and protect his exotic lover Dil (Jaye Davidson). As expected, the two strike up a casual friendship that eventually blossoms into a tentative romantic relationship. And soon, even after the Big Twist, elements from Fergus's past as an IRA terrorist come back to haunt him. "The Crying Game" is a film that often explores the complexities of human nature (both the sordid histories of both Fergus and Dil come to the forefront for them both to deal with), against a backdrop of complex political intrigue, nationality, sexuality, race, and gender. These details, in addition to the subtle body language and nuances of the performers, make "The Crying Game" a complex and highly involving psychological thriller. It's a boldly acted, written, and directed little film with big-time ambitions. "The Crying Game" was undoubtedly one of the best films of 1992 and for plenty of good reason. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I just couldn't get myself to like this movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lagudafuad
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Crying game has critical acclaim but I still found it hard to rate it above 5; to me it is something that is not for everybody. The acting delivered by the trio of Forest Whitaker, Stephen Rea and Jaye Davidson is the only thing this movie runs on, a triumphant entry into a world of perfect acting is what this movie delivers from the first scene. The movie's plot is also strong enough to keep you watching if you are that interested. The surprise that Fergus got when he found out that his new love is not exactly what he think she is, is the eye opener in the movie. Getting 6 Academy Award nominations and wining one for Best Original Screenplay, The Crying Game was released in 1992 to a favorable review holding a 100% approval rating from critics in Rotten Tomatoes. This psychological thriller drama was written and directed by filmmaker Neil Jordan (who is also a novelist on the side) who was behind the 1994 movie Interview with the Vampire: The Vampire Chronicles and the 2007 movie The Brave One with Jodie Foster. Interview with the Vampire also had Stephen Rea as one of the cast with Tom Cruise and Brad Pitt. The movie went into production with the name The Soldier's Wife but the late Stanley Kubrick a good friend of Neil advised him against it, saying with a name like that people will expect a war film. The name of the movie is actually a song Dil (Jaye Davidson) sang at the club where she met Fergus (Stephen Rea). The Crying Game is a song by Boy George. The movies strong point is the plot, it thickens as the movie goes on; the plot has an IRA soldier named Fergus (Stephen Rea) and his unit, including a woman named Jude (Miranda Richardson) who was the bait to help kidnap Jody (Forest Whitaker). The IRA kidnapped Jody so as to use him as a bargain chip as they demand the release of other jailed IRA members, threatening to execute Jody if their demands are not met. While Fergus guards Jody, they develop a bond during which, Jody tells Fergus the story about the Scorpion and the Frog, which teaches the lesson that something's are natural to some people regardless of the circumstances in which they find themselves. Jody gets killed and Fergus has to keep a promise that he made to him to help take care of Dil. I won't want to rob you of the few thrills I got from the movie, but at least I can say it is not as grand as they all say, but I will let you be the judge of that. www.lagsreviews.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Prominently atmospheric, incisively humorous..."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sindre Kaspersen
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Irish screenwriter, producer and director Neil Jordan's seventh feature film which he wrote, premiered at the 49th Venice Film Festival in 1992, was screened at the 17th Toronto International Film Festival in 1992, was shot on location in England and Ireland and is a UK-Japan co- production which was produced by producer Stephen Woolley. It tells the story about an Irish Volunteer in the IRA named Fergus Clegg who whilst staying with a small group of other IRA terrorists in Belfast, Northern Ireland kidnaps an English soldier named Jody whom a woman named Jude has lured into a trap. Whilst guarding the soldier who believes that it is only a matter of time before he will be killed, Fergus becomes acquainted with him an learns about his girlfriend named Dil who works at a hair salon in the capital city of England, but as Fergus begins to appreciate Jody's company and regard him as his friend he is assigned to assassinate him by his superior named Peter. Distinctly and precisely directed by Irish filmmaker Neil Jordan, this finely tuned fictional tale which is narrated mostly from the two main characters' viewpoints, draws an intriguing and multifaceted portrayal of an Irishman who travels to London, England to honor a friend's last wish and to get away from his associations with the Irish Republican Army. While notable for it's variegated and naturalistic milieu depictions, sterling cinematography by English cinematographer Ian Wilson, production design by production designer Jim Clay and use of colors and light, this character-driven and narrative-driven story about deception, attraction and overcoming one's preconceptions where a hairdresser and singer whom has just left her boyfriend one day gets a new customer who introduces himself as a Scottish native and later shows up at the bar where she sings, depicts two interrelated and charming studies of character and contains a great score by English composer Anne Dudley. This somewhat political, conversational and eloquently romantic psychological thriller from the early 1990s which is set in Belfast, Northern Ireland and London, England during the Troubles in Northern Ireland in the late 20th century and where a man presents himself with another name than his own to a stranger he only knows from a picture, is impelled and reinforced by it's cogent narrative structure, substantial character development, subtle continuity, endearing and colorful characters, brilliant dialog, merging of themes and genres, timely use of music and remarkable acting performances by Irish actor Stephen Rea, American actor Jaye Davidson in his debut feature film role, English actress Miranda Richardson and American actor, producer and director Forest Whitaker. A prominently atmospheric, incisively humorous and memorable love-story which gained, among numerous other awards, the Alexander Korda Award for Best British Film at the 46th BAFTA Awards in 1993.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Crying Game- Good Noir Cinema (1992)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ashish sood (ashistrong@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "The Crying Game" is one of those films that you see and would like even more in retrospect. The film was huge in 1992 and earned a Best Picture nomination from the Academy, with director It is a complicated puzzle that involves an IRA (Provisional Irish Republican Army) volunteer Fergus(Stephen Rea) befriending with Dil (Jaye Davidson) girlfriend of an English soldier Jody(Forest Whitaker) whom he had kidnapped. The twists and turns of "The Crying Game" are what make the film work. The movie although has flaws in several areas, but overall ranks real high on the list of other great films of the 1990s. Director Neil Jordan creates a modern-day noir, and the film scores on both the levels of plot and character evident with the fact that he won Academy Award for Best Writing, Screenplay Written Directly for the Screen along with 5 other nominations for his movie. MY RATING: 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If It Wasn't For That Twist It Would Have Been Totally Obscure
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Theo Robertson
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A British soldier called Jody is kidnapped by the IRA and held hostage . Given the task of guarding him Fergus listens to Jody discuss his life . Showing Fergus a photograph of his girlfriend Dil and Fergus starts a strange obsession for Dil In 1992 this came and went in the blink of an eye at the British box office . Hardly surprising because the British box office appetite for Brit movies was still three or four years away . A British film in those days was basically a TV play with slightly better production values and this one is little different . When it was released in the rest of the world it became the film to see especially in America . Cynical Brits who hadn't seen the film would sneer that showing the IRA is a good light might have everything to do with it but then critics and marketing started making reference to the film's twist so much that when the film started picking up nominations at the big awards ceremonies people would jokingly ask if Jaye Davidson would be Oscar nominated as best supporting actor or best supporting actress This of course lets the cat out of the bag for everyone who hadn't seen the film . THE CRYING GAME exists mainly to set up this plot twist . If it was a conventional love story it would have headed straight to video and obscurity . Great suspension of disbelief is needed and the disbelief is a bit too difficult to suspend . Dil might look very feminine on celluloid but I can tell you in real life ladyboy wannabes are not so convincing . I remember one time in Pokhara in Nepal the town opened its gates to a ladyboy convention and I guarantee you not even Stevie Wonder would be fooled . There's a mannerism and a metaphysical aura to a transsexual impersonating a woman that fails to convince and knowing this you'd have severe doubts that Fergus would be taken in . The screenplay itself is very contrived with Jody having to become conveniently deaf which seals his fate and Fergus having to bump in to old friends That said I did find myself not exactly enjoying the film after first seeing it after a gap of nearly twenty years but respecting it more . This is certainly almost down to the hype surrounding the film on its release in America where the critics gave the impression this was the greatest film ever made . It's not but is a well acted well made drama . Forest Whittaker makes a mess of his accent which while rarely slipping in to American doesn't sound like a London accent . Stephen Rea manages to make his character likable even though he playing the long clich&eacute;d role of a " good " IRA man . Miranda Richardson who seemed to appear in every British film from the period does well enough enough to exorcise memories of her singularly awful performances as Queen Ezlibath in BLACKADDER 2 but the film quite rightly belongs to Jaye Davidson as Dil after appearing in this also gave an equally good performance in STARGATE then promptly disappeared as quickly arrived In summary THE CRYING GAME is a film that probably suffered from its own hype after becoming a sleeper hit in the States . It's never as deep as it tries try to be fusing issues of sexuality and identity . It's a love story with a difference but apart from the shock plot twist it's a film that would have appeared on channel 4 one Thursday night without causing a ripple
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I wish more scripts were written like this.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sergeant_Tibbs
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Continuing my quest to see all the Oscar screenplay nominees and currently knocking down the winners, I move onto The Crying Game, a film I've been intending to see for a few years now even though I knew its twist. It has a fantastic script. Very real characters and a sharp wit gives it a great edge. It's quite small scale with two distinct halves, both a slow burn to big payoffs. Forget the context and content, this is how scripts should be written. Although Stephen Rea is great, I did find myself having problems with Forest Whitaker and Jaye Davidson in their awkward and forced line deliveries to the point where I thought there was something wrong with the sound. They may have taken me out of the moment sometimes during the long stretches of emotional brooding, but it's the film's thrilling moments that makes the film such a treat. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very twisted early 90's Irish thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    delenn7
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie come out when I was 8. But I only saw it last week but still powerful to this day. Themes of trans phobia, Irish revolution on the English, kidnapping and Fergus/Jimmy caught between morals and Honor. The scorpion and the frog would fit "the title" well. Jaye Davidson was in only one other known movie Stargate as Ra the space villain which started the Staragate TV Shows. Shame he isn't acting today. The song-title of the movie the Crying game is a catchy song. Weird how Fergus "kidnaps" the "boyfriend" of transgendered "girlfriend" and becomes her "new boyfriend". Of course Jody the bad chick in the film adds zest. I recommend Breakfast in Pluto for a similar Irish LGBT film. Rated R FOR Sexuality scenes, language and violence.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Masterpiece!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'The Crying Game' is A Masterpiece in filmmaking! A Hard-Hitting, Engrossing Film, that also offers marvelous Direction, top-class Cinematography & flawless Performances! 'The Crying Game' Synopsis: A British soldier is kidnapped by IRA terrorists. He befriends one of his captors, who is drawn into the soldier's world. 'The Crying Game' explores themes of race, gender, nationality, and sexuality against the backdrop of the Irish Troubles. Neil Jordan's Oscar-Winning Screenplay is Hard-Hitting & Engrossing. Its so brave, that it doesn't let you move from your seat. Its raises questions on humanity & seeks for answers. Its amongst The Most Amazing Screenplays Ever Written! Neil Jordan's Direction, on the other-hand, is marvelous. He has executed the film with flourish. Ian Wilson's Cinematography is top-class. Each & Every Frame has Clarity! Editing is good. Art Design is appropriate. Make-Up is fabulously done. Performance-Wise: Stephen Rea is astonishing. He plays a guilt-driven man with utter brilliance. Jaye Davidson embodies the part & delivers in high regard. The Sequences Between Rea & Davidson are magnificent. Forest Whitaker is extra-ordinary. Miranda Richardson is haunting, while Adrian Dunbar is convincing. Jim Broadbent is charming. On the whole, 'The Crying Game' is not to be missed!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Twilight: The Movie of a young black man
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Blackman TheBlackMan
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have never seen such a great movie, it was STUNNING and beautiful in all aspects, I am honestly wondering why this is not top 10 yet, the scene where the girl was crying and the boy went up to her and slapped her was great. y friend thought this movie was bad at first but then he thought it was awesome, so did I. so Basically we win and you don't, we would like to buy a cheeseburger. Thank you. Also, if you prefer horror movies, watch this because I think you will get a hair of stuff if you continue to rise beyond the many colors of reduntant colors and reluctant decisions of your succinct thoughts. Even though you are the prime-minister you will enjoy this movie, I would personally give this a 9.5/10, this is really an upcoming film. Christopher Nolan, move out of the way! i have cancer please hep me.. i like it when the black man is afraid of trains and stop by die in everyone
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One Story Two Many
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This well known Film and its equally well known and at the time unexpected, explicit, and shocking scene, tries to be a dual Drama. It has a "split personality". It has both humanistic and political concerns. The double story combines uneasily and probably would have been better concentrating on the trans-looking and trans-spirited nature and the uncomfortable, but warm, relationship of the two very sensitive characters that are at the heart of this gallant effort. The opening scenes are the least affecting and the intertwining of both "soldiers" back-story commitment is uneasy, if not forced into the narrative. The best parts are some creative dialog and the "lovers" interplay. The result is a not so great film with an attraction of aspects that do move things along, but with uneven results. It is the compelling and quite different coupling that works the best and the other part seems to belong in another Film with another agenda. To geminate the two story lines appears to be the biggest failing and in the end it is very good by a half.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's all about the subtle details in "The Crying Game" (1992)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dee.reid
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Writer-director Neil Jordan's "The Crying Game" caused a huge sensation in 1992 before and after the time of its release that year. I myself have a strange history with this movie. I had a very strong idea about this film's "big plot twist" long before I actually sat down and watched it; a documentary on slasher movies also clued me in to the little detail that this film had hiding within its complex story structures. I have to say that upon having completely watched "The Crying Game" in its entirety, the "big twist" is still pretty shocking - even if it is to be expected. The film begins as an intense political thriller: IRA terrorist Fergus (Stephen Rea) is part of a plot to kidnap a black British soldier named Jody (Forest Whitaker, sporting his best British accent ever) in exchange for the freedom of several IRA members being held captive by the British military. The two strike up an unexpected, albeit tragic friendship: Jody knows that Fergus is no killer at heart, but instead extracts a promise from Fergus that in the event of his inevitable execution, he go to London to track down and protect his exotic lover Dil (Jaye Davidson). As expected, the two strike up a casual friendship that eventually blossoms into a tentative romantic relationship. And soon, even after the Big Twist, elements from Fergus's past as an IRA terrorist come back to haunt him. "The Crying Game" is a film that often explores the complexities of human nature (both the sordid histories of both Fergus and Dil come to the forefront for them both to deal with), against a backdrop of complex political intrigue, nationality, sexuality, race, and gender. These details, in addition to the subtle body language and nuances of the performers, make "The Crying Game" a complex and highly involving psychological thriller. It's a boldly acted, written, and directed little film with big-time ambitions. "The Crying Game" was undoubtedly one of the best films of 1992 and for plenty of good reason. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I just couldn't get myself to like this movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lagudafuad
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Crying game has critical acclaim but I still found it hard to rate it above 5; to me it is something that is not for everybody. The acting delivered by the trio of Forest Whitaker, Stephen Rea and Jaye Davidson is the only thing this movie runs on, a triumphant entry into a world of perfect acting is what this movie delivers from the first scene. The movie's plot is also strong enough to keep you watching if you are that interested. The surprise that Fergus got when he found out that his new love is not exactly what he think she is, is the eye opener in the movie. Getting 6 Academy Award nominations and wining one for Best Original Screenplay, The Crying Game was released in 1992 to a favorable review holding a 100% approval rating from critics in Rotten Tomatoes. This psychological thriller drama was written and directed by filmmaker Neil Jordan (who is also a novelist on the side) who was behind the 1994 movie Interview with the Vampire: The Vampire Chronicles and the 2007 movie The Brave One with Jodie Foster. Interview with the Vampire also had Stephen Rea as one of the cast with Tom Cruise and Brad Pitt. The movie went into production with the name The Soldier's Wife but the late Stanley Kubrick a good friend of Neil advised him against it, saying with a name like that people will expect a war film. The name of the movie is actually a song Dil (Jaye Davidson) sang at the club where she met Fergus (Stephen Rea). The Crying Game is a song by Boy George. The movies strong point is the plot, it thickens as the movie goes on; the plot has an IRA soldier named Fergus (Stephen Rea) and his unit, including a woman named Jude (Miranda Richardson) who was the bait to help kidnap Jody (Forest Whitaker). The IRA kidnapped Jody so as to use him as a bargain chip as they demand the release of other jailed IRA members, threatening to execute Jody if their demands are not met. While Fergus guards Jody, they develop a bond during which, Jody tells Fergus the story about the Scorpion and the Frog, which teaches the lesson that something's are natural to some people regardless of the circumstances in which they find themselves. Jody gets killed and Fergus has to keep a promise that he made to him to help take care of Dil. I won't want to rob you of the few thrills I got from the movie, but at least I can say it is not as grand as they all say, but I will let you be the judge of that. www.lagsreviews.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Prominently atmospheric, incisively humorous..."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sindre Kaspersen
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Irish screenwriter, producer and director Neil Jordan's seventh feature film which he wrote, premiered at the 49th Venice Film Festival in 1992, was screened at the 17th Toronto International Film Festival in 1992, was shot on location in England and Ireland and is a UK-Japan co- production which was produced by producer Stephen Woolley. It tells the story about an Irish Volunteer in the IRA named Fergus Clegg who whilst staying with a small group of other IRA terrorists in Belfast, Northern Ireland kidnaps an English soldier named Jody whom a woman named Jude has lured into a trap. Whilst guarding the soldier who believes that it is only a matter of time before he will be killed, Fergus becomes acquainted with him an learns about his girlfriend named Dil who works at a hair salon in the capital city of England, but as Fergus begins to appreciate Jody's company and regard him as his friend he is assigned to assassinate him by his superior named Peter. Distinctly and precisely directed by Irish filmmaker Neil Jordan, this finely tuned fictional tale which is narrated mostly from the two main characters' viewpoints, draws an intriguing and multifaceted portrayal of an Irishman who travels to London, England to honor a friend's last wish and to get away from his associations with the Irish Republican Army. While notable for it's variegated and naturalistic milieu depictions, sterling cinematography by English cinematographer Ian Wilson, production design by production designer Jim Clay and use of colors and light, this character-driven and narrative-driven story about deception, attraction and overcoming one's preconceptions where a hairdresser and singer whom has just left her boyfriend one day gets a new customer who introduces himself as a Scottish native and later shows up at the bar where she sings, depicts two interrelated and charming studies of character and contains a great score by English composer Anne Dudley. This somewhat political, conversational and eloquently romantic psychological thriller from the early 1990s which is set in Belfast, Northern Ireland and London, England during the Troubles in Northern Ireland in the late 20th century and where a man presents himself with another name than his own to a stranger he only knows from a picture, is impelled and reinforced by it's cogent narrative structure, substantial character development, subtle continuity, endearing and colorful characters, brilliant dialog, merging of themes and genres, timely use of music and remarkable acting performances by Irish actor Stephen Rea, American actor Jaye Davidson in his debut feature film role, English actress Miranda Richardson and American actor, producer and director Forest Whitaker. A prominently atmospheric, incisively humorous and memorable love-story which gained, among numerous other awards, the Alexander Korda Award for Best British Film at the 46th BAFTA Awards in 1993.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Crying Game- Good Noir Cinema (1992)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ashish sood (ashistrong@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "The Crying Game" is one of those films that you see and would like even more in retrospect. The film was huge in 1992 and earned a Best Picture nomination from the Academy, with director It is a complicated puzzle that involves an IRA (Provisional Irish Republican Army) volunteer Fergus(Stephen Rea) befriending with Dil (Jaye Davidson) girlfriend of an English soldier Jody(Forest Whitaker) whom he had kidnapped. The twists and turns of "The Crying Game" are what make the film work. The movie although has flaws in several areas, but overall ranks real high on the list of other great films of the 1990s. Director Neil Jordan creates a modern-day noir, and the film scores on both the levels of plot and character evident with the fact that he won Academy Award for Best Writing, Screenplay Written Directly for the Screen along with 5 other nominations for his movie. MY RATING: 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If It Wasn't For That Twist It Would Have Been Totally Obscure
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Theo Robertson
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A British soldier called Jody is kidnapped by the IRA and held hostage . Given the task of guarding him Fergus listens to Jody discuss his life . Showing Fergus a photograph of his girlfriend Dil and Fergus starts a strange obsession for Dil In 1992 this came and went in the blink of an eye at the British box office . Hardly surprising because the British box office appetite for Brit movies was still three or four years away . A British film in those days was basically a TV play with slightly better production values and this one is little different . When it was released in the rest of the world it became the film to see especially in America . Cynical Brits who hadn't seen the film would sneer that showing the IRA is a good light might have everything to do with it but then critics and marketing started making reference to the film's twist so much that when the film started picking up nominations at the big awards ceremonies people would jokingly ask if Jaye Davidson would be Oscar nominated as best supporting actor or best supporting actress This of course lets the cat out of the bag for everyone who hadn't seen the film . THE CRYING GAME exists mainly to set up this plot twist . If it was a conventional love story it would have headed straight to video and obscurity . Great suspension of disbelief is needed and the disbelief is a bit too difficult to suspend . Dil might look very feminine on celluloid but I can tell you in real life ladyboy wannabes are not so convincing . I remember one time in Pokhara in Nepal the town opened its gates to a ladyboy convention and I guarantee you not even Stevie Wonder would be fooled . There's a mannerism and a metaphysical aura to a transsexual impersonating a woman that fails to convince and knowing this you'd have severe doubts that Fergus would be taken in . The screenplay itself is very contrived with Jody having to become conveniently deaf which seals his fate and Fergus having to bump in to old friends That said I did find myself not exactly enjoying the film after first seeing it after a gap of nearly twenty years but respecting it more . This is certainly almost down to the hype surrounding the film on its release in America where the critics gave the impression this was the greatest film ever made . It's not but is a well acted well made drama . Forest Whittaker makes a mess of his accent which while rarely slipping in to American doesn't sound like a London accent . Stephen Rea manages to make his character likable even though he playing the long clich&eacute;d role of a " good " IRA man . Miranda Richardson who seemed to appear in every British film from the period does well enough enough to exorcise memories of her singularly awful performances as Queen Ezlibath in BLACKADDER 2 but the film quite rightly belongs to Jaye Davidson as Dil after appearing in this also gave an equally good performance in STARGATE then promptly disappeared as quickly arrived In summary THE CRYING GAME is a film that probably suffered from its own hype after becoming a sleeper hit in the States . It's never as deep as it tries try to be fusing issues of sexuality and identity . It's a love story with a difference but apart from the shock plot twist it's a film that would have appeared on channel 4 one Thursday night without causing a ripple
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I wish more scripts were written like this.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sergeant_Tibbs
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Continuing my quest to see all the Oscar screenplay nominees and currently knocking down the winners, I move onto The Crying Game, a film I've been intending to see for a few years now even though I knew its twist. It has a fantastic script. Very real characters and a sharp wit gives it a great edge. It's quite small scale with two distinct halves, both a slow burn to big payoffs. Forget the context and content, this is how scripts should be written. Although Stephen Rea is great, I did find myself having problems with Forest Whitaker and Jaye Davidson in their awkward and forced line deliveries to the point where I thought there was something wrong with the sound. They may have taken me out of the moment sometimes during the long stretches of emotional brooding, but it's the film's thrilling moments that makes the film such a treat. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very twisted early 90's Irish thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    delenn7
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie come out when I was 8. But I only saw it last week but still powerful to this day. Themes of trans phobia, Irish revolution on the English, kidnapping and Fergus/Jimmy caught between morals and Honor. The scorpion and the frog would fit "the title" well. Jaye Davidson was in only one other known movie Stargate as Ra the space villain which started the Staragate TV Shows. Shame he isn't acting today. The song-title of the movie the Crying game is a catchy song. Weird how Fergus "kidnaps" the "boyfriend" of transgendered "girlfriend" and becomes her "new boyfriend". Of course Jody the bad chick in the film adds zest. I recommend Breakfast in Pluto for a similar Irish LGBT film. Rated R FOR Sexuality scenes, language and violence.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Masterpiece!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'The Crying Game' is A Masterpiece in filmmaking! A Hard-Hitting, Engrossing Film, that also offers marvelous Direction, top-class Cinematography & flawless Performances! 'The Crying Game' Synopsis: A British soldier is kidnapped by IRA terrorists. He befriends one of his captors, who is drawn into the soldier's world. 'The Crying Game' explores themes of race, gender, nationality, and sexuality against the backdrop of the Irish Troubles. Neil Jordan's Oscar-Winning Screenplay is Hard-Hitting & Engrossing. Its so brave, that it doesn't let you move from your seat. Its raises questions on humanity & seeks for answers. Its amongst The Most Amazing Screenplays Ever Written! Neil Jordan's Direction, on the other-hand, is marvelous. He has executed the film with flourish. Ian Wilson's Cinematography is top-class. Each & Every Frame has Clarity! Editing is good. Art Design is appropriate. Make-Up is fabulously done. Performance-Wise: Stephen Rea is astonishing. He plays a guilt-driven man with utter brilliance. Jaye Davidson embodies the part & delivers in high regard. The Sequences Between Rea & Davidson are magnificent. Forest Whitaker is extra-ordinary. Miranda Richardson is haunting, while Adrian Dunbar is convincing. Jim Broadbent is charming. On the whole, 'The Crying Game' is not to be missed!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Twilight: The Movie of a young black man
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Blackman TheBlackMan
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have never seen such a great movie, it was STUNNING and beautiful in all aspects, I am honestly wondering why this is not top 10 yet, the scene where the girl was crying and the boy went up to her and slapped her was great. y friend thought this movie was bad at first but then he thought it was awesome, so did I. so Basically we win and you don't, we would like to buy a cheeseburger. Thank you. Also, if you prefer horror movies, watch this because I think you will get a hair of stuff if you continue to rise beyond the many colors of reduntant colors and reluctant decisions of your succinct thoughts. Even though you are the prime-minister you will enjoy this movie, I would personally give this a 9.5/10, this is really an upcoming film. Christopher Nolan, move out of the way! i have cancer please hep me.. i like it when the black man is afraid of trains and stop by die in everyone
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One Story Two Many
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This well known Film and its equally well known and at the time unexpected, explicit, and shocking scene, tries to be a dual Drama. It has a "split personality". It has both humanistic and political concerns. The double story combines uneasily and probably would have been better concentrating on the trans-looking and trans-spirited nature and the uncomfortable, but warm, relationship of the two very sensitive characters that are at the heart of this gallant effort. The opening scenes are the least affecting and the intertwining of both "soldiers" back-story commitment is uneasy, if not forced into the narrative. The best parts are some creative dialog and the "lovers" interplay. The result is a not so great film with an attraction of aspects that do move things along, but with uneven results. It is the compelling and quite different coupling that works the best and the other part seems to belong in another Film with another agenda. To geminate the two story lines appears to be the biggest failing and in the end it is very good by a half.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's all about the subtle details in "The Crying Game" (1992)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dee.reid
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Writer-director Neil Jordan's "The Crying Game" caused a huge sensation in 1992 before and after the time of its release that year. I myself have a strange history with this movie. I had a very strong idea about this film's "big plot twist" long before I actually sat down and watched it; a documentary on slasher movies also clued me in to the little detail that this film had hiding within its complex story structures. I have to say that upon having completely watched "The Crying Game" in its entirety, the "big twist" is still pretty shocking - even if it is to be expected. The film begins as an intense political thriller: IRA terrorist Fergus (Stephen Rea) is part of a plot to kidnap a black British soldier named Jody (Forest Whitaker, sporting his best British accent ever) in exchange for the freedom of several IRA members being held captive by the British military. The two strike up an unexpected, albeit tragic friendship: Jody knows that Fergus is no killer at heart, but instead extracts a promise from Fergus that in the event of his inevitable execution, he go to London to track down and protect his exotic lover Dil (Jaye Davidson). As expected, the two strike up a casual friendship that eventually blossoms into a tentative romantic relationship. And soon, even after the Big Twist, elements from Fergus's past as an IRA terrorist come back to haunt him. "The Crying Game" is a film that often explores the complexities of human nature (both the sordid histories of both Fergus and Dil come to the forefront for them both to deal with), against a backdrop of complex political intrigue, nationality, sexuality, race, and gender. These details, in addition to the subtle body language and nuances of the performers, make "The Crying Game" a complex and highly involving psychological thriller. It's a boldly acted, written, and directed little film with big-time ambitions. "The Crying Game" was undoubtedly one of the best films of 1992 and for plenty of good reason. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I just couldn't get myself to like this movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lagudafuad
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Crying game has critical acclaim but I still found it hard to rate it above 5; to me it is something that is not for everybody. The acting delivered by the trio of Forest Whitaker, Stephen Rea and Jaye Davidson is the only thing this movie runs on, a triumphant entry into a world of perfect acting is what this movie delivers from the first scene. The movie's plot is also strong enough to keep you watching if you are that interested. The surprise that Fergus got when he found out that his new love is not exactly what he think she is, is the eye opener in the movie. Getting 6 Academy Award nominations and wining one for Best Original Screenplay, The Crying Game was released in 1992 to a favorable review holding a 100% approval rating from critics in Rotten Tomatoes. This psychological thriller drama was written and directed by filmmaker Neil Jordan (who is also a novelist on the side) who was behind the 1994 movie Interview with the Vampire: The Vampire Chronicles and the 2007 movie The Brave One with Jodie Foster. Interview with the Vampire also had Stephen Rea as one of the cast with Tom Cruise and Brad Pitt. The movie went into production with the name The Soldier's Wife but the late Stanley Kubrick a good friend of Neil advised him against it, saying with a name like that people will expect a war film. The name of the movie is actually a song Dil (Jaye Davidson) sang at the club where she met Fergus (Stephen Rea). The Crying Game is a song by Boy George. The movies strong point is the plot, it thickens as the movie goes on; the plot has an IRA soldier named Fergus (Stephen Rea) and his unit, including a woman named Jude (Miranda Richardson) who was the bait to help kidnap Jody (Forest Whitaker). The IRA kidnapped Jody so as to use him as a bargain chip as they demand the release of other jailed IRA members, threatening to execute Jody if their demands are not met. While Fergus guards Jody, they develop a bond during which, Jody tells Fergus the story about the Scorpion and the Frog, which teaches the lesson that something's are natural to some people regardless of the circumstances in which they find themselves. Jody gets killed and Fergus has to keep a promise that he made to him to help take care of Dil. I won't want to rob you of the few thrills I got from the movie, but at least I can say it is not as grand as they all say, but I will let you be the judge of that. www.lagsreviews.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Prominently atmospheric, incisively humorous..."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sindre Kaspersen
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Irish screenwriter, producer and director Neil Jordan's seventh feature film which he wrote, premiered at the 49th Venice Film Festival in 1992, was screened at the 17th Toronto International Film Festival in 1992, was shot on location in England and Ireland and is a UK-Japan co- production which was produced by producer Stephen Woolley. It tells the story about an Irish Volunteer in the IRA named Fergus Clegg who whilst staying with a small group of other IRA terrorists in Belfast, Northern Ireland kidnaps an English soldier named Jody whom a woman named Jude has lured into a trap. Whilst guarding the soldier who believes that it is only a matter of time before he will be killed, Fergus becomes acquainted with him an learns about his girlfriend named Dil who works at a hair salon in the capital city of England, but as Fergus begins to appreciate Jody's company and regard him as his friend he is assigned to assassinate him by his superior named Peter. Distinctly and precisely directed by Irish filmmaker Neil Jordan, this finely tuned fictional tale which is narrated mostly from the two main characters' viewpoints, draws an intriguing and multifaceted portrayal of an Irishman who travels to London, England to honor a friend's last wish and to get away from his associations with the Irish Republican Army. While notable for it's variegated and naturalistic milieu depictions, sterling cinematography by English cinematographer Ian Wilson, production design by production designer Jim Clay and use of colors and light, this character-driven and narrative-driven story about deception, attraction and overcoming one's preconceptions where a hairdresser and singer whom has just left her boyfriend one day gets a new customer who introduces himself as a Scottish native and later shows up at the bar where she sings, depicts two interrelated and charming studies of character and contains a great score by English composer Anne Dudley. This somewhat political, conversational and eloquently romantic psychological thriller from the early 1990s which is set in Belfast, Northern Ireland and London, England during the Troubles in Northern Ireland in the late 20th century and where a man presents himself with another name than his own to a stranger he only knows from a picture, is impelled and reinforced by it's cogent narrative structure, substantial character development, subtle continuity, endearing and colorful characters, brilliant dialog, merging of themes and genres, timely use of music and remarkable acting performances by Irish actor Stephen Rea, American actor Jaye Davidson in his debut feature film role, English actress Miranda Richardson and American actor, producer and director Forest Whitaker. A prominently atmospheric, incisively humorous and memorable love-story which gained, among numerous other awards, the Alexander Korda Award for Best British Film at the 46th BAFTA Awards in 1993.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Crying Game- Good Noir Cinema (1992)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ashish sood (ashistrong@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "The Crying Game" is one of those films that you see and would like even more in retrospect. The film was huge in 1992 and earned a Best Picture nomination from the Academy, with director It is a complicated puzzle that involves an IRA (Provisional Irish Republican Army) volunteer Fergus(Stephen Rea) befriending with Dil (Jaye Davidson) girlfriend of an English soldier Jody(Forest Whitaker) whom he had kidnapped. The twists and turns of "The Crying Game" are what make the film work. The movie although has flaws in several areas, but overall ranks real high on the list of other great films of the 1990s. Director Neil Jordan creates a modern-day noir, and the film scores on both the levels of plot and character evident with the fact that he won Academy Award for Best Writing, Screenplay Written Directly for the Screen along with 5 other nominations for his movie. MY RATING: 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If It Wasn't For That Twist It Would Have Been Totally Obscure
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Theo Robertson
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A British soldier called Jody is kidnapped by the IRA and held hostage . Given the task of guarding him Fergus listens to Jody discuss his life . Showing Fergus a photograph of his girlfriend Dil and Fergus starts a strange obsession for Dil In 1992 this came and went in the blink of an eye at the British box office . Hardly surprising because the British box office appetite for Brit movies was still three or four years away . A British film in those days was basically a TV play with slightly better production values and this one is little different . When it was released in the rest of the world it became the film to see especially in America . Cynical Brits who hadn't seen the film would sneer that showing the IRA is a good light might have everything to do with it but then critics and marketing started making reference to the film's twist so much that when the film started picking up nominations at the big awards ceremonies people would jokingly ask if Jaye Davidson would be Oscar nominated as best supporting actor or best supporting actress This of course lets the cat out of the bag for everyone who hadn't seen the film . THE CRYING GAME exists mainly to set up this plot twist . If it was a conventional love story it would have headed straight to video and obscurity . Great suspension of disbelief is needed and the disbelief is a bit too difficult to suspend . Dil might look very feminine on celluloid but I can tell you in real life ladyboy wannabes are not so convincing . I remember one time in Pokhara in Nepal the town opened its gates to a ladyboy convention and I guarantee you not even Stevie Wonder would be fooled . There's a mannerism and a metaphysical aura to a transsexual impersonating a woman that fails to convince and knowing this you'd have severe doubts that Fergus would be taken in . The screenplay itself is very contrived with Jody having to become conveniently deaf which seals his fate and Fergus having to bump in to old friends That said I did find myself not exactly enjoying the film after first seeing it after a gap of nearly twenty years but respecting it more . This is certainly almost down to the hype surrounding the film on its release in America where the critics gave the impression this was the greatest film ever made . It's not but is a well acted well made drama . Forest Whittaker makes a mess of his accent which while rarely slipping in to American doesn't sound like a London accent . Stephen Rea manages to make his character likable even though he playing the long clich&eacute;d role of a " good " IRA man . Miranda Richardson who seemed to appear in every British film from the period does well enough enough to exorcise memories of her singularly awful performances as Queen Ezlibath in BLACKADDER 2 but the film quite rightly belongs to Jaye Davidson as Dil after appearing in this also gave an equally good performance in STARGATE then promptly disappeared as quickly arrived In summary THE CRYING GAME is a film that probably suffered from its own hype after becoming a sleeper hit in the States . It's never as deep as it tries try to be fusing issues of sexuality and identity . It's a love story with a difference but apart from the shock plot twist it's a film that would have appeared on channel 4 one Thursday night without causing a ripple
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I wish more scripts were written like this.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sergeant_Tibbs
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Continuing my quest to see all the Oscar screenplay nominees and currently knocking down the winners, I move onto The Crying Game, a film I've been intending to see for a few years now even though I knew its twist. It has a fantastic script. Very real characters and a sharp wit gives it a great edge. It's quite small scale with two distinct halves, both a slow burn to big payoffs. Forget the context and content, this is how scripts should be written. Although Stephen Rea is great, I did find myself having problems with Forest Whitaker and Jaye Davidson in their awkward and forced line deliveries to the point where I thought there was something wrong with the sound. They may have taken me out of the moment sometimes during the long stretches of emotional brooding, but it's the film's thrilling moments that makes the film such a treat. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very twisted early 90's Irish thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    delenn7
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie come out when I was 8. But I only saw it last week but still powerful to this day. Themes of trans phobia, Irish revolution on the English, kidnapping and Fergus/Jimmy caught between morals and Honor. The scorpion and the frog would fit "the title" well. Jaye Davidson was in only one other known movie Stargate as Ra the space villain which started the Staragate TV Shows. Shame he isn't acting today. The song-title of the movie the Crying game is a catchy song. Weird how Fergus "kidnaps" the "boyfriend" of transgendered "girlfriend" and becomes her "new boyfriend". Of course Jody the bad chick in the film adds zest. I recommend Breakfast in Pluto for a similar Irish LGBT film. Rated R FOR Sexuality scenes, language and violence.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Masterpiece!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'The Crying Game' is A Masterpiece in filmmaking! A Hard-Hitting, Engrossing Film, that also offers marvelous Direction, top-class Cinematography & flawless Performances! 'The Crying Game' Synopsis: A British soldier is kidnapped by IRA terrorists. He befriends one of his captors, who is drawn into the soldier's world. 'The Crying Game' explores themes of race, gender, nationality, and sexuality against the backdrop of the Irish Troubles. Neil Jordan's Oscar-Winning Screenplay is Hard-Hitting & Engrossing. Its so brave, that it doesn't let you move from your seat. Its raises questions on humanity & seeks for answers. Its amongst The Most Amazing Screenplays Ever Written! Neil Jordan's Direction, on the other-hand, is marvelous. He has executed the film with flourish. Ian Wilson's Cinematography is top-class. Each & Every Frame has Clarity! Editing is good. Art Design is appropriate. Make-Up is fabulously done. Performance-Wise: Stephen Rea is astonishing. He plays a guilt-driven man with utter brilliance. Jaye Davidson embodies the part & delivers in high regard. The Sequences Between Rea & Davidson are magnificent. Forest Whitaker is extra-ordinary. Miranda Richardson is haunting, while Adrian Dunbar is convincing. Jim Broadbent is charming. On the whole, 'The Crying Game' is not to be missed!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Twilight: The Movie of a young black man
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Blackman TheBlackMan
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have never seen such a great movie, it was STUNNING and beautiful in all aspects, I am honestly wondering why this is not top 10 yet, the scene where the girl was crying and the boy went up to her and slapped her was great. y friend thought this movie was bad at first but then he thought it was awesome, so did I. so Basically we win and you don't, we would like to buy a cheeseburger. Thank you. Also, if you prefer horror movies, watch this because I think you will get a hair of stuff if you continue to rise beyond the many colors of reduntant colors and reluctant decisions of your succinct thoughts. Even though you are the prime-minister you will enjoy this movie, I would personally give this a 9.5/10, this is really an upcoming film. Christopher Nolan, move out of the way! i have cancer please hep me.. i like it when the black man is afraid of trains and stop by die in everyone
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One Story Two Many
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This well known Film and its equally well known and at the time unexpected, explicit, and shocking scene, tries to be a dual Drama. It has a "split personality". It has both humanistic and political concerns. The double story combines uneasily and probably would have been better concentrating on the trans-looking and trans-spirited nature and the uncomfortable, but warm, relationship of the two very sensitive characters that are at the heart of this gallant effort. The opening scenes are the least affecting and the intertwining of both "soldiers" back-story commitment is uneasy, if not forced into the narrative. The best parts are some creative dialog and the "lovers" interplay. The result is a not so great film with an attraction of aspects that do move things along, but with uneven results. It is the compelling and quite different coupling that works the best and the other part seems to belong in another Film with another agenda. To geminate the two story lines appears to be the biggest failing and in the end it is very good by a half.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's all about the subtle details in "The Crying Game" (1992)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dee.reid
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Writer-director Neil Jordan's "The Crying Game" caused a huge sensation in 1992 before and after the time of its release that year. I myself have a strange history with this movie. I had a very strong idea about this film's "big plot twist" long before I actually sat down and watched it; a documentary on slasher movies also clued me in to the little detail that this film had hiding within its complex story structures. I have to say that upon having completely watched "The Crying Game" in its entirety, the "big twist" is still pretty shocking - even if it is to be expected. The film begins as an intense political thriller: IRA terrorist Fergus (Stephen Rea) is part of a plot to kidnap a black British soldier named Jody (Forest Whitaker, sporting his best British accent ever) in exchange for the freedom of several IRA members being held captive by the British military. The two strike up an unexpected, albeit tragic friendship: Jody knows that Fergus is no killer at heart, but instead extracts a promise from Fergus that in the event of his inevitable execution, he go to London to track down and protect his exotic lover Dil (Jaye Davidson). As expected, the two strike up a casual friendship that eventually blossoms into a tentative romantic relationship. And soon, even after the Big Twist, elements from Fergus's past as an IRA terrorist come back to haunt him. "The Crying Game" is a film that often explores the complexities of human nature (both the sordid histories of both Fergus and Dil come to the forefront for them both to deal with), against a backdrop of complex political intrigue, nationality, sexuality, race, and gender. These details, in addition to the subtle body language and nuances of the performers, make "The Crying Game" a complex and highly involving psychological thriller. It's a boldly acted, written, and directed little film with big-time ambitions. "The Crying Game" was undoubtedly one of the best films of 1992 and for plenty of good reason. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I just couldn't get myself to like this movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lagudafuad
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Crying game has critical acclaim but I still found it hard to rate it above 5; to me it is something that is not for everybody. The acting delivered by the trio of Forest Whitaker, Stephen Rea and Jaye Davidson is the only thing this movie runs on, a triumphant entry into a world of perfect acting is what this movie delivers from the first scene. The movie's plot is also strong enough to keep you watching if you are that interested. The surprise that Fergus got when he found out that his new love is not exactly what he think she is, is the eye opener in the movie. Getting 6 Academy Award nominations and wining one for Best Original Screenplay, The Crying Game was released in 1992 to a favorable review holding a 100% approval rating from critics in Rotten Tomatoes. This psychological thriller drama was written and directed by filmmaker Neil Jordan (who is also a novelist on the side) who was behind the 1994 movie Interview with the Vampire: The Vampire Chronicles and the 2007 movie The Brave One with Jodie Foster. Interview with the Vampire also had Stephen Rea as one of the cast with Tom Cruise and Brad Pitt. The movie went into production with the name The Soldier's Wife but the late Stanley Kubrick a good friend of Neil advised him against it, saying with a name like that people will expect a war film. The name of the movie is actually a song Dil (Jaye Davidson) sang at the club where she met Fergus (Stephen Rea). The Crying Game is a song by Boy George. The movies strong point is the plot, it thickens as the movie goes on; the plot has an IRA soldier named Fergus (Stephen Rea) and his unit, including a woman named Jude (Miranda Richardson) who was the bait to help kidnap Jody (Forest Whitaker). The IRA kidnapped Jody so as to use him as a bargain chip as they demand the release of other jailed IRA members, threatening to execute Jody if their demands are not met. While Fergus guards Jody, they develop a bond during which, Jody tells Fergus the story about the Scorpion and the Frog, which teaches the lesson that something's are natural to some people regardless of the circumstances in which they find themselves. Jody gets killed and Fergus has to keep a promise that he made to him to help take care of Dil. I won't want to rob you of the few thrills I got from the movie, but at least I can say it is not as grand as they all say, but I will let you be the judge of that. www.lagsreviews.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Prominently atmospheric, incisively humorous..."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sindre Kaspersen
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Irish screenwriter, producer and director Neil Jordan's seventh feature film which he wrote, premiered at the 49th Venice Film Festival in 1992, was screened at the 17th Toronto International Film Festival in 1992, was shot on location in England and Ireland and is a UK-Japan co- production which was produced by producer Stephen Woolley. It tells the story about an Irish Volunteer in the IRA named Fergus Clegg who whilst staying with a small group of other IRA terrorists in Belfast, Northern Ireland kidnaps an English soldier named Jody whom a woman named Jude has lured into a trap. Whilst guarding the soldier who believes that it is only a matter of time before he will be killed, Fergus becomes acquainted with him an learns about his girlfriend named Dil who works at a hair salon in the capital city of England, but as Fergus begins to appreciate Jody's company and regard him as his friend he is assigned to assassinate him by his superior named Peter. Distinctly and precisely directed by Irish filmmaker Neil Jordan, this finely tuned fictional tale which is narrated mostly from the two main characters' viewpoints, draws an intriguing and multifaceted portrayal of an Irishman who travels to London, England to honor a friend's last wish and to get away from his associations with the Irish Republican Army. While notable for it's variegated and naturalistic milieu depictions, sterling cinematography by English cinematographer Ian Wilson, production design by production designer Jim Clay and use of colors and light, this character-driven and narrative-driven story about deception, attraction and overcoming one's preconceptions where a hairdresser and singer whom has just left her boyfriend one day gets a new customer who introduces himself as a Scottish native and later shows up at the bar where she sings, depicts two interrelated and charming studies of character and contains a great score by English composer Anne Dudley. This somewhat political, conversational and eloquently romantic psychological thriller from the early 1990s which is set in Belfast, Northern Ireland and London, England during the Troubles in Northern Ireland in the late 20th century and where a man presents himself with another name than his own to a stranger he only knows from a picture, is impelled and reinforced by it's cogent narrative structure, substantial character development, subtle continuity, endearing and colorful characters, brilliant dialog, merging of themes and genres, timely use of music and remarkable acting performances by Irish actor Stephen Rea, American actor Jaye Davidson in his debut feature film role, English actress Miranda Richardson and American actor, producer and director Forest Whitaker. A prominently atmospheric, incisively humorous and memorable love-story which gained, among numerous other awards, the Alexander Korda Award for Best British Film at the 46th BAFTA Awards in 1993.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Crying Game- Good Noir Cinema (1992)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ashish sood (ashistrong@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "The Crying Game" is one of those films that you see and would like even more in retrospect. The film was huge in 1992 and earned a Best Picture nomination from the Academy, with director It is a complicated puzzle that involves an IRA (Provisional Irish Republican Army) volunteer Fergus(Stephen Rea) befriending with Dil (Jaye Davidson) girlfriend of an English soldier Jody(Forest Whitaker) whom he had kidnapped. The twists and turns of "The Crying Game" are what make the film work. The movie although has flaws in several areas, but overall ranks real high on the list of other great films of the 1990s. Director Neil Jordan creates a modern-day noir, and the film scores on both the levels of plot and character evident with the fact that he won Academy Award for Best Writing, Screenplay Written Directly for the Screen along with 5 other nominations for his movie. MY RATING: 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If It Wasn't For That Twist It Would Have Been Totally Obscure
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Theo Robertson
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A British soldier called Jody is kidnapped by the IRA and held hostage . Given the task of guarding him Fergus listens to Jody discuss his life . Showing Fergus a photograph of his girlfriend Dil and Fergus starts a strange obsession for Dil In 1992 this came and went in the blink of an eye at the British box office . Hardly surprising because the British box office appetite for Brit movies was still three or four years away . A British film in those days was basically a TV play with slightly better production values and this one is little different . When it was released in the rest of the world it became the film to see especially in America . Cynical Brits who hadn't seen the film would sneer that showing the IRA is a good light might have everything to do with it but then critics and marketing started making reference to the film's twist so much that when the film started picking up nominations at the big awards ceremonies people would jokingly ask if Jaye Davidson would be Oscar nominated as best supporting actor or best supporting actress This of course lets the cat out of the bag for everyone who hadn't seen the film . THE CRYING GAME exists mainly to set up this plot twist . If it was a conventional love story it would have headed straight to video and obscurity . Great suspension of disbelief is needed and the disbelief is a bit too difficult to suspend . Dil might look very feminine on celluloid but I can tell you in real life ladyboy wannabes are not so convincing . I remember one time in Pokhara in Nepal the town opened its gates to a ladyboy convention and I guarantee you not even Stevie Wonder would be fooled . There's a mannerism and a metaphysical aura to a transsexual impersonating a woman that fails to convince and knowing this you'd have severe doubts that Fergus would be taken in . The screenplay itself is very contrived with Jody having to become conveniently deaf which seals his fate and Fergus having to bump in to old friends That said I did find myself not exactly enjoying the film after first seeing it after a gap of nearly twenty years but respecting it more . This is certainly almost down to the hype surrounding the film on its release in America where the critics gave the impression this was the greatest film ever made . It's not but is a well acted well made drama . Forest Whittaker makes a mess of his accent which while rarely slipping in to American doesn't sound like a London accent . Stephen Rea manages to make his character likable even though he playing the long clich&eacute;d role of a " good " IRA man . Miranda Richardson who seemed to appear in every British film from the period does well enough enough to exorcise memories of her singularly awful performances as Queen Ezlibath in BLACKADDER 2 but the film quite rightly belongs to Jaye Davidson as Dil after appearing in this also gave an equally good performance in STARGATE then promptly disappeared as quickly arrived In summary THE CRYING GAME is a film that probably suffered from its own hype after becoming a sleeper hit in the States . It's never as deep as it tries try to be fusing issues of sexuality and identity . It's a love story with a difference but apart from the shock plot twist it's a film that would have appeared on channel 4 one Thursday night without causing a ripple
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I wish more scripts were written like this.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sergeant_Tibbs
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Continuing my quest to see all the Oscar screenplay nominees and currently knocking down the winners, I move onto The Crying Game, a film I've been intending to see for a few years now even though I knew its twist. It has a fantastic script. Very real characters and a sharp wit gives it a great edge. It's quite small scale with two distinct halves, both a slow burn to big payoffs. Forget the context and content, this is how scripts should be written. Although Stephen Rea is great, I did find myself having problems with Forest Whitaker and Jaye Davidson in their awkward and forced line deliveries to the point where I thought there was something wrong with the sound. They may have taken me out of the moment sometimes during the long stretches of emotional brooding, but it's the film's thrilling moments that makes the film such a treat. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very twisted early 90's Irish thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    delenn7
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie come out when I was 8. But I only saw it last week but still powerful to this day. Themes of trans phobia, Irish revolution on the English, kidnapping and Fergus/Jimmy caught between morals and Honor. The scorpion and the frog would fit "the title" well. Jaye Davidson was in only one other known movie Stargate as Ra the space villain which started the Staragate TV Shows. Shame he isn't acting today. The song-title of the movie the Crying game is a catchy song. Weird how Fergus "kidnaps" the "boyfriend" of transgendered "girlfriend" and becomes her "new boyfriend". Of course Jody the bad chick in the film adds zest. I recommend Breakfast in Pluto for a similar Irish LGBT film. Rated R FOR Sexuality scenes, language and violence.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Masterpiece!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'The Crying Game' is A Masterpiece in filmmaking! A Hard-Hitting, Engrossing Film, that also offers marvelous Direction, top-class Cinematography & flawless Performances! 'The Crying Game' Synopsis: A British soldier is kidnapped by IRA terrorists. He befriends one of his captors, who is drawn into the soldier's world. 'The Crying Game' explores themes of race, gender, nationality, and sexuality against the backdrop of the Irish Troubles. Neil Jordan's Oscar-Winning Screenplay is Hard-Hitting & Engrossing. Its so brave, that it doesn't let you move from your seat. Its raises questions on humanity & seeks for answers. Its amongst The Most Amazing Screenplays Ever Written! Neil Jordan's Direction, on the other-hand, is marvelous. He has executed the film with flourish. Ian Wilson's Cinematography is top-class. Each & Every Frame has Clarity! Editing is good. Art Design is appropriate. Make-Up is fabulously done. Performance-Wise: Stephen Rea is astonishing. He plays a guilt-driven man with utter brilliance. Jaye Davidson embodies the part & delivers in high regard. The Sequences Between Rea & Davidson are magnificent. Forest Whitaker is extra-ordinary. Miranda Richardson is haunting, while Adrian Dunbar is convincing. Jim Broadbent is charming. On the whole, 'The Crying Game' is not to be missed!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Twilight: The Movie of a young black man
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Blackman TheBlackMan
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have never seen such a great movie, it was STUNNING and beautiful in all aspects, I am honestly wondering why this is not top 10 yet, the scene where the girl was crying and the boy went up to her and slapped her was great. y friend thought this movie was bad at first but then he thought it was awesome, so did I. so Basically we win and you don't, we would like to buy a cheeseburger. Thank you. Also, if you prefer horror movies, watch this because I think you will get a hair of stuff if you continue to rise beyond the many colors of reduntant colors and reluctant decisions of your succinct thoughts. Even though you are the prime-minister you will enjoy this movie, I would personally give this a 9.5/10, this is really an upcoming film. Christopher Nolan, move out of the way! i have cancer please hep me.. i like it when the black man is afraid of trains and stop by die in everyone
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One Story Two Many
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This well known Film and its equally well known and at the time unexpected, explicit, and shocking scene, tries to be a dual Drama. It has a "split personality". It has both humanistic and political concerns. The double story combines uneasily and probably would have been better concentrating on the trans-looking and trans-spirited nature and the uncomfortable, but warm, relationship of the two very sensitive characters that are at the heart of this gallant effort. The opening scenes are the least affecting and the intertwining of both "soldiers" back-story commitment is uneasy, if not forced into the narrative. The best parts are some creative dialog and the "lovers" interplay. The result is a not so great film with an attraction of aspects that do move things along, but with uneven results. It is the compelling and quite different coupling that works the best and the other part seems to belong in another Film with another agenda. To geminate the two story lines appears to be the biggest failing and in the end it is very good by a half.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's all about the subtle details in "The Crying Game" (1992)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dee.reid
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Writer-director Neil Jordan's "The Crying Game" caused a huge sensation in 1992 before and after the time of its release that year. I myself have a strange history with this movie. I had a very strong idea about this film's "big plot twist" long before I actually sat down and watched it; a documentary on slasher movies also clued me in to the little detail that this film had hiding within its complex story structures. I have to say that upon having completely watched "The Crying Game" in its entirety, the "big twist" is still pretty shocking - even if it is to be expected. The film begins as an intense political thriller: IRA terrorist Fergus (Stephen Rea) is part of a plot to kidnap a black British soldier named Jody (Forest Whitaker, sporting his best British accent ever) in exchange for the freedom of several IRA members being held captive by the British military. The two strike up an unexpected, albeit tragic friendship: Jody knows that Fergus is no killer at heart, but instead extracts a promise from Fergus that in the event of his inevitable execution, he go to London to track down and protect his exotic lover Dil (Jaye Davidson). As expected, the two strike up a casual friendship that eventually blossoms into a tentative romantic relationship. And soon, even after the Big Twist, elements from Fergus's past as an IRA terrorist come back to haunt him. "The Crying Game" is a film that often explores the complexities of human nature (both the sordid histories of both Fergus and Dil come to the forefront for them both to deal with), against a backdrop of complex political intrigue, nationality, sexuality, race, and gender. These details, in addition to the subtle body language and nuances of the performers, make "The Crying Game" a complex and highly involving psychological thriller. It's a boldly acted, written, and directed little film with big-time ambitions. "The Crying Game" was undoubtedly one of the best films of 1992 and for plenty of good reason. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I just couldn't get myself to like this movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lagudafuad
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Crying game has critical acclaim but I still found it hard to rate it above 5; to me it is something that is not for everybody. The acting delivered by the trio of Forest Whitaker, Stephen Rea and Jaye Davidson is the only thing this movie runs on, a triumphant entry into a world of perfect acting is what this movie delivers from the first scene. The movie's plot is also strong enough to keep you watching if you are that interested. The surprise that Fergus got when he found out that his new love is not exactly what he think she is, is the eye opener in the movie. Getting 6 Academy Award nominations and wining one for Best Original Screenplay, The Crying Game was released in 1992 to a favorable review holding a 100% approval rating from critics in Rotten Tomatoes. This psychological thriller drama was written and directed by filmmaker Neil Jordan (who is also a novelist on the side) who was behind the 1994 movie Interview with the Vampire: The Vampire Chronicles and the 2007 movie The Brave One with Jodie Foster. Interview with the Vampire also had Stephen Rea as one of the cast with Tom Cruise and Brad Pitt. The movie went into production with the name The Soldier's Wife but the late Stanley Kubrick a good friend of Neil advised him against it, saying with a name like that people will expect a war film. The name of the movie is actually a song Dil (Jaye Davidson) sang at the club where she met Fergus (Stephen Rea). The Crying Game is a song by Boy George. The movies strong point is the plot, it thickens as the movie goes on; the plot has an IRA soldier named Fergus (Stephen Rea) and his unit, including a woman named Jude (Miranda Richardson) who was the bait to help kidnap Jody (Forest Whitaker). The IRA kidnapped Jody so as to use him as a bargain chip as they demand the release of other jailed IRA members, threatening to execute Jody if their demands are not met. While Fergus guards Jody, they develop a bond during which, Jody tells Fergus the story about the Scorpion and the Frog, which teaches the lesson that something's are natural to some people regardless of the circumstances in which they find themselves. Jody gets killed and Fergus has to keep a promise that he made to him to help take care of Dil. I won't want to rob you of the few thrills I got from the movie, but at least I can say it is not as grand as they all say, but I will let you be the judge of that. www.lagsreviews.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Prominently atmospheric, incisively humorous..."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sindre Kaspersen
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Irish screenwriter, producer and director Neil Jordan's seventh feature film which he wrote, premiered at the 49th Venice Film Festival in 1992, was screened at the 17th Toronto International Film Festival in 1992, was shot on location in England and Ireland and is a UK-Japan co- production which was produced by producer Stephen Woolley. It tells the story about an Irish Volunteer in the IRA named Fergus Clegg who whilst staying with a small group of other IRA terrorists in Belfast, Northern Ireland kidnaps an English soldier named Jody whom a woman named Jude has lured into a trap. Whilst guarding the soldier who believes that it is only a matter of time before he will be killed, Fergus becomes acquainted with him an learns about his girlfriend named Dil who works at a hair salon in the capital city of England, but as Fergus begins to appreciate Jody's company and regard him as his friend he is assigned to assassinate him by his superior named Peter. Distinctly and precisely directed by Irish filmmaker Neil Jordan, this finely tuned fictional tale which is narrated mostly from the two main characters' viewpoints, draws an intriguing and multifaceted portrayal of an Irishman who travels to London, England to honor a friend's last wish and to get away from his associations with the Irish Republican Army. While notable for it's variegated and naturalistic milieu depictions, sterling cinematography by English cinematographer Ian Wilson, production design by production designer Jim Clay and use of colors and light, this character-driven and narrative-driven story about deception, attraction and overcoming one's preconceptions where a hairdresser and singer whom has just left her boyfriend one day gets a new customer who introduces himself as a Scottish native and later shows up at the bar where she sings, depicts two interrelated and charming studies of character and contains a great score by English composer Anne Dudley. This somewhat political, conversational and eloquently romantic psychological thriller from the early 1990s which is set in Belfast, Northern Ireland and London, England during the Troubles in Northern Ireland in the late 20th century and where a man presents himself with another name than his own to a stranger he only knows from a picture, is impelled and reinforced by it's cogent narrative structure, substantial character development, subtle continuity, endearing and colorful characters, brilliant dialog, merging of themes and genres, timely use of music and remarkable acting performances by Irish actor Stephen Rea, American actor Jaye Davidson in his debut feature film role, English actress Miranda Richardson and American actor, producer and director Forest Whitaker. A prominently atmospheric, incisively humorous and memorable love-story which gained, among numerous other awards, the Alexander Korda Award for Best British Film at the 46th BAFTA Awards in 1993.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Crying Game- Good Noir Cinema (1992)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ashish sood (ashistrong@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "The Crying Game" is one of those films that you see and would like even more in retrospect. The film was huge in 1992 and earned a Best Picture nomination from the Academy, with director It is a complicated puzzle that involves an IRA (Provisional Irish Republican Army) volunteer Fergus(Stephen Rea) befriending with Dil (Jaye Davidson) girlfriend of an English soldier Jody(Forest Whitaker) whom he had kidnapped. The twists and turns of "The Crying Game" are what make the film work. The movie although has flaws in several areas, but overall ranks real high on the list of other great films of the 1990s. Director Neil Jordan creates a modern-day noir, and the film scores on both the levels of plot and character evident with the fact that he won Academy Award for Best Writing, Screenplay Written Directly for the Screen along with 5 other nominations for his movie. MY RATING: 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If It Wasn't For That Twist It Would Have Been Totally Obscure
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Theo Robertson
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A British soldier called Jody is kidnapped by the IRA and held hostage . Given the task of guarding him Fergus listens to Jody discuss his life . Showing Fergus a photograph of his girlfriend Dil and Fergus starts a strange obsession for Dil In 1992 this came and went in the blink of an eye at the British box office . Hardly surprising because the British box office appetite for Brit movies was still three or four years away . A British film in those days was basically a TV play with slightly better production values and this one is little different . When it was released in the rest of the world it became the film to see especially in America . Cynical Brits who hadn't seen the film would sneer that showing the IRA is a good light might have everything to do with it but then critics and marketing started making reference to the film's twist so much that when the film started picking up nominations at the big awards ceremonies people would jokingly ask if Jaye Davidson would be Oscar nominated as best supporting actor or best supporting actress This of course lets the cat out of the bag for everyone who hadn't seen the film . THE CRYING GAME exists mainly to set up this plot twist . If it was a conventional love story it would have headed straight to video and obscurity . Great suspension of disbelief is needed and the disbelief is a bit too difficult to suspend . Dil might look very feminine on celluloid but I can tell you in real life ladyboy wannabes are not so convincing . I remember one time in Pokhara in Nepal the town opened its gates to a ladyboy convention and I guarantee you not even Stevie Wonder would be fooled . There's a mannerism and a metaphysical aura to a transsexual impersonating a woman that fails to convince and knowing this you'd have severe doubts that Fergus would be taken in . The screenplay itself is very contrived with Jody having to become conveniently deaf which seals his fate and Fergus having to bump in to old friends That said I did find myself not exactly enjoying the film after first seeing it after a gap of nearly twenty years but respecting it more . This is certainly almost down to the hype surrounding the film on its release in America where the critics gave the impression this was the greatest film ever made . It's not but is a well acted well made drama . Forest Whittaker makes a mess of his accent which while rarely slipping in to American doesn't sound like a London accent . Stephen Rea manages to make his character likable even though he playing the long clich&eacute;d role of a " good " IRA man . Miranda Richardson who seemed to appear in every British film from the period does well enough enough to exorcise memories of her singularly awful performances as Queen Ezlibath in BLACKADDER 2 but the film quite rightly belongs to Jaye Davidson as Dil after appearing in this also gave an equally good performance in STARGATE then promptly disappeared as quickly arrived In summary THE CRYING GAME is a film that probably suffered from its own hype after becoming a sleeper hit in the States . It's never as deep as it tries try to be fusing issues of sexuality and identity . It's a love story with a difference but apart from the shock plot twist it's a film that would have appeared on channel 4 one Thursday night without causing a ripple
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I wish more scripts were written like this.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sergeant_Tibbs
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Continuing my quest to see all the Oscar screenplay nominees and currently knocking down the winners, I move onto The Crying Game, a film I've been intending to see for a few years now even though I knew its twist. It has a fantastic script. Very real characters and a sharp wit gives it a great edge. It's quite small scale with two distinct halves, both a slow burn to big payoffs. Forget the context and content, this is how scripts should be written. Although Stephen Rea is great, I did find myself having problems with Forest Whitaker and Jaye Davidson in their awkward and forced line deliveries to the point where I thought there was something wrong with the sound. They may have taken me out of the moment sometimes during the long stretches of emotional brooding, but it's the film's thrilling moments that makes the film such a treat. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very twisted early 90's Irish thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    delenn7
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie come out when I was 8. But I only saw it last week but still powerful to this day. Themes of trans phobia, Irish revolution on the English, kidnapping and Fergus/Jimmy caught between morals and Honor. The scorpion and the frog would fit "the title" well. Jaye Davidson was in only one other known movie Stargate as Ra the space villain which started the Staragate TV Shows. Shame he isn't acting today. The song-title of the movie the Crying game is a catchy song. Weird how Fergus "kidnaps" the "boyfriend" of transgendered "girlfriend" and becomes her "new boyfriend". Of course Jody the bad chick in the film adds zest. I recommend Breakfast in Pluto for a similar Irish LGBT film. Rated R FOR Sexuality scenes, language and violence.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Masterpiece!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'The Crying Game' is A Masterpiece in filmmaking! A Hard-Hitting, Engrossing Film, that also offers marvelous Direction, top-class Cinematography & flawless Performances! 'The Crying Game' Synopsis: A British soldier is kidnapped by IRA terrorists. He befriends one of his captors, who is drawn into the soldier's world. 'The Crying Game' explores themes of race, gender, nationality, and sexuality against the backdrop of the Irish Troubles. Neil Jordan's Oscar-Winning Screenplay is Hard-Hitting & Engrossing. Its so brave, that it doesn't let you move from your seat. Its raises questions on humanity & seeks for answers. Its amongst The Most Amazing Screenplays Ever Written! Neil Jordan's Direction, on the other-hand, is marvelous. He has executed the film with flourish. Ian Wilson's Cinematography is top-class. Each & Every Frame has Clarity! Editing is good. Art Design is appropriate. Make-Up is fabulously done. Performance-Wise: Stephen Rea is astonishing. He plays a guilt-driven man with utter brilliance. Jaye Davidson embodies the part & delivers in high regard. The Sequences Between Rea & Davidson are magnificent. Forest Whitaker is extra-ordinary. Miranda Richardson is haunting, while Adrian Dunbar is convincing. Jim Broadbent is charming. On the whole, 'The Crying Game' is not to be missed!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Twilight: The Movie of a young black man
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Blackman TheBlackMan
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have never seen such a great movie, it was STUNNING and beautiful in all aspects, I am honestly wondering why this is not top 10 yet, the scene where the girl was crying and the boy went up to her and slapped her was great. y friend thought this movie was bad at first but then he thought it was awesome, so did I. so Basically we win and you don't, we would like to buy a cheeseburger. Thank you. Also, if you prefer horror movies, watch this because I think you will get a hair of stuff if you continue to rise beyond the many colors of reduntant colors and reluctant decisions of your succinct thoughts. Even though you are the prime-minister you will enjoy this movie, I would personally give this a 9.5/10, this is really an upcoming film. Christopher Nolan, move out of the way! i have cancer please hep me.. i like it when the black man is afraid of trains and stop by die in everyone
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One Story Two Many
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This well known Film and its equally well known and at the time unexpected, explicit, and shocking scene, tries to be a dual Drama. It has a "split personality". It has both humanistic and political concerns. The double story combines uneasily and probably would have been better concentrating on the trans-looking and trans-spirited nature and the uncomfortable, but warm, relationship of the two very sensitive characters that are at the heart of this gallant effort. The opening scenes are the least affecting and the intertwining of both "soldiers" back-story commitment is uneasy, if not forced into the narrative. The best parts are some creative dialog and the "lovers" interplay. The result is a not so great film with an attraction of aspects that do move things along, but with uneven results. It is the compelling and quite different coupling that works the best and the other part seems to belong in another Film with another agenda. To geminate the two story lines appears to be the biggest failing and in the end it is very good by a half.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's all about the subtle details in "The Crying Game" (1992)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dee.reid
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Writer-director Neil Jordan's "The Crying Game" caused a huge sensation in 1992 before and after the time of its release that year. I myself have a strange history with this movie. I had a very strong idea about this film's "big plot twist" long before I actually sat down and watched it; a documentary on slasher movies also clued me in to the little detail that this film had hiding within its complex story structures. I have to say that upon having completely watched "The Crying Game" in its entirety, the "big twist" is still pretty shocking - even if it is to be expected. The film begins as an intense political thriller: IRA terrorist Fergus (Stephen Rea) is part of a plot to kidnap a black British soldier named Jody (Forest Whitaker, sporting his best British accent ever) in exchange for the freedom of several IRA members being held captive by the British military. The two strike up an unexpected, albeit tragic friendship: Jody knows that Fergus is no killer at heart, but instead extracts a promise from Fergus that in the event of his inevitable execution, he go to London to track down and protect his exotic lover Dil (Jaye Davidson). As expected, the two strike up a casual friendship that eventually blossoms into a tentative romantic relationship. And soon, even after the Big Twist, elements from Fergus's past as an IRA terrorist come back to haunt him. "The Crying Game" is a film that often explores the complexities of human nature (both the sordid histories of both Fergus and Dil come to the forefront for them both to deal with), against a backdrop of complex political intrigue, nationality, sexuality, race, and gender. These details, in addition to the subtle body language and nuances of the performers, make "The Crying Game" a complex and highly involving psychological thriller. It's a boldly acted, written, and directed little film with big-time ambitions. "The Crying Game" was undoubtedly one of the best films of 1992 and for plenty of good reason. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I just couldn't get myself to like this movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lagudafuad
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Crying game has critical acclaim but I still found it hard to rate it above 5; to me it is something that is not for everybody. The acting delivered by the trio of Forest Whitaker, Stephen Rea and Jaye Davidson is the only thing this movie runs on, a triumphant entry into a world of perfect acting is what this movie delivers from the first scene. The movie's plot is also strong enough to keep you watching if you are that interested. The surprise that Fergus got when he found out that his new love is not exactly what he think she is, is the eye opener in the movie. Getting 6 Academy Award nominations and wining one for Best Original Screenplay, The Crying Game was released in 1992 to a favorable review holding a 100% approval rating from critics in Rotten Tomatoes. This psychological thriller drama was written and directed by filmmaker Neil Jordan (who is also a novelist on the side) who was behind the 1994 movie Interview with the Vampire: The Vampire Chronicles and the 2007 movie The Brave One with Jodie Foster. Interview with the Vampire also had Stephen Rea as one of the cast with Tom Cruise and Brad Pitt. The movie went into production with the name The Soldier's Wife but the late Stanley Kubrick a good friend of Neil advised him against it, saying with a name like that people will expect a war film. The name of the movie is actually a song Dil (Jaye Davidson) sang at the club where she met Fergus (Stephen Rea). The Crying Game is a song by Boy George. The movies strong point is the plot, it thickens as the movie goes on; the plot has an IRA soldier named Fergus (Stephen Rea) and his unit, including a woman named Jude (Miranda Richardson) who was the bait to help kidnap Jody (Forest Whitaker). The IRA kidnapped Jody so as to use him as a bargain chip as they demand the release of other jailed IRA members, threatening to execute Jody if their demands are not met. While Fergus guards Jody, they develop a bond during which, Jody tells Fergus the story about the Scorpion and the Frog, which teaches the lesson that something's are natural to some people regardless of the circumstances in which they find themselves. Jody gets killed and Fergus has to keep a promise that he made to him to help take care of Dil. I won't want to rob you of the few thrills I got from the movie, but at least I can say it is not as grand as they all say, but I will let you be the judge of that. www.lagsreviews.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Prominently atmospheric, incisively humorous..."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sindre Kaspersen
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Irish screenwriter, producer and director Neil Jordan's seventh feature film which he wrote, premiered at the 49th Venice Film Festival in 1992, was screened at the 17th Toronto International Film Festival in 1992, was shot on location in England and Ireland and is a UK-Japan co- production which was produced by producer Stephen Woolley. It tells the story about an Irish Volunteer in the IRA named Fergus Clegg who whilst staying with a small group of other IRA terrorists in Belfast, Northern Ireland kidnaps an English soldier named Jody whom a woman named Jude has lured into a trap. Whilst guarding the soldier who believes that it is only a matter of time before he will be killed, Fergus becomes acquainted with him an learns about his girlfriend named Dil who works at a hair salon in the capital city of England, but as Fergus begins to appreciate Jody's company and regard him as his friend he is assigned to assassinate him by his superior named Peter. Distinctly and precisely directed by Irish filmmaker Neil Jordan, this finely tuned fictional tale which is narrated mostly from the two main characters' viewpoints, draws an intriguing and multifaceted portrayal of an Irishman who travels to London, England to honor a friend's last wish and to get away from his associations with the Irish Republican Army. While notable for it's variegated and naturalistic milieu depictions, sterling cinematography by English cinematographer Ian Wilson, production design by production designer Jim Clay and use of colors and light, this character-driven and narrative-driven story about deception, attraction and overcoming one's preconceptions where a hairdresser and singer whom has just left her boyfriend one day gets a new customer who introduces himself as a Scottish native and later shows up at the bar where she sings, depicts two interrelated and charming studies of character and contains a great score by English composer Anne Dudley. This somewhat political, conversational and eloquently romantic psychological thriller from the early 1990s which is set in Belfast, Northern Ireland and London, England during the Troubles in Northern Ireland in the late 20th century and where a man presents himself with another name than his own to a stranger he only knows from a picture, is impelled and reinforced by it's cogent narrative structure, substantial character development, subtle continuity, endearing and colorful characters, brilliant dialog, merging of themes and genres, timely use of music and remarkable acting performances by Irish actor Stephen Rea, American actor Jaye Davidson in his debut feature film role, English actress Miranda Richardson and American actor, producer and director Forest Whitaker. A prominently atmospheric, incisively humorous and memorable love-story which gained, among numerous other awards, the Alexander Korda Award for Best British Film at the 46th BAFTA Awards in 1993.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Crying Game- Good Noir Cinema (1992)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ashish sood (ashistrong@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "The Crying Game" is one of those films that you see and would like even more in retrospect. The film was huge in 1992 and earned a Best Picture nomination from the Academy, with director It is a complicated puzzle that involves an IRA (Provisional Irish Republican Army) volunteer Fergus(Stephen Rea) befriending with Dil (Jaye Davidson) girlfriend of an English soldier Jody(Forest Whitaker) whom he had kidnapped. The twists and turns of "The Crying Game" are what make the film work. The movie although has flaws in several areas, but overall ranks real high on the list of other great films of the 1990s. Director Neil Jordan creates a modern-day noir, and the film scores on both the levels of plot and character evident with the fact that he won Academy Award for Best Writing, Screenplay Written Directly for the Screen along with 5 other nominations for his movie. MY RATING: 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If It Wasn't For That Twist It Would Have Been Totally Obscure
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Theo Robertson
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A British soldier called Jody is kidnapped by the IRA and held hostage . Given the task of guarding him Fergus listens to Jody discuss his life . Showing Fergus a photograph of his girlfriend Dil and Fergus starts a strange obsession for Dil In 1992 this came and went in the blink of an eye at the British box office . Hardly surprising because the British box office appetite for Brit movies was still three or four years away . A British film in those days was basically a TV play with slightly better production values and this one is little different . When it was released in the rest of the world it became the film to see especially in America . Cynical Brits who hadn't seen the film would sneer that showing the IRA is a good light might have everything to do with it but then critics and marketing started making reference to the film's twist so much that when the film started picking up nominations at the big awards ceremonies people would jokingly ask if Jaye Davidson would be Oscar nominated as best supporting actor or best supporting actress This of course lets the cat out of the bag for everyone who hadn't seen the film . THE CRYING GAME exists mainly to set up this plot twist . If it was a conventional love story it would have headed straight to video and obscurity . Great suspension of disbelief is needed and the disbelief is a bit too difficult to suspend . Dil might look very feminine on celluloid but I can tell you in real life ladyboy wannabes are not so convincing . I remember one time in Pokhara in Nepal the town opened its gates to a ladyboy convention and I guarantee you not even Stevie Wonder would be fooled . There's a mannerism and a metaphysical aura to a transsexual impersonating a woman that fails to convince and knowing this you'd have severe doubts that Fergus would be taken in . The screenplay itself is very contrived with Jody having to become conveniently deaf which seals his fate and Fergus having to bump in to old friends That said I did find myself not exactly enjoying the film after first seeing it after a gap of nearly twenty years but respecting it more . This is certainly almost down to the hype surrounding the film on its release in America where the critics gave the impression this was the greatest film ever made . It's not but is a well acted well made drama . Forest Whittaker makes a mess of his accent which while rarely slipping in to American doesn't sound like a London accent . Stephen Rea manages to make his character likable even though he playing the long clich&eacute;d role of a " good " IRA man . Miranda Richardson who seemed to appear in every British film from the period does well enough enough to exorcise memories of her singularly awful performances as Queen Ezlibath in BLACKADDER 2 but the film quite rightly belongs to Jaye Davidson as Dil after appearing in this also gave an equally good performance in STARGATE then promptly disappeared as quickly arrived In summary THE CRYING GAME is a film that probably suffered from its own hype after becoming a sleeper hit in the States . It's never as deep as it tries try to be fusing issues of sexuality and identity . It's a love story with a difference but apart from the shock plot twist it's a film that would have appeared on channel 4 one Thursday night without causing a ripple
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I wish more scripts were written like this.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sergeant_Tibbs
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Continuing my quest to see all the Oscar screenplay nominees and currently knocking down the winners, I move onto The Crying Game, a film I've been intending to see for a few years now even though I knew its twist. It has a fantastic script. Very real characters and a sharp wit gives it a great edge. It's quite small scale with two distinct halves, both a slow burn to big payoffs. Forget the context and content, this is how scripts should be written. Although Stephen Rea is great, I did find myself having problems with Forest Whitaker and Jaye Davidson in their awkward and forced line deliveries to the point where I thought there was something wrong with the sound. They may have taken me out of the moment sometimes during the long stretches of emotional brooding, but it's the film's thrilling moments that makes the film such a treat. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very twisted early 90's Irish thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    delenn7
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie come out when I was 8. But I only saw it last week but still powerful to this day. Themes of trans phobia, Irish revolution on the English, kidnapping and Fergus/Jimmy caught between morals and Honor. The scorpion and the frog would fit "the title" well. Jaye Davidson was in only one other known movie Stargate as Ra the space villain which started the Staragate TV Shows. Shame he isn't acting today. The song-title of the movie the Crying game is a catchy song. Weird how Fergus "kidnaps" the "boyfriend" of transgendered "girlfriend" and becomes her "new boyfriend". Of course Jody the bad chick in the film adds zest. I recommend Breakfast in Pluto for a similar Irish LGBT film. Rated R FOR Sexuality scenes, language and violence.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Masterpiece!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'The Crying Game' is A Masterpiece in filmmaking! A Hard-Hitting, Engrossing Film, that also offers marvelous Direction, top-class Cinematography & flawless Performances! 'The Crying Game' Synopsis: A British soldier is kidnapped by IRA terrorists. He befriends one of his captors, who is drawn into the soldier's world. 'The Crying Game' explores themes of race, gender, nationality, and sexuality against the backdrop of the Irish Troubles. Neil Jordan's Oscar-Winning Screenplay is Hard-Hitting & Engrossing. Its so brave, that it doesn't let you move from your seat. Its raises questions on humanity & seeks for answers. Its amongst The Most Amazing Screenplays Ever Written! Neil Jordan's Direction, on the other-hand, is marvelous. He has executed the film with flourish. Ian Wilson's Cinematography is top-class. Each & Every Frame has Clarity! Editing is good. Art Design is appropriate. Make-Up is fabulously done. Performance-Wise: Stephen Rea is astonishing. He plays a guilt-driven man with utter brilliance. Jaye Davidson embodies the part & delivers in high regard. The Sequences Between Rea & Davidson are magnificent. Forest Whitaker is extra-ordinary. Miranda Richardson is haunting, while Adrian Dunbar is convincing. Jim Broadbent is charming. On the whole, 'The Crying Game' is not to be missed!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Twilight: The Movie of a young black man
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Blackman TheBlackMan
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have never seen such a great movie, it was STUNNING and beautiful in all aspects, I am honestly wondering why this is not top 10 yet, the scene where the girl was crying and the boy went up to her and slapped her was great. y friend thought this movie was bad at first but then he thought it was awesome, so did I. so Basically we win and you don't, we would like to buy a cheeseburger. Thank you. Also, if you prefer horror movies, watch this because I think you will get a hair of stuff if you continue to rise beyond the many colors of reduntant colors and reluctant decisions of your succinct thoughts. Even though you are the prime-minister you will enjoy this movie, I would personally give this a 9.5/10, this is really an upcoming film. Christopher Nolan, move out of the way! i have cancer please hep me.. i like it when the black man is afraid of trains and stop by die in everyone
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One Story Two Many
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This well known Film and its equally well known and at the time unexpected, explicit, and shocking scene, tries to be a dual Drama. It has a "split personality". It has both humanistic and political concerns. The double story combines uneasily and probably would have been better concentrating on the trans-looking and trans-spirited nature and the uncomfortable, but warm, relationship of the two very sensitive characters that are at the heart of this gallant effort. The opening scenes are the least affecting and the intertwining of both "soldiers" back-story commitment is uneasy, if not forced into the narrative. The best parts are some creative dialog and the "lovers" interplay. The result is a not so great film with an attraction of aspects that do move things along, but with uneven results. It is the compelling and quite different coupling that works the best and the other part seems to belong in another Film with another agenda. To geminate the two story lines appears to be the biggest failing and in the end it is very good by a half.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's all about the subtle details in "The Crying Game" (1992)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dee.reid
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Writer-director Neil Jordan's "The Crying Game" caused a huge sensation in 1992 before and after the time of its release that year. I myself have a strange history with this movie. I had a very strong idea about this film's "big plot twist" long before I actually sat down and watched it; a documentary on slasher movies also clued me in to the little detail that this film had hiding within its complex story structures. I have to say that upon having completely watched "The Crying Game" in its entirety, the "big twist" is still pretty shocking - even if it is to be expected. The film begins as an intense political thriller: IRA terrorist Fergus (Stephen Rea) is part of a plot to kidnap a black British soldier named Jody (Forest Whitaker, sporting his best British accent ever) in exchange for the freedom of several IRA members being held captive by the British military. The two strike up an unexpected, albeit tragic friendship: Jody knows that Fergus is no killer at heart, but instead extracts a promise from Fergus that in the event of his inevitable execution, he go to London to track down and protect his exotic lover Dil (Jaye Davidson). As expected, the two strike up a casual friendship that eventually blossoms into a tentative romantic relationship. And soon, even after the Big Twist, elements from Fergus's past as an IRA terrorist come back to haunt him. "The Crying Game" is a film that often explores the complexities of human nature (both the sordid histories of both Fergus and Dil come to the forefront for them both to deal with), against a backdrop of complex political intrigue, nationality, sexuality, race, and gender. These details, in addition to the subtle body language and nuances of the performers, make "The Crying Game" a complex and highly involving psychological thriller. It's a boldly acted, written, and directed little film with big-time ambitions. "The Crying Game" was undoubtedly one of the best films of 1992 and for plenty of good reason. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I just couldn't get myself to like this movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lagudafuad
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Crying game has critical acclaim but I still found it hard to rate it above 5; to me it is something that is not for everybody. The acting delivered by the trio of Forest Whitaker, Stephen Rea and Jaye Davidson is the only thing this movie runs on, a triumphant entry into a world of perfect acting is what this movie delivers from the first scene. The movie's plot is also strong enough to keep you watching if you are that interested. The surprise that Fergus got when he found out that his new love is not exactly what he think she is, is the eye opener in the movie. Getting 6 Academy Award nominations and wining one for Best Original Screenplay, The Crying Game was released in 1992 to a favorable review holding a 100% approval rating from critics in Rotten Tomatoes. This psychological thriller drama was written and directed by filmmaker Neil Jordan (who is also a novelist on the side) who was behind the 1994 movie Interview with the Vampire: The Vampire Chronicles and the 2007 movie The Brave One with Jodie Foster. Interview with the Vampire also had Stephen Rea as one of the cast with Tom Cruise and Brad Pitt. The movie went into production with the name The Soldier's Wife but the late Stanley Kubrick a good friend of Neil advised him against it, saying with a name like that people will expect a war film. The name of the movie is actually a song Dil (Jaye Davidson) sang at the club where she met Fergus (Stephen Rea). The Crying Game is a song by Boy George. The movies strong point is the plot, it thickens as the movie goes on; the plot has an IRA soldier named Fergus (Stephen Rea) and his unit, including a woman named Jude (Miranda Richardson) who was the bait to help kidnap Jody (Forest Whitaker). The IRA kidnapped Jody so as to use him as a bargain chip as they demand the release of other jailed IRA members, threatening to execute Jody if their demands are not met. While Fergus guards Jody, they develop a bond during which, Jody tells Fergus the story about the Scorpion and the Frog, which teaches the lesson that something's are natural to some people regardless of the circumstances in which they find themselves. Jody gets killed and Fergus has to keep a promise that he made to him to help take care of Dil. I won't want to rob you of the few thrills I got from the movie, but at least I can say it is not as grand as they all say, but I will let you be the judge of that. www.lagsreviews.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Prominently atmospheric, incisively humorous..."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sindre Kaspersen
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Irish screenwriter, producer and director Neil Jordan's seventh feature film which he wrote, premiered at the 49th Venice Film Festival in 1992, was screened at the 17th Toronto International Film Festival in 1992, was shot on location in England and Ireland and is a UK-Japan co- production which was produced by producer Stephen Woolley. It tells the story about an Irish Volunteer in the IRA named Fergus Clegg who whilst staying with a small group of other IRA terrorists in Belfast, Northern Ireland kidnaps an English soldier named Jody whom a woman named Jude has lured into a trap. Whilst guarding the soldier who believes that it is only a matter of time before he will be killed, Fergus becomes acquainted with him an learns about his girlfriend named Dil who works at a hair salon in the capital city of England, but as Fergus begins to appreciate Jody's company and regard him as his friend he is assigned to assassinate him by his superior named Peter. Distinctly and precisely directed by Irish filmmaker Neil Jordan, this finely tuned fictional tale which is narrated mostly from the two main characters' viewpoints, draws an intriguing and multifaceted portrayal of an Irishman who travels to London, England to honor a friend's last wish and to get away from his associations with the Irish Republican Army. While notable for it's variegated and naturalistic milieu depictions, sterling cinematography by English cinematographer Ian Wilson, production design by production designer Jim Clay and use of colors and light, this character-driven and narrative-driven story about deception, attraction and overcoming one's preconceptions where a hairdresser and singer whom has just left her boyfriend one day gets a new customer who introduces himself as a Scottish native and later shows up at the bar where she sings, depicts two interrelated and charming studies of character and contains a great score by English composer Anne Dudley. This somewhat political, conversational and eloquently romantic psychological thriller from the early 1990s which is set in Belfast, Northern Ireland and London, England during the Troubles in Northern Ireland in the late 20th century and where a man presents himself with another name than his own to a stranger he only knows from a picture, is impelled and reinforced by it's cogent narrative structure, substantial character development, subtle continuity, endearing and colorful characters, brilliant dialog, merging of themes and genres, timely use of music and remarkable acting performances by Irish actor Stephen Rea, American actor Jaye Davidson in his debut feature film role, English actress Miranda Richardson and American actor, producer and director Forest Whitaker. A prominently atmospheric, incisively humorous and memorable love-story which gained, among numerous other awards, the Alexander Korda Award for Best British Film at the 46th BAFTA Awards in 1993.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Crying Game- Good Noir Cinema (1992)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ashish sood (ashistrong@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "The Crying Game" is one of those films that you see and would like even more in retrospect. The film was huge in 1992 and earned a Best Picture nomination from the Academy, with director It is a complicated puzzle that involves an IRA (Provisional Irish Republican Army) volunteer Fergus(Stephen Rea) befriending with Dil (Jaye Davidson) girlfriend of an English soldier Jody(Forest Whitaker) whom he had kidnapped. The twists and turns of "The Crying Game" are what make the film work. The movie although has flaws in several areas, but overall ranks real high on the list of other great films of the 1990s. Director Neil Jordan creates a modern-day noir, and the film scores on both the levels of plot and character evident with the fact that he won Academy Award for Best Writing, Screenplay Written Directly for the Screen along with 5 other nominations for his movie. MY RATING: 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If It Wasn't For That Twist It Would Have Been Totally Obscure
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Theo Robertson
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A British soldier called Jody is kidnapped by the IRA and held hostage . Given the task of guarding him Fergus listens to Jody discuss his life . Showing Fergus a photograph of his girlfriend Dil and Fergus starts a strange obsession for Dil In 1992 this came and went in the blink of an eye at the British box office . Hardly surprising because the British box office appetite for Brit movies was still three or four years away . A British film in those days was basically a TV play with slightly better production values and this one is little different . When it was released in the rest of the world it became the film to see especially in America . Cynical Brits who hadn't seen the film would sneer that showing the IRA is a good light might have everything to do with it but then critics and marketing started making reference to the film's twist so much that when the film started picking up nominations at the big awards ceremonies people would jokingly ask if Jaye Davidson would be Oscar nominated as best supporting actor or best supporting actress This of course lets the cat out of the bag for everyone who hadn't seen the film . THE CRYING GAME exists mainly to set up this plot twist . If it was a conventional love story it would have headed straight to video and obscurity . Great suspension of disbelief is needed and the disbelief is a bit too difficult to suspend . Dil might look very feminine on celluloid but I can tell you in real life ladyboy wannabes are not so convincing . I remember one time in Pokhara in Nepal the town opened its gates to a ladyboy convention and I guarantee you not even Stevie Wonder would be fooled . There's a mannerism and a metaphysical aura to a transsexual impersonating a woman that fails to convince and knowing this you'd have severe doubts that Fergus would be taken in . The screenplay itself is very contrived with Jody having to become conveniently deaf which seals his fate and Fergus having to bump in to old friends That said I did find myself not exactly enjoying the film after first seeing it after a gap of nearly twenty years but respecting it more . This is certainly almost down to the hype surrounding the film on its release in America where the critics gave the impression this was the greatest film ever made . It's not but is a well acted well made drama . Forest Whittaker makes a mess of his accent which while rarely slipping in to American doesn't sound like a London accent . Stephen Rea manages to make his character likable even though he playing the long clich&eacute;d role of a " good " IRA man . Miranda Richardson who seemed to appear in every British film from the period does well enough enough to exorcise memories of her singularly awful performances as Queen Ezlibath in BLACKADDER 2 but the film quite rightly belongs to Jaye Davidson as Dil after appearing in this also gave an equally good performance in STARGATE then promptly disappeared as quickly arrived In summary THE CRYING GAME is a film that probably suffered from its own hype after becoming a sleeper hit in the States . It's never as deep as it tries try to be fusing issues of sexuality and identity . It's a love story with a difference but apart from the shock plot twist it's a film that would have appeared on channel 4 one Thursday night without causing a ripple
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I wish more scripts were written like this.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sergeant_Tibbs
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Continuing my quest to see all the Oscar screenplay nominees and currently knocking down the winners, I move onto The Crying Game, a film I've been intending to see for a few years now even though I knew its twist. It has a fantastic script. Very real characters and a sharp wit gives it a great edge. It's quite small scale with two distinct halves, both a slow burn to big payoffs. Forget the context and content, this is how scripts should be written. Although Stephen Rea is great, I did find myself having problems with Forest Whitaker and Jaye Davidson in their awkward and forced line deliveries to the point where I thought there was something wrong with the sound. They may have taken me out of the moment sometimes during the long stretches of emotional brooding, but it's the film's thrilling moments that makes the film such a treat. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very twisted early 90's Irish thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    delenn7
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie come out when I was 8. But I only saw it last week but still powerful to this day. Themes of trans phobia, Irish revolution on the English, kidnapping and Fergus/Jimmy caught between morals and Honor. The scorpion and the frog would fit "the title" well. Jaye Davidson was in only one other known movie Stargate as Ra the space villain which started the Staragate TV Shows. Shame he isn't acting today. The song-title of the movie the Crying game is a catchy song. Weird how Fergus "kidnaps" the "boyfriend" of transgendered "girlfriend" and becomes her "new boyfriend". Of course Jody the bad chick in the film adds zest. I recommend Breakfast in Pluto for a similar Irish LGBT film. Rated R FOR Sexuality scenes, language and violence.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Masterpiece!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'The Crying Game' is A Masterpiece in filmmaking! A Hard-Hitting, Engrossing Film, that also offers marvelous Direction, top-class Cinematography & flawless Performances! 'The Crying Game' Synopsis: A British soldier is kidnapped by IRA terrorists. He befriends one of his captors, who is drawn into the soldier's world. 'The Crying Game' explores themes of race, gender, nationality, and sexuality against the backdrop of the Irish Troubles. Neil Jordan's Oscar-Winning Screenplay is Hard-Hitting & Engrossing. Its so brave, that it doesn't let you move from your seat. Its raises questions on humanity & seeks for answers. Its amongst The Most Amazing Screenplays Ever Written! Neil Jordan's Direction, on the other-hand, is marvelous. He has executed the film with flourish. Ian Wilson's Cinematography is top-class. Each & Every Frame has Clarity! Editing is good. Art Design is appropriate. Make-Up is fabulously done. Performance-Wise: Stephen Rea is astonishing. He plays a guilt-driven man with utter brilliance. Jaye Davidson embodies the part & delivers in high regard. The Sequences Between Rea & Davidson are magnificent. Forest Whitaker is extra-ordinary. Miranda Richardson is haunting, while Adrian Dunbar is convincing. Jim Broadbent is charming. On the whole, 'The Crying Game' is not to be missed!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Twilight: The Movie of a young black man
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Blackman TheBlackMan
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have never seen such a great movie, it was STUNNING and beautiful in all aspects, I am honestly wondering why this is not top 10 yet, the scene where the girl was crying and the boy went up to her and slapped her was great. y friend thought this movie was bad at first but then he thought it was awesome, so did I. so Basically we win and you don't, we would like to buy a cheeseburger. Thank you. Also, if you prefer horror movies, watch this because I think you will get a hair of stuff if you continue to rise beyond the many colors of reduntant colors and reluctant decisions of your succinct thoughts. Even though you are the prime-minister you will enjoy this movie, I would personally give this a 9.5/10, this is really an upcoming film. Christopher Nolan, move out of the way! i have cancer please hep me.. i like it when the black man is afraid of trains and stop by die in everyone
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One Story Two Many
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This well known Film and its equally well known and at the time unexpected, explicit, and shocking scene, tries to be a dual Drama. It has a "split personality". It has both humanistic and political concerns. The double story combines uneasily and probably would have been better concentrating on the trans-looking and trans-spirited nature and the uncomfortable, but warm, relationship of the two very sensitive characters that are at the heart of this gallant effort. The opening scenes are the least affecting and the intertwining of both "soldiers" back-story commitment is uneasy, if not forced into the narrative. The best parts are some creative dialog and the "lovers" interplay. The result is a not so great film with an attraction of aspects that do move things along, but with uneven results. It is the compelling and quite different coupling that works the best and the other part seems to belong in another Film with another agenda. To geminate the two story lines appears to be the biggest failing and in the end it is very good by a half.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's all about the subtle details in "The Crying Game" (1992)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dee.reid
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Writer-director Neil Jordan's "The Crying Game" caused a huge sensation in 1992 before and after the time of its release that year. I myself have a strange history with this movie. I had a very strong idea about this film's "big plot twist" long before I actually sat down and watched it; a documentary on slasher movies also clued me in to the little detail that this film had hiding within its complex story structures. I have to say that upon having completely watched "The Crying Game" in its entirety, the "big twist" is still pretty shocking - even if it is to be expected. The film begins as an intense political thriller: IRA terrorist Fergus (Stephen Rea) is part of a plot to kidnap a black British soldier named Jody (Forest Whitaker, sporting his best British accent ever) in exchange for the freedom of several IRA members being held captive by the British military. The two strike up an unexpected, albeit tragic friendship: Jody knows that Fergus is no killer at heart, but instead extracts a promise from Fergus that in the event of his inevitable execution, he go to London to track down and protect his exotic lover Dil (Jaye Davidson). As expected, the two strike up a casual friendship that eventually blossoms into a tentative romantic relationship. And soon, even after the Big Twist, elements from Fergus's past as an IRA terrorist come back to haunt him. "The Crying Game" is a film that often explores the complexities of human nature (both the sordid histories of both Fergus and Dil come to the forefront for them both to deal with), against a backdrop of complex political intrigue, nationality, sexuality, race, and gender. These details, in addition to the subtle body language and nuances of the performers, make "The Crying Game" a complex and highly involving psychological thriller. It's a boldly acted, written, and directed little film with big-time ambitions. "The Crying Game" was undoubtedly one of the best films of 1992 and for plenty of good reason. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I just couldn't get myself to like this movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lagudafuad
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Crying game has critical acclaim but I still found it hard to rate it above 5; to me it is something that is not for everybody. The acting delivered by the trio of Forest Whitaker, Stephen Rea and Jaye Davidson is the only thing this movie runs on, a triumphant entry into a world of perfect acting is what this movie delivers from the first scene. The movie's plot is also strong enough to keep you watching if you are that interested. The surprise that Fergus got when he found out that his new love is not exactly what he think she is, is the eye opener in the movie. Getting 6 Academy Award nominations and wining one for Best Original Screenplay, The Crying Game was released in 1992 to a favorable review holding a 100% approval rating from critics in Rotten Tomatoes. This psychological thriller drama was written and directed by filmmaker Neil Jordan (who is also a novelist on the side) who was behind the 1994 movie Interview with the Vampire: The Vampire Chronicles and the 2007 movie The Brave One with Jodie Foster. Interview with the Vampire also had Stephen Rea as one of the cast with Tom Cruise and Brad Pitt. The movie went into production with the name The Soldier's Wife but the late Stanley Kubrick a good friend of Neil advised him against it, saying with a name like that people will expect a war film. The name of the movie is actually a song Dil (Jaye Davidson) sang at the club where she met Fergus (Stephen Rea). The Crying Game is a song by Boy George. The movies strong point is the plot, it thickens as the movie goes on; the plot has an IRA soldier named Fergus (Stephen Rea) and his unit, including a woman named Jude (Miranda Richardson) who was the bait to help kidnap Jody (Forest Whitaker). The IRA kidnapped Jody so as to use him as a bargain chip as they demand the release of other jailed IRA members, threatening to execute Jody if their demands are not met. While Fergus guards Jody, they develop a bond during which, Jody tells Fergus the story about the Scorpion and the Frog, which teaches the lesson that something's are natural to some people regardless of the circumstances in which they find themselves. Jody gets killed and Fergus has to keep a promise that he made to him to help take care of Dil. I won't want to rob you of the few thrills I got from the movie, but at least I can say it is not as grand as they all say, but I will let you be the judge of that. www.lagsreviews.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Prominently atmospheric, incisively humorous..."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sindre Kaspersen
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Irish screenwriter, producer and director Neil Jordan's seventh feature film which he wrote, premiered at the 49th Venice Film Festival in 1992, was screened at the 17th Toronto International Film Festival in 1992, was shot on location in England and Ireland and is a UK-Japan co- production which was produced by producer Stephen Woolley. It tells the story about an Irish Volunteer in the IRA named Fergus Clegg who whilst staying with a small group of other IRA terrorists in Belfast, Northern Ireland kidnaps an English soldier named Jody whom a woman named Jude has lured into a trap. Whilst guarding the soldier who believes that it is only a matter of time before he will be killed, Fergus becomes acquainted with him an learns about his girlfriend named Dil who works at a hair salon in the capital city of England, but as Fergus begins to appreciate Jody's company and regard him as his friend he is assigned to assassinate him by his superior named Peter. Distinctly and precisely directed by Irish filmmaker Neil Jordan, this finely tuned fictional tale which is narrated mostly from the two main characters' viewpoints, draws an intriguing and multifaceted portrayal of an Irishman who travels to London, England to honor a friend's last wish and to get away from his associations with the Irish Republican Army. While notable for it's variegated and naturalistic milieu depictions, sterling cinematography by English cinematographer Ian Wilson, production design by production designer Jim Clay and use of colors and light, this character-driven and narrative-driven story about deception, attraction and overcoming one's preconceptions where a hairdresser and singer whom has just left her boyfriend one day gets a new customer who introduces himself as a Scottish native and later shows up at the bar where she sings, depicts two interrelated and charming studies of character and contains a great score by English composer Anne Dudley. This somewhat political, conversational and eloquently romantic psychological thriller from the early 1990s which is set in Belfast, Northern Ireland and London, England during the Troubles in Northern Ireland in the late 20th century and where a man presents himself with another name than his own to a stranger he only knows from a picture, is impelled and reinforced by it's cogent narrative structure, substantial character development, subtle continuity, endearing and colorful characters, brilliant dialog, merging of themes and genres, timely use of music and remarkable acting performances by Irish actor Stephen Rea, American actor Jaye Davidson in his debut feature film role, English actress Miranda Richardson and American actor, producer and director Forest Whitaker. A prominently atmospheric, incisively humorous and memorable love-story which gained, among numerous other awards, the Alexander Korda Award for Best British Film at the 46th BAFTA Awards in 1993.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Crying Game- Good Noir Cinema (1992)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ashish sood (ashistrong@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "The Crying Game" is one of those films that you see and would like even more in retrospect. The film was huge in 1992 and earned a Best Picture nomination from the Academy, with director It is a complicated puzzle that involves an IRA (Provisional Irish Republican Army) volunteer Fergus(Stephen Rea) befriending with Dil (Jaye Davidson) girlfriend of an English soldier Jody(Forest Whitaker) whom he had kidnapped. The twists and turns of "The Crying Game" are what make the film work. The movie although has flaws in several areas, but overall ranks real high on the list of other great films of the 1990s. Director Neil Jordan creates a modern-day noir, and the film scores on both the levels of plot and character evident with the fact that he won Academy Award for Best Writing, Screenplay Written Directly for the Screen along with 5 other nominations for his movie. MY RATING: 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If It Wasn't For That Twist It Would Have Been Totally Obscure
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Theo Robertson
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A British soldier called Jody is kidnapped by the IRA and held hostage . Given the task of guarding him Fergus listens to Jody discuss his life . Showing Fergus a photograph of his girlfriend Dil and Fergus starts a strange obsession for Dil In 1992 this came and went in the blink of an eye at the British box office . Hardly surprising because the British box office appetite for Brit movies was still three or four years away . A British film in those days was basically a TV play with slightly better production values and this one is little different . When it was released in the rest of the world it became the film to see especially in America . Cynical Brits who hadn't seen the film would sneer that showing the IRA is a good light might have everything to do with it but then critics and marketing started making reference to the film's twist so much that when the film started picking up nominations at the big awards ceremonies people would jokingly ask if Jaye Davidson would be Oscar nominated as best supporting actor or best supporting actress This of course lets the cat out of the bag for everyone who hadn't seen the film . THE CRYING GAME exists mainly to set up this plot twist . If it was a conventional love story it would have headed straight to video and obscurity . Great suspension of disbelief is needed and the disbelief is a bit too difficult to suspend . Dil might look very feminine on celluloid but I can tell you in real life ladyboy wannabes are not so convincing . I remember one time in Pokhara in Nepal the town opened its gates to a ladyboy convention and I guarantee you not even Stevie Wonder would be fooled . There's a mannerism and a metaphysical aura to a transsexual impersonating a woman that fails to convince and knowing this you'd have severe doubts that Fergus would be taken in . The screenplay itself is very contrived with Jody having to become conveniently deaf which seals his fate and Fergus having to bump in to old friends That said I did find myself not exactly enjoying the film after first seeing it after a gap of nearly twenty years but respecting it more . This is certainly almost down to the hype surrounding the film on its release in America where the critics gave the impression this was the greatest film ever made . It's not but is a well acted well made drama . Forest Whittaker makes a mess of his accent which while rarely slipping in to American doesn't sound like a London accent . Stephen Rea manages to make his character likable even though he playing the long clich&eacute;d role of a " good " IRA man . Miranda Richardson who seemed to appear in every British film from the period does well enough enough to exorcise memories of her singularly awful performances as Queen Ezlibath in BLACKADDER 2 but the film quite rightly belongs to Jaye Davidson as Dil after appearing in this also gave an equally good performance in STARGATE then promptly disappeared as quickly arrived In summary THE CRYING GAME is a film that probably suffered from its own hype after becoming a sleeper hit in the States . It's never as deep as it tries try to be fusing issues of sexuality and identity . It's a love story with a difference but apart from the shock plot twist it's a film that would have appeared on channel 4 one Thursday night without causing a ripple
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I wish more scripts were written like this.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sergeant_Tibbs
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Continuing my quest to see all the Oscar screenplay nominees and currently knocking down the winners, I move onto The Crying Game, a film I've been intending to see for a few years now even though I knew its twist. It has a fantastic script. Very real characters and a sharp wit gives it a great edge. It's quite small scale with two distinct halves, both a slow burn to big payoffs. Forget the context and content, this is how scripts should be written. Although Stephen Rea is great, I did find myself having problems with Forest Whitaker and Jaye Davidson in their awkward and forced line deliveries to the point where I thought there was something wrong with the sound. They may have taken me out of the moment sometimes during the long stretches of emotional brooding, but it's the film's thrilling moments that makes the film such a treat. 8/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very twisted early 90's Irish thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    delenn7
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie come out when I was 8. But I only saw it last week but still powerful to this day. Themes of trans phobia, Irish revolution on the English, kidnapping and Fergus/Jimmy caught between morals and Honor. The scorpion and the frog would fit "the title" well. Jaye Davidson was in only one other known movie Stargate as Ra the space villain which started the Staragate TV Shows. Shame he isn't acting today. The song-title of the movie the Crying game is a catchy song. Weird how Fergus "kidnaps" the "boyfriend" of transgendered "girlfriend" and becomes her "new boyfriend". Of course Jody the bad chick in the film adds zest. I recommend Breakfast in Pluto for a similar Irish LGBT film. Rated R FOR Sexuality scenes, language and violence.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Masterpiece!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'The Crying Game' is A Masterpiece in filmmaking! A Hard-Hitting, Engrossing Film, that also offers marvelous Direction, top-class Cinematography & flawless Performances! 'The Crying Game' Synopsis: A British soldier is kidnapped by IRA terrorists. He befriends one of his captors, who is drawn into the soldier's world. 'The Crying Game' explores themes of race, gender, nationality, and sexuality against the backdrop of the Irish Troubles. Neil Jordan's Oscar-Winning Screenplay is Hard-Hitting & Engrossing. Its so brave, that it doesn't let you move from your seat. Its raises questions on humanity & seeks for answers. Its amongst The Most Amazing Screenplays Ever Written! Neil Jordan's Direction, on the other-hand, is marvelous. He has executed the film with flourish. Ian Wilson's Cinematography is top-class. Each & Every Frame has Clarity! Editing is good. Art Design is appropriate. Make-Up is fabulously done. Performance-Wise: Stephen Rea is astonishing. He plays a guilt-driven man with utter brilliance. Jaye Davidson embodies the part & delivers in high regard. The Sequences Between Rea & Davidson are magnificent. Forest Whitaker is extra-ordinary. Miranda Richardson is haunting, while Adrian Dunbar is convincing. Jim Broadbent is charming. On the whole, 'The Crying Game' is not to be missed!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Twilight: The Movie of a young black man
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Blackman TheBlackMan
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have never seen such a great movie, it was STUNNING and beautiful in all aspects, I am honestly wondering why this is not top 10 yet, the scene where the girl was crying and the boy went up to her and slapped her was great. y friend thought this movie was bad at first but then he thought it was awesome, so did I. so Basically we win and you don't, we would like to buy a cheeseburger. Thank you. Also, if you prefer horror movies, watch this because I think you will get a hair of stuff if you continue to rise beyond the many colors of reduntant colors and reluctant decisions of your succinct thoughts. Even though you are the prime-minister you will enjoy this movie, I would personally give this a 9.5/10, this is really an upcoming film. Christopher Nolan, move out of the way! i have cancer please hep me.. i like it when the black man is afraid of trains and stop by die in everyone
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One Story Two Many
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This well known Film and its equally well known and at the time unexpected, explicit, and shocking scene, tries to be a dual Drama. It has a "split personality". It has both humanistic and political concerns. The double story combines uneasily and probably would have been better concentrating on the trans-looking and trans-spirited nature and the uncomfortable, but warm, relationship of the two very sensitive characters that are at the heart of this gallant effort. The opening scenes are the least affecting and the intertwining of both "soldiers" back-story commitment is uneasy, if not forced into the narrative. The best parts are some creative dialog and the "lovers" interplay. The result is a not so great film with an attraction of aspects that do move things along, but with uneven results. It is the compelling and quite different coupling that works the best and the other part seems to belong in another Film with another agenda. To geminate the two story lines appears to be the biggest failing and in the end it is very good by a half.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's all about the subtle details in "The Crying Game" (1992)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dee.reid
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Writer-director Neil Jordan's "The Crying Game" caused a huge sensation in 1992 before and after the time of its release that year. I myself have a strange history with this movie. I had a very strong idea about this film's "big plot twist" long before I actually sat down and watched it; a documentary on slasher movies also clued me in to the little detail that this film had hiding within its complex story structures. I have to say that upon having completely watched "The Crying Game" in its entirety, the "big twist" is still pretty shocking - even if it is to be expected. The film begins as an intense political thriller: IRA terrorist Fergus (Stephen Rea) is part of a plot to kidnap a black British soldier named Jody (Forest Whitaker, sporting his best British accent ever) in exchange for the freedom of several IRA members being held captive by the British military. The two strike up an unexpected, albeit tragic friendship: Jody knows that Fergus is no killer at heart, but instead extracts a promise from Fergus that in the event of his inevitable execution, he go to London to track down and protect his exotic lover Dil (Jaye Davidson). As expected, the two strike up a casual friendship that eventually blossoms into a tentative romantic relationship. And soon, even after the Big Twist, elements from Fergus's past as an IRA terrorist come back to haunt him. "The Crying Game" is a film that often explores the complexities of human nature (both the sordid histories of both Fergus and Dil come to the forefront for them both to deal with), against a backdrop of complex political intrigue, nationality, sexuality, race, and gender. These details, in addition to the subtle body language and nuances of the performers, make "The Crying Game" a complex and highly involving psychological thriller. It's a boldly acted, written, and directed little film with big-time ambitions. "The Crying Game" was undoubtedly one of the best films of 1992 and for plenty of good reason. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I just couldn't get myself to like this movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lagudafuad
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Crying game has critical acclaim but I still found it hard to rate it above 5; to me it is something that is not for everybody. The acting delivered by the trio of Forest Whitaker, Stephen Rea and Jaye Davidson is the only thing this movie runs on, a triumphant entry into a world of perfect acting is what this movie delivers from the first scene. The movie's plot is also strong enough to keep you watching if you are that interested. The surprise that Fergus got when he found out that his new love is not exactly what he think she is, is the eye opener in the movie. Getting 6 Academy Award nominations and wining one for Best Original Screenplay, The Crying Game was released in 1992 to a favorable review holding a 100% approval rating from critics in Rotten Tomatoes. This psychological thriller drama was written and directed by filmmaker Neil Jordan (who is also a novelist on the side) who was behind the 1994 movie Interview with the Vampire: The Vampire Chronicles and the 2007 movie The Brave One with Jodie Foster. Interview with the Vampire also had Stephen Rea as one of the cast with Tom Cruise and Brad Pitt. The movie went into production with the name The Soldier's Wife but the late Stanley Kubrick a good friend of Neil advised him against it, saying with a name like that people will expect a war film. The name of the movie is actually a song Dil (Jaye Davidson) sang at the club where she met Fergus (Stephen Rea). The Crying Game is a song by Boy George. The movies strong point is the plot, it thickens as the movie goes on; the plot has an IRA soldier named Fergus (Stephen Rea) and his unit, including a woman named Jude (Miranda Richardson) who was the bait to help kidnap Jody (Forest Whitaker). The IRA kidnapped Jody so as to use him as a bargain chip as they demand the release of other jailed IRA members, threatening to execute Jody if their demands are not met. While Fergus guards Jody, they develop a bond during which, Jody tells Fergus the story about the Scorpion and the Frog, which teaches the lesson that something's are natural to some people regardless of the circumstances in which they find themselves. Jody gets killed and Fergus has to keep a promise that he made to him to help take care of Dil. I won't want to rob you of the few thrills I got from the movie, but at least I can say it is not as grand as they all say, but I will let you be the judge of that. www.lagsreviews.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
