<filme>
 <id>
  636
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0082340
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1981
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Fuga de Nova York
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  7.2
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  In 1997, when the US President crashes into Manhattan, now a giant max. security prison, a convicted bank robber is sent in for a rescue.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  In the future, crime is out of control and New York City is a maximum security prison. Grabbing a bargaining chip right out of the air, convicts bring down the President's plane in bad old Gotham. Gruff Snake Plissken, a one-eyed lone warrior new to prison life, is coerced into bringing the President, and his cargo, out of this land of undesirables.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Action
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Sci-Fi
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   snake
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   rescue
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   prison
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   escape
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   new york city
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   John Carpenter
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   John Carpenter
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Nick Castle
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Kurt Russell
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Lee Van Cleef
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Ernest Borgnine
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sci-Punk Noir
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of the Director's better Movies. It is a completely Cynical and Dark atmosphere that relays its intent on the Audience with an effectiveness that only a talented B-Movie Director could concoct. The ability to take Comic-Book Stories and Characters, dress them up, and announce the whole thing as gritty, sleazy Fun. Style personified. The Film is oozing with Style. From the Haunting, but typical, thumping of the Synthesizer, not one scene in the Daylight (Dawn at best), Thrift Store Chic Costumes, a Larger than Life Anti-Hero, and assorted Street Dregs, mixed with the Classical Chestnut "do this thing and you are Pardoned", it all comes together with simplistic, but Colorful Sets and Graphics and bit of the ol' Ultraviolence. It is Sci-Punk Noir and the Talented Creators both in front of and behind the Camera make for an Amalgamated Apocalyptic Fan Favorite Film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cerebral....sort of like an episode of "Masterpiece Theatre".
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Okay, I'll admit it...my summary is completely ridiculous! "Escape From New York" is anything but cerebral or sophisticated. Instead, it's a rather absurd little sci-fi film that actually manages to be awfully entertaining despite being utterly ridiculous. Much of this is because the film takes itself so very seriously--and this heightens the campy atmosphere and makes the film a lot of fun. This John Carpenter film is set in the near future. Lawlessness has taken hold until society has come up with a strange solution--to turn Manhattan Island into a giant prison. This 'prison' is really just a dumping ground--a dumping ground where there are no guards and no rules--just a weird self-created society of scum. When a terrorist hijacks Air Force One and crashes it into this city, the President is able to use an escape pod--but he lands in the middle of this hellish city. For some odd reason, instead of sending in the Marines or the Navy Seals, they send in one man--'Snake' Plissken (Kurt Russell). Plissken is ridiculously overplayed by Russell--and that adds to the fun. I am pretty sure he didn't take himself very seriously and the viewer certainly can't! Plissken is sort of like Rambo and Clint Eastwood (Russell REALLY had the Eastwood voice down pat)--but even more indestructible! Now Plissken is NOT the hero type. He himself is a convicted criminal but he's also a war hero. To convince him to take the assignment, they not only promise him his freedom but his life. You see, this is because they implanted a nanoprobe into him that will kill him if the assignment isn't completed in 24 hours! Can he do it? What do you think? As I said above, Plissken is played in such an overly serious and over-the-top manner that the film is really a hoot to watch. Also, the film is very original even if it is silly. A few other things I loved were the faux computer graphics (done amazingly well considering everything--see the IMDb trivia for more on this), the scene towards the end of the President having his revenge on 'The Duke' and the incredible soundtrack (by Carpenter himself). All in all, a dumb but incredibly cool guilty pleasure. And sometimes you just have to let your brain relax and watch something mindlessly fun.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Future Is Now Past.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    John Carpenter directed this exciting action yarn that stars Kurt Russell(excellent performance) as Snake Plissken, a wanted criminal and amoral mercenary(think a modern "Man With No Name") that is captured by authorities, but offered a pardon if he will undertake an important mission: rescue the president, who has crash-landed Air Force One into the penal colony of "futuristic"(1997) Manhattan, which has been sealed off from the rest of the country after the crime rate skyrockets. The president(played by Donald Pleasance) is being held by a powerful gang as a bargaining ploy, and Snake must rescue him, and retrieve an important document related to a speech he was going to give. After gliding in, he has a limited amount of time to find the president, before a poison kills him(he will be given the antidote upon successful completion of the rescue.) Well-designed and entertaining film has a good cast(Adrienne Barbeau, Ernest Borgnine, and Lee Van Cleef among them). Well worth watching, and a lot of fun.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    John Carpenter Classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SnoopyStyle
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    John Carpenter creates one of the most original movie and an iconic fantasy world. 'Escape from New York' is a cult classic. It's the future 1997, Manhattan has been turned into a maximum security prison. The President had to do an emergency ejection, but lands inside the prison. Snake Plissken (Kurt Russell) is coerced into bringing the President and his cargo out. Once inside, Snake gets help from Cabbie (Ernest Borgnine), and Maggie (Adrienne Barbeau). This was about the beginning of the end of the '70s crime ridden NY paranoia. The style is no longer realism but rather surreal. It is the best of campy adventure. Kurt Russell creates an iconic character.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "There was an accident. About an hour ago, a small jet went down inside New York City. The President was on board." "President of what?"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Al_The_Strange
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In this dark dystopian sci-fi adventure, ultimate tough guy Snake Plissken is sent on a mission to enter New York, a city now turned into the world's largest penitentiary with a huge retaining wall, to rescue the President from a group of the roughest and most violent criminals imaginable. Sounds awesome, right? Escape From New York has all the right elements to make something awesome. The premise, the characters, the settings, and the overall essence of the film are indeed awesome. However, in the hands of John Carpenter, the film moves at a slow and brooding pace. It's the same creepy, methodic style that makes his other movies - Halloween, The Fog, Christine, The Thing  so effective. For this movie, I never felt that it works as well as it should: the film creeps along so much in the dark that all sense of action and excitement is dampened. When action does hit  a few pedestrian scenes where bad guys throw rocks and sticks, beat and rape a few people, throw Snake into a death match arena, and then finally chase the heroes across a mined bridge  it's all pretty lightweight, lacking in particularly deep impact or thrills. I can't help but to think that, in the hands of guys like John McTiernan or Paul Verhoeven, Escape From NY could be the awesomest, pulpiest, and most badass movie out there. As it is, it's mildly cool, but it never fully capitalizes off of its own potential. The story this film tells is pretty neat, filled with some far-out sci-fi concepts (ideas that would be replicated in plenty of other films, most blatant of which is Doomdsay). The actual plot is pretty standard; it gives you just enough to the story and characters to understand what's going on and to kick off the big adventure, but there's not much depth or exploration offered beyond the surface-level expositions. Characters are pretty flat and lifeless all around, except for Snake Plissken, who is the epitome of cool, with his moody, dangerous, devil-may-care attitude. His character is not only a great antihero, but also a massive influence on other popular characters (remember Solid Snake from Metal Gear Solid?). The only problem is, you never really learn much about Snake beyond that surface level; he is as one-dimensional as everybody else. There are moments where I also wonder if this movie tries to pick at some social themes regarding American society and culture; after all, this is one of America's biggest and most popular cities turned into a total hellhole, and it's the American President caught up in the middle of the chaos. There are times when it seems like the film is underscoring the ugly undercurrent of social corruption and decay, but these themes never really materialize into anything tangible. This film uses rather pedestrian photography, in a manner not much different than Halloween. The camera moves and angles are interesting at times, but the shots are so long that they appear pretty indistinctive. Lighting is very dark throughout, for appropriate effect. Editing is good. Acting is generally okay: Kurt Russell is the man throughout, opposite Lee Van Cleef and Isaac Hayes, who also try their best to be tough. Ernest Borgnine provides a little bit of goofiness to the mix, and Adrienne Barbeau adds a little bit of sex appeal. Harry Dean Stanton isn't given much to do, and his role is ultimately forgettable. And, Donald Pleasence is pretty much himself. Writing is okay; there are a few amusing lines. This movie uses sets, props, and costumes that show some limitations, but get the job done very well. John Carpenter's music score is pretty darn cool. Escape From New York has its share of coolness, but it could be cooler yet. It's not terribly exciting, but it is mildly interesting and mildly satisfying. Given its popularity, the film is a must-see for fans of dark and violent dystopian sci-fi. 3.5/5 (Entertainment: Pretty Good | Story: Average | Film: Pretty Good)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Worst Piece of CRAP I've seen in years
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FriscoJoe
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Really? A wall around Manhattan island? No police force and no fire department yet the place hasn't burned down? The whole premise is just plain STUPID. They land a glider on the roof of one of the World Trade Center towers. I worked in the WTC. What happened to the observation deck on top? Hmmmm? Compared to the absolutely moronic plot, though, the WTC flaws are forgivable. Notice that the female leads all have spotless, perfectly made-up faces and hair. Spoiler... sorta'... if you're waiting for Adrienne Barbeau's boobs to "escape", don't hold your breath: they don't. This is a ONE star movie, folks. It belongs in the hall of fame of worst movies ever made, just a shade above Ed Wood's D-Grade movies, but not nearly as unintentionally funny.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Timeless Cult Adventure of the Badass Anti-Hero Snake Plissken
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Claudio Carvalho
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In 1997, Manhattan has been transformed in the New York Maximum Security Penitentiary, where criminals are sent in life sentence. When the Air Force One crashes in Manhattan with the president of the USA (Donald Pleasence) that is traveling to a summit with other leaders, the prison dean Hauk (Lee Van Cleef) proposes a deal to the convicted one-eyed bank robber Snake Plissken (Kurt Russell). If he rescues the president and his tape in less than 23 hours, he would be granted pardon. In order to guarantee full commitment of Snake Plissken, Hauk lures him and injects a lethal capsule in his blood that will dissolve in the scheduled time. Snake Plissken uses a small plane to land one the roof of the World Trade Center. Soon he finds that the tracking device was removed from the president. When he meets the taxi driver Cabbie (Ernest Borgnine), he learns that the warlord The Duke (Isaac Hayes) has captured the president. Now Snake Plissken has to team-up with his former partner Brain (Harry Dean Stanton), who has double-crossed him in the past, and his squeeze Maggie (Adrienne Barbeau) to rescue the president and save his own life. "Escape from New York" is the timeless cult adventure of the badass one- eyed anti-hero Snake Plissken by John Carpenter. It is amazing how this movie has not aged and even after watching it so many times, I do not get tired of it. Kurt Russell has a fantastic shape and is perfect in the role of the tough Snake Plissken. The president dressed with blonde wig and with cosmetics and his rage in the end against The Duke seems to indicate that something else had happened to him besides losing his thumb. The movie has a dream cast and also a wonderful music score. My vote is ten. Title (Brazi): "Fuga de Nova York" ("Escape from New York")
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Classic Old Fashioned Cinematic Look At The Future
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Theo Robertson
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In 1988 America experiences a surge in criminal violence that leads to Manhatten being turned in to one massive prison . In 1997 Airforce One is hijacked and crashes in to the prison . Newly convicted prisoner Snake Plissken is given a be given deal - if he can rescue the president he'll be given an amnesty but only has 22 hours to do so . If the mission fails the world may very well be heading towards World War 3 Earlier tonight I watched AEON FLUX , a film that some could claim is style over substance . I certainly didn't see any substance in that film and if you saw any style let me know what scene it appeared in . ESCAPE FROM NY is entirely different from FLUX . It's directed by John Carpenter who also did the electronic score and opened to moderate business on its released and later became a cult film . It's easy to see why . The camera work might be relatively static but this with hindsight compared to film making in the 21st century is a blessing since the visuals don't overwhelm the storytelling The story itself from real life events that over took this fictional scenario where in 1997 the cold war looks like hotting up big time but I doubt if Mikhail Gorbachev was sitting down at a table thinking ending the cold war would invalidate John Carpenter's vision of the future but that said a Marxist Leninist spouting rhetoric about workers and imperialist pigs does date the film Thankfully the film isn't really interested in politics and concentrates on keeping the audience excited which is does a good job at as Snake finds constant barriers in his way as he tries to find the missing president knowing that the clock is ticking away . Some of the action scenes aren't entirely plausible such as a machine pistol having an unrealistic capacity and despite being a not unlikable anti-hero in the vein of New Hollywood Kurt Russell plays Snake Plissken far too much like Clint Eastwood would have . Has anyone watched Russell's performance and not mentioned Eastwood ? Regardless of this ESCAPE FROM NY is a very enjoyable action thriller set in the future
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good in its own time, but now it feels outdated...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    luger7
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I can understand why a lot of fellows say this is a one of the best action movies, maybe because they watched this when they were younger or kids and it made a good impression on their minds. Well I remember watching this movie when I was a kid, and yes of course I enjoyed it, but never like other action movies I have in high regard like Predator, Commando or Aliens. So I watched Escape From New York again, and sorry dear fans but this is a really boring movie. The plot and the background of the story are not bad, a lot of potential here, but the development and the "action" is just slow and dry. Snake is a good character, i really think so, but this movie didn't age very well.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not Carpenters best work...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Prolox
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    KURT RUSSELL stars as a long thought dead SNAKE PLISSKEN, a former war hero turned notorious outlaw, who is recruited by local law enforcement to help rescue the president of the United States, who's plane has crashed & is trapped behind the walls of New York City in the year 1997, which has now been converted into a maximum security prison, where society's worst nightmares run amok. Implamented with an explosive device that will ignite if he tries to escape from his mission & armed with some nifty gadgets. Snake attempts to keep himself alive & from danger, as he looks for the man's whereabouts, only to discover the President is being held captive by the criminal ruler of New York's prison, a cold hearted criminal played by ISAAC HAYES. When Snake winds up being captured, he is forced to fight for his life against the well armed thugs that work for the main villain & escape with the president, before his time runs out. ESCAPE FROM NEW YORK is hailed as a classic among genre fans, with some even saying it's JOHN CARPENTER'S best work. After hearing so much praise about the film, I just had to see it, mainly because I'm a big fan of Carpenter's work, that & because the film carries a pretty good bevy of talent both in front & behind the screen. Unfortunately after seeing it twice, I was kind of left scratching my head, trying to figure out what everyone is so crazy about the film, because in actuality there really isn't all that much to it. The reason I saw it twice is because I thought I might have missed something or misunderstood it, but sadly all to no avail. Director Carpenter brought along his HALLOWEEN crew, Director of Photography DEAN CUNDEY, Producer DEBRA HILL, Michael Myers himself NICK CASTLE (Who serves as co-writer) Composer ALAN HOWARTH, BARRY BERNARDI (THE FOG) & even JAWS Production designer JOE ALVES & LARRY FRANCO (THE THING/THEY LIVE/ PRINCE OF DARKNESS) JAMES CAMERON (TITANIC) as effect supervisor) & then there's the acting troupe supporting the film, such as Carpenter's then wife, ADRIENNE BARBEAU, HARRY DEAN STANTON, LEE VAN CLEEF & ISAAC HAYES, DONALD PLESEANCE, BUCK FLOWER & KURT RUSSELL as the hero, which is why the film in my eyes, should have turned out a lot better than it did. ESCAPE FROM NEW YORK is billed as a Sci-fi/action film, but there's precious little action to be had throughout the films running time & it's clear Carpenter had much higher aspirations for the film then what he was able to pull off. The film passes the idea off that Manhatten has been converted to a maximum security prison, but yet there's no more than a few small crowds of criminals that could so easily have fit into a normal prison. It's very clear that Carpenter envisioned a much more fuller Manhattan, full of criminals, but that vision is hamstrung by his decent, but still limited budget. Joe Alves was obviously hamstrung by the films tight 7 million dollar budget as well, since he doesn't do much except strewn some rubble around here & there (where was the crumbled statue of Liberty on the box art?) The films plot does indeed show some promise & at the beginning looks to be set to become a very tight action sci-fi thriller, the best of it's kind. But once Plissken is dropped into New York, Carpenter drops the ball. The remainder of the films running time merely shows Russell roaming the streets, visiting old allies, meeting a kind hearted cabbie & visiting abandon buildings & is never engaged in any real fights against scores of criminals, not high powered shoot outs, fist fights, explosions, nothing. Issac Hayes is a good actor, but is hardly anything you would call menacing as the main villain & is unable to pull off that certain sense of dread & intimidation that most action movie villains have & the same goes for the criminals who are paper thin & hardly anything terrifying or even amusing. The acting is fairly decent by all involved...all involved of course with the exception of Kurt Russell. Kurt clearly is playing Snake as a sort of futuristic CLINT EASTWOOD style hero, but this merely just makes Snake bland & hardly makes him an interesting hero. Even worse there's almost no action to speak of minus a very poorly choreographed fight scened where Russell is forced to fend for himself against a brute of a man, in a crudely made wrestling ring, while surrounded by the crazy gangs & a poorly done car chase. In the end, I so desperately wanted to include myself in the millions of fans who love this film. I wanted to embrace it & at the same time, add it as one of Carpenters best work, but I just couldn't. I just couldn't get into the film & there were just to many missed opportunities on hand here that could have made the film really special. JOHN CARPENTER's direction was just as good as it's always been here, but I just felt let down by this movie. Maybe I was just expecting to much out of it, is why I wound up being let down, after hearing about the films hype for many years, I just anticipated a much better film than what I wound up with. In fact I've seen much better films made, that fans were split on. In the end, I'm in the minority of people left scratching my head & wondering what all the fuss was over. Maybe if I would have seen the film when I was younger I would have had different feelings over it, but as it is, ESCAPE FROM NEW YORK just didn't do it for me. It's merely a film that is just hardly above mediocrity. Followed by ESCAPE FROM L.A. **1/2 stars
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sci-Punk Noir
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of the Director's better Movies. It is a completely Cynical and Dark atmosphere that relays its intent on the Audience with an effectiveness that only a talented B-Movie Director could concoct. The ability to take Comic-Book Stories and Characters, dress them up, and announce the whole thing as gritty, sleazy Fun. Style personified. The Film is oozing with Style. From the Haunting, but typical, thumping of the Synthesizer, not one scene in the Daylight (Dawn at best), Thrift Store Chic Costumes, a Larger than Life Anti-Hero, and assorted Street Dregs, mixed with the Classical Chestnut "do this thing and you are Pardoned", it all comes together with simplistic, but Colorful Sets and Graphics and bit of the ol' Ultraviolence. It is Sci-Punk Noir and the Talented Creators both in front of and behind the Camera make for an Amalgamated Apocalyptic Fan Favorite Film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cerebral....sort of like an episode of "Masterpiece Theatre".
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Okay, I'll admit it...my summary is completely ridiculous! "Escape From New York" is anything but cerebral or sophisticated. Instead, it's a rather absurd little sci-fi film that actually manages to be awfully entertaining despite being utterly ridiculous. Much of this is because the film takes itself so very seriously--and this heightens the campy atmosphere and makes the film a lot of fun. This John Carpenter film is set in the near future. Lawlessness has taken hold until society has come up with a strange solution--to turn Manhattan Island into a giant prison. This 'prison' is really just a dumping ground--a dumping ground where there are no guards and no rules--just a weird self-created society of scum. When a terrorist hijacks Air Force One and crashes it into this city, the President is able to use an escape pod--but he lands in the middle of this hellish city. For some odd reason, instead of sending in the Marines or the Navy Seals, they send in one man--'Snake' Plissken (Kurt Russell). Plissken is ridiculously overplayed by Russell--and that adds to the fun. I am pretty sure he didn't take himself very seriously and the viewer certainly can't! Plissken is sort of like Rambo and Clint Eastwood (Russell REALLY had the Eastwood voice down pat)--but even more indestructible! Now Plissken is NOT the hero type. He himself is a convicted criminal but he's also a war hero. To convince him to take the assignment, they not only promise him his freedom but his life. You see, this is because they implanted a nanoprobe into him that will kill him if the assignment isn't completed in 24 hours! Can he do it? What do you think? As I said above, Plissken is played in such an overly serious and over-the-top manner that the film is really a hoot to watch. Also, the film is very original even if it is silly. A few other things I loved were the faux computer graphics (done amazingly well considering everything--see the IMDb trivia for more on this), the scene towards the end of the President having his revenge on 'The Duke' and the incredible soundtrack (by Carpenter himself). All in all, a dumb but incredibly cool guilty pleasure. And sometimes you just have to let your brain relax and watch something mindlessly fun.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Future Is Now Past.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    John Carpenter directed this exciting action yarn that stars Kurt Russell(excellent performance) as Snake Plissken, a wanted criminal and amoral mercenary(think a modern "Man With No Name") that is captured by authorities, but offered a pardon if he will undertake an important mission: rescue the president, who has crash-landed Air Force One into the penal colony of "futuristic"(1997) Manhattan, which has been sealed off from the rest of the country after the crime rate skyrockets. The president(played by Donald Pleasance) is being held by a powerful gang as a bargaining ploy, and Snake must rescue him, and retrieve an important document related to a speech he was going to give. After gliding in, he has a limited amount of time to find the president, before a poison kills him(he will be given the antidote upon successful completion of the rescue.) Well-designed and entertaining film has a good cast(Adrienne Barbeau, Ernest Borgnine, and Lee Van Cleef among them). Well worth watching, and a lot of fun.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    John Carpenter Classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SnoopyStyle
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    John Carpenter creates one of the most original movie and an iconic fantasy world. 'Escape from New York' is a cult classic. It's the future 1997, Manhattan has been turned into a maximum security prison. The President had to do an emergency ejection, but lands inside the prison. Snake Plissken (Kurt Russell) is coerced into bringing the President and his cargo out. Once inside, Snake gets help from Cabbie (Ernest Borgnine), and Maggie (Adrienne Barbeau). This was about the beginning of the end of the '70s crime ridden NY paranoia. The style is no longer realism but rather surreal. It is the best of campy adventure. Kurt Russell creates an iconic character.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "There was an accident. About an hour ago, a small jet went down inside New York City. The President was on board." "President of what?"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Al_The_Strange
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In this dark dystopian sci-fi adventure, ultimate tough guy Snake Plissken is sent on a mission to enter New York, a city now turned into the world's largest penitentiary with a huge retaining wall, to rescue the President from a group of the roughest and most violent criminals imaginable. Sounds awesome, right? Escape From New York has all the right elements to make something awesome. The premise, the characters, the settings, and the overall essence of the film are indeed awesome. However, in the hands of John Carpenter, the film moves at a slow and brooding pace. It's the same creepy, methodic style that makes his other movies - Halloween, The Fog, Christine, The Thing  so effective. For this movie, I never felt that it works as well as it should: the film creeps along so much in the dark that all sense of action and excitement is dampened. When action does hit  a few pedestrian scenes where bad guys throw rocks and sticks, beat and rape a few people, throw Snake into a death match arena, and then finally chase the heroes across a mined bridge  it's all pretty lightweight, lacking in particularly deep impact or thrills. I can't help but to think that, in the hands of guys like John McTiernan or Paul Verhoeven, Escape From NY could be the awesomest, pulpiest, and most badass movie out there. As it is, it's mildly cool, but it never fully capitalizes off of its own potential. The story this film tells is pretty neat, filled with some far-out sci-fi concepts (ideas that would be replicated in plenty of other films, most blatant of which is Doomdsay). The actual plot is pretty standard; it gives you just enough to the story and characters to understand what's going on and to kick off the big adventure, but there's not much depth or exploration offered beyond the surface-level expositions. Characters are pretty flat and lifeless all around, except for Snake Plissken, who is the epitome of cool, with his moody, dangerous, devil-may-care attitude. His character is not only a great antihero, but also a massive influence on other popular characters (remember Solid Snake from Metal Gear Solid?). The only problem is, you never really learn much about Snake beyond that surface level; he is as one-dimensional as everybody else. There are moments where I also wonder if this movie tries to pick at some social themes regarding American society and culture; after all, this is one of America's biggest and most popular cities turned into a total hellhole, and it's the American President caught up in the middle of the chaos. There are times when it seems like the film is underscoring the ugly undercurrent of social corruption and decay, but these themes never really materialize into anything tangible. This film uses rather pedestrian photography, in a manner not much different than Halloween. The camera moves and angles are interesting at times, but the shots are so long that they appear pretty indistinctive. Lighting is very dark throughout, for appropriate effect. Editing is good. Acting is generally okay: Kurt Russell is the man throughout, opposite Lee Van Cleef and Isaac Hayes, who also try their best to be tough. Ernest Borgnine provides a little bit of goofiness to the mix, and Adrienne Barbeau adds a little bit of sex appeal. Harry Dean Stanton isn't given much to do, and his role is ultimately forgettable. And, Donald Pleasence is pretty much himself. Writing is okay; there are a few amusing lines. This movie uses sets, props, and costumes that show some limitations, but get the job done very well. John Carpenter's music score is pretty darn cool. Escape From New York has its share of coolness, but it could be cooler yet. It's not terribly exciting, but it is mildly interesting and mildly satisfying. Given its popularity, the film is a must-see for fans of dark and violent dystopian sci-fi. 3.5/5 (Entertainment: Pretty Good | Story: Average | Film: Pretty Good)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Worst Piece of CRAP I've seen in years
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FriscoJoe
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Really? A wall around Manhattan island? No police force and no fire department yet the place hasn't burned down? The whole premise is just plain STUPID. They land a glider on the roof of one of the World Trade Center towers. I worked in the WTC. What happened to the observation deck on top? Hmmmm? Compared to the absolutely moronic plot, though, the WTC flaws are forgivable. Notice that the female leads all have spotless, perfectly made-up faces and hair. Spoiler... sorta'... if you're waiting for Adrienne Barbeau's boobs to "escape", don't hold your breath: they don't. This is a ONE star movie, folks. It belongs in the hall of fame of worst movies ever made, just a shade above Ed Wood's D-Grade movies, but not nearly as unintentionally funny.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Timeless Cult Adventure of the Badass Anti-Hero Snake Plissken
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Claudio Carvalho
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In 1997, Manhattan has been transformed in the New York Maximum Security Penitentiary, where criminals are sent in life sentence. When the Air Force One crashes in Manhattan with the president of the USA (Donald Pleasence) that is traveling to a summit with other leaders, the prison dean Hauk (Lee Van Cleef) proposes a deal to the convicted one-eyed bank robber Snake Plissken (Kurt Russell). If he rescues the president and his tape in less than 23 hours, he would be granted pardon. In order to guarantee full commitment of Snake Plissken, Hauk lures him and injects a lethal capsule in his blood that will dissolve in the scheduled time. Snake Plissken uses a small plane to land one the roof of the World Trade Center. Soon he finds that the tracking device was removed from the president. When he meets the taxi driver Cabbie (Ernest Borgnine), he learns that the warlord The Duke (Isaac Hayes) has captured the president. Now Snake Plissken has to team-up with his former partner Brain (Harry Dean Stanton), who has double-crossed him in the past, and his squeeze Maggie (Adrienne Barbeau) to rescue the president and save his own life. "Escape from New York" is the timeless cult adventure of the badass one- eyed anti-hero Snake Plissken by John Carpenter. It is amazing how this movie has not aged and even after watching it so many times, I do not get tired of it. Kurt Russell has a fantastic shape and is perfect in the role of the tough Snake Plissken. The president dressed with blonde wig and with cosmetics and his rage in the end against The Duke seems to indicate that something else had happened to him besides losing his thumb. The movie has a dream cast and also a wonderful music score. My vote is ten. Title (Brazi): "Fuga de Nova York" ("Escape from New York")
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Classic Old Fashioned Cinematic Look At The Future
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Theo Robertson
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In 1988 America experiences a surge in criminal violence that leads to Manhatten being turned in to one massive prison . In 1997 Airforce One is hijacked and crashes in to the prison . Newly convicted prisoner Snake Plissken is given a be given deal - if he can rescue the president he'll be given an amnesty but only has 22 hours to do so . If the mission fails the world may very well be heading towards World War 3 Earlier tonight I watched AEON FLUX , a film that some could claim is style over substance . I certainly didn't see any substance in that film and if you saw any style let me know what scene it appeared in . ESCAPE FROM NY is entirely different from FLUX . It's directed by John Carpenter who also did the electronic score and opened to moderate business on its released and later became a cult film . It's easy to see why . The camera work might be relatively static but this with hindsight compared to film making in the 21st century is a blessing since the visuals don't overwhelm the storytelling The story itself from real life events that over took this fictional scenario where in 1997 the cold war looks like hotting up big time but I doubt if Mikhail Gorbachev was sitting down at a table thinking ending the cold war would invalidate John Carpenter's vision of the future but that said a Marxist Leninist spouting rhetoric about workers and imperialist pigs does date the film Thankfully the film isn't really interested in politics and concentrates on keeping the audience excited which is does a good job at as Snake finds constant barriers in his way as he tries to find the missing president knowing that the clock is ticking away . Some of the action scenes aren't entirely plausible such as a machine pistol having an unrealistic capacity and despite being a not unlikable anti-hero in the vein of New Hollywood Kurt Russell plays Snake Plissken far too much like Clint Eastwood would have . Has anyone watched Russell's performance and not mentioned Eastwood ? Regardless of this ESCAPE FROM NY is a very enjoyable action thriller set in the future
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good in its own time, but now it feels outdated...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    luger7
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I can understand why a lot of fellows say this is a one of the best action movies, maybe because they watched this when they were younger or kids and it made a good impression on their minds. Well I remember watching this movie when I was a kid, and yes of course I enjoyed it, but never like other action movies I have in high regard like Predator, Commando or Aliens. So I watched Escape From New York again, and sorry dear fans but this is a really boring movie. The plot and the background of the story are not bad, a lot of potential here, but the development and the "action" is just slow and dry. Snake is a good character, i really think so, but this movie didn't age very well.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not Carpenters best work...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Prolox
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    KURT RUSSELL stars as a long thought dead SNAKE PLISSKEN, a former war hero turned notorious outlaw, who is recruited by local law enforcement to help rescue the president of the United States, who's plane has crashed & is trapped behind the walls of New York City in the year 1997, which has now been converted into a maximum security prison, where society's worst nightmares run amok. Implamented with an explosive device that will ignite if he tries to escape from his mission & armed with some nifty gadgets. Snake attempts to keep himself alive & from danger, as he looks for the man's whereabouts, only to discover the President is being held captive by the criminal ruler of New York's prison, a cold hearted criminal played by ISAAC HAYES. When Snake winds up being captured, he is forced to fight for his life against the well armed thugs that work for the main villain & escape with the president, before his time runs out. ESCAPE FROM NEW YORK is hailed as a classic among genre fans, with some even saying it's JOHN CARPENTER'S best work. After hearing so much praise about the film, I just had to see it, mainly because I'm a big fan of Carpenter's work, that & because the film carries a pretty good bevy of talent both in front & behind the screen. Unfortunately after seeing it twice, I was kind of left scratching my head, trying to figure out what everyone is so crazy about the film, because in actuality there really isn't all that much to it. The reason I saw it twice is because I thought I might have missed something or misunderstood it, but sadly all to no avail. Director Carpenter brought along his HALLOWEEN crew, Director of Photography DEAN CUNDEY, Producer DEBRA HILL, Michael Myers himself NICK CASTLE (Who serves as co-writer) Composer ALAN HOWARTH, BARRY BERNARDI (THE FOG) & even JAWS Production designer JOE ALVES & LARRY FRANCO (THE THING/THEY LIVE/ PRINCE OF DARKNESS) JAMES CAMERON (TITANIC) as effect supervisor) & then there's the acting troupe supporting the film, such as Carpenter's then wife, ADRIENNE BARBEAU, HARRY DEAN STANTON, LEE VAN CLEEF & ISAAC HAYES, DONALD PLESEANCE, BUCK FLOWER & KURT RUSSELL as the hero, which is why the film in my eyes, should have turned out a lot better than it did. ESCAPE FROM NEW YORK is billed as a Sci-fi/action film, but there's precious little action to be had throughout the films running time & it's clear Carpenter had much higher aspirations for the film then what he was able to pull off. The film passes the idea off that Manhatten has been converted to a maximum security prison, but yet there's no more than a few small crowds of criminals that could so easily have fit into a normal prison. It's very clear that Carpenter envisioned a much more fuller Manhattan, full of criminals, but that vision is hamstrung by his decent, but still limited budget. Joe Alves was obviously hamstrung by the films tight 7 million dollar budget as well, since he doesn't do much except strewn some rubble around here & there (where was the crumbled statue of Liberty on the box art?) The films plot does indeed show some promise & at the beginning looks to be set to become a very tight action sci-fi thriller, the best of it's kind. But once Plissken is dropped into New York, Carpenter drops the ball. The remainder of the films running time merely shows Russell roaming the streets, visiting old allies, meeting a kind hearted cabbie & visiting abandon buildings & is never engaged in any real fights against scores of criminals, not high powered shoot outs, fist fights, explosions, nothing. Issac Hayes is a good actor, but is hardly anything you would call menacing as the main villain & is unable to pull off that certain sense of dread & intimidation that most action movie villains have & the same goes for the criminals who are paper thin & hardly anything terrifying or even amusing. The acting is fairly decent by all involved...all involved of course with the exception of Kurt Russell. Kurt clearly is playing Snake as a sort of futuristic CLINT EASTWOOD style hero, but this merely just makes Snake bland & hardly makes him an interesting hero. Even worse there's almost no action to speak of minus a very poorly choreographed fight scened where Russell is forced to fend for himself against a brute of a man, in a crudely made wrestling ring, while surrounded by the crazy gangs & a poorly done car chase. In the end, I so desperately wanted to include myself in the millions of fans who love this film. I wanted to embrace it & at the same time, add it as one of Carpenters best work, but I just couldn't. I just couldn't get into the film & there were just to many missed opportunities on hand here that could have made the film really special. JOHN CARPENTER's direction was just as good as it's always been here, but I just felt let down by this movie. Maybe I was just expecting to much out of it, is why I wound up being let down, after hearing about the films hype for many years, I just anticipated a much better film than what I wound up with. In fact I've seen much better films made, that fans were split on. In the end, I'm in the minority of people left scratching my head & wondering what all the fuss was over. Maybe if I would have seen the film when I was younger I would have had different feelings over it, but as it is, ESCAPE FROM NEW YORK just didn't do it for me. It's merely a film that is just hardly above mediocrity. Followed by ESCAPE FROM L.A. **1/2 stars
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sci-Punk Noir
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of the Director's better Movies. It is a completely Cynical and Dark atmosphere that relays its intent on the Audience with an effectiveness that only a talented B-Movie Director could concoct. The ability to take Comic-Book Stories and Characters, dress them up, and announce the whole thing as gritty, sleazy Fun. Style personified. The Film is oozing with Style. From the Haunting, but typical, thumping of the Synthesizer, not one scene in the Daylight (Dawn at best), Thrift Store Chic Costumes, a Larger than Life Anti-Hero, and assorted Street Dregs, mixed with the Classical Chestnut "do this thing and you are Pardoned", it all comes together with simplistic, but Colorful Sets and Graphics and bit of the ol' Ultraviolence. It is Sci-Punk Noir and the Talented Creators both in front of and behind the Camera make for an Amalgamated Apocalyptic Fan Favorite Film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cerebral....sort of like an episode of "Masterpiece Theatre".
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Okay, I'll admit it...my summary is completely ridiculous! "Escape From New York" is anything but cerebral or sophisticated. Instead, it's a rather absurd little sci-fi film that actually manages to be awfully entertaining despite being utterly ridiculous. Much of this is because the film takes itself so very seriously--and this heightens the campy atmosphere and makes the film a lot of fun. This John Carpenter film is set in the near future. Lawlessness has taken hold until society has come up with a strange solution--to turn Manhattan Island into a giant prison. This 'prison' is really just a dumping ground--a dumping ground where there are no guards and no rules--just a weird self-created society of scum. When a terrorist hijacks Air Force One and crashes it into this city, the President is able to use an escape pod--but he lands in the middle of this hellish city. For some odd reason, instead of sending in the Marines or the Navy Seals, they send in one man--'Snake' Plissken (Kurt Russell). Plissken is ridiculously overplayed by Russell--and that adds to the fun. I am pretty sure he didn't take himself very seriously and the viewer certainly can't! Plissken is sort of like Rambo and Clint Eastwood (Russell REALLY had the Eastwood voice down pat)--but even more indestructible! Now Plissken is NOT the hero type. He himself is a convicted criminal but he's also a war hero. To convince him to take the assignment, they not only promise him his freedom but his life. You see, this is because they implanted a nanoprobe into him that will kill him if the assignment isn't completed in 24 hours! Can he do it? What do you think? As I said above, Plissken is played in such an overly serious and over-the-top manner that the film is really a hoot to watch. Also, the film is very original even if it is silly. A few other things I loved were the faux computer graphics (done amazingly well considering everything--see the IMDb trivia for more on this), the scene towards the end of the President having his revenge on 'The Duke' and the incredible soundtrack (by Carpenter himself). All in all, a dumb but incredibly cool guilty pleasure. And sometimes you just have to let your brain relax and watch something mindlessly fun.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Future Is Now Past.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    John Carpenter directed this exciting action yarn that stars Kurt Russell(excellent performance) as Snake Plissken, a wanted criminal and amoral mercenary(think a modern "Man With No Name") that is captured by authorities, but offered a pardon if he will undertake an important mission: rescue the president, who has crash-landed Air Force One into the penal colony of "futuristic"(1997) Manhattan, which has been sealed off from the rest of the country after the crime rate skyrockets. The president(played by Donald Pleasance) is being held by a powerful gang as a bargaining ploy, and Snake must rescue him, and retrieve an important document related to a speech he was going to give. After gliding in, he has a limited amount of time to find the president, before a poison kills him(he will be given the antidote upon successful completion of the rescue.) Well-designed and entertaining film has a good cast(Adrienne Barbeau, Ernest Borgnine, and Lee Van Cleef among them). Well worth watching, and a lot of fun.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    John Carpenter Classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SnoopyStyle
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    John Carpenter creates one of the most original movie and an iconic fantasy world. 'Escape from New York' is a cult classic. It's the future 1997, Manhattan has been turned into a maximum security prison. The President had to do an emergency ejection, but lands inside the prison. Snake Plissken (Kurt Russell) is coerced into bringing the President and his cargo out. Once inside, Snake gets help from Cabbie (Ernest Borgnine), and Maggie (Adrienne Barbeau). This was about the beginning of the end of the '70s crime ridden NY paranoia. The style is no longer realism but rather surreal. It is the best of campy adventure. Kurt Russell creates an iconic character.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "There was an accident. About an hour ago, a small jet went down inside New York City. The President was on board." "President of what?"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Al_The_Strange
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In this dark dystopian sci-fi adventure, ultimate tough guy Snake Plissken is sent on a mission to enter New York, a city now turned into the world's largest penitentiary with a huge retaining wall, to rescue the President from a group of the roughest and most violent criminals imaginable. Sounds awesome, right? Escape From New York has all the right elements to make something awesome. The premise, the characters, the settings, and the overall essence of the film are indeed awesome. However, in the hands of John Carpenter, the film moves at a slow and brooding pace. It's the same creepy, methodic style that makes his other movies - Halloween, The Fog, Christine, The Thing  so effective. For this movie, I never felt that it works as well as it should: the film creeps along so much in the dark that all sense of action and excitement is dampened. When action does hit  a few pedestrian scenes where bad guys throw rocks and sticks, beat and rape a few people, throw Snake into a death match arena, and then finally chase the heroes across a mined bridge  it's all pretty lightweight, lacking in particularly deep impact or thrills. I can't help but to think that, in the hands of guys like John McTiernan or Paul Verhoeven, Escape From NY could be the awesomest, pulpiest, and most badass movie out there. As it is, it's mildly cool, but it never fully capitalizes off of its own potential. The story this film tells is pretty neat, filled with some far-out sci-fi concepts (ideas that would be replicated in plenty of other films, most blatant of which is Doomdsay). The actual plot is pretty standard; it gives you just enough to the story and characters to understand what's going on and to kick off the big adventure, but there's not much depth or exploration offered beyond the surface-level expositions. Characters are pretty flat and lifeless all around, except for Snake Plissken, who is the epitome of cool, with his moody, dangerous, devil-may-care attitude. His character is not only a great antihero, but also a massive influence on other popular characters (remember Solid Snake from Metal Gear Solid?). The only problem is, you never really learn much about Snake beyond that surface level; he is as one-dimensional as everybody else. There are moments where I also wonder if this movie tries to pick at some social themes regarding American society and culture; after all, this is one of America's biggest and most popular cities turned into a total hellhole, and it's the American President caught up in the middle of the chaos. There are times when it seems like the film is underscoring the ugly undercurrent of social corruption and decay, but these themes never really materialize into anything tangible. This film uses rather pedestrian photography, in a manner not much different than Halloween. The camera moves and angles are interesting at times, but the shots are so long that they appear pretty indistinctive. Lighting is very dark throughout, for appropriate effect. Editing is good. Acting is generally okay: Kurt Russell is the man throughout, opposite Lee Van Cleef and Isaac Hayes, who also try their best to be tough. Ernest Borgnine provides a little bit of goofiness to the mix, and Adrienne Barbeau adds a little bit of sex appeal. Harry Dean Stanton isn't given much to do, and his role is ultimately forgettable. And, Donald Pleasence is pretty much himself. Writing is okay; there are a few amusing lines. This movie uses sets, props, and costumes that show some limitations, but get the job done very well. John Carpenter's music score is pretty darn cool. Escape From New York has its share of coolness, but it could be cooler yet. It's not terribly exciting, but it is mildly interesting and mildly satisfying. Given its popularity, the film is a must-see for fans of dark and violent dystopian sci-fi. 3.5/5 (Entertainment: Pretty Good | Story: Average | Film: Pretty Good)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Worst Piece of CRAP I've seen in years
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FriscoJoe
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Really? A wall around Manhattan island? No police force and no fire department yet the place hasn't burned down? The whole premise is just plain STUPID. They land a glider on the roof of one of the World Trade Center towers. I worked in the WTC. What happened to the observation deck on top? Hmmmm? Compared to the absolutely moronic plot, though, the WTC flaws are forgivable. Notice that the female leads all have spotless, perfectly made-up faces and hair. Spoiler... sorta'... if you're waiting for Adrienne Barbeau's boobs to "escape", don't hold your breath: they don't. This is a ONE star movie, folks. It belongs in the hall of fame of worst movies ever made, just a shade above Ed Wood's D-Grade movies, but not nearly as unintentionally funny.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Timeless Cult Adventure of the Badass Anti-Hero Snake Plissken
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Claudio Carvalho
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In 1997, Manhattan has been transformed in the New York Maximum Security Penitentiary, where criminals are sent in life sentence. When the Air Force One crashes in Manhattan with the president of the USA (Donald Pleasence) that is traveling to a summit with other leaders, the prison dean Hauk (Lee Van Cleef) proposes a deal to the convicted one-eyed bank robber Snake Plissken (Kurt Russell). If he rescues the president and his tape in less than 23 hours, he would be granted pardon. In order to guarantee full commitment of Snake Plissken, Hauk lures him and injects a lethal capsule in his blood that will dissolve in the scheduled time. Snake Plissken uses a small plane to land one the roof of the World Trade Center. Soon he finds that the tracking device was removed from the president. When he meets the taxi driver Cabbie (Ernest Borgnine), he learns that the warlord The Duke (Isaac Hayes) has captured the president. Now Snake Plissken has to team-up with his former partner Brain (Harry Dean Stanton), who has double-crossed him in the past, and his squeeze Maggie (Adrienne Barbeau) to rescue the president and save his own life. "Escape from New York" is the timeless cult adventure of the badass one- eyed anti-hero Snake Plissken by John Carpenter. It is amazing how this movie has not aged and even after watching it so many times, I do not get tired of it. Kurt Russell has a fantastic shape and is perfect in the role of the tough Snake Plissken. The president dressed with blonde wig and with cosmetics and his rage in the end against The Duke seems to indicate that something else had happened to him besides losing his thumb. The movie has a dream cast and also a wonderful music score. My vote is ten. Title (Brazi): "Fuga de Nova York" ("Escape from New York")
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Classic Old Fashioned Cinematic Look At The Future
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Theo Robertson
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In 1988 America experiences a surge in criminal violence that leads to Manhatten being turned in to one massive prison . In 1997 Airforce One is hijacked and crashes in to the prison . Newly convicted prisoner Snake Plissken is given a be given deal - if he can rescue the president he'll be given an amnesty but only has 22 hours to do so . If the mission fails the world may very well be heading towards World War 3 Earlier tonight I watched AEON FLUX , a film that some could claim is style over substance . I certainly didn't see any substance in that film and if you saw any style let me know what scene it appeared in . ESCAPE FROM NY is entirely different from FLUX . It's directed by John Carpenter who also did the electronic score and opened to moderate business on its released and later became a cult film . It's easy to see why . The camera work might be relatively static but this with hindsight compared to film making in the 21st century is a blessing since the visuals don't overwhelm the storytelling The story itself from real life events that over took this fictional scenario where in 1997 the cold war looks like hotting up big time but I doubt if Mikhail Gorbachev was sitting down at a table thinking ending the cold war would invalidate John Carpenter's vision of the future but that said a Marxist Leninist spouting rhetoric about workers and imperialist pigs does date the film Thankfully the film isn't really interested in politics and concentrates on keeping the audience excited which is does a good job at as Snake finds constant barriers in his way as he tries to find the missing president knowing that the clock is ticking away . Some of the action scenes aren't entirely plausible such as a machine pistol having an unrealistic capacity and despite being a not unlikable anti-hero in the vein of New Hollywood Kurt Russell plays Snake Plissken far too much like Clint Eastwood would have . Has anyone watched Russell's performance and not mentioned Eastwood ? Regardless of this ESCAPE FROM NY is a very enjoyable action thriller set in the future
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good in its own time, but now it feels outdated...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    luger7
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I can understand why a lot of fellows say this is a one of the best action movies, maybe because they watched this when they were younger or kids and it made a good impression on their minds. Well I remember watching this movie when I was a kid, and yes of course I enjoyed it, but never like other action movies I have in high regard like Predator, Commando or Aliens. So I watched Escape From New York again, and sorry dear fans but this is a really boring movie. The plot and the background of the story are not bad, a lot of potential here, but the development and the "action" is just slow and dry. Snake is a good character, i really think so, but this movie didn't age very well.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not Carpenters best work...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Prolox
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    KURT RUSSELL stars as a long thought dead SNAKE PLISSKEN, a former war hero turned notorious outlaw, who is recruited by local law enforcement to help rescue the president of the United States, who's plane has crashed & is trapped behind the walls of New York City in the year 1997, which has now been converted into a maximum security prison, where society's worst nightmares run amok. Implamented with an explosive device that will ignite if he tries to escape from his mission & armed with some nifty gadgets. Snake attempts to keep himself alive & from danger, as he looks for the man's whereabouts, only to discover the President is being held captive by the criminal ruler of New York's prison, a cold hearted criminal played by ISAAC HAYES. When Snake winds up being captured, he is forced to fight for his life against the well armed thugs that work for the main villain & escape with the president, before his time runs out. ESCAPE FROM NEW YORK is hailed as a classic among genre fans, with some even saying it's JOHN CARPENTER'S best work. After hearing so much praise about the film, I just had to see it, mainly because I'm a big fan of Carpenter's work, that & because the film carries a pretty good bevy of talent both in front & behind the screen. Unfortunately after seeing it twice, I was kind of left scratching my head, trying to figure out what everyone is so crazy about the film, because in actuality there really isn't all that much to it. The reason I saw it twice is because I thought I might have missed something or misunderstood it, but sadly all to no avail. Director Carpenter brought along his HALLOWEEN crew, Director of Photography DEAN CUNDEY, Producer DEBRA HILL, Michael Myers himself NICK CASTLE (Who serves as co-writer) Composer ALAN HOWARTH, BARRY BERNARDI (THE FOG) & even JAWS Production designer JOE ALVES & LARRY FRANCO (THE THING/THEY LIVE/ PRINCE OF DARKNESS) JAMES CAMERON (TITANIC) as effect supervisor) & then there's the acting troupe supporting the film, such as Carpenter's then wife, ADRIENNE BARBEAU, HARRY DEAN STANTON, LEE VAN CLEEF & ISAAC HAYES, DONALD PLESEANCE, BUCK FLOWER & KURT RUSSELL as the hero, which is why the film in my eyes, should have turned out a lot better than it did. ESCAPE FROM NEW YORK is billed as a Sci-fi/action film, but there's precious little action to be had throughout the films running time & it's clear Carpenter had much higher aspirations for the film then what he was able to pull off. The film passes the idea off that Manhatten has been converted to a maximum security prison, but yet there's no more than a few small crowds of criminals that could so easily have fit into a normal prison. It's very clear that Carpenter envisioned a much more fuller Manhattan, full of criminals, but that vision is hamstrung by his decent, but still limited budget. Joe Alves was obviously hamstrung by the films tight 7 million dollar budget as well, since he doesn't do much except strewn some rubble around here & there (where was the crumbled statue of Liberty on the box art?) The films plot does indeed show some promise & at the beginning looks to be set to become a very tight action sci-fi thriller, the best of it's kind. But once Plissken is dropped into New York, Carpenter drops the ball. The remainder of the films running time merely shows Russell roaming the streets, visiting old allies, meeting a kind hearted cabbie & visiting abandon buildings & is never engaged in any real fights against scores of criminals, not high powered shoot outs, fist fights, explosions, nothing. Issac Hayes is a good actor, but is hardly anything you would call menacing as the main villain & is unable to pull off that certain sense of dread & intimidation that most action movie villains have & the same goes for the criminals who are paper thin & hardly anything terrifying or even amusing. The acting is fairly decent by all involved...all involved of course with the exception of Kurt Russell. Kurt clearly is playing Snake as a sort of futuristic CLINT EASTWOOD style hero, but this merely just makes Snake bland & hardly makes him an interesting hero. Even worse there's almost no action to speak of minus a very poorly choreographed fight scened where Russell is forced to fend for himself against a brute of a man, in a crudely made wrestling ring, while surrounded by the crazy gangs & a poorly done car chase. In the end, I so desperately wanted to include myself in the millions of fans who love this film. I wanted to embrace it & at the same time, add it as one of Carpenters best work, but I just couldn't. I just couldn't get into the film & there were just to many missed opportunities on hand here that could have made the film really special. JOHN CARPENTER's direction was just as good as it's always been here, but I just felt let down by this movie. Maybe I was just expecting to much out of it, is why I wound up being let down, after hearing about the films hype for many years, I just anticipated a much better film than what I wound up with. In fact I've seen much better films made, that fans were split on. In the end, I'm in the minority of people left scratching my head & wondering what all the fuss was over. Maybe if I would have seen the film when I was younger I would have had different feelings over it, but as it is, ESCAPE FROM NEW YORK just didn't do it for me. It's merely a film that is just hardly above mediocrity. Followed by ESCAPE FROM L.A. **1/2 stars
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sci-Punk Noir
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of the Director's better Movies. It is a completely Cynical and Dark atmosphere that relays its intent on the Audience with an effectiveness that only a talented B-Movie Director could concoct. The ability to take Comic-Book Stories and Characters, dress them up, and announce the whole thing as gritty, sleazy Fun. Style personified. The Film is oozing with Style. From the Haunting, but typical, thumping of the Synthesizer, not one scene in the Daylight (Dawn at best), Thrift Store Chic Costumes, a Larger than Life Anti-Hero, and assorted Street Dregs, mixed with the Classical Chestnut "do this thing and you are Pardoned", it all comes together with simplistic, but Colorful Sets and Graphics and bit of the ol' Ultraviolence. It is Sci-Punk Noir and the Talented Creators both in front of and behind the Camera make for an Amalgamated Apocalyptic Fan Favorite Film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cerebral....sort of like an episode of "Masterpiece Theatre".
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Okay, I'll admit it...my summary is completely ridiculous! "Escape From New York" is anything but cerebral or sophisticated. Instead, it's a rather absurd little sci-fi film that actually manages to be awfully entertaining despite being utterly ridiculous. Much of this is because the film takes itself so very seriously--and this heightens the campy atmosphere and makes the film a lot of fun. This John Carpenter film is set in the near future. Lawlessness has taken hold until society has come up with a strange solution--to turn Manhattan Island into a giant prison. This 'prison' is really just a dumping ground--a dumping ground where there are no guards and no rules--just a weird self-created society of scum. When a terrorist hijacks Air Force One and crashes it into this city, the President is able to use an escape pod--but he lands in the middle of this hellish city. For some odd reason, instead of sending in the Marines or the Navy Seals, they send in one man--'Snake' Plissken (Kurt Russell). Plissken is ridiculously overplayed by Russell--and that adds to the fun. I am pretty sure he didn't take himself very seriously and the viewer certainly can't! Plissken is sort of like Rambo and Clint Eastwood (Russell REALLY had the Eastwood voice down pat)--but even more indestructible! Now Plissken is NOT the hero type. He himself is a convicted criminal but he's also a war hero. To convince him to take the assignment, they not only promise him his freedom but his life. You see, this is because they implanted a nanoprobe into him that will kill him if the assignment isn't completed in 24 hours! Can he do it? What do you think? As I said above, Plissken is played in such an overly serious and over-the-top manner that the film is really a hoot to watch. Also, the film is very original even if it is silly. A few other things I loved were the faux computer graphics (done amazingly well considering everything--see the IMDb trivia for more on this), the scene towards the end of the President having his revenge on 'The Duke' and the incredible soundtrack (by Carpenter himself). All in all, a dumb but incredibly cool guilty pleasure. And sometimes you just have to let your brain relax and watch something mindlessly fun.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Future Is Now Past.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    John Carpenter directed this exciting action yarn that stars Kurt Russell(excellent performance) as Snake Plissken, a wanted criminal and amoral mercenary(think a modern "Man With No Name") that is captured by authorities, but offered a pardon if he will undertake an important mission: rescue the president, who has crash-landed Air Force One into the penal colony of "futuristic"(1997) Manhattan, which has been sealed off from the rest of the country after the crime rate skyrockets. The president(played by Donald Pleasance) is being held by a powerful gang as a bargaining ploy, and Snake must rescue him, and retrieve an important document related to a speech he was going to give. After gliding in, he has a limited amount of time to find the president, before a poison kills him(he will be given the antidote upon successful completion of the rescue.) Well-designed and entertaining film has a good cast(Adrienne Barbeau, Ernest Borgnine, and Lee Van Cleef among them). Well worth watching, and a lot of fun.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    John Carpenter Classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SnoopyStyle
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    John Carpenter creates one of the most original movie and an iconic fantasy world. 'Escape from New York' is a cult classic. It's the future 1997, Manhattan has been turned into a maximum security prison. The President had to do an emergency ejection, but lands inside the prison. Snake Plissken (Kurt Russell) is coerced into bringing the President and his cargo out. Once inside, Snake gets help from Cabbie (Ernest Borgnine), and Maggie (Adrienne Barbeau). This was about the beginning of the end of the '70s crime ridden NY paranoia. The style is no longer realism but rather surreal. It is the best of campy adventure. Kurt Russell creates an iconic character.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "There was an accident. About an hour ago, a small jet went down inside New York City. The President was on board." "President of what?"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Al_The_Strange
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In this dark dystopian sci-fi adventure, ultimate tough guy Snake Plissken is sent on a mission to enter New York, a city now turned into the world's largest penitentiary with a huge retaining wall, to rescue the President from a group of the roughest and most violent criminals imaginable. Sounds awesome, right? Escape From New York has all the right elements to make something awesome. The premise, the characters, the settings, and the overall essence of the film are indeed awesome. However, in the hands of John Carpenter, the film moves at a slow and brooding pace. It's the same creepy, methodic style that makes his other movies - Halloween, The Fog, Christine, The Thing  so effective. For this movie, I never felt that it works as well as it should: the film creeps along so much in the dark that all sense of action and excitement is dampened. When action does hit  a few pedestrian scenes where bad guys throw rocks and sticks, beat and rape a few people, throw Snake into a death match arena, and then finally chase the heroes across a mined bridge  it's all pretty lightweight, lacking in particularly deep impact or thrills. I can't help but to think that, in the hands of guys like John McTiernan or Paul Verhoeven, Escape From NY could be the awesomest, pulpiest, and most badass movie out there. As it is, it's mildly cool, but it never fully capitalizes off of its own potential. The story this film tells is pretty neat, filled with some far-out sci-fi concepts (ideas that would be replicated in plenty of other films, most blatant of which is Doomdsay). The actual plot is pretty standard; it gives you just enough to the story and characters to understand what's going on and to kick off the big adventure, but there's not much depth or exploration offered beyond the surface-level expositions. Characters are pretty flat and lifeless all around, except for Snake Plissken, who is the epitome of cool, with his moody, dangerous, devil-may-care attitude. His character is not only a great antihero, but also a massive influence on other popular characters (remember Solid Snake from Metal Gear Solid?). The only problem is, you never really learn much about Snake beyond that surface level; he is as one-dimensional as everybody else. There are moments where I also wonder if this movie tries to pick at some social themes regarding American society and culture; after all, this is one of America's biggest and most popular cities turned into a total hellhole, and it's the American President caught up in the middle of the chaos. There are times when it seems like the film is underscoring the ugly undercurrent of social corruption and decay, but these themes never really materialize into anything tangible. This film uses rather pedestrian photography, in a manner not much different than Halloween. The camera moves and angles are interesting at times, but the shots are so long that they appear pretty indistinctive. Lighting is very dark throughout, for appropriate effect. Editing is good. Acting is generally okay: Kurt Russell is the man throughout, opposite Lee Van Cleef and Isaac Hayes, who also try their best to be tough. Ernest Borgnine provides a little bit of goofiness to the mix, and Adrienne Barbeau adds a little bit of sex appeal. Harry Dean Stanton isn't given much to do, and his role is ultimately forgettable. And, Donald Pleasence is pretty much himself. Writing is okay; there are a few amusing lines. This movie uses sets, props, and costumes that show some limitations, but get the job done very well. John Carpenter's music score is pretty darn cool. Escape From New York has its share of coolness, but it could be cooler yet. It's not terribly exciting, but it is mildly interesting and mildly satisfying. Given its popularity, the film is a must-see for fans of dark and violent dystopian sci-fi. 3.5/5 (Entertainment: Pretty Good | Story: Average | Film: Pretty Good)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Worst Piece of CRAP I've seen in years
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FriscoJoe
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Really? A wall around Manhattan island? No police force and no fire department yet the place hasn't burned down? The whole premise is just plain STUPID. They land a glider on the roof of one of the World Trade Center towers. I worked in the WTC. What happened to the observation deck on top? Hmmmm? Compared to the absolutely moronic plot, though, the WTC flaws are forgivable. Notice that the female leads all have spotless, perfectly made-up faces and hair. Spoiler... sorta'... if you're waiting for Adrienne Barbeau's boobs to "escape", don't hold your breath: they don't. This is a ONE star movie, folks. It belongs in the hall of fame of worst movies ever made, just a shade above Ed Wood's D-Grade movies, but not nearly as unintentionally funny.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Timeless Cult Adventure of the Badass Anti-Hero Snake Plissken
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Claudio Carvalho
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In 1997, Manhattan has been transformed in the New York Maximum Security Penitentiary, where criminals are sent in life sentence. When the Air Force One crashes in Manhattan with the president of the USA (Donald Pleasence) that is traveling to a summit with other leaders, the prison dean Hauk (Lee Van Cleef) proposes a deal to the convicted one-eyed bank robber Snake Plissken (Kurt Russell). If he rescues the president and his tape in less than 23 hours, he would be granted pardon. In order to guarantee full commitment of Snake Plissken, Hauk lures him and injects a lethal capsule in his blood that will dissolve in the scheduled time. Snake Plissken uses a small plane to land one the roof of the World Trade Center. Soon he finds that the tracking device was removed from the president. When he meets the taxi driver Cabbie (Ernest Borgnine), he learns that the warlord The Duke (Isaac Hayes) has captured the president. Now Snake Plissken has to team-up with his former partner Brain (Harry Dean Stanton), who has double-crossed him in the past, and his squeeze Maggie (Adrienne Barbeau) to rescue the president and save his own life. "Escape from New York" is the timeless cult adventure of the badass one- eyed anti-hero Snake Plissken by John Carpenter. It is amazing how this movie has not aged and even after watching it so many times, I do not get tired of it. Kurt Russell has a fantastic shape and is perfect in the role of the tough Snake Plissken. The president dressed with blonde wig and with cosmetics and his rage in the end against The Duke seems to indicate that something else had happened to him besides losing his thumb. The movie has a dream cast and also a wonderful music score. My vote is ten. Title (Brazi): "Fuga de Nova York" ("Escape from New York")
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Classic Old Fashioned Cinematic Look At The Future
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Theo Robertson
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In 1988 America experiences a surge in criminal violence that leads to Manhatten being turned in to one massive prison . In 1997 Airforce One is hijacked and crashes in to the prison . Newly convicted prisoner Snake Plissken is given a be given deal - if he can rescue the president he'll be given an amnesty but only has 22 hours to do so . If the mission fails the world may very well be heading towards World War 3 Earlier tonight I watched AEON FLUX , a film that some could claim is style over substance . I certainly didn't see any substance in that film and if you saw any style let me know what scene it appeared in . ESCAPE FROM NY is entirely different from FLUX . It's directed by John Carpenter who also did the electronic score and opened to moderate business on its released and later became a cult film . It's easy to see why . The camera work might be relatively static but this with hindsight compared to film making in the 21st century is a blessing since the visuals don't overwhelm the storytelling The story itself from real life events that over took this fictional scenario where in 1997 the cold war looks like hotting up big time but I doubt if Mikhail Gorbachev was sitting down at a table thinking ending the cold war would invalidate John Carpenter's vision of the future but that said a Marxist Leninist spouting rhetoric about workers and imperialist pigs does date the film Thankfully the film isn't really interested in politics and concentrates on keeping the audience excited which is does a good job at as Snake finds constant barriers in his way as he tries to find the missing president knowing that the clock is ticking away . Some of the action scenes aren't entirely plausible such as a machine pistol having an unrealistic capacity and despite being a not unlikable anti-hero in the vein of New Hollywood Kurt Russell plays Snake Plissken far too much like Clint Eastwood would have . Has anyone watched Russell's performance and not mentioned Eastwood ? Regardless of this ESCAPE FROM NY is a very enjoyable action thriller set in the future
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good in its own time, but now it feels outdated...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    luger7
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I can understand why a lot of fellows say this is a one of the best action movies, maybe because they watched this when they were younger or kids and it made a good impression on their minds. Well I remember watching this movie when I was a kid, and yes of course I enjoyed it, but never like other action movies I have in high regard like Predator, Commando or Aliens. So I watched Escape From New York again, and sorry dear fans but this is a really boring movie. The plot and the background of the story are not bad, a lot of potential here, but the development and the "action" is just slow and dry. Snake is a good character, i really think so, but this movie didn't age very well.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not Carpenters best work...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Prolox
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    KURT RUSSELL stars as a long thought dead SNAKE PLISSKEN, a former war hero turned notorious outlaw, who is recruited by local law enforcement to help rescue the president of the United States, who's plane has crashed & is trapped behind the walls of New York City in the year 1997, which has now been converted into a maximum security prison, where society's worst nightmares run amok. Implamented with an explosive device that will ignite if he tries to escape from his mission & armed with some nifty gadgets. Snake attempts to keep himself alive & from danger, as he looks for the man's whereabouts, only to discover the President is being held captive by the criminal ruler of New York's prison, a cold hearted criminal played by ISAAC HAYES. When Snake winds up being captured, he is forced to fight for his life against the well armed thugs that work for the main villain & escape with the president, before his time runs out. ESCAPE FROM NEW YORK is hailed as a classic among genre fans, with some even saying it's JOHN CARPENTER'S best work. After hearing so much praise about the film, I just had to see it, mainly because I'm a big fan of Carpenter's work, that & because the film carries a pretty good bevy of talent both in front & behind the screen. Unfortunately after seeing it twice, I was kind of left scratching my head, trying to figure out what everyone is so crazy about the film, because in actuality there really isn't all that much to it. The reason I saw it twice is because I thought I might have missed something or misunderstood it, but sadly all to no avail. Director Carpenter brought along his HALLOWEEN crew, Director of Photography DEAN CUNDEY, Producer DEBRA HILL, Michael Myers himself NICK CASTLE (Who serves as co-writer) Composer ALAN HOWARTH, BARRY BERNARDI (THE FOG) & even JAWS Production designer JOE ALVES & LARRY FRANCO (THE THING/THEY LIVE/ PRINCE OF DARKNESS) JAMES CAMERON (TITANIC) as effect supervisor) & then there's the acting troupe supporting the film, such as Carpenter's then wife, ADRIENNE BARBEAU, HARRY DEAN STANTON, LEE VAN CLEEF & ISAAC HAYES, DONALD PLESEANCE, BUCK FLOWER & KURT RUSSELL as the hero, which is why the film in my eyes, should have turned out a lot better than it did. ESCAPE FROM NEW YORK is billed as a Sci-fi/action film, but there's precious little action to be had throughout the films running time & it's clear Carpenter had much higher aspirations for the film then what he was able to pull off. The film passes the idea off that Manhatten has been converted to a maximum security prison, but yet there's no more than a few small crowds of criminals that could so easily have fit into a normal prison. It's very clear that Carpenter envisioned a much more fuller Manhattan, full of criminals, but that vision is hamstrung by his decent, but still limited budget. Joe Alves was obviously hamstrung by the films tight 7 million dollar budget as well, since he doesn't do much except strewn some rubble around here & there (where was the crumbled statue of Liberty on the box art?) The films plot does indeed show some promise & at the beginning looks to be set to become a very tight action sci-fi thriller, the best of it's kind. But once Plissken is dropped into New York, Carpenter drops the ball. The remainder of the films running time merely shows Russell roaming the streets, visiting old allies, meeting a kind hearted cabbie & visiting abandon buildings & is never engaged in any real fights against scores of criminals, not high powered shoot outs, fist fights, explosions, nothing. Issac Hayes is a good actor, but is hardly anything you would call menacing as the main villain & is unable to pull off that certain sense of dread & intimidation that most action movie villains have & the same goes for the criminals who are paper thin & hardly anything terrifying or even amusing. The acting is fairly decent by all involved...all involved of course with the exception of Kurt Russell. Kurt clearly is playing Snake as a sort of futuristic CLINT EASTWOOD style hero, but this merely just makes Snake bland & hardly makes him an interesting hero. Even worse there's almost no action to speak of minus a very poorly choreographed fight scened where Russell is forced to fend for himself against a brute of a man, in a crudely made wrestling ring, while surrounded by the crazy gangs & a poorly done car chase. In the end, I so desperately wanted to include myself in the millions of fans who love this film. I wanted to embrace it & at the same time, add it as one of Carpenters best work, but I just couldn't. I just couldn't get into the film & there were just to many missed opportunities on hand here that could have made the film really special. JOHN CARPENTER's direction was just as good as it's always been here, but I just felt let down by this movie. Maybe I was just expecting to much out of it, is why I wound up being let down, after hearing about the films hype for many years, I just anticipated a much better film than what I wound up with. In fact I've seen much better films made, that fans were split on. In the end, I'm in the minority of people left scratching my head & wondering what all the fuss was over. Maybe if I would have seen the film when I was younger I would have had different feelings over it, but as it is, ESCAPE FROM NEW YORK just didn't do it for me. It's merely a film that is just hardly above mediocrity. Followed by ESCAPE FROM L.A. **1/2 stars
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sci-Punk Noir
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of the Director's better Movies. It is a completely Cynical and Dark atmosphere that relays its intent on the Audience with an effectiveness that only a talented B-Movie Director could concoct. The ability to take Comic-Book Stories and Characters, dress them up, and announce the whole thing as gritty, sleazy Fun. Style personified. The Film is oozing with Style. From the Haunting, but typical, thumping of the Synthesizer, not one scene in the Daylight (Dawn at best), Thrift Store Chic Costumes, a Larger than Life Anti-Hero, and assorted Street Dregs, mixed with the Classical Chestnut "do this thing and you are Pardoned", it all comes together with simplistic, but Colorful Sets and Graphics and bit of the ol' Ultraviolence. It is Sci-Punk Noir and the Talented Creators both in front of and behind the Camera make for an Amalgamated Apocalyptic Fan Favorite Film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cerebral....sort of like an episode of "Masterpiece Theatre".
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Okay, I'll admit it...my summary is completely ridiculous! "Escape From New York" is anything but cerebral or sophisticated. Instead, it's a rather absurd little sci-fi film that actually manages to be awfully entertaining despite being utterly ridiculous. Much of this is because the film takes itself so very seriously--and this heightens the campy atmosphere and makes the film a lot of fun. This John Carpenter film is set in the near future. Lawlessness has taken hold until society has come up with a strange solution--to turn Manhattan Island into a giant prison. This 'prison' is really just a dumping ground--a dumping ground where there are no guards and no rules--just a weird self-created society of scum. When a terrorist hijacks Air Force One and crashes it into this city, the President is able to use an escape pod--but he lands in the middle of this hellish city. For some odd reason, instead of sending in the Marines or the Navy Seals, they send in one man--'Snake' Plissken (Kurt Russell). Plissken is ridiculously overplayed by Russell--and that adds to the fun. I am pretty sure he didn't take himself very seriously and the viewer certainly can't! Plissken is sort of like Rambo and Clint Eastwood (Russell REALLY had the Eastwood voice down pat)--but even more indestructible! Now Plissken is NOT the hero type. He himself is a convicted criminal but he's also a war hero. To convince him to take the assignment, they not only promise him his freedom but his life. You see, this is because they implanted a nanoprobe into him that will kill him if the assignment isn't completed in 24 hours! Can he do it? What do you think? As I said above, Plissken is played in such an overly serious and over-the-top manner that the film is really a hoot to watch. Also, the film is very original even if it is silly. A few other things I loved were the faux computer graphics (done amazingly well considering everything--see the IMDb trivia for more on this), the scene towards the end of the President having his revenge on 'The Duke' and the incredible soundtrack (by Carpenter himself). All in all, a dumb but incredibly cool guilty pleasure. And sometimes you just have to let your brain relax and watch something mindlessly fun.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Future Is Now Past.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    John Carpenter directed this exciting action yarn that stars Kurt Russell(excellent performance) as Snake Plissken, a wanted criminal and amoral mercenary(think a modern "Man With No Name") that is captured by authorities, but offered a pardon if he will undertake an important mission: rescue the president, who has crash-landed Air Force One into the penal colony of "futuristic"(1997) Manhattan, which has been sealed off from the rest of the country after the crime rate skyrockets. The president(played by Donald Pleasance) is being held by a powerful gang as a bargaining ploy, and Snake must rescue him, and retrieve an important document related to a speech he was going to give. After gliding in, he has a limited amount of time to find the president, before a poison kills him(he will be given the antidote upon successful completion of the rescue.) Well-designed and entertaining film has a good cast(Adrienne Barbeau, Ernest Borgnine, and Lee Van Cleef among them). Well worth watching, and a lot of fun.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    John Carpenter Classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SnoopyStyle
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    John Carpenter creates one of the most original movie and an iconic fantasy world. 'Escape from New York' is a cult classic. It's the future 1997, Manhattan has been turned into a maximum security prison. The President had to do an emergency ejection, but lands inside the prison. Snake Plissken (Kurt Russell) is coerced into bringing the President and his cargo out. Once inside, Snake gets help from Cabbie (Ernest Borgnine), and Maggie (Adrienne Barbeau). This was about the beginning of the end of the '70s crime ridden NY paranoia. The style is no longer realism but rather surreal. It is the best of campy adventure. Kurt Russell creates an iconic character.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "There was an accident. About an hour ago, a small jet went down inside New York City. The President was on board." "President of what?"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Al_The_Strange
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In this dark dystopian sci-fi adventure, ultimate tough guy Snake Plissken is sent on a mission to enter New York, a city now turned into the world's largest penitentiary with a huge retaining wall, to rescue the President from a group of the roughest and most violent criminals imaginable. Sounds awesome, right? Escape From New York has all the right elements to make something awesome. The premise, the characters, the settings, and the overall essence of the film are indeed awesome. However, in the hands of John Carpenter, the film moves at a slow and brooding pace. It's the same creepy, methodic style that makes his other movies - Halloween, The Fog, Christine, The Thing  so effective. For this movie, I never felt that it works as well as it should: the film creeps along so much in the dark that all sense of action and excitement is dampened. When action does hit  a few pedestrian scenes where bad guys throw rocks and sticks, beat and rape a few people, throw Snake into a death match arena, and then finally chase the heroes across a mined bridge  it's all pretty lightweight, lacking in particularly deep impact or thrills. I can't help but to think that, in the hands of guys like John McTiernan or Paul Verhoeven, Escape From NY could be the awesomest, pulpiest, and most badass movie out there. As it is, it's mildly cool, but it never fully capitalizes off of its own potential. The story this film tells is pretty neat, filled with some far-out sci-fi concepts (ideas that would be replicated in plenty of other films, most blatant of which is Doomdsay). The actual plot is pretty standard; it gives you just enough to the story and characters to understand what's going on and to kick off the big adventure, but there's not much depth or exploration offered beyond the surface-level expositions. Characters are pretty flat and lifeless all around, except for Snake Plissken, who is the epitome of cool, with his moody, dangerous, devil-may-care attitude. His character is not only a great antihero, but also a massive influence on other popular characters (remember Solid Snake from Metal Gear Solid?). The only problem is, you never really learn much about Snake beyond that surface level; he is as one-dimensional as everybody else. There are moments where I also wonder if this movie tries to pick at some social themes regarding American society and culture; after all, this is one of America's biggest and most popular cities turned into a total hellhole, and it's the American President caught up in the middle of the chaos. There are times when it seems like the film is underscoring the ugly undercurrent of social corruption and decay, but these themes never really materialize into anything tangible. This film uses rather pedestrian photography, in a manner not much different than Halloween. The camera moves and angles are interesting at times, but the shots are so long that they appear pretty indistinctive. Lighting is very dark throughout, for appropriate effect. Editing is good. Acting is generally okay: Kurt Russell is the man throughout, opposite Lee Van Cleef and Isaac Hayes, who also try their best to be tough. Ernest Borgnine provides a little bit of goofiness to the mix, and Adrienne Barbeau adds a little bit of sex appeal. Harry Dean Stanton isn't given much to do, and his role is ultimately forgettable. And, Donald Pleasence is pretty much himself. Writing is okay; there are a few amusing lines. This movie uses sets, props, and costumes that show some limitations, but get the job done very well. John Carpenter's music score is pretty darn cool. Escape From New York has its share of coolness, but it could be cooler yet. It's not terribly exciting, but it is mildly interesting and mildly satisfying. Given its popularity, the film is a must-see for fans of dark and violent dystopian sci-fi. 3.5/5 (Entertainment: Pretty Good | Story: Average | Film: Pretty Good)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Worst Piece of CRAP I've seen in years
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FriscoJoe
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Really? A wall around Manhattan island? No police force and no fire department yet the place hasn't burned down? The whole premise is just plain STUPID. They land a glider on the roof of one of the World Trade Center towers. I worked in the WTC. What happened to the observation deck on top? Hmmmm? Compared to the absolutely moronic plot, though, the WTC flaws are forgivable. Notice that the female leads all have spotless, perfectly made-up faces and hair. Spoiler... sorta'... if you're waiting for Adrienne Barbeau's boobs to "escape", don't hold your breath: they don't. This is a ONE star movie, folks. It belongs in the hall of fame of worst movies ever made, just a shade above Ed Wood's D-Grade movies, but not nearly as unintentionally funny.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Timeless Cult Adventure of the Badass Anti-Hero Snake Plissken
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Claudio Carvalho
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In 1997, Manhattan has been transformed in the New York Maximum Security Penitentiary, where criminals are sent in life sentence. When the Air Force One crashes in Manhattan with the president of the USA (Donald Pleasence) that is traveling to a summit with other leaders, the prison dean Hauk (Lee Van Cleef) proposes a deal to the convicted one-eyed bank robber Snake Plissken (Kurt Russell). If he rescues the president and his tape in less than 23 hours, he would be granted pardon. In order to guarantee full commitment of Snake Plissken, Hauk lures him and injects a lethal capsule in his blood that will dissolve in the scheduled time. Snake Plissken uses a small plane to land one the roof of the World Trade Center. Soon he finds that the tracking device was removed from the president. When he meets the taxi driver Cabbie (Ernest Borgnine), he learns that the warlord The Duke (Isaac Hayes) has captured the president. Now Snake Plissken has to team-up with his former partner Brain (Harry Dean Stanton), who has double-crossed him in the past, and his squeeze Maggie (Adrienne Barbeau) to rescue the president and save his own life. "Escape from New York" is the timeless cult adventure of the badass one- eyed anti-hero Snake Plissken by John Carpenter. It is amazing how this movie has not aged and even after watching it so many times, I do not get tired of it. Kurt Russell has a fantastic shape and is perfect in the role of the tough Snake Plissken. The president dressed with blonde wig and with cosmetics and his rage in the end against The Duke seems to indicate that something else had happened to him besides losing his thumb. The movie has a dream cast and also a wonderful music score. My vote is ten. Title (Brazi): "Fuga de Nova York" ("Escape from New York")
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Classic Old Fashioned Cinematic Look At The Future
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Theo Robertson
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In 1988 America experiences a surge in criminal violence that leads to Manhatten being turned in to one massive prison . In 1997 Airforce One is hijacked and crashes in to the prison . Newly convicted prisoner Snake Plissken is given a be given deal - if he can rescue the president he'll be given an amnesty but only has 22 hours to do so . If the mission fails the world may very well be heading towards World War 3 Earlier tonight I watched AEON FLUX , a film that some could claim is style over substance . I certainly didn't see any substance in that film and if you saw any style let me know what scene it appeared in . ESCAPE FROM NY is entirely different from FLUX . It's directed by John Carpenter who also did the electronic score and opened to moderate business on its released and later became a cult film . It's easy to see why . The camera work might be relatively static but this with hindsight compared to film making in the 21st century is a blessing since the visuals don't overwhelm the storytelling The story itself from real life events that over took this fictional scenario where in 1997 the cold war looks like hotting up big time but I doubt if Mikhail Gorbachev was sitting down at a table thinking ending the cold war would invalidate John Carpenter's vision of the future but that said a Marxist Leninist spouting rhetoric about workers and imperialist pigs does date the film Thankfully the film isn't really interested in politics and concentrates on keeping the audience excited which is does a good job at as Snake finds constant barriers in his way as he tries to find the missing president knowing that the clock is ticking away . Some of the action scenes aren't entirely plausible such as a machine pistol having an unrealistic capacity and despite being a not unlikable anti-hero in the vein of New Hollywood Kurt Russell plays Snake Plissken far too much like Clint Eastwood would have . Has anyone watched Russell's performance and not mentioned Eastwood ? Regardless of this ESCAPE FROM NY is a very enjoyable action thriller set in the future
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good in its own time, but now it feels outdated...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    luger7
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I can understand why a lot of fellows say this is a one of the best action movies, maybe because they watched this when they were younger or kids and it made a good impression on their minds. Well I remember watching this movie when I was a kid, and yes of course I enjoyed it, but never like other action movies I have in high regard like Predator, Commando or Aliens. So I watched Escape From New York again, and sorry dear fans but this is a really boring movie. The plot and the background of the story are not bad, a lot of potential here, but the development and the "action" is just slow and dry. Snake is a good character, i really think so, but this movie didn't age very well.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not Carpenters best work...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Prolox
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    KURT RUSSELL stars as a long thought dead SNAKE PLISSKEN, a former war hero turned notorious outlaw, who is recruited by local law enforcement to help rescue the president of the United States, who's plane has crashed & is trapped behind the walls of New York City in the year 1997, which has now been converted into a maximum security prison, where society's worst nightmares run amok. Implamented with an explosive device that will ignite if he tries to escape from his mission & armed with some nifty gadgets. Snake attempts to keep himself alive & from danger, as he looks for the man's whereabouts, only to discover the President is being held captive by the criminal ruler of New York's prison, a cold hearted criminal played by ISAAC HAYES. When Snake winds up being captured, he is forced to fight for his life against the well armed thugs that work for the main villain & escape with the president, before his time runs out. ESCAPE FROM NEW YORK is hailed as a classic among genre fans, with some even saying it's JOHN CARPENTER'S best work. After hearing so much praise about the film, I just had to see it, mainly because I'm a big fan of Carpenter's work, that & because the film carries a pretty good bevy of talent both in front & behind the screen. Unfortunately after seeing it twice, I was kind of left scratching my head, trying to figure out what everyone is so crazy about the film, because in actuality there really isn't all that much to it. The reason I saw it twice is because I thought I might have missed something or misunderstood it, but sadly all to no avail. Director Carpenter brought along his HALLOWEEN crew, Director of Photography DEAN CUNDEY, Producer DEBRA HILL, Michael Myers himself NICK CASTLE (Who serves as co-writer) Composer ALAN HOWARTH, BARRY BERNARDI (THE FOG) & even JAWS Production designer JOE ALVES & LARRY FRANCO (THE THING/THEY LIVE/ PRINCE OF DARKNESS) JAMES CAMERON (TITANIC) as effect supervisor) & then there's the acting troupe supporting the film, such as Carpenter's then wife, ADRIENNE BARBEAU, HARRY DEAN STANTON, LEE VAN CLEEF & ISAAC HAYES, DONALD PLESEANCE, BUCK FLOWER & KURT RUSSELL as the hero, which is why the film in my eyes, should have turned out a lot better than it did. ESCAPE FROM NEW YORK is billed as a Sci-fi/action film, but there's precious little action to be had throughout the films running time & it's clear Carpenter had much higher aspirations for the film then what he was able to pull off. The film passes the idea off that Manhatten has been converted to a maximum security prison, but yet there's no more than a few small crowds of criminals that could so easily have fit into a normal prison. It's very clear that Carpenter envisioned a much more fuller Manhattan, full of criminals, but that vision is hamstrung by his decent, but still limited budget. Joe Alves was obviously hamstrung by the films tight 7 million dollar budget as well, since he doesn't do much except strewn some rubble around here & there (where was the crumbled statue of Liberty on the box art?) The films plot does indeed show some promise & at the beginning looks to be set to become a very tight action sci-fi thriller, the best of it's kind. But once Plissken is dropped into New York, Carpenter drops the ball. The remainder of the films running time merely shows Russell roaming the streets, visiting old allies, meeting a kind hearted cabbie & visiting abandon buildings & is never engaged in any real fights against scores of criminals, not high powered shoot outs, fist fights, explosions, nothing. Issac Hayes is a good actor, but is hardly anything you would call menacing as the main villain & is unable to pull off that certain sense of dread & intimidation that most action movie villains have & the same goes for the criminals who are paper thin & hardly anything terrifying or even amusing. The acting is fairly decent by all involved...all involved of course with the exception of Kurt Russell. Kurt clearly is playing Snake as a sort of futuristic CLINT EASTWOOD style hero, but this merely just makes Snake bland & hardly makes him an interesting hero. Even worse there's almost no action to speak of minus a very poorly choreographed fight scened where Russell is forced to fend for himself against a brute of a man, in a crudely made wrestling ring, while surrounded by the crazy gangs & a poorly done car chase. In the end, I so desperately wanted to include myself in the millions of fans who love this film. I wanted to embrace it & at the same time, add it as one of Carpenters best work, but I just couldn't. I just couldn't get into the film & there were just to many missed opportunities on hand here that could have made the film really special. JOHN CARPENTER's direction was just as good as it's always been here, but I just felt let down by this movie. Maybe I was just expecting to much out of it, is why I wound up being let down, after hearing about the films hype for many years, I just anticipated a much better film than what I wound up with. In fact I've seen much better films made, that fans were split on. In the end, I'm in the minority of people left scratching my head & wondering what all the fuss was over. Maybe if I would have seen the film when I was younger I would have had different feelings over it, but as it is, ESCAPE FROM NEW YORK just didn't do it for me. It's merely a film that is just hardly above mediocrity. Followed by ESCAPE FROM L.A. **1/2 stars
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sci-Punk Noir
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of the Director's better Movies. It is a completely Cynical and Dark atmosphere that relays its intent on the Audience with an effectiveness that only a talented B-Movie Director could concoct. The ability to take Comic-Book Stories and Characters, dress them up, and announce the whole thing as gritty, sleazy Fun. Style personified. The Film is oozing with Style. From the Haunting, but typical, thumping of the Synthesizer, not one scene in the Daylight (Dawn at best), Thrift Store Chic Costumes, a Larger than Life Anti-Hero, and assorted Street Dregs, mixed with the Classical Chestnut "do this thing and you are Pardoned", it all comes together with simplistic, but Colorful Sets and Graphics and bit of the ol' Ultraviolence. It is Sci-Punk Noir and the Talented Creators both in front of and behind the Camera make for an Amalgamated Apocalyptic Fan Favorite Film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cerebral....sort of like an episode of "Masterpiece Theatre".
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Okay, I'll admit it...my summary is completely ridiculous! "Escape From New York" is anything but cerebral or sophisticated. Instead, it's a rather absurd little sci-fi film that actually manages to be awfully entertaining despite being utterly ridiculous. Much of this is because the film takes itself so very seriously--and this heightens the campy atmosphere and makes the film a lot of fun. This John Carpenter film is set in the near future. Lawlessness has taken hold until society has come up with a strange solution--to turn Manhattan Island into a giant prison. This 'prison' is really just a dumping ground--a dumping ground where there are no guards and no rules--just a weird self-created society of scum. When a terrorist hijacks Air Force One and crashes it into this city, the President is able to use an escape pod--but he lands in the middle of this hellish city. For some odd reason, instead of sending in the Marines or the Navy Seals, they send in one man--'Snake' Plissken (Kurt Russell). Plissken is ridiculously overplayed by Russell--and that adds to the fun. I am pretty sure he didn't take himself very seriously and the viewer certainly can't! Plissken is sort of like Rambo and Clint Eastwood (Russell REALLY had the Eastwood voice down pat)--but even more indestructible! Now Plissken is NOT the hero type. He himself is a convicted criminal but he's also a war hero. To convince him to take the assignment, they not only promise him his freedom but his life. You see, this is because they implanted a nanoprobe into him that will kill him if the assignment isn't completed in 24 hours! Can he do it? What do you think? As I said above, Plissken is played in such an overly serious and over-the-top manner that the film is really a hoot to watch. Also, the film is very original even if it is silly. A few other things I loved were the faux computer graphics (done amazingly well considering everything--see the IMDb trivia for more on this), the scene towards the end of the President having his revenge on 'The Duke' and the incredible soundtrack (by Carpenter himself). All in all, a dumb but incredibly cool guilty pleasure. And sometimes you just have to let your brain relax and watch something mindlessly fun.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Future Is Now Past.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    John Carpenter directed this exciting action yarn that stars Kurt Russell(excellent performance) as Snake Plissken, a wanted criminal and amoral mercenary(think a modern "Man With No Name") that is captured by authorities, but offered a pardon if he will undertake an important mission: rescue the president, who has crash-landed Air Force One into the penal colony of "futuristic"(1997) Manhattan, which has been sealed off from the rest of the country after the crime rate skyrockets. The president(played by Donald Pleasance) is being held by a powerful gang as a bargaining ploy, and Snake must rescue him, and retrieve an important document related to a speech he was going to give. After gliding in, he has a limited amount of time to find the president, before a poison kills him(he will be given the antidote upon successful completion of the rescue.) Well-designed and entertaining film has a good cast(Adrienne Barbeau, Ernest Borgnine, and Lee Van Cleef among them). Well worth watching, and a lot of fun.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    John Carpenter Classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SnoopyStyle
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    John Carpenter creates one of the most original movie and an iconic fantasy world. 'Escape from New York' is a cult classic. It's the future 1997, Manhattan has been turned into a maximum security prison. The President had to do an emergency ejection, but lands inside the prison. Snake Plissken (Kurt Russell) is coerced into bringing the President and his cargo out. Once inside, Snake gets help from Cabbie (Ernest Borgnine), and Maggie (Adrienne Barbeau). This was about the beginning of the end of the '70s crime ridden NY paranoia. The style is no longer realism but rather surreal. It is the best of campy adventure. Kurt Russell creates an iconic character.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "There was an accident. About an hour ago, a small jet went down inside New York City. The President was on board." "President of what?"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Al_The_Strange
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In this dark dystopian sci-fi adventure, ultimate tough guy Snake Plissken is sent on a mission to enter New York, a city now turned into the world's largest penitentiary with a huge retaining wall, to rescue the President from a group of the roughest and most violent criminals imaginable. Sounds awesome, right? Escape From New York has all the right elements to make something awesome. The premise, the characters, the settings, and the overall essence of the film are indeed awesome. However, in the hands of John Carpenter, the film moves at a slow and brooding pace. It's the same creepy, methodic style that makes his other movies - Halloween, The Fog, Christine, The Thing  so effective. For this movie, I never felt that it works as well as it should: the film creeps along so much in the dark that all sense of action and excitement is dampened. When action does hit  a few pedestrian scenes where bad guys throw rocks and sticks, beat and rape a few people, throw Snake into a death match arena, and then finally chase the heroes across a mined bridge  it's all pretty lightweight, lacking in particularly deep impact or thrills. I can't help but to think that, in the hands of guys like John McTiernan or Paul Verhoeven, Escape From NY could be the awesomest, pulpiest, and most badass movie out there. As it is, it's mildly cool, but it never fully capitalizes off of its own potential. The story this film tells is pretty neat, filled with some far-out sci-fi concepts (ideas that would be replicated in plenty of other films, most blatant of which is Doomdsay). The actual plot is pretty standard; it gives you just enough to the story and characters to understand what's going on and to kick off the big adventure, but there's not much depth or exploration offered beyond the surface-level expositions. Characters are pretty flat and lifeless all around, except for Snake Plissken, who is the epitome of cool, with his moody, dangerous, devil-may-care attitude. His character is not only a great antihero, but also a massive influence on other popular characters (remember Solid Snake from Metal Gear Solid?). The only problem is, you never really learn much about Snake beyond that surface level; he is as one-dimensional as everybody else. There are moments where I also wonder if this movie tries to pick at some social themes regarding American society and culture; after all, this is one of America's biggest and most popular cities turned into a total hellhole, and it's the American President caught up in the middle of the chaos. There are times when it seems like the film is underscoring the ugly undercurrent of social corruption and decay, but these themes never really materialize into anything tangible. This film uses rather pedestrian photography, in a manner not much different than Halloween. The camera moves and angles are interesting at times, but the shots are so long that they appear pretty indistinctive. Lighting is very dark throughout, for appropriate effect. Editing is good. Acting is generally okay: Kurt Russell is the man throughout, opposite Lee Van Cleef and Isaac Hayes, who also try their best to be tough. Ernest Borgnine provides a little bit of goofiness to the mix, and Adrienne Barbeau adds a little bit of sex appeal. Harry Dean Stanton isn't given much to do, and his role is ultimately forgettable. And, Donald Pleasence is pretty much himself. Writing is okay; there are a few amusing lines. This movie uses sets, props, and costumes that show some limitations, but get the job done very well. John Carpenter's music score is pretty darn cool. Escape From New York has its share of coolness, but it could be cooler yet. It's not terribly exciting, but it is mildly interesting and mildly satisfying. Given its popularity, the film is a must-see for fans of dark and violent dystopian sci-fi. 3.5/5 (Entertainment: Pretty Good | Story: Average | Film: Pretty Good)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Worst Piece of CRAP I've seen in years
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FriscoJoe
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Really? A wall around Manhattan island? No police force and no fire department yet the place hasn't burned down? The whole premise is just plain STUPID. They land a glider on the roof of one of the World Trade Center towers. I worked in the WTC. What happened to the observation deck on top? Hmmmm? Compared to the absolutely moronic plot, though, the WTC flaws are forgivable. Notice that the female leads all have spotless, perfectly made-up faces and hair. Spoiler... sorta'... if you're waiting for Adrienne Barbeau's boobs to "escape", don't hold your breath: they don't. This is a ONE star movie, folks. It belongs in the hall of fame of worst movies ever made, just a shade above Ed Wood's D-Grade movies, but not nearly as unintentionally funny.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Timeless Cult Adventure of the Badass Anti-Hero Snake Plissken
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Claudio Carvalho
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In 1997, Manhattan has been transformed in the New York Maximum Security Penitentiary, where criminals are sent in life sentence. When the Air Force One crashes in Manhattan with the president of the USA (Donald Pleasence) that is traveling to a summit with other leaders, the prison dean Hauk (Lee Van Cleef) proposes a deal to the convicted one-eyed bank robber Snake Plissken (Kurt Russell). If he rescues the president and his tape in less than 23 hours, he would be granted pardon. In order to guarantee full commitment of Snake Plissken, Hauk lures him and injects a lethal capsule in his blood that will dissolve in the scheduled time. Snake Plissken uses a small plane to land one the roof of the World Trade Center. Soon he finds that the tracking device was removed from the president. When he meets the taxi driver Cabbie (Ernest Borgnine), he learns that the warlord The Duke (Isaac Hayes) has captured the president. Now Snake Plissken has to team-up with his former partner Brain (Harry Dean Stanton), who has double-crossed him in the past, and his squeeze Maggie (Adrienne Barbeau) to rescue the president and save his own life. "Escape from New York" is the timeless cult adventure of the badass one- eyed anti-hero Snake Plissken by John Carpenter. It is amazing how this movie has not aged and even after watching it so many times, I do not get tired of it. Kurt Russell has a fantastic shape and is perfect in the role of the tough Snake Plissken. The president dressed with blonde wig and with cosmetics and his rage in the end against The Duke seems to indicate that something else had happened to him besides losing his thumb. The movie has a dream cast and also a wonderful music score. My vote is ten. Title (Brazi): "Fuga de Nova York" ("Escape from New York")
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Classic Old Fashioned Cinematic Look At The Future
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Theo Robertson
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In 1988 America experiences a surge in criminal violence that leads to Manhatten being turned in to one massive prison . In 1997 Airforce One is hijacked and crashes in to the prison . Newly convicted prisoner Snake Plissken is given a be given deal - if he can rescue the president he'll be given an amnesty but only has 22 hours to do so . If the mission fails the world may very well be heading towards World War 3 Earlier tonight I watched AEON FLUX , a film that some could claim is style over substance . I certainly didn't see any substance in that film and if you saw any style let me know what scene it appeared in . ESCAPE FROM NY is entirely different from FLUX . It's directed by John Carpenter who also did the electronic score and opened to moderate business on its released and later became a cult film . It's easy to see why . The camera work might be relatively static but this with hindsight compared to film making in the 21st century is a blessing since the visuals don't overwhelm the storytelling The story itself from real life events that over took this fictional scenario where in 1997 the cold war looks like hotting up big time but I doubt if Mikhail Gorbachev was sitting down at a table thinking ending the cold war would invalidate John Carpenter's vision of the future but that said a Marxist Leninist spouting rhetoric about workers and imperialist pigs does date the film Thankfully the film isn't really interested in politics and concentrates on keeping the audience excited which is does a good job at as Snake finds constant barriers in his way as he tries to find the missing president knowing that the clock is ticking away . Some of the action scenes aren't entirely plausible such as a machine pistol having an unrealistic capacity and despite being a not unlikable anti-hero in the vein of New Hollywood Kurt Russell plays Snake Plissken far too much like Clint Eastwood would have . Has anyone watched Russell's performance and not mentioned Eastwood ? Regardless of this ESCAPE FROM NY is a very enjoyable action thriller set in the future
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good in its own time, but now it feels outdated...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    luger7
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I can understand why a lot of fellows say this is a one of the best action movies, maybe because they watched this when they were younger or kids and it made a good impression on their minds. Well I remember watching this movie when I was a kid, and yes of course I enjoyed it, but never like other action movies I have in high regard like Predator, Commando or Aliens. So I watched Escape From New York again, and sorry dear fans but this is a really boring movie. The plot and the background of the story are not bad, a lot of potential here, but the development and the "action" is just slow and dry. Snake is a good character, i really think so, but this movie didn't age very well.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not Carpenters best work...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Prolox
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    KURT RUSSELL stars as a long thought dead SNAKE PLISSKEN, a former war hero turned notorious outlaw, who is recruited by local law enforcement to help rescue the president of the United States, who's plane has crashed & is trapped behind the walls of New York City in the year 1997, which has now been converted into a maximum security prison, where society's worst nightmares run amok. Implamented with an explosive device that will ignite if he tries to escape from his mission & armed with some nifty gadgets. Snake attempts to keep himself alive & from danger, as he looks for the man's whereabouts, only to discover the President is being held captive by the criminal ruler of New York's prison, a cold hearted criminal played by ISAAC HAYES. When Snake winds up being captured, he is forced to fight for his life against the well armed thugs that work for the main villain & escape with the president, before his time runs out. ESCAPE FROM NEW YORK is hailed as a classic among genre fans, with some even saying it's JOHN CARPENTER'S best work. After hearing so much praise about the film, I just had to see it, mainly because I'm a big fan of Carpenter's work, that & because the film carries a pretty good bevy of talent both in front & behind the screen. Unfortunately after seeing it twice, I was kind of left scratching my head, trying to figure out what everyone is so crazy about the film, because in actuality there really isn't all that much to it. The reason I saw it twice is because I thought I might have missed something or misunderstood it, but sadly all to no avail. Director Carpenter brought along his HALLOWEEN crew, Director of Photography DEAN CUNDEY, Producer DEBRA HILL, Michael Myers himself NICK CASTLE (Who serves as co-writer) Composer ALAN HOWARTH, BARRY BERNARDI (THE FOG) & even JAWS Production designer JOE ALVES & LARRY FRANCO (THE THING/THEY LIVE/ PRINCE OF DARKNESS) JAMES CAMERON (TITANIC) as effect supervisor) & then there's the acting troupe supporting the film, such as Carpenter's then wife, ADRIENNE BARBEAU, HARRY DEAN STANTON, LEE VAN CLEEF & ISAAC HAYES, DONALD PLESEANCE, BUCK FLOWER & KURT RUSSELL as the hero, which is why the film in my eyes, should have turned out a lot better than it did. ESCAPE FROM NEW YORK is billed as a Sci-fi/action film, but there's precious little action to be had throughout the films running time & it's clear Carpenter had much higher aspirations for the film then what he was able to pull off. The film passes the idea off that Manhatten has been converted to a maximum security prison, but yet there's no more than a few small crowds of criminals that could so easily have fit into a normal prison. It's very clear that Carpenter envisioned a much more fuller Manhattan, full of criminals, but that vision is hamstrung by his decent, but still limited budget. Joe Alves was obviously hamstrung by the films tight 7 million dollar budget as well, since he doesn't do much except strewn some rubble around here & there (where was the crumbled statue of Liberty on the box art?) The films plot does indeed show some promise & at the beginning looks to be set to become a very tight action sci-fi thriller, the best of it's kind. But once Plissken is dropped into New York, Carpenter drops the ball. The remainder of the films running time merely shows Russell roaming the streets, visiting old allies, meeting a kind hearted cabbie & visiting abandon buildings & is never engaged in any real fights against scores of criminals, not high powered shoot outs, fist fights, explosions, nothing. Issac Hayes is a good actor, but is hardly anything you would call menacing as the main villain & is unable to pull off that certain sense of dread & intimidation that most action movie villains have & the same goes for the criminals who are paper thin & hardly anything terrifying or even amusing. The acting is fairly decent by all involved...all involved of course with the exception of Kurt Russell. Kurt clearly is playing Snake as a sort of futuristic CLINT EASTWOOD style hero, but this merely just makes Snake bland & hardly makes him an interesting hero. Even worse there's almost no action to speak of minus a very poorly choreographed fight scened where Russell is forced to fend for himself against a brute of a man, in a crudely made wrestling ring, while surrounded by the crazy gangs & a poorly done car chase. In the end, I so desperately wanted to include myself in the millions of fans who love this film. I wanted to embrace it & at the same time, add it as one of Carpenters best work, but I just couldn't. I just couldn't get into the film & there were just to many missed opportunities on hand here that could have made the film really special. JOHN CARPENTER's direction was just as good as it's always been here, but I just felt let down by this movie. Maybe I was just expecting to much out of it, is why I wound up being let down, after hearing about the films hype for many years, I just anticipated a much better film than what I wound up with. In fact I've seen much better films made, that fans were split on. In the end, I'm in the minority of people left scratching my head & wondering what all the fuss was over. Maybe if I would have seen the film when I was younger I would have had different feelings over it, but as it is, ESCAPE FROM NEW YORK just didn't do it for me. It's merely a film that is just hardly above mediocrity. Followed by ESCAPE FROM L.A. **1/2 stars
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sci-Punk Noir
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of the Director's better Movies. It is a completely Cynical and Dark atmosphere that relays its intent on the Audience with an effectiveness that only a talented B-Movie Director could concoct. The ability to take Comic-Book Stories and Characters, dress them up, and announce the whole thing as gritty, sleazy Fun. Style personified. The Film is oozing with Style. From the Haunting, but typical, thumping of the Synthesizer, not one scene in the Daylight (Dawn at best), Thrift Store Chic Costumes, a Larger than Life Anti-Hero, and assorted Street Dregs, mixed with the Classical Chestnut "do this thing and you are Pardoned", it all comes together with simplistic, but Colorful Sets and Graphics and bit of the ol' Ultraviolence. It is Sci-Punk Noir and the Talented Creators both in front of and behind the Camera make for an Amalgamated Apocalyptic Fan Favorite Film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cerebral....sort of like an episode of "Masterpiece Theatre".
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Okay, I'll admit it...my summary is completely ridiculous! "Escape From New York" is anything but cerebral or sophisticated. Instead, it's a rather absurd little sci-fi film that actually manages to be awfully entertaining despite being utterly ridiculous. Much of this is because the film takes itself so very seriously--and this heightens the campy atmosphere and makes the film a lot of fun. This John Carpenter film is set in the near future. Lawlessness has taken hold until society has come up with a strange solution--to turn Manhattan Island into a giant prison. This 'prison' is really just a dumping ground--a dumping ground where there are no guards and no rules--just a weird self-created society of scum. When a terrorist hijacks Air Force One and crashes it into this city, the President is able to use an escape pod--but he lands in the middle of this hellish city. For some odd reason, instead of sending in the Marines or the Navy Seals, they send in one man--'Snake' Plissken (Kurt Russell). Plissken is ridiculously overplayed by Russell--and that adds to the fun. I am pretty sure he didn't take himself very seriously and the viewer certainly can't! Plissken is sort of like Rambo and Clint Eastwood (Russell REALLY had the Eastwood voice down pat)--but even more indestructible! Now Plissken is NOT the hero type. He himself is a convicted criminal but he's also a war hero. To convince him to take the assignment, they not only promise him his freedom but his life. You see, this is because they implanted a nanoprobe into him that will kill him if the assignment isn't completed in 24 hours! Can he do it? What do you think? As I said above, Plissken is played in such an overly serious and over-the-top manner that the film is really a hoot to watch. Also, the film is very original even if it is silly. A few other things I loved were the faux computer graphics (done amazingly well considering everything--see the IMDb trivia for more on this), the scene towards the end of the President having his revenge on 'The Duke' and the incredible soundtrack (by Carpenter himself). All in all, a dumb but incredibly cool guilty pleasure. And sometimes you just have to let your brain relax and watch something mindlessly fun.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Future Is Now Past.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    John Carpenter directed this exciting action yarn that stars Kurt Russell(excellent performance) as Snake Plissken, a wanted criminal and amoral mercenary(think a modern "Man With No Name") that is captured by authorities, but offered a pardon if he will undertake an important mission: rescue the president, who has crash-landed Air Force One into the penal colony of "futuristic"(1997) Manhattan, which has been sealed off from the rest of the country after the crime rate skyrockets. The president(played by Donald Pleasance) is being held by a powerful gang as a bargaining ploy, and Snake must rescue him, and retrieve an important document related to a speech he was going to give. After gliding in, he has a limited amount of time to find the president, before a poison kills him(he will be given the antidote upon successful completion of the rescue.) Well-designed and entertaining film has a good cast(Adrienne Barbeau, Ernest Borgnine, and Lee Van Cleef among them). Well worth watching, and a lot of fun.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    John Carpenter Classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SnoopyStyle
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    John Carpenter creates one of the most original movie and an iconic fantasy world. 'Escape from New York' is a cult classic. It's the future 1997, Manhattan has been turned into a maximum security prison. The President had to do an emergency ejection, but lands inside the prison. Snake Plissken (Kurt Russell) is coerced into bringing the President and his cargo out. Once inside, Snake gets help from Cabbie (Ernest Borgnine), and Maggie (Adrienne Barbeau). This was about the beginning of the end of the '70s crime ridden NY paranoia. The style is no longer realism but rather surreal. It is the best of campy adventure. Kurt Russell creates an iconic character.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "There was an accident. About an hour ago, a small jet went down inside New York City. The President was on board." "President of what?"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Al_The_Strange
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In this dark dystopian sci-fi adventure, ultimate tough guy Snake Plissken is sent on a mission to enter New York, a city now turned into the world's largest penitentiary with a huge retaining wall, to rescue the President from a group of the roughest and most violent criminals imaginable. Sounds awesome, right? Escape From New York has all the right elements to make something awesome. The premise, the characters, the settings, and the overall essence of the film are indeed awesome. However, in the hands of John Carpenter, the film moves at a slow and brooding pace. It's the same creepy, methodic style that makes his other movies - Halloween, The Fog, Christine, The Thing  so effective. For this movie, I never felt that it works as well as it should: the film creeps along so much in the dark that all sense of action and excitement is dampened. When action does hit  a few pedestrian scenes where bad guys throw rocks and sticks, beat and rape a few people, throw Snake into a death match arena, and then finally chase the heroes across a mined bridge  it's all pretty lightweight, lacking in particularly deep impact or thrills. I can't help but to think that, in the hands of guys like John McTiernan or Paul Verhoeven, Escape From NY could be the awesomest, pulpiest, and most badass movie out there. As it is, it's mildly cool, but it never fully capitalizes off of its own potential. The story this film tells is pretty neat, filled with some far-out sci-fi concepts (ideas that would be replicated in plenty of other films, most blatant of which is Doomdsay). The actual plot is pretty standard; it gives you just enough to the story and characters to understand what's going on and to kick off the big adventure, but there's not much depth or exploration offered beyond the surface-level expositions. Characters are pretty flat and lifeless all around, except for Snake Plissken, who is the epitome of cool, with his moody, dangerous, devil-may-care attitude. His character is not only a great antihero, but also a massive influence on other popular characters (remember Solid Snake from Metal Gear Solid?). The only problem is, you never really learn much about Snake beyond that surface level; he is as one-dimensional as everybody else. There are moments where I also wonder if this movie tries to pick at some social themes regarding American society and culture; after all, this is one of America's biggest and most popular cities turned into a total hellhole, and it's the American President caught up in the middle of the chaos. There are times when it seems like the film is underscoring the ugly undercurrent of social corruption and decay, but these themes never really materialize into anything tangible. This film uses rather pedestrian photography, in a manner not much different than Halloween. The camera moves and angles are interesting at times, but the shots are so long that they appear pretty indistinctive. Lighting is very dark throughout, for appropriate effect. Editing is good. Acting is generally okay: Kurt Russell is the man throughout, opposite Lee Van Cleef and Isaac Hayes, who also try their best to be tough. Ernest Borgnine provides a little bit of goofiness to the mix, and Adrienne Barbeau adds a little bit of sex appeal. Harry Dean Stanton isn't given much to do, and his role is ultimately forgettable. And, Donald Pleasence is pretty much himself. Writing is okay; there are a few amusing lines. This movie uses sets, props, and costumes that show some limitations, but get the job done very well. John Carpenter's music score is pretty darn cool. Escape From New York has its share of coolness, but it could be cooler yet. It's not terribly exciting, but it is mildly interesting and mildly satisfying. Given its popularity, the film is a must-see for fans of dark and violent dystopian sci-fi. 3.5/5 (Entertainment: Pretty Good | Story: Average | Film: Pretty Good)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Worst Piece of CRAP I've seen in years
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FriscoJoe
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Really? A wall around Manhattan island? No police force and no fire department yet the place hasn't burned down? The whole premise is just plain STUPID. They land a glider on the roof of one of the World Trade Center towers. I worked in the WTC. What happened to the observation deck on top? Hmmmm? Compared to the absolutely moronic plot, though, the WTC flaws are forgivable. Notice that the female leads all have spotless, perfectly made-up faces and hair. Spoiler... sorta'... if you're waiting for Adrienne Barbeau's boobs to "escape", don't hold your breath: they don't. This is a ONE star movie, folks. It belongs in the hall of fame of worst movies ever made, just a shade above Ed Wood's D-Grade movies, but not nearly as unintentionally funny.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Timeless Cult Adventure of the Badass Anti-Hero Snake Plissken
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Claudio Carvalho
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In 1997, Manhattan has been transformed in the New York Maximum Security Penitentiary, where criminals are sent in life sentence. When the Air Force One crashes in Manhattan with the president of the USA (Donald Pleasence) that is traveling to a summit with other leaders, the prison dean Hauk (Lee Van Cleef) proposes a deal to the convicted one-eyed bank robber Snake Plissken (Kurt Russell). If he rescues the president and his tape in less than 23 hours, he would be granted pardon. In order to guarantee full commitment of Snake Plissken, Hauk lures him and injects a lethal capsule in his blood that will dissolve in the scheduled time. Snake Plissken uses a small plane to land one the roof of the World Trade Center. Soon he finds that the tracking device was removed from the president. When he meets the taxi driver Cabbie (Ernest Borgnine), he learns that the warlord The Duke (Isaac Hayes) has captured the president. Now Snake Plissken has to team-up with his former partner Brain (Harry Dean Stanton), who has double-crossed him in the past, and his squeeze Maggie (Adrienne Barbeau) to rescue the president and save his own life. "Escape from New York" is the timeless cult adventure of the badass one- eyed anti-hero Snake Plissken by John Carpenter. It is amazing how this movie has not aged and even after watching it so many times, I do not get tired of it. Kurt Russell has a fantastic shape and is perfect in the role of the tough Snake Plissken. The president dressed with blonde wig and with cosmetics and his rage in the end against The Duke seems to indicate that something else had happened to him besides losing his thumb. The movie has a dream cast and also a wonderful music score. My vote is ten. Title (Brazi): "Fuga de Nova York" ("Escape from New York")
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Classic Old Fashioned Cinematic Look At The Future
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Theo Robertson
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In 1988 America experiences a surge in criminal violence that leads to Manhatten being turned in to one massive prison . In 1997 Airforce One is hijacked and crashes in to the prison . Newly convicted prisoner Snake Plissken is given a be given deal - if he can rescue the president he'll be given an amnesty but only has 22 hours to do so . If the mission fails the world may very well be heading towards World War 3 Earlier tonight I watched AEON FLUX , a film that some could claim is style over substance . I certainly didn't see any substance in that film and if you saw any style let me know what scene it appeared in . ESCAPE FROM NY is entirely different from FLUX . It's directed by John Carpenter who also did the electronic score and opened to moderate business on its released and later became a cult film . It's easy to see why . The camera work might be relatively static but this with hindsight compared to film making in the 21st century is a blessing since the visuals don't overwhelm the storytelling The story itself from real life events that over took this fictional scenario where in 1997 the cold war looks like hotting up big time but I doubt if Mikhail Gorbachev was sitting down at a table thinking ending the cold war would invalidate John Carpenter's vision of the future but that said a Marxist Leninist spouting rhetoric about workers and imperialist pigs does date the film Thankfully the film isn't really interested in politics and concentrates on keeping the audience excited which is does a good job at as Snake finds constant barriers in his way as he tries to find the missing president knowing that the clock is ticking away . Some of the action scenes aren't entirely plausible such as a machine pistol having an unrealistic capacity and despite being a not unlikable anti-hero in the vein of New Hollywood Kurt Russell plays Snake Plissken far too much like Clint Eastwood would have . Has anyone watched Russell's performance and not mentioned Eastwood ? Regardless of this ESCAPE FROM NY is a very enjoyable action thriller set in the future
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good in its own time, but now it feels outdated...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    luger7
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I can understand why a lot of fellows say this is a one of the best action movies, maybe because they watched this when they were younger or kids and it made a good impression on their minds. Well I remember watching this movie when I was a kid, and yes of course I enjoyed it, but never like other action movies I have in high regard like Predator, Commando or Aliens. So I watched Escape From New York again, and sorry dear fans but this is a really boring movie. The plot and the background of the story are not bad, a lot of potential here, but the development and the "action" is just slow and dry. Snake is a good character, i really think so, but this movie didn't age very well.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not Carpenters best work...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Prolox
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    KURT RUSSELL stars as a long thought dead SNAKE PLISSKEN, a former war hero turned notorious outlaw, who is recruited by local law enforcement to help rescue the president of the United States, who's plane has crashed & is trapped behind the walls of New York City in the year 1997, which has now been converted into a maximum security prison, where society's worst nightmares run amok. Implamented with an explosive device that will ignite if he tries to escape from his mission & armed with some nifty gadgets. Snake attempts to keep himself alive & from danger, as he looks for the man's whereabouts, only to discover the President is being held captive by the criminal ruler of New York's prison, a cold hearted criminal played by ISAAC HAYES. When Snake winds up being captured, he is forced to fight for his life against the well armed thugs that work for the main villain & escape with the president, before his time runs out. ESCAPE FROM NEW YORK is hailed as a classic among genre fans, with some even saying it's JOHN CARPENTER'S best work. After hearing so much praise about the film, I just had to see it, mainly because I'm a big fan of Carpenter's work, that & because the film carries a pretty good bevy of talent both in front & behind the screen. Unfortunately after seeing it twice, I was kind of left scratching my head, trying to figure out what everyone is so crazy about the film, because in actuality there really isn't all that much to it. The reason I saw it twice is because I thought I might have missed something or misunderstood it, but sadly all to no avail. Director Carpenter brought along his HALLOWEEN crew, Director of Photography DEAN CUNDEY, Producer DEBRA HILL, Michael Myers himself NICK CASTLE (Who serves as co-writer) Composer ALAN HOWARTH, BARRY BERNARDI (THE FOG) & even JAWS Production designer JOE ALVES & LARRY FRANCO (THE THING/THEY LIVE/ PRINCE OF DARKNESS) JAMES CAMERON (TITANIC) as effect supervisor) & then there's the acting troupe supporting the film, such as Carpenter's then wife, ADRIENNE BARBEAU, HARRY DEAN STANTON, LEE VAN CLEEF & ISAAC HAYES, DONALD PLESEANCE, BUCK FLOWER & KURT RUSSELL as the hero, which is why the film in my eyes, should have turned out a lot better than it did. ESCAPE FROM NEW YORK is billed as a Sci-fi/action film, but there's precious little action to be had throughout the films running time & it's clear Carpenter had much higher aspirations for the film then what he was able to pull off. The film passes the idea off that Manhatten has been converted to a maximum security prison, but yet there's no more than a few small crowds of criminals that could so easily have fit into a normal prison. It's very clear that Carpenter envisioned a much more fuller Manhattan, full of criminals, but that vision is hamstrung by his decent, but still limited budget. Joe Alves was obviously hamstrung by the films tight 7 million dollar budget as well, since he doesn't do much except strewn some rubble around here & there (where was the crumbled statue of Liberty on the box art?) The films plot does indeed show some promise & at the beginning looks to be set to become a very tight action sci-fi thriller, the best of it's kind. But once Plissken is dropped into New York, Carpenter drops the ball. The remainder of the films running time merely shows Russell roaming the streets, visiting old allies, meeting a kind hearted cabbie & visiting abandon buildings & is never engaged in any real fights against scores of criminals, not high powered shoot outs, fist fights, explosions, nothing. Issac Hayes is a good actor, but is hardly anything you would call menacing as the main villain & is unable to pull off that certain sense of dread & intimidation that most action movie villains have & the same goes for the criminals who are paper thin & hardly anything terrifying or even amusing. The acting is fairly decent by all involved...all involved of course with the exception of Kurt Russell. Kurt clearly is playing Snake as a sort of futuristic CLINT EASTWOOD style hero, but this merely just makes Snake bland & hardly makes him an interesting hero. Even worse there's almost no action to speak of minus a very poorly choreographed fight scened where Russell is forced to fend for himself against a brute of a man, in a crudely made wrestling ring, while surrounded by the crazy gangs & a poorly done car chase. In the end, I so desperately wanted to include myself in the millions of fans who love this film. I wanted to embrace it & at the same time, add it as one of Carpenters best work, but I just couldn't. I just couldn't get into the film & there were just to many missed opportunities on hand here that could have made the film really special. JOHN CARPENTER's direction was just as good as it's always been here, but I just felt let down by this movie. Maybe I was just expecting to much out of it, is why I wound up being let down, after hearing about the films hype for many years, I just anticipated a much better film than what I wound up with. In fact I've seen much better films made, that fans were split on. In the end, I'm in the minority of people left scratching my head & wondering what all the fuss was over. Maybe if I would have seen the film when I was younger I would have had different feelings over it, but as it is, ESCAPE FROM NEW YORK just didn't do it for me. It's merely a film that is just hardly above mediocrity. Followed by ESCAPE FROM L.A. **1/2 stars
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sci-Punk Noir
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of the Director's better Movies. It is a completely Cynical and Dark atmosphere that relays its intent on the Audience with an effectiveness that only a talented B-Movie Director could concoct. The ability to take Comic-Book Stories and Characters, dress them up, and announce the whole thing as gritty, sleazy Fun. Style personified. The Film is oozing with Style. From the Haunting, but typical, thumping of the Synthesizer, not one scene in the Daylight (Dawn at best), Thrift Store Chic Costumes, a Larger than Life Anti-Hero, and assorted Street Dregs, mixed with the Classical Chestnut "do this thing and you are Pardoned", it all comes together with simplistic, but Colorful Sets and Graphics and bit of the ol' Ultraviolence. It is Sci-Punk Noir and the Talented Creators both in front of and behind the Camera make for an Amalgamated Apocalyptic Fan Favorite Film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cerebral....sort of like an episode of "Masterpiece Theatre".
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Okay, I'll admit it...my summary is completely ridiculous! "Escape From New York" is anything but cerebral or sophisticated. Instead, it's a rather absurd little sci-fi film that actually manages to be awfully entertaining despite being utterly ridiculous. Much of this is because the film takes itself so very seriously--and this heightens the campy atmosphere and makes the film a lot of fun. This John Carpenter film is set in the near future. Lawlessness has taken hold until society has come up with a strange solution--to turn Manhattan Island into a giant prison. This 'prison' is really just a dumping ground--a dumping ground where there are no guards and no rules--just a weird self-created society of scum. When a terrorist hijacks Air Force One and crashes it into this city, the President is able to use an escape pod--but he lands in the middle of this hellish city. For some odd reason, instead of sending in the Marines or the Navy Seals, they send in one man--'Snake' Plissken (Kurt Russell). Plissken is ridiculously overplayed by Russell--and that adds to the fun. I am pretty sure he didn't take himself very seriously and the viewer certainly can't! Plissken is sort of like Rambo and Clint Eastwood (Russell REALLY had the Eastwood voice down pat)--but even more indestructible! Now Plissken is NOT the hero type. He himself is a convicted criminal but he's also a war hero. To convince him to take the assignment, they not only promise him his freedom but his life. You see, this is because they implanted a nanoprobe into him that will kill him if the assignment isn't completed in 24 hours! Can he do it? What do you think? As I said above, Plissken is played in such an overly serious and over-the-top manner that the film is really a hoot to watch. Also, the film is very original even if it is silly. A few other things I loved were the faux computer graphics (done amazingly well considering everything--see the IMDb trivia for more on this), the scene towards the end of the President having his revenge on 'The Duke' and the incredible soundtrack (by Carpenter himself). All in all, a dumb but incredibly cool guilty pleasure. And sometimes you just have to let your brain relax and watch something mindlessly fun.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Future Is Now Past.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    John Carpenter directed this exciting action yarn that stars Kurt Russell(excellent performance) as Snake Plissken, a wanted criminal and amoral mercenary(think a modern "Man With No Name") that is captured by authorities, but offered a pardon if he will undertake an important mission: rescue the president, who has crash-landed Air Force One into the penal colony of "futuristic"(1997) Manhattan, which has been sealed off from the rest of the country after the crime rate skyrockets. The president(played by Donald Pleasance) is being held by a powerful gang as a bargaining ploy, and Snake must rescue him, and retrieve an important document related to a speech he was going to give. After gliding in, he has a limited amount of time to find the president, before a poison kills him(he will be given the antidote upon successful completion of the rescue.) Well-designed and entertaining film has a good cast(Adrienne Barbeau, Ernest Borgnine, and Lee Van Cleef among them). Well worth watching, and a lot of fun.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    John Carpenter Classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SnoopyStyle
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    John Carpenter creates one of the most original movie and an iconic fantasy world. 'Escape from New York' is a cult classic. It's the future 1997, Manhattan has been turned into a maximum security prison. The President had to do an emergency ejection, but lands inside the prison. Snake Plissken (Kurt Russell) is coerced into bringing the President and his cargo out. Once inside, Snake gets help from Cabbie (Ernest Borgnine), and Maggie (Adrienne Barbeau). This was about the beginning of the end of the '70s crime ridden NY paranoia. The style is no longer realism but rather surreal. It is the best of campy adventure. Kurt Russell creates an iconic character.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "There was an accident. About an hour ago, a small jet went down inside New York City. The President was on board." "President of what?"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Al_The_Strange
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In this dark dystopian sci-fi adventure, ultimate tough guy Snake Plissken is sent on a mission to enter New York, a city now turned into the world's largest penitentiary with a huge retaining wall, to rescue the President from a group of the roughest and most violent criminals imaginable. Sounds awesome, right? Escape From New York has all the right elements to make something awesome. The premise, the characters, the settings, and the overall essence of the film are indeed awesome. However, in the hands of John Carpenter, the film moves at a slow and brooding pace. It's the same creepy, methodic style that makes his other movies - Halloween, The Fog, Christine, The Thing  so effective. For this movie, I never felt that it works as well as it should: the film creeps along so much in the dark that all sense of action and excitement is dampened. When action does hit  a few pedestrian scenes where bad guys throw rocks and sticks, beat and rape a few people, throw Snake into a death match arena, and then finally chase the heroes across a mined bridge  it's all pretty lightweight, lacking in particularly deep impact or thrills. I can't help but to think that, in the hands of guys like John McTiernan or Paul Verhoeven, Escape From NY could be the awesomest, pulpiest, and most badass movie out there. As it is, it's mildly cool, but it never fully capitalizes off of its own potential. The story this film tells is pretty neat, filled with some far-out sci-fi concepts (ideas that would be replicated in plenty of other films, most blatant of which is Doomdsay). The actual plot is pretty standard; it gives you just enough to the story and characters to understand what's going on and to kick off the big adventure, but there's not much depth or exploration offered beyond the surface-level expositions. Characters are pretty flat and lifeless all around, except for Snake Plissken, who is the epitome of cool, with his moody, dangerous, devil-may-care attitude. His character is not only a great antihero, but also a massive influence on other popular characters (remember Solid Snake from Metal Gear Solid?). The only problem is, you never really learn much about Snake beyond that surface level; he is as one-dimensional as everybody else. There are moments where I also wonder if this movie tries to pick at some social themes regarding American society and culture; after all, this is one of America's biggest and most popular cities turned into a total hellhole, and it's the American President caught up in the middle of the chaos. There are times when it seems like the film is underscoring the ugly undercurrent of social corruption and decay, but these themes never really materialize into anything tangible. This film uses rather pedestrian photography, in a manner not much different than Halloween. The camera moves and angles are interesting at times, but the shots are so long that they appear pretty indistinctive. Lighting is very dark throughout, for appropriate effect. Editing is good. Acting is generally okay: Kurt Russell is the man throughout, opposite Lee Van Cleef and Isaac Hayes, who also try their best to be tough. Ernest Borgnine provides a little bit of goofiness to the mix, and Adrienne Barbeau adds a little bit of sex appeal. Harry Dean Stanton isn't given much to do, and his role is ultimately forgettable. And, Donald Pleasence is pretty much himself. Writing is okay; there are a few amusing lines. This movie uses sets, props, and costumes that show some limitations, but get the job done very well. John Carpenter's music score is pretty darn cool. Escape From New York has its share of coolness, but it could be cooler yet. It's not terribly exciting, but it is mildly interesting and mildly satisfying. Given its popularity, the film is a must-see for fans of dark and violent dystopian sci-fi. 3.5/5 (Entertainment: Pretty Good | Story: Average | Film: Pretty Good)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Worst Piece of CRAP I've seen in years
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FriscoJoe
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Really? A wall around Manhattan island? No police force and no fire department yet the place hasn't burned down? The whole premise is just plain STUPID. They land a glider on the roof of one of the World Trade Center towers. I worked in the WTC. What happened to the observation deck on top? Hmmmm? Compared to the absolutely moronic plot, though, the WTC flaws are forgivable. Notice that the female leads all have spotless, perfectly made-up faces and hair. Spoiler... sorta'... if you're waiting for Adrienne Barbeau's boobs to "escape", don't hold your breath: they don't. This is a ONE star movie, folks. It belongs in the hall of fame of worst movies ever made, just a shade above Ed Wood's D-Grade movies, but not nearly as unintentionally funny.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Timeless Cult Adventure of the Badass Anti-Hero Snake Plissken
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Claudio Carvalho
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In 1997, Manhattan has been transformed in the New York Maximum Security Penitentiary, where criminals are sent in life sentence. When the Air Force One crashes in Manhattan with the president of the USA (Donald Pleasence) that is traveling to a summit with other leaders, the prison dean Hauk (Lee Van Cleef) proposes a deal to the convicted one-eyed bank robber Snake Plissken (Kurt Russell). If he rescues the president and his tape in less than 23 hours, he would be granted pardon. In order to guarantee full commitment of Snake Plissken, Hauk lures him and injects a lethal capsule in his blood that will dissolve in the scheduled time. Snake Plissken uses a small plane to land one the roof of the World Trade Center. Soon he finds that the tracking device was removed from the president. When he meets the taxi driver Cabbie (Ernest Borgnine), he learns that the warlord The Duke (Isaac Hayes) has captured the president. Now Snake Plissken has to team-up with his former partner Brain (Harry Dean Stanton), who has double-crossed him in the past, and his squeeze Maggie (Adrienne Barbeau) to rescue the president and save his own life. "Escape from New York" is the timeless cult adventure of the badass one- eyed anti-hero Snake Plissken by John Carpenter. It is amazing how this movie has not aged and even after watching it so many times, I do not get tired of it. Kurt Russell has a fantastic shape and is perfect in the role of the tough Snake Plissken. The president dressed with blonde wig and with cosmetics and his rage in the end against The Duke seems to indicate that something else had happened to him besides losing his thumb. The movie has a dream cast and also a wonderful music score. My vote is ten. Title (Brazi): "Fuga de Nova York" ("Escape from New York")
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Classic Old Fashioned Cinematic Look At The Future
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Theo Robertson
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In 1988 America experiences a surge in criminal violence that leads to Manhatten being turned in to one massive prison . In 1997 Airforce One is hijacked and crashes in to the prison . Newly convicted prisoner Snake Plissken is given a be given deal - if he can rescue the president he'll be given an amnesty but only has 22 hours to do so . If the mission fails the world may very well be heading towards World War 3 Earlier tonight I watched AEON FLUX , a film that some could claim is style over substance . I certainly didn't see any substance in that film and if you saw any style let me know what scene it appeared in . ESCAPE FROM NY is entirely different from FLUX . It's directed by John Carpenter who also did the electronic score and opened to moderate business on its released and later became a cult film . It's easy to see why . The camera work might be relatively static but this with hindsight compared to film making in the 21st century is a blessing since the visuals don't overwhelm the storytelling The story itself from real life events that over took this fictional scenario where in 1997 the cold war looks like hotting up big time but I doubt if Mikhail Gorbachev was sitting down at a table thinking ending the cold war would invalidate John Carpenter's vision of the future but that said a Marxist Leninist spouting rhetoric about workers and imperialist pigs does date the film Thankfully the film isn't really interested in politics and concentrates on keeping the audience excited which is does a good job at as Snake finds constant barriers in his way as he tries to find the missing president knowing that the clock is ticking away . Some of the action scenes aren't entirely plausible such as a machine pistol having an unrealistic capacity and despite being a not unlikable anti-hero in the vein of New Hollywood Kurt Russell plays Snake Plissken far too much like Clint Eastwood would have . Has anyone watched Russell's performance and not mentioned Eastwood ? Regardless of this ESCAPE FROM NY is a very enjoyable action thriller set in the future
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good in its own time, but now it feels outdated...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    luger7
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I can understand why a lot of fellows say this is a one of the best action movies, maybe because they watched this when they were younger or kids and it made a good impression on their minds. Well I remember watching this movie when I was a kid, and yes of course I enjoyed it, but never like other action movies I have in high regard like Predator, Commando or Aliens. So I watched Escape From New York again, and sorry dear fans but this is a really boring movie. The plot and the background of the story are not bad, a lot of potential here, but the development and the "action" is just slow and dry. Snake is a good character, i really think so, but this movie didn't age very well.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not Carpenters best work...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Prolox
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    KURT RUSSELL stars as a long thought dead SNAKE PLISSKEN, a former war hero turned notorious outlaw, who is recruited by local law enforcement to help rescue the president of the United States, who's plane has crashed & is trapped behind the walls of New York City in the year 1997, which has now been converted into a maximum security prison, where society's worst nightmares run amok. Implamented with an explosive device that will ignite if he tries to escape from his mission & armed with some nifty gadgets. Snake attempts to keep himself alive & from danger, as he looks for the man's whereabouts, only to discover the President is being held captive by the criminal ruler of New York's prison, a cold hearted criminal played by ISAAC HAYES. When Snake winds up being captured, he is forced to fight for his life against the well armed thugs that work for the main villain & escape with the president, before his time runs out. ESCAPE FROM NEW YORK is hailed as a classic among genre fans, with some even saying it's JOHN CARPENTER'S best work. After hearing so much praise about the film, I just had to see it, mainly because I'm a big fan of Carpenter's work, that & because the film carries a pretty good bevy of talent both in front & behind the screen. Unfortunately after seeing it twice, I was kind of left scratching my head, trying to figure out what everyone is so crazy about the film, because in actuality there really isn't all that much to it. The reason I saw it twice is because I thought I might have missed something or misunderstood it, but sadly all to no avail. Director Carpenter brought along his HALLOWEEN crew, Director of Photography DEAN CUNDEY, Producer DEBRA HILL, Michael Myers himself NICK CASTLE (Who serves as co-writer) Composer ALAN HOWARTH, BARRY BERNARDI (THE FOG) & even JAWS Production designer JOE ALVES & LARRY FRANCO (THE THING/THEY LIVE/ PRINCE OF DARKNESS) JAMES CAMERON (TITANIC) as effect supervisor) & then there's the acting troupe supporting the film, such as Carpenter's then wife, ADRIENNE BARBEAU, HARRY DEAN STANTON, LEE VAN CLEEF & ISAAC HAYES, DONALD PLESEANCE, BUCK FLOWER & KURT RUSSELL as the hero, which is why the film in my eyes, should have turned out a lot better than it did. ESCAPE FROM NEW YORK is billed as a Sci-fi/action film, but there's precious little action to be had throughout the films running time & it's clear Carpenter had much higher aspirations for the film then what he was able to pull off. The film passes the idea off that Manhatten has been converted to a maximum security prison, but yet there's no more than a few small crowds of criminals that could so easily have fit into a normal prison. It's very clear that Carpenter envisioned a much more fuller Manhattan, full of criminals, but that vision is hamstrung by his decent, but still limited budget. Joe Alves was obviously hamstrung by the films tight 7 million dollar budget as well, since he doesn't do much except strewn some rubble around here & there (where was the crumbled statue of Liberty on the box art?) The films plot does indeed show some promise & at the beginning looks to be set to become a very tight action sci-fi thriller, the best of it's kind. But once Plissken is dropped into New York, Carpenter drops the ball. The remainder of the films running time merely shows Russell roaming the streets, visiting old allies, meeting a kind hearted cabbie & visiting abandon buildings & is never engaged in any real fights against scores of criminals, not high powered shoot outs, fist fights, explosions, nothing. Issac Hayes is a good actor, but is hardly anything you would call menacing as the main villain & is unable to pull off that certain sense of dread & intimidation that most action movie villains have & the same goes for the criminals who are paper thin & hardly anything terrifying or even amusing. The acting is fairly decent by all involved...all involved of course with the exception of Kurt Russell. Kurt clearly is playing Snake as a sort of futuristic CLINT EASTWOOD style hero, but this merely just makes Snake bland & hardly makes him an interesting hero. Even worse there's almost no action to speak of minus a very poorly choreographed fight scened where Russell is forced to fend for himself against a brute of a man, in a crudely made wrestling ring, while surrounded by the crazy gangs & a poorly done car chase. In the end, I so desperately wanted to include myself in the millions of fans who love this film. I wanted to embrace it & at the same time, add it as one of Carpenters best work, but I just couldn't. I just couldn't get into the film & there were just to many missed opportunities on hand here that could have made the film really special. JOHN CARPENTER's direction was just as good as it's always been here, but I just felt let down by this movie. Maybe I was just expecting to much out of it, is why I wound up being let down, after hearing about the films hype for many years, I just anticipated a much better film than what I wound up with. In fact I've seen much better films made, that fans were split on. In the end, I'm in the minority of people left scratching my head & wondering what all the fuss was over. Maybe if I would have seen the film when I was younger I would have had different feelings over it, but as it is, ESCAPE FROM NEW YORK just didn't do it for me. It's merely a film that is just hardly above mediocrity. Followed by ESCAPE FROM L.A. **1/2 stars
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sci-Punk Noir
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of the Director's better Movies. It is a completely Cynical and Dark atmosphere that relays its intent on the Audience with an effectiveness that only a talented B-Movie Director could concoct. The ability to take Comic-Book Stories and Characters, dress them up, and announce the whole thing as gritty, sleazy Fun. Style personified. The Film is oozing with Style. From the Haunting, but typical, thumping of the Synthesizer, not one scene in the Daylight (Dawn at best), Thrift Store Chic Costumes, a Larger than Life Anti-Hero, and assorted Street Dregs, mixed with the Classical Chestnut "do this thing and you are Pardoned", it all comes together with simplistic, but Colorful Sets and Graphics and bit of the ol' Ultraviolence. It is Sci-Punk Noir and the Talented Creators both in front of and behind the Camera make for an Amalgamated Apocalyptic Fan Favorite Film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cerebral....sort of like an episode of "Masterpiece Theatre".
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Okay, I'll admit it...my summary is completely ridiculous! "Escape From New York" is anything but cerebral or sophisticated. Instead, it's a rather absurd little sci-fi film that actually manages to be awfully entertaining despite being utterly ridiculous. Much of this is because the film takes itself so very seriously--and this heightens the campy atmosphere and makes the film a lot of fun. This John Carpenter film is set in the near future. Lawlessness has taken hold until society has come up with a strange solution--to turn Manhattan Island into a giant prison. This 'prison' is really just a dumping ground--a dumping ground where there are no guards and no rules--just a weird self-created society of scum. When a terrorist hijacks Air Force One and crashes it into this city, the President is able to use an escape pod--but he lands in the middle of this hellish city. For some odd reason, instead of sending in the Marines or the Navy Seals, they send in one man--'Snake' Plissken (Kurt Russell). Plissken is ridiculously overplayed by Russell--and that adds to the fun. I am pretty sure he didn't take himself very seriously and the viewer certainly can't! Plissken is sort of like Rambo and Clint Eastwood (Russell REALLY had the Eastwood voice down pat)--but even more indestructible! Now Plissken is NOT the hero type. He himself is a convicted criminal but he's also a war hero. To convince him to take the assignment, they not only promise him his freedom but his life. You see, this is because they implanted a nanoprobe into him that will kill him if the assignment isn't completed in 24 hours! Can he do it? What do you think? As I said above, Plissken is played in such an overly serious and over-the-top manner that the film is really a hoot to watch. Also, the film is very original even if it is silly. A few other things I loved were the faux computer graphics (done amazingly well considering everything--see the IMDb trivia for more on this), the scene towards the end of the President having his revenge on 'The Duke' and the incredible soundtrack (by Carpenter himself). All in all, a dumb but incredibly cool guilty pleasure. And sometimes you just have to let your brain relax and watch something mindlessly fun.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Future Is Now Past.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    John Carpenter directed this exciting action yarn that stars Kurt Russell(excellent performance) as Snake Plissken, a wanted criminal and amoral mercenary(think a modern "Man With No Name") that is captured by authorities, but offered a pardon if he will undertake an important mission: rescue the president, who has crash-landed Air Force One into the penal colony of "futuristic"(1997) Manhattan, which has been sealed off from the rest of the country after the crime rate skyrockets. The president(played by Donald Pleasance) is being held by a powerful gang as a bargaining ploy, and Snake must rescue him, and retrieve an important document related to a speech he was going to give. After gliding in, he has a limited amount of time to find the president, before a poison kills him(he will be given the antidote upon successful completion of the rescue.) Well-designed and entertaining film has a good cast(Adrienne Barbeau, Ernest Borgnine, and Lee Van Cleef among them). Well worth watching, and a lot of fun.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    John Carpenter Classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SnoopyStyle
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    John Carpenter creates one of the most original movie and an iconic fantasy world. 'Escape from New York' is a cult classic. It's the future 1997, Manhattan has been turned into a maximum security prison. The President had to do an emergency ejection, but lands inside the prison. Snake Plissken (Kurt Russell) is coerced into bringing the President and his cargo out. Once inside, Snake gets help from Cabbie (Ernest Borgnine), and Maggie (Adrienne Barbeau). This was about the beginning of the end of the '70s crime ridden NY paranoia. The style is no longer realism but rather surreal. It is the best of campy adventure. Kurt Russell creates an iconic character.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "There was an accident. About an hour ago, a small jet went down inside New York City. The President was on board." "President of what?"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Al_The_Strange
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In this dark dystopian sci-fi adventure, ultimate tough guy Snake Plissken is sent on a mission to enter New York, a city now turned into the world's largest penitentiary with a huge retaining wall, to rescue the President from a group of the roughest and most violent criminals imaginable. Sounds awesome, right? Escape From New York has all the right elements to make something awesome. The premise, the characters, the settings, and the overall essence of the film are indeed awesome. However, in the hands of John Carpenter, the film moves at a slow and brooding pace. It's the same creepy, methodic style that makes his other movies - Halloween, The Fog, Christine, The Thing  so effective. For this movie, I never felt that it works as well as it should: the film creeps along so much in the dark that all sense of action and excitement is dampened. When action does hit  a few pedestrian scenes where bad guys throw rocks and sticks, beat and rape a few people, throw Snake into a death match arena, and then finally chase the heroes across a mined bridge  it's all pretty lightweight, lacking in particularly deep impact or thrills. I can't help but to think that, in the hands of guys like John McTiernan or Paul Verhoeven, Escape From NY could be the awesomest, pulpiest, and most badass movie out there. As it is, it's mildly cool, but it never fully capitalizes off of its own potential. The story this film tells is pretty neat, filled with some far-out sci-fi concepts (ideas that would be replicated in plenty of other films, most blatant of which is Doomdsay). The actual plot is pretty standard; it gives you just enough to the story and characters to understand what's going on and to kick off the big adventure, but there's not much depth or exploration offered beyond the surface-level expositions. Characters are pretty flat and lifeless all around, except for Snake Plissken, who is the epitome of cool, with his moody, dangerous, devil-may-care attitude. His character is not only a great antihero, but also a massive influence on other popular characters (remember Solid Snake from Metal Gear Solid?). The only problem is, you never really learn much about Snake beyond that surface level; he is as one-dimensional as everybody else. There are moments where I also wonder if this movie tries to pick at some social themes regarding American society and culture; after all, this is one of America's biggest and most popular cities turned into a total hellhole, and it's the American President caught up in the middle of the chaos. There are times when it seems like the film is underscoring the ugly undercurrent of social corruption and decay, but these themes never really materialize into anything tangible. This film uses rather pedestrian photography, in a manner not much different than Halloween. The camera moves and angles are interesting at times, but the shots are so long that they appear pretty indistinctive. Lighting is very dark throughout, for appropriate effect. Editing is good. Acting is generally okay: Kurt Russell is the man throughout, opposite Lee Van Cleef and Isaac Hayes, who also try their best to be tough. Ernest Borgnine provides a little bit of goofiness to the mix, and Adrienne Barbeau adds a little bit of sex appeal. Harry Dean Stanton isn't given much to do, and his role is ultimately forgettable. And, Donald Pleasence is pretty much himself. Writing is okay; there are a few amusing lines. This movie uses sets, props, and costumes that show some limitations, but get the job done very well. John Carpenter's music score is pretty darn cool. Escape From New York has its share of coolness, but it could be cooler yet. It's not terribly exciting, but it is mildly interesting and mildly satisfying. Given its popularity, the film is a must-see for fans of dark and violent dystopian sci-fi. 3.5/5 (Entertainment: Pretty Good | Story: Average | Film: Pretty Good)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Worst Piece of CRAP I've seen in years
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FriscoJoe
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Really? A wall around Manhattan island? No police force and no fire department yet the place hasn't burned down? The whole premise is just plain STUPID. They land a glider on the roof of one of the World Trade Center towers. I worked in the WTC. What happened to the observation deck on top? Hmmmm? Compared to the absolutely moronic plot, though, the WTC flaws are forgivable. Notice that the female leads all have spotless, perfectly made-up faces and hair. Spoiler... sorta'... if you're waiting for Adrienne Barbeau's boobs to "escape", don't hold your breath: they don't. This is a ONE star movie, folks. It belongs in the hall of fame of worst movies ever made, just a shade above Ed Wood's D-Grade movies, but not nearly as unintentionally funny.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Timeless Cult Adventure of the Badass Anti-Hero Snake Plissken
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Claudio Carvalho
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In 1997, Manhattan has been transformed in the New York Maximum Security Penitentiary, where criminals are sent in life sentence. When the Air Force One crashes in Manhattan with the president of the USA (Donald Pleasence) that is traveling to a summit with other leaders, the prison dean Hauk (Lee Van Cleef) proposes a deal to the convicted one-eyed bank robber Snake Plissken (Kurt Russell). If he rescues the president and his tape in less than 23 hours, he would be granted pardon. In order to guarantee full commitment of Snake Plissken, Hauk lures him and injects a lethal capsule in his blood that will dissolve in the scheduled time. Snake Plissken uses a small plane to land one the roof of the World Trade Center. Soon he finds that the tracking device was removed from the president. When he meets the taxi driver Cabbie (Ernest Borgnine), he learns that the warlord The Duke (Isaac Hayes) has captured the president. Now Snake Plissken has to team-up with his former partner Brain (Harry Dean Stanton), who has double-crossed him in the past, and his squeeze Maggie (Adrienne Barbeau) to rescue the president and save his own life. "Escape from New York" is the timeless cult adventure of the badass one- eyed anti-hero Snake Plissken by John Carpenter. It is amazing how this movie has not aged and even after watching it so many times, I do not get tired of it. Kurt Russell has a fantastic shape and is perfect in the role of the tough Snake Plissken. The president dressed with blonde wig and with cosmetics and his rage in the end against The Duke seems to indicate that something else had happened to him besides losing his thumb. The movie has a dream cast and also a wonderful music score. My vote is ten. Title (Brazi): "Fuga de Nova York" ("Escape from New York")
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Classic Old Fashioned Cinematic Look At The Future
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Theo Robertson
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In 1988 America experiences a surge in criminal violence that leads to Manhatten being turned in to one massive prison . In 1997 Airforce One is hijacked and crashes in to the prison . Newly convicted prisoner Snake Plissken is given a be given deal - if he can rescue the president he'll be given an amnesty but only has 22 hours to do so . If the mission fails the world may very well be heading towards World War 3 Earlier tonight I watched AEON FLUX , a film that some could claim is style over substance . I certainly didn't see any substance in that film and if you saw any style let me know what scene it appeared in . ESCAPE FROM NY is entirely different from FLUX . It's directed by John Carpenter who also did the electronic score and opened to moderate business on its released and later became a cult film . It's easy to see why . The camera work might be relatively static but this with hindsight compared to film making in the 21st century is a blessing since the visuals don't overwhelm the storytelling The story itself from real life events that over took this fictional scenario where in 1997 the cold war looks like hotting up big time but I doubt if Mikhail Gorbachev was sitting down at a table thinking ending the cold war would invalidate John Carpenter's vision of the future but that said a Marxist Leninist spouting rhetoric about workers and imperialist pigs does date the film Thankfully the film isn't really interested in politics and concentrates on keeping the audience excited which is does a good job at as Snake finds constant barriers in his way as he tries to find the missing president knowing that the clock is ticking away . Some of the action scenes aren't entirely plausible such as a machine pistol having an unrealistic capacity and despite being a not unlikable anti-hero in the vein of New Hollywood Kurt Russell plays Snake Plissken far too much like Clint Eastwood would have . Has anyone watched Russell's performance and not mentioned Eastwood ? Regardless of this ESCAPE FROM NY is a very enjoyable action thriller set in the future
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good in its own time, but now it feels outdated...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    luger7
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I can understand why a lot of fellows say this is a one of the best action movies, maybe because they watched this when they were younger or kids and it made a good impression on their minds. Well I remember watching this movie when I was a kid, and yes of course I enjoyed it, but never like other action movies I have in high regard like Predator, Commando or Aliens. So I watched Escape From New York again, and sorry dear fans but this is a really boring movie. The plot and the background of the story are not bad, a lot of potential here, but the development and the "action" is just slow and dry. Snake is a good character, i really think so, but this movie didn't age very well.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not Carpenters best work...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Prolox
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    KURT RUSSELL stars as a long thought dead SNAKE PLISSKEN, a former war hero turned notorious outlaw, who is recruited by local law enforcement to help rescue the president of the United States, who's plane has crashed & is trapped behind the walls of New York City in the year 1997, which has now been converted into a maximum security prison, where society's worst nightmares run amok. Implamented with an explosive device that will ignite if he tries to escape from his mission & armed with some nifty gadgets. Snake attempts to keep himself alive & from danger, as he looks for the man's whereabouts, only to discover the President is being held captive by the criminal ruler of New York's prison, a cold hearted criminal played by ISAAC HAYES. When Snake winds up being captured, he is forced to fight for his life against the well armed thugs that work for the main villain & escape with the president, before his time runs out. ESCAPE FROM NEW YORK is hailed as a classic among genre fans, with some even saying it's JOHN CARPENTER'S best work. After hearing so much praise about the film, I just had to see it, mainly because I'm a big fan of Carpenter's work, that & because the film carries a pretty good bevy of talent both in front & behind the screen. Unfortunately after seeing it twice, I was kind of left scratching my head, trying to figure out what everyone is so crazy about the film, because in actuality there really isn't all that much to it. The reason I saw it twice is because I thought I might have missed something or misunderstood it, but sadly all to no avail. Director Carpenter brought along his HALLOWEEN crew, Director of Photography DEAN CUNDEY, Producer DEBRA HILL, Michael Myers himself NICK CASTLE (Who serves as co-writer) Composer ALAN HOWARTH, BARRY BERNARDI (THE FOG) & even JAWS Production designer JOE ALVES & LARRY FRANCO (THE THING/THEY LIVE/ PRINCE OF DARKNESS) JAMES CAMERON (TITANIC) as effect supervisor) & then there's the acting troupe supporting the film, such as Carpenter's then wife, ADRIENNE BARBEAU, HARRY DEAN STANTON, LEE VAN CLEEF & ISAAC HAYES, DONALD PLESEANCE, BUCK FLOWER & KURT RUSSELL as the hero, which is why the film in my eyes, should have turned out a lot better than it did. ESCAPE FROM NEW YORK is billed as a Sci-fi/action film, but there's precious little action to be had throughout the films running time & it's clear Carpenter had much higher aspirations for the film then what he was able to pull off. The film passes the idea off that Manhatten has been converted to a maximum security prison, but yet there's no more than a few small crowds of criminals that could so easily have fit into a normal prison. It's very clear that Carpenter envisioned a much more fuller Manhattan, full of criminals, but that vision is hamstrung by his decent, but still limited budget. Joe Alves was obviously hamstrung by the films tight 7 million dollar budget as well, since he doesn't do much except strewn some rubble around here & there (where was the crumbled statue of Liberty on the box art?) The films plot does indeed show some promise & at the beginning looks to be set to become a very tight action sci-fi thriller, the best of it's kind. But once Plissken is dropped into New York, Carpenter drops the ball. The remainder of the films running time merely shows Russell roaming the streets, visiting old allies, meeting a kind hearted cabbie & visiting abandon buildings & is never engaged in any real fights against scores of criminals, not high powered shoot outs, fist fights, explosions, nothing. Issac Hayes is a good actor, but is hardly anything you would call menacing as the main villain & is unable to pull off that certain sense of dread & intimidation that most action movie villains have & the same goes for the criminals who are paper thin & hardly anything terrifying or even amusing. The acting is fairly decent by all involved...all involved of course with the exception of Kurt Russell. Kurt clearly is playing Snake as a sort of futuristic CLINT EASTWOOD style hero, but this merely just makes Snake bland & hardly makes him an interesting hero. Even worse there's almost no action to speak of minus a very poorly choreographed fight scened where Russell is forced to fend for himself against a brute of a man, in a crudely made wrestling ring, while surrounded by the crazy gangs & a poorly done car chase. In the end, I so desperately wanted to include myself in the millions of fans who love this film. I wanted to embrace it & at the same time, add it as one of Carpenters best work, but I just couldn't. I just couldn't get into the film & there were just to many missed opportunities on hand here that could have made the film really special. JOHN CARPENTER's direction was just as good as it's always been here, but I just felt let down by this movie. Maybe I was just expecting to much out of it, is why I wound up being let down, after hearing about the films hype for many years, I just anticipated a much better film than what I wound up with. In fact I've seen much better films made, that fans were split on. In the end, I'm in the minority of people left scratching my head & wondering what all the fuss was over. Maybe if I would have seen the film when I was younger I would have had different feelings over it, but as it is, ESCAPE FROM NEW YORK just didn't do it for me. It's merely a film that is just hardly above mediocrity. Followed by ESCAPE FROM L.A. **1/2 stars
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sci-Punk Noir
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of the Director's better Movies. It is a completely Cynical and Dark atmosphere that relays its intent on the Audience with an effectiveness that only a talented B-Movie Director could concoct. The ability to take Comic-Book Stories and Characters, dress them up, and announce the whole thing as gritty, sleazy Fun. Style personified. The Film is oozing with Style. From the Haunting, but typical, thumping of the Synthesizer, not one scene in the Daylight (Dawn at best), Thrift Store Chic Costumes, a Larger than Life Anti-Hero, and assorted Street Dregs, mixed with the Classical Chestnut "do this thing and you are Pardoned", it all comes together with simplistic, but Colorful Sets and Graphics and bit of the ol' Ultraviolence. It is Sci-Punk Noir and the Talented Creators both in front of and behind the Camera make for an Amalgamated Apocalyptic Fan Favorite Film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cerebral....sort of like an episode of "Masterpiece Theatre".
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Okay, I'll admit it...my summary is completely ridiculous! "Escape From New York" is anything but cerebral or sophisticated. Instead, it's a rather absurd little sci-fi film that actually manages to be awfully entertaining despite being utterly ridiculous. Much of this is because the film takes itself so very seriously--and this heightens the campy atmosphere and makes the film a lot of fun. This John Carpenter film is set in the near future. Lawlessness has taken hold until society has come up with a strange solution--to turn Manhattan Island into a giant prison. This 'prison' is really just a dumping ground--a dumping ground where there are no guards and no rules--just a weird self-created society of scum. When a terrorist hijacks Air Force One and crashes it into this city, the President is able to use an escape pod--but he lands in the middle of this hellish city. For some odd reason, instead of sending in the Marines or the Navy Seals, they send in one man--'Snake' Plissken (Kurt Russell). Plissken is ridiculously overplayed by Russell--and that adds to the fun. I am pretty sure he didn't take himself very seriously and the viewer certainly can't! Plissken is sort of like Rambo and Clint Eastwood (Russell REALLY had the Eastwood voice down pat)--but even more indestructible! Now Plissken is NOT the hero type. He himself is a convicted criminal but he's also a war hero. To convince him to take the assignment, they not only promise him his freedom but his life. You see, this is because they implanted a nanoprobe into him that will kill him if the assignment isn't completed in 24 hours! Can he do it? What do you think? As I said above, Plissken is played in such an overly serious and over-the-top manner that the film is really a hoot to watch. Also, the film is very original even if it is silly. A few other things I loved were the faux computer graphics (done amazingly well considering everything--see the IMDb trivia for more on this), the scene towards the end of the President having his revenge on 'The Duke' and the incredible soundtrack (by Carpenter himself). All in all, a dumb but incredibly cool guilty pleasure. And sometimes you just have to let your brain relax and watch something mindlessly fun.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Future Is Now Past.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    John Carpenter directed this exciting action yarn that stars Kurt Russell(excellent performance) as Snake Plissken, a wanted criminal and amoral mercenary(think a modern "Man With No Name") that is captured by authorities, but offered a pardon if he will undertake an important mission: rescue the president, who has crash-landed Air Force One into the penal colony of "futuristic"(1997) Manhattan, which has been sealed off from the rest of the country after the crime rate skyrockets. The president(played by Donald Pleasance) is being held by a powerful gang as a bargaining ploy, and Snake must rescue him, and retrieve an important document related to a speech he was going to give. After gliding in, he has a limited amount of time to find the president, before a poison kills him(he will be given the antidote upon successful completion of the rescue.) Well-designed and entertaining film has a good cast(Adrienne Barbeau, Ernest Borgnine, and Lee Van Cleef among them). Well worth watching, and a lot of fun.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    John Carpenter Classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SnoopyStyle
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    John Carpenter creates one of the most original movie and an iconic fantasy world. 'Escape from New York' is a cult classic. It's the future 1997, Manhattan has been turned into a maximum security prison. The President had to do an emergency ejection, but lands inside the prison. Snake Plissken (Kurt Russell) is coerced into bringing the President and his cargo out. Once inside, Snake gets help from Cabbie (Ernest Borgnine), and Maggie (Adrienne Barbeau). This was about the beginning of the end of the '70s crime ridden NY paranoia. The style is no longer realism but rather surreal. It is the best of campy adventure. Kurt Russell creates an iconic character.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "There was an accident. About an hour ago, a small jet went down inside New York City. The President was on board." "President of what?"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Al_The_Strange
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In this dark dystopian sci-fi adventure, ultimate tough guy Snake Plissken is sent on a mission to enter New York, a city now turned into the world's largest penitentiary with a huge retaining wall, to rescue the President from a group of the roughest and most violent criminals imaginable. Sounds awesome, right? Escape From New York has all the right elements to make something awesome. The premise, the characters, the settings, and the overall essence of the film are indeed awesome. However, in the hands of John Carpenter, the film moves at a slow and brooding pace. It's the same creepy, methodic style that makes his other movies - Halloween, The Fog, Christine, The Thing  so effective. For this movie, I never felt that it works as well as it should: the film creeps along so much in the dark that all sense of action and excitement is dampened. When action does hit  a few pedestrian scenes where bad guys throw rocks and sticks, beat and rape a few people, throw Snake into a death match arena, and then finally chase the heroes across a mined bridge  it's all pretty lightweight, lacking in particularly deep impact or thrills. I can't help but to think that, in the hands of guys like John McTiernan or Paul Verhoeven, Escape From NY could be the awesomest, pulpiest, and most badass movie out there. As it is, it's mildly cool, but it never fully capitalizes off of its own potential. The story this film tells is pretty neat, filled with some far-out sci-fi concepts (ideas that would be replicated in plenty of other films, most blatant of which is Doomdsay). The actual plot is pretty standard; it gives you just enough to the story and characters to understand what's going on and to kick off the big adventure, but there's not much depth or exploration offered beyond the surface-level expositions. Characters are pretty flat and lifeless all around, except for Snake Plissken, who is the epitome of cool, with his moody, dangerous, devil-may-care attitude. His character is not only a great antihero, but also a massive influence on other popular characters (remember Solid Snake from Metal Gear Solid?). The only problem is, you never really learn much about Snake beyond that surface level; he is as one-dimensional as everybody else. There are moments where I also wonder if this movie tries to pick at some social themes regarding American society and culture; after all, this is one of America's biggest and most popular cities turned into a total hellhole, and it's the American President caught up in the middle of the chaos. There are times when it seems like the film is underscoring the ugly undercurrent of social corruption and decay, but these themes never really materialize into anything tangible. This film uses rather pedestrian photography, in a manner not much different than Halloween. The camera moves and angles are interesting at times, but the shots are so long that they appear pretty indistinctive. Lighting is very dark throughout, for appropriate effect. Editing is good. Acting is generally okay: Kurt Russell is the man throughout, opposite Lee Van Cleef and Isaac Hayes, who also try their best to be tough. Ernest Borgnine provides a little bit of goofiness to the mix, and Adrienne Barbeau adds a little bit of sex appeal. Harry Dean Stanton isn't given much to do, and his role is ultimately forgettable. And, Donald Pleasence is pretty much himself. Writing is okay; there are a few amusing lines. This movie uses sets, props, and costumes that show some limitations, but get the job done very well. John Carpenter's music score is pretty darn cool. Escape From New York has its share of coolness, but it could be cooler yet. It's not terribly exciting, but it is mildly interesting and mildly satisfying. Given its popularity, the film is a must-see for fans of dark and violent dystopian sci-fi. 3.5/5 (Entertainment: Pretty Good | Story: Average | Film: Pretty Good)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Worst Piece of CRAP I've seen in years
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FriscoJoe
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Really? A wall around Manhattan island? No police force and no fire department yet the place hasn't burned down? The whole premise is just plain STUPID. They land a glider on the roof of one of the World Trade Center towers. I worked in the WTC. What happened to the observation deck on top? Hmmmm? Compared to the absolutely moronic plot, though, the WTC flaws are forgivable. Notice that the female leads all have spotless, perfectly made-up faces and hair. Spoiler... sorta'... if you're waiting for Adrienne Barbeau's boobs to "escape", don't hold your breath: they don't. This is a ONE star movie, folks. It belongs in the hall of fame of worst movies ever made, just a shade above Ed Wood's D-Grade movies, but not nearly as unintentionally funny.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Timeless Cult Adventure of the Badass Anti-Hero Snake Plissken
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Claudio Carvalho
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In 1997, Manhattan has been transformed in the New York Maximum Security Penitentiary, where criminals are sent in life sentence. When the Air Force One crashes in Manhattan with the president of the USA (Donald Pleasence) that is traveling to a summit with other leaders, the prison dean Hauk (Lee Van Cleef) proposes a deal to the convicted one-eyed bank robber Snake Plissken (Kurt Russell). If he rescues the president and his tape in less than 23 hours, he would be granted pardon. In order to guarantee full commitment of Snake Plissken, Hauk lures him and injects a lethal capsule in his blood that will dissolve in the scheduled time. Snake Plissken uses a small plane to land one the roof of the World Trade Center. Soon he finds that the tracking device was removed from the president. When he meets the taxi driver Cabbie (Ernest Borgnine), he learns that the warlord The Duke (Isaac Hayes) has captured the president. Now Snake Plissken has to team-up with his former partner Brain (Harry Dean Stanton), who has double-crossed him in the past, and his squeeze Maggie (Adrienne Barbeau) to rescue the president and save his own life. "Escape from New York" is the timeless cult adventure of the badass one- eyed anti-hero Snake Plissken by John Carpenter. It is amazing how this movie has not aged and even after watching it so many times, I do not get tired of it. Kurt Russell has a fantastic shape and is perfect in the role of the tough Snake Plissken. The president dressed with blonde wig and with cosmetics and his rage in the end against The Duke seems to indicate that something else had happened to him besides losing his thumb. The movie has a dream cast and also a wonderful music score. My vote is ten. Title (Brazi): "Fuga de Nova York" ("Escape from New York")
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Classic Old Fashioned Cinematic Look At The Future
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Theo Robertson
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In 1988 America experiences a surge in criminal violence that leads to Manhatten being turned in to one massive prison . In 1997 Airforce One is hijacked and crashes in to the prison . Newly convicted prisoner Snake Plissken is given a be given deal - if he can rescue the president he'll be given an amnesty but only has 22 hours to do so . If the mission fails the world may very well be heading towards World War 3 Earlier tonight I watched AEON FLUX , a film that some could claim is style over substance . I certainly didn't see any substance in that film and if you saw any style let me know what scene it appeared in . ESCAPE FROM NY is entirely different from FLUX . It's directed by John Carpenter who also did the electronic score and opened to moderate business on its released and later became a cult film . It's easy to see why . The camera work might be relatively static but this with hindsight compared to film making in the 21st century is a blessing since the visuals don't overwhelm the storytelling The story itself from real life events that over took this fictional scenario where in 1997 the cold war looks like hotting up big time but I doubt if Mikhail Gorbachev was sitting down at a table thinking ending the cold war would invalidate John Carpenter's vision of the future but that said a Marxist Leninist spouting rhetoric about workers and imperialist pigs does date the film Thankfully the film isn't really interested in politics and concentrates on keeping the audience excited which is does a good job at as Snake finds constant barriers in his way as he tries to find the missing president knowing that the clock is ticking away . Some of the action scenes aren't entirely plausible such as a machine pistol having an unrealistic capacity and despite being a not unlikable anti-hero in the vein of New Hollywood Kurt Russell plays Snake Plissken far too much like Clint Eastwood would have . Has anyone watched Russell's performance and not mentioned Eastwood ? Regardless of this ESCAPE FROM NY is a very enjoyable action thriller set in the future
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good in its own time, but now it feels outdated...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    luger7
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I can understand why a lot of fellows say this is a one of the best action movies, maybe because they watched this when they were younger or kids and it made a good impression on their minds. Well I remember watching this movie when I was a kid, and yes of course I enjoyed it, but never like other action movies I have in high regard like Predator, Commando or Aliens. So I watched Escape From New York again, and sorry dear fans but this is a really boring movie. The plot and the background of the story are not bad, a lot of potential here, but the development and the "action" is just slow and dry. Snake is a good character, i really think so, but this movie didn't age very well.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not Carpenters best work...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Prolox
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    KURT RUSSELL stars as a long thought dead SNAKE PLISSKEN, a former war hero turned notorious outlaw, who is recruited by local law enforcement to help rescue the president of the United States, who's plane has crashed & is trapped behind the walls of New York City in the year 1997, which has now been converted into a maximum security prison, where society's worst nightmares run amok. Implamented with an explosive device that will ignite if he tries to escape from his mission & armed with some nifty gadgets. Snake attempts to keep himself alive & from danger, as he looks for the man's whereabouts, only to discover the President is being held captive by the criminal ruler of New York's prison, a cold hearted criminal played by ISAAC HAYES. When Snake winds up being captured, he is forced to fight for his life against the well armed thugs that work for the main villain & escape with the president, before his time runs out. ESCAPE FROM NEW YORK is hailed as a classic among genre fans, with some even saying it's JOHN CARPENTER'S best work. After hearing so much praise about the film, I just had to see it, mainly because I'm a big fan of Carpenter's work, that & because the film carries a pretty good bevy of talent both in front & behind the screen. Unfortunately after seeing it twice, I was kind of left scratching my head, trying to figure out what everyone is so crazy about the film, because in actuality there really isn't all that much to it. The reason I saw it twice is because I thought I might have missed something or misunderstood it, but sadly all to no avail. Director Carpenter brought along his HALLOWEEN crew, Director of Photography DEAN CUNDEY, Producer DEBRA HILL, Michael Myers himself NICK CASTLE (Who serves as co-writer) Composer ALAN HOWARTH, BARRY BERNARDI (THE FOG) & even JAWS Production designer JOE ALVES & LARRY FRANCO (THE THING/THEY LIVE/ PRINCE OF DARKNESS) JAMES CAMERON (TITANIC) as effect supervisor) & then there's the acting troupe supporting the film, such as Carpenter's then wife, ADRIENNE BARBEAU, HARRY DEAN STANTON, LEE VAN CLEEF & ISAAC HAYES, DONALD PLESEANCE, BUCK FLOWER & KURT RUSSELL as the hero, which is why the film in my eyes, should have turned out a lot better than it did. ESCAPE FROM NEW YORK is billed as a Sci-fi/action film, but there's precious little action to be had throughout the films running time & it's clear Carpenter had much higher aspirations for the film then what he was able to pull off. The film passes the idea off that Manhatten has been converted to a maximum security prison, but yet there's no more than a few small crowds of criminals that could so easily have fit into a normal prison. It's very clear that Carpenter envisioned a much more fuller Manhattan, full of criminals, but that vision is hamstrung by his decent, but still limited budget. Joe Alves was obviously hamstrung by the films tight 7 million dollar budget as well, since he doesn't do much except strewn some rubble around here & there (where was the crumbled statue of Liberty on the box art?) The films plot does indeed show some promise & at the beginning looks to be set to become a very tight action sci-fi thriller, the best of it's kind. But once Plissken is dropped into New York, Carpenter drops the ball. The remainder of the films running time merely shows Russell roaming the streets, visiting old allies, meeting a kind hearted cabbie & visiting abandon buildings & is never engaged in any real fights against scores of criminals, not high powered shoot outs, fist fights, explosions, nothing. Issac Hayes is a good actor, but is hardly anything you would call menacing as the main villain & is unable to pull off that certain sense of dread & intimidation that most action movie villains have & the same goes for the criminals who are paper thin & hardly anything terrifying or even amusing. The acting is fairly decent by all involved...all involved of course with the exception of Kurt Russell. Kurt clearly is playing Snake as a sort of futuristic CLINT EASTWOOD style hero, but this merely just makes Snake bland & hardly makes him an interesting hero. Even worse there's almost no action to speak of minus a very poorly choreographed fight scened where Russell is forced to fend for himself against a brute of a man, in a crudely made wrestling ring, while surrounded by the crazy gangs & a poorly done car chase. In the end, I so desperately wanted to include myself in the millions of fans who love this film. I wanted to embrace it & at the same time, add it as one of Carpenters best work, but I just couldn't. I just couldn't get into the film & there were just to many missed opportunities on hand here that could have made the film really special. JOHN CARPENTER's direction was just as good as it's always been here, but I just felt let down by this movie. Maybe I was just expecting to much out of it, is why I wound up being let down, after hearing about the films hype for many years, I just anticipated a much better film than what I wound up with. In fact I've seen much better films made, that fans were split on. In the end, I'm in the minority of people left scratching my head & wondering what all the fuss was over. Maybe if I would have seen the film when I was younger I would have had different feelings over it, but as it is, ESCAPE FROM NEW YORK just didn't do it for me. It's merely a film that is just hardly above mediocrity. Followed by ESCAPE FROM L.A. **1/2 stars
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
