<filme>
 <id>
  637
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0082533
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1981
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Grito de Horror
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.5
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  After a bizarre and near fatal encounter with a serial killer, a television newswoman is sent to a remote mountain resort whose residents may not be what they seem.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Television newswoman Karen White takes some much-needed time off after a traumatic incident with a serial killer. Hoping to conquer her inner demons, she heads for The Colony, a secluded retreat where the creepy residents are a little too eager to make her feel at home. Also, there seems to be a bizarre connection between Eddie Quist and this supposedly safe haven. And when, after nights of being tormented by unearthly cries, Karen ventures into the forest and makes a terrifying discovery. Now she must not only fight for her life... but for her very soul! Helped launch the short-lived werewolf craze in the early 1980s.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Horror
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   serial killer
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   colony
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   werewolf
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   night
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   news anchor
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Joe Dante
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Gary Brandner
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   John Sayles
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Dee Wallace
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Patrick Macnee
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Dennis Dugan
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Scary But Fun.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Joe Dante pulled off an impressive feat directing this scary but humorous film about a traumatized newswoman (sweet & appealing Dee Wallace) who is persuaded to go to a mysterious retreat by a noted psychologist(Patrick Macnee, very suave but sympathetic) where her bad luck sadly continues when she is forced to confront some sinister werewolves... Very clever script incorporates real-life werewolf directors as character names, and has awe-inspiring make-up F/X, the first of their kind. Well-directed and suspenseful, though final sequence goes a little too far in self-aware humor. Otherwise, cant-miss film for genre fans.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It goes on a bit
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Despite numerous in-jokes, characters named after horror directors, a cameo by Roger Corman and appearances from Joe Dante favourites Kevin McCarthy, Dick Miller and Robert Picardo, this werewolf movie is almost entirely lacking in enjoyment. It's a dreary and boring movie composed of leaden silences punctuated by droning dialogue recited by flat characters at a droning pace. Dee Wallace is a TV newswoman who heads to a retreat run by doctor Patrick Macnee but finds that her holiday isn't as peaceful as she expected when the place is overrun by werewolves. Although Dante has some fun contrasting what the characters are watching on TV with the events of the movie, the disappointingly droopy plot gets less interesting the more it goes on and by the end, when everyone's bearing their fangs and sprouting rubbery wolf faces, it all looks pretty stupid.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I do hope the book is better
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    siderite
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've begun watching The Howling with high expectations, as someone described it as "one of the 2 best Werewolf movies ever made". Unfortunately, he just might be right, but that is not saying much. Probably the spike in quality is caused by the movie being a book adaptation and I do hope the book was a lot better. Now, don't imagine the movie is very bad. For an 1981 movie with werewolves, indeed it is good, but it has that feel of a money grabbing movie studio doing an adaptation after a money grabbing publisher selling books of a certain type. You've all read those books: somewhere in a small American town, where everybody knows each other and there is dark secret, a city dweller comes to shake up the status quo. Probably Americans read a lot of these books, but I've had it up to my furry neck and my pointy teeth with this kind of bull. It is boring, pretentious and most of the time rehashing similar stories that were probably good when they were written but have now dissolved into lameness. Bottom line: I am sure I have seen this movie before, when I was young, but except the scene at the end, which had its share of drama and societal satire, I did not remember one thing while watching it again now. It is a mostly forgettable movie, with unsympathetic characters and a rushed story so that it can cover the entire book. Yes, indeed, take the story, make it a miniseries in the style of Stephen King adaptations and add some decent acting and special effects, and it would do great today, but this film just feels... wrong.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Disappointed
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SanteeFats
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I realize this movie was made over thirty years ago and it is not a blood and guts for shock value type movie (which I like) buuuuuttt!!! This is one very slow developing story. First if you can become a werewolf by bite or scratch the world would be overrun with them. This one does have them as shape shifters and therefore not tied to the Hollywood stereotypical full moon only ability to change. I will admit that when they started the transformations it was done very well for the time period, no CGI there. Then you have reporter who shows up with (gasp) the magic silver bullets! There is goof here as he first jacks a bullet in to the chamber when he gets out of his car and then again when he is in the office. I do like when he shoots one of the werewolves that has the girl, they rest just stop and stare for a second. See what happens when you are supremely overconfident in your ability to be harmed? I do like the end where she changes on TV and then is shot and killed in full view of the audience. Of course few will believe!!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "The Howling" is a 1980s slow-burning horror classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ersinkdotcom
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After news anchor Karen White (Dee Wallace) is attacked by a mysterious stranger (Robert Picardo), she starts having bizarre dreams and night terrors about the incident. Karen's doctor (Patrick Macnee) convinces her that she and husband Bill (Christopher Stone) should go through his treatment at "The Colony." Strange things start to happen as soon as they arrive. Could Karen be cracking up or is there something sinister going on in the secluded resort? Like most movies from the 1970s and the 1980s, "The Howling" is a slow- burner. This isn't one of those horror films that starts with a bang, keeps a frantic pace, and goes out with a bang. It slowly establishes its plot and characters and gives the audience a little at a time until the climactic and shocking end. Things might move too slowly for today's impatient audience. I even found it tedious at times. The scenes get choppy throughout and it seems like director Joe Dante was rushing things at some points. Rob Bottin's special effects for "The Howling" are still just as effective today as they were in 1981. The werewolf transformation scenes are unnerving and quite detailed. One transformation takes what seems like three to four minutes. It's all about attention to detail when it comes to Bottin's practical effects and animatronics versus today's obsession with rapid fire CGI scenes of metamorphosis. "The Howling" does feature quite a bit of the usual unnecessary nudity found in 1980's horror films. However, this time around director Dante attempts to justify it by analyzing our need to let the beast within out, mostly through sexual and physical acts of violence. The doctor, played by the late Patrick Macnee, convincingly regurgitates a lot of "primal scream" mumbo jumbo throughout the movie. Although it's a bit slow and takes some time getting started, great special effects and interesting, albeit hokey, social commentary set "The Howling" apart from the normal monster movie fare.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Joe Dante and Wolves...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Janis Livens
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Howling is one of the best werewolf movies up their with American Werewolf in London. It has everything you would want from a good monster movie: good scares, good laughs and some great effects. Dee Wallace stars in this werewolf film as a reporter who goes to a strange commune after experiencing a bizarre accident with a serial killer. And from that point it's a roller coaster ride of silly characters, wonderful practical effects and awkward werewolf sex. The Howling is a low budget film made for just one million dollars and looks stunning. The cinematography is absolutely gorgeous and makes a great use of both colour and shadows. Joe Dante's direction lends well to the material and shows what he can do with a simple monster movie premise and turns it into something memorable, funny and even heartbreaking. The performances are pretty good. Dee Wallace is great as the tragic heroine and the supporting cast include such goof ball character actors like John Carradine, Slim Pickens and Robert Pickardo. Not to mention the crazy sexy Elisabeth Brooks who does some kinky werewolf sex and so on. The Howling unlike the modern horror movies that feature werewolves and other supernatural creatures, feature great practical effects that are only rivaled by American Werewolf. However, I wouldn't call this film scary. It's hard to scare me or creep me out with something supernatural and especially if you have Slim Pickens in your movie. But horror movie doesn't need to be that scary to be good unlike comedies that need to be funny to any good. Werewolf movies doesn't get much better than Howling and American Werewolf in London. If you enjoy good monster movies that are made with love and care, you owe it to yourself to watch this film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Undoubtedly the inspiration for Michael Jackson's 'Thriller'
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sherazade
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The special effects were as good as can be expected of a movie made in 1980/81 but other than that is was poorly written, poorly directed, poorly acted (especially by the female actors/characters), poorly edited and there were way too many inconsistencies and plot holes. Werewolves movies were to the 80s what Vampire movies are to us now, some were good and most were bad. I would recommend this movie only to people who are fans of some actor in the film and want to see every film they've ever acted in or for those who want to view it for nostalgic reasons or if you're like me and the movie was before your time and you just want to see what films of this genre looked like that back then.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a werewolf classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    trashgang
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Howling has become the father of the new werewolf flicks in the heydays of the eighties. But there was another masterpiece that sadly came out just after The Howling was released, An American Werewolf In London (1982). Why I'm saying this, because Rick Baker, make-up and special effects was involved in both of them. American Werewolf started earlier then The Howling but had financial problems so Rick started with The Howling but when the director of American Werewolf(John Landis) heard that news money was raised and Barker left The Howling to give it towards Rick Bottin. Rick made it a movie with excellent effects and became notorious surely after The Thing (1982). The Howling wanted to do the werewolf transformation in one shot but money prevented it to become that way. American Werewolf did it. But The Howling was the best known werewolf flick. Although being a classic I prefer American because things starts of immediately. The Howling takes almost 50 minutes before a werewolf comes in and the effects become clear. But I must say that the last 40 minutes are worth watching. What a delight to see. The acting was rather good and the way it was filmed (advised by Bottin to use shadow and not that much of lighting) gave it a creepy feeling. A lot of memorable names are here to see but one that was becoming the next big thing was the werewolf Marsha (Elisabeth Brooks). She was noticed because she went full frontal here but her career was suddenly stopped by cancer, she died age 46. Mixed feelings because it isn't a good movie the first 50 minutes but it's a classic for so many reasons. Still, I gave it an 8 for the effects alone. Still, not that gory for a werewolf flick made in the heydays of slashers. Gore 1,5/5 Nudity 1/5 Effects 5/5 Story 3/5 Comedy 0/5
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Great Werewolf Film!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gwnightscream
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dee Wallace, Patrick Macnee, Christopher Stone, Robert Picardo, Dennis Dugan, Belinda Balaski and Elizabeth Brooks star in Joe Dante's 1981 horror film. This begins with newswoman, Karen White (Wallace) preparing to meet man, Eddie Quist (Picardo) whom reveals his secret being a werewolf and is attacked by him. After Eddie is shot by police but not dead, Karen starts to feel different and tries to remember what happened. Macnee plays doctor, George Waggner who helps her and invites her to his spa in the country, the colony. She goes with her husband, Bill Neil (Stone) and they meet an odd group of people staying there and discover there are werewolves. Dugan plays Karen's friend, Chris, Balaski plays his girlfriend, Teri, the late, Brooks plays Marsha, a woman who seduces Bill and Stone was also Wallace's real-life husband. Dick Miller, Roger Corman and Kevin McCarthy also appear and Rob Bottin's make-up effects are terrific as usual. I recommend this great werewolf film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A smart, sexy, and genuinely scary horror classic that still has plenty of bite
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    happyendingrocks
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The werewolf is sort of the neglected middle child of the horror monster hierarchy: gifted, unique, and brilliant, but eternally overshadowed by its dad the Devil, older vampiric siblings, mummified Egyptian stepsons from a previous marriage, and kid brother zombies who are always getting into trouble and keeping the family distracted. Of course there have been great, even legendary, films with lycanthrope antagonists, but that particular sub-genre is rather limited in scope. However, despite the admitted paucity of competition, I can still say with absolute certainty that The Howling is the best movie about werewolves ever made. It makes sense that the film heavily references The Wolf Man, the eternal Lon Chaney Jr./Universal Monsters staple, because The Howling is executed in a way that clearly reveals its acknowledgment of its roots in the traditions of classic horror. The pace is restrained and meticulous, the atmosphere is a character in itself, and despite the film's utilization of creature effects that weren't even dreamed of in Universal's genre heyday, good old-fashioned ensemble acting is what truly drives the action in the piece. If this description makes The Howling sound like a dry production more suited for the theater stage, don't misunderstand me; this is bloody and ferocious fare that will greatly please fans of visceral horror. But it is the taut and well-crafted story, not merely the FX, that make this such a gem, and director Joe Dante is seasoned enough here to allow a gradual and steady immersion into the film's world before bowling us over with Rob Bottin's peerless set-pieces, which have all the more impact when they take command because of how effectively the movie has teased us with tantalizing glimpses throughout. Though the creatures are understandably a feature attraction here, the main focus of the plot is on news anchor Karen White, who has become the fixation of deranged serial killer Eddie Quist and agrees to be used as bait as part of a police operation to capture him. Quist is seemingly killed during her harrowing and macabre encounter, and Karen is subsequently haunted by bizarre dreams and fuzzy, repressed recollections of what actually occurred that night. When she heeds a pop psychologist's suggestion that she and her husband should attend a therapy retreat he oversees at a secluded commune, the getaway does anything but assuage her trauma. Instead, Karen encounters odd and subtly menacing locals and the titular unholy moans emanating from the fog-shrouded forests. It doesn't take long for us to learn that the commune is located at the nucleus of the hunting grounds prowled by a pack of malevolent predatory beasts, and after Karen's husband is seduced and transformed by a sultry lady wolf, her and her visiting reporter friend begin to uncover the sinister secret of the commune. I'll refrain from stepping up on my soapbox to deliver an impassioned soliloquy about how CGI has ruined the art of special make-up FX, but those who appreciate the magic of the wizards who revolutionized the art-form in the late '70s and early '80s will find the work of Rob Bottin here absolutely awe-inspiring. The climactic transformation scene is delivered unflinchingly and in real time, step by grotesque step, and the result is an indelible sequence that remains far more impressive and enthralling than anything modern film-makers handling the same material could ever cook up on a computer. The gore is used sparingly for maximum impact, but whenever it arrives, the results are stunning and gruesome. Perhaps most importantly, the werewolves themselves are a thing of fearsome beauty to behold, monsters that resonate as wholly believable extensions of the established mythology while still maintaining an innovative stroke of originality that makes them belong to this film alone. These creatures aren't merely big wolves, they are eight-foot tall bipedal killing machines with fangs and claws capable of tearing people to shreds, a skill that they demonstrate with acute proficiency during the course of the movie. The performances are all excellent even when the roles veer into the melodramatic, and the presence of one of the power couples of '80s horror, Christopher Stone and Dee Wallace (later Dee Wallace Stone), as well as a marvelous extended cameo from beloved genre vet Dick Miller, will delight fans of the era. Both the gritty, sleazy streets that open the movie and the isolated location housing the commune complex are perfectly presented and utilized, the clues to the greater mystery are unfolded with the taut grace of a top-notch thriller, and the film as a whole feels like an entirely plausible representation of ancient folk lore-based creatures existing in a modern world. The denouement falters slightly since Bottin's best tricks have already been displayed, but the sentiment of the finale is striking enough to end the saga on a dark and tragic note. If your love of the genre goes back to its natal days, be sure to stick around after the credits too, where you'll find a nice coda that bookends the homage to The Wolf Man present throughout these reels. The Howling is, in my estimation, not only the finest and most enduring lycanthropy fable in the canon, it's also quite simply one of the best horror films of all time. Don't skip this one.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Scary But Fun.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Joe Dante pulled off an impressive feat directing this scary but humorous film about a traumatized newswoman (sweet & appealing Dee Wallace) who is persuaded to go to a mysterious retreat by a noted psychologist(Patrick Macnee, very suave but sympathetic) where her bad luck sadly continues when she is forced to confront some sinister werewolves... Very clever script incorporates real-life werewolf directors as character names, and has awe-inspiring make-up F/X, the first of their kind. Well-directed and suspenseful, though final sequence goes a little too far in self-aware humor. Otherwise, cant-miss film for genre fans.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It goes on a bit
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Despite numerous in-jokes, characters named after horror directors, a cameo by Roger Corman and appearances from Joe Dante favourites Kevin McCarthy, Dick Miller and Robert Picardo, this werewolf movie is almost entirely lacking in enjoyment. It's a dreary and boring movie composed of leaden silences punctuated by droning dialogue recited by flat characters at a droning pace. Dee Wallace is a TV newswoman who heads to a retreat run by doctor Patrick Macnee but finds that her holiday isn't as peaceful as she expected when the place is overrun by werewolves. Although Dante has some fun contrasting what the characters are watching on TV with the events of the movie, the disappointingly droopy plot gets less interesting the more it goes on and by the end, when everyone's bearing their fangs and sprouting rubbery wolf faces, it all looks pretty stupid.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I do hope the book is better
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    siderite
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've begun watching The Howling with high expectations, as someone described it as "one of the 2 best Werewolf movies ever made". Unfortunately, he just might be right, but that is not saying much. Probably the spike in quality is caused by the movie being a book adaptation and I do hope the book was a lot better. Now, don't imagine the movie is very bad. For an 1981 movie with werewolves, indeed it is good, but it has that feel of a money grabbing movie studio doing an adaptation after a money grabbing publisher selling books of a certain type. You've all read those books: somewhere in a small American town, where everybody knows each other and there is dark secret, a city dweller comes to shake up the status quo. Probably Americans read a lot of these books, but I've had it up to my furry neck and my pointy teeth with this kind of bull. It is boring, pretentious and most of the time rehashing similar stories that were probably good when they were written but have now dissolved into lameness. Bottom line: I am sure I have seen this movie before, when I was young, but except the scene at the end, which had its share of drama and societal satire, I did not remember one thing while watching it again now. It is a mostly forgettable movie, with unsympathetic characters and a rushed story so that it can cover the entire book. Yes, indeed, take the story, make it a miniseries in the style of Stephen King adaptations and add some decent acting and special effects, and it would do great today, but this film just feels... wrong.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Disappointed
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SanteeFats
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I realize this movie was made over thirty years ago and it is not a blood and guts for shock value type movie (which I like) buuuuuttt!!! This is one very slow developing story. First if you can become a werewolf by bite or scratch the world would be overrun with them. This one does have them as shape shifters and therefore not tied to the Hollywood stereotypical full moon only ability to change. I will admit that when they started the transformations it was done very well for the time period, no CGI there. Then you have reporter who shows up with (gasp) the magic silver bullets! There is goof here as he first jacks a bullet in to the chamber when he gets out of his car and then again when he is in the office. I do like when he shoots one of the werewolves that has the girl, they rest just stop and stare for a second. See what happens when you are supremely overconfident in your ability to be harmed? I do like the end where she changes on TV and then is shot and killed in full view of the audience. Of course few will believe!!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "The Howling" is a 1980s slow-burning horror classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ersinkdotcom
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After news anchor Karen White (Dee Wallace) is attacked by a mysterious stranger (Robert Picardo), she starts having bizarre dreams and night terrors about the incident. Karen's doctor (Patrick Macnee) convinces her that she and husband Bill (Christopher Stone) should go through his treatment at "The Colony." Strange things start to happen as soon as they arrive. Could Karen be cracking up or is there something sinister going on in the secluded resort? Like most movies from the 1970s and the 1980s, "The Howling" is a slow- burner. This isn't one of those horror films that starts with a bang, keeps a frantic pace, and goes out with a bang. It slowly establishes its plot and characters and gives the audience a little at a time until the climactic and shocking end. Things might move too slowly for today's impatient audience. I even found it tedious at times. The scenes get choppy throughout and it seems like director Joe Dante was rushing things at some points. Rob Bottin's special effects for "The Howling" are still just as effective today as they were in 1981. The werewolf transformation scenes are unnerving and quite detailed. One transformation takes what seems like three to four minutes. It's all about attention to detail when it comes to Bottin's practical effects and animatronics versus today's obsession with rapid fire CGI scenes of metamorphosis. "The Howling" does feature quite a bit of the usual unnecessary nudity found in 1980's horror films. However, this time around director Dante attempts to justify it by analyzing our need to let the beast within out, mostly through sexual and physical acts of violence. The doctor, played by the late Patrick Macnee, convincingly regurgitates a lot of "primal scream" mumbo jumbo throughout the movie. Although it's a bit slow and takes some time getting started, great special effects and interesting, albeit hokey, social commentary set "The Howling" apart from the normal monster movie fare.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Joe Dante and Wolves...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Janis Livens
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Howling is one of the best werewolf movies up their with American Werewolf in London. It has everything you would want from a good monster movie: good scares, good laughs and some great effects. Dee Wallace stars in this werewolf film as a reporter who goes to a strange commune after experiencing a bizarre accident with a serial killer. And from that point it's a roller coaster ride of silly characters, wonderful practical effects and awkward werewolf sex. The Howling is a low budget film made for just one million dollars and looks stunning. The cinematography is absolutely gorgeous and makes a great use of both colour and shadows. Joe Dante's direction lends well to the material and shows what he can do with a simple monster movie premise and turns it into something memorable, funny and even heartbreaking. The performances are pretty good. Dee Wallace is great as the tragic heroine and the supporting cast include such goof ball character actors like John Carradine, Slim Pickens and Robert Pickardo. Not to mention the crazy sexy Elisabeth Brooks who does some kinky werewolf sex and so on. The Howling unlike the modern horror movies that feature werewolves and other supernatural creatures, feature great practical effects that are only rivaled by American Werewolf. However, I wouldn't call this film scary. It's hard to scare me or creep me out with something supernatural and especially if you have Slim Pickens in your movie. But horror movie doesn't need to be that scary to be good unlike comedies that need to be funny to any good. Werewolf movies doesn't get much better than Howling and American Werewolf in London. If you enjoy good monster movies that are made with love and care, you owe it to yourself to watch this film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Undoubtedly the inspiration for Michael Jackson's 'Thriller'
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sherazade
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The special effects were as good as can be expected of a movie made in 1980/81 but other than that is was poorly written, poorly directed, poorly acted (especially by the female actors/characters), poorly edited and there were way too many inconsistencies and plot holes. Werewolves movies were to the 80s what Vampire movies are to us now, some were good and most were bad. I would recommend this movie only to people who are fans of some actor in the film and want to see every film they've ever acted in or for those who want to view it for nostalgic reasons or if you're like me and the movie was before your time and you just want to see what films of this genre looked like that back then.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a werewolf classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    trashgang
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Howling has become the father of the new werewolf flicks in the heydays of the eighties. But there was another masterpiece that sadly came out just after The Howling was released, An American Werewolf In London (1982). Why I'm saying this, because Rick Baker, make-up and special effects was involved in both of them. American Werewolf started earlier then The Howling but had financial problems so Rick started with The Howling but when the director of American Werewolf(John Landis) heard that news money was raised and Barker left The Howling to give it towards Rick Bottin. Rick made it a movie with excellent effects and became notorious surely after The Thing (1982). The Howling wanted to do the werewolf transformation in one shot but money prevented it to become that way. American Werewolf did it. But The Howling was the best known werewolf flick. Although being a classic I prefer American because things starts of immediately. The Howling takes almost 50 minutes before a werewolf comes in and the effects become clear. But I must say that the last 40 minutes are worth watching. What a delight to see. The acting was rather good and the way it was filmed (advised by Bottin to use shadow and not that much of lighting) gave it a creepy feeling. A lot of memorable names are here to see but one that was becoming the next big thing was the werewolf Marsha (Elisabeth Brooks). She was noticed because she went full frontal here but her career was suddenly stopped by cancer, she died age 46. Mixed feelings because it isn't a good movie the first 50 minutes but it's a classic for so many reasons. Still, I gave it an 8 for the effects alone. Still, not that gory for a werewolf flick made in the heydays of slashers. Gore 1,5/5 Nudity 1/5 Effects 5/5 Story 3/5 Comedy 0/5
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Great Werewolf Film!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gwnightscream
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dee Wallace, Patrick Macnee, Christopher Stone, Robert Picardo, Dennis Dugan, Belinda Balaski and Elizabeth Brooks star in Joe Dante's 1981 horror film. This begins with newswoman, Karen White (Wallace) preparing to meet man, Eddie Quist (Picardo) whom reveals his secret being a werewolf and is attacked by him. After Eddie is shot by police but not dead, Karen starts to feel different and tries to remember what happened. Macnee plays doctor, George Waggner who helps her and invites her to his spa in the country, the colony. She goes with her husband, Bill Neil (Stone) and they meet an odd group of people staying there and discover there are werewolves. Dugan plays Karen's friend, Chris, Balaski plays his girlfriend, Teri, the late, Brooks plays Marsha, a woman who seduces Bill and Stone was also Wallace's real-life husband. Dick Miller, Roger Corman and Kevin McCarthy also appear and Rob Bottin's make-up effects are terrific as usual. I recommend this great werewolf film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A smart, sexy, and genuinely scary horror classic that still has plenty of bite
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    happyendingrocks
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The werewolf is sort of the neglected middle child of the horror monster hierarchy: gifted, unique, and brilliant, but eternally overshadowed by its dad the Devil, older vampiric siblings, mummified Egyptian stepsons from a previous marriage, and kid brother zombies who are always getting into trouble and keeping the family distracted. Of course there have been great, even legendary, films with lycanthrope antagonists, but that particular sub-genre is rather limited in scope. However, despite the admitted paucity of competition, I can still say with absolute certainty that The Howling is the best movie about werewolves ever made. It makes sense that the film heavily references The Wolf Man, the eternal Lon Chaney Jr./Universal Monsters staple, because The Howling is executed in a way that clearly reveals its acknowledgment of its roots in the traditions of classic horror. The pace is restrained and meticulous, the atmosphere is a character in itself, and despite the film's utilization of creature effects that weren't even dreamed of in Universal's genre heyday, good old-fashioned ensemble acting is what truly drives the action in the piece. If this description makes The Howling sound like a dry production more suited for the theater stage, don't misunderstand me; this is bloody and ferocious fare that will greatly please fans of visceral horror. But it is the taut and well-crafted story, not merely the FX, that make this such a gem, and director Joe Dante is seasoned enough here to allow a gradual and steady immersion into the film's world before bowling us over with Rob Bottin's peerless set-pieces, which have all the more impact when they take command because of how effectively the movie has teased us with tantalizing glimpses throughout. Though the creatures are understandably a feature attraction here, the main focus of the plot is on news anchor Karen White, who has become the fixation of deranged serial killer Eddie Quist and agrees to be used as bait as part of a police operation to capture him. Quist is seemingly killed during her harrowing and macabre encounter, and Karen is subsequently haunted by bizarre dreams and fuzzy, repressed recollections of what actually occurred that night. When she heeds a pop psychologist's suggestion that she and her husband should attend a therapy retreat he oversees at a secluded commune, the getaway does anything but assuage her trauma. Instead, Karen encounters odd and subtly menacing locals and the titular unholy moans emanating from the fog-shrouded forests. It doesn't take long for us to learn that the commune is located at the nucleus of the hunting grounds prowled by a pack of malevolent predatory beasts, and after Karen's husband is seduced and transformed by a sultry lady wolf, her and her visiting reporter friend begin to uncover the sinister secret of the commune. I'll refrain from stepping up on my soapbox to deliver an impassioned soliloquy about how CGI has ruined the art of special make-up FX, but those who appreciate the magic of the wizards who revolutionized the art-form in the late '70s and early '80s will find the work of Rob Bottin here absolutely awe-inspiring. The climactic transformation scene is delivered unflinchingly and in real time, step by grotesque step, and the result is an indelible sequence that remains far more impressive and enthralling than anything modern film-makers handling the same material could ever cook up on a computer. The gore is used sparingly for maximum impact, but whenever it arrives, the results are stunning and gruesome. Perhaps most importantly, the werewolves themselves are a thing of fearsome beauty to behold, monsters that resonate as wholly believable extensions of the established mythology while still maintaining an innovative stroke of originality that makes them belong to this film alone. These creatures aren't merely big wolves, they are eight-foot tall bipedal killing machines with fangs and claws capable of tearing people to shreds, a skill that they demonstrate with acute proficiency during the course of the movie. The performances are all excellent even when the roles veer into the melodramatic, and the presence of one of the power couples of '80s horror, Christopher Stone and Dee Wallace (later Dee Wallace Stone), as well as a marvelous extended cameo from beloved genre vet Dick Miller, will delight fans of the era. Both the gritty, sleazy streets that open the movie and the isolated location housing the commune complex are perfectly presented and utilized, the clues to the greater mystery are unfolded with the taut grace of a top-notch thriller, and the film as a whole feels like an entirely plausible representation of ancient folk lore-based creatures existing in a modern world. The denouement falters slightly since Bottin's best tricks have already been displayed, but the sentiment of the finale is striking enough to end the saga on a dark and tragic note. If your love of the genre goes back to its natal days, be sure to stick around after the credits too, where you'll find a nice coda that bookends the homage to The Wolf Man present throughout these reels. The Howling is, in my estimation, not only the finest and most enduring lycanthropy fable in the canon, it's also quite simply one of the best horror films of all time. Don't skip this one.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Scary But Fun.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Joe Dante pulled off an impressive feat directing this scary but humorous film about a traumatized newswoman (sweet & appealing Dee Wallace) who is persuaded to go to a mysterious retreat by a noted psychologist(Patrick Macnee, very suave but sympathetic) where her bad luck sadly continues when she is forced to confront some sinister werewolves... Very clever script incorporates real-life werewolf directors as character names, and has awe-inspiring make-up F/X, the first of their kind. Well-directed and suspenseful, though final sequence goes a little too far in self-aware humor. Otherwise, cant-miss film for genre fans.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It goes on a bit
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Despite numerous in-jokes, characters named after horror directors, a cameo by Roger Corman and appearances from Joe Dante favourites Kevin McCarthy, Dick Miller and Robert Picardo, this werewolf movie is almost entirely lacking in enjoyment. It's a dreary and boring movie composed of leaden silences punctuated by droning dialogue recited by flat characters at a droning pace. Dee Wallace is a TV newswoman who heads to a retreat run by doctor Patrick Macnee but finds that her holiday isn't as peaceful as she expected when the place is overrun by werewolves. Although Dante has some fun contrasting what the characters are watching on TV with the events of the movie, the disappointingly droopy plot gets less interesting the more it goes on and by the end, when everyone's bearing their fangs and sprouting rubbery wolf faces, it all looks pretty stupid.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I do hope the book is better
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    siderite
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've begun watching The Howling with high expectations, as someone described it as "one of the 2 best Werewolf movies ever made". Unfortunately, he just might be right, but that is not saying much. Probably the spike in quality is caused by the movie being a book adaptation and I do hope the book was a lot better. Now, don't imagine the movie is very bad. For an 1981 movie with werewolves, indeed it is good, but it has that feel of a money grabbing movie studio doing an adaptation after a money grabbing publisher selling books of a certain type. You've all read those books: somewhere in a small American town, where everybody knows each other and there is dark secret, a city dweller comes to shake up the status quo. Probably Americans read a lot of these books, but I've had it up to my furry neck and my pointy teeth with this kind of bull. It is boring, pretentious and most of the time rehashing similar stories that were probably good when they were written but have now dissolved into lameness. Bottom line: I am sure I have seen this movie before, when I was young, but except the scene at the end, which had its share of drama and societal satire, I did not remember one thing while watching it again now. It is a mostly forgettable movie, with unsympathetic characters and a rushed story so that it can cover the entire book. Yes, indeed, take the story, make it a miniseries in the style of Stephen King adaptations and add some decent acting and special effects, and it would do great today, but this film just feels... wrong.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Disappointed
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SanteeFats
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I realize this movie was made over thirty years ago and it is not a blood and guts for shock value type movie (which I like) buuuuuttt!!! This is one very slow developing story. First if you can become a werewolf by bite or scratch the world would be overrun with them. This one does have them as shape shifters and therefore not tied to the Hollywood stereotypical full moon only ability to change. I will admit that when they started the transformations it was done very well for the time period, no CGI there. Then you have reporter who shows up with (gasp) the magic silver bullets! There is goof here as he first jacks a bullet in to the chamber when he gets out of his car and then again when he is in the office. I do like when he shoots one of the werewolves that has the girl, they rest just stop and stare for a second. See what happens when you are supremely overconfident in your ability to be harmed? I do like the end where she changes on TV and then is shot and killed in full view of the audience. Of course few will believe!!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "The Howling" is a 1980s slow-burning horror classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ersinkdotcom
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After news anchor Karen White (Dee Wallace) is attacked by a mysterious stranger (Robert Picardo), she starts having bizarre dreams and night terrors about the incident. Karen's doctor (Patrick Macnee) convinces her that she and husband Bill (Christopher Stone) should go through his treatment at "The Colony." Strange things start to happen as soon as they arrive. Could Karen be cracking up or is there something sinister going on in the secluded resort? Like most movies from the 1970s and the 1980s, "The Howling" is a slow- burner. This isn't one of those horror films that starts with a bang, keeps a frantic pace, and goes out with a bang. It slowly establishes its plot and characters and gives the audience a little at a time until the climactic and shocking end. Things might move too slowly for today's impatient audience. I even found it tedious at times. The scenes get choppy throughout and it seems like director Joe Dante was rushing things at some points. Rob Bottin's special effects for "The Howling" are still just as effective today as they were in 1981. The werewolf transformation scenes are unnerving and quite detailed. One transformation takes what seems like three to four minutes. It's all about attention to detail when it comes to Bottin's practical effects and animatronics versus today's obsession with rapid fire CGI scenes of metamorphosis. "The Howling" does feature quite a bit of the usual unnecessary nudity found in 1980's horror films. However, this time around director Dante attempts to justify it by analyzing our need to let the beast within out, mostly through sexual and physical acts of violence. The doctor, played by the late Patrick Macnee, convincingly regurgitates a lot of "primal scream" mumbo jumbo throughout the movie. Although it's a bit slow and takes some time getting started, great special effects and interesting, albeit hokey, social commentary set "The Howling" apart from the normal monster movie fare.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Joe Dante and Wolves...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Janis Livens
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Howling is one of the best werewolf movies up their with American Werewolf in London. It has everything you would want from a good monster movie: good scares, good laughs and some great effects. Dee Wallace stars in this werewolf film as a reporter who goes to a strange commune after experiencing a bizarre accident with a serial killer. And from that point it's a roller coaster ride of silly characters, wonderful practical effects and awkward werewolf sex. The Howling is a low budget film made for just one million dollars and looks stunning. The cinematography is absolutely gorgeous and makes a great use of both colour and shadows. Joe Dante's direction lends well to the material and shows what he can do with a simple monster movie premise and turns it into something memorable, funny and even heartbreaking. The performances are pretty good. Dee Wallace is great as the tragic heroine and the supporting cast include such goof ball character actors like John Carradine, Slim Pickens and Robert Pickardo. Not to mention the crazy sexy Elisabeth Brooks who does some kinky werewolf sex and so on. The Howling unlike the modern horror movies that feature werewolves and other supernatural creatures, feature great practical effects that are only rivaled by American Werewolf. However, I wouldn't call this film scary. It's hard to scare me or creep me out with something supernatural and especially if you have Slim Pickens in your movie. But horror movie doesn't need to be that scary to be good unlike comedies that need to be funny to any good. Werewolf movies doesn't get much better than Howling and American Werewolf in London. If you enjoy good monster movies that are made with love and care, you owe it to yourself to watch this film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Undoubtedly the inspiration for Michael Jackson's 'Thriller'
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sherazade
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The special effects were as good as can be expected of a movie made in 1980/81 but other than that is was poorly written, poorly directed, poorly acted (especially by the female actors/characters), poorly edited and there were way too many inconsistencies and plot holes. Werewolves movies were to the 80s what Vampire movies are to us now, some were good and most were bad. I would recommend this movie only to people who are fans of some actor in the film and want to see every film they've ever acted in or for those who want to view it for nostalgic reasons or if you're like me and the movie was before your time and you just want to see what films of this genre looked like that back then.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a werewolf classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    trashgang
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Howling has become the father of the new werewolf flicks in the heydays of the eighties. But there was another masterpiece that sadly came out just after The Howling was released, An American Werewolf In London (1982). Why I'm saying this, because Rick Baker, make-up and special effects was involved in both of them. American Werewolf started earlier then The Howling but had financial problems so Rick started with The Howling but when the director of American Werewolf(John Landis) heard that news money was raised and Barker left The Howling to give it towards Rick Bottin. Rick made it a movie with excellent effects and became notorious surely after The Thing (1982). The Howling wanted to do the werewolf transformation in one shot but money prevented it to become that way. American Werewolf did it. But The Howling was the best known werewolf flick. Although being a classic I prefer American because things starts of immediately. The Howling takes almost 50 minutes before a werewolf comes in and the effects become clear. But I must say that the last 40 minutes are worth watching. What a delight to see. The acting was rather good and the way it was filmed (advised by Bottin to use shadow and not that much of lighting) gave it a creepy feeling. A lot of memorable names are here to see but one that was becoming the next big thing was the werewolf Marsha (Elisabeth Brooks). She was noticed because she went full frontal here but her career was suddenly stopped by cancer, she died age 46. Mixed feelings because it isn't a good movie the first 50 minutes but it's a classic for so many reasons. Still, I gave it an 8 for the effects alone. Still, not that gory for a werewolf flick made in the heydays of slashers. Gore 1,5/5 Nudity 1/5 Effects 5/5 Story 3/5 Comedy 0/5
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Great Werewolf Film!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gwnightscream
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dee Wallace, Patrick Macnee, Christopher Stone, Robert Picardo, Dennis Dugan, Belinda Balaski and Elizabeth Brooks star in Joe Dante's 1981 horror film. This begins with newswoman, Karen White (Wallace) preparing to meet man, Eddie Quist (Picardo) whom reveals his secret being a werewolf and is attacked by him. After Eddie is shot by police but not dead, Karen starts to feel different and tries to remember what happened. Macnee plays doctor, George Waggner who helps her and invites her to his spa in the country, the colony. She goes with her husband, Bill Neil (Stone) and they meet an odd group of people staying there and discover there are werewolves. Dugan plays Karen's friend, Chris, Balaski plays his girlfriend, Teri, the late, Brooks plays Marsha, a woman who seduces Bill and Stone was also Wallace's real-life husband. Dick Miller, Roger Corman and Kevin McCarthy also appear and Rob Bottin's make-up effects are terrific as usual. I recommend this great werewolf film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A smart, sexy, and genuinely scary horror classic that still has plenty of bite
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    happyendingrocks
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The werewolf is sort of the neglected middle child of the horror monster hierarchy: gifted, unique, and brilliant, but eternally overshadowed by its dad the Devil, older vampiric siblings, mummified Egyptian stepsons from a previous marriage, and kid brother zombies who are always getting into trouble and keeping the family distracted. Of course there have been great, even legendary, films with lycanthrope antagonists, but that particular sub-genre is rather limited in scope. However, despite the admitted paucity of competition, I can still say with absolute certainty that The Howling is the best movie about werewolves ever made. It makes sense that the film heavily references The Wolf Man, the eternal Lon Chaney Jr./Universal Monsters staple, because The Howling is executed in a way that clearly reveals its acknowledgment of its roots in the traditions of classic horror. The pace is restrained and meticulous, the atmosphere is a character in itself, and despite the film's utilization of creature effects that weren't even dreamed of in Universal's genre heyday, good old-fashioned ensemble acting is what truly drives the action in the piece. If this description makes The Howling sound like a dry production more suited for the theater stage, don't misunderstand me; this is bloody and ferocious fare that will greatly please fans of visceral horror. But it is the taut and well-crafted story, not merely the FX, that make this such a gem, and director Joe Dante is seasoned enough here to allow a gradual and steady immersion into the film's world before bowling us over with Rob Bottin's peerless set-pieces, which have all the more impact when they take command because of how effectively the movie has teased us with tantalizing glimpses throughout. Though the creatures are understandably a feature attraction here, the main focus of the plot is on news anchor Karen White, who has become the fixation of deranged serial killer Eddie Quist and agrees to be used as bait as part of a police operation to capture him. Quist is seemingly killed during her harrowing and macabre encounter, and Karen is subsequently haunted by bizarre dreams and fuzzy, repressed recollections of what actually occurred that night. When she heeds a pop psychologist's suggestion that she and her husband should attend a therapy retreat he oversees at a secluded commune, the getaway does anything but assuage her trauma. Instead, Karen encounters odd and subtly menacing locals and the titular unholy moans emanating from the fog-shrouded forests. It doesn't take long for us to learn that the commune is located at the nucleus of the hunting grounds prowled by a pack of malevolent predatory beasts, and after Karen's husband is seduced and transformed by a sultry lady wolf, her and her visiting reporter friend begin to uncover the sinister secret of the commune. I'll refrain from stepping up on my soapbox to deliver an impassioned soliloquy about how CGI has ruined the art of special make-up FX, but those who appreciate the magic of the wizards who revolutionized the art-form in the late '70s and early '80s will find the work of Rob Bottin here absolutely awe-inspiring. The climactic transformation scene is delivered unflinchingly and in real time, step by grotesque step, and the result is an indelible sequence that remains far more impressive and enthralling than anything modern film-makers handling the same material could ever cook up on a computer. The gore is used sparingly for maximum impact, but whenever it arrives, the results are stunning and gruesome. Perhaps most importantly, the werewolves themselves are a thing of fearsome beauty to behold, monsters that resonate as wholly believable extensions of the established mythology while still maintaining an innovative stroke of originality that makes them belong to this film alone. These creatures aren't merely big wolves, they are eight-foot tall bipedal killing machines with fangs and claws capable of tearing people to shreds, a skill that they demonstrate with acute proficiency during the course of the movie. The performances are all excellent even when the roles veer into the melodramatic, and the presence of one of the power couples of '80s horror, Christopher Stone and Dee Wallace (later Dee Wallace Stone), as well as a marvelous extended cameo from beloved genre vet Dick Miller, will delight fans of the era. Both the gritty, sleazy streets that open the movie and the isolated location housing the commune complex are perfectly presented and utilized, the clues to the greater mystery are unfolded with the taut grace of a top-notch thriller, and the film as a whole feels like an entirely plausible representation of ancient folk lore-based creatures existing in a modern world. The denouement falters slightly since Bottin's best tricks have already been displayed, but the sentiment of the finale is striking enough to end the saga on a dark and tragic note. If your love of the genre goes back to its natal days, be sure to stick around after the credits too, where you'll find a nice coda that bookends the homage to The Wolf Man present throughout these reels. The Howling is, in my estimation, not only the finest and most enduring lycanthropy fable in the canon, it's also quite simply one of the best horror films of all time. Don't skip this one.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Scary But Fun.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Joe Dante pulled off an impressive feat directing this scary but humorous film about a traumatized newswoman (sweet & appealing Dee Wallace) who is persuaded to go to a mysterious retreat by a noted psychologist(Patrick Macnee, very suave but sympathetic) where her bad luck sadly continues when she is forced to confront some sinister werewolves... Very clever script incorporates real-life werewolf directors as character names, and has awe-inspiring make-up F/X, the first of their kind. Well-directed and suspenseful, though final sequence goes a little too far in self-aware humor. Otherwise, cant-miss film for genre fans.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It goes on a bit
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Despite numerous in-jokes, characters named after horror directors, a cameo by Roger Corman and appearances from Joe Dante favourites Kevin McCarthy, Dick Miller and Robert Picardo, this werewolf movie is almost entirely lacking in enjoyment. It's a dreary and boring movie composed of leaden silences punctuated by droning dialogue recited by flat characters at a droning pace. Dee Wallace is a TV newswoman who heads to a retreat run by doctor Patrick Macnee but finds that her holiday isn't as peaceful as she expected when the place is overrun by werewolves. Although Dante has some fun contrasting what the characters are watching on TV with the events of the movie, the disappointingly droopy plot gets less interesting the more it goes on and by the end, when everyone's bearing their fangs and sprouting rubbery wolf faces, it all looks pretty stupid.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I do hope the book is better
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    siderite
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've begun watching The Howling with high expectations, as someone described it as "one of the 2 best Werewolf movies ever made". Unfortunately, he just might be right, but that is not saying much. Probably the spike in quality is caused by the movie being a book adaptation and I do hope the book was a lot better. Now, don't imagine the movie is very bad. For an 1981 movie with werewolves, indeed it is good, but it has that feel of a money grabbing movie studio doing an adaptation after a money grabbing publisher selling books of a certain type. You've all read those books: somewhere in a small American town, where everybody knows each other and there is dark secret, a city dweller comes to shake up the status quo. Probably Americans read a lot of these books, but I've had it up to my furry neck and my pointy teeth with this kind of bull. It is boring, pretentious and most of the time rehashing similar stories that were probably good when they were written but have now dissolved into lameness. Bottom line: I am sure I have seen this movie before, when I was young, but except the scene at the end, which had its share of drama and societal satire, I did not remember one thing while watching it again now. It is a mostly forgettable movie, with unsympathetic characters and a rushed story so that it can cover the entire book. Yes, indeed, take the story, make it a miniseries in the style of Stephen King adaptations and add some decent acting and special effects, and it would do great today, but this film just feels... wrong.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Disappointed
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SanteeFats
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I realize this movie was made over thirty years ago and it is not a blood and guts for shock value type movie (which I like) buuuuuttt!!! This is one very slow developing story. First if you can become a werewolf by bite or scratch the world would be overrun with them. This one does have them as shape shifters and therefore not tied to the Hollywood stereotypical full moon only ability to change. I will admit that when they started the transformations it was done very well for the time period, no CGI there. Then you have reporter who shows up with (gasp) the magic silver bullets! There is goof here as he first jacks a bullet in to the chamber when he gets out of his car and then again when he is in the office. I do like when he shoots one of the werewolves that has the girl, they rest just stop and stare for a second. See what happens when you are supremely overconfident in your ability to be harmed? I do like the end where she changes on TV and then is shot and killed in full view of the audience. Of course few will believe!!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "The Howling" is a 1980s slow-burning horror classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ersinkdotcom
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After news anchor Karen White (Dee Wallace) is attacked by a mysterious stranger (Robert Picardo), she starts having bizarre dreams and night terrors about the incident. Karen's doctor (Patrick Macnee) convinces her that she and husband Bill (Christopher Stone) should go through his treatment at "The Colony." Strange things start to happen as soon as they arrive. Could Karen be cracking up or is there something sinister going on in the secluded resort? Like most movies from the 1970s and the 1980s, "The Howling" is a slow- burner. This isn't one of those horror films that starts with a bang, keeps a frantic pace, and goes out with a bang. It slowly establishes its plot and characters and gives the audience a little at a time until the climactic and shocking end. Things might move too slowly for today's impatient audience. I even found it tedious at times. The scenes get choppy throughout and it seems like director Joe Dante was rushing things at some points. Rob Bottin's special effects for "The Howling" are still just as effective today as they were in 1981. The werewolf transformation scenes are unnerving and quite detailed. One transformation takes what seems like three to four minutes. It's all about attention to detail when it comes to Bottin's practical effects and animatronics versus today's obsession with rapid fire CGI scenes of metamorphosis. "The Howling" does feature quite a bit of the usual unnecessary nudity found in 1980's horror films. However, this time around director Dante attempts to justify it by analyzing our need to let the beast within out, mostly through sexual and physical acts of violence. The doctor, played by the late Patrick Macnee, convincingly regurgitates a lot of "primal scream" mumbo jumbo throughout the movie. Although it's a bit slow and takes some time getting started, great special effects and interesting, albeit hokey, social commentary set "The Howling" apart from the normal monster movie fare.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Joe Dante and Wolves...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Janis Livens
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Howling is one of the best werewolf movies up their with American Werewolf in London. It has everything you would want from a good monster movie: good scares, good laughs and some great effects. Dee Wallace stars in this werewolf film as a reporter who goes to a strange commune after experiencing a bizarre accident with a serial killer. And from that point it's a roller coaster ride of silly characters, wonderful practical effects and awkward werewolf sex. The Howling is a low budget film made for just one million dollars and looks stunning. The cinematography is absolutely gorgeous and makes a great use of both colour and shadows. Joe Dante's direction lends well to the material and shows what he can do with a simple monster movie premise and turns it into something memorable, funny and even heartbreaking. The performances are pretty good. Dee Wallace is great as the tragic heroine and the supporting cast include such goof ball character actors like John Carradine, Slim Pickens and Robert Pickardo. Not to mention the crazy sexy Elisabeth Brooks who does some kinky werewolf sex and so on. The Howling unlike the modern horror movies that feature werewolves and other supernatural creatures, feature great practical effects that are only rivaled by American Werewolf. However, I wouldn't call this film scary. It's hard to scare me or creep me out with something supernatural and especially if you have Slim Pickens in your movie. But horror movie doesn't need to be that scary to be good unlike comedies that need to be funny to any good. Werewolf movies doesn't get much better than Howling and American Werewolf in London. If you enjoy good monster movies that are made with love and care, you owe it to yourself to watch this film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Undoubtedly the inspiration for Michael Jackson's 'Thriller'
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sherazade
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The special effects were as good as can be expected of a movie made in 1980/81 but other than that is was poorly written, poorly directed, poorly acted (especially by the female actors/characters), poorly edited and there were way too many inconsistencies and plot holes. Werewolves movies were to the 80s what Vampire movies are to us now, some were good and most were bad. I would recommend this movie only to people who are fans of some actor in the film and want to see every film they've ever acted in or for those who want to view it for nostalgic reasons or if you're like me and the movie was before your time and you just want to see what films of this genre looked like that back then.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a werewolf classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    trashgang
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Howling has become the father of the new werewolf flicks in the heydays of the eighties. But there was another masterpiece that sadly came out just after The Howling was released, An American Werewolf In London (1982). Why I'm saying this, because Rick Baker, make-up and special effects was involved in both of them. American Werewolf started earlier then The Howling but had financial problems so Rick started with The Howling but when the director of American Werewolf(John Landis) heard that news money was raised and Barker left The Howling to give it towards Rick Bottin. Rick made it a movie with excellent effects and became notorious surely after The Thing (1982). The Howling wanted to do the werewolf transformation in one shot but money prevented it to become that way. American Werewolf did it. But The Howling was the best known werewolf flick. Although being a classic I prefer American because things starts of immediately. The Howling takes almost 50 minutes before a werewolf comes in and the effects become clear. But I must say that the last 40 minutes are worth watching. What a delight to see. The acting was rather good and the way it was filmed (advised by Bottin to use shadow and not that much of lighting) gave it a creepy feeling. A lot of memorable names are here to see but one that was becoming the next big thing was the werewolf Marsha (Elisabeth Brooks). She was noticed because she went full frontal here but her career was suddenly stopped by cancer, she died age 46. Mixed feelings because it isn't a good movie the first 50 minutes but it's a classic for so many reasons. Still, I gave it an 8 for the effects alone. Still, not that gory for a werewolf flick made in the heydays of slashers. Gore 1,5/5 Nudity 1/5 Effects 5/5 Story 3/5 Comedy 0/5
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Great Werewolf Film!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gwnightscream
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dee Wallace, Patrick Macnee, Christopher Stone, Robert Picardo, Dennis Dugan, Belinda Balaski and Elizabeth Brooks star in Joe Dante's 1981 horror film. This begins with newswoman, Karen White (Wallace) preparing to meet man, Eddie Quist (Picardo) whom reveals his secret being a werewolf and is attacked by him. After Eddie is shot by police but not dead, Karen starts to feel different and tries to remember what happened. Macnee plays doctor, George Waggner who helps her and invites her to his spa in the country, the colony. She goes with her husband, Bill Neil (Stone) and they meet an odd group of people staying there and discover there are werewolves. Dugan plays Karen's friend, Chris, Balaski plays his girlfriend, Teri, the late, Brooks plays Marsha, a woman who seduces Bill and Stone was also Wallace's real-life husband. Dick Miller, Roger Corman and Kevin McCarthy also appear and Rob Bottin's make-up effects are terrific as usual. I recommend this great werewolf film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A smart, sexy, and genuinely scary horror classic that still has plenty of bite
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    happyendingrocks
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The werewolf is sort of the neglected middle child of the horror monster hierarchy: gifted, unique, and brilliant, but eternally overshadowed by its dad the Devil, older vampiric siblings, mummified Egyptian stepsons from a previous marriage, and kid brother zombies who are always getting into trouble and keeping the family distracted. Of course there have been great, even legendary, films with lycanthrope antagonists, but that particular sub-genre is rather limited in scope. However, despite the admitted paucity of competition, I can still say with absolute certainty that The Howling is the best movie about werewolves ever made. It makes sense that the film heavily references The Wolf Man, the eternal Lon Chaney Jr./Universal Monsters staple, because The Howling is executed in a way that clearly reveals its acknowledgment of its roots in the traditions of classic horror. The pace is restrained and meticulous, the atmosphere is a character in itself, and despite the film's utilization of creature effects that weren't even dreamed of in Universal's genre heyday, good old-fashioned ensemble acting is what truly drives the action in the piece. If this description makes The Howling sound like a dry production more suited for the theater stage, don't misunderstand me; this is bloody and ferocious fare that will greatly please fans of visceral horror. But it is the taut and well-crafted story, not merely the FX, that make this such a gem, and director Joe Dante is seasoned enough here to allow a gradual and steady immersion into the film's world before bowling us over with Rob Bottin's peerless set-pieces, which have all the more impact when they take command because of how effectively the movie has teased us with tantalizing glimpses throughout. Though the creatures are understandably a feature attraction here, the main focus of the plot is on news anchor Karen White, who has become the fixation of deranged serial killer Eddie Quist and agrees to be used as bait as part of a police operation to capture him. Quist is seemingly killed during her harrowing and macabre encounter, and Karen is subsequently haunted by bizarre dreams and fuzzy, repressed recollections of what actually occurred that night. When she heeds a pop psychologist's suggestion that she and her husband should attend a therapy retreat he oversees at a secluded commune, the getaway does anything but assuage her trauma. Instead, Karen encounters odd and subtly menacing locals and the titular unholy moans emanating from the fog-shrouded forests. It doesn't take long for us to learn that the commune is located at the nucleus of the hunting grounds prowled by a pack of malevolent predatory beasts, and after Karen's husband is seduced and transformed by a sultry lady wolf, her and her visiting reporter friend begin to uncover the sinister secret of the commune. I'll refrain from stepping up on my soapbox to deliver an impassioned soliloquy about how CGI has ruined the art of special make-up FX, but those who appreciate the magic of the wizards who revolutionized the art-form in the late '70s and early '80s will find the work of Rob Bottin here absolutely awe-inspiring. The climactic transformation scene is delivered unflinchingly and in real time, step by grotesque step, and the result is an indelible sequence that remains far more impressive and enthralling than anything modern film-makers handling the same material could ever cook up on a computer. The gore is used sparingly for maximum impact, but whenever it arrives, the results are stunning and gruesome. Perhaps most importantly, the werewolves themselves are a thing of fearsome beauty to behold, monsters that resonate as wholly believable extensions of the established mythology while still maintaining an innovative stroke of originality that makes them belong to this film alone. These creatures aren't merely big wolves, they are eight-foot tall bipedal killing machines with fangs and claws capable of tearing people to shreds, a skill that they demonstrate with acute proficiency during the course of the movie. The performances are all excellent even when the roles veer into the melodramatic, and the presence of one of the power couples of '80s horror, Christopher Stone and Dee Wallace (later Dee Wallace Stone), as well as a marvelous extended cameo from beloved genre vet Dick Miller, will delight fans of the era. Both the gritty, sleazy streets that open the movie and the isolated location housing the commune complex are perfectly presented and utilized, the clues to the greater mystery are unfolded with the taut grace of a top-notch thriller, and the film as a whole feels like an entirely plausible representation of ancient folk lore-based creatures existing in a modern world. The denouement falters slightly since Bottin's best tricks have already been displayed, but the sentiment of the finale is striking enough to end the saga on a dark and tragic note. If your love of the genre goes back to its natal days, be sure to stick around after the credits too, where you'll find a nice coda that bookends the homage to The Wolf Man present throughout these reels. The Howling is, in my estimation, not only the finest and most enduring lycanthropy fable in the canon, it's also quite simply one of the best horror films of all time. Don't skip this one.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Scary But Fun.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Joe Dante pulled off an impressive feat directing this scary but humorous film about a traumatized newswoman (sweet & appealing Dee Wallace) who is persuaded to go to a mysterious retreat by a noted psychologist(Patrick Macnee, very suave but sympathetic) where her bad luck sadly continues when she is forced to confront some sinister werewolves... Very clever script incorporates real-life werewolf directors as character names, and has awe-inspiring make-up F/X, the first of their kind. Well-directed and suspenseful, though final sequence goes a little too far in self-aware humor. Otherwise, cant-miss film for genre fans.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It goes on a bit
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Despite numerous in-jokes, characters named after horror directors, a cameo by Roger Corman and appearances from Joe Dante favourites Kevin McCarthy, Dick Miller and Robert Picardo, this werewolf movie is almost entirely lacking in enjoyment. It's a dreary and boring movie composed of leaden silences punctuated by droning dialogue recited by flat characters at a droning pace. Dee Wallace is a TV newswoman who heads to a retreat run by doctor Patrick Macnee but finds that her holiday isn't as peaceful as she expected when the place is overrun by werewolves. Although Dante has some fun contrasting what the characters are watching on TV with the events of the movie, the disappointingly droopy plot gets less interesting the more it goes on and by the end, when everyone's bearing their fangs and sprouting rubbery wolf faces, it all looks pretty stupid.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I do hope the book is better
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    siderite
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've begun watching The Howling with high expectations, as someone described it as "one of the 2 best Werewolf movies ever made". Unfortunately, he just might be right, but that is not saying much. Probably the spike in quality is caused by the movie being a book adaptation and I do hope the book was a lot better. Now, don't imagine the movie is very bad. For an 1981 movie with werewolves, indeed it is good, but it has that feel of a money grabbing movie studio doing an adaptation after a money grabbing publisher selling books of a certain type. You've all read those books: somewhere in a small American town, where everybody knows each other and there is dark secret, a city dweller comes to shake up the status quo. Probably Americans read a lot of these books, but I've had it up to my furry neck and my pointy teeth with this kind of bull. It is boring, pretentious and most of the time rehashing similar stories that were probably good when they were written but have now dissolved into lameness. Bottom line: I am sure I have seen this movie before, when I was young, but except the scene at the end, which had its share of drama and societal satire, I did not remember one thing while watching it again now. It is a mostly forgettable movie, with unsympathetic characters and a rushed story so that it can cover the entire book. Yes, indeed, take the story, make it a miniseries in the style of Stephen King adaptations and add some decent acting and special effects, and it would do great today, but this film just feels... wrong.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Disappointed
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SanteeFats
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I realize this movie was made over thirty years ago and it is not a blood and guts for shock value type movie (which I like) buuuuuttt!!! This is one very slow developing story. First if you can become a werewolf by bite or scratch the world would be overrun with them. This one does have them as shape shifters and therefore not tied to the Hollywood stereotypical full moon only ability to change. I will admit that when they started the transformations it was done very well for the time period, no CGI there. Then you have reporter who shows up with (gasp) the magic silver bullets! There is goof here as he first jacks a bullet in to the chamber when he gets out of his car and then again when he is in the office. I do like when he shoots one of the werewolves that has the girl, they rest just stop and stare for a second. See what happens when you are supremely overconfident in your ability to be harmed? I do like the end where she changes on TV and then is shot and killed in full view of the audience. Of course few will believe!!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "The Howling" is a 1980s slow-burning horror classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ersinkdotcom
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After news anchor Karen White (Dee Wallace) is attacked by a mysterious stranger (Robert Picardo), she starts having bizarre dreams and night terrors about the incident. Karen's doctor (Patrick Macnee) convinces her that she and husband Bill (Christopher Stone) should go through his treatment at "The Colony." Strange things start to happen as soon as they arrive. Could Karen be cracking up or is there something sinister going on in the secluded resort? Like most movies from the 1970s and the 1980s, "The Howling" is a slow- burner. This isn't one of those horror films that starts with a bang, keeps a frantic pace, and goes out with a bang. It slowly establishes its plot and characters and gives the audience a little at a time until the climactic and shocking end. Things might move too slowly for today's impatient audience. I even found it tedious at times. The scenes get choppy throughout and it seems like director Joe Dante was rushing things at some points. Rob Bottin's special effects for "The Howling" are still just as effective today as they were in 1981. The werewolf transformation scenes are unnerving and quite detailed. One transformation takes what seems like three to four minutes. It's all about attention to detail when it comes to Bottin's practical effects and animatronics versus today's obsession with rapid fire CGI scenes of metamorphosis. "The Howling" does feature quite a bit of the usual unnecessary nudity found in 1980's horror films. However, this time around director Dante attempts to justify it by analyzing our need to let the beast within out, mostly through sexual and physical acts of violence. The doctor, played by the late Patrick Macnee, convincingly regurgitates a lot of "primal scream" mumbo jumbo throughout the movie. Although it's a bit slow and takes some time getting started, great special effects and interesting, albeit hokey, social commentary set "The Howling" apart from the normal monster movie fare.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Joe Dante and Wolves...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Janis Livens
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Howling is one of the best werewolf movies up their with American Werewolf in London. It has everything you would want from a good monster movie: good scares, good laughs and some great effects. Dee Wallace stars in this werewolf film as a reporter who goes to a strange commune after experiencing a bizarre accident with a serial killer. And from that point it's a roller coaster ride of silly characters, wonderful practical effects and awkward werewolf sex. The Howling is a low budget film made for just one million dollars and looks stunning. The cinematography is absolutely gorgeous and makes a great use of both colour and shadows. Joe Dante's direction lends well to the material and shows what he can do with a simple monster movie premise and turns it into something memorable, funny and even heartbreaking. The performances are pretty good. Dee Wallace is great as the tragic heroine and the supporting cast include such goof ball character actors like John Carradine, Slim Pickens and Robert Pickardo. Not to mention the crazy sexy Elisabeth Brooks who does some kinky werewolf sex and so on. The Howling unlike the modern horror movies that feature werewolves and other supernatural creatures, feature great practical effects that are only rivaled by American Werewolf. However, I wouldn't call this film scary. It's hard to scare me or creep me out with something supernatural and especially if you have Slim Pickens in your movie. But horror movie doesn't need to be that scary to be good unlike comedies that need to be funny to any good. Werewolf movies doesn't get much better than Howling and American Werewolf in London. If you enjoy good monster movies that are made with love and care, you owe it to yourself to watch this film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Undoubtedly the inspiration for Michael Jackson's 'Thriller'
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sherazade
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The special effects were as good as can be expected of a movie made in 1980/81 but other than that is was poorly written, poorly directed, poorly acted (especially by the female actors/characters), poorly edited and there were way too many inconsistencies and plot holes. Werewolves movies were to the 80s what Vampire movies are to us now, some were good and most were bad. I would recommend this movie only to people who are fans of some actor in the film and want to see every film they've ever acted in or for those who want to view it for nostalgic reasons or if you're like me and the movie was before your time and you just want to see what films of this genre looked like that back then.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a werewolf classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    trashgang
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Howling has become the father of the new werewolf flicks in the heydays of the eighties. But there was another masterpiece that sadly came out just after The Howling was released, An American Werewolf In London (1982). Why I'm saying this, because Rick Baker, make-up and special effects was involved in both of them. American Werewolf started earlier then The Howling but had financial problems so Rick started with The Howling but when the director of American Werewolf(John Landis) heard that news money was raised and Barker left The Howling to give it towards Rick Bottin. Rick made it a movie with excellent effects and became notorious surely after The Thing (1982). The Howling wanted to do the werewolf transformation in one shot but money prevented it to become that way. American Werewolf did it. But The Howling was the best known werewolf flick. Although being a classic I prefer American because things starts of immediately. The Howling takes almost 50 minutes before a werewolf comes in and the effects become clear. But I must say that the last 40 minutes are worth watching. What a delight to see. The acting was rather good and the way it was filmed (advised by Bottin to use shadow and not that much of lighting) gave it a creepy feeling. A lot of memorable names are here to see but one that was becoming the next big thing was the werewolf Marsha (Elisabeth Brooks). She was noticed because she went full frontal here but her career was suddenly stopped by cancer, she died age 46. Mixed feelings because it isn't a good movie the first 50 minutes but it's a classic for so many reasons. Still, I gave it an 8 for the effects alone. Still, not that gory for a werewolf flick made in the heydays of slashers. Gore 1,5/5 Nudity 1/5 Effects 5/5 Story 3/5 Comedy 0/5
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Great Werewolf Film!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gwnightscream
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dee Wallace, Patrick Macnee, Christopher Stone, Robert Picardo, Dennis Dugan, Belinda Balaski and Elizabeth Brooks star in Joe Dante's 1981 horror film. This begins with newswoman, Karen White (Wallace) preparing to meet man, Eddie Quist (Picardo) whom reveals his secret being a werewolf and is attacked by him. After Eddie is shot by police but not dead, Karen starts to feel different and tries to remember what happened. Macnee plays doctor, George Waggner who helps her and invites her to his spa in the country, the colony. She goes with her husband, Bill Neil (Stone) and they meet an odd group of people staying there and discover there are werewolves. Dugan plays Karen's friend, Chris, Balaski plays his girlfriend, Teri, the late, Brooks plays Marsha, a woman who seduces Bill and Stone was also Wallace's real-life husband. Dick Miller, Roger Corman and Kevin McCarthy also appear and Rob Bottin's make-up effects are terrific as usual. I recommend this great werewolf film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A smart, sexy, and genuinely scary horror classic that still has plenty of bite
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    happyendingrocks
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The werewolf is sort of the neglected middle child of the horror monster hierarchy: gifted, unique, and brilliant, but eternally overshadowed by its dad the Devil, older vampiric siblings, mummified Egyptian stepsons from a previous marriage, and kid brother zombies who are always getting into trouble and keeping the family distracted. Of course there have been great, even legendary, films with lycanthrope antagonists, but that particular sub-genre is rather limited in scope. However, despite the admitted paucity of competition, I can still say with absolute certainty that The Howling is the best movie about werewolves ever made. It makes sense that the film heavily references The Wolf Man, the eternal Lon Chaney Jr./Universal Monsters staple, because The Howling is executed in a way that clearly reveals its acknowledgment of its roots in the traditions of classic horror. The pace is restrained and meticulous, the atmosphere is a character in itself, and despite the film's utilization of creature effects that weren't even dreamed of in Universal's genre heyday, good old-fashioned ensemble acting is what truly drives the action in the piece. If this description makes The Howling sound like a dry production more suited for the theater stage, don't misunderstand me; this is bloody and ferocious fare that will greatly please fans of visceral horror. But it is the taut and well-crafted story, not merely the FX, that make this such a gem, and director Joe Dante is seasoned enough here to allow a gradual and steady immersion into the film's world before bowling us over with Rob Bottin's peerless set-pieces, which have all the more impact when they take command because of how effectively the movie has teased us with tantalizing glimpses throughout. Though the creatures are understandably a feature attraction here, the main focus of the plot is on news anchor Karen White, who has become the fixation of deranged serial killer Eddie Quist and agrees to be used as bait as part of a police operation to capture him. Quist is seemingly killed during her harrowing and macabre encounter, and Karen is subsequently haunted by bizarre dreams and fuzzy, repressed recollections of what actually occurred that night. When she heeds a pop psychologist's suggestion that she and her husband should attend a therapy retreat he oversees at a secluded commune, the getaway does anything but assuage her trauma. Instead, Karen encounters odd and subtly menacing locals and the titular unholy moans emanating from the fog-shrouded forests. It doesn't take long for us to learn that the commune is located at the nucleus of the hunting grounds prowled by a pack of malevolent predatory beasts, and after Karen's husband is seduced and transformed by a sultry lady wolf, her and her visiting reporter friend begin to uncover the sinister secret of the commune. I'll refrain from stepping up on my soapbox to deliver an impassioned soliloquy about how CGI has ruined the art of special make-up FX, but those who appreciate the magic of the wizards who revolutionized the art-form in the late '70s and early '80s will find the work of Rob Bottin here absolutely awe-inspiring. The climactic transformation scene is delivered unflinchingly and in real time, step by grotesque step, and the result is an indelible sequence that remains far more impressive and enthralling than anything modern film-makers handling the same material could ever cook up on a computer. The gore is used sparingly for maximum impact, but whenever it arrives, the results are stunning and gruesome. Perhaps most importantly, the werewolves themselves are a thing of fearsome beauty to behold, monsters that resonate as wholly believable extensions of the established mythology while still maintaining an innovative stroke of originality that makes them belong to this film alone. These creatures aren't merely big wolves, they are eight-foot tall bipedal killing machines with fangs and claws capable of tearing people to shreds, a skill that they demonstrate with acute proficiency during the course of the movie. The performances are all excellent even when the roles veer into the melodramatic, and the presence of one of the power couples of '80s horror, Christopher Stone and Dee Wallace (later Dee Wallace Stone), as well as a marvelous extended cameo from beloved genre vet Dick Miller, will delight fans of the era. Both the gritty, sleazy streets that open the movie and the isolated location housing the commune complex are perfectly presented and utilized, the clues to the greater mystery are unfolded with the taut grace of a top-notch thriller, and the film as a whole feels like an entirely plausible representation of ancient folk lore-based creatures existing in a modern world. The denouement falters slightly since Bottin's best tricks have already been displayed, but the sentiment of the finale is striking enough to end the saga on a dark and tragic note. If your love of the genre goes back to its natal days, be sure to stick around after the credits too, where you'll find a nice coda that bookends the homage to The Wolf Man present throughout these reels. The Howling is, in my estimation, not only the finest and most enduring lycanthropy fable in the canon, it's also quite simply one of the best horror films of all time. Don't skip this one.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Scary But Fun.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Joe Dante pulled off an impressive feat directing this scary but humorous film about a traumatized newswoman (sweet & appealing Dee Wallace) who is persuaded to go to a mysterious retreat by a noted psychologist(Patrick Macnee, very suave but sympathetic) where her bad luck sadly continues when she is forced to confront some sinister werewolves... Very clever script incorporates real-life werewolf directors as character names, and has awe-inspiring make-up F/X, the first of their kind. Well-directed and suspenseful, though final sequence goes a little too far in self-aware humor. Otherwise, cant-miss film for genre fans.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It goes on a bit
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Despite numerous in-jokes, characters named after horror directors, a cameo by Roger Corman and appearances from Joe Dante favourites Kevin McCarthy, Dick Miller and Robert Picardo, this werewolf movie is almost entirely lacking in enjoyment. It's a dreary and boring movie composed of leaden silences punctuated by droning dialogue recited by flat characters at a droning pace. Dee Wallace is a TV newswoman who heads to a retreat run by doctor Patrick Macnee but finds that her holiday isn't as peaceful as she expected when the place is overrun by werewolves. Although Dante has some fun contrasting what the characters are watching on TV with the events of the movie, the disappointingly droopy plot gets less interesting the more it goes on and by the end, when everyone's bearing their fangs and sprouting rubbery wolf faces, it all looks pretty stupid.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I do hope the book is better
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    siderite
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've begun watching The Howling with high expectations, as someone described it as "one of the 2 best Werewolf movies ever made". Unfortunately, he just might be right, but that is not saying much. Probably the spike in quality is caused by the movie being a book adaptation and I do hope the book was a lot better. Now, don't imagine the movie is very bad. For an 1981 movie with werewolves, indeed it is good, but it has that feel of a money grabbing movie studio doing an adaptation after a money grabbing publisher selling books of a certain type. You've all read those books: somewhere in a small American town, where everybody knows each other and there is dark secret, a city dweller comes to shake up the status quo. Probably Americans read a lot of these books, but I've had it up to my furry neck and my pointy teeth with this kind of bull. It is boring, pretentious and most of the time rehashing similar stories that were probably good when they were written but have now dissolved into lameness. Bottom line: I am sure I have seen this movie before, when I was young, but except the scene at the end, which had its share of drama and societal satire, I did not remember one thing while watching it again now. It is a mostly forgettable movie, with unsympathetic characters and a rushed story so that it can cover the entire book. Yes, indeed, take the story, make it a miniseries in the style of Stephen King adaptations and add some decent acting and special effects, and it would do great today, but this film just feels... wrong.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Disappointed
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SanteeFats
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I realize this movie was made over thirty years ago and it is not a blood and guts for shock value type movie (which I like) buuuuuttt!!! This is one very slow developing story. First if you can become a werewolf by bite or scratch the world would be overrun with them. This one does have them as shape shifters and therefore not tied to the Hollywood stereotypical full moon only ability to change. I will admit that when they started the transformations it was done very well for the time period, no CGI there. Then you have reporter who shows up with (gasp) the magic silver bullets! There is goof here as he first jacks a bullet in to the chamber when he gets out of his car and then again when he is in the office. I do like when he shoots one of the werewolves that has the girl, they rest just stop and stare for a second. See what happens when you are supremely overconfident in your ability to be harmed? I do like the end where she changes on TV and then is shot and killed in full view of the audience. Of course few will believe!!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "The Howling" is a 1980s slow-burning horror classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ersinkdotcom
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After news anchor Karen White (Dee Wallace) is attacked by a mysterious stranger (Robert Picardo), she starts having bizarre dreams and night terrors about the incident. Karen's doctor (Patrick Macnee) convinces her that she and husband Bill (Christopher Stone) should go through his treatment at "The Colony." Strange things start to happen as soon as they arrive. Could Karen be cracking up or is there something sinister going on in the secluded resort? Like most movies from the 1970s and the 1980s, "The Howling" is a slow- burner. This isn't one of those horror films that starts with a bang, keeps a frantic pace, and goes out with a bang. It slowly establishes its plot and characters and gives the audience a little at a time until the climactic and shocking end. Things might move too slowly for today's impatient audience. I even found it tedious at times. The scenes get choppy throughout and it seems like director Joe Dante was rushing things at some points. Rob Bottin's special effects for "The Howling" are still just as effective today as they were in 1981. The werewolf transformation scenes are unnerving and quite detailed. One transformation takes what seems like three to four minutes. It's all about attention to detail when it comes to Bottin's practical effects and animatronics versus today's obsession with rapid fire CGI scenes of metamorphosis. "The Howling" does feature quite a bit of the usual unnecessary nudity found in 1980's horror films. However, this time around director Dante attempts to justify it by analyzing our need to let the beast within out, mostly through sexual and physical acts of violence. The doctor, played by the late Patrick Macnee, convincingly regurgitates a lot of "primal scream" mumbo jumbo throughout the movie. Although it's a bit slow and takes some time getting started, great special effects and interesting, albeit hokey, social commentary set "The Howling" apart from the normal monster movie fare.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Joe Dante and Wolves...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Janis Livens
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Howling is one of the best werewolf movies up their with American Werewolf in London. It has everything you would want from a good monster movie: good scares, good laughs and some great effects. Dee Wallace stars in this werewolf film as a reporter who goes to a strange commune after experiencing a bizarre accident with a serial killer. And from that point it's a roller coaster ride of silly characters, wonderful practical effects and awkward werewolf sex. The Howling is a low budget film made for just one million dollars and looks stunning. The cinematography is absolutely gorgeous and makes a great use of both colour and shadows. Joe Dante's direction lends well to the material and shows what he can do with a simple monster movie premise and turns it into something memorable, funny and even heartbreaking. The performances are pretty good. Dee Wallace is great as the tragic heroine and the supporting cast include such goof ball character actors like John Carradine, Slim Pickens and Robert Pickardo. Not to mention the crazy sexy Elisabeth Brooks who does some kinky werewolf sex and so on. The Howling unlike the modern horror movies that feature werewolves and other supernatural creatures, feature great practical effects that are only rivaled by American Werewolf. However, I wouldn't call this film scary. It's hard to scare me or creep me out with something supernatural and especially if you have Slim Pickens in your movie. But horror movie doesn't need to be that scary to be good unlike comedies that need to be funny to any good. Werewolf movies doesn't get much better than Howling and American Werewolf in London. If you enjoy good monster movies that are made with love and care, you owe it to yourself to watch this film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Undoubtedly the inspiration for Michael Jackson's 'Thriller'
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sherazade
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The special effects were as good as can be expected of a movie made in 1980/81 but other than that is was poorly written, poorly directed, poorly acted (especially by the female actors/characters), poorly edited and there were way too many inconsistencies and plot holes. Werewolves movies were to the 80s what Vampire movies are to us now, some were good and most were bad. I would recommend this movie only to people who are fans of some actor in the film and want to see every film they've ever acted in or for those who want to view it for nostalgic reasons or if you're like me and the movie was before your time and you just want to see what films of this genre looked like that back then.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a werewolf classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    trashgang
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Howling has become the father of the new werewolf flicks in the heydays of the eighties. But there was another masterpiece that sadly came out just after The Howling was released, An American Werewolf In London (1982). Why I'm saying this, because Rick Baker, make-up and special effects was involved in both of them. American Werewolf started earlier then The Howling but had financial problems so Rick started with The Howling but when the director of American Werewolf(John Landis) heard that news money was raised and Barker left The Howling to give it towards Rick Bottin. Rick made it a movie with excellent effects and became notorious surely after The Thing (1982). The Howling wanted to do the werewolf transformation in one shot but money prevented it to become that way. American Werewolf did it. But The Howling was the best known werewolf flick. Although being a classic I prefer American because things starts of immediately. The Howling takes almost 50 minutes before a werewolf comes in and the effects become clear. But I must say that the last 40 minutes are worth watching. What a delight to see. The acting was rather good and the way it was filmed (advised by Bottin to use shadow and not that much of lighting) gave it a creepy feeling. A lot of memorable names are here to see but one that was becoming the next big thing was the werewolf Marsha (Elisabeth Brooks). She was noticed because she went full frontal here but her career was suddenly stopped by cancer, she died age 46. Mixed feelings because it isn't a good movie the first 50 minutes but it's a classic for so many reasons. Still, I gave it an 8 for the effects alone. Still, not that gory for a werewolf flick made in the heydays of slashers. Gore 1,5/5 Nudity 1/5 Effects 5/5 Story 3/5 Comedy 0/5
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Great Werewolf Film!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gwnightscream
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dee Wallace, Patrick Macnee, Christopher Stone, Robert Picardo, Dennis Dugan, Belinda Balaski and Elizabeth Brooks star in Joe Dante's 1981 horror film. This begins with newswoman, Karen White (Wallace) preparing to meet man, Eddie Quist (Picardo) whom reveals his secret being a werewolf and is attacked by him. After Eddie is shot by police but not dead, Karen starts to feel different and tries to remember what happened. Macnee plays doctor, George Waggner who helps her and invites her to his spa in the country, the colony. She goes with her husband, Bill Neil (Stone) and they meet an odd group of people staying there and discover there are werewolves. Dugan plays Karen's friend, Chris, Balaski plays his girlfriend, Teri, the late, Brooks plays Marsha, a woman who seduces Bill and Stone was also Wallace's real-life husband. Dick Miller, Roger Corman and Kevin McCarthy also appear and Rob Bottin's make-up effects are terrific as usual. I recommend this great werewolf film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A smart, sexy, and genuinely scary horror classic that still has plenty of bite
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    happyendingrocks
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The werewolf is sort of the neglected middle child of the horror monster hierarchy: gifted, unique, and brilliant, but eternally overshadowed by its dad the Devil, older vampiric siblings, mummified Egyptian stepsons from a previous marriage, and kid brother zombies who are always getting into trouble and keeping the family distracted. Of course there have been great, even legendary, films with lycanthrope antagonists, but that particular sub-genre is rather limited in scope. However, despite the admitted paucity of competition, I can still say with absolute certainty that The Howling is the best movie about werewolves ever made. It makes sense that the film heavily references The Wolf Man, the eternal Lon Chaney Jr./Universal Monsters staple, because The Howling is executed in a way that clearly reveals its acknowledgment of its roots in the traditions of classic horror. The pace is restrained and meticulous, the atmosphere is a character in itself, and despite the film's utilization of creature effects that weren't even dreamed of in Universal's genre heyday, good old-fashioned ensemble acting is what truly drives the action in the piece. If this description makes The Howling sound like a dry production more suited for the theater stage, don't misunderstand me; this is bloody and ferocious fare that will greatly please fans of visceral horror. But it is the taut and well-crafted story, not merely the FX, that make this such a gem, and director Joe Dante is seasoned enough here to allow a gradual and steady immersion into the film's world before bowling us over with Rob Bottin's peerless set-pieces, which have all the more impact when they take command because of how effectively the movie has teased us with tantalizing glimpses throughout. Though the creatures are understandably a feature attraction here, the main focus of the plot is on news anchor Karen White, who has become the fixation of deranged serial killer Eddie Quist and agrees to be used as bait as part of a police operation to capture him. Quist is seemingly killed during her harrowing and macabre encounter, and Karen is subsequently haunted by bizarre dreams and fuzzy, repressed recollections of what actually occurred that night. When she heeds a pop psychologist's suggestion that she and her husband should attend a therapy retreat he oversees at a secluded commune, the getaway does anything but assuage her trauma. Instead, Karen encounters odd and subtly menacing locals and the titular unholy moans emanating from the fog-shrouded forests. It doesn't take long for us to learn that the commune is located at the nucleus of the hunting grounds prowled by a pack of malevolent predatory beasts, and after Karen's husband is seduced and transformed by a sultry lady wolf, her and her visiting reporter friend begin to uncover the sinister secret of the commune. I'll refrain from stepping up on my soapbox to deliver an impassioned soliloquy about how CGI has ruined the art of special make-up FX, but those who appreciate the magic of the wizards who revolutionized the art-form in the late '70s and early '80s will find the work of Rob Bottin here absolutely awe-inspiring. The climactic transformation scene is delivered unflinchingly and in real time, step by grotesque step, and the result is an indelible sequence that remains far more impressive and enthralling than anything modern film-makers handling the same material could ever cook up on a computer. The gore is used sparingly for maximum impact, but whenever it arrives, the results are stunning and gruesome. Perhaps most importantly, the werewolves themselves are a thing of fearsome beauty to behold, monsters that resonate as wholly believable extensions of the established mythology while still maintaining an innovative stroke of originality that makes them belong to this film alone. These creatures aren't merely big wolves, they are eight-foot tall bipedal killing machines with fangs and claws capable of tearing people to shreds, a skill that they demonstrate with acute proficiency during the course of the movie. The performances are all excellent even when the roles veer into the melodramatic, and the presence of one of the power couples of '80s horror, Christopher Stone and Dee Wallace (later Dee Wallace Stone), as well as a marvelous extended cameo from beloved genre vet Dick Miller, will delight fans of the era. Both the gritty, sleazy streets that open the movie and the isolated location housing the commune complex are perfectly presented and utilized, the clues to the greater mystery are unfolded with the taut grace of a top-notch thriller, and the film as a whole feels like an entirely plausible representation of ancient folk lore-based creatures existing in a modern world. The denouement falters slightly since Bottin's best tricks have already been displayed, but the sentiment of the finale is striking enough to end the saga on a dark and tragic note. If your love of the genre goes back to its natal days, be sure to stick around after the credits too, where you'll find a nice coda that bookends the homage to The Wolf Man present throughout these reels. The Howling is, in my estimation, not only the finest and most enduring lycanthropy fable in the canon, it's also quite simply one of the best horror films of all time. Don't skip this one.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Scary But Fun.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Joe Dante pulled off an impressive feat directing this scary but humorous film about a traumatized newswoman (sweet & appealing Dee Wallace) who is persuaded to go to a mysterious retreat by a noted psychologist(Patrick Macnee, very suave but sympathetic) where her bad luck sadly continues when she is forced to confront some sinister werewolves... Very clever script incorporates real-life werewolf directors as character names, and has awe-inspiring make-up F/X, the first of their kind. Well-directed and suspenseful, though final sequence goes a little too far in self-aware humor. Otherwise, cant-miss film for genre fans.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It goes on a bit
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Despite numerous in-jokes, characters named after horror directors, a cameo by Roger Corman and appearances from Joe Dante favourites Kevin McCarthy, Dick Miller and Robert Picardo, this werewolf movie is almost entirely lacking in enjoyment. It's a dreary and boring movie composed of leaden silences punctuated by droning dialogue recited by flat characters at a droning pace. Dee Wallace is a TV newswoman who heads to a retreat run by doctor Patrick Macnee but finds that her holiday isn't as peaceful as she expected when the place is overrun by werewolves. Although Dante has some fun contrasting what the characters are watching on TV with the events of the movie, the disappointingly droopy plot gets less interesting the more it goes on and by the end, when everyone's bearing their fangs and sprouting rubbery wolf faces, it all looks pretty stupid.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I do hope the book is better
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    siderite
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've begun watching The Howling with high expectations, as someone described it as "one of the 2 best Werewolf movies ever made". Unfortunately, he just might be right, but that is not saying much. Probably the spike in quality is caused by the movie being a book adaptation and I do hope the book was a lot better. Now, don't imagine the movie is very bad. For an 1981 movie with werewolves, indeed it is good, but it has that feel of a money grabbing movie studio doing an adaptation after a money grabbing publisher selling books of a certain type. You've all read those books: somewhere in a small American town, where everybody knows each other and there is dark secret, a city dweller comes to shake up the status quo. Probably Americans read a lot of these books, but I've had it up to my furry neck and my pointy teeth with this kind of bull. It is boring, pretentious and most of the time rehashing similar stories that were probably good when they were written but have now dissolved into lameness. Bottom line: I am sure I have seen this movie before, when I was young, but except the scene at the end, which had its share of drama and societal satire, I did not remember one thing while watching it again now. It is a mostly forgettable movie, with unsympathetic characters and a rushed story so that it can cover the entire book. Yes, indeed, take the story, make it a miniseries in the style of Stephen King adaptations and add some decent acting and special effects, and it would do great today, but this film just feels... wrong.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Disappointed
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SanteeFats
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I realize this movie was made over thirty years ago and it is not a blood and guts for shock value type movie (which I like) buuuuuttt!!! This is one very slow developing story. First if you can become a werewolf by bite or scratch the world would be overrun with them. This one does have them as shape shifters and therefore not tied to the Hollywood stereotypical full moon only ability to change. I will admit that when they started the transformations it was done very well for the time period, no CGI there. Then you have reporter who shows up with (gasp) the magic silver bullets! There is goof here as he first jacks a bullet in to the chamber when he gets out of his car and then again when he is in the office. I do like when he shoots one of the werewolves that has the girl, they rest just stop and stare for a second. See what happens when you are supremely overconfident in your ability to be harmed? I do like the end where she changes on TV and then is shot and killed in full view of the audience. Of course few will believe!!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "The Howling" is a 1980s slow-burning horror classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ersinkdotcom
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After news anchor Karen White (Dee Wallace) is attacked by a mysterious stranger (Robert Picardo), she starts having bizarre dreams and night terrors about the incident. Karen's doctor (Patrick Macnee) convinces her that she and husband Bill (Christopher Stone) should go through his treatment at "The Colony." Strange things start to happen as soon as they arrive. Could Karen be cracking up or is there something sinister going on in the secluded resort? Like most movies from the 1970s and the 1980s, "The Howling" is a slow- burner. This isn't one of those horror films that starts with a bang, keeps a frantic pace, and goes out with a bang. It slowly establishes its plot and characters and gives the audience a little at a time until the climactic and shocking end. Things might move too slowly for today's impatient audience. I even found it tedious at times. The scenes get choppy throughout and it seems like director Joe Dante was rushing things at some points. Rob Bottin's special effects for "The Howling" are still just as effective today as they were in 1981. The werewolf transformation scenes are unnerving and quite detailed. One transformation takes what seems like three to four minutes. It's all about attention to detail when it comes to Bottin's practical effects and animatronics versus today's obsession with rapid fire CGI scenes of metamorphosis. "The Howling" does feature quite a bit of the usual unnecessary nudity found in 1980's horror films. However, this time around director Dante attempts to justify it by analyzing our need to let the beast within out, mostly through sexual and physical acts of violence. The doctor, played by the late Patrick Macnee, convincingly regurgitates a lot of "primal scream" mumbo jumbo throughout the movie. Although it's a bit slow and takes some time getting started, great special effects and interesting, albeit hokey, social commentary set "The Howling" apart from the normal monster movie fare.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Joe Dante and Wolves...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Janis Livens
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Howling is one of the best werewolf movies up their with American Werewolf in London. It has everything you would want from a good monster movie: good scares, good laughs and some great effects. Dee Wallace stars in this werewolf film as a reporter who goes to a strange commune after experiencing a bizarre accident with a serial killer. And from that point it's a roller coaster ride of silly characters, wonderful practical effects and awkward werewolf sex. The Howling is a low budget film made for just one million dollars and looks stunning. The cinematography is absolutely gorgeous and makes a great use of both colour and shadows. Joe Dante's direction lends well to the material and shows what he can do with a simple monster movie premise and turns it into something memorable, funny and even heartbreaking. The performances are pretty good. Dee Wallace is great as the tragic heroine and the supporting cast include such goof ball character actors like John Carradine, Slim Pickens and Robert Pickardo. Not to mention the crazy sexy Elisabeth Brooks who does some kinky werewolf sex and so on. The Howling unlike the modern horror movies that feature werewolves and other supernatural creatures, feature great practical effects that are only rivaled by American Werewolf. However, I wouldn't call this film scary. It's hard to scare me or creep me out with something supernatural and especially if you have Slim Pickens in your movie. But horror movie doesn't need to be that scary to be good unlike comedies that need to be funny to any good. Werewolf movies doesn't get much better than Howling and American Werewolf in London. If you enjoy good monster movies that are made with love and care, you owe it to yourself to watch this film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Undoubtedly the inspiration for Michael Jackson's 'Thriller'
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sherazade
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The special effects were as good as can be expected of a movie made in 1980/81 but other than that is was poorly written, poorly directed, poorly acted (especially by the female actors/characters), poorly edited and there were way too many inconsistencies and plot holes. Werewolves movies were to the 80s what Vampire movies are to us now, some were good and most were bad. I would recommend this movie only to people who are fans of some actor in the film and want to see every film they've ever acted in or for those who want to view it for nostalgic reasons or if you're like me and the movie was before your time and you just want to see what films of this genre looked like that back then.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a werewolf classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    trashgang
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Howling has become the father of the new werewolf flicks in the heydays of the eighties. But there was another masterpiece that sadly came out just after The Howling was released, An American Werewolf In London (1982). Why I'm saying this, because Rick Baker, make-up and special effects was involved in both of them. American Werewolf started earlier then The Howling but had financial problems so Rick started with The Howling but when the director of American Werewolf(John Landis) heard that news money was raised and Barker left The Howling to give it towards Rick Bottin. Rick made it a movie with excellent effects and became notorious surely after The Thing (1982). The Howling wanted to do the werewolf transformation in one shot but money prevented it to become that way. American Werewolf did it. But The Howling was the best known werewolf flick. Although being a classic I prefer American because things starts of immediately. The Howling takes almost 50 minutes before a werewolf comes in and the effects become clear. But I must say that the last 40 minutes are worth watching. What a delight to see. The acting was rather good and the way it was filmed (advised by Bottin to use shadow and not that much of lighting) gave it a creepy feeling. A lot of memorable names are here to see but one that was becoming the next big thing was the werewolf Marsha (Elisabeth Brooks). She was noticed because she went full frontal here but her career was suddenly stopped by cancer, she died age 46. Mixed feelings because it isn't a good movie the first 50 minutes but it's a classic for so many reasons. Still, I gave it an 8 for the effects alone. Still, not that gory for a werewolf flick made in the heydays of slashers. Gore 1,5/5 Nudity 1/5 Effects 5/5 Story 3/5 Comedy 0/5
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Great Werewolf Film!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gwnightscream
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dee Wallace, Patrick Macnee, Christopher Stone, Robert Picardo, Dennis Dugan, Belinda Balaski and Elizabeth Brooks star in Joe Dante's 1981 horror film. This begins with newswoman, Karen White (Wallace) preparing to meet man, Eddie Quist (Picardo) whom reveals his secret being a werewolf and is attacked by him. After Eddie is shot by police but not dead, Karen starts to feel different and tries to remember what happened. Macnee plays doctor, George Waggner who helps her and invites her to his spa in the country, the colony. She goes with her husband, Bill Neil (Stone) and they meet an odd group of people staying there and discover there are werewolves. Dugan plays Karen's friend, Chris, Balaski plays his girlfriend, Teri, the late, Brooks plays Marsha, a woman who seduces Bill and Stone was also Wallace's real-life husband. Dick Miller, Roger Corman and Kevin McCarthy also appear and Rob Bottin's make-up effects are terrific as usual. I recommend this great werewolf film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A smart, sexy, and genuinely scary horror classic that still has plenty of bite
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    happyendingrocks
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The werewolf is sort of the neglected middle child of the horror monster hierarchy: gifted, unique, and brilliant, but eternally overshadowed by its dad the Devil, older vampiric siblings, mummified Egyptian stepsons from a previous marriage, and kid brother zombies who are always getting into trouble and keeping the family distracted. Of course there have been great, even legendary, films with lycanthrope antagonists, but that particular sub-genre is rather limited in scope. However, despite the admitted paucity of competition, I can still say with absolute certainty that The Howling is the best movie about werewolves ever made. It makes sense that the film heavily references The Wolf Man, the eternal Lon Chaney Jr./Universal Monsters staple, because The Howling is executed in a way that clearly reveals its acknowledgment of its roots in the traditions of classic horror. The pace is restrained and meticulous, the atmosphere is a character in itself, and despite the film's utilization of creature effects that weren't even dreamed of in Universal's genre heyday, good old-fashioned ensemble acting is what truly drives the action in the piece. If this description makes The Howling sound like a dry production more suited for the theater stage, don't misunderstand me; this is bloody and ferocious fare that will greatly please fans of visceral horror. But it is the taut and well-crafted story, not merely the FX, that make this such a gem, and director Joe Dante is seasoned enough here to allow a gradual and steady immersion into the film's world before bowling us over with Rob Bottin's peerless set-pieces, which have all the more impact when they take command because of how effectively the movie has teased us with tantalizing glimpses throughout. Though the creatures are understandably a feature attraction here, the main focus of the plot is on news anchor Karen White, who has become the fixation of deranged serial killer Eddie Quist and agrees to be used as bait as part of a police operation to capture him. Quist is seemingly killed during her harrowing and macabre encounter, and Karen is subsequently haunted by bizarre dreams and fuzzy, repressed recollections of what actually occurred that night. When she heeds a pop psychologist's suggestion that she and her husband should attend a therapy retreat he oversees at a secluded commune, the getaway does anything but assuage her trauma. Instead, Karen encounters odd and subtly menacing locals and the titular unholy moans emanating from the fog-shrouded forests. It doesn't take long for us to learn that the commune is located at the nucleus of the hunting grounds prowled by a pack of malevolent predatory beasts, and after Karen's husband is seduced and transformed by a sultry lady wolf, her and her visiting reporter friend begin to uncover the sinister secret of the commune. I'll refrain from stepping up on my soapbox to deliver an impassioned soliloquy about how CGI has ruined the art of special make-up FX, but those who appreciate the magic of the wizards who revolutionized the art-form in the late '70s and early '80s will find the work of Rob Bottin here absolutely awe-inspiring. The climactic transformation scene is delivered unflinchingly and in real time, step by grotesque step, and the result is an indelible sequence that remains far more impressive and enthralling than anything modern film-makers handling the same material could ever cook up on a computer. The gore is used sparingly for maximum impact, but whenever it arrives, the results are stunning and gruesome. Perhaps most importantly, the werewolves themselves are a thing of fearsome beauty to behold, monsters that resonate as wholly believable extensions of the established mythology while still maintaining an innovative stroke of originality that makes them belong to this film alone. These creatures aren't merely big wolves, they are eight-foot tall bipedal killing machines with fangs and claws capable of tearing people to shreds, a skill that they demonstrate with acute proficiency during the course of the movie. The performances are all excellent even when the roles veer into the melodramatic, and the presence of one of the power couples of '80s horror, Christopher Stone and Dee Wallace (later Dee Wallace Stone), as well as a marvelous extended cameo from beloved genre vet Dick Miller, will delight fans of the era. Both the gritty, sleazy streets that open the movie and the isolated location housing the commune complex are perfectly presented and utilized, the clues to the greater mystery are unfolded with the taut grace of a top-notch thriller, and the film as a whole feels like an entirely plausible representation of ancient folk lore-based creatures existing in a modern world. The denouement falters slightly since Bottin's best tricks have already been displayed, but the sentiment of the finale is striking enough to end the saga on a dark and tragic note. If your love of the genre goes back to its natal days, be sure to stick around after the credits too, where you'll find a nice coda that bookends the homage to The Wolf Man present throughout these reels. The Howling is, in my estimation, not only the finest and most enduring lycanthropy fable in the canon, it's also quite simply one of the best horror films of all time. Don't skip this one.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Scary But Fun.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Joe Dante pulled off an impressive feat directing this scary but humorous film about a traumatized newswoman (sweet & appealing Dee Wallace) who is persuaded to go to a mysterious retreat by a noted psychologist(Patrick Macnee, very suave but sympathetic) where her bad luck sadly continues when she is forced to confront some sinister werewolves... Very clever script incorporates real-life werewolf directors as character names, and has awe-inspiring make-up F/X, the first of their kind. Well-directed and suspenseful, though final sequence goes a little too far in self-aware humor. Otherwise, cant-miss film for genre fans.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It goes on a bit
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Despite numerous in-jokes, characters named after horror directors, a cameo by Roger Corman and appearances from Joe Dante favourites Kevin McCarthy, Dick Miller and Robert Picardo, this werewolf movie is almost entirely lacking in enjoyment. It's a dreary and boring movie composed of leaden silences punctuated by droning dialogue recited by flat characters at a droning pace. Dee Wallace is a TV newswoman who heads to a retreat run by doctor Patrick Macnee but finds that her holiday isn't as peaceful as she expected when the place is overrun by werewolves. Although Dante has some fun contrasting what the characters are watching on TV with the events of the movie, the disappointingly droopy plot gets less interesting the more it goes on and by the end, when everyone's bearing their fangs and sprouting rubbery wolf faces, it all looks pretty stupid.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I do hope the book is better
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    siderite
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've begun watching The Howling with high expectations, as someone described it as "one of the 2 best Werewolf movies ever made". Unfortunately, he just might be right, but that is not saying much. Probably the spike in quality is caused by the movie being a book adaptation and I do hope the book was a lot better. Now, don't imagine the movie is very bad. For an 1981 movie with werewolves, indeed it is good, but it has that feel of a money grabbing movie studio doing an adaptation after a money grabbing publisher selling books of a certain type. You've all read those books: somewhere in a small American town, where everybody knows each other and there is dark secret, a city dweller comes to shake up the status quo. Probably Americans read a lot of these books, but I've had it up to my furry neck and my pointy teeth with this kind of bull. It is boring, pretentious and most of the time rehashing similar stories that were probably good when they were written but have now dissolved into lameness. Bottom line: I am sure I have seen this movie before, when I was young, but except the scene at the end, which had its share of drama and societal satire, I did not remember one thing while watching it again now. It is a mostly forgettable movie, with unsympathetic characters and a rushed story so that it can cover the entire book. Yes, indeed, take the story, make it a miniseries in the style of Stephen King adaptations and add some decent acting and special effects, and it would do great today, but this film just feels... wrong.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Disappointed
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SanteeFats
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I realize this movie was made over thirty years ago and it is not a blood and guts for shock value type movie (which I like) buuuuuttt!!! This is one very slow developing story. First if you can become a werewolf by bite or scratch the world would be overrun with them. This one does have them as shape shifters and therefore not tied to the Hollywood stereotypical full moon only ability to change. I will admit that when they started the transformations it was done very well for the time period, no CGI there. Then you have reporter who shows up with (gasp) the magic silver bullets! There is goof here as he first jacks a bullet in to the chamber when he gets out of his car and then again when he is in the office. I do like when he shoots one of the werewolves that has the girl, they rest just stop and stare for a second. See what happens when you are supremely overconfident in your ability to be harmed? I do like the end where she changes on TV and then is shot and killed in full view of the audience. Of course few will believe!!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "The Howling" is a 1980s slow-burning horror classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ersinkdotcom
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After news anchor Karen White (Dee Wallace) is attacked by a mysterious stranger (Robert Picardo), she starts having bizarre dreams and night terrors about the incident. Karen's doctor (Patrick Macnee) convinces her that she and husband Bill (Christopher Stone) should go through his treatment at "The Colony." Strange things start to happen as soon as they arrive. Could Karen be cracking up or is there something sinister going on in the secluded resort? Like most movies from the 1970s and the 1980s, "The Howling" is a slow- burner. This isn't one of those horror films that starts with a bang, keeps a frantic pace, and goes out with a bang. It slowly establishes its plot and characters and gives the audience a little at a time until the climactic and shocking end. Things might move too slowly for today's impatient audience. I even found it tedious at times. The scenes get choppy throughout and it seems like director Joe Dante was rushing things at some points. Rob Bottin's special effects for "The Howling" are still just as effective today as they were in 1981. The werewolf transformation scenes are unnerving and quite detailed. One transformation takes what seems like three to four minutes. It's all about attention to detail when it comes to Bottin's practical effects and animatronics versus today's obsession with rapid fire CGI scenes of metamorphosis. "The Howling" does feature quite a bit of the usual unnecessary nudity found in 1980's horror films. However, this time around director Dante attempts to justify it by analyzing our need to let the beast within out, mostly through sexual and physical acts of violence. The doctor, played by the late Patrick Macnee, convincingly regurgitates a lot of "primal scream" mumbo jumbo throughout the movie. Although it's a bit slow and takes some time getting started, great special effects and interesting, albeit hokey, social commentary set "The Howling" apart from the normal monster movie fare.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Joe Dante and Wolves...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Janis Livens
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Howling is one of the best werewolf movies up their with American Werewolf in London. It has everything you would want from a good monster movie: good scares, good laughs and some great effects. Dee Wallace stars in this werewolf film as a reporter who goes to a strange commune after experiencing a bizarre accident with a serial killer. And from that point it's a roller coaster ride of silly characters, wonderful practical effects and awkward werewolf sex. The Howling is a low budget film made for just one million dollars and looks stunning. The cinematography is absolutely gorgeous and makes a great use of both colour and shadows. Joe Dante's direction lends well to the material and shows what he can do with a simple monster movie premise and turns it into something memorable, funny and even heartbreaking. The performances are pretty good. Dee Wallace is great as the tragic heroine and the supporting cast include such goof ball character actors like John Carradine, Slim Pickens and Robert Pickardo. Not to mention the crazy sexy Elisabeth Brooks who does some kinky werewolf sex and so on. The Howling unlike the modern horror movies that feature werewolves and other supernatural creatures, feature great practical effects that are only rivaled by American Werewolf. However, I wouldn't call this film scary. It's hard to scare me or creep me out with something supernatural and especially if you have Slim Pickens in your movie. But horror movie doesn't need to be that scary to be good unlike comedies that need to be funny to any good. Werewolf movies doesn't get much better than Howling and American Werewolf in London. If you enjoy good monster movies that are made with love and care, you owe it to yourself to watch this film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Undoubtedly the inspiration for Michael Jackson's 'Thriller'
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sherazade
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The special effects were as good as can be expected of a movie made in 1980/81 but other than that is was poorly written, poorly directed, poorly acted (especially by the female actors/characters), poorly edited and there were way too many inconsistencies and plot holes. Werewolves movies were to the 80s what Vampire movies are to us now, some were good and most were bad. I would recommend this movie only to people who are fans of some actor in the film and want to see every film they've ever acted in or for those who want to view it for nostalgic reasons or if you're like me and the movie was before your time and you just want to see what films of this genre looked like that back then.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a werewolf classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    trashgang
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Howling has become the father of the new werewolf flicks in the heydays of the eighties. But there was another masterpiece that sadly came out just after The Howling was released, An American Werewolf In London (1982). Why I'm saying this, because Rick Baker, make-up and special effects was involved in both of them. American Werewolf started earlier then The Howling but had financial problems so Rick started with The Howling but when the director of American Werewolf(John Landis) heard that news money was raised and Barker left The Howling to give it towards Rick Bottin. Rick made it a movie with excellent effects and became notorious surely after The Thing (1982). The Howling wanted to do the werewolf transformation in one shot but money prevented it to become that way. American Werewolf did it. But The Howling was the best known werewolf flick. Although being a classic I prefer American because things starts of immediately. The Howling takes almost 50 minutes before a werewolf comes in and the effects become clear. But I must say that the last 40 minutes are worth watching. What a delight to see. The acting was rather good and the way it was filmed (advised by Bottin to use shadow and not that much of lighting) gave it a creepy feeling. A lot of memorable names are here to see but one that was becoming the next big thing was the werewolf Marsha (Elisabeth Brooks). She was noticed because she went full frontal here but her career was suddenly stopped by cancer, she died age 46. Mixed feelings because it isn't a good movie the first 50 minutes but it's a classic for so many reasons. Still, I gave it an 8 for the effects alone. Still, not that gory for a werewolf flick made in the heydays of slashers. Gore 1,5/5 Nudity 1/5 Effects 5/5 Story 3/5 Comedy 0/5
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Great Werewolf Film!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gwnightscream
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dee Wallace, Patrick Macnee, Christopher Stone, Robert Picardo, Dennis Dugan, Belinda Balaski and Elizabeth Brooks star in Joe Dante's 1981 horror film. This begins with newswoman, Karen White (Wallace) preparing to meet man, Eddie Quist (Picardo) whom reveals his secret being a werewolf and is attacked by him. After Eddie is shot by police but not dead, Karen starts to feel different and tries to remember what happened. Macnee plays doctor, George Waggner who helps her and invites her to his spa in the country, the colony. She goes with her husband, Bill Neil (Stone) and they meet an odd group of people staying there and discover there are werewolves. Dugan plays Karen's friend, Chris, Balaski plays his girlfriend, Teri, the late, Brooks plays Marsha, a woman who seduces Bill and Stone was also Wallace's real-life husband. Dick Miller, Roger Corman and Kevin McCarthy also appear and Rob Bottin's make-up effects are terrific as usual. I recommend this great werewolf film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A smart, sexy, and genuinely scary horror classic that still has plenty of bite
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    happyendingrocks
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The werewolf is sort of the neglected middle child of the horror monster hierarchy: gifted, unique, and brilliant, but eternally overshadowed by its dad the Devil, older vampiric siblings, mummified Egyptian stepsons from a previous marriage, and kid brother zombies who are always getting into trouble and keeping the family distracted. Of course there have been great, even legendary, films with lycanthrope antagonists, but that particular sub-genre is rather limited in scope. However, despite the admitted paucity of competition, I can still say with absolute certainty that The Howling is the best movie about werewolves ever made. It makes sense that the film heavily references The Wolf Man, the eternal Lon Chaney Jr./Universal Monsters staple, because The Howling is executed in a way that clearly reveals its acknowledgment of its roots in the traditions of classic horror. The pace is restrained and meticulous, the atmosphere is a character in itself, and despite the film's utilization of creature effects that weren't even dreamed of in Universal's genre heyday, good old-fashioned ensemble acting is what truly drives the action in the piece. If this description makes The Howling sound like a dry production more suited for the theater stage, don't misunderstand me; this is bloody and ferocious fare that will greatly please fans of visceral horror. But it is the taut and well-crafted story, not merely the FX, that make this such a gem, and director Joe Dante is seasoned enough here to allow a gradual and steady immersion into the film's world before bowling us over with Rob Bottin's peerless set-pieces, which have all the more impact when they take command because of how effectively the movie has teased us with tantalizing glimpses throughout. Though the creatures are understandably a feature attraction here, the main focus of the plot is on news anchor Karen White, who has become the fixation of deranged serial killer Eddie Quist and agrees to be used as bait as part of a police operation to capture him. Quist is seemingly killed during her harrowing and macabre encounter, and Karen is subsequently haunted by bizarre dreams and fuzzy, repressed recollections of what actually occurred that night. When she heeds a pop psychologist's suggestion that she and her husband should attend a therapy retreat he oversees at a secluded commune, the getaway does anything but assuage her trauma. Instead, Karen encounters odd and subtly menacing locals and the titular unholy moans emanating from the fog-shrouded forests. It doesn't take long for us to learn that the commune is located at the nucleus of the hunting grounds prowled by a pack of malevolent predatory beasts, and after Karen's husband is seduced and transformed by a sultry lady wolf, her and her visiting reporter friend begin to uncover the sinister secret of the commune. I'll refrain from stepping up on my soapbox to deliver an impassioned soliloquy about how CGI has ruined the art of special make-up FX, but those who appreciate the magic of the wizards who revolutionized the art-form in the late '70s and early '80s will find the work of Rob Bottin here absolutely awe-inspiring. The climactic transformation scene is delivered unflinchingly and in real time, step by grotesque step, and the result is an indelible sequence that remains far more impressive and enthralling than anything modern film-makers handling the same material could ever cook up on a computer. The gore is used sparingly for maximum impact, but whenever it arrives, the results are stunning and gruesome. Perhaps most importantly, the werewolves themselves are a thing of fearsome beauty to behold, monsters that resonate as wholly believable extensions of the established mythology while still maintaining an innovative stroke of originality that makes them belong to this film alone. These creatures aren't merely big wolves, they are eight-foot tall bipedal killing machines with fangs and claws capable of tearing people to shreds, a skill that they demonstrate with acute proficiency during the course of the movie. The performances are all excellent even when the roles veer into the melodramatic, and the presence of one of the power couples of '80s horror, Christopher Stone and Dee Wallace (later Dee Wallace Stone), as well as a marvelous extended cameo from beloved genre vet Dick Miller, will delight fans of the era. Both the gritty, sleazy streets that open the movie and the isolated location housing the commune complex are perfectly presented and utilized, the clues to the greater mystery are unfolded with the taut grace of a top-notch thriller, and the film as a whole feels like an entirely plausible representation of ancient folk lore-based creatures existing in a modern world. The denouement falters slightly since Bottin's best tricks have already been displayed, but the sentiment of the finale is striking enough to end the saga on a dark and tragic note. If your love of the genre goes back to its natal days, be sure to stick around after the credits too, where you'll find a nice coda that bookends the homage to The Wolf Man present throughout these reels. The Howling is, in my estimation, not only the finest and most enduring lycanthropy fable in the canon, it's also quite simply one of the best horror films of all time. Don't skip this one.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Scary But Fun.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Joe Dante pulled off an impressive feat directing this scary but humorous film about a traumatized newswoman (sweet & appealing Dee Wallace) who is persuaded to go to a mysterious retreat by a noted psychologist(Patrick Macnee, very suave but sympathetic) where her bad luck sadly continues when she is forced to confront some sinister werewolves... Very clever script incorporates real-life werewolf directors as character names, and has awe-inspiring make-up F/X, the first of their kind. Well-directed and suspenseful, though final sequence goes a little too far in self-aware humor. Otherwise, cant-miss film for genre fans.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It goes on a bit
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Despite numerous in-jokes, characters named after horror directors, a cameo by Roger Corman and appearances from Joe Dante favourites Kevin McCarthy, Dick Miller and Robert Picardo, this werewolf movie is almost entirely lacking in enjoyment. It's a dreary and boring movie composed of leaden silences punctuated by droning dialogue recited by flat characters at a droning pace. Dee Wallace is a TV newswoman who heads to a retreat run by doctor Patrick Macnee but finds that her holiday isn't as peaceful as she expected when the place is overrun by werewolves. Although Dante has some fun contrasting what the characters are watching on TV with the events of the movie, the disappointingly droopy plot gets less interesting the more it goes on and by the end, when everyone's bearing their fangs and sprouting rubbery wolf faces, it all looks pretty stupid.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I do hope the book is better
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    siderite
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've begun watching The Howling with high expectations, as someone described it as "one of the 2 best Werewolf movies ever made". Unfortunately, he just might be right, but that is not saying much. Probably the spike in quality is caused by the movie being a book adaptation and I do hope the book was a lot better. Now, don't imagine the movie is very bad. For an 1981 movie with werewolves, indeed it is good, but it has that feel of a money grabbing movie studio doing an adaptation after a money grabbing publisher selling books of a certain type. You've all read those books: somewhere in a small American town, where everybody knows each other and there is dark secret, a city dweller comes to shake up the status quo. Probably Americans read a lot of these books, but I've had it up to my furry neck and my pointy teeth with this kind of bull. It is boring, pretentious and most of the time rehashing similar stories that were probably good when they were written but have now dissolved into lameness. Bottom line: I am sure I have seen this movie before, when I was young, but except the scene at the end, which had its share of drama and societal satire, I did not remember one thing while watching it again now. It is a mostly forgettable movie, with unsympathetic characters and a rushed story so that it can cover the entire book. Yes, indeed, take the story, make it a miniseries in the style of Stephen King adaptations and add some decent acting and special effects, and it would do great today, but this film just feels... wrong.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Disappointed
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SanteeFats
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I realize this movie was made over thirty years ago and it is not a blood and guts for shock value type movie (which I like) buuuuuttt!!! This is one very slow developing story. First if you can become a werewolf by bite or scratch the world would be overrun with them. This one does have them as shape shifters and therefore not tied to the Hollywood stereotypical full moon only ability to change. I will admit that when they started the transformations it was done very well for the time period, no CGI there. Then you have reporter who shows up with (gasp) the magic silver bullets! There is goof here as he first jacks a bullet in to the chamber when he gets out of his car and then again when he is in the office. I do like when he shoots one of the werewolves that has the girl, they rest just stop and stare for a second. See what happens when you are supremely overconfident in your ability to be harmed? I do like the end where she changes on TV and then is shot and killed in full view of the audience. Of course few will believe!!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "The Howling" is a 1980s slow-burning horror classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ersinkdotcom
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After news anchor Karen White (Dee Wallace) is attacked by a mysterious stranger (Robert Picardo), she starts having bizarre dreams and night terrors about the incident. Karen's doctor (Patrick Macnee) convinces her that she and husband Bill (Christopher Stone) should go through his treatment at "The Colony." Strange things start to happen as soon as they arrive. Could Karen be cracking up or is there something sinister going on in the secluded resort? Like most movies from the 1970s and the 1980s, "The Howling" is a slow- burner. This isn't one of those horror films that starts with a bang, keeps a frantic pace, and goes out with a bang. It slowly establishes its plot and characters and gives the audience a little at a time until the climactic and shocking end. Things might move too slowly for today's impatient audience. I even found it tedious at times. The scenes get choppy throughout and it seems like director Joe Dante was rushing things at some points. Rob Bottin's special effects for "The Howling" are still just as effective today as they were in 1981. The werewolf transformation scenes are unnerving and quite detailed. One transformation takes what seems like three to four minutes. It's all about attention to detail when it comes to Bottin's practical effects and animatronics versus today's obsession with rapid fire CGI scenes of metamorphosis. "The Howling" does feature quite a bit of the usual unnecessary nudity found in 1980's horror films. However, this time around director Dante attempts to justify it by analyzing our need to let the beast within out, mostly through sexual and physical acts of violence. The doctor, played by the late Patrick Macnee, convincingly regurgitates a lot of "primal scream" mumbo jumbo throughout the movie. Although it's a bit slow and takes some time getting started, great special effects and interesting, albeit hokey, social commentary set "The Howling" apart from the normal monster movie fare.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Joe Dante and Wolves...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Janis Livens
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Howling is one of the best werewolf movies up their with American Werewolf in London. It has everything you would want from a good monster movie: good scares, good laughs and some great effects. Dee Wallace stars in this werewolf film as a reporter who goes to a strange commune after experiencing a bizarre accident with a serial killer. And from that point it's a roller coaster ride of silly characters, wonderful practical effects and awkward werewolf sex. The Howling is a low budget film made for just one million dollars and looks stunning. The cinematography is absolutely gorgeous and makes a great use of both colour and shadows. Joe Dante's direction lends well to the material and shows what he can do with a simple monster movie premise and turns it into something memorable, funny and even heartbreaking. The performances are pretty good. Dee Wallace is great as the tragic heroine and the supporting cast include such goof ball character actors like John Carradine, Slim Pickens and Robert Pickardo. Not to mention the crazy sexy Elisabeth Brooks who does some kinky werewolf sex and so on. The Howling unlike the modern horror movies that feature werewolves and other supernatural creatures, feature great practical effects that are only rivaled by American Werewolf. However, I wouldn't call this film scary. It's hard to scare me or creep me out with something supernatural and especially if you have Slim Pickens in your movie. But horror movie doesn't need to be that scary to be good unlike comedies that need to be funny to any good. Werewolf movies doesn't get much better than Howling and American Werewolf in London. If you enjoy good monster movies that are made with love and care, you owe it to yourself to watch this film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Undoubtedly the inspiration for Michael Jackson's 'Thriller'
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sherazade
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The special effects were as good as can be expected of a movie made in 1980/81 but other than that is was poorly written, poorly directed, poorly acted (especially by the female actors/characters), poorly edited and there were way too many inconsistencies and plot holes. Werewolves movies were to the 80s what Vampire movies are to us now, some were good and most were bad. I would recommend this movie only to people who are fans of some actor in the film and want to see every film they've ever acted in or for those who want to view it for nostalgic reasons or if you're like me and the movie was before your time and you just want to see what films of this genre looked like that back then.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a werewolf classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    trashgang
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Howling has become the father of the new werewolf flicks in the heydays of the eighties. But there was another masterpiece that sadly came out just after The Howling was released, An American Werewolf In London (1982). Why I'm saying this, because Rick Baker, make-up and special effects was involved in both of them. American Werewolf started earlier then The Howling but had financial problems so Rick started with The Howling but when the director of American Werewolf(John Landis) heard that news money was raised and Barker left The Howling to give it towards Rick Bottin. Rick made it a movie with excellent effects and became notorious surely after The Thing (1982). The Howling wanted to do the werewolf transformation in one shot but money prevented it to become that way. American Werewolf did it. But The Howling was the best known werewolf flick. Although being a classic I prefer American because things starts of immediately. The Howling takes almost 50 minutes before a werewolf comes in and the effects become clear. But I must say that the last 40 minutes are worth watching. What a delight to see. The acting was rather good and the way it was filmed (advised by Bottin to use shadow and not that much of lighting) gave it a creepy feeling. A lot of memorable names are here to see but one that was becoming the next big thing was the werewolf Marsha (Elisabeth Brooks). She was noticed because she went full frontal here but her career was suddenly stopped by cancer, she died age 46. Mixed feelings because it isn't a good movie the first 50 minutes but it's a classic for so many reasons. Still, I gave it an 8 for the effects alone. Still, not that gory for a werewolf flick made in the heydays of slashers. Gore 1,5/5 Nudity 1/5 Effects 5/5 Story 3/5 Comedy 0/5
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Great Werewolf Film!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gwnightscream
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dee Wallace, Patrick Macnee, Christopher Stone, Robert Picardo, Dennis Dugan, Belinda Balaski and Elizabeth Brooks star in Joe Dante's 1981 horror film. This begins with newswoman, Karen White (Wallace) preparing to meet man, Eddie Quist (Picardo) whom reveals his secret being a werewolf and is attacked by him. After Eddie is shot by police but not dead, Karen starts to feel different and tries to remember what happened. Macnee plays doctor, George Waggner who helps her and invites her to his spa in the country, the colony. She goes with her husband, Bill Neil (Stone) and they meet an odd group of people staying there and discover there are werewolves. Dugan plays Karen's friend, Chris, Balaski plays his girlfriend, Teri, the late, Brooks plays Marsha, a woman who seduces Bill and Stone was also Wallace's real-life husband. Dick Miller, Roger Corman and Kevin McCarthy also appear and Rob Bottin's make-up effects are terrific as usual. I recommend this great werewolf film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A smart, sexy, and genuinely scary horror classic that still has plenty of bite
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    happyendingrocks
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The werewolf is sort of the neglected middle child of the horror monster hierarchy: gifted, unique, and brilliant, but eternally overshadowed by its dad the Devil, older vampiric siblings, mummified Egyptian stepsons from a previous marriage, and kid brother zombies who are always getting into trouble and keeping the family distracted. Of course there have been great, even legendary, films with lycanthrope antagonists, but that particular sub-genre is rather limited in scope. However, despite the admitted paucity of competition, I can still say with absolute certainty that The Howling is the best movie about werewolves ever made. It makes sense that the film heavily references The Wolf Man, the eternal Lon Chaney Jr./Universal Monsters staple, because The Howling is executed in a way that clearly reveals its acknowledgment of its roots in the traditions of classic horror. The pace is restrained and meticulous, the atmosphere is a character in itself, and despite the film's utilization of creature effects that weren't even dreamed of in Universal's genre heyday, good old-fashioned ensemble acting is what truly drives the action in the piece. If this description makes The Howling sound like a dry production more suited for the theater stage, don't misunderstand me; this is bloody and ferocious fare that will greatly please fans of visceral horror. But it is the taut and well-crafted story, not merely the FX, that make this such a gem, and director Joe Dante is seasoned enough here to allow a gradual and steady immersion into the film's world before bowling us over with Rob Bottin's peerless set-pieces, which have all the more impact when they take command because of how effectively the movie has teased us with tantalizing glimpses throughout. Though the creatures are understandably a feature attraction here, the main focus of the plot is on news anchor Karen White, who has become the fixation of deranged serial killer Eddie Quist and agrees to be used as bait as part of a police operation to capture him. Quist is seemingly killed during her harrowing and macabre encounter, and Karen is subsequently haunted by bizarre dreams and fuzzy, repressed recollections of what actually occurred that night. When she heeds a pop psychologist's suggestion that she and her husband should attend a therapy retreat he oversees at a secluded commune, the getaway does anything but assuage her trauma. Instead, Karen encounters odd and subtly menacing locals and the titular unholy moans emanating from the fog-shrouded forests. It doesn't take long for us to learn that the commune is located at the nucleus of the hunting grounds prowled by a pack of malevolent predatory beasts, and after Karen's husband is seduced and transformed by a sultry lady wolf, her and her visiting reporter friend begin to uncover the sinister secret of the commune. I'll refrain from stepping up on my soapbox to deliver an impassioned soliloquy about how CGI has ruined the art of special make-up FX, but those who appreciate the magic of the wizards who revolutionized the art-form in the late '70s and early '80s will find the work of Rob Bottin here absolutely awe-inspiring. The climactic transformation scene is delivered unflinchingly and in real time, step by grotesque step, and the result is an indelible sequence that remains far more impressive and enthralling than anything modern film-makers handling the same material could ever cook up on a computer. The gore is used sparingly for maximum impact, but whenever it arrives, the results are stunning and gruesome. Perhaps most importantly, the werewolves themselves are a thing of fearsome beauty to behold, monsters that resonate as wholly believable extensions of the established mythology while still maintaining an innovative stroke of originality that makes them belong to this film alone. These creatures aren't merely big wolves, they are eight-foot tall bipedal killing machines with fangs and claws capable of tearing people to shreds, a skill that they demonstrate with acute proficiency during the course of the movie. The performances are all excellent even when the roles veer into the melodramatic, and the presence of one of the power couples of '80s horror, Christopher Stone and Dee Wallace (later Dee Wallace Stone), as well as a marvelous extended cameo from beloved genre vet Dick Miller, will delight fans of the era. Both the gritty, sleazy streets that open the movie and the isolated location housing the commune complex are perfectly presented and utilized, the clues to the greater mystery are unfolded with the taut grace of a top-notch thriller, and the film as a whole feels like an entirely plausible representation of ancient folk lore-based creatures existing in a modern world. The denouement falters slightly since Bottin's best tricks have already been displayed, but the sentiment of the finale is striking enough to end the saga on a dark and tragic note. If your love of the genre goes back to its natal days, be sure to stick around after the credits too, where you'll find a nice coda that bookends the homage to The Wolf Man present throughout these reels. The Howling is, in my estimation, not only the finest and most enduring lycanthropy fable in the canon, it's also quite simply one of the best horror films of all time. Don't skip this one.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Scary But Fun.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Joe Dante pulled off an impressive feat directing this scary but humorous film about a traumatized newswoman (sweet & appealing Dee Wallace) who is persuaded to go to a mysterious retreat by a noted psychologist(Patrick Macnee, very suave but sympathetic) where her bad luck sadly continues when she is forced to confront some sinister werewolves... Very clever script incorporates real-life werewolf directors as character names, and has awe-inspiring make-up F/X, the first of their kind. Well-directed and suspenseful, though final sequence goes a little too far in self-aware humor. Otherwise, cant-miss film for genre fans.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It goes on a bit
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Despite numerous in-jokes, characters named after horror directors, a cameo by Roger Corman and appearances from Joe Dante favourites Kevin McCarthy, Dick Miller and Robert Picardo, this werewolf movie is almost entirely lacking in enjoyment. It's a dreary and boring movie composed of leaden silences punctuated by droning dialogue recited by flat characters at a droning pace. Dee Wallace is a TV newswoman who heads to a retreat run by doctor Patrick Macnee but finds that her holiday isn't as peaceful as she expected when the place is overrun by werewolves. Although Dante has some fun contrasting what the characters are watching on TV with the events of the movie, the disappointingly droopy plot gets less interesting the more it goes on and by the end, when everyone's bearing their fangs and sprouting rubbery wolf faces, it all looks pretty stupid.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I do hope the book is better
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    siderite
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've begun watching The Howling with high expectations, as someone described it as "one of the 2 best Werewolf movies ever made". Unfortunately, he just might be right, but that is not saying much. Probably the spike in quality is caused by the movie being a book adaptation and I do hope the book was a lot better. Now, don't imagine the movie is very bad. For an 1981 movie with werewolves, indeed it is good, but it has that feel of a money grabbing movie studio doing an adaptation after a money grabbing publisher selling books of a certain type. You've all read those books: somewhere in a small American town, where everybody knows each other and there is dark secret, a city dweller comes to shake up the status quo. Probably Americans read a lot of these books, but I've had it up to my furry neck and my pointy teeth with this kind of bull. It is boring, pretentious and most of the time rehashing similar stories that were probably good when they were written but have now dissolved into lameness. Bottom line: I am sure I have seen this movie before, when I was young, but except the scene at the end, which had its share of drama and societal satire, I did not remember one thing while watching it again now. It is a mostly forgettable movie, with unsympathetic characters and a rushed story so that it can cover the entire book. Yes, indeed, take the story, make it a miniseries in the style of Stephen King adaptations and add some decent acting and special effects, and it would do great today, but this film just feels... wrong.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Disappointed
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SanteeFats
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I realize this movie was made over thirty years ago and it is not a blood and guts for shock value type movie (which I like) buuuuuttt!!! This is one very slow developing story. First if you can become a werewolf by bite or scratch the world would be overrun with them. This one does have them as shape shifters and therefore not tied to the Hollywood stereotypical full moon only ability to change. I will admit that when they started the transformations it was done very well for the time period, no CGI there. Then you have reporter who shows up with (gasp) the magic silver bullets! There is goof here as he first jacks a bullet in to the chamber when he gets out of his car and then again when he is in the office. I do like when he shoots one of the werewolves that has the girl, they rest just stop and stare for a second. See what happens when you are supremely overconfident in your ability to be harmed? I do like the end where she changes on TV and then is shot and killed in full view of the audience. Of course few will believe!!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "The Howling" is a 1980s slow-burning horror classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ersinkdotcom
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After news anchor Karen White (Dee Wallace) is attacked by a mysterious stranger (Robert Picardo), she starts having bizarre dreams and night terrors about the incident. Karen's doctor (Patrick Macnee) convinces her that she and husband Bill (Christopher Stone) should go through his treatment at "The Colony." Strange things start to happen as soon as they arrive. Could Karen be cracking up or is there something sinister going on in the secluded resort? Like most movies from the 1970s and the 1980s, "The Howling" is a slow- burner. This isn't one of those horror films that starts with a bang, keeps a frantic pace, and goes out with a bang. It slowly establishes its plot and characters and gives the audience a little at a time until the climactic and shocking end. Things might move too slowly for today's impatient audience. I even found it tedious at times. The scenes get choppy throughout and it seems like director Joe Dante was rushing things at some points. Rob Bottin's special effects for "The Howling" are still just as effective today as they were in 1981. The werewolf transformation scenes are unnerving and quite detailed. One transformation takes what seems like three to four minutes. It's all about attention to detail when it comes to Bottin's practical effects and animatronics versus today's obsession with rapid fire CGI scenes of metamorphosis. "The Howling" does feature quite a bit of the usual unnecessary nudity found in 1980's horror films. However, this time around director Dante attempts to justify it by analyzing our need to let the beast within out, mostly through sexual and physical acts of violence. The doctor, played by the late Patrick Macnee, convincingly regurgitates a lot of "primal scream" mumbo jumbo throughout the movie. Although it's a bit slow and takes some time getting started, great special effects and interesting, albeit hokey, social commentary set "The Howling" apart from the normal monster movie fare.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Joe Dante and Wolves...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Janis Livens
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Howling is one of the best werewolf movies up their with American Werewolf in London. It has everything you would want from a good monster movie: good scares, good laughs and some great effects. Dee Wallace stars in this werewolf film as a reporter who goes to a strange commune after experiencing a bizarre accident with a serial killer. And from that point it's a roller coaster ride of silly characters, wonderful practical effects and awkward werewolf sex. The Howling is a low budget film made for just one million dollars and looks stunning. The cinematography is absolutely gorgeous and makes a great use of both colour and shadows. Joe Dante's direction lends well to the material and shows what he can do with a simple monster movie premise and turns it into something memorable, funny and even heartbreaking. The performances are pretty good. Dee Wallace is great as the tragic heroine and the supporting cast include such goof ball character actors like John Carradine, Slim Pickens and Robert Pickardo. Not to mention the crazy sexy Elisabeth Brooks who does some kinky werewolf sex and so on. The Howling unlike the modern horror movies that feature werewolves and other supernatural creatures, feature great practical effects that are only rivaled by American Werewolf. However, I wouldn't call this film scary. It's hard to scare me or creep me out with something supernatural and especially if you have Slim Pickens in your movie. But horror movie doesn't need to be that scary to be good unlike comedies that need to be funny to any good. Werewolf movies doesn't get much better than Howling and American Werewolf in London. If you enjoy good monster movies that are made with love and care, you owe it to yourself to watch this film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Undoubtedly the inspiration for Michael Jackson's 'Thriller'
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sherazade
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The special effects were as good as can be expected of a movie made in 1980/81 but other than that is was poorly written, poorly directed, poorly acted (especially by the female actors/characters), poorly edited and there were way too many inconsistencies and plot holes. Werewolves movies were to the 80s what Vampire movies are to us now, some were good and most were bad. I would recommend this movie only to people who are fans of some actor in the film and want to see every film they've ever acted in or for those who want to view it for nostalgic reasons or if you're like me and the movie was before your time and you just want to see what films of this genre looked like that back then.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a werewolf classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    trashgang
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Howling has become the father of the new werewolf flicks in the heydays of the eighties. But there was another masterpiece that sadly came out just after The Howling was released, An American Werewolf In London (1982). Why I'm saying this, because Rick Baker, make-up and special effects was involved in both of them. American Werewolf started earlier then The Howling but had financial problems so Rick started with The Howling but when the director of American Werewolf(John Landis) heard that news money was raised and Barker left The Howling to give it towards Rick Bottin. Rick made it a movie with excellent effects and became notorious surely after The Thing (1982). The Howling wanted to do the werewolf transformation in one shot but money prevented it to become that way. American Werewolf did it. But The Howling was the best known werewolf flick. Although being a classic I prefer American because things starts of immediately. The Howling takes almost 50 minutes before a werewolf comes in and the effects become clear. But I must say that the last 40 minutes are worth watching. What a delight to see. The acting was rather good and the way it was filmed (advised by Bottin to use shadow and not that much of lighting) gave it a creepy feeling. A lot of memorable names are here to see but one that was becoming the next big thing was the werewolf Marsha (Elisabeth Brooks). She was noticed because she went full frontal here but her career was suddenly stopped by cancer, she died age 46. Mixed feelings because it isn't a good movie the first 50 minutes but it's a classic for so many reasons. Still, I gave it an 8 for the effects alone. Still, not that gory for a werewolf flick made in the heydays of slashers. Gore 1,5/5 Nudity 1/5 Effects 5/5 Story 3/5 Comedy 0/5
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Great Werewolf Film!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gwnightscream
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dee Wallace, Patrick Macnee, Christopher Stone, Robert Picardo, Dennis Dugan, Belinda Balaski and Elizabeth Brooks star in Joe Dante's 1981 horror film. This begins with newswoman, Karen White (Wallace) preparing to meet man, Eddie Quist (Picardo) whom reveals his secret being a werewolf and is attacked by him. After Eddie is shot by police but not dead, Karen starts to feel different and tries to remember what happened. Macnee plays doctor, George Waggner who helps her and invites her to his spa in the country, the colony. She goes with her husband, Bill Neil (Stone) and they meet an odd group of people staying there and discover there are werewolves. Dugan plays Karen's friend, Chris, Balaski plays his girlfriend, Teri, the late, Brooks plays Marsha, a woman who seduces Bill and Stone was also Wallace's real-life husband. Dick Miller, Roger Corman and Kevin McCarthy also appear and Rob Bottin's make-up effects are terrific as usual. I recommend this great werewolf film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A smart, sexy, and genuinely scary horror classic that still has plenty of bite
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    happyendingrocks
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The werewolf is sort of the neglected middle child of the horror monster hierarchy: gifted, unique, and brilliant, but eternally overshadowed by its dad the Devil, older vampiric siblings, mummified Egyptian stepsons from a previous marriage, and kid brother zombies who are always getting into trouble and keeping the family distracted. Of course there have been great, even legendary, films with lycanthrope antagonists, but that particular sub-genre is rather limited in scope. However, despite the admitted paucity of competition, I can still say with absolute certainty that The Howling is the best movie about werewolves ever made. It makes sense that the film heavily references The Wolf Man, the eternal Lon Chaney Jr./Universal Monsters staple, because The Howling is executed in a way that clearly reveals its acknowledgment of its roots in the traditions of classic horror. The pace is restrained and meticulous, the atmosphere is a character in itself, and despite the film's utilization of creature effects that weren't even dreamed of in Universal's genre heyday, good old-fashioned ensemble acting is what truly drives the action in the piece. If this description makes The Howling sound like a dry production more suited for the theater stage, don't misunderstand me; this is bloody and ferocious fare that will greatly please fans of visceral horror. But it is the taut and well-crafted story, not merely the FX, that make this such a gem, and director Joe Dante is seasoned enough here to allow a gradual and steady immersion into the film's world before bowling us over with Rob Bottin's peerless set-pieces, which have all the more impact when they take command because of how effectively the movie has teased us with tantalizing glimpses throughout. Though the creatures are understandably a feature attraction here, the main focus of the plot is on news anchor Karen White, who has become the fixation of deranged serial killer Eddie Quist and agrees to be used as bait as part of a police operation to capture him. Quist is seemingly killed during her harrowing and macabre encounter, and Karen is subsequently haunted by bizarre dreams and fuzzy, repressed recollections of what actually occurred that night. When she heeds a pop psychologist's suggestion that she and her husband should attend a therapy retreat he oversees at a secluded commune, the getaway does anything but assuage her trauma. Instead, Karen encounters odd and subtly menacing locals and the titular unholy moans emanating from the fog-shrouded forests. It doesn't take long for us to learn that the commune is located at the nucleus of the hunting grounds prowled by a pack of malevolent predatory beasts, and after Karen's husband is seduced and transformed by a sultry lady wolf, her and her visiting reporter friend begin to uncover the sinister secret of the commune. I'll refrain from stepping up on my soapbox to deliver an impassioned soliloquy about how CGI has ruined the art of special make-up FX, but those who appreciate the magic of the wizards who revolutionized the art-form in the late '70s and early '80s will find the work of Rob Bottin here absolutely awe-inspiring. The climactic transformation scene is delivered unflinchingly and in real time, step by grotesque step, and the result is an indelible sequence that remains far more impressive and enthralling than anything modern film-makers handling the same material could ever cook up on a computer. The gore is used sparingly for maximum impact, but whenever it arrives, the results are stunning and gruesome. Perhaps most importantly, the werewolves themselves are a thing of fearsome beauty to behold, monsters that resonate as wholly believable extensions of the established mythology while still maintaining an innovative stroke of originality that makes them belong to this film alone. These creatures aren't merely big wolves, they are eight-foot tall bipedal killing machines with fangs and claws capable of tearing people to shreds, a skill that they demonstrate with acute proficiency during the course of the movie. The performances are all excellent even when the roles veer into the melodramatic, and the presence of one of the power couples of '80s horror, Christopher Stone and Dee Wallace (later Dee Wallace Stone), as well as a marvelous extended cameo from beloved genre vet Dick Miller, will delight fans of the era. Both the gritty, sleazy streets that open the movie and the isolated location housing the commune complex are perfectly presented and utilized, the clues to the greater mystery are unfolded with the taut grace of a top-notch thriller, and the film as a whole feels like an entirely plausible representation of ancient folk lore-based creatures existing in a modern world. The denouement falters slightly since Bottin's best tricks have already been displayed, but the sentiment of the finale is striking enough to end the saga on a dark and tragic note. If your love of the genre goes back to its natal days, be sure to stick around after the credits too, where you'll find a nice coda that bookends the homage to The Wolf Man present throughout these reels. The Howling is, in my estimation, not only the finest and most enduring lycanthropy fable in the canon, it's also quite simply one of the best horror films of all time. Don't skip this one.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
