<filme>
 <id>
  64
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0111161
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1994
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Um Sonho de Liberdade
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  9.3
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Two imprisoned men bond over a number of years, finding solace and eventual redemption through acts of common decency.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Andy Dufresne is a young and successful banker whose life changes drastically when he is convicted and sentenced to life imprisonment for the murder of his wife and her lover. Set in the 1940's, the film shows how Andy, with the help of his friend Red, the prison entrepreneur, turns out to be a most unconventional prisoner.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Crime
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   prison
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   murder
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   friend
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   life imprisonment
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   banker
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Frank Darabont
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Stephen King
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Frank Darabont
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Tim Robbins
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Morgan Freeman
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Bob Gunton
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Shawshank Redemption
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Anand Nandkumar
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you are a movie buff and have not watched The Shawshank Redemption then trust me you are not a certified movie buff.!! This is the best movie made in the history of mankind. I have seen many movies but no movie has moved me or attracted me the way this one has. There is a special charm in the whole narration that keeps going on with the movie which controls me every time. Every line, every shot is just remarkable !Can watch it any number of times and still keep loving it more. So you better waste no time if you haven't watch it yet and then i am sure you would post a review too !! No wonder this movie has won so many accolades to it and will will surely always be in the top char of IMDb for ever and ever and ever.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The determination of the human spirit
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bernardo Rapazote Flores
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The best movies are ones that touch the soul. It takes a movie like The Shawshank Redemption to touch the soul. Shawshank Redemption was my favorite movie when I first saw it, and I only realized its weakness later, this movie will look a lot worst the second time you watch it with its mysteries revealed and questions fully answered because one of the great qualities of this movie is its impossibility to guess which direction the story will take until it reaches the end. However, the movie celebrates the determination of the human spirit "There's something inside you that they can't get to, that they can't touch. It's yours.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A lot of feelings
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    carlosalan-pc
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What to say about this movie, a true masterpiece and a well deserved 1st place here in IMDb. So many feelings felt while watching it. I could definitely watch it again and again and would have the same reactions. As someone said in another review: Excellent acting, soundtrack, photography, etc. Tim Robbins was the perfect guy for the role and all the other actors did great too. Do buy this movie because you not only will be able to enjoy it but you will learn a lot from your own reflections on various aspects of life and will be glad that you are free. The movie itself has a strong message with much impact. Don't miss it by any chance, there's a limited number of movies that will make you feel this emotional about being free and alive.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    motivation
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    barcellosmilton
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Nothing is Impossible. This movie is the perfect way to understand that you don't need to be inside or outside a prison to get freedom. I believe the people need to believe in your dreams more than people say it's no possible, and the situation on this perfect movie by Morgan and Tim explain how to make dreams possible. Just think, work, patience, and believe. This is the way. I watch this movie every time I want to be more motivated. I saw this movie last night and I tell my friends and my family that we can't play with life, and we need to do everything correct to make a good way and get health days. After that I saw I lot of movies from Morgan and Tim, and a lot of this movie we can see on there movies.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Amazing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Elizabeth Olsen
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of the best films that I have watched, so completely enticing! It had me in tears at the end, such an emotional film.. So glad that it was made, the screen-writers/directors/producers should all be so proud of themselves, the film is so amazing and if only I was a few years older.. I'd have loved to have been a part of it. So interesting and catchy, once I'd started to watch I couldn't stop!! Although parts of it did drag slightly, they recovered extremely well. I thoroughly enjoyed watching this film. Morgan Freeman is such an amazing actor, I couldn't imagine anyone else to play the role of Red it was done so well. Tim Robbin's was also well cast. Well done.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Epic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Azzman112
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Shawshank Redemption is a defining moment in cinema. The movie (directed by Frank Darabont) takes a straight-forward, soul- searching novel by horror icon Stephen King and transforms it into a somber, bloated prison drama designed to fill you up with inspiration. Thanks to supreme performances and beautiful cinematography, you get that inspirational jump-start frame after frame. And you get generous helpings of the novella's deft ironic humour about a inmate quietly turning a corrupt system against itself. A small box office release which made its name once released on home video, this movie is well worth a watch if you happened to have missed it first time around.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    the best movie i have ever seen of all time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    john_fawzy2008
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    the most beautiful part of the film lies within its thematic material, such as its focus on the human desires for the most abstract concepts, like hope and freedom. These themes, which concern things the human spirit undoubtedly yearns for, seem so intricately woven into the plot that it easily draws its audience in to its story. Though full of hardened criminals, your heart will go out to these men as they display the most basic of human emotions, and deliver some of the most quotable lines in a film to date. Like a great novel, this film manages to succeed at greater things than simply entertaining an audience. Darabont tells his story most masterfully, illustrating principles and inspiring his audience to think. He leaves us a poignant film with a powerful message of hope, and redemption, something we all seek. This film manages to redeem Hollywood in the eyes of people who feared it long lost in a dark sea of clich&eacute;s and predictability. Darabont shows us that artists still work in the Hollywood studios and production facilities. These artists show their capability to produce art; real art that inspires you to look at the deeper aspects of life and the world around you. The Shawshank Redemption delivers much-needed breath of fresh air for anyone who realizes the capability of film. It proves that masters of the craft still live on this earth, and still bless us with timeless masterpieces that we will never forget.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nice
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gvelesianitazo
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Whenever I talk about this movie with my friends, I do not even refer to it by title, but rather as "The Movie". When I say "The Movie", my friends know exactly what I'm talking about. In fact the main reason that me and my friends don't refer to it by title is because this movie is so great, that we do not feel worthy enough to say it's name in vain! I still remember the first time I saw The Shawshank Redemption. Some friends of mine and I went to see it at one of those "Budget Theaters" over the summer of 1995. None of us really knew anything about the movie, but we had heard that it was pretty good. So, not having any real expectations, we saw it. When the final credits rolled and the lights came on in the theater, all of us just sat there with our jaws hanging down on the floor. I turned my head towards my friend Bob and said "That was the greatest movie I have ever seen in my entire life!" There's really no other way I can put it in words. Every moment of this movie captivated me and inspired me to believe in the one true thing in life...... "HOPE". This movie is sad, uplifting, inspiring, harsh, cold, funny (at the right times), jaw-dropping, and heart-warming all at the same time. I get chills every time I watch this film and this film contains the greatest ending (which takes place over the last 30 minutes or so)in movie history! How it all just "comes together" is so incredible and uplifting. I should also mention the music in this movie is nearly flawless as well, and the soundtrack is a "must buy" for any music fan. The only bad thing about this movie is the fact that I know I will never see a better movie, no matter how many I may see. I've seen many movies over the past few years, many excellent films. However, every time I walk out of the theater, I turn to my friend or family member that I saw it with and I say, "That was a great movie, but it wasn't nearly as good as 'you know what'!" There have been many movies over the past few years that thought would really move me or that I might one day call my "favorite of all time", but they've all fallen far short of "The Shawshank Redemption". So, if you have yet to see this movie, please run to the video store immediately. You're guaranteed to find it in the "employee picks" section. And if it isn't in that section, then you should tell the employees there that there is something seriously wrong with them. If you have seen this movie, go see it again. If you haven't bought your own copy yet, buy one. In fact buy two, and put one in a fire-proof safe, just in case of an emergency. :o) So, you want a 1-10 rating??? I give it a 13!!!!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Niceed Movieee!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ramacosgun
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Why do I want to write the 234th comment on The Shawshank Redemption? I am not sure - almost everything that could be possibly said about it has been said. But like so many other people who wrote comments, I was and am profoundly moved by this simple and eloquent depiction of hope and friendship and redemption. The only other movie I have ever seen that effects me as strongly is To Kill a Mockingbird. Both movies leave me feeling cleaner for having watched them. I didn't intend to see this movie at all: I do not like prison movies and I don't normally watch them. I work at a branch library and one day as I was checking The Shawshank Redemption out to one of our older patrons, she said to me, "Whenever I feel down or depressed, I check out this movie and watch it and it always makes me feel better." At the time, I thought that was very strange. One day there was nothing on TV except things I absolutely would not watch under any circumstance or things that I had seen too many times already. I remembered what she said, so I watched it. I have watched it many many times since then and it gets better with every showing. No action, no special effects - just men in prison uniforms talking to each other. The Shawshank Redemption and To Kill a Mockingbird are the best movies I have ever seen. I do not judge it by it's technical merits - I don't really care about that. I have read that Citizen Kane or The Godfather or this or that movie is the best movie ever made. They may have the best technique or be the most influential motion pictures ever made, but not the best. The best movies are ones that touch the soul. It takes a movie like The Shawshank Redemption to touch the soul.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Speechless
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Huzefa Akhter
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let me keep it straight and simple.. I am simply too impressed and therefore out of words to describe what this movie portrays. The acting and realism of this fiction is eye catching. I really wonder how much better it would get if it was based on a true story. Indeed, you can rate, review, describe, audit, revise or summarize a movie, but not art. Whether you are a movie fan or not, simply don't miss this one if you are a human ! BTW, Mr. Brooks was my favorite character.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Shawshank Redemption
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Anand Nandkumar
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you are a movie buff and have not watched The Shawshank Redemption then trust me you are not a certified movie buff.!! This is the best movie made in the history of mankind. I have seen many movies but no movie has moved me or attracted me the way this one has. There is a special charm in the whole narration that keeps going on with the movie which controls me every time. Every line, every shot is just remarkable !Can watch it any number of times and still keep loving it more. So you better waste no time if you haven't watch it yet and then i am sure you would post a review too !! No wonder this movie has won so many accolades to it and will will surely always be in the top char of IMDb for ever and ever and ever.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The determination of the human spirit
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bernardo Rapazote Flores
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The best movies are ones that touch the soul. It takes a movie like The Shawshank Redemption to touch the soul. Shawshank Redemption was my favorite movie when I first saw it, and I only realized its weakness later, this movie will look a lot worst the second time you watch it with its mysteries revealed and questions fully answered because one of the great qualities of this movie is its impossibility to guess which direction the story will take until it reaches the end. However, the movie celebrates the determination of the human spirit "There's something inside you that they can't get to, that they can't touch. It's yours.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A lot of feelings
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    carlosalan-pc
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What to say about this movie, a true masterpiece and a well deserved 1st place here in IMDb. So many feelings felt while watching it. I could definitely watch it again and again and would have the same reactions. As someone said in another review: Excellent acting, soundtrack, photography, etc. Tim Robbins was the perfect guy for the role and all the other actors did great too. Do buy this movie because you not only will be able to enjoy it but you will learn a lot from your own reflections on various aspects of life and will be glad that you are free. The movie itself has a strong message with much impact. Don't miss it by any chance, there's a limited number of movies that will make you feel this emotional about being free and alive.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    motivation
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    barcellosmilton
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Nothing is Impossible. This movie is the perfect way to understand that you don't need to be inside or outside a prison to get freedom. I believe the people need to believe in your dreams more than people say it's no possible, and the situation on this perfect movie by Morgan and Tim explain how to make dreams possible. Just think, work, patience, and believe. This is the way. I watch this movie every time I want to be more motivated. I saw this movie last night and I tell my friends and my family that we can't play with life, and we need to do everything correct to make a good way and get health days. After that I saw I lot of movies from Morgan and Tim, and a lot of this movie we can see on there movies.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Amazing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Elizabeth Olsen
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of the best films that I have watched, so completely enticing! It had me in tears at the end, such an emotional film.. So glad that it was made, the screen-writers/directors/producers should all be so proud of themselves, the film is so amazing and if only I was a few years older.. I'd have loved to have been a part of it. So interesting and catchy, once I'd started to watch I couldn't stop!! Although parts of it did drag slightly, they recovered extremely well. I thoroughly enjoyed watching this film. Morgan Freeman is such an amazing actor, I couldn't imagine anyone else to play the role of Red it was done so well. Tim Robbin's was also well cast. Well done.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Epic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Azzman112
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Shawshank Redemption is a defining moment in cinema. The movie (directed by Frank Darabont) takes a straight-forward, soul- searching novel by horror icon Stephen King and transforms it into a somber, bloated prison drama designed to fill you up with inspiration. Thanks to supreme performances and beautiful cinematography, you get that inspirational jump-start frame after frame. And you get generous helpings of the novella's deft ironic humour about a inmate quietly turning a corrupt system against itself. A small box office release which made its name once released on home video, this movie is well worth a watch if you happened to have missed it first time around.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    the best movie i have ever seen of all time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    john_fawzy2008
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    the most beautiful part of the film lies within its thematic material, such as its focus on the human desires for the most abstract concepts, like hope and freedom. These themes, which concern things the human spirit undoubtedly yearns for, seem so intricately woven into the plot that it easily draws its audience in to its story. Though full of hardened criminals, your heart will go out to these men as they display the most basic of human emotions, and deliver some of the most quotable lines in a film to date. Like a great novel, this film manages to succeed at greater things than simply entertaining an audience. Darabont tells his story most masterfully, illustrating principles and inspiring his audience to think. He leaves us a poignant film with a powerful message of hope, and redemption, something we all seek. This film manages to redeem Hollywood in the eyes of people who feared it long lost in a dark sea of clich&eacute;s and predictability. Darabont shows us that artists still work in the Hollywood studios and production facilities. These artists show their capability to produce art; real art that inspires you to look at the deeper aspects of life and the world around you. The Shawshank Redemption delivers much-needed breath of fresh air for anyone who realizes the capability of film. It proves that masters of the craft still live on this earth, and still bless us with timeless masterpieces that we will never forget.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nice
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gvelesianitazo
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Whenever I talk about this movie with my friends, I do not even refer to it by title, but rather as "The Movie". When I say "The Movie", my friends know exactly what I'm talking about. In fact the main reason that me and my friends don't refer to it by title is because this movie is so great, that we do not feel worthy enough to say it's name in vain! I still remember the first time I saw The Shawshank Redemption. Some friends of mine and I went to see it at one of those "Budget Theaters" over the summer of 1995. None of us really knew anything about the movie, but we had heard that it was pretty good. So, not having any real expectations, we saw it. When the final credits rolled and the lights came on in the theater, all of us just sat there with our jaws hanging down on the floor. I turned my head towards my friend Bob and said "That was the greatest movie I have ever seen in my entire life!" There's really no other way I can put it in words. Every moment of this movie captivated me and inspired me to believe in the one true thing in life...... "HOPE". This movie is sad, uplifting, inspiring, harsh, cold, funny (at the right times), jaw-dropping, and heart-warming all at the same time. I get chills every time I watch this film and this film contains the greatest ending (which takes place over the last 30 minutes or so)in movie history! How it all just "comes together" is so incredible and uplifting. I should also mention the music in this movie is nearly flawless as well, and the soundtrack is a "must buy" for any music fan. The only bad thing about this movie is the fact that I know I will never see a better movie, no matter how many I may see. I've seen many movies over the past few years, many excellent films. However, every time I walk out of the theater, I turn to my friend or family member that I saw it with and I say, "That was a great movie, but it wasn't nearly as good as 'you know what'!" There have been many movies over the past few years that thought would really move me or that I might one day call my "favorite of all time", but they've all fallen far short of "The Shawshank Redemption". So, if you have yet to see this movie, please run to the video store immediately. You're guaranteed to find it in the "employee picks" section. And if it isn't in that section, then you should tell the employees there that there is something seriously wrong with them. If you have seen this movie, go see it again. If you haven't bought your own copy yet, buy one. In fact buy two, and put one in a fire-proof safe, just in case of an emergency. :o) So, you want a 1-10 rating??? I give it a 13!!!!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Niceed Movieee!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ramacosgun
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Why do I want to write the 234th comment on The Shawshank Redemption? I am not sure - almost everything that could be possibly said about it has been said. But like so many other people who wrote comments, I was and am profoundly moved by this simple and eloquent depiction of hope and friendship and redemption. The only other movie I have ever seen that effects me as strongly is To Kill a Mockingbird. Both movies leave me feeling cleaner for having watched them. I didn't intend to see this movie at all: I do not like prison movies and I don't normally watch them. I work at a branch library and one day as I was checking The Shawshank Redemption out to one of our older patrons, she said to me, "Whenever I feel down or depressed, I check out this movie and watch it and it always makes me feel better." At the time, I thought that was very strange. One day there was nothing on TV except things I absolutely would not watch under any circumstance or things that I had seen too many times already. I remembered what she said, so I watched it. I have watched it many many times since then and it gets better with every showing. No action, no special effects - just men in prison uniforms talking to each other. The Shawshank Redemption and To Kill a Mockingbird are the best movies I have ever seen. I do not judge it by it's technical merits - I don't really care about that. I have read that Citizen Kane or The Godfather or this or that movie is the best movie ever made. They may have the best technique or be the most influential motion pictures ever made, but not the best. The best movies are ones that touch the soul. It takes a movie like The Shawshank Redemption to touch the soul.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Speechless
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Huzefa Akhter
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let me keep it straight and simple.. I am simply too impressed and therefore out of words to describe what this movie portrays. The acting and realism of this fiction is eye catching. I really wonder how much better it would get if it was based on a true story. Indeed, you can rate, review, describe, audit, revise or summarize a movie, but not art. Whether you are a movie fan or not, simply don't miss this one if you are a human ! BTW, Mr. Brooks was my favorite character.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Shawshank Redemption
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Anand Nandkumar
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you are a movie buff and have not watched The Shawshank Redemption then trust me you are not a certified movie buff.!! This is the best movie made in the history of mankind. I have seen many movies but no movie has moved me or attracted me the way this one has. There is a special charm in the whole narration that keeps going on with the movie which controls me every time. Every line, every shot is just remarkable !Can watch it any number of times and still keep loving it more. So you better waste no time if you haven't watch it yet and then i am sure you would post a review too !! No wonder this movie has won so many accolades to it and will will surely always be in the top char of IMDb for ever and ever and ever.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The determination of the human spirit
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bernardo Rapazote Flores
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The best movies are ones that touch the soul. It takes a movie like The Shawshank Redemption to touch the soul. Shawshank Redemption was my favorite movie when I first saw it, and I only realized its weakness later, this movie will look a lot worst the second time you watch it with its mysteries revealed and questions fully answered because one of the great qualities of this movie is its impossibility to guess which direction the story will take until it reaches the end. However, the movie celebrates the determination of the human spirit "There's something inside you that they can't get to, that they can't touch. It's yours.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A lot of feelings
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    carlosalan-pc
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What to say about this movie, a true masterpiece and a well deserved 1st place here in IMDb. So many feelings felt while watching it. I could definitely watch it again and again and would have the same reactions. As someone said in another review: Excellent acting, soundtrack, photography, etc. Tim Robbins was the perfect guy for the role and all the other actors did great too. Do buy this movie because you not only will be able to enjoy it but you will learn a lot from your own reflections on various aspects of life and will be glad that you are free. The movie itself has a strong message with much impact. Don't miss it by any chance, there's a limited number of movies that will make you feel this emotional about being free and alive.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    motivation
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    barcellosmilton
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Nothing is Impossible. This movie is the perfect way to understand that you don't need to be inside or outside a prison to get freedom. I believe the people need to believe in your dreams more than people say it's no possible, and the situation on this perfect movie by Morgan and Tim explain how to make dreams possible. Just think, work, patience, and believe. This is the way. I watch this movie every time I want to be more motivated. I saw this movie last night and I tell my friends and my family that we can't play with life, and we need to do everything correct to make a good way and get health days. After that I saw I lot of movies from Morgan and Tim, and a lot of this movie we can see on there movies.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Amazing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Elizabeth Olsen
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of the best films that I have watched, so completely enticing! It had me in tears at the end, such an emotional film.. So glad that it was made, the screen-writers/directors/producers should all be so proud of themselves, the film is so amazing and if only I was a few years older.. I'd have loved to have been a part of it. So interesting and catchy, once I'd started to watch I couldn't stop!! Although parts of it did drag slightly, they recovered extremely well. I thoroughly enjoyed watching this film. Morgan Freeman is such an amazing actor, I couldn't imagine anyone else to play the role of Red it was done so well. Tim Robbin's was also well cast. Well done.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Epic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Azzman112
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Shawshank Redemption is a defining moment in cinema. The movie (directed by Frank Darabont) takes a straight-forward, soul- searching novel by horror icon Stephen King and transforms it into a somber, bloated prison drama designed to fill you up with inspiration. Thanks to supreme performances and beautiful cinematography, you get that inspirational jump-start frame after frame. And you get generous helpings of the novella's deft ironic humour about a inmate quietly turning a corrupt system against itself. A small box office release which made its name once released on home video, this movie is well worth a watch if you happened to have missed it first time around.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    the best movie i have ever seen of all time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    john_fawzy2008
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    the most beautiful part of the film lies within its thematic material, such as its focus on the human desires for the most abstract concepts, like hope and freedom. These themes, which concern things the human spirit undoubtedly yearns for, seem so intricately woven into the plot that it easily draws its audience in to its story. Though full of hardened criminals, your heart will go out to these men as they display the most basic of human emotions, and deliver some of the most quotable lines in a film to date. Like a great novel, this film manages to succeed at greater things than simply entertaining an audience. Darabont tells his story most masterfully, illustrating principles and inspiring his audience to think. He leaves us a poignant film with a powerful message of hope, and redemption, something we all seek. This film manages to redeem Hollywood in the eyes of people who feared it long lost in a dark sea of clich&eacute;s and predictability. Darabont shows us that artists still work in the Hollywood studios and production facilities. These artists show their capability to produce art; real art that inspires you to look at the deeper aspects of life and the world around you. The Shawshank Redemption delivers much-needed breath of fresh air for anyone who realizes the capability of film. It proves that masters of the craft still live on this earth, and still bless us with timeless masterpieces that we will never forget.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nice
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gvelesianitazo
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Whenever I talk about this movie with my friends, I do not even refer to it by title, but rather as "The Movie". When I say "The Movie", my friends know exactly what I'm talking about. In fact the main reason that me and my friends don't refer to it by title is because this movie is so great, that we do not feel worthy enough to say it's name in vain! I still remember the first time I saw The Shawshank Redemption. Some friends of mine and I went to see it at one of those "Budget Theaters" over the summer of 1995. None of us really knew anything about the movie, but we had heard that it was pretty good. So, not having any real expectations, we saw it. When the final credits rolled and the lights came on in the theater, all of us just sat there with our jaws hanging down on the floor. I turned my head towards my friend Bob and said "That was the greatest movie I have ever seen in my entire life!" There's really no other way I can put it in words. Every moment of this movie captivated me and inspired me to believe in the one true thing in life...... "HOPE". This movie is sad, uplifting, inspiring, harsh, cold, funny (at the right times), jaw-dropping, and heart-warming all at the same time. I get chills every time I watch this film and this film contains the greatest ending (which takes place over the last 30 minutes or so)in movie history! How it all just "comes together" is so incredible and uplifting. I should also mention the music in this movie is nearly flawless as well, and the soundtrack is a "must buy" for any music fan. The only bad thing about this movie is the fact that I know I will never see a better movie, no matter how many I may see. I've seen many movies over the past few years, many excellent films. However, every time I walk out of the theater, I turn to my friend or family member that I saw it with and I say, "That was a great movie, but it wasn't nearly as good as 'you know what'!" There have been many movies over the past few years that thought would really move me or that I might one day call my "favorite of all time", but they've all fallen far short of "The Shawshank Redemption". So, if you have yet to see this movie, please run to the video store immediately. You're guaranteed to find it in the "employee picks" section. And if it isn't in that section, then you should tell the employees there that there is something seriously wrong with them. If you have seen this movie, go see it again. If you haven't bought your own copy yet, buy one. In fact buy two, and put one in a fire-proof safe, just in case of an emergency. :o) So, you want a 1-10 rating??? I give it a 13!!!!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Niceed Movieee!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ramacosgun
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Why do I want to write the 234th comment on The Shawshank Redemption? I am not sure - almost everything that could be possibly said about it has been said. But like so many other people who wrote comments, I was and am profoundly moved by this simple and eloquent depiction of hope and friendship and redemption. The only other movie I have ever seen that effects me as strongly is To Kill a Mockingbird. Both movies leave me feeling cleaner for having watched them. I didn't intend to see this movie at all: I do not like prison movies and I don't normally watch them. I work at a branch library and one day as I was checking The Shawshank Redemption out to one of our older patrons, she said to me, "Whenever I feel down or depressed, I check out this movie and watch it and it always makes me feel better." At the time, I thought that was very strange. One day there was nothing on TV except things I absolutely would not watch under any circumstance or things that I had seen too many times already. I remembered what she said, so I watched it. I have watched it many many times since then and it gets better with every showing. No action, no special effects - just men in prison uniforms talking to each other. The Shawshank Redemption and To Kill a Mockingbird are the best movies I have ever seen. I do not judge it by it's technical merits - I don't really care about that. I have read that Citizen Kane or The Godfather or this or that movie is the best movie ever made. They may have the best technique or be the most influential motion pictures ever made, but not the best. The best movies are ones that touch the soul. It takes a movie like The Shawshank Redemption to touch the soul.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Speechless
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Huzefa Akhter
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let me keep it straight and simple.. I am simply too impressed and therefore out of words to describe what this movie portrays. The acting and realism of this fiction is eye catching. I really wonder how much better it would get if it was based on a true story. Indeed, you can rate, review, describe, audit, revise or summarize a movie, but not art. Whether you are a movie fan or not, simply don't miss this one if you are a human ! BTW, Mr. Brooks was my favorite character.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Shawshank Redemption
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Anand Nandkumar
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you are a movie buff and have not watched The Shawshank Redemption then trust me you are not a certified movie buff.!! This is the best movie made in the history of mankind. I have seen many movies but no movie has moved me or attracted me the way this one has. There is a special charm in the whole narration that keeps going on with the movie which controls me every time. Every line, every shot is just remarkable !Can watch it any number of times and still keep loving it more. So you better waste no time if you haven't watch it yet and then i am sure you would post a review too !! No wonder this movie has won so many accolades to it and will will surely always be in the top char of IMDb for ever and ever and ever.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The determination of the human spirit
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bernardo Rapazote Flores
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The best movies are ones that touch the soul. It takes a movie like The Shawshank Redemption to touch the soul. Shawshank Redemption was my favorite movie when I first saw it, and I only realized its weakness later, this movie will look a lot worst the second time you watch it with its mysteries revealed and questions fully answered because one of the great qualities of this movie is its impossibility to guess which direction the story will take until it reaches the end. However, the movie celebrates the determination of the human spirit "There's something inside you that they can't get to, that they can't touch. It's yours.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A lot of feelings
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    carlosalan-pc
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What to say about this movie, a true masterpiece and a well deserved 1st place here in IMDb. So many feelings felt while watching it. I could definitely watch it again and again and would have the same reactions. As someone said in another review: Excellent acting, soundtrack, photography, etc. Tim Robbins was the perfect guy for the role and all the other actors did great too. Do buy this movie because you not only will be able to enjoy it but you will learn a lot from your own reflections on various aspects of life and will be glad that you are free. The movie itself has a strong message with much impact. Don't miss it by any chance, there's a limited number of movies that will make you feel this emotional about being free and alive.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    motivation
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    barcellosmilton
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Nothing is Impossible. This movie is the perfect way to understand that you don't need to be inside or outside a prison to get freedom. I believe the people need to believe in your dreams more than people say it's no possible, and the situation on this perfect movie by Morgan and Tim explain how to make dreams possible. Just think, work, patience, and believe. This is the way. I watch this movie every time I want to be more motivated. I saw this movie last night and I tell my friends and my family that we can't play with life, and we need to do everything correct to make a good way and get health days. After that I saw I lot of movies from Morgan and Tim, and a lot of this movie we can see on there movies.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Amazing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Elizabeth Olsen
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of the best films that I have watched, so completely enticing! It had me in tears at the end, such an emotional film.. So glad that it was made, the screen-writers/directors/producers should all be so proud of themselves, the film is so amazing and if only I was a few years older.. I'd have loved to have been a part of it. So interesting and catchy, once I'd started to watch I couldn't stop!! Although parts of it did drag slightly, they recovered extremely well. I thoroughly enjoyed watching this film. Morgan Freeman is such an amazing actor, I couldn't imagine anyone else to play the role of Red it was done so well. Tim Robbin's was also well cast. Well done.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Epic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Azzman112
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Shawshank Redemption is a defining moment in cinema. The movie (directed by Frank Darabont) takes a straight-forward, soul- searching novel by horror icon Stephen King and transforms it into a somber, bloated prison drama designed to fill you up with inspiration. Thanks to supreme performances and beautiful cinematography, you get that inspirational jump-start frame after frame. And you get generous helpings of the novella's deft ironic humour about a inmate quietly turning a corrupt system against itself. A small box office release which made its name once released on home video, this movie is well worth a watch if you happened to have missed it first time around.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    the best movie i have ever seen of all time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    john_fawzy2008
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    the most beautiful part of the film lies within its thematic material, such as its focus on the human desires for the most abstract concepts, like hope and freedom. These themes, which concern things the human spirit undoubtedly yearns for, seem so intricately woven into the plot that it easily draws its audience in to its story. Though full of hardened criminals, your heart will go out to these men as they display the most basic of human emotions, and deliver some of the most quotable lines in a film to date. Like a great novel, this film manages to succeed at greater things than simply entertaining an audience. Darabont tells his story most masterfully, illustrating principles and inspiring his audience to think. He leaves us a poignant film with a powerful message of hope, and redemption, something we all seek. This film manages to redeem Hollywood in the eyes of people who feared it long lost in a dark sea of clich&eacute;s and predictability. Darabont shows us that artists still work in the Hollywood studios and production facilities. These artists show their capability to produce art; real art that inspires you to look at the deeper aspects of life and the world around you. The Shawshank Redemption delivers much-needed breath of fresh air for anyone who realizes the capability of film. It proves that masters of the craft still live on this earth, and still bless us with timeless masterpieces that we will never forget.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nice
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gvelesianitazo
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Whenever I talk about this movie with my friends, I do not even refer to it by title, but rather as "The Movie". When I say "The Movie", my friends know exactly what I'm talking about. In fact the main reason that me and my friends don't refer to it by title is because this movie is so great, that we do not feel worthy enough to say it's name in vain! I still remember the first time I saw The Shawshank Redemption. Some friends of mine and I went to see it at one of those "Budget Theaters" over the summer of 1995. None of us really knew anything about the movie, but we had heard that it was pretty good. So, not having any real expectations, we saw it. When the final credits rolled and the lights came on in the theater, all of us just sat there with our jaws hanging down on the floor. I turned my head towards my friend Bob and said "That was the greatest movie I have ever seen in my entire life!" There's really no other way I can put it in words. Every moment of this movie captivated me and inspired me to believe in the one true thing in life...... "HOPE". This movie is sad, uplifting, inspiring, harsh, cold, funny (at the right times), jaw-dropping, and heart-warming all at the same time. I get chills every time I watch this film and this film contains the greatest ending (which takes place over the last 30 minutes or so)in movie history! How it all just "comes together" is so incredible and uplifting. I should also mention the music in this movie is nearly flawless as well, and the soundtrack is a "must buy" for any music fan. The only bad thing about this movie is the fact that I know I will never see a better movie, no matter how many I may see. I've seen many movies over the past few years, many excellent films. However, every time I walk out of the theater, I turn to my friend or family member that I saw it with and I say, "That was a great movie, but it wasn't nearly as good as 'you know what'!" There have been many movies over the past few years that thought would really move me or that I might one day call my "favorite of all time", but they've all fallen far short of "The Shawshank Redemption". So, if you have yet to see this movie, please run to the video store immediately. You're guaranteed to find it in the "employee picks" section. And if it isn't in that section, then you should tell the employees there that there is something seriously wrong with them. If you have seen this movie, go see it again. If you haven't bought your own copy yet, buy one. In fact buy two, and put one in a fire-proof safe, just in case of an emergency. :o) So, you want a 1-10 rating??? I give it a 13!!!!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Niceed Movieee!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ramacosgun
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Why do I want to write the 234th comment on The Shawshank Redemption? I am not sure - almost everything that could be possibly said about it has been said. But like so many other people who wrote comments, I was and am profoundly moved by this simple and eloquent depiction of hope and friendship and redemption. The only other movie I have ever seen that effects me as strongly is To Kill a Mockingbird. Both movies leave me feeling cleaner for having watched them. I didn't intend to see this movie at all: I do not like prison movies and I don't normally watch them. I work at a branch library and one day as I was checking The Shawshank Redemption out to one of our older patrons, she said to me, "Whenever I feel down or depressed, I check out this movie and watch it and it always makes me feel better." At the time, I thought that was very strange. One day there was nothing on TV except things I absolutely would not watch under any circumstance or things that I had seen too many times already. I remembered what she said, so I watched it. I have watched it many many times since then and it gets better with every showing. No action, no special effects - just men in prison uniforms talking to each other. The Shawshank Redemption and To Kill a Mockingbird are the best movies I have ever seen. I do not judge it by it's technical merits - I don't really care about that. I have read that Citizen Kane or The Godfather or this or that movie is the best movie ever made. They may have the best technique or be the most influential motion pictures ever made, but not the best. The best movies are ones that touch the soul. It takes a movie like The Shawshank Redemption to touch the soul.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Speechless
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Huzefa Akhter
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let me keep it straight and simple.. I am simply too impressed and therefore out of words to describe what this movie portrays. The acting and realism of this fiction is eye catching. I really wonder how much better it would get if it was based on a true story. Indeed, you can rate, review, describe, audit, revise or summarize a movie, but not art. Whether you are a movie fan or not, simply don't miss this one if you are a human ! BTW, Mr. Brooks was my favorite character.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Shawshank Redemption
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Anand Nandkumar
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you are a movie buff and have not watched The Shawshank Redemption then trust me you are not a certified movie buff.!! This is the best movie made in the history of mankind. I have seen many movies but no movie has moved me or attracted me the way this one has. There is a special charm in the whole narration that keeps going on with the movie which controls me every time. Every line, every shot is just remarkable !Can watch it any number of times and still keep loving it more. So you better waste no time if you haven't watch it yet and then i am sure you would post a review too !! No wonder this movie has won so many accolades to it and will will surely always be in the top char of IMDb for ever and ever and ever.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The determination of the human spirit
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bernardo Rapazote Flores
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The best movies are ones that touch the soul. It takes a movie like The Shawshank Redemption to touch the soul. Shawshank Redemption was my favorite movie when I first saw it, and I only realized its weakness later, this movie will look a lot worst the second time you watch it with its mysteries revealed and questions fully answered because one of the great qualities of this movie is its impossibility to guess which direction the story will take until it reaches the end. However, the movie celebrates the determination of the human spirit "There's something inside you that they can't get to, that they can't touch. It's yours.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A lot of feelings
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    carlosalan-pc
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What to say about this movie, a true masterpiece and a well deserved 1st place here in IMDb. So many feelings felt while watching it. I could definitely watch it again and again and would have the same reactions. As someone said in another review: Excellent acting, soundtrack, photography, etc. Tim Robbins was the perfect guy for the role and all the other actors did great too. Do buy this movie because you not only will be able to enjoy it but you will learn a lot from your own reflections on various aspects of life and will be glad that you are free. The movie itself has a strong message with much impact. Don't miss it by any chance, there's a limited number of movies that will make you feel this emotional about being free and alive.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    motivation
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    barcellosmilton
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Nothing is Impossible. This movie is the perfect way to understand that you don't need to be inside or outside a prison to get freedom. I believe the people need to believe in your dreams more than people say it's no possible, and the situation on this perfect movie by Morgan and Tim explain how to make dreams possible. Just think, work, patience, and believe. This is the way. I watch this movie every time I want to be more motivated. I saw this movie last night and I tell my friends and my family that we can't play with life, and we need to do everything correct to make a good way and get health days. After that I saw I lot of movies from Morgan and Tim, and a lot of this movie we can see on there movies.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Amazing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Elizabeth Olsen
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of the best films that I have watched, so completely enticing! It had me in tears at the end, such an emotional film.. So glad that it was made, the screen-writers/directors/producers should all be so proud of themselves, the film is so amazing and if only I was a few years older.. I'd have loved to have been a part of it. So interesting and catchy, once I'd started to watch I couldn't stop!! Although parts of it did drag slightly, they recovered extremely well. I thoroughly enjoyed watching this film. Morgan Freeman is such an amazing actor, I couldn't imagine anyone else to play the role of Red it was done so well. Tim Robbin's was also well cast. Well done.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Epic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Azzman112
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Shawshank Redemption is a defining moment in cinema. The movie (directed by Frank Darabont) takes a straight-forward, soul- searching novel by horror icon Stephen King and transforms it into a somber, bloated prison drama designed to fill you up with inspiration. Thanks to supreme performances and beautiful cinematography, you get that inspirational jump-start frame after frame. And you get generous helpings of the novella's deft ironic humour about a inmate quietly turning a corrupt system against itself. A small box office release which made its name once released on home video, this movie is well worth a watch if you happened to have missed it first time around.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    the best movie i have ever seen of all time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    john_fawzy2008
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    the most beautiful part of the film lies within its thematic material, such as its focus on the human desires for the most abstract concepts, like hope and freedom. These themes, which concern things the human spirit undoubtedly yearns for, seem so intricately woven into the plot that it easily draws its audience in to its story. Though full of hardened criminals, your heart will go out to these men as they display the most basic of human emotions, and deliver some of the most quotable lines in a film to date. Like a great novel, this film manages to succeed at greater things than simply entertaining an audience. Darabont tells his story most masterfully, illustrating principles and inspiring his audience to think. He leaves us a poignant film with a powerful message of hope, and redemption, something we all seek. This film manages to redeem Hollywood in the eyes of people who feared it long lost in a dark sea of clich&eacute;s and predictability. Darabont shows us that artists still work in the Hollywood studios and production facilities. These artists show their capability to produce art; real art that inspires you to look at the deeper aspects of life and the world around you. The Shawshank Redemption delivers much-needed breath of fresh air for anyone who realizes the capability of film. It proves that masters of the craft still live on this earth, and still bless us with timeless masterpieces that we will never forget.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nice
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gvelesianitazo
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Whenever I talk about this movie with my friends, I do not even refer to it by title, but rather as "The Movie". When I say "The Movie", my friends know exactly what I'm talking about. In fact the main reason that me and my friends don't refer to it by title is because this movie is so great, that we do not feel worthy enough to say it's name in vain! I still remember the first time I saw The Shawshank Redemption. Some friends of mine and I went to see it at one of those "Budget Theaters" over the summer of 1995. None of us really knew anything about the movie, but we had heard that it was pretty good. So, not having any real expectations, we saw it. When the final credits rolled and the lights came on in the theater, all of us just sat there with our jaws hanging down on the floor. I turned my head towards my friend Bob and said "That was the greatest movie I have ever seen in my entire life!" There's really no other way I can put it in words. Every moment of this movie captivated me and inspired me to believe in the one true thing in life...... "HOPE". This movie is sad, uplifting, inspiring, harsh, cold, funny (at the right times), jaw-dropping, and heart-warming all at the same time. I get chills every time I watch this film and this film contains the greatest ending (which takes place over the last 30 minutes or so)in movie history! How it all just "comes together" is so incredible and uplifting. I should also mention the music in this movie is nearly flawless as well, and the soundtrack is a "must buy" for any music fan. The only bad thing about this movie is the fact that I know I will never see a better movie, no matter how many I may see. I've seen many movies over the past few years, many excellent films. However, every time I walk out of the theater, I turn to my friend or family member that I saw it with and I say, "That was a great movie, but it wasn't nearly as good as 'you know what'!" There have been many movies over the past few years that thought would really move me or that I might one day call my "favorite of all time", but they've all fallen far short of "The Shawshank Redemption". So, if you have yet to see this movie, please run to the video store immediately. You're guaranteed to find it in the "employee picks" section. And if it isn't in that section, then you should tell the employees there that there is something seriously wrong with them. If you have seen this movie, go see it again. If you haven't bought your own copy yet, buy one. In fact buy two, and put one in a fire-proof safe, just in case of an emergency. :o) So, you want a 1-10 rating??? I give it a 13!!!!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Niceed Movieee!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ramacosgun
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Why do I want to write the 234th comment on The Shawshank Redemption? I am not sure - almost everything that could be possibly said about it has been said. But like so many other people who wrote comments, I was and am profoundly moved by this simple and eloquent depiction of hope and friendship and redemption. The only other movie I have ever seen that effects me as strongly is To Kill a Mockingbird. Both movies leave me feeling cleaner for having watched them. I didn't intend to see this movie at all: I do not like prison movies and I don't normally watch them. I work at a branch library and one day as I was checking The Shawshank Redemption out to one of our older patrons, she said to me, "Whenever I feel down or depressed, I check out this movie and watch it and it always makes me feel better." At the time, I thought that was very strange. One day there was nothing on TV except things I absolutely would not watch under any circumstance or things that I had seen too many times already. I remembered what she said, so I watched it. I have watched it many many times since then and it gets better with every showing. No action, no special effects - just men in prison uniforms talking to each other. The Shawshank Redemption and To Kill a Mockingbird are the best movies I have ever seen. I do not judge it by it's technical merits - I don't really care about that. I have read that Citizen Kane or The Godfather or this or that movie is the best movie ever made. They may have the best technique or be the most influential motion pictures ever made, but not the best. The best movies are ones that touch the soul. It takes a movie like The Shawshank Redemption to touch the soul.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Speechless
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Huzefa Akhter
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let me keep it straight and simple.. I am simply too impressed and therefore out of words to describe what this movie portrays. The acting and realism of this fiction is eye catching. I really wonder how much better it would get if it was based on a true story. Indeed, you can rate, review, describe, audit, revise or summarize a movie, but not art. Whether you are a movie fan or not, simply don't miss this one if you are a human ! BTW, Mr. Brooks was my favorite character.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Shawshank Redemption
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Anand Nandkumar
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you are a movie buff and have not watched The Shawshank Redemption then trust me you are not a certified movie buff.!! This is the best movie made in the history of mankind. I have seen many movies but no movie has moved me or attracted me the way this one has. There is a special charm in the whole narration that keeps going on with the movie which controls me every time. Every line, every shot is just remarkable !Can watch it any number of times and still keep loving it more. So you better waste no time if you haven't watch it yet and then i am sure you would post a review too !! No wonder this movie has won so many accolades to it and will will surely always be in the top char of IMDb for ever and ever and ever.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The determination of the human spirit
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bernardo Rapazote Flores
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The best movies are ones that touch the soul. It takes a movie like The Shawshank Redemption to touch the soul. Shawshank Redemption was my favorite movie when I first saw it, and I only realized its weakness later, this movie will look a lot worst the second time you watch it with its mysteries revealed and questions fully answered because one of the great qualities of this movie is its impossibility to guess which direction the story will take until it reaches the end. However, the movie celebrates the determination of the human spirit "There's something inside you that they can't get to, that they can't touch. It's yours.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A lot of feelings
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    carlosalan-pc
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What to say about this movie, a true masterpiece and a well deserved 1st place here in IMDb. So many feelings felt while watching it. I could definitely watch it again and again and would have the same reactions. As someone said in another review: Excellent acting, soundtrack, photography, etc. Tim Robbins was the perfect guy for the role and all the other actors did great too. Do buy this movie because you not only will be able to enjoy it but you will learn a lot from your own reflections on various aspects of life and will be glad that you are free. The movie itself has a strong message with much impact. Don't miss it by any chance, there's a limited number of movies that will make you feel this emotional about being free and alive.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    motivation
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    barcellosmilton
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Nothing is Impossible. This movie is the perfect way to understand that you don't need to be inside or outside a prison to get freedom. I believe the people need to believe in your dreams more than people say it's no possible, and the situation on this perfect movie by Morgan and Tim explain how to make dreams possible. Just think, work, patience, and believe. This is the way. I watch this movie every time I want to be more motivated. I saw this movie last night and I tell my friends and my family that we can't play with life, and we need to do everything correct to make a good way and get health days. After that I saw I lot of movies from Morgan and Tim, and a lot of this movie we can see on there movies.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Amazing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Elizabeth Olsen
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of the best films that I have watched, so completely enticing! It had me in tears at the end, such an emotional film.. So glad that it was made, the screen-writers/directors/producers should all be so proud of themselves, the film is so amazing and if only I was a few years older.. I'd have loved to have been a part of it. So interesting and catchy, once I'd started to watch I couldn't stop!! Although parts of it did drag slightly, they recovered extremely well. I thoroughly enjoyed watching this film. Morgan Freeman is such an amazing actor, I couldn't imagine anyone else to play the role of Red it was done so well. Tim Robbin's was also well cast. Well done.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Epic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Azzman112
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Shawshank Redemption is a defining moment in cinema. The movie (directed by Frank Darabont) takes a straight-forward, soul- searching novel by horror icon Stephen King and transforms it into a somber, bloated prison drama designed to fill you up with inspiration. Thanks to supreme performances and beautiful cinematography, you get that inspirational jump-start frame after frame. And you get generous helpings of the novella's deft ironic humour about a inmate quietly turning a corrupt system against itself. A small box office release which made its name once released on home video, this movie is well worth a watch if you happened to have missed it first time around.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    the best movie i have ever seen of all time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    john_fawzy2008
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    the most beautiful part of the film lies within its thematic material, such as its focus on the human desires for the most abstract concepts, like hope and freedom. These themes, which concern things the human spirit undoubtedly yearns for, seem so intricately woven into the plot that it easily draws its audience in to its story. Though full of hardened criminals, your heart will go out to these men as they display the most basic of human emotions, and deliver some of the most quotable lines in a film to date. Like a great novel, this film manages to succeed at greater things than simply entertaining an audience. Darabont tells his story most masterfully, illustrating principles and inspiring his audience to think. He leaves us a poignant film with a powerful message of hope, and redemption, something we all seek. This film manages to redeem Hollywood in the eyes of people who feared it long lost in a dark sea of clich&eacute;s and predictability. Darabont shows us that artists still work in the Hollywood studios and production facilities. These artists show their capability to produce art; real art that inspires you to look at the deeper aspects of life and the world around you. The Shawshank Redemption delivers much-needed breath of fresh air for anyone who realizes the capability of film. It proves that masters of the craft still live on this earth, and still bless us with timeless masterpieces that we will never forget.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nice
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gvelesianitazo
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Whenever I talk about this movie with my friends, I do not even refer to it by title, but rather as "The Movie". When I say "The Movie", my friends know exactly what I'm talking about. In fact the main reason that me and my friends don't refer to it by title is because this movie is so great, that we do not feel worthy enough to say it's name in vain! I still remember the first time I saw The Shawshank Redemption. Some friends of mine and I went to see it at one of those "Budget Theaters" over the summer of 1995. None of us really knew anything about the movie, but we had heard that it was pretty good. So, not having any real expectations, we saw it. When the final credits rolled and the lights came on in the theater, all of us just sat there with our jaws hanging down on the floor. I turned my head towards my friend Bob and said "That was the greatest movie I have ever seen in my entire life!" There's really no other way I can put it in words. Every moment of this movie captivated me and inspired me to believe in the one true thing in life...... "HOPE". This movie is sad, uplifting, inspiring, harsh, cold, funny (at the right times), jaw-dropping, and heart-warming all at the same time. I get chills every time I watch this film and this film contains the greatest ending (which takes place over the last 30 minutes or so)in movie history! How it all just "comes together" is so incredible and uplifting. I should also mention the music in this movie is nearly flawless as well, and the soundtrack is a "must buy" for any music fan. The only bad thing about this movie is the fact that I know I will never see a better movie, no matter how many I may see. I've seen many movies over the past few years, many excellent films. However, every time I walk out of the theater, I turn to my friend or family member that I saw it with and I say, "That was a great movie, but it wasn't nearly as good as 'you know what'!" There have been many movies over the past few years that thought would really move me or that I might one day call my "favorite of all time", but they've all fallen far short of "The Shawshank Redemption". So, if you have yet to see this movie, please run to the video store immediately. You're guaranteed to find it in the "employee picks" section. And if it isn't in that section, then you should tell the employees there that there is something seriously wrong with them. If you have seen this movie, go see it again. If you haven't bought your own copy yet, buy one. In fact buy two, and put one in a fire-proof safe, just in case of an emergency. :o) So, you want a 1-10 rating??? I give it a 13!!!!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Niceed Movieee!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ramacosgun
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Why do I want to write the 234th comment on The Shawshank Redemption? I am not sure - almost everything that could be possibly said about it has been said. But like so many other people who wrote comments, I was and am profoundly moved by this simple and eloquent depiction of hope and friendship and redemption. The only other movie I have ever seen that effects me as strongly is To Kill a Mockingbird. Both movies leave me feeling cleaner for having watched them. I didn't intend to see this movie at all: I do not like prison movies and I don't normally watch them. I work at a branch library and one day as I was checking The Shawshank Redemption out to one of our older patrons, she said to me, "Whenever I feel down or depressed, I check out this movie and watch it and it always makes me feel better." At the time, I thought that was very strange. One day there was nothing on TV except things I absolutely would not watch under any circumstance or things that I had seen too many times already. I remembered what she said, so I watched it. I have watched it many many times since then and it gets better with every showing. No action, no special effects - just men in prison uniforms talking to each other. The Shawshank Redemption and To Kill a Mockingbird are the best movies I have ever seen. I do not judge it by it's technical merits - I don't really care about that. I have read that Citizen Kane or The Godfather or this or that movie is the best movie ever made. They may have the best technique or be the most influential motion pictures ever made, but not the best. The best movies are ones that touch the soul. It takes a movie like The Shawshank Redemption to touch the soul.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Speechless
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Huzefa Akhter
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let me keep it straight and simple.. I am simply too impressed and therefore out of words to describe what this movie portrays. The acting and realism of this fiction is eye catching. I really wonder how much better it would get if it was based on a true story. Indeed, you can rate, review, describe, audit, revise or summarize a movie, but not art. Whether you are a movie fan or not, simply don't miss this one if you are a human ! BTW, Mr. Brooks was my favorite character.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Shawshank Redemption
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Anand Nandkumar
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you are a movie buff and have not watched The Shawshank Redemption then trust me you are not a certified movie buff.!! This is the best movie made in the history of mankind. I have seen many movies but no movie has moved me or attracted me the way this one has. There is a special charm in the whole narration that keeps going on with the movie which controls me every time. Every line, every shot is just remarkable !Can watch it any number of times and still keep loving it more. So you better waste no time if you haven't watch it yet and then i am sure you would post a review too !! No wonder this movie has won so many accolades to it and will will surely always be in the top char of IMDb for ever and ever and ever.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The determination of the human spirit
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bernardo Rapazote Flores
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The best movies are ones that touch the soul. It takes a movie like The Shawshank Redemption to touch the soul. Shawshank Redemption was my favorite movie when I first saw it, and I only realized its weakness later, this movie will look a lot worst the second time you watch it with its mysteries revealed and questions fully answered because one of the great qualities of this movie is its impossibility to guess which direction the story will take until it reaches the end. However, the movie celebrates the determination of the human spirit "There's something inside you that they can't get to, that they can't touch. It's yours.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A lot of feelings
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    carlosalan-pc
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What to say about this movie, a true masterpiece and a well deserved 1st place here in IMDb. So many feelings felt while watching it. I could definitely watch it again and again and would have the same reactions. As someone said in another review: Excellent acting, soundtrack, photography, etc. Tim Robbins was the perfect guy for the role and all the other actors did great too. Do buy this movie because you not only will be able to enjoy it but you will learn a lot from your own reflections on various aspects of life and will be glad that you are free. The movie itself has a strong message with much impact. Don't miss it by any chance, there's a limited number of movies that will make you feel this emotional about being free and alive.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    motivation
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    barcellosmilton
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Nothing is Impossible. This movie is the perfect way to understand that you don't need to be inside or outside a prison to get freedom. I believe the people need to believe in your dreams more than people say it's no possible, and the situation on this perfect movie by Morgan and Tim explain how to make dreams possible. Just think, work, patience, and believe. This is the way. I watch this movie every time I want to be more motivated. I saw this movie last night and I tell my friends and my family that we can't play with life, and we need to do everything correct to make a good way and get health days. After that I saw I lot of movies from Morgan and Tim, and a lot of this movie we can see on there movies.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Amazing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Elizabeth Olsen
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of the best films that I have watched, so completely enticing! It had me in tears at the end, such an emotional film.. So glad that it was made, the screen-writers/directors/producers should all be so proud of themselves, the film is so amazing and if only I was a few years older.. I'd have loved to have been a part of it. So interesting and catchy, once I'd started to watch I couldn't stop!! Although parts of it did drag slightly, they recovered extremely well. I thoroughly enjoyed watching this film. Morgan Freeman is such an amazing actor, I couldn't imagine anyone else to play the role of Red it was done so well. Tim Robbin's was also well cast. Well done.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Epic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Azzman112
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Shawshank Redemption is a defining moment in cinema. The movie (directed by Frank Darabont) takes a straight-forward, soul- searching novel by horror icon Stephen King and transforms it into a somber, bloated prison drama designed to fill you up with inspiration. Thanks to supreme performances and beautiful cinematography, you get that inspirational jump-start frame after frame. And you get generous helpings of the novella's deft ironic humour about a inmate quietly turning a corrupt system against itself. A small box office release which made its name once released on home video, this movie is well worth a watch if you happened to have missed it first time around.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    the best movie i have ever seen of all time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    john_fawzy2008
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    the most beautiful part of the film lies within its thematic material, such as its focus on the human desires for the most abstract concepts, like hope and freedom. These themes, which concern things the human spirit undoubtedly yearns for, seem so intricately woven into the plot that it easily draws its audience in to its story. Though full of hardened criminals, your heart will go out to these men as they display the most basic of human emotions, and deliver some of the most quotable lines in a film to date. Like a great novel, this film manages to succeed at greater things than simply entertaining an audience. Darabont tells his story most masterfully, illustrating principles and inspiring his audience to think. He leaves us a poignant film with a powerful message of hope, and redemption, something we all seek. This film manages to redeem Hollywood in the eyes of people who feared it long lost in a dark sea of clich&eacute;s and predictability. Darabont shows us that artists still work in the Hollywood studios and production facilities. These artists show their capability to produce art; real art that inspires you to look at the deeper aspects of life and the world around you. The Shawshank Redemption delivers much-needed breath of fresh air for anyone who realizes the capability of film. It proves that masters of the craft still live on this earth, and still bless us with timeless masterpieces that we will never forget.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nice
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gvelesianitazo
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Whenever I talk about this movie with my friends, I do not even refer to it by title, but rather as "The Movie". When I say "The Movie", my friends know exactly what I'm talking about. In fact the main reason that me and my friends don't refer to it by title is because this movie is so great, that we do not feel worthy enough to say it's name in vain! I still remember the first time I saw The Shawshank Redemption. Some friends of mine and I went to see it at one of those "Budget Theaters" over the summer of 1995. None of us really knew anything about the movie, but we had heard that it was pretty good. So, not having any real expectations, we saw it. When the final credits rolled and the lights came on in the theater, all of us just sat there with our jaws hanging down on the floor. I turned my head towards my friend Bob and said "That was the greatest movie I have ever seen in my entire life!" There's really no other way I can put it in words. Every moment of this movie captivated me and inspired me to believe in the one true thing in life...... "HOPE". This movie is sad, uplifting, inspiring, harsh, cold, funny (at the right times), jaw-dropping, and heart-warming all at the same time. I get chills every time I watch this film and this film contains the greatest ending (which takes place over the last 30 minutes or so)in movie history! How it all just "comes together" is so incredible and uplifting. I should also mention the music in this movie is nearly flawless as well, and the soundtrack is a "must buy" for any music fan. The only bad thing about this movie is the fact that I know I will never see a better movie, no matter how many I may see. I've seen many movies over the past few years, many excellent films. However, every time I walk out of the theater, I turn to my friend or family member that I saw it with and I say, "That was a great movie, but it wasn't nearly as good as 'you know what'!" There have been many movies over the past few years that thought would really move me or that I might one day call my "favorite of all time", but they've all fallen far short of "The Shawshank Redemption". So, if you have yet to see this movie, please run to the video store immediately. You're guaranteed to find it in the "employee picks" section. And if it isn't in that section, then you should tell the employees there that there is something seriously wrong with them. If you have seen this movie, go see it again. If you haven't bought your own copy yet, buy one. In fact buy two, and put one in a fire-proof safe, just in case of an emergency. :o) So, you want a 1-10 rating??? I give it a 13!!!!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Niceed Movieee!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ramacosgun
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Why do I want to write the 234th comment on The Shawshank Redemption? I am not sure - almost everything that could be possibly said about it has been said. But like so many other people who wrote comments, I was and am profoundly moved by this simple and eloquent depiction of hope and friendship and redemption. The only other movie I have ever seen that effects me as strongly is To Kill a Mockingbird. Both movies leave me feeling cleaner for having watched them. I didn't intend to see this movie at all: I do not like prison movies and I don't normally watch them. I work at a branch library and one day as I was checking The Shawshank Redemption out to one of our older patrons, she said to me, "Whenever I feel down or depressed, I check out this movie and watch it and it always makes me feel better." At the time, I thought that was very strange. One day there was nothing on TV except things I absolutely would not watch under any circumstance or things that I had seen too many times already. I remembered what she said, so I watched it. I have watched it many many times since then and it gets better with every showing. No action, no special effects - just men in prison uniforms talking to each other. The Shawshank Redemption and To Kill a Mockingbird are the best movies I have ever seen. I do not judge it by it's technical merits - I don't really care about that. I have read that Citizen Kane or The Godfather or this or that movie is the best movie ever made. They may have the best technique or be the most influential motion pictures ever made, but not the best. The best movies are ones that touch the soul. It takes a movie like The Shawshank Redemption to touch the soul.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Speechless
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Huzefa Akhter
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let me keep it straight and simple.. I am simply too impressed and therefore out of words to describe what this movie portrays. The acting and realism of this fiction is eye catching. I really wonder how much better it would get if it was based on a true story. Indeed, you can rate, review, describe, audit, revise or summarize a movie, but not art. Whether you are a movie fan or not, simply don't miss this one if you are a human ! BTW, Mr. Brooks was my favorite character.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Shawshank Redemption
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Anand Nandkumar
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you are a movie buff and have not watched The Shawshank Redemption then trust me you are not a certified movie buff.!! This is the best movie made in the history of mankind. I have seen many movies but no movie has moved me or attracted me the way this one has. There is a special charm in the whole narration that keeps going on with the movie which controls me every time. Every line, every shot is just remarkable !Can watch it any number of times and still keep loving it more. So you better waste no time if you haven't watch it yet and then i am sure you would post a review too !! No wonder this movie has won so many accolades to it and will will surely always be in the top char of IMDb for ever and ever and ever.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The determination of the human spirit
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bernardo Rapazote Flores
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The best movies are ones that touch the soul. It takes a movie like The Shawshank Redemption to touch the soul. Shawshank Redemption was my favorite movie when I first saw it, and I only realized its weakness later, this movie will look a lot worst the second time you watch it with its mysteries revealed and questions fully answered because one of the great qualities of this movie is its impossibility to guess which direction the story will take until it reaches the end. However, the movie celebrates the determination of the human spirit "There's something inside you that they can't get to, that they can't touch. It's yours.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A lot of feelings
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    carlosalan-pc
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What to say about this movie, a true masterpiece and a well deserved 1st place here in IMDb. So many feelings felt while watching it. I could definitely watch it again and again and would have the same reactions. As someone said in another review: Excellent acting, soundtrack, photography, etc. Tim Robbins was the perfect guy for the role and all the other actors did great too. Do buy this movie because you not only will be able to enjoy it but you will learn a lot from your own reflections on various aspects of life and will be glad that you are free. The movie itself has a strong message with much impact. Don't miss it by any chance, there's a limited number of movies that will make you feel this emotional about being free and alive.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    motivation
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    barcellosmilton
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Nothing is Impossible. This movie is the perfect way to understand that you don't need to be inside or outside a prison to get freedom. I believe the people need to believe in your dreams more than people say it's no possible, and the situation on this perfect movie by Morgan and Tim explain how to make dreams possible. Just think, work, patience, and believe. This is the way. I watch this movie every time I want to be more motivated. I saw this movie last night and I tell my friends and my family that we can't play with life, and we need to do everything correct to make a good way and get health days. After that I saw I lot of movies from Morgan and Tim, and a lot of this movie we can see on there movies.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Amazing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Elizabeth Olsen
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of the best films that I have watched, so completely enticing! It had me in tears at the end, such an emotional film.. So glad that it was made, the screen-writers/directors/producers should all be so proud of themselves, the film is so amazing and if only I was a few years older.. I'd have loved to have been a part of it. So interesting and catchy, once I'd started to watch I couldn't stop!! Although parts of it did drag slightly, they recovered extremely well. I thoroughly enjoyed watching this film. Morgan Freeman is such an amazing actor, I couldn't imagine anyone else to play the role of Red it was done so well. Tim Robbin's was also well cast. Well done.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Epic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Azzman112
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Shawshank Redemption is a defining moment in cinema. The movie (directed by Frank Darabont) takes a straight-forward, soul- searching novel by horror icon Stephen King and transforms it into a somber, bloated prison drama designed to fill you up with inspiration. Thanks to supreme performances and beautiful cinematography, you get that inspirational jump-start frame after frame. And you get generous helpings of the novella's deft ironic humour about a inmate quietly turning a corrupt system against itself. A small box office release which made its name once released on home video, this movie is well worth a watch if you happened to have missed it first time around.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    the best movie i have ever seen of all time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    john_fawzy2008
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    the most beautiful part of the film lies within its thematic material, such as its focus on the human desires for the most abstract concepts, like hope and freedom. These themes, which concern things the human spirit undoubtedly yearns for, seem so intricately woven into the plot that it easily draws its audience in to its story. Though full of hardened criminals, your heart will go out to these men as they display the most basic of human emotions, and deliver some of the most quotable lines in a film to date. Like a great novel, this film manages to succeed at greater things than simply entertaining an audience. Darabont tells his story most masterfully, illustrating principles and inspiring his audience to think. He leaves us a poignant film with a powerful message of hope, and redemption, something we all seek. This film manages to redeem Hollywood in the eyes of people who feared it long lost in a dark sea of clich&eacute;s and predictability. Darabont shows us that artists still work in the Hollywood studios and production facilities. These artists show their capability to produce art; real art that inspires you to look at the deeper aspects of life and the world around you. The Shawshank Redemption delivers much-needed breath of fresh air for anyone who realizes the capability of film. It proves that masters of the craft still live on this earth, and still bless us with timeless masterpieces that we will never forget.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nice
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gvelesianitazo
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Whenever I talk about this movie with my friends, I do not even refer to it by title, but rather as "The Movie". When I say "The Movie", my friends know exactly what I'm talking about. In fact the main reason that me and my friends don't refer to it by title is because this movie is so great, that we do not feel worthy enough to say it's name in vain! I still remember the first time I saw The Shawshank Redemption. Some friends of mine and I went to see it at one of those "Budget Theaters" over the summer of 1995. None of us really knew anything about the movie, but we had heard that it was pretty good. So, not having any real expectations, we saw it. When the final credits rolled and the lights came on in the theater, all of us just sat there with our jaws hanging down on the floor. I turned my head towards my friend Bob and said "That was the greatest movie I have ever seen in my entire life!" There's really no other way I can put it in words. Every moment of this movie captivated me and inspired me to believe in the one true thing in life...... "HOPE". This movie is sad, uplifting, inspiring, harsh, cold, funny (at the right times), jaw-dropping, and heart-warming all at the same time. I get chills every time I watch this film and this film contains the greatest ending (which takes place over the last 30 minutes or so)in movie history! How it all just "comes together" is so incredible and uplifting. I should also mention the music in this movie is nearly flawless as well, and the soundtrack is a "must buy" for any music fan. The only bad thing about this movie is the fact that I know I will never see a better movie, no matter how many I may see. I've seen many movies over the past few years, many excellent films. However, every time I walk out of the theater, I turn to my friend or family member that I saw it with and I say, "That was a great movie, but it wasn't nearly as good as 'you know what'!" There have been many movies over the past few years that thought would really move me or that I might one day call my "favorite of all time", but they've all fallen far short of "The Shawshank Redemption". So, if you have yet to see this movie, please run to the video store immediately. You're guaranteed to find it in the "employee picks" section. And if it isn't in that section, then you should tell the employees there that there is something seriously wrong with them. If you have seen this movie, go see it again. If you haven't bought your own copy yet, buy one. In fact buy two, and put one in a fire-proof safe, just in case of an emergency. :o) So, you want a 1-10 rating??? I give it a 13!!!!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Niceed Movieee!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ramacosgun
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Why do I want to write the 234th comment on The Shawshank Redemption? I am not sure - almost everything that could be possibly said about it has been said. But like so many other people who wrote comments, I was and am profoundly moved by this simple and eloquent depiction of hope and friendship and redemption. The only other movie I have ever seen that effects me as strongly is To Kill a Mockingbird. Both movies leave me feeling cleaner for having watched them. I didn't intend to see this movie at all: I do not like prison movies and I don't normally watch them. I work at a branch library and one day as I was checking The Shawshank Redemption out to one of our older patrons, she said to me, "Whenever I feel down or depressed, I check out this movie and watch it and it always makes me feel better." At the time, I thought that was very strange. One day there was nothing on TV except things I absolutely would not watch under any circumstance or things that I had seen too many times already. I remembered what she said, so I watched it. I have watched it many many times since then and it gets better with every showing. No action, no special effects - just men in prison uniforms talking to each other. The Shawshank Redemption and To Kill a Mockingbird are the best movies I have ever seen. I do not judge it by it's technical merits - I don't really care about that. I have read that Citizen Kane or The Godfather or this or that movie is the best movie ever made. They may have the best technique or be the most influential motion pictures ever made, but not the best. The best movies are ones that touch the soul. It takes a movie like The Shawshank Redemption to touch the soul.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Speechless
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Huzefa Akhter
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let me keep it straight and simple.. I am simply too impressed and therefore out of words to describe what this movie portrays. The acting and realism of this fiction is eye catching. I really wonder how much better it would get if it was based on a true story. Indeed, you can rate, review, describe, audit, revise or summarize a movie, but not art. Whether you are a movie fan or not, simply don't miss this one if you are a human ! BTW, Mr. Brooks was my favorite character.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Shawshank Redemption
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Anand Nandkumar
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you are a movie buff and have not watched The Shawshank Redemption then trust me you are not a certified movie buff.!! This is the best movie made in the history of mankind. I have seen many movies but no movie has moved me or attracted me the way this one has. There is a special charm in the whole narration that keeps going on with the movie which controls me every time. Every line, every shot is just remarkable !Can watch it any number of times and still keep loving it more. So you better waste no time if you haven't watch it yet and then i am sure you would post a review too !! No wonder this movie has won so many accolades to it and will will surely always be in the top char of IMDb for ever and ever and ever.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The determination of the human spirit
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bernardo Rapazote Flores
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The best movies are ones that touch the soul. It takes a movie like The Shawshank Redemption to touch the soul. Shawshank Redemption was my favorite movie when I first saw it, and I only realized its weakness later, this movie will look a lot worst the second time you watch it with its mysteries revealed and questions fully answered because one of the great qualities of this movie is its impossibility to guess which direction the story will take until it reaches the end. However, the movie celebrates the determination of the human spirit "There's something inside you that they can't get to, that they can't touch. It's yours.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A lot of feelings
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    carlosalan-pc
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What to say about this movie, a true masterpiece and a well deserved 1st place here in IMDb. So many feelings felt while watching it. I could definitely watch it again and again and would have the same reactions. As someone said in another review: Excellent acting, soundtrack, photography, etc. Tim Robbins was the perfect guy for the role and all the other actors did great too. Do buy this movie because you not only will be able to enjoy it but you will learn a lot from your own reflections on various aspects of life and will be glad that you are free. The movie itself has a strong message with much impact. Don't miss it by any chance, there's a limited number of movies that will make you feel this emotional about being free and alive.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    motivation
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    barcellosmilton
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Nothing is Impossible. This movie is the perfect way to understand that you don't need to be inside or outside a prison to get freedom. I believe the people need to believe in your dreams more than people say it's no possible, and the situation on this perfect movie by Morgan and Tim explain how to make dreams possible. Just think, work, patience, and believe. This is the way. I watch this movie every time I want to be more motivated. I saw this movie last night and I tell my friends and my family that we can't play with life, and we need to do everything correct to make a good way and get health days. After that I saw I lot of movies from Morgan and Tim, and a lot of this movie we can see on there movies.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Amazing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Elizabeth Olsen
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of the best films that I have watched, so completely enticing! It had me in tears at the end, such an emotional film.. So glad that it was made, the screen-writers/directors/producers should all be so proud of themselves, the film is so amazing and if only I was a few years older.. I'd have loved to have been a part of it. So interesting and catchy, once I'd started to watch I couldn't stop!! Although parts of it did drag slightly, they recovered extremely well. I thoroughly enjoyed watching this film. Morgan Freeman is such an amazing actor, I couldn't imagine anyone else to play the role of Red it was done so well. Tim Robbin's was also well cast. Well done.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Epic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Azzman112
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Shawshank Redemption is a defining moment in cinema. The movie (directed by Frank Darabont) takes a straight-forward, soul- searching novel by horror icon Stephen King and transforms it into a somber, bloated prison drama designed to fill you up with inspiration. Thanks to supreme performances and beautiful cinematography, you get that inspirational jump-start frame after frame. And you get generous helpings of the novella's deft ironic humour about a inmate quietly turning a corrupt system against itself. A small box office release which made its name once released on home video, this movie is well worth a watch if you happened to have missed it first time around.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    the best movie i have ever seen of all time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    john_fawzy2008
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    the most beautiful part of the film lies within its thematic material, such as its focus on the human desires for the most abstract concepts, like hope and freedom. These themes, which concern things the human spirit undoubtedly yearns for, seem so intricately woven into the plot that it easily draws its audience in to its story. Though full of hardened criminals, your heart will go out to these men as they display the most basic of human emotions, and deliver some of the most quotable lines in a film to date. Like a great novel, this film manages to succeed at greater things than simply entertaining an audience. Darabont tells his story most masterfully, illustrating principles and inspiring his audience to think. He leaves us a poignant film with a powerful message of hope, and redemption, something we all seek. This film manages to redeem Hollywood in the eyes of people who feared it long lost in a dark sea of clich&eacute;s and predictability. Darabont shows us that artists still work in the Hollywood studios and production facilities. These artists show their capability to produce art; real art that inspires you to look at the deeper aspects of life and the world around you. The Shawshank Redemption delivers much-needed breath of fresh air for anyone who realizes the capability of film. It proves that masters of the craft still live on this earth, and still bless us with timeless masterpieces that we will never forget.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nice
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gvelesianitazo
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Whenever I talk about this movie with my friends, I do not even refer to it by title, but rather as "The Movie". When I say "The Movie", my friends know exactly what I'm talking about. In fact the main reason that me and my friends don't refer to it by title is because this movie is so great, that we do not feel worthy enough to say it's name in vain! I still remember the first time I saw The Shawshank Redemption. Some friends of mine and I went to see it at one of those "Budget Theaters" over the summer of 1995. None of us really knew anything about the movie, but we had heard that it was pretty good. So, not having any real expectations, we saw it. When the final credits rolled and the lights came on in the theater, all of us just sat there with our jaws hanging down on the floor. I turned my head towards my friend Bob and said "That was the greatest movie I have ever seen in my entire life!" There's really no other way I can put it in words. Every moment of this movie captivated me and inspired me to believe in the one true thing in life...... "HOPE". This movie is sad, uplifting, inspiring, harsh, cold, funny (at the right times), jaw-dropping, and heart-warming all at the same time. I get chills every time I watch this film and this film contains the greatest ending (which takes place over the last 30 minutes or so)in movie history! How it all just "comes together" is so incredible and uplifting. I should also mention the music in this movie is nearly flawless as well, and the soundtrack is a "must buy" for any music fan. The only bad thing about this movie is the fact that I know I will never see a better movie, no matter how many I may see. I've seen many movies over the past few years, many excellent films. However, every time I walk out of the theater, I turn to my friend or family member that I saw it with and I say, "That was a great movie, but it wasn't nearly as good as 'you know what'!" There have been many movies over the past few years that thought would really move me or that I might one day call my "favorite of all time", but they've all fallen far short of "The Shawshank Redemption". So, if you have yet to see this movie, please run to the video store immediately. You're guaranteed to find it in the "employee picks" section. And if it isn't in that section, then you should tell the employees there that there is something seriously wrong with them. If you have seen this movie, go see it again. If you haven't bought your own copy yet, buy one. In fact buy two, and put one in a fire-proof safe, just in case of an emergency. :o) So, you want a 1-10 rating??? I give it a 13!!!!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Niceed Movieee!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ramacosgun
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Why do I want to write the 234th comment on The Shawshank Redemption? I am not sure - almost everything that could be possibly said about it has been said. But like so many other people who wrote comments, I was and am profoundly moved by this simple and eloquent depiction of hope and friendship and redemption. The only other movie I have ever seen that effects me as strongly is To Kill a Mockingbird. Both movies leave me feeling cleaner for having watched them. I didn't intend to see this movie at all: I do not like prison movies and I don't normally watch them. I work at a branch library and one day as I was checking The Shawshank Redemption out to one of our older patrons, she said to me, "Whenever I feel down or depressed, I check out this movie and watch it and it always makes me feel better." At the time, I thought that was very strange. One day there was nothing on TV except things I absolutely would not watch under any circumstance or things that I had seen too many times already. I remembered what she said, so I watched it. I have watched it many many times since then and it gets better with every showing. No action, no special effects - just men in prison uniforms talking to each other. The Shawshank Redemption and To Kill a Mockingbird are the best movies I have ever seen. I do not judge it by it's technical merits - I don't really care about that. I have read that Citizen Kane or The Godfather or this or that movie is the best movie ever made. They may have the best technique or be the most influential motion pictures ever made, but not the best. The best movies are ones that touch the soul. It takes a movie like The Shawshank Redemption to touch the soul.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Speechless
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Huzefa Akhter
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let me keep it straight and simple.. I am simply too impressed and therefore out of words to describe what this movie portrays. The acting and realism of this fiction is eye catching. I really wonder how much better it would get if it was based on a true story. Indeed, you can rate, review, describe, audit, revise or summarize a movie, but not art. Whether you are a movie fan or not, simply don't miss this one if you are a human ! BTW, Mr. Brooks was my favorite character.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Shawshank Redemption
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Anand Nandkumar
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you are a movie buff and have not watched The Shawshank Redemption then trust me you are not a certified movie buff.!! This is the best movie made in the history of mankind. I have seen many movies but no movie has moved me or attracted me the way this one has. There is a special charm in the whole narration that keeps going on with the movie which controls me every time. Every line, every shot is just remarkable !Can watch it any number of times and still keep loving it more. So you better waste no time if you haven't watch it yet and then i am sure you would post a review too !! No wonder this movie has won so many accolades to it and will will surely always be in the top char of IMDb for ever and ever and ever.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The determination of the human spirit
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bernardo Rapazote Flores
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The best movies are ones that touch the soul. It takes a movie like The Shawshank Redemption to touch the soul. Shawshank Redemption was my favorite movie when I first saw it, and I only realized its weakness later, this movie will look a lot worst the second time you watch it with its mysteries revealed and questions fully answered because one of the great qualities of this movie is its impossibility to guess which direction the story will take until it reaches the end. However, the movie celebrates the determination of the human spirit "There's something inside you that they can't get to, that they can't touch. It's yours.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A lot of feelings
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    carlosalan-pc
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What to say about this movie, a true masterpiece and a well deserved 1st place here in IMDb. So many feelings felt while watching it. I could definitely watch it again and again and would have the same reactions. As someone said in another review: Excellent acting, soundtrack, photography, etc. Tim Robbins was the perfect guy for the role and all the other actors did great too. Do buy this movie because you not only will be able to enjoy it but you will learn a lot from your own reflections on various aspects of life and will be glad that you are free. The movie itself has a strong message with much impact. Don't miss it by any chance, there's a limited number of movies that will make you feel this emotional about being free and alive.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    motivation
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    barcellosmilton
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Nothing is Impossible. This movie is the perfect way to understand that you don't need to be inside or outside a prison to get freedom. I believe the people need to believe in your dreams more than people say it's no possible, and the situation on this perfect movie by Morgan and Tim explain how to make dreams possible. Just think, work, patience, and believe. This is the way. I watch this movie every time I want to be more motivated. I saw this movie last night and I tell my friends and my family that we can't play with life, and we need to do everything correct to make a good way and get health days. After that I saw I lot of movies from Morgan and Tim, and a lot of this movie we can see on there movies.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Amazing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Elizabeth Olsen
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of the best films that I have watched, so completely enticing! It had me in tears at the end, such an emotional film.. So glad that it was made, the screen-writers/directors/producers should all be so proud of themselves, the film is so amazing and if only I was a few years older.. I'd have loved to have been a part of it. So interesting and catchy, once I'd started to watch I couldn't stop!! Although parts of it did drag slightly, they recovered extremely well. I thoroughly enjoyed watching this film. Morgan Freeman is such an amazing actor, I couldn't imagine anyone else to play the role of Red it was done so well. Tim Robbin's was also well cast. Well done.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Epic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Azzman112
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Shawshank Redemption is a defining moment in cinema. The movie (directed by Frank Darabont) takes a straight-forward, soul- searching novel by horror icon Stephen King and transforms it into a somber, bloated prison drama designed to fill you up with inspiration. Thanks to supreme performances and beautiful cinematography, you get that inspirational jump-start frame after frame. And you get generous helpings of the novella's deft ironic humour about a inmate quietly turning a corrupt system against itself. A small box office release which made its name once released on home video, this movie is well worth a watch if you happened to have missed it first time around.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    the best movie i have ever seen of all time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    john_fawzy2008
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    the most beautiful part of the film lies within its thematic material, such as its focus on the human desires for the most abstract concepts, like hope and freedom. These themes, which concern things the human spirit undoubtedly yearns for, seem so intricately woven into the plot that it easily draws its audience in to its story. Though full of hardened criminals, your heart will go out to these men as they display the most basic of human emotions, and deliver some of the most quotable lines in a film to date. Like a great novel, this film manages to succeed at greater things than simply entertaining an audience. Darabont tells his story most masterfully, illustrating principles and inspiring his audience to think. He leaves us a poignant film with a powerful message of hope, and redemption, something we all seek. This film manages to redeem Hollywood in the eyes of people who feared it long lost in a dark sea of clich&eacute;s and predictability. Darabont shows us that artists still work in the Hollywood studios and production facilities. These artists show their capability to produce art; real art that inspires you to look at the deeper aspects of life and the world around you. The Shawshank Redemption delivers much-needed breath of fresh air for anyone who realizes the capability of film. It proves that masters of the craft still live on this earth, and still bless us with timeless masterpieces that we will never forget.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Nice
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gvelesianitazo
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Whenever I talk about this movie with my friends, I do not even refer to it by title, but rather as "The Movie". When I say "The Movie", my friends know exactly what I'm talking about. In fact the main reason that me and my friends don't refer to it by title is because this movie is so great, that we do not feel worthy enough to say it's name in vain! I still remember the first time I saw The Shawshank Redemption. Some friends of mine and I went to see it at one of those "Budget Theaters" over the summer of 1995. None of us really knew anything about the movie, but we had heard that it was pretty good. So, not having any real expectations, we saw it. When the final credits rolled and the lights came on in the theater, all of us just sat there with our jaws hanging down on the floor. I turned my head towards my friend Bob and said "That was the greatest movie I have ever seen in my entire life!" There's really no other way I can put it in words. Every moment of this movie captivated me and inspired me to believe in the one true thing in life...... "HOPE". This movie is sad, uplifting, inspiring, harsh, cold, funny (at the right times), jaw-dropping, and heart-warming all at the same time. I get chills every time I watch this film and this film contains the greatest ending (which takes place over the last 30 minutes or so)in movie history! How it all just "comes together" is so incredible and uplifting. I should also mention the music in this movie is nearly flawless as well, and the soundtrack is a "must buy" for any music fan. The only bad thing about this movie is the fact that I know I will never see a better movie, no matter how many I may see. I've seen many movies over the past few years, many excellent films. However, every time I walk out of the theater, I turn to my friend or family member that I saw it with and I say, "That was a great movie, but it wasn't nearly as good as 'you know what'!" There have been many movies over the past few years that thought would really move me or that I might one day call my "favorite of all time", but they've all fallen far short of "The Shawshank Redemption". So, if you have yet to see this movie, please run to the video store immediately. You're guaranteed to find it in the "employee picks" section. And if it isn't in that section, then you should tell the employees there that there is something seriously wrong with them. If you have seen this movie, go see it again. If you haven't bought your own copy yet, buy one. In fact buy two, and put one in a fire-proof safe, just in case of an emergency. :o) So, you want a 1-10 rating??? I give it a 13!!!!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Niceed Movieee!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ramacosgun
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Why do I want to write the 234th comment on The Shawshank Redemption? I am not sure - almost everything that could be possibly said about it has been said. But like so many other people who wrote comments, I was and am profoundly moved by this simple and eloquent depiction of hope and friendship and redemption. The only other movie I have ever seen that effects me as strongly is To Kill a Mockingbird. Both movies leave me feeling cleaner for having watched them. I didn't intend to see this movie at all: I do not like prison movies and I don't normally watch them. I work at a branch library and one day as I was checking The Shawshank Redemption out to one of our older patrons, she said to me, "Whenever I feel down or depressed, I check out this movie and watch it and it always makes me feel better." At the time, I thought that was very strange. One day there was nothing on TV except things I absolutely would not watch under any circumstance or things that I had seen too many times already. I remembered what she said, so I watched it. I have watched it many many times since then and it gets better with every showing. No action, no special effects - just men in prison uniforms talking to each other. The Shawshank Redemption and To Kill a Mockingbird are the best movies I have ever seen. I do not judge it by it's technical merits - I don't really care about that. I have read that Citizen Kane or The Godfather or this or that movie is the best movie ever made. They may have the best technique or be the most influential motion pictures ever made, but not the best. The best movies are ones that touch the soul. It takes a movie like The Shawshank Redemption to touch the soul.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Speechless
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Huzefa Akhter
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let me keep it straight and simple.. I am simply too impressed and therefore out of words to describe what this movie portrays. The acting and realism of this fiction is eye catching. I really wonder how much better it would get if it was based on a true story. Indeed, you can rate, review, describe, audit, revise or summarize a movie, but not art. Whether you are a movie fan or not, simply don't miss this one if you are a human ! BTW, Mr. Brooks was my favorite character.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
