<filme>
 <id>
  653
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0052311
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1958
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  A Marca da Maldade
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  8.2
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  A stark, perverse story of murder, kidnapping, and police corruption in a Mexican border town.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Mexican Narcotics officer Ramon Miguel 'Mike' Vargas has to interrupt his honeymoon on the Mexican-US border when an American building contractor is killed after someone places a bomb in his car. He's killed on the US side of the border but it's clear that the bomb was planted on the Mexican side. As a result, Vargas delays his return to Mexico City where he has been mounting a case against the Grandi family crime and narcotics syndicate. Police Captain Hank Quinlan is in charge on the US side and he soon has a suspect, a Mexican named Manolo Sanchez. Vargas is soon onto Quinlan and his Sergeant, Pete Menzies, when he catches them planting evidence to convict Sanchez. With his new American wife, Susie, safely tucked away in a hotel on the US side of the border - or so he thinks - he starts to review Quinlan's earlier cases. While concentrating on the corrupt policeman however, the Grandis have their own plans for Vargas and they start with his wife Susie.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Crime
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Film-Noir
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Thriller
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   mexican
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   border
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   honeymoon
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   investigation
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   police
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Orson Welles
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Orson Welles
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Whit Masterson
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Charlton Heston
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Orson Welles
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Janet Leigh
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just a Touch of American Stereotypes
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rexx Villotti
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    During his honeymoon, Mexican police officer Mike Vargas (Charlton Heston) is dragged into a deadly battler with the respected-but- corrupted American Police Captain Hank Quinlan (Orson Welles). While protecting his wife, avoiding prejudice, and trying to uncover the truth, Vargas has more foes to deal with than he thinks. Involving Mexican drug smugglers, kidnappers, and the dimwitted American police force, Quinlan tries to discredit and stop his attempt to uncover the truth. One of the Film Noirs, Orson Welles' "Touch of Evil" is a Mexican border town mystery unlike any other. In other movies with the same setting, "A Fist Full of Dollars" for example, the hero would be an attractive American cowboy and the villain would be a dirty, greedy Mexican. In typical Welles fashion of breaking film norms, he flips the American image of good and evil. The villain, portrayed by Welles himself, is a fat, corrupt American Cop. While Quinlan is the villain, Welles also makes him the victim also. He is a victim of himself, and from the police work that has consumed his life and humanity. Welles intentionally creates these characters to break free from the chains that often bind him and other film directors of the time. There is not a clear cut plot that can be seen and set up in the first few minutes of the film, the viewers are taken from crime scenes to mobster run hotels before they glimpse at the corrupt American police at work. The main plot cannot be set up very easily in this film without the proper introduction to the characters. For example, the viewer must understand why the Grandi mob family wants Vargas dead. Without this knowledge that the film provides in the action leading up to the reveal of police activities, the viewers would be left wondering why the mob family is so eager to be involved in American police business. This complex plot combined with Welles' dynamic and intriguing cinematography creates a thrilling game of wits between American and Mexican police.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dynamite Opening Crane Shot
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    romanorum1
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A shadowy man places a time-bomb in the trunk of a new Chrysler and runs away just before another man and a woman enter and drive off. In the darkness, among the sounds of traffic and seedy strip clubs and gaudy hotels in the Mexican border town of Los Robles, the auto meanders across the border into the USA. We see crumbling arches and peeling walls. For more than three minutes we wonder what will happen. Tick  tick  tick  The Chrysler passes by mustached Charlton Heston (Mike Vargas) and stunning Janet Leigh (Susan Vargas). As Mike stops to kiss his new wife, we hear the explosion, and there is a cut to the burning vehicle. "This could be very bad for us, utters Mike." Vargas, as a police investigator (and Chairman of the Pan-American Narcotics Commission), was returning to Mexico to testify against Vic Grandi's Mexican crime family. As the explosion occurred on the American side of the border, police chief Harry Quinlan (Orson Welles) is called in to investigate. Bloated, stubbly, puffy-faced Quinlan has a history of planting evidence to convict those whom he wants. Sweating, he oozes corruption from every pore. "You're a mess," fortune-teller Tana (Marlene Dietrich) would later tell him. To Quinlan's displeasure, Vargas decides to hang around because of his concern that his native Mexico may be involved in an international incident. He tells his wife to return to the hotel. She gets intercepted by a gang who takes her to "visit" Uncle Joe Grandi (Akim Tamiroff). He warns her to tell her husband to desist from the Grandi trial, or else. The man who died in the car explosion was Rudolph Linnekar, a wealthy contractor; his girl was a blonde night club dancer. Mexican Manelo Sanchez, a shoe clerk, who had been dating Linnekar's daughter Marcia against her father's wishes, is visited by Quinlan. Now Sanchez does not really care for Marcia, but, as he freely admits, likes only her money. Quinlan, who maintains that Sanchez murdered Rudolph Linnekar because the latter disapproved of Sanchez's marriage to Marcia, plants two sticks of dynamite in a box in Sanchez's bathroom. As Vargas knows that Quinlan planted the evidence, he does not abide by the arrest. He decides to gather evidence against him, and begins working with honest assistant DA Schwartz. Meanwhile Susan Vargas is in danger; as her husband had inconceivably left her alone. She moved to the Mirador Motel, which consists of a number of uninhabited cabins in the desert. Neither her husband nor she can imagine that the hotel is owned by Uncle Joe Grandi. She is the only customer, and he has plans for her, as his leather-jacketed gang of thugs often operates from there. Her only shield  and he really is not one  is neurotic Dennis Weaver, the night man. He acts more psycho than Norman Bates, without the latter's murders. Since Quinlan is quickly onto Mike's intention, he is forced to work with Uncle Joe to frame wife Susan as a druggie. So Susan, besieged in her room, is easy prey for the gang. She is drugged and apparently gang-raped while lesbian leader Mercedes McCambridge watches. Then Susan is brought to a different hotel where she lies unconscious while surrounded by drug paraphernalia. Both Uncle Joe and Quinlan arrive there, but Quinlan turns against him and strangles Joe and leaves evidence to implicate Susan. But he inexplicably leaves his cane in the room, which his sergeant, Pete Menzies (Joseph Calleia) later finds. Menzies has been Quinlan's stooge for years, and although he probably could not exist without Quinlan, soon decides to reverse his previous deeds. Before long, Menzies and Vargas are working together to tape record Quinlan admission of his decadence among the pumping oil derricks and garbage heaps at a canal. Bullets will be fired, and only one of the three will walk away. And only in the end is it confirmed for certain who placed the bomb in the car trunk (although the culprit is obvious). Orson Welles was already a giant for his excellent portrayal in "Citizen Kane" (1942), considered by many critics as the greatest movie of all time. Those who feel that Charlton Heston was miscast should be aware that he portrayed various historical figures. They include Moses, Marc Antony, John the Baptist, El Cid, Michelangelo, both Henry VIII and Sir Thomas More (!), Cardinal Richelieu, Lt. William Clark (of Lewis and Clark fame), Thomas Jefferson, Andrew Jackson, Abe Lincoln, Brigham Young, General "Chinese" Gordon, and Buffalo Bill Cody. Heston could pass as a Mexican of European heritage. Vivacious Janet Leigh was already famous; she had starred in "Angels in the Outfield" (1951), "Scaramouche" (1952), and "The Naked Spur" (1953). The last one is considered by Leonard Maltin to be one of the greatest westerns ever made. Psycho would follow (1960), and Manchurian Candidate after that (1962). The greatness of the movie is not its message; in fact, one may even identify several peculiar settings. Those who hate the movie generally dislike the material. But the film's prominence is in HOW the story is told. It is like "Citizen Kane," which has a rather thin plot, but an incredible revelation. Take the hotel room scene where Welles takes Janet Leigh's nylon stocking and wraps it around his fingers. He looks menacingly at Akim Tamiroff while the neon lights flash from outside. It is a hungry lion facing a trapped antelope. Uncle Joe is finished, and he knows it. "Touch of Evil" has high-level technical qualities of expressionist lighting and shadow, low camera angles, wide-angle lens, and dark, brooding photography. The movie has atmosphere in miles. Henry Mancini's dazzling sound track hits the spot (and works very well even in the truncated 95-minute version of the movie). As "Touch of Evil" is recognized by enthusiasts as one of the greatest movies made in world cinema history, it appears on many Top 100 Lists.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    strange gem
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vincentiu
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    a special form of masterpiece. common story. minimalist scenes. but seed of genius. not a surprise - Orson Welles can be himself - but the joy to discover an admirable construction remains. secret - the cast. Marlene Dietrich in a role of few lines who preserves mystery and seduction, Janet Leigh as innocent victim of dark business, Charlton Heston as Charlton Heston and Welles in a role like a fascinating puzzle. it is more than a film. it is not exactly a masterpiece for usual definition. it is a gem. why ? after see it, you may be have an answer. or, only, a sketch about this precise exercise of precision in each of details.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just a touch
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kosmasp
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Orson Welles did have a "magic touch" (no pun intended), although it didn't always translate into commercial success. Which of course had to do with the studios being reluctant giving him the free reign he had on his Citizen Kane classic. There are quite a few versions out there of this movie and we got treated to one of them (close to what Welles imagined at the time as biographer told us) at the Berlin International Festival. When I say close, it does mean that it's as close to what Welles would have wanted in the movie (from the footage that was shot), especially concerning the audio in the beginning. He had a vision in his head and the studio bosses wouldn't always agree with him. Another problem might have been that he himself wasn't always satisfied and would change things. So while the version I saw, was close to a memo he send to the studio (suggesting cuts and especially the audio change in the beginning), he might have changed all that at a later time, if he had the chance (at least he might have written another memo after watching it the way, he wanted it to be). Having said and written all that, the movie has a powerful performance by Charlton Heston as well. Characters reactions to some things might feel dated or clich&eacute;, but that is just because we have seen other films copying some of the working formula that is being used here. B&W it might be, but it still has quite a punch to it ... morally and otherwise
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The best Film Noir & one of the all-time greatest films.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stephen-scott83
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I first watched Touch of Evil I was absolutely astounded. I was mesmerised by Orson and the simply remarkable depth of his character. I rank this movie as the greatest film noir ever made and one of the greatest movies ever made. It's that simple. I watch this movie at least 2-3 times a month. Orson's character, Hank Quinlan is the ultimate crooked, bigot cop. This character is like a monster that no one seems to know how to stop. That's the easy description, the true genius is in the script, mannerisms and camera angles. You could not make this film in color, it wouldn't work. One of my favorite aspects about this movie is the subtle use of sarcasm - especially Quinlan's Sargeant - that leads to the overall mood of arrogance spread out in this amazing movie. This movie requires multiple viewings if you really want to appreciate the stunning script and superlative camera shots/angles. Dennis Weaver's character is in my opinion, one of the most bizarre in movie history especially considering there was no development his hyper-manic oddball character. Truly bizarre - but so entertaining! The cameo by Zsa Zsa Gabor is neat but the extended "cameo" by Marlene Dietrich is stunning. I bought this movie after 1 viewing - safe to say, you will too. Orson, thank you, thank you, thank you for making this CLASSIC!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "You don't have a future."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Red-125
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Touch of Evil (1958), scripted and directed by Orson Welles, is deservedly one of IMDb's top 250 movies. The story of the movie as a movie is almost as dramatic as the plot of the film. Before the editing took place, Welles was removed from the project. He responded with a long, detailed memo about how the film should be edited. This memo was mostly ignored, and an inferior short version of Touch of Evil was released in theaters and later for the small screen. Fortunately, years later, with immense effort, most of the original footage was salvaged, and the film was reconstructed almost in the way Welles had envisioned it. This longer version was what we saw in the excellent--and newly refurbished-- Dryden Theatre at Eastman House in Rochester, NY. The film seems dated today, but it's still powerful and engrossing. Charlton Heston plays Mike Vargas, a high-ranking Mexican police official. He has just married an American, Susan, played by Janet Leigh. They become involved in a murder investigation because someone dies when dynamite is placed in a car in Mexico, but the explosion takes place across the border in the U.S. It's at this point that Vargas has to interact with Police Captain Hank Quinlan, played by Welles. Quinlan is an overweight, limping, unshaven bully. However, he has almost magical powers to detect criminals, who are then invariably convicted. The means he uses in his investigations are not found in a police manual. So, it's clear from the beginning that Vargas wears the white hat and Quinlan wears the black hat. Janet Leigh is wasted in her role as naive and gullible young wife. Heston does a good job as the straight arrow cop. Welles, of course, is perfect for the role of a (really) bad cop. Quinlan has built his whole career based on his larger-than-life personality, and no one in his town is going to try to change his techniques. Welles was born to play this role. Two supporting characters deserve mention: Dennis Weaver as the Mirador Motel Night Manager. He turns in a brilliant performance that combines stupidity, timidity, and rigidity in equal parts. Marlene Dietrich plays Tanya, a former flame of Quinlan's from the days when he was young and handsome. Dietrich--who looks sad, cynical, and very beautiful--delivers the best line of the film. Quinlan asks her to read his future in her Tarot cards. She tells him, "You haven't got any. Your future is all used up." This is a movie worth seeking out and seeing. It will work better on a large screen. However, even in DVD, it's a must-see film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Way He Sees and Lets Us See
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Antti Keisala
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Orson Welles is one director to whom I'm drawn time and again for refreshment and reinvigoration. He's leagues beyond me, and in the words of Fran&ccedil;ois Truffaut, "When you come out of 'Touch of Evil' you feel less intelligent than before but gratified anyhow by the poetry and art."* Yet there are certain things I always know to look for, whether the film in question is "Citizen Kane" (1941), "The Tragedy of Othello: The Moor of Venice" (1952), "Mr. Arkadin" (1955) or "F for Fake" (1973): the narrative is going to be free-flowingly evasive and explorative, always interested not finding out the truth but rather becoming aware of all the layers of fabrication within the narrative; and the way he sees and lets us see the world will be breathtaking. And so it is. His way of moving the camera with absolute effortlessness astonishes each time, so does the lighting of the interiors and the way he shoots claustrophobic closed spaces. Heston and Welles play wonderfully together, and Welles' performance is among the highlights of his career. Dietrich's character refers to Von Sternberg's "Der Blaue Engel" (1930), a satire about a sexual free fall, a strong undersong in this film. The film's production history, as that of many other films by Welles, is closely linked to the film itself. As such, "Touch of Evil" is also rewarding as an artifact of film history. It's interesting to read Welles' 58-page memo (available online) and compare to any of the versions available. Watching them either chronologically or in reverse order is great fun. So is comparing the aspect ratios. The Region B Blu-ray released by the Masters of Cinema series is most certainly at the summit of the format and what can be done with it. On two Blu-rays there are the three existing versions of the film (the 1958 theatrical version, the 1958 preview version and the 1998 reconstructed version), the 1958 theatrical and the 1998 reconstruction presented in two aspect ratios. They are beautiful transfers, and host interesting and informative commentary tracks. I see myself revisiting this, and then revisiting it again. And again. * The review "Touch of Evil", by Fran&ccedil;ois Truffaut, originally published in "Arts" (June 4, 1958), available in the collection "Les films de ma vie" (1975) and translated into English as "The Films of My Life" (1978). I read this review in the booklet of the Masters of Cinema Blu-ray (p. 5).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    holy cow is this a good movie!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    xhearto
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    thrills! chills! Welles! if you feel like you've seen this movie a thousand times upon first viewing, it's probably because almost every moment has been "borrowed" by filmmakers for over half a century. And then copied by people who saw the borrowings. journey to the dark heart of man? Check. Marlene smoking over a crystal ball? Check. Janet terrorized in a motel? Check. Orson at the pinnacle of his game? Check. a shining example of what defines the difference between a film and a "movie" check. top ten list.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Macho Man?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gamay9
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Film noir at its' best....and, what a cast! The only unlikely scene is where Susie (Janet Leigh) is screaming for help from a fire escape and Vargas (Charleton Heston) drives right by, heads for a bar and roughs up the thugs....meanwhile Susie is arrested and jailed. Wouldn't a macho guy like Heston aid his wife first and then confront the thugs? After all, this is 1958 when guys rolled cigarette packs into their t-shirt sleeves. That was a lame scene. One of the actors, Calleia, was the director; not Hitchcock. It would have been easy for Heston to have the script changed to a more likely scenario. Otherwise, I enjoyed the film; anytime one can see Janet Leigh, Charleton Heston, Orson Welles, Marlene Deitrich (dark-haired Mexican) and Dennis Weaver in the same film, it's a blast!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Touch of Evil
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Directed by and starring Orson Welles, I may remember watching the first ten or something minutes of this film but giving up on it, I was certainly up for giving it another chance when I saw it listed and recommended as one of the 1001 Movies You Must See Before You Die in the book. Basically on the border between the United States of America and Mexico a time bomb is planted in the boot of a car, and it is drives to cross the border, and a couple of times newlyweds Ramon Miguel 'Mike' Vargas (Charlton Heston) and Susan 'Susie' (Janet Leigh) pass the vehicle before it crosses, and after doing so it blows up and kills the passengers. Mike works for the Mexican government as a drug enforcement official, and knowing the implications of bombs from Mexico to America exploding he decides to join in any investigation he can, and also looking into it are police Chief Gould (Harry Shannon) and District Attorney Adair (Ray Collins), but also the peculiar Police Captain Hank Quinlan (Orson Welles) and his long time partner Police Sergeant Pete Menzies (Joseph Calleia). Young Mexican man Manelo Sanchez (Victor Millan) is the prime suspect for Quinlan and Menzies, as he was secretly married to the daughter of one of the victims in the explosion, Mike is there during the interrogation, he accidentally knocks over an empty shoebox, and in moments this same box two sticks of dynamite are in it, so Mike suspects Quinlan has been planting evidence to help with his convictions over the years. Although Quinlan denies this Vargas still wants to see his public case records, so Al Schwartz (Mort Mills), the District Attorney's assistant lets him study them, and Gould and Adair are shown the findings as well, but Quinlan himself comes in and threatens resignation in anger over their discussion. There is a risk of the brother of a man Mike was investigating, 'Uncle' Joe Grandi (Akim Tamiroff) trying to expose things, so Susie moves from their Mexican hotel to a motel in America, one that Menzies recommended, staffed by mentally challenged Night Manager (Duel's Dennis Weaver) and with no other guests staying, but family members of Grandi take over the motel. Mike becomes worried when he tries telephoning Susie and she does not answer, in fact Quinlan has arrangement with Grandi that his gang will kidnap her, inject her with drugs and taken to another motel out of town, and indeed this happens, Quinlan murders Grandi and Susie is framed for the murder to give her husband a bad name. Mike goes to have a word with Menzies about the history of the cases he and Quinlan investigating and "found" evidence in, he dismisses any conspiracy he has, and then he goes looking for his wife at the motel but she and her gun have gone, so he goes to the other motel that Grandi owns and confronts his gang, they refuse to answer questions so he beats them up. Schwartz tells him that Susie was arrested for murder, but when he finds her she is barely conscious, and then Menzies comes to tell him that Quinlan's cane was found at the scene of Grandi's murder, so Mike fits him with a wire so he can go to see his partner and hear a conversation between them. At an oil field is where Quinlan and Menzies meet to discuss their activities while Mike records everything, the traitor cop admits he planted evidence on people to make them guiltier than they already were, but the tapping is uncovered by the sound of static. Quinlan knows that Mike is there watching and listening, and in the heat of the moment he shoots Menzies with Vargas's gun, but before he can shoot Mike dead Menzies gets up and shoots Quinlan, Menzies dies and eventually so does Quinlan, Sanchez is revealed to have admitted to the crime of planting the car bomb, and Mike leaves town with a recovered Susie. Also starring Joanna Moore as Marcia Linnekar , Valentin De Vargas as Pancho, Lalo Rios as Risto , Marlene Dietrich as Tanya, Zsa Zsa Gabor as Strip-Club Owner, The Third Man's Joseph Cotten as Coroner and The Exorcist's Mercedes McCambridge as Gang Leader. Heston gives a good performance as the man determined to get to the truth of the matter, Leigh gets her moments as the wife pulled into the situations, but obviously Welles is best part of this film as the treacherous cop with the villainous dark side, and his direction is well paced as well, some supporting cast members, especially Dietrich, are terrific as well. The film opens with one of the most famous long shots in cinema which is played out so well with clever tracking, and the film is filled with interesting material about conspiracy, double-crossing, murder and melodrama, it is one of the last true film noir style pictures, I admit I lost track of plot on occasions, but overall it is a watchable classic crime thriller. Very good!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just a Touch of American Stereotypes
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rexx Villotti
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    During his honeymoon, Mexican police officer Mike Vargas (Charlton Heston) is dragged into a deadly battler with the respected-but- corrupted American Police Captain Hank Quinlan (Orson Welles). While protecting his wife, avoiding prejudice, and trying to uncover the truth, Vargas has more foes to deal with than he thinks. Involving Mexican drug smugglers, kidnappers, and the dimwitted American police force, Quinlan tries to discredit and stop his attempt to uncover the truth. One of the Film Noirs, Orson Welles' "Touch of Evil" is a Mexican border town mystery unlike any other. In other movies with the same setting, "A Fist Full of Dollars" for example, the hero would be an attractive American cowboy and the villain would be a dirty, greedy Mexican. In typical Welles fashion of breaking film norms, he flips the American image of good and evil. The villain, portrayed by Welles himself, is a fat, corrupt American Cop. While Quinlan is the villain, Welles also makes him the victim also. He is a victim of himself, and from the police work that has consumed his life and humanity. Welles intentionally creates these characters to break free from the chains that often bind him and other film directors of the time. There is not a clear cut plot that can be seen and set up in the first few minutes of the film, the viewers are taken from crime scenes to mobster run hotels before they glimpse at the corrupt American police at work. The main plot cannot be set up very easily in this film without the proper introduction to the characters. For example, the viewer must understand why the Grandi mob family wants Vargas dead. Without this knowledge that the film provides in the action leading up to the reveal of police activities, the viewers would be left wondering why the mob family is so eager to be involved in American police business. This complex plot combined with Welles' dynamic and intriguing cinematography creates a thrilling game of wits between American and Mexican police.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dynamite Opening Crane Shot
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    romanorum1
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A shadowy man places a time-bomb in the trunk of a new Chrysler and runs away just before another man and a woman enter and drive off. In the darkness, among the sounds of traffic and seedy strip clubs and gaudy hotels in the Mexican border town of Los Robles, the auto meanders across the border into the USA. We see crumbling arches and peeling walls. For more than three minutes we wonder what will happen. Tick  tick  tick  The Chrysler passes by mustached Charlton Heston (Mike Vargas) and stunning Janet Leigh (Susan Vargas). As Mike stops to kiss his new wife, we hear the explosion, and there is a cut to the burning vehicle. "This could be very bad for us, utters Mike." Vargas, as a police investigator (and Chairman of the Pan-American Narcotics Commission), was returning to Mexico to testify against Vic Grandi's Mexican crime family. As the explosion occurred on the American side of the border, police chief Harry Quinlan (Orson Welles) is called in to investigate. Bloated, stubbly, puffy-faced Quinlan has a history of planting evidence to convict those whom he wants. Sweating, he oozes corruption from every pore. "You're a mess," fortune-teller Tana (Marlene Dietrich) would later tell him. To Quinlan's displeasure, Vargas decides to hang around because of his concern that his native Mexico may be involved in an international incident. He tells his wife to return to the hotel. She gets intercepted by a gang who takes her to "visit" Uncle Joe Grandi (Akim Tamiroff). He warns her to tell her husband to desist from the Grandi trial, or else. The man who died in the car explosion was Rudolph Linnekar, a wealthy contractor; his girl was a blonde night club dancer. Mexican Manelo Sanchez, a shoe clerk, who had been dating Linnekar's daughter Marcia against her father's wishes, is visited by Quinlan. Now Sanchez does not really care for Marcia, but, as he freely admits, likes only her money. Quinlan, who maintains that Sanchez murdered Rudolph Linnekar because the latter disapproved of Sanchez's marriage to Marcia, plants two sticks of dynamite in a box in Sanchez's bathroom. As Vargas knows that Quinlan planted the evidence, he does not abide by the arrest. He decides to gather evidence against him, and begins working with honest assistant DA Schwartz. Meanwhile Susan Vargas is in danger; as her husband had inconceivably left her alone. She moved to the Mirador Motel, which consists of a number of uninhabited cabins in the desert. Neither her husband nor she can imagine that the hotel is owned by Uncle Joe Grandi. She is the only customer, and he has plans for her, as his leather-jacketed gang of thugs often operates from there. Her only shield  and he really is not one  is neurotic Dennis Weaver, the night man. He acts more psycho than Norman Bates, without the latter's murders. Since Quinlan is quickly onto Mike's intention, he is forced to work with Uncle Joe to frame wife Susan as a druggie. So Susan, besieged in her room, is easy prey for the gang. She is drugged and apparently gang-raped while lesbian leader Mercedes McCambridge watches. Then Susan is brought to a different hotel where she lies unconscious while surrounded by drug paraphernalia. Both Uncle Joe and Quinlan arrive there, but Quinlan turns against him and strangles Joe and leaves evidence to implicate Susan. But he inexplicably leaves his cane in the room, which his sergeant, Pete Menzies (Joseph Calleia) later finds. Menzies has been Quinlan's stooge for years, and although he probably could not exist without Quinlan, soon decides to reverse his previous deeds. Before long, Menzies and Vargas are working together to tape record Quinlan admission of his decadence among the pumping oil derricks and garbage heaps at a canal. Bullets will be fired, and only one of the three will walk away. And only in the end is it confirmed for certain who placed the bomb in the car trunk (although the culprit is obvious). Orson Welles was already a giant for his excellent portrayal in "Citizen Kane" (1942), considered by many critics as the greatest movie of all time. Those who feel that Charlton Heston was miscast should be aware that he portrayed various historical figures. They include Moses, Marc Antony, John the Baptist, El Cid, Michelangelo, both Henry VIII and Sir Thomas More (!), Cardinal Richelieu, Lt. William Clark (of Lewis and Clark fame), Thomas Jefferson, Andrew Jackson, Abe Lincoln, Brigham Young, General "Chinese" Gordon, and Buffalo Bill Cody. Heston could pass as a Mexican of European heritage. Vivacious Janet Leigh was already famous; she had starred in "Angels in the Outfield" (1951), "Scaramouche" (1952), and "The Naked Spur" (1953). The last one is considered by Leonard Maltin to be one of the greatest westerns ever made. Psycho would follow (1960), and Manchurian Candidate after that (1962). The greatness of the movie is not its message; in fact, one may even identify several peculiar settings. Those who hate the movie generally dislike the material. But the film's prominence is in HOW the story is told. It is like "Citizen Kane," which has a rather thin plot, but an incredible revelation. Take the hotel room scene where Welles takes Janet Leigh's nylon stocking and wraps it around his fingers. He looks menacingly at Akim Tamiroff while the neon lights flash from outside. It is a hungry lion facing a trapped antelope. Uncle Joe is finished, and he knows it. "Touch of Evil" has high-level technical qualities of expressionist lighting and shadow, low camera angles, wide-angle lens, and dark, brooding photography. The movie has atmosphere in miles. Henry Mancini's dazzling sound track hits the spot (and works very well even in the truncated 95-minute version of the movie). As "Touch of Evil" is recognized by enthusiasts as one of the greatest movies made in world cinema history, it appears on many Top 100 Lists.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    strange gem
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vincentiu
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    a special form of masterpiece. common story. minimalist scenes. but seed of genius. not a surprise - Orson Welles can be himself - but the joy to discover an admirable construction remains. secret - the cast. Marlene Dietrich in a role of few lines who preserves mystery and seduction, Janet Leigh as innocent victim of dark business, Charlton Heston as Charlton Heston and Welles in a role like a fascinating puzzle. it is more than a film. it is not exactly a masterpiece for usual definition. it is a gem. why ? after see it, you may be have an answer. or, only, a sketch about this precise exercise of precision in each of details.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just a touch
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kosmasp
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Orson Welles did have a "magic touch" (no pun intended), although it didn't always translate into commercial success. Which of course had to do with the studios being reluctant giving him the free reign he had on his Citizen Kane classic. There are quite a few versions out there of this movie and we got treated to one of them (close to what Welles imagined at the time as biographer told us) at the Berlin International Festival. When I say close, it does mean that it's as close to what Welles would have wanted in the movie (from the footage that was shot), especially concerning the audio in the beginning. He had a vision in his head and the studio bosses wouldn't always agree with him. Another problem might have been that he himself wasn't always satisfied and would change things. So while the version I saw, was close to a memo he send to the studio (suggesting cuts and especially the audio change in the beginning), he might have changed all that at a later time, if he had the chance (at least he might have written another memo after watching it the way, he wanted it to be). Having said and written all that, the movie has a powerful performance by Charlton Heston as well. Characters reactions to some things might feel dated or clich&eacute;, but that is just because we have seen other films copying some of the working formula that is being used here. B&W it might be, but it still has quite a punch to it ... morally and otherwise
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The best Film Noir & one of the all-time greatest films.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stephen-scott83
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I first watched Touch of Evil I was absolutely astounded. I was mesmerised by Orson and the simply remarkable depth of his character. I rank this movie as the greatest film noir ever made and one of the greatest movies ever made. It's that simple. I watch this movie at least 2-3 times a month. Orson's character, Hank Quinlan is the ultimate crooked, bigot cop. This character is like a monster that no one seems to know how to stop. That's the easy description, the true genius is in the script, mannerisms and camera angles. You could not make this film in color, it wouldn't work. One of my favorite aspects about this movie is the subtle use of sarcasm - especially Quinlan's Sargeant - that leads to the overall mood of arrogance spread out in this amazing movie. This movie requires multiple viewings if you really want to appreciate the stunning script and superlative camera shots/angles. Dennis Weaver's character is in my opinion, one of the most bizarre in movie history especially considering there was no development his hyper-manic oddball character. Truly bizarre - but so entertaining! The cameo by Zsa Zsa Gabor is neat but the extended "cameo" by Marlene Dietrich is stunning. I bought this movie after 1 viewing - safe to say, you will too. Orson, thank you, thank you, thank you for making this CLASSIC!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "You don't have a future."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Red-125
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Touch of Evil (1958), scripted and directed by Orson Welles, is deservedly one of IMDb's top 250 movies. The story of the movie as a movie is almost as dramatic as the plot of the film. Before the editing took place, Welles was removed from the project. He responded with a long, detailed memo about how the film should be edited. This memo was mostly ignored, and an inferior short version of Touch of Evil was released in theaters and later for the small screen. Fortunately, years later, with immense effort, most of the original footage was salvaged, and the film was reconstructed almost in the way Welles had envisioned it. This longer version was what we saw in the excellent--and newly refurbished-- Dryden Theatre at Eastman House in Rochester, NY. The film seems dated today, but it's still powerful and engrossing. Charlton Heston plays Mike Vargas, a high-ranking Mexican police official. He has just married an American, Susan, played by Janet Leigh. They become involved in a murder investigation because someone dies when dynamite is placed in a car in Mexico, but the explosion takes place across the border in the U.S. It's at this point that Vargas has to interact with Police Captain Hank Quinlan, played by Welles. Quinlan is an overweight, limping, unshaven bully. However, he has almost magical powers to detect criminals, who are then invariably convicted. The means he uses in his investigations are not found in a police manual. So, it's clear from the beginning that Vargas wears the white hat and Quinlan wears the black hat. Janet Leigh is wasted in her role as naive and gullible young wife. Heston does a good job as the straight arrow cop. Welles, of course, is perfect for the role of a (really) bad cop. Quinlan has built his whole career based on his larger-than-life personality, and no one in his town is going to try to change his techniques. Welles was born to play this role. Two supporting characters deserve mention: Dennis Weaver as the Mirador Motel Night Manager. He turns in a brilliant performance that combines stupidity, timidity, and rigidity in equal parts. Marlene Dietrich plays Tanya, a former flame of Quinlan's from the days when he was young and handsome. Dietrich--who looks sad, cynical, and very beautiful--delivers the best line of the film. Quinlan asks her to read his future in her Tarot cards. She tells him, "You haven't got any. Your future is all used up." This is a movie worth seeking out and seeing. It will work better on a large screen. However, even in DVD, it's a must-see film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Way He Sees and Lets Us See
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Antti Keisala
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Orson Welles is one director to whom I'm drawn time and again for refreshment and reinvigoration. He's leagues beyond me, and in the words of Fran&ccedil;ois Truffaut, "When you come out of 'Touch of Evil' you feel less intelligent than before but gratified anyhow by the poetry and art."* Yet there are certain things I always know to look for, whether the film in question is "Citizen Kane" (1941), "The Tragedy of Othello: The Moor of Venice" (1952), "Mr. Arkadin" (1955) or "F for Fake" (1973): the narrative is going to be free-flowingly evasive and explorative, always interested not finding out the truth but rather becoming aware of all the layers of fabrication within the narrative; and the way he sees and lets us see the world will be breathtaking. And so it is. His way of moving the camera with absolute effortlessness astonishes each time, so does the lighting of the interiors and the way he shoots claustrophobic closed spaces. Heston and Welles play wonderfully together, and Welles' performance is among the highlights of his career. Dietrich's character refers to Von Sternberg's "Der Blaue Engel" (1930), a satire about a sexual free fall, a strong undersong in this film. The film's production history, as that of many other films by Welles, is closely linked to the film itself. As such, "Touch of Evil" is also rewarding as an artifact of film history. It's interesting to read Welles' 58-page memo (available online) and compare to any of the versions available. Watching them either chronologically or in reverse order is great fun. So is comparing the aspect ratios. The Region B Blu-ray released by the Masters of Cinema series is most certainly at the summit of the format and what can be done with it. On two Blu-rays there are the three existing versions of the film (the 1958 theatrical version, the 1958 preview version and the 1998 reconstructed version), the 1958 theatrical and the 1998 reconstruction presented in two aspect ratios. They are beautiful transfers, and host interesting and informative commentary tracks. I see myself revisiting this, and then revisiting it again. And again. * The review "Touch of Evil", by Fran&ccedil;ois Truffaut, originally published in "Arts" (June 4, 1958), available in the collection "Les films de ma vie" (1975) and translated into English as "The Films of My Life" (1978). I read this review in the booklet of the Masters of Cinema Blu-ray (p. 5).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    holy cow is this a good movie!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    xhearto
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    thrills! chills! Welles! if you feel like you've seen this movie a thousand times upon first viewing, it's probably because almost every moment has been "borrowed" by filmmakers for over half a century. And then copied by people who saw the borrowings. journey to the dark heart of man? Check. Marlene smoking over a crystal ball? Check. Janet terrorized in a motel? Check. Orson at the pinnacle of his game? Check. a shining example of what defines the difference between a film and a "movie" check. top ten list.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Macho Man?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gamay9
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Film noir at its' best....and, what a cast! The only unlikely scene is where Susie (Janet Leigh) is screaming for help from a fire escape and Vargas (Charleton Heston) drives right by, heads for a bar and roughs up the thugs....meanwhile Susie is arrested and jailed. Wouldn't a macho guy like Heston aid his wife first and then confront the thugs? After all, this is 1958 when guys rolled cigarette packs into their t-shirt sleeves. That was a lame scene. One of the actors, Calleia, was the director; not Hitchcock. It would have been easy for Heston to have the script changed to a more likely scenario. Otherwise, I enjoyed the film; anytime one can see Janet Leigh, Charleton Heston, Orson Welles, Marlene Deitrich (dark-haired Mexican) and Dennis Weaver in the same film, it's a blast!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Touch of Evil
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Directed by and starring Orson Welles, I may remember watching the first ten or something minutes of this film but giving up on it, I was certainly up for giving it another chance when I saw it listed and recommended as one of the 1001 Movies You Must See Before You Die in the book. Basically on the border between the United States of America and Mexico a time bomb is planted in the boot of a car, and it is drives to cross the border, and a couple of times newlyweds Ramon Miguel 'Mike' Vargas (Charlton Heston) and Susan 'Susie' (Janet Leigh) pass the vehicle before it crosses, and after doing so it blows up and kills the passengers. Mike works for the Mexican government as a drug enforcement official, and knowing the implications of bombs from Mexico to America exploding he decides to join in any investigation he can, and also looking into it are police Chief Gould (Harry Shannon) and District Attorney Adair (Ray Collins), but also the peculiar Police Captain Hank Quinlan (Orson Welles) and his long time partner Police Sergeant Pete Menzies (Joseph Calleia). Young Mexican man Manelo Sanchez (Victor Millan) is the prime suspect for Quinlan and Menzies, as he was secretly married to the daughter of one of the victims in the explosion, Mike is there during the interrogation, he accidentally knocks over an empty shoebox, and in moments this same box two sticks of dynamite are in it, so Mike suspects Quinlan has been planting evidence to help with his convictions over the years. Although Quinlan denies this Vargas still wants to see his public case records, so Al Schwartz (Mort Mills), the District Attorney's assistant lets him study them, and Gould and Adair are shown the findings as well, but Quinlan himself comes in and threatens resignation in anger over their discussion. There is a risk of the brother of a man Mike was investigating, 'Uncle' Joe Grandi (Akim Tamiroff) trying to expose things, so Susie moves from their Mexican hotel to a motel in America, one that Menzies recommended, staffed by mentally challenged Night Manager (Duel's Dennis Weaver) and with no other guests staying, but family members of Grandi take over the motel. Mike becomes worried when he tries telephoning Susie and she does not answer, in fact Quinlan has arrangement with Grandi that his gang will kidnap her, inject her with drugs and taken to another motel out of town, and indeed this happens, Quinlan murders Grandi and Susie is framed for the murder to give her husband a bad name. Mike goes to have a word with Menzies about the history of the cases he and Quinlan investigating and "found" evidence in, he dismisses any conspiracy he has, and then he goes looking for his wife at the motel but she and her gun have gone, so he goes to the other motel that Grandi owns and confronts his gang, they refuse to answer questions so he beats them up. Schwartz tells him that Susie was arrested for murder, but when he finds her she is barely conscious, and then Menzies comes to tell him that Quinlan's cane was found at the scene of Grandi's murder, so Mike fits him with a wire so he can go to see his partner and hear a conversation between them. At an oil field is where Quinlan and Menzies meet to discuss their activities while Mike records everything, the traitor cop admits he planted evidence on people to make them guiltier than they already were, but the tapping is uncovered by the sound of static. Quinlan knows that Mike is there watching and listening, and in the heat of the moment he shoots Menzies with Vargas's gun, but before he can shoot Mike dead Menzies gets up and shoots Quinlan, Menzies dies and eventually so does Quinlan, Sanchez is revealed to have admitted to the crime of planting the car bomb, and Mike leaves town with a recovered Susie. Also starring Joanna Moore as Marcia Linnekar , Valentin De Vargas as Pancho, Lalo Rios as Risto , Marlene Dietrich as Tanya, Zsa Zsa Gabor as Strip-Club Owner, The Third Man's Joseph Cotten as Coroner and The Exorcist's Mercedes McCambridge as Gang Leader. Heston gives a good performance as the man determined to get to the truth of the matter, Leigh gets her moments as the wife pulled into the situations, but obviously Welles is best part of this film as the treacherous cop with the villainous dark side, and his direction is well paced as well, some supporting cast members, especially Dietrich, are terrific as well. The film opens with one of the most famous long shots in cinema which is played out so well with clever tracking, and the film is filled with interesting material about conspiracy, double-crossing, murder and melodrama, it is one of the last true film noir style pictures, I admit I lost track of plot on occasions, but overall it is a watchable classic crime thriller. Very good!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just a Touch of American Stereotypes
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rexx Villotti
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    During his honeymoon, Mexican police officer Mike Vargas (Charlton Heston) is dragged into a deadly battler with the respected-but- corrupted American Police Captain Hank Quinlan (Orson Welles). While protecting his wife, avoiding prejudice, and trying to uncover the truth, Vargas has more foes to deal with than he thinks. Involving Mexican drug smugglers, kidnappers, and the dimwitted American police force, Quinlan tries to discredit and stop his attempt to uncover the truth. One of the Film Noirs, Orson Welles' "Touch of Evil" is a Mexican border town mystery unlike any other. In other movies with the same setting, "A Fist Full of Dollars" for example, the hero would be an attractive American cowboy and the villain would be a dirty, greedy Mexican. In typical Welles fashion of breaking film norms, he flips the American image of good and evil. The villain, portrayed by Welles himself, is a fat, corrupt American Cop. While Quinlan is the villain, Welles also makes him the victim also. He is a victim of himself, and from the police work that has consumed his life and humanity. Welles intentionally creates these characters to break free from the chains that often bind him and other film directors of the time. There is not a clear cut plot that can be seen and set up in the first few minutes of the film, the viewers are taken from crime scenes to mobster run hotels before they glimpse at the corrupt American police at work. The main plot cannot be set up very easily in this film without the proper introduction to the characters. For example, the viewer must understand why the Grandi mob family wants Vargas dead. Without this knowledge that the film provides in the action leading up to the reveal of police activities, the viewers would be left wondering why the mob family is so eager to be involved in American police business. This complex plot combined with Welles' dynamic and intriguing cinematography creates a thrilling game of wits between American and Mexican police.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dynamite Opening Crane Shot
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    romanorum1
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A shadowy man places a time-bomb in the trunk of a new Chrysler and runs away just before another man and a woman enter and drive off. In the darkness, among the sounds of traffic and seedy strip clubs and gaudy hotels in the Mexican border town of Los Robles, the auto meanders across the border into the USA. We see crumbling arches and peeling walls. For more than three minutes we wonder what will happen. Tick  tick  tick  The Chrysler passes by mustached Charlton Heston (Mike Vargas) and stunning Janet Leigh (Susan Vargas). As Mike stops to kiss his new wife, we hear the explosion, and there is a cut to the burning vehicle. "This could be very bad for us, utters Mike." Vargas, as a police investigator (and Chairman of the Pan-American Narcotics Commission), was returning to Mexico to testify against Vic Grandi's Mexican crime family. As the explosion occurred on the American side of the border, police chief Harry Quinlan (Orson Welles) is called in to investigate. Bloated, stubbly, puffy-faced Quinlan has a history of planting evidence to convict those whom he wants. Sweating, he oozes corruption from every pore. "You're a mess," fortune-teller Tana (Marlene Dietrich) would later tell him. To Quinlan's displeasure, Vargas decides to hang around because of his concern that his native Mexico may be involved in an international incident. He tells his wife to return to the hotel. She gets intercepted by a gang who takes her to "visit" Uncle Joe Grandi (Akim Tamiroff). He warns her to tell her husband to desist from the Grandi trial, or else. The man who died in the car explosion was Rudolph Linnekar, a wealthy contractor; his girl was a blonde night club dancer. Mexican Manelo Sanchez, a shoe clerk, who had been dating Linnekar's daughter Marcia against her father's wishes, is visited by Quinlan. Now Sanchez does not really care for Marcia, but, as he freely admits, likes only her money. Quinlan, who maintains that Sanchez murdered Rudolph Linnekar because the latter disapproved of Sanchez's marriage to Marcia, plants two sticks of dynamite in a box in Sanchez's bathroom. As Vargas knows that Quinlan planted the evidence, he does not abide by the arrest. He decides to gather evidence against him, and begins working with honest assistant DA Schwartz. Meanwhile Susan Vargas is in danger; as her husband had inconceivably left her alone. She moved to the Mirador Motel, which consists of a number of uninhabited cabins in the desert. Neither her husband nor she can imagine that the hotel is owned by Uncle Joe Grandi. She is the only customer, and he has plans for her, as his leather-jacketed gang of thugs often operates from there. Her only shield  and he really is not one  is neurotic Dennis Weaver, the night man. He acts more psycho than Norman Bates, without the latter's murders. Since Quinlan is quickly onto Mike's intention, he is forced to work with Uncle Joe to frame wife Susan as a druggie. So Susan, besieged in her room, is easy prey for the gang. She is drugged and apparently gang-raped while lesbian leader Mercedes McCambridge watches. Then Susan is brought to a different hotel where she lies unconscious while surrounded by drug paraphernalia. Both Uncle Joe and Quinlan arrive there, but Quinlan turns against him and strangles Joe and leaves evidence to implicate Susan. But he inexplicably leaves his cane in the room, which his sergeant, Pete Menzies (Joseph Calleia) later finds. Menzies has been Quinlan's stooge for years, and although he probably could not exist without Quinlan, soon decides to reverse his previous deeds. Before long, Menzies and Vargas are working together to tape record Quinlan admission of his decadence among the pumping oil derricks and garbage heaps at a canal. Bullets will be fired, and only one of the three will walk away. And only in the end is it confirmed for certain who placed the bomb in the car trunk (although the culprit is obvious). Orson Welles was already a giant for his excellent portrayal in "Citizen Kane" (1942), considered by many critics as the greatest movie of all time. Those who feel that Charlton Heston was miscast should be aware that he portrayed various historical figures. They include Moses, Marc Antony, John the Baptist, El Cid, Michelangelo, both Henry VIII and Sir Thomas More (!), Cardinal Richelieu, Lt. William Clark (of Lewis and Clark fame), Thomas Jefferson, Andrew Jackson, Abe Lincoln, Brigham Young, General "Chinese" Gordon, and Buffalo Bill Cody. Heston could pass as a Mexican of European heritage. Vivacious Janet Leigh was already famous; she had starred in "Angels in the Outfield" (1951), "Scaramouche" (1952), and "The Naked Spur" (1953). The last one is considered by Leonard Maltin to be one of the greatest westerns ever made. Psycho would follow (1960), and Manchurian Candidate after that (1962). The greatness of the movie is not its message; in fact, one may even identify several peculiar settings. Those who hate the movie generally dislike the material. But the film's prominence is in HOW the story is told. It is like "Citizen Kane," which has a rather thin plot, but an incredible revelation. Take the hotel room scene where Welles takes Janet Leigh's nylon stocking and wraps it around his fingers. He looks menacingly at Akim Tamiroff while the neon lights flash from outside. It is a hungry lion facing a trapped antelope. Uncle Joe is finished, and he knows it. "Touch of Evil" has high-level technical qualities of expressionist lighting and shadow, low camera angles, wide-angle lens, and dark, brooding photography. The movie has atmosphere in miles. Henry Mancini's dazzling sound track hits the spot (and works very well even in the truncated 95-minute version of the movie). As "Touch of Evil" is recognized by enthusiasts as one of the greatest movies made in world cinema history, it appears on many Top 100 Lists.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    strange gem
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vincentiu
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    a special form of masterpiece. common story. minimalist scenes. but seed of genius. not a surprise - Orson Welles can be himself - but the joy to discover an admirable construction remains. secret - the cast. Marlene Dietrich in a role of few lines who preserves mystery and seduction, Janet Leigh as innocent victim of dark business, Charlton Heston as Charlton Heston and Welles in a role like a fascinating puzzle. it is more than a film. it is not exactly a masterpiece for usual definition. it is a gem. why ? after see it, you may be have an answer. or, only, a sketch about this precise exercise of precision in each of details.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just a touch
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kosmasp
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Orson Welles did have a "magic touch" (no pun intended), although it didn't always translate into commercial success. Which of course had to do with the studios being reluctant giving him the free reign he had on his Citizen Kane classic. There are quite a few versions out there of this movie and we got treated to one of them (close to what Welles imagined at the time as biographer told us) at the Berlin International Festival. When I say close, it does mean that it's as close to what Welles would have wanted in the movie (from the footage that was shot), especially concerning the audio in the beginning. He had a vision in his head and the studio bosses wouldn't always agree with him. Another problem might have been that he himself wasn't always satisfied and would change things. So while the version I saw, was close to a memo he send to the studio (suggesting cuts and especially the audio change in the beginning), he might have changed all that at a later time, if he had the chance (at least he might have written another memo after watching it the way, he wanted it to be). Having said and written all that, the movie has a powerful performance by Charlton Heston as well. Characters reactions to some things might feel dated or clich&eacute;, but that is just because we have seen other films copying some of the working formula that is being used here. B&W it might be, but it still has quite a punch to it ... morally and otherwise
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The best Film Noir & one of the all-time greatest films.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stephen-scott83
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I first watched Touch of Evil I was absolutely astounded. I was mesmerised by Orson and the simply remarkable depth of his character. I rank this movie as the greatest film noir ever made and one of the greatest movies ever made. It's that simple. I watch this movie at least 2-3 times a month. Orson's character, Hank Quinlan is the ultimate crooked, bigot cop. This character is like a monster that no one seems to know how to stop. That's the easy description, the true genius is in the script, mannerisms and camera angles. You could not make this film in color, it wouldn't work. One of my favorite aspects about this movie is the subtle use of sarcasm - especially Quinlan's Sargeant - that leads to the overall mood of arrogance spread out in this amazing movie. This movie requires multiple viewings if you really want to appreciate the stunning script and superlative camera shots/angles. Dennis Weaver's character is in my opinion, one of the most bizarre in movie history especially considering there was no development his hyper-manic oddball character. Truly bizarre - but so entertaining! The cameo by Zsa Zsa Gabor is neat but the extended "cameo" by Marlene Dietrich is stunning. I bought this movie after 1 viewing - safe to say, you will too. Orson, thank you, thank you, thank you for making this CLASSIC!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "You don't have a future."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Red-125
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Touch of Evil (1958), scripted and directed by Orson Welles, is deservedly one of IMDb's top 250 movies. The story of the movie as a movie is almost as dramatic as the plot of the film. Before the editing took place, Welles was removed from the project. He responded with a long, detailed memo about how the film should be edited. This memo was mostly ignored, and an inferior short version of Touch of Evil was released in theaters and later for the small screen. Fortunately, years later, with immense effort, most of the original footage was salvaged, and the film was reconstructed almost in the way Welles had envisioned it. This longer version was what we saw in the excellent--and newly refurbished-- Dryden Theatre at Eastman House in Rochester, NY. The film seems dated today, but it's still powerful and engrossing. Charlton Heston plays Mike Vargas, a high-ranking Mexican police official. He has just married an American, Susan, played by Janet Leigh. They become involved in a murder investigation because someone dies when dynamite is placed in a car in Mexico, but the explosion takes place across the border in the U.S. It's at this point that Vargas has to interact with Police Captain Hank Quinlan, played by Welles. Quinlan is an overweight, limping, unshaven bully. However, he has almost magical powers to detect criminals, who are then invariably convicted. The means he uses in his investigations are not found in a police manual. So, it's clear from the beginning that Vargas wears the white hat and Quinlan wears the black hat. Janet Leigh is wasted in her role as naive and gullible young wife. Heston does a good job as the straight arrow cop. Welles, of course, is perfect for the role of a (really) bad cop. Quinlan has built his whole career based on his larger-than-life personality, and no one in his town is going to try to change his techniques. Welles was born to play this role. Two supporting characters deserve mention: Dennis Weaver as the Mirador Motel Night Manager. He turns in a brilliant performance that combines stupidity, timidity, and rigidity in equal parts. Marlene Dietrich plays Tanya, a former flame of Quinlan's from the days when he was young and handsome. Dietrich--who looks sad, cynical, and very beautiful--delivers the best line of the film. Quinlan asks her to read his future in her Tarot cards. She tells him, "You haven't got any. Your future is all used up." This is a movie worth seeking out and seeing. It will work better on a large screen. However, even in DVD, it's a must-see film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Way He Sees and Lets Us See
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Antti Keisala
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Orson Welles is one director to whom I'm drawn time and again for refreshment and reinvigoration. He's leagues beyond me, and in the words of Fran&ccedil;ois Truffaut, "When you come out of 'Touch of Evil' you feel less intelligent than before but gratified anyhow by the poetry and art."* Yet there are certain things I always know to look for, whether the film in question is "Citizen Kane" (1941), "The Tragedy of Othello: The Moor of Venice" (1952), "Mr. Arkadin" (1955) or "F for Fake" (1973): the narrative is going to be free-flowingly evasive and explorative, always interested not finding out the truth but rather becoming aware of all the layers of fabrication within the narrative; and the way he sees and lets us see the world will be breathtaking. And so it is. His way of moving the camera with absolute effortlessness astonishes each time, so does the lighting of the interiors and the way he shoots claustrophobic closed spaces. Heston and Welles play wonderfully together, and Welles' performance is among the highlights of his career. Dietrich's character refers to Von Sternberg's "Der Blaue Engel" (1930), a satire about a sexual free fall, a strong undersong in this film. The film's production history, as that of many other films by Welles, is closely linked to the film itself. As such, "Touch of Evil" is also rewarding as an artifact of film history. It's interesting to read Welles' 58-page memo (available online) and compare to any of the versions available. Watching them either chronologically or in reverse order is great fun. So is comparing the aspect ratios. The Region B Blu-ray released by the Masters of Cinema series is most certainly at the summit of the format and what can be done with it. On two Blu-rays there are the three existing versions of the film (the 1958 theatrical version, the 1958 preview version and the 1998 reconstructed version), the 1958 theatrical and the 1998 reconstruction presented in two aspect ratios. They are beautiful transfers, and host interesting and informative commentary tracks. I see myself revisiting this, and then revisiting it again. And again. * The review "Touch of Evil", by Fran&ccedil;ois Truffaut, originally published in "Arts" (June 4, 1958), available in the collection "Les films de ma vie" (1975) and translated into English as "The Films of My Life" (1978). I read this review in the booklet of the Masters of Cinema Blu-ray (p. 5).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    holy cow is this a good movie!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    xhearto
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    thrills! chills! Welles! if you feel like you've seen this movie a thousand times upon first viewing, it's probably because almost every moment has been "borrowed" by filmmakers for over half a century. And then copied by people who saw the borrowings. journey to the dark heart of man? Check. Marlene smoking over a crystal ball? Check. Janet terrorized in a motel? Check. Orson at the pinnacle of his game? Check. a shining example of what defines the difference between a film and a "movie" check. top ten list.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Macho Man?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gamay9
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Film noir at its' best....and, what a cast! The only unlikely scene is where Susie (Janet Leigh) is screaming for help from a fire escape and Vargas (Charleton Heston) drives right by, heads for a bar and roughs up the thugs....meanwhile Susie is arrested and jailed. Wouldn't a macho guy like Heston aid his wife first and then confront the thugs? After all, this is 1958 when guys rolled cigarette packs into their t-shirt sleeves. That was a lame scene. One of the actors, Calleia, was the director; not Hitchcock. It would have been easy for Heston to have the script changed to a more likely scenario. Otherwise, I enjoyed the film; anytime one can see Janet Leigh, Charleton Heston, Orson Welles, Marlene Deitrich (dark-haired Mexican) and Dennis Weaver in the same film, it's a blast!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Touch of Evil
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Directed by and starring Orson Welles, I may remember watching the first ten or something minutes of this film but giving up on it, I was certainly up for giving it another chance when I saw it listed and recommended as one of the 1001 Movies You Must See Before You Die in the book. Basically on the border between the United States of America and Mexico a time bomb is planted in the boot of a car, and it is drives to cross the border, and a couple of times newlyweds Ramon Miguel 'Mike' Vargas (Charlton Heston) and Susan 'Susie' (Janet Leigh) pass the vehicle before it crosses, and after doing so it blows up and kills the passengers. Mike works for the Mexican government as a drug enforcement official, and knowing the implications of bombs from Mexico to America exploding he decides to join in any investigation he can, and also looking into it are police Chief Gould (Harry Shannon) and District Attorney Adair (Ray Collins), but also the peculiar Police Captain Hank Quinlan (Orson Welles) and his long time partner Police Sergeant Pete Menzies (Joseph Calleia). Young Mexican man Manelo Sanchez (Victor Millan) is the prime suspect for Quinlan and Menzies, as he was secretly married to the daughter of one of the victims in the explosion, Mike is there during the interrogation, he accidentally knocks over an empty shoebox, and in moments this same box two sticks of dynamite are in it, so Mike suspects Quinlan has been planting evidence to help with his convictions over the years. Although Quinlan denies this Vargas still wants to see his public case records, so Al Schwartz (Mort Mills), the District Attorney's assistant lets him study them, and Gould and Adair are shown the findings as well, but Quinlan himself comes in and threatens resignation in anger over their discussion. There is a risk of the brother of a man Mike was investigating, 'Uncle' Joe Grandi (Akim Tamiroff) trying to expose things, so Susie moves from their Mexican hotel to a motel in America, one that Menzies recommended, staffed by mentally challenged Night Manager (Duel's Dennis Weaver) and with no other guests staying, but family members of Grandi take over the motel. Mike becomes worried when he tries telephoning Susie and she does not answer, in fact Quinlan has arrangement with Grandi that his gang will kidnap her, inject her with drugs and taken to another motel out of town, and indeed this happens, Quinlan murders Grandi and Susie is framed for the murder to give her husband a bad name. Mike goes to have a word with Menzies about the history of the cases he and Quinlan investigating and "found" evidence in, he dismisses any conspiracy he has, and then he goes looking for his wife at the motel but she and her gun have gone, so he goes to the other motel that Grandi owns and confronts his gang, they refuse to answer questions so he beats them up. Schwartz tells him that Susie was arrested for murder, but when he finds her she is barely conscious, and then Menzies comes to tell him that Quinlan's cane was found at the scene of Grandi's murder, so Mike fits him with a wire so he can go to see his partner and hear a conversation between them. At an oil field is where Quinlan and Menzies meet to discuss their activities while Mike records everything, the traitor cop admits he planted evidence on people to make them guiltier than they already were, but the tapping is uncovered by the sound of static. Quinlan knows that Mike is there watching and listening, and in the heat of the moment he shoots Menzies with Vargas's gun, but before he can shoot Mike dead Menzies gets up and shoots Quinlan, Menzies dies and eventually so does Quinlan, Sanchez is revealed to have admitted to the crime of planting the car bomb, and Mike leaves town with a recovered Susie. Also starring Joanna Moore as Marcia Linnekar , Valentin De Vargas as Pancho, Lalo Rios as Risto , Marlene Dietrich as Tanya, Zsa Zsa Gabor as Strip-Club Owner, The Third Man's Joseph Cotten as Coroner and The Exorcist's Mercedes McCambridge as Gang Leader. Heston gives a good performance as the man determined to get to the truth of the matter, Leigh gets her moments as the wife pulled into the situations, but obviously Welles is best part of this film as the treacherous cop with the villainous dark side, and his direction is well paced as well, some supporting cast members, especially Dietrich, are terrific as well. The film opens with one of the most famous long shots in cinema which is played out so well with clever tracking, and the film is filled with interesting material about conspiracy, double-crossing, murder and melodrama, it is one of the last true film noir style pictures, I admit I lost track of plot on occasions, but overall it is a watchable classic crime thriller. Very good!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just a Touch of American Stereotypes
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rexx Villotti
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    During his honeymoon, Mexican police officer Mike Vargas (Charlton Heston) is dragged into a deadly battler with the respected-but- corrupted American Police Captain Hank Quinlan (Orson Welles). While protecting his wife, avoiding prejudice, and trying to uncover the truth, Vargas has more foes to deal with than he thinks. Involving Mexican drug smugglers, kidnappers, and the dimwitted American police force, Quinlan tries to discredit and stop his attempt to uncover the truth. One of the Film Noirs, Orson Welles' "Touch of Evil" is a Mexican border town mystery unlike any other. In other movies with the same setting, "A Fist Full of Dollars" for example, the hero would be an attractive American cowboy and the villain would be a dirty, greedy Mexican. In typical Welles fashion of breaking film norms, he flips the American image of good and evil. The villain, portrayed by Welles himself, is a fat, corrupt American Cop. While Quinlan is the villain, Welles also makes him the victim also. He is a victim of himself, and from the police work that has consumed his life and humanity. Welles intentionally creates these characters to break free from the chains that often bind him and other film directors of the time. There is not a clear cut plot that can be seen and set up in the first few minutes of the film, the viewers are taken from crime scenes to mobster run hotels before they glimpse at the corrupt American police at work. The main plot cannot be set up very easily in this film without the proper introduction to the characters. For example, the viewer must understand why the Grandi mob family wants Vargas dead. Without this knowledge that the film provides in the action leading up to the reveal of police activities, the viewers would be left wondering why the mob family is so eager to be involved in American police business. This complex plot combined with Welles' dynamic and intriguing cinematography creates a thrilling game of wits between American and Mexican police.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dynamite Opening Crane Shot
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    romanorum1
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A shadowy man places a time-bomb in the trunk of a new Chrysler and runs away just before another man and a woman enter and drive off. In the darkness, among the sounds of traffic and seedy strip clubs and gaudy hotels in the Mexican border town of Los Robles, the auto meanders across the border into the USA. We see crumbling arches and peeling walls. For more than three minutes we wonder what will happen. Tick  tick  tick  The Chrysler passes by mustached Charlton Heston (Mike Vargas) and stunning Janet Leigh (Susan Vargas). As Mike stops to kiss his new wife, we hear the explosion, and there is a cut to the burning vehicle. "This could be very bad for us, utters Mike." Vargas, as a police investigator (and Chairman of the Pan-American Narcotics Commission), was returning to Mexico to testify against Vic Grandi's Mexican crime family. As the explosion occurred on the American side of the border, police chief Harry Quinlan (Orson Welles) is called in to investigate. Bloated, stubbly, puffy-faced Quinlan has a history of planting evidence to convict those whom he wants. Sweating, he oozes corruption from every pore. "You're a mess," fortune-teller Tana (Marlene Dietrich) would later tell him. To Quinlan's displeasure, Vargas decides to hang around because of his concern that his native Mexico may be involved in an international incident. He tells his wife to return to the hotel. She gets intercepted by a gang who takes her to "visit" Uncle Joe Grandi (Akim Tamiroff). He warns her to tell her husband to desist from the Grandi trial, or else. The man who died in the car explosion was Rudolph Linnekar, a wealthy contractor; his girl was a blonde night club dancer. Mexican Manelo Sanchez, a shoe clerk, who had been dating Linnekar's daughter Marcia against her father's wishes, is visited by Quinlan. Now Sanchez does not really care for Marcia, but, as he freely admits, likes only her money. Quinlan, who maintains that Sanchez murdered Rudolph Linnekar because the latter disapproved of Sanchez's marriage to Marcia, plants two sticks of dynamite in a box in Sanchez's bathroom. As Vargas knows that Quinlan planted the evidence, he does not abide by the arrest. He decides to gather evidence against him, and begins working with honest assistant DA Schwartz. Meanwhile Susan Vargas is in danger; as her husband had inconceivably left her alone. She moved to the Mirador Motel, which consists of a number of uninhabited cabins in the desert. Neither her husband nor she can imagine that the hotel is owned by Uncle Joe Grandi. She is the only customer, and he has plans for her, as his leather-jacketed gang of thugs often operates from there. Her only shield  and he really is not one  is neurotic Dennis Weaver, the night man. He acts more psycho than Norman Bates, without the latter's murders. Since Quinlan is quickly onto Mike's intention, he is forced to work with Uncle Joe to frame wife Susan as a druggie. So Susan, besieged in her room, is easy prey for the gang. She is drugged and apparently gang-raped while lesbian leader Mercedes McCambridge watches. Then Susan is brought to a different hotel where she lies unconscious while surrounded by drug paraphernalia. Both Uncle Joe and Quinlan arrive there, but Quinlan turns against him and strangles Joe and leaves evidence to implicate Susan. But he inexplicably leaves his cane in the room, which his sergeant, Pete Menzies (Joseph Calleia) later finds. Menzies has been Quinlan's stooge for years, and although he probably could not exist without Quinlan, soon decides to reverse his previous deeds. Before long, Menzies and Vargas are working together to tape record Quinlan admission of his decadence among the pumping oil derricks and garbage heaps at a canal. Bullets will be fired, and only one of the three will walk away. And only in the end is it confirmed for certain who placed the bomb in the car trunk (although the culprit is obvious). Orson Welles was already a giant for his excellent portrayal in "Citizen Kane" (1942), considered by many critics as the greatest movie of all time. Those who feel that Charlton Heston was miscast should be aware that he portrayed various historical figures. They include Moses, Marc Antony, John the Baptist, El Cid, Michelangelo, both Henry VIII and Sir Thomas More (!), Cardinal Richelieu, Lt. William Clark (of Lewis and Clark fame), Thomas Jefferson, Andrew Jackson, Abe Lincoln, Brigham Young, General "Chinese" Gordon, and Buffalo Bill Cody. Heston could pass as a Mexican of European heritage. Vivacious Janet Leigh was already famous; she had starred in "Angels in the Outfield" (1951), "Scaramouche" (1952), and "The Naked Spur" (1953). The last one is considered by Leonard Maltin to be one of the greatest westerns ever made. Psycho would follow (1960), and Manchurian Candidate after that (1962). The greatness of the movie is not its message; in fact, one may even identify several peculiar settings. Those who hate the movie generally dislike the material. But the film's prominence is in HOW the story is told. It is like "Citizen Kane," which has a rather thin plot, but an incredible revelation. Take the hotel room scene where Welles takes Janet Leigh's nylon stocking and wraps it around his fingers. He looks menacingly at Akim Tamiroff while the neon lights flash from outside. It is a hungry lion facing a trapped antelope. Uncle Joe is finished, and he knows it. "Touch of Evil" has high-level technical qualities of expressionist lighting and shadow, low camera angles, wide-angle lens, and dark, brooding photography. The movie has atmosphere in miles. Henry Mancini's dazzling sound track hits the spot (and works very well even in the truncated 95-minute version of the movie). As "Touch of Evil" is recognized by enthusiasts as one of the greatest movies made in world cinema history, it appears on many Top 100 Lists.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    strange gem
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vincentiu
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    a special form of masterpiece. common story. minimalist scenes. but seed of genius. not a surprise - Orson Welles can be himself - but the joy to discover an admirable construction remains. secret - the cast. Marlene Dietrich in a role of few lines who preserves mystery and seduction, Janet Leigh as innocent victim of dark business, Charlton Heston as Charlton Heston and Welles in a role like a fascinating puzzle. it is more than a film. it is not exactly a masterpiece for usual definition. it is a gem. why ? after see it, you may be have an answer. or, only, a sketch about this precise exercise of precision in each of details.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just a touch
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kosmasp
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Orson Welles did have a "magic touch" (no pun intended), although it didn't always translate into commercial success. Which of course had to do with the studios being reluctant giving him the free reign he had on his Citizen Kane classic. There are quite a few versions out there of this movie and we got treated to one of them (close to what Welles imagined at the time as biographer told us) at the Berlin International Festival. When I say close, it does mean that it's as close to what Welles would have wanted in the movie (from the footage that was shot), especially concerning the audio in the beginning. He had a vision in his head and the studio bosses wouldn't always agree with him. Another problem might have been that he himself wasn't always satisfied and would change things. So while the version I saw, was close to a memo he send to the studio (suggesting cuts and especially the audio change in the beginning), he might have changed all that at a later time, if he had the chance (at least he might have written another memo after watching it the way, he wanted it to be). Having said and written all that, the movie has a powerful performance by Charlton Heston as well. Characters reactions to some things might feel dated or clich&eacute;, but that is just because we have seen other films copying some of the working formula that is being used here. B&W it might be, but it still has quite a punch to it ... morally and otherwise
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The best Film Noir & one of the all-time greatest films.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stephen-scott83
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I first watched Touch of Evil I was absolutely astounded. I was mesmerised by Orson and the simply remarkable depth of his character. I rank this movie as the greatest film noir ever made and one of the greatest movies ever made. It's that simple. I watch this movie at least 2-3 times a month. Orson's character, Hank Quinlan is the ultimate crooked, bigot cop. This character is like a monster that no one seems to know how to stop. That's the easy description, the true genius is in the script, mannerisms and camera angles. You could not make this film in color, it wouldn't work. One of my favorite aspects about this movie is the subtle use of sarcasm - especially Quinlan's Sargeant - that leads to the overall mood of arrogance spread out in this amazing movie. This movie requires multiple viewings if you really want to appreciate the stunning script and superlative camera shots/angles. Dennis Weaver's character is in my opinion, one of the most bizarre in movie history especially considering there was no development his hyper-manic oddball character. Truly bizarre - but so entertaining! The cameo by Zsa Zsa Gabor is neat but the extended "cameo" by Marlene Dietrich is stunning. I bought this movie after 1 viewing - safe to say, you will too. Orson, thank you, thank you, thank you for making this CLASSIC!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "You don't have a future."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Red-125
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Touch of Evil (1958), scripted and directed by Orson Welles, is deservedly one of IMDb's top 250 movies. The story of the movie as a movie is almost as dramatic as the plot of the film. Before the editing took place, Welles was removed from the project. He responded with a long, detailed memo about how the film should be edited. This memo was mostly ignored, and an inferior short version of Touch of Evil was released in theaters and later for the small screen. Fortunately, years later, with immense effort, most of the original footage was salvaged, and the film was reconstructed almost in the way Welles had envisioned it. This longer version was what we saw in the excellent--and newly refurbished-- Dryden Theatre at Eastman House in Rochester, NY. The film seems dated today, but it's still powerful and engrossing. Charlton Heston plays Mike Vargas, a high-ranking Mexican police official. He has just married an American, Susan, played by Janet Leigh. They become involved in a murder investigation because someone dies when dynamite is placed in a car in Mexico, but the explosion takes place across the border in the U.S. It's at this point that Vargas has to interact with Police Captain Hank Quinlan, played by Welles. Quinlan is an overweight, limping, unshaven bully. However, he has almost magical powers to detect criminals, who are then invariably convicted. The means he uses in his investigations are not found in a police manual. So, it's clear from the beginning that Vargas wears the white hat and Quinlan wears the black hat. Janet Leigh is wasted in her role as naive and gullible young wife. Heston does a good job as the straight arrow cop. Welles, of course, is perfect for the role of a (really) bad cop. Quinlan has built his whole career based on his larger-than-life personality, and no one in his town is going to try to change his techniques. Welles was born to play this role. Two supporting characters deserve mention: Dennis Weaver as the Mirador Motel Night Manager. He turns in a brilliant performance that combines stupidity, timidity, and rigidity in equal parts. Marlene Dietrich plays Tanya, a former flame of Quinlan's from the days when he was young and handsome. Dietrich--who looks sad, cynical, and very beautiful--delivers the best line of the film. Quinlan asks her to read his future in her Tarot cards. She tells him, "You haven't got any. Your future is all used up." This is a movie worth seeking out and seeing. It will work better on a large screen. However, even in DVD, it's a must-see film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Way He Sees and Lets Us See
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Antti Keisala
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Orson Welles is one director to whom I'm drawn time and again for refreshment and reinvigoration. He's leagues beyond me, and in the words of Fran&ccedil;ois Truffaut, "When you come out of 'Touch of Evil' you feel less intelligent than before but gratified anyhow by the poetry and art."* Yet there are certain things I always know to look for, whether the film in question is "Citizen Kane" (1941), "The Tragedy of Othello: The Moor of Venice" (1952), "Mr. Arkadin" (1955) or "F for Fake" (1973): the narrative is going to be free-flowingly evasive and explorative, always interested not finding out the truth but rather becoming aware of all the layers of fabrication within the narrative; and the way he sees and lets us see the world will be breathtaking. And so it is. His way of moving the camera with absolute effortlessness astonishes each time, so does the lighting of the interiors and the way he shoots claustrophobic closed spaces. Heston and Welles play wonderfully together, and Welles' performance is among the highlights of his career. Dietrich's character refers to Von Sternberg's "Der Blaue Engel" (1930), a satire about a sexual free fall, a strong undersong in this film. The film's production history, as that of many other films by Welles, is closely linked to the film itself. As such, "Touch of Evil" is also rewarding as an artifact of film history. It's interesting to read Welles' 58-page memo (available online) and compare to any of the versions available. Watching them either chronologically or in reverse order is great fun. So is comparing the aspect ratios. The Region B Blu-ray released by the Masters of Cinema series is most certainly at the summit of the format and what can be done with it. On two Blu-rays there are the three existing versions of the film (the 1958 theatrical version, the 1958 preview version and the 1998 reconstructed version), the 1958 theatrical and the 1998 reconstruction presented in two aspect ratios. They are beautiful transfers, and host interesting and informative commentary tracks. I see myself revisiting this, and then revisiting it again. And again. * The review "Touch of Evil", by Fran&ccedil;ois Truffaut, originally published in "Arts" (June 4, 1958), available in the collection "Les films de ma vie" (1975) and translated into English as "The Films of My Life" (1978). I read this review in the booklet of the Masters of Cinema Blu-ray (p. 5).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    holy cow is this a good movie!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    xhearto
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    thrills! chills! Welles! if you feel like you've seen this movie a thousand times upon first viewing, it's probably because almost every moment has been "borrowed" by filmmakers for over half a century. And then copied by people who saw the borrowings. journey to the dark heart of man? Check. Marlene smoking over a crystal ball? Check. Janet terrorized in a motel? Check. Orson at the pinnacle of his game? Check. a shining example of what defines the difference between a film and a "movie" check. top ten list.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Macho Man?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gamay9
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Film noir at its' best....and, what a cast! The only unlikely scene is where Susie (Janet Leigh) is screaming for help from a fire escape and Vargas (Charleton Heston) drives right by, heads for a bar and roughs up the thugs....meanwhile Susie is arrested and jailed. Wouldn't a macho guy like Heston aid his wife first and then confront the thugs? After all, this is 1958 when guys rolled cigarette packs into their t-shirt sleeves. That was a lame scene. One of the actors, Calleia, was the director; not Hitchcock. It would have been easy for Heston to have the script changed to a more likely scenario. Otherwise, I enjoyed the film; anytime one can see Janet Leigh, Charleton Heston, Orson Welles, Marlene Deitrich (dark-haired Mexican) and Dennis Weaver in the same film, it's a blast!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Touch of Evil
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Directed by and starring Orson Welles, I may remember watching the first ten or something minutes of this film but giving up on it, I was certainly up for giving it another chance when I saw it listed and recommended as one of the 1001 Movies You Must See Before You Die in the book. Basically on the border between the United States of America and Mexico a time bomb is planted in the boot of a car, and it is drives to cross the border, and a couple of times newlyweds Ramon Miguel 'Mike' Vargas (Charlton Heston) and Susan 'Susie' (Janet Leigh) pass the vehicle before it crosses, and after doing so it blows up and kills the passengers. Mike works for the Mexican government as a drug enforcement official, and knowing the implications of bombs from Mexico to America exploding he decides to join in any investigation he can, and also looking into it are police Chief Gould (Harry Shannon) and District Attorney Adair (Ray Collins), but also the peculiar Police Captain Hank Quinlan (Orson Welles) and his long time partner Police Sergeant Pete Menzies (Joseph Calleia). Young Mexican man Manelo Sanchez (Victor Millan) is the prime suspect for Quinlan and Menzies, as he was secretly married to the daughter of one of the victims in the explosion, Mike is there during the interrogation, he accidentally knocks over an empty shoebox, and in moments this same box two sticks of dynamite are in it, so Mike suspects Quinlan has been planting evidence to help with his convictions over the years. Although Quinlan denies this Vargas still wants to see his public case records, so Al Schwartz (Mort Mills), the District Attorney's assistant lets him study them, and Gould and Adair are shown the findings as well, but Quinlan himself comes in and threatens resignation in anger over their discussion. There is a risk of the brother of a man Mike was investigating, 'Uncle' Joe Grandi (Akim Tamiroff) trying to expose things, so Susie moves from their Mexican hotel to a motel in America, one that Menzies recommended, staffed by mentally challenged Night Manager (Duel's Dennis Weaver) and with no other guests staying, but family members of Grandi take over the motel. Mike becomes worried when he tries telephoning Susie and she does not answer, in fact Quinlan has arrangement with Grandi that his gang will kidnap her, inject her with drugs and taken to another motel out of town, and indeed this happens, Quinlan murders Grandi and Susie is framed for the murder to give her husband a bad name. Mike goes to have a word with Menzies about the history of the cases he and Quinlan investigating and "found" evidence in, he dismisses any conspiracy he has, and then he goes looking for his wife at the motel but she and her gun have gone, so he goes to the other motel that Grandi owns and confronts his gang, they refuse to answer questions so he beats them up. Schwartz tells him that Susie was arrested for murder, but when he finds her she is barely conscious, and then Menzies comes to tell him that Quinlan's cane was found at the scene of Grandi's murder, so Mike fits him with a wire so he can go to see his partner and hear a conversation between them. At an oil field is where Quinlan and Menzies meet to discuss their activities while Mike records everything, the traitor cop admits he planted evidence on people to make them guiltier than they already were, but the tapping is uncovered by the sound of static. Quinlan knows that Mike is there watching and listening, and in the heat of the moment he shoots Menzies with Vargas's gun, but before he can shoot Mike dead Menzies gets up and shoots Quinlan, Menzies dies and eventually so does Quinlan, Sanchez is revealed to have admitted to the crime of planting the car bomb, and Mike leaves town with a recovered Susie. Also starring Joanna Moore as Marcia Linnekar , Valentin De Vargas as Pancho, Lalo Rios as Risto , Marlene Dietrich as Tanya, Zsa Zsa Gabor as Strip-Club Owner, The Third Man's Joseph Cotten as Coroner and The Exorcist's Mercedes McCambridge as Gang Leader. Heston gives a good performance as the man determined to get to the truth of the matter, Leigh gets her moments as the wife pulled into the situations, but obviously Welles is best part of this film as the treacherous cop with the villainous dark side, and his direction is well paced as well, some supporting cast members, especially Dietrich, are terrific as well. The film opens with one of the most famous long shots in cinema which is played out so well with clever tracking, and the film is filled with interesting material about conspiracy, double-crossing, murder and melodrama, it is one of the last true film noir style pictures, I admit I lost track of plot on occasions, but overall it is a watchable classic crime thriller. Very good!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just a Touch of American Stereotypes
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rexx Villotti
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    During his honeymoon, Mexican police officer Mike Vargas (Charlton Heston) is dragged into a deadly battler with the respected-but- corrupted American Police Captain Hank Quinlan (Orson Welles). While protecting his wife, avoiding prejudice, and trying to uncover the truth, Vargas has more foes to deal with than he thinks. Involving Mexican drug smugglers, kidnappers, and the dimwitted American police force, Quinlan tries to discredit and stop his attempt to uncover the truth. One of the Film Noirs, Orson Welles' "Touch of Evil" is a Mexican border town mystery unlike any other. In other movies with the same setting, "A Fist Full of Dollars" for example, the hero would be an attractive American cowboy and the villain would be a dirty, greedy Mexican. In typical Welles fashion of breaking film norms, he flips the American image of good and evil. The villain, portrayed by Welles himself, is a fat, corrupt American Cop. While Quinlan is the villain, Welles also makes him the victim also. He is a victim of himself, and from the police work that has consumed his life and humanity. Welles intentionally creates these characters to break free from the chains that often bind him and other film directors of the time. There is not a clear cut plot that can be seen and set up in the first few minutes of the film, the viewers are taken from crime scenes to mobster run hotels before they glimpse at the corrupt American police at work. The main plot cannot be set up very easily in this film without the proper introduction to the characters. For example, the viewer must understand why the Grandi mob family wants Vargas dead. Without this knowledge that the film provides in the action leading up to the reveal of police activities, the viewers would be left wondering why the mob family is so eager to be involved in American police business. This complex plot combined with Welles' dynamic and intriguing cinematography creates a thrilling game of wits between American and Mexican police.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dynamite Opening Crane Shot
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    romanorum1
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A shadowy man places a time-bomb in the trunk of a new Chrysler and runs away just before another man and a woman enter and drive off. In the darkness, among the sounds of traffic and seedy strip clubs and gaudy hotels in the Mexican border town of Los Robles, the auto meanders across the border into the USA. We see crumbling arches and peeling walls. For more than three minutes we wonder what will happen. Tick  tick  tick  The Chrysler passes by mustached Charlton Heston (Mike Vargas) and stunning Janet Leigh (Susan Vargas). As Mike stops to kiss his new wife, we hear the explosion, and there is a cut to the burning vehicle. "This could be very bad for us, utters Mike." Vargas, as a police investigator (and Chairman of the Pan-American Narcotics Commission), was returning to Mexico to testify against Vic Grandi's Mexican crime family. As the explosion occurred on the American side of the border, police chief Harry Quinlan (Orson Welles) is called in to investigate. Bloated, stubbly, puffy-faced Quinlan has a history of planting evidence to convict those whom he wants. Sweating, he oozes corruption from every pore. "You're a mess," fortune-teller Tana (Marlene Dietrich) would later tell him. To Quinlan's displeasure, Vargas decides to hang around because of his concern that his native Mexico may be involved in an international incident. He tells his wife to return to the hotel. She gets intercepted by a gang who takes her to "visit" Uncle Joe Grandi (Akim Tamiroff). He warns her to tell her husband to desist from the Grandi trial, or else. The man who died in the car explosion was Rudolph Linnekar, a wealthy contractor; his girl was a blonde night club dancer. Mexican Manelo Sanchez, a shoe clerk, who had been dating Linnekar's daughter Marcia against her father's wishes, is visited by Quinlan. Now Sanchez does not really care for Marcia, but, as he freely admits, likes only her money. Quinlan, who maintains that Sanchez murdered Rudolph Linnekar because the latter disapproved of Sanchez's marriage to Marcia, plants two sticks of dynamite in a box in Sanchez's bathroom. As Vargas knows that Quinlan planted the evidence, he does not abide by the arrest. He decides to gather evidence against him, and begins working with honest assistant DA Schwartz. Meanwhile Susan Vargas is in danger; as her husband had inconceivably left her alone. She moved to the Mirador Motel, which consists of a number of uninhabited cabins in the desert. Neither her husband nor she can imagine that the hotel is owned by Uncle Joe Grandi. She is the only customer, and he has plans for her, as his leather-jacketed gang of thugs often operates from there. Her only shield  and he really is not one  is neurotic Dennis Weaver, the night man. He acts more psycho than Norman Bates, without the latter's murders. Since Quinlan is quickly onto Mike's intention, he is forced to work with Uncle Joe to frame wife Susan as a druggie. So Susan, besieged in her room, is easy prey for the gang. She is drugged and apparently gang-raped while lesbian leader Mercedes McCambridge watches. Then Susan is brought to a different hotel where she lies unconscious while surrounded by drug paraphernalia. Both Uncle Joe and Quinlan arrive there, but Quinlan turns against him and strangles Joe and leaves evidence to implicate Susan. But he inexplicably leaves his cane in the room, which his sergeant, Pete Menzies (Joseph Calleia) later finds. Menzies has been Quinlan's stooge for years, and although he probably could not exist without Quinlan, soon decides to reverse his previous deeds. Before long, Menzies and Vargas are working together to tape record Quinlan admission of his decadence among the pumping oil derricks and garbage heaps at a canal. Bullets will be fired, and only one of the three will walk away. And only in the end is it confirmed for certain who placed the bomb in the car trunk (although the culprit is obvious). Orson Welles was already a giant for his excellent portrayal in "Citizen Kane" (1942), considered by many critics as the greatest movie of all time. Those who feel that Charlton Heston was miscast should be aware that he portrayed various historical figures. They include Moses, Marc Antony, John the Baptist, El Cid, Michelangelo, both Henry VIII and Sir Thomas More (!), Cardinal Richelieu, Lt. William Clark (of Lewis and Clark fame), Thomas Jefferson, Andrew Jackson, Abe Lincoln, Brigham Young, General "Chinese" Gordon, and Buffalo Bill Cody. Heston could pass as a Mexican of European heritage. Vivacious Janet Leigh was already famous; she had starred in "Angels in the Outfield" (1951), "Scaramouche" (1952), and "The Naked Spur" (1953). The last one is considered by Leonard Maltin to be one of the greatest westerns ever made. Psycho would follow (1960), and Manchurian Candidate after that (1962). The greatness of the movie is not its message; in fact, one may even identify several peculiar settings. Those who hate the movie generally dislike the material. But the film's prominence is in HOW the story is told. It is like "Citizen Kane," which has a rather thin plot, but an incredible revelation. Take the hotel room scene where Welles takes Janet Leigh's nylon stocking and wraps it around his fingers. He looks menacingly at Akim Tamiroff while the neon lights flash from outside. It is a hungry lion facing a trapped antelope. Uncle Joe is finished, and he knows it. "Touch of Evil" has high-level technical qualities of expressionist lighting and shadow, low camera angles, wide-angle lens, and dark, brooding photography. The movie has atmosphere in miles. Henry Mancini's dazzling sound track hits the spot (and works very well even in the truncated 95-minute version of the movie). As "Touch of Evil" is recognized by enthusiasts as one of the greatest movies made in world cinema history, it appears on many Top 100 Lists.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    strange gem
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vincentiu
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    a special form of masterpiece. common story. minimalist scenes. but seed of genius. not a surprise - Orson Welles can be himself - but the joy to discover an admirable construction remains. secret - the cast. Marlene Dietrich in a role of few lines who preserves mystery and seduction, Janet Leigh as innocent victim of dark business, Charlton Heston as Charlton Heston and Welles in a role like a fascinating puzzle. it is more than a film. it is not exactly a masterpiece for usual definition. it is a gem. why ? after see it, you may be have an answer. or, only, a sketch about this precise exercise of precision in each of details.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just a touch
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kosmasp
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Orson Welles did have a "magic touch" (no pun intended), although it didn't always translate into commercial success. Which of course had to do with the studios being reluctant giving him the free reign he had on his Citizen Kane classic. There are quite a few versions out there of this movie and we got treated to one of them (close to what Welles imagined at the time as biographer told us) at the Berlin International Festival. When I say close, it does mean that it's as close to what Welles would have wanted in the movie (from the footage that was shot), especially concerning the audio in the beginning. He had a vision in his head and the studio bosses wouldn't always agree with him. Another problem might have been that he himself wasn't always satisfied and would change things. So while the version I saw, was close to a memo he send to the studio (suggesting cuts and especially the audio change in the beginning), he might have changed all that at a later time, if he had the chance (at least he might have written another memo after watching it the way, he wanted it to be). Having said and written all that, the movie has a powerful performance by Charlton Heston as well. Characters reactions to some things might feel dated or clich&eacute;, but that is just because we have seen other films copying some of the working formula that is being used here. B&W it might be, but it still has quite a punch to it ... morally and otherwise
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The best Film Noir & one of the all-time greatest films.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stephen-scott83
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I first watched Touch of Evil I was absolutely astounded. I was mesmerised by Orson and the simply remarkable depth of his character. I rank this movie as the greatest film noir ever made and one of the greatest movies ever made. It's that simple. I watch this movie at least 2-3 times a month. Orson's character, Hank Quinlan is the ultimate crooked, bigot cop. This character is like a monster that no one seems to know how to stop. That's the easy description, the true genius is in the script, mannerisms and camera angles. You could not make this film in color, it wouldn't work. One of my favorite aspects about this movie is the subtle use of sarcasm - especially Quinlan's Sargeant - that leads to the overall mood of arrogance spread out in this amazing movie. This movie requires multiple viewings if you really want to appreciate the stunning script and superlative camera shots/angles. Dennis Weaver's character is in my opinion, one of the most bizarre in movie history especially considering there was no development his hyper-manic oddball character. Truly bizarre - but so entertaining! The cameo by Zsa Zsa Gabor is neat but the extended "cameo" by Marlene Dietrich is stunning. I bought this movie after 1 viewing - safe to say, you will too. Orson, thank you, thank you, thank you for making this CLASSIC!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "You don't have a future."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Red-125
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Touch of Evil (1958), scripted and directed by Orson Welles, is deservedly one of IMDb's top 250 movies. The story of the movie as a movie is almost as dramatic as the plot of the film. Before the editing took place, Welles was removed from the project. He responded with a long, detailed memo about how the film should be edited. This memo was mostly ignored, and an inferior short version of Touch of Evil was released in theaters and later for the small screen. Fortunately, years later, with immense effort, most of the original footage was salvaged, and the film was reconstructed almost in the way Welles had envisioned it. This longer version was what we saw in the excellent--and newly refurbished-- Dryden Theatre at Eastman House in Rochester, NY. The film seems dated today, but it's still powerful and engrossing. Charlton Heston plays Mike Vargas, a high-ranking Mexican police official. He has just married an American, Susan, played by Janet Leigh. They become involved in a murder investigation because someone dies when dynamite is placed in a car in Mexico, but the explosion takes place across the border in the U.S. It's at this point that Vargas has to interact with Police Captain Hank Quinlan, played by Welles. Quinlan is an overweight, limping, unshaven bully. However, he has almost magical powers to detect criminals, who are then invariably convicted. The means he uses in his investigations are not found in a police manual. So, it's clear from the beginning that Vargas wears the white hat and Quinlan wears the black hat. Janet Leigh is wasted in her role as naive and gullible young wife. Heston does a good job as the straight arrow cop. Welles, of course, is perfect for the role of a (really) bad cop. Quinlan has built his whole career based on his larger-than-life personality, and no one in his town is going to try to change his techniques. Welles was born to play this role. Two supporting characters deserve mention: Dennis Weaver as the Mirador Motel Night Manager. He turns in a brilliant performance that combines stupidity, timidity, and rigidity in equal parts. Marlene Dietrich plays Tanya, a former flame of Quinlan's from the days when he was young and handsome. Dietrich--who looks sad, cynical, and very beautiful--delivers the best line of the film. Quinlan asks her to read his future in her Tarot cards. She tells him, "You haven't got any. Your future is all used up." This is a movie worth seeking out and seeing. It will work better on a large screen. However, even in DVD, it's a must-see film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Way He Sees and Lets Us See
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Antti Keisala
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Orson Welles is one director to whom I'm drawn time and again for refreshment and reinvigoration. He's leagues beyond me, and in the words of Fran&ccedil;ois Truffaut, "When you come out of 'Touch of Evil' you feel less intelligent than before but gratified anyhow by the poetry and art."* Yet there are certain things I always know to look for, whether the film in question is "Citizen Kane" (1941), "The Tragedy of Othello: The Moor of Venice" (1952), "Mr. Arkadin" (1955) or "F for Fake" (1973): the narrative is going to be free-flowingly evasive and explorative, always interested not finding out the truth but rather becoming aware of all the layers of fabrication within the narrative; and the way he sees and lets us see the world will be breathtaking. And so it is. His way of moving the camera with absolute effortlessness astonishes each time, so does the lighting of the interiors and the way he shoots claustrophobic closed spaces. Heston and Welles play wonderfully together, and Welles' performance is among the highlights of his career. Dietrich's character refers to Von Sternberg's "Der Blaue Engel" (1930), a satire about a sexual free fall, a strong undersong in this film. The film's production history, as that of many other films by Welles, is closely linked to the film itself. As such, "Touch of Evil" is also rewarding as an artifact of film history. It's interesting to read Welles' 58-page memo (available online) and compare to any of the versions available. Watching them either chronologically or in reverse order is great fun. So is comparing the aspect ratios. The Region B Blu-ray released by the Masters of Cinema series is most certainly at the summit of the format and what can be done with it. On two Blu-rays there are the three existing versions of the film (the 1958 theatrical version, the 1958 preview version and the 1998 reconstructed version), the 1958 theatrical and the 1998 reconstruction presented in two aspect ratios. They are beautiful transfers, and host interesting and informative commentary tracks. I see myself revisiting this, and then revisiting it again. And again. * The review "Touch of Evil", by Fran&ccedil;ois Truffaut, originally published in "Arts" (June 4, 1958), available in the collection "Les films de ma vie" (1975) and translated into English as "The Films of My Life" (1978). I read this review in the booklet of the Masters of Cinema Blu-ray (p. 5).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    holy cow is this a good movie!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    xhearto
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    thrills! chills! Welles! if you feel like you've seen this movie a thousand times upon first viewing, it's probably because almost every moment has been "borrowed" by filmmakers for over half a century. And then copied by people who saw the borrowings. journey to the dark heart of man? Check. Marlene smoking over a crystal ball? Check. Janet terrorized in a motel? Check. Orson at the pinnacle of his game? Check. a shining example of what defines the difference between a film and a "movie" check. top ten list.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Macho Man?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gamay9
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Film noir at its' best....and, what a cast! The only unlikely scene is where Susie (Janet Leigh) is screaming for help from a fire escape and Vargas (Charleton Heston) drives right by, heads for a bar and roughs up the thugs....meanwhile Susie is arrested and jailed. Wouldn't a macho guy like Heston aid his wife first and then confront the thugs? After all, this is 1958 when guys rolled cigarette packs into their t-shirt sleeves. That was a lame scene. One of the actors, Calleia, was the director; not Hitchcock. It would have been easy for Heston to have the script changed to a more likely scenario. Otherwise, I enjoyed the film; anytime one can see Janet Leigh, Charleton Heston, Orson Welles, Marlene Deitrich (dark-haired Mexican) and Dennis Weaver in the same film, it's a blast!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Touch of Evil
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Directed by and starring Orson Welles, I may remember watching the first ten or something minutes of this film but giving up on it, I was certainly up for giving it another chance when I saw it listed and recommended as one of the 1001 Movies You Must See Before You Die in the book. Basically on the border between the United States of America and Mexico a time bomb is planted in the boot of a car, and it is drives to cross the border, and a couple of times newlyweds Ramon Miguel 'Mike' Vargas (Charlton Heston) and Susan 'Susie' (Janet Leigh) pass the vehicle before it crosses, and after doing so it blows up and kills the passengers. Mike works for the Mexican government as a drug enforcement official, and knowing the implications of bombs from Mexico to America exploding he decides to join in any investigation he can, and also looking into it are police Chief Gould (Harry Shannon) and District Attorney Adair (Ray Collins), but also the peculiar Police Captain Hank Quinlan (Orson Welles) and his long time partner Police Sergeant Pete Menzies (Joseph Calleia). Young Mexican man Manelo Sanchez (Victor Millan) is the prime suspect for Quinlan and Menzies, as he was secretly married to the daughter of one of the victims in the explosion, Mike is there during the interrogation, he accidentally knocks over an empty shoebox, and in moments this same box two sticks of dynamite are in it, so Mike suspects Quinlan has been planting evidence to help with his convictions over the years. Although Quinlan denies this Vargas still wants to see his public case records, so Al Schwartz (Mort Mills), the District Attorney's assistant lets him study them, and Gould and Adair are shown the findings as well, but Quinlan himself comes in and threatens resignation in anger over their discussion. There is a risk of the brother of a man Mike was investigating, 'Uncle' Joe Grandi (Akim Tamiroff) trying to expose things, so Susie moves from their Mexican hotel to a motel in America, one that Menzies recommended, staffed by mentally challenged Night Manager (Duel's Dennis Weaver) and with no other guests staying, but family members of Grandi take over the motel. Mike becomes worried when he tries telephoning Susie and she does not answer, in fact Quinlan has arrangement with Grandi that his gang will kidnap her, inject her with drugs and taken to another motel out of town, and indeed this happens, Quinlan murders Grandi and Susie is framed for the murder to give her husband a bad name. Mike goes to have a word with Menzies about the history of the cases he and Quinlan investigating and "found" evidence in, he dismisses any conspiracy he has, and then he goes looking for his wife at the motel but she and her gun have gone, so he goes to the other motel that Grandi owns and confronts his gang, they refuse to answer questions so he beats them up. Schwartz tells him that Susie was arrested for murder, but when he finds her she is barely conscious, and then Menzies comes to tell him that Quinlan's cane was found at the scene of Grandi's murder, so Mike fits him with a wire so he can go to see his partner and hear a conversation between them. At an oil field is where Quinlan and Menzies meet to discuss their activities while Mike records everything, the traitor cop admits he planted evidence on people to make them guiltier than they already were, but the tapping is uncovered by the sound of static. Quinlan knows that Mike is there watching and listening, and in the heat of the moment he shoots Menzies with Vargas's gun, but before he can shoot Mike dead Menzies gets up and shoots Quinlan, Menzies dies and eventually so does Quinlan, Sanchez is revealed to have admitted to the crime of planting the car bomb, and Mike leaves town with a recovered Susie. Also starring Joanna Moore as Marcia Linnekar , Valentin De Vargas as Pancho, Lalo Rios as Risto , Marlene Dietrich as Tanya, Zsa Zsa Gabor as Strip-Club Owner, The Third Man's Joseph Cotten as Coroner and The Exorcist's Mercedes McCambridge as Gang Leader. Heston gives a good performance as the man determined to get to the truth of the matter, Leigh gets her moments as the wife pulled into the situations, but obviously Welles is best part of this film as the treacherous cop with the villainous dark side, and his direction is well paced as well, some supporting cast members, especially Dietrich, are terrific as well. The film opens with one of the most famous long shots in cinema which is played out so well with clever tracking, and the film is filled with interesting material about conspiracy, double-crossing, murder and melodrama, it is one of the last true film noir style pictures, I admit I lost track of plot on occasions, but overall it is a watchable classic crime thriller. Very good!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just a Touch of American Stereotypes
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rexx Villotti
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    During his honeymoon, Mexican police officer Mike Vargas (Charlton Heston) is dragged into a deadly battler with the respected-but- corrupted American Police Captain Hank Quinlan (Orson Welles). While protecting his wife, avoiding prejudice, and trying to uncover the truth, Vargas has more foes to deal with than he thinks. Involving Mexican drug smugglers, kidnappers, and the dimwitted American police force, Quinlan tries to discredit and stop his attempt to uncover the truth. One of the Film Noirs, Orson Welles' "Touch of Evil" is a Mexican border town mystery unlike any other. In other movies with the same setting, "A Fist Full of Dollars" for example, the hero would be an attractive American cowboy and the villain would be a dirty, greedy Mexican. In typical Welles fashion of breaking film norms, he flips the American image of good and evil. The villain, portrayed by Welles himself, is a fat, corrupt American Cop. While Quinlan is the villain, Welles also makes him the victim also. He is a victim of himself, and from the police work that has consumed his life and humanity. Welles intentionally creates these characters to break free from the chains that often bind him and other film directors of the time. There is not a clear cut plot that can be seen and set up in the first few minutes of the film, the viewers are taken from crime scenes to mobster run hotels before they glimpse at the corrupt American police at work. The main plot cannot be set up very easily in this film without the proper introduction to the characters. For example, the viewer must understand why the Grandi mob family wants Vargas dead. Without this knowledge that the film provides in the action leading up to the reveal of police activities, the viewers would be left wondering why the mob family is so eager to be involved in American police business. This complex plot combined with Welles' dynamic and intriguing cinematography creates a thrilling game of wits between American and Mexican police.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dynamite Opening Crane Shot
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    romanorum1
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A shadowy man places a time-bomb in the trunk of a new Chrysler and runs away just before another man and a woman enter and drive off. In the darkness, among the sounds of traffic and seedy strip clubs and gaudy hotels in the Mexican border town of Los Robles, the auto meanders across the border into the USA. We see crumbling arches and peeling walls. For more than three minutes we wonder what will happen. Tick  tick  tick  The Chrysler passes by mustached Charlton Heston (Mike Vargas) and stunning Janet Leigh (Susan Vargas). As Mike stops to kiss his new wife, we hear the explosion, and there is a cut to the burning vehicle. "This could be very bad for us, utters Mike." Vargas, as a police investigator (and Chairman of the Pan-American Narcotics Commission), was returning to Mexico to testify against Vic Grandi's Mexican crime family. As the explosion occurred on the American side of the border, police chief Harry Quinlan (Orson Welles) is called in to investigate. Bloated, stubbly, puffy-faced Quinlan has a history of planting evidence to convict those whom he wants. Sweating, he oozes corruption from every pore. "You're a mess," fortune-teller Tana (Marlene Dietrich) would later tell him. To Quinlan's displeasure, Vargas decides to hang around because of his concern that his native Mexico may be involved in an international incident. He tells his wife to return to the hotel. She gets intercepted by a gang who takes her to "visit" Uncle Joe Grandi (Akim Tamiroff). He warns her to tell her husband to desist from the Grandi trial, or else. The man who died in the car explosion was Rudolph Linnekar, a wealthy contractor; his girl was a blonde night club dancer. Mexican Manelo Sanchez, a shoe clerk, who had been dating Linnekar's daughter Marcia against her father's wishes, is visited by Quinlan. Now Sanchez does not really care for Marcia, but, as he freely admits, likes only her money. Quinlan, who maintains that Sanchez murdered Rudolph Linnekar because the latter disapproved of Sanchez's marriage to Marcia, plants two sticks of dynamite in a box in Sanchez's bathroom. As Vargas knows that Quinlan planted the evidence, he does not abide by the arrest. He decides to gather evidence against him, and begins working with honest assistant DA Schwartz. Meanwhile Susan Vargas is in danger; as her husband had inconceivably left her alone. She moved to the Mirador Motel, which consists of a number of uninhabited cabins in the desert. Neither her husband nor she can imagine that the hotel is owned by Uncle Joe Grandi. She is the only customer, and he has plans for her, as his leather-jacketed gang of thugs often operates from there. Her only shield  and he really is not one  is neurotic Dennis Weaver, the night man. He acts more psycho than Norman Bates, without the latter's murders. Since Quinlan is quickly onto Mike's intention, he is forced to work with Uncle Joe to frame wife Susan as a druggie. So Susan, besieged in her room, is easy prey for the gang. She is drugged and apparently gang-raped while lesbian leader Mercedes McCambridge watches. Then Susan is brought to a different hotel where she lies unconscious while surrounded by drug paraphernalia. Both Uncle Joe and Quinlan arrive there, but Quinlan turns against him and strangles Joe and leaves evidence to implicate Susan. But he inexplicably leaves his cane in the room, which his sergeant, Pete Menzies (Joseph Calleia) later finds. Menzies has been Quinlan's stooge for years, and although he probably could not exist without Quinlan, soon decides to reverse his previous deeds. Before long, Menzies and Vargas are working together to tape record Quinlan admission of his decadence among the pumping oil derricks and garbage heaps at a canal. Bullets will be fired, and only one of the three will walk away. And only in the end is it confirmed for certain who placed the bomb in the car trunk (although the culprit is obvious). Orson Welles was already a giant for his excellent portrayal in "Citizen Kane" (1942), considered by many critics as the greatest movie of all time. Those who feel that Charlton Heston was miscast should be aware that he portrayed various historical figures. They include Moses, Marc Antony, John the Baptist, El Cid, Michelangelo, both Henry VIII and Sir Thomas More (!), Cardinal Richelieu, Lt. William Clark (of Lewis and Clark fame), Thomas Jefferson, Andrew Jackson, Abe Lincoln, Brigham Young, General "Chinese" Gordon, and Buffalo Bill Cody. Heston could pass as a Mexican of European heritage. Vivacious Janet Leigh was already famous; she had starred in "Angels in the Outfield" (1951), "Scaramouche" (1952), and "The Naked Spur" (1953). The last one is considered by Leonard Maltin to be one of the greatest westerns ever made. Psycho would follow (1960), and Manchurian Candidate after that (1962). The greatness of the movie is not its message; in fact, one may even identify several peculiar settings. Those who hate the movie generally dislike the material. But the film's prominence is in HOW the story is told. It is like "Citizen Kane," which has a rather thin plot, but an incredible revelation. Take the hotel room scene where Welles takes Janet Leigh's nylon stocking and wraps it around his fingers. He looks menacingly at Akim Tamiroff while the neon lights flash from outside. It is a hungry lion facing a trapped antelope. Uncle Joe is finished, and he knows it. "Touch of Evil" has high-level technical qualities of expressionist lighting and shadow, low camera angles, wide-angle lens, and dark, brooding photography. The movie has atmosphere in miles. Henry Mancini's dazzling sound track hits the spot (and works very well even in the truncated 95-minute version of the movie). As "Touch of Evil" is recognized by enthusiasts as one of the greatest movies made in world cinema history, it appears on many Top 100 Lists.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    strange gem
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vincentiu
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    a special form of masterpiece. common story. minimalist scenes. but seed of genius. not a surprise - Orson Welles can be himself - but the joy to discover an admirable construction remains. secret - the cast. Marlene Dietrich in a role of few lines who preserves mystery and seduction, Janet Leigh as innocent victim of dark business, Charlton Heston as Charlton Heston and Welles in a role like a fascinating puzzle. it is more than a film. it is not exactly a masterpiece for usual definition. it is a gem. why ? after see it, you may be have an answer. or, only, a sketch about this precise exercise of precision in each of details.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just a touch
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kosmasp
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Orson Welles did have a "magic touch" (no pun intended), although it didn't always translate into commercial success. Which of course had to do with the studios being reluctant giving him the free reign he had on his Citizen Kane classic. There are quite a few versions out there of this movie and we got treated to one of them (close to what Welles imagined at the time as biographer told us) at the Berlin International Festival. When I say close, it does mean that it's as close to what Welles would have wanted in the movie (from the footage that was shot), especially concerning the audio in the beginning. He had a vision in his head and the studio bosses wouldn't always agree with him. Another problem might have been that he himself wasn't always satisfied and would change things. So while the version I saw, was close to a memo he send to the studio (suggesting cuts and especially the audio change in the beginning), he might have changed all that at a later time, if he had the chance (at least he might have written another memo after watching it the way, he wanted it to be). Having said and written all that, the movie has a powerful performance by Charlton Heston as well. Characters reactions to some things might feel dated or clich&eacute;, but that is just because we have seen other films copying some of the working formula that is being used here. B&W it might be, but it still has quite a punch to it ... morally and otherwise
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The best Film Noir & one of the all-time greatest films.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stephen-scott83
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I first watched Touch of Evil I was absolutely astounded. I was mesmerised by Orson and the simply remarkable depth of his character. I rank this movie as the greatest film noir ever made and one of the greatest movies ever made. It's that simple. I watch this movie at least 2-3 times a month. Orson's character, Hank Quinlan is the ultimate crooked, bigot cop. This character is like a monster that no one seems to know how to stop. That's the easy description, the true genius is in the script, mannerisms and camera angles. You could not make this film in color, it wouldn't work. One of my favorite aspects about this movie is the subtle use of sarcasm - especially Quinlan's Sargeant - that leads to the overall mood of arrogance spread out in this amazing movie. This movie requires multiple viewings if you really want to appreciate the stunning script and superlative camera shots/angles. Dennis Weaver's character is in my opinion, one of the most bizarre in movie history especially considering there was no development his hyper-manic oddball character. Truly bizarre - but so entertaining! The cameo by Zsa Zsa Gabor is neat but the extended "cameo" by Marlene Dietrich is stunning. I bought this movie after 1 viewing - safe to say, you will too. Orson, thank you, thank you, thank you for making this CLASSIC!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "You don't have a future."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Red-125
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Touch of Evil (1958), scripted and directed by Orson Welles, is deservedly one of IMDb's top 250 movies. The story of the movie as a movie is almost as dramatic as the plot of the film. Before the editing took place, Welles was removed from the project. He responded with a long, detailed memo about how the film should be edited. This memo was mostly ignored, and an inferior short version of Touch of Evil was released in theaters and later for the small screen. Fortunately, years later, with immense effort, most of the original footage was salvaged, and the film was reconstructed almost in the way Welles had envisioned it. This longer version was what we saw in the excellent--and newly refurbished-- Dryden Theatre at Eastman House in Rochester, NY. The film seems dated today, but it's still powerful and engrossing. Charlton Heston plays Mike Vargas, a high-ranking Mexican police official. He has just married an American, Susan, played by Janet Leigh. They become involved in a murder investigation because someone dies when dynamite is placed in a car in Mexico, but the explosion takes place across the border in the U.S. It's at this point that Vargas has to interact with Police Captain Hank Quinlan, played by Welles. Quinlan is an overweight, limping, unshaven bully. However, he has almost magical powers to detect criminals, who are then invariably convicted. The means he uses in his investigations are not found in a police manual. So, it's clear from the beginning that Vargas wears the white hat and Quinlan wears the black hat. Janet Leigh is wasted in her role as naive and gullible young wife. Heston does a good job as the straight arrow cop. Welles, of course, is perfect for the role of a (really) bad cop. Quinlan has built his whole career based on his larger-than-life personality, and no one in his town is going to try to change his techniques. Welles was born to play this role. Two supporting characters deserve mention: Dennis Weaver as the Mirador Motel Night Manager. He turns in a brilliant performance that combines stupidity, timidity, and rigidity in equal parts. Marlene Dietrich plays Tanya, a former flame of Quinlan's from the days when he was young and handsome. Dietrich--who looks sad, cynical, and very beautiful--delivers the best line of the film. Quinlan asks her to read his future in her Tarot cards. She tells him, "You haven't got any. Your future is all used up." This is a movie worth seeking out and seeing. It will work better on a large screen. However, even in DVD, it's a must-see film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Way He Sees and Lets Us See
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Antti Keisala
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Orson Welles is one director to whom I'm drawn time and again for refreshment and reinvigoration. He's leagues beyond me, and in the words of Fran&ccedil;ois Truffaut, "When you come out of 'Touch of Evil' you feel less intelligent than before but gratified anyhow by the poetry and art."* Yet there are certain things I always know to look for, whether the film in question is "Citizen Kane" (1941), "The Tragedy of Othello: The Moor of Venice" (1952), "Mr. Arkadin" (1955) or "F for Fake" (1973): the narrative is going to be free-flowingly evasive and explorative, always interested not finding out the truth but rather becoming aware of all the layers of fabrication within the narrative; and the way he sees and lets us see the world will be breathtaking. And so it is. His way of moving the camera with absolute effortlessness astonishes each time, so does the lighting of the interiors and the way he shoots claustrophobic closed spaces. Heston and Welles play wonderfully together, and Welles' performance is among the highlights of his career. Dietrich's character refers to Von Sternberg's "Der Blaue Engel" (1930), a satire about a sexual free fall, a strong undersong in this film. The film's production history, as that of many other films by Welles, is closely linked to the film itself. As such, "Touch of Evil" is also rewarding as an artifact of film history. It's interesting to read Welles' 58-page memo (available online) and compare to any of the versions available. Watching them either chronologically or in reverse order is great fun. So is comparing the aspect ratios. The Region B Blu-ray released by the Masters of Cinema series is most certainly at the summit of the format and what can be done with it. On two Blu-rays there are the three existing versions of the film (the 1958 theatrical version, the 1958 preview version and the 1998 reconstructed version), the 1958 theatrical and the 1998 reconstruction presented in two aspect ratios. They are beautiful transfers, and host interesting and informative commentary tracks. I see myself revisiting this, and then revisiting it again. And again. * The review "Touch of Evil", by Fran&ccedil;ois Truffaut, originally published in "Arts" (June 4, 1958), available in the collection "Les films de ma vie" (1975) and translated into English as "The Films of My Life" (1978). I read this review in the booklet of the Masters of Cinema Blu-ray (p. 5).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    holy cow is this a good movie!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    xhearto
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    thrills! chills! Welles! if you feel like you've seen this movie a thousand times upon first viewing, it's probably because almost every moment has been "borrowed" by filmmakers for over half a century. And then copied by people who saw the borrowings. journey to the dark heart of man? Check. Marlene smoking over a crystal ball? Check. Janet terrorized in a motel? Check. Orson at the pinnacle of his game? Check. a shining example of what defines the difference between a film and a "movie" check. top ten list.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Macho Man?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gamay9
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Film noir at its' best....and, what a cast! The only unlikely scene is where Susie (Janet Leigh) is screaming for help from a fire escape and Vargas (Charleton Heston) drives right by, heads for a bar and roughs up the thugs....meanwhile Susie is arrested and jailed. Wouldn't a macho guy like Heston aid his wife first and then confront the thugs? After all, this is 1958 when guys rolled cigarette packs into their t-shirt sleeves. That was a lame scene. One of the actors, Calleia, was the director; not Hitchcock. It would have been easy for Heston to have the script changed to a more likely scenario. Otherwise, I enjoyed the film; anytime one can see Janet Leigh, Charleton Heston, Orson Welles, Marlene Deitrich (dark-haired Mexican) and Dennis Weaver in the same film, it's a blast!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Touch of Evil
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Directed by and starring Orson Welles, I may remember watching the first ten or something minutes of this film but giving up on it, I was certainly up for giving it another chance when I saw it listed and recommended as one of the 1001 Movies You Must See Before You Die in the book. Basically on the border between the United States of America and Mexico a time bomb is planted in the boot of a car, and it is drives to cross the border, and a couple of times newlyweds Ramon Miguel 'Mike' Vargas (Charlton Heston) and Susan 'Susie' (Janet Leigh) pass the vehicle before it crosses, and after doing so it blows up and kills the passengers. Mike works for the Mexican government as a drug enforcement official, and knowing the implications of bombs from Mexico to America exploding he decides to join in any investigation he can, and also looking into it are police Chief Gould (Harry Shannon) and District Attorney Adair (Ray Collins), but also the peculiar Police Captain Hank Quinlan (Orson Welles) and his long time partner Police Sergeant Pete Menzies (Joseph Calleia). Young Mexican man Manelo Sanchez (Victor Millan) is the prime suspect for Quinlan and Menzies, as he was secretly married to the daughter of one of the victims in the explosion, Mike is there during the interrogation, he accidentally knocks over an empty shoebox, and in moments this same box two sticks of dynamite are in it, so Mike suspects Quinlan has been planting evidence to help with his convictions over the years. Although Quinlan denies this Vargas still wants to see his public case records, so Al Schwartz (Mort Mills), the District Attorney's assistant lets him study them, and Gould and Adair are shown the findings as well, but Quinlan himself comes in and threatens resignation in anger over their discussion. There is a risk of the brother of a man Mike was investigating, 'Uncle' Joe Grandi (Akim Tamiroff) trying to expose things, so Susie moves from their Mexican hotel to a motel in America, one that Menzies recommended, staffed by mentally challenged Night Manager (Duel's Dennis Weaver) and with no other guests staying, but family members of Grandi take over the motel. Mike becomes worried when he tries telephoning Susie and she does not answer, in fact Quinlan has arrangement with Grandi that his gang will kidnap her, inject her with drugs and taken to another motel out of town, and indeed this happens, Quinlan murders Grandi and Susie is framed for the murder to give her husband a bad name. Mike goes to have a word with Menzies about the history of the cases he and Quinlan investigating and "found" evidence in, he dismisses any conspiracy he has, and then he goes looking for his wife at the motel but she and her gun have gone, so he goes to the other motel that Grandi owns and confronts his gang, they refuse to answer questions so he beats them up. Schwartz tells him that Susie was arrested for murder, but when he finds her she is barely conscious, and then Menzies comes to tell him that Quinlan's cane was found at the scene of Grandi's murder, so Mike fits him with a wire so he can go to see his partner and hear a conversation between them. At an oil field is where Quinlan and Menzies meet to discuss their activities while Mike records everything, the traitor cop admits he planted evidence on people to make them guiltier than they already were, but the tapping is uncovered by the sound of static. Quinlan knows that Mike is there watching and listening, and in the heat of the moment he shoots Menzies with Vargas's gun, but before he can shoot Mike dead Menzies gets up and shoots Quinlan, Menzies dies and eventually so does Quinlan, Sanchez is revealed to have admitted to the crime of planting the car bomb, and Mike leaves town with a recovered Susie. Also starring Joanna Moore as Marcia Linnekar , Valentin De Vargas as Pancho, Lalo Rios as Risto , Marlene Dietrich as Tanya, Zsa Zsa Gabor as Strip-Club Owner, The Third Man's Joseph Cotten as Coroner and The Exorcist's Mercedes McCambridge as Gang Leader. Heston gives a good performance as the man determined to get to the truth of the matter, Leigh gets her moments as the wife pulled into the situations, but obviously Welles is best part of this film as the treacherous cop with the villainous dark side, and his direction is well paced as well, some supporting cast members, especially Dietrich, are terrific as well. The film opens with one of the most famous long shots in cinema which is played out so well with clever tracking, and the film is filled with interesting material about conspiracy, double-crossing, murder and melodrama, it is one of the last true film noir style pictures, I admit I lost track of plot on occasions, but overall it is a watchable classic crime thriller. Very good!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just a Touch of American Stereotypes
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rexx Villotti
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    During his honeymoon, Mexican police officer Mike Vargas (Charlton Heston) is dragged into a deadly battler with the respected-but- corrupted American Police Captain Hank Quinlan (Orson Welles). While protecting his wife, avoiding prejudice, and trying to uncover the truth, Vargas has more foes to deal with than he thinks. Involving Mexican drug smugglers, kidnappers, and the dimwitted American police force, Quinlan tries to discredit and stop his attempt to uncover the truth. One of the Film Noirs, Orson Welles' "Touch of Evil" is a Mexican border town mystery unlike any other. In other movies with the same setting, "A Fist Full of Dollars" for example, the hero would be an attractive American cowboy and the villain would be a dirty, greedy Mexican. In typical Welles fashion of breaking film norms, he flips the American image of good and evil. The villain, portrayed by Welles himself, is a fat, corrupt American Cop. While Quinlan is the villain, Welles also makes him the victim also. He is a victim of himself, and from the police work that has consumed his life and humanity. Welles intentionally creates these characters to break free from the chains that often bind him and other film directors of the time. There is not a clear cut plot that can be seen and set up in the first few minutes of the film, the viewers are taken from crime scenes to mobster run hotels before they glimpse at the corrupt American police at work. The main plot cannot be set up very easily in this film without the proper introduction to the characters. For example, the viewer must understand why the Grandi mob family wants Vargas dead. Without this knowledge that the film provides in the action leading up to the reveal of police activities, the viewers would be left wondering why the mob family is so eager to be involved in American police business. This complex plot combined with Welles' dynamic and intriguing cinematography creates a thrilling game of wits between American and Mexican police.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dynamite Opening Crane Shot
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    romanorum1
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A shadowy man places a time-bomb in the trunk of a new Chrysler and runs away just before another man and a woman enter and drive off. In the darkness, among the sounds of traffic and seedy strip clubs and gaudy hotels in the Mexican border town of Los Robles, the auto meanders across the border into the USA. We see crumbling arches and peeling walls. For more than three minutes we wonder what will happen. Tick  tick  tick  The Chrysler passes by mustached Charlton Heston (Mike Vargas) and stunning Janet Leigh (Susan Vargas). As Mike stops to kiss his new wife, we hear the explosion, and there is a cut to the burning vehicle. "This could be very bad for us, utters Mike." Vargas, as a police investigator (and Chairman of the Pan-American Narcotics Commission), was returning to Mexico to testify against Vic Grandi's Mexican crime family. As the explosion occurred on the American side of the border, police chief Harry Quinlan (Orson Welles) is called in to investigate. Bloated, stubbly, puffy-faced Quinlan has a history of planting evidence to convict those whom he wants. Sweating, he oozes corruption from every pore. "You're a mess," fortune-teller Tana (Marlene Dietrich) would later tell him. To Quinlan's displeasure, Vargas decides to hang around because of his concern that his native Mexico may be involved in an international incident. He tells his wife to return to the hotel. She gets intercepted by a gang who takes her to "visit" Uncle Joe Grandi (Akim Tamiroff). He warns her to tell her husband to desist from the Grandi trial, or else. The man who died in the car explosion was Rudolph Linnekar, a wealthy contractor; his girl was a blonde night club dancer. Mexican Manelo Sanchez, a shoe clerk, who had been dating Linnekar's daughter Marcia against her father's wishes, is visited by Quinlan. Now Sanchez does not really care for Marcia, but, as he freely admits, likes only her money. Quinlan, who maintains that Sanchez murdered Rudolph Linnekar because the latter disapproved of Sanchez's marriage to Marcia, plants two sticks of dynamite in a box in Sanchez's bathroom. As Vargas knows that Quinlan planted the evidence, he does not abide by the arrest. He decides to gather evidence against him, and begins working with honest assistant DA Schwartz. Meanwhile Susan Vargas is in danger; as her husband had inconceivably left her alone. She moved to the Mirador Motel, which consists of a number of uninhabited cabins in the desert. Neither her husband nor she can imagine that the hotel is owned by Uncle Joe Grandi. She is the only customer, and he has plans for her, as his leather-jacketed gang of thugs often operates from there. Her only shield  and he really is not one  is neurotic Dennis Weaver, the night man. He acts more psycho than Norman Bates, without the latter's murders. Since Quinlan is quickly onto Mike's intention, he is forced to work with Uncle Joe to frame wife Susan as a druggie. So Susan, besieged in her room, is easy prey for the gang. She is drugged and apparently gang-raped while lesbian leader Mercedes McCambridge watches. Then Susan is brought to a different hotel where she lies unconscious while surrounded by drug paraphernalia. Both Uncle Joe and Quinlan arrive there, but Quinlan turns against him and strangles Joe and leaves evidence to implicate Susan. But he inexplicably leaves his cane in the room, which his sergeant, Pete Menzies (Joseph Calleia) later finds. Menzies has been Quinlan's stooge for years, and although he probably could not exist without Quinlan, soon decides to reverse his previous deeds. Before long, Menzies and Vargas are working together to tape record Quinlan admission of his decadence among the pumping oil derricks and garbage heaps at a canal. Bullets will be fired, and only one of the three will walk away. And only in the end is it confirmed for certain who placed the bomb in the car trunk (although the culprit is obvious). Orson Welles was already a giant for his excellent portrayal in "Citizen Kane" (1942), considered by many critics as the greatest movie of all time. Those who feel that Charlton Heston was miscast should be aware that he portrayed various historical figures. They include Moses, Marc Antony, John the Baptist, El Cid, Michelangelo, both Henry VIII and Sir Thomas More (!), Cardinal Richelieu, Lt. William Clark (of Lewis and Clark fame), Thomas Jefferson, Andrew Jackson, Abe Lincoln, Brigham Young, General "Chinese" Gordon, and Buffalo Bill Cody. Heston could pass as a Mexican of European heritage. Vivacious Janet Leigh was already famous; she had starred in "Angels in the Outfield" (1951), "Scaramouche" (1952), and "The Naked Spur" (1953). The last one is considered by Leonard Maltin to be one of the greatest westerns ever made. Psycho would follow (1960), and Manchurian Candidate after that (1962). The greatness of the movie is not its message; in fact, one may even identify several peculiar settings. Those who hate the movie generally dislike the material. But the film's prominence is in HOW the story is told. It is like "Citizen Kane," which has a rather thin plot, but an incredible revelation. Take the hotel room scene where Welles takes Janet Leigh's nylon stocking and wraps it around his fingers. He looks menacingly at Akim Tamiroff while the neon lights flash from outside. It is a hungry lion facing a trapped antelope. Uncle Joe is finished, and he knows it. "Touch of Evil" has high-level technical qualities of expressionist lighting and shadow, low camera angles, wide-angle lens, and dark, brooding photography. The movie has atmosphere in miles. Henry Mancini's dazzling sound track hits the spot (and works very well even in the truncated 95-minute version of the movie). As "Touch of Evil" is recognized by enthusiasts as one of the greatest movies made in world cinema history, it appears on many Top 100 Lists.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    strange gem
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vincentiu
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    a special form of masterpiece. common story. minimalist scenes. but seed of genius. not a surprise - Orson Welles can be himself - but the joy to discover an admirable construction remains. secret - the cast. Marlene Dietrich in a role of few lines who preserves mystery and seduction, Janet Leigh as innocent victim of dark business, Charlton Heston as Charlton Heston and Welles in a role like a fascinating puzzle. it is more than a film. it is not exactly a masterpiece for usual definition. it is a gem. why ? after see it, you may be have an answer. or, only, a sketch about this precise exercise of precision in each of details.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just a touch
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kosmasp
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Orson Welles did have a "magic touch" (no pun intended), although it didn't always translate into commercial success. Which of course had to do with the studios being reluctant giving him the free reign he had on his Citizen Kane classic. There are quite a few versions out there of this movie and we got treated to one of them (close to what Welles imagined at the time as biographer told us) at the Berlin International Festival. When I say close, it does mean that it's as close to what Welles would have wanted in the movie (from the footage that was shot), especially concerning the audio in the beginning. He had a vision in his head and the studio bosses wouldn't always agree with him. Another problem might have been that he himself wasn't always satisfied and would change things. So while the version I saw, was close to a memo he send to the studio (suggesting cuts and especially the audio change in the beginning), he might have changed all that at a later time, if he had the chance (at least he might have written another memo after watching it the way, he wanted it to be). Having said and written all that, the movie has a powerful performance by Charlton Heston as well. Characters reactions to some things might feel dated or clich&eacute;, but that is just because we have seen other films copying some of the working formula that is being used here. B&W it might be, but it still has quite a punch to it ... morally and otherwise
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The best Film Noir & one of the all-time greatest films.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stephen-scott83
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I first watched Touch of Evil I was absolutely astounded. I was mesmerised by Orson and the simply remarkable depth of his character. I rank this movie as the greatest film noir ever made and one of the greatest movies ever made. It's that simple. I watch this movie at least 2-3 times a month. Orson's character, Hank Quinlan is the ultimate crooked, bigot cop. This character is like a monster that no one seems to know how to stop. That's the easy description, the true genius is in the script, mannerisms and camera angles. You could not make this film in color, it wouldn't work. One of my favorite aspects about this movie is the subtle use of sarcasm - especially Quinlan's Sargeant - that leads to the overall mood of arrogance spread out in this amazing movie. This movie requires multiple viewings if you really want to appreciate the stunning script and superlative camera shots/angles. Dennis Weaver's character is in my opinion, one of the most bizarre in movie history especially considering there was no development his hyper-manic oddball character. Truly bizarre - but so entertaining! The cameo by Zsa Zsa Gabor is neat but the extended "cameo" by Marlene Dietrich is stunning. I bought this movie after 1 viewing - safe to say, you will too. Orson, thank you, thank you, thank you for making this CLASSIC!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "You don't have a future."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Red-125
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Touch of Evil (1958), scripted and directed by Orson Welles, is deservedly one of IMDb's top 250 movies. The story of the movie as a movie is almost as dramatic as the plot of the film. Before the editing took place, Welles was removed from the project. He responded with a long, detailed memo about how the film should be edited. This memo was mostly ignored, and an inferior short version of Touch of Evil was released in theaters and later for the small screen. Fortunately, years later, with immense effort, most of the original footage was salvaged, and the film was reconstructed almost in the way Welles had envisioned it. This longer version was what we saw in the excellent--and newly refurbished-- Dryden Theatre at Eastman House in Rochester, NY. The film seems dated today, but it's still powerful and engrossing. Charlton Heston plays Mike Vargas, a high-ranking Mexican police official. He has just married an American, Susan, played by Janet Leigh. They become involved in a murder investigation because someone dies when dynamite is placed in a car in Mexico, but the explosion takes place across the border in the U.S. It's at this point that Vargas has to interact with Police Captain Hank Quinlan, played by Welles. Quinlan is an overweight, limping, unshaven bully. However, he has almost magical powers to detect criminals, who are then invariably convicted. The means he uses in his investigations are not found in a police manual. So, it's clear from the beginning that Vargas wears the white hat and Quinlan wears the black hat. Janet Leigh is wasted in her role as naive and gullible young wife. Heston does a good job as the straight arrow cop. Welles, of course, is perfect for the role of a (really) bad cop. Quinlan has built his whole career based on his larger-than-life personality, and no one in his town is going to try to change his techniques. Welles was born to play this role. Two supporting characters deserve mention: Dennis Weaver as the Mirador Motel Night Manager. He turns in a brilliant performance that combines stupidity, timidity, and rigidity in equal parts. Marlene Dietrich plays Tanya, a former flame of Quinlan's from the days when he was young and handsome. Dietrich--who looks sad, cynical, and very beautiful--delivers the best line of the film. Quinlan asks her to read his future in her Tarot cards. She tells him, "You haven't got any. Your future is all used up." This is a movie worth seeking out and seeing. It will work better on a large screen. However, even in DVD, it's a must-see film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Way He Sees and Lets Us See
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Antti Keisala
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Orson Welles is one director to whom I'm drawn time and again for refreshment and reinvigoration. He's leagues beyond me, and in the words of Fran&ccedil;ois Truffaut, "When you come out of 'Touch of Evil' you feel less intelligent than before but gratified anyhow by the poetry and art."* Yet there are certain things I always know to look for, whether the film in question is "Citizen Kane" (1941), "The Tragedy of Othello: The Moor of Venice" (1952), "Mr. Arkadin" (1955) or "F for Fake" (1973): the narrative is going to be free-flowingly evasive and explorative, always interested not finding out the truth but rather becoming aware of all the layers of fabrication within the narrative; and the way he sees and lets us see the world will be breathtaking. And so it is. His way of moving the camera with absolute effortlessness astonishes each time, so does the lighting of the interiors and the way he shoots claustrophobic closed spaces. Heston and Welles play wonderfully together, and Welles' performance is among the highlights of his career. Dietrich's character refers to Von Sternberg's "Der Blaue Engel" (1930), a satire about a sexual free fall, a strong undersong in this film. The film's production history, as that of many other films by Welles, is closely linked to the film itself. As such, "Touch of Evil" is also rewarding as an artifact of film history. It's interesting to read Welles' 58-page memo (available online) and compare to any of the versions available. Watching them either chronologically or in reverse order is great fun. So is comparing the aspect ratios. The Region B Blu-ray released by the Masters of Cinema series is most certainly at the summit of the format and what can be done with it. On two Blu-rays there are the three existing versions of the film (the 1958 theatrical version, the 1958 preview version and the 1998 reconstructed version), the 1958 theatrical and the 1998 reconstruction presented in two aspect ratios. They are beautiful transfers, and host interesting and informative commentary tracks. I see myself revisiting this, and then revisiting it again. And again. * The review "Touch of Evil", by Fran&ccedil;ois Truffaut, originally published in "Arts" (June 4, 1958), available in the collection "Les films de ma vie" (1975) and translated into English as "The Films of My Life" (1978). I read this review in the booklet of the Masters of Cinema Blu-ray (p. 5).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    holy cow is this a good movie!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    xhearto
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    thrills! chills! Welles! if you feel like you've seen this movie a thousand times upon first viewing, it's probably because almost every moment has been "borrowed" by filmmakers for over half a century. And then copied by people who saw the borrowings. journey to the dark heart of man? Check. Marlene smoking over a crystal ball? Check. Janet terrorized in a motel? Check. Orson at the pinnacle of his game? Check. a shining example of what defines the difference between a film and a "movie" check. top ten list.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Macho Man?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gamay9
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Film noir at its' best....and, what a cast! The only unlikely scene is where Susie (Janet Leigh) is screaming for help from a fire escape and Vargas (Charleton Heston) drives right by, heads for a bar and roughs up the thugs....meanwhile Susie is arrested and jailed. Wouldn't a macho guy like Heston aid his wife first and then confront the thugs? After all, this is 1958 when guys rolled cigarette packs into their t-shirt sleeves. That was a lame scene. One of the actors, Calleia, was the director; not Hitchcock. It would have been easy for Heston to have the script changed to a more likely scenario. Otherwise, I enjoyed the film; anytime one can see Janet Leigh, Charleton Heston, Orson Welles, Marlene Deitrich (dark-haired Mexican) and Dennis Weaver in the same film, it's a blast!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Touch of Evil
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Directed by and starring Orson Welles, I may remember watching the first ten or something minutes of this film but giving up on it, I was certainly up for giving it another chance when I saw it listed and recommended as one of the 1001 Movies You Must See Before You Die in the book. Basically on the border between the United States of America and Mexico a time bomb is planted in the boot of a car, and it is drives to cross the border, and a couple of times newlyweds Ramon Miguel 'Mike' Vargas (Charlton Heston) and Susan 'Susie' (Janet Leigh) pass the vehicle before it crosses, and after doing so it blows up and kills the passengers. Mike works for the Mexican government as a drug enforcement official, and knowing the implications of bombs from Mexico to America exploding he decides to join in any investigation he can, and also looking into it are police Chief Gould (Harry Shannon) and District Attorney Adair (Ray Collins), but also the peculiar Police Captain Hank Quinlan (Orson Welles) and his long time partner Police Sergeant Pete Menzies (Joseph Calleia). Young Mexican man Manelo Sanchez (Victor Millan) is the prime suspect for Quinlan and Menzies, as he was secretly married to the daughter of one of the victims in the explosion, Mike is there during the interrogation, he accidentally knocks over an empty shoebox, and in moments this same box two sticks of dynamite are in it, so Mike suspects Quinlan has been planting evidence to help with his convictions over the years. Although Quinlan denies this Vargas still wants to see his public case records, so Al Schwartz (Mort Mills), the District Attorney's assistant lets him study them, and Gould and Adair are shown the findings as well, but Quinlan himself comes in and threatens resignation in anger over their discussion. There is a risk of the brother of a man Mike was investigating, 'Uncle' Joe Grandi (Akim Tamiroff) trying to expose things, so Susie moves from their Mexican hotel to a motel in America, one that Menzies recommended, staffed by mentally challenged Night Manager (Duel's Dennis Weaver) and with no other guests staying, but family members of Grandi take over the motel. Mike becomes worried when he tries telephoning Susie and she does not answer, in fact Quinlan has arrangement with Grandi that his gang will kidnap her, inject her with drugs and taken to another motel out of town, and indeed this happens, Quinlan murders Grandi and Susie is framed for the murder to give her husband a bad name. Mike goes to have a word with Menzies about the history of the cases he and Quinlan investigating and "found" evidence in, he dismisses any conspiracy he has, and then he goes looking for his wife at the motel but she and her gun have gone, so he goes to the other motel that Grandi owns and confronts his gang, they refuse to answer questions so he beats them up. Schwartz tells him that Susie was arrested for murder, but when he finds her she is barely conscious, and then Menzies comes to tell him that Quinlan's cane was found at the scene of Grandi's murder, so Mike fits him with a wire so he can go to see his partner and hear a conversation between them. At an oil field is where Quinlan and Menzies meet to discuss their activities while Mike records everything, the traitor cop admits he planted evidence on people to make them guiltier than they already were, but the tapping is uncovered by the sound of static. Quinlan knows that Mike is there watching and listening, and in the heat of the moment he shoots Menzies with Vargas's gun, but before he can shoot Mike dead Menzies gets up and shoots Quinlan, Menzies dies and eventually so does Quinlan, Sanchez is revealed to have admitted to the crime of planting the car bomb, and Mike leaves town with a recovered Susie. Also starring Joanna Moore as Marcia Linnekar , Valentin De Vargas as Pancho, Lalo Rios as Risto , Marlene Dietrich as Tanya, Zsa Zsa Gabor as Strip-Club Owner, The Third Man's Joseph Cotten as Coroner and The Exorcist's Mercedes McCambridge as Gang Leader. Heston gives a good performance as the man determined to get to the truth of the matter, Leigh gets her moments as the wife pulled into the situations, but obviously Welles is best part of this film as the treacherous cop with the villainous dark side, and his direction is well paced as well, some supporting cast members, especially Dietrich, are terrific as well. The film opens with one of the most famous long shots in cinema which is played out so well with clever tracking, and the film is filled with interesting material about conspiracy, double-crossing, murder and melodrama, it is one of the last true film noir style pictures, I admit I lost track of plot on occasions, but overall it is a watchable classic crime thriller. Very good!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just a Touch of American Stereotypes
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rexx Villotti
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    During his honeymoon, Mexican police officer Mike Vargas (Charlton Heston) is dragged into a deadly battler with the respected-but- corrupted American Police Captain Hank Quinlan (Orson Welles). While protecting his wife, avoiding prejudice, and trying to uncover the truth, Vargas has more foes to deal with than he thinks. Involving Mexican drug smugglers, kidnappers, and the dimwitted American police force, Quinlan tries to discredit and stop his attempt to uncover the truth. One of the Film Noirs, Orson Welles' "Touch of Evil" is a Mexican border town mystery unlike any other. In other movies with the same setting, "A Fist Full of Dollars" for example, the hero would be an attractive American cowboy and the villain would be a dirty, greedy Mexican. In typical Welles fashion of breaking film norms, he flips the American image of good and evil. The villain, portrayed by Welles himself, is a fat, corrupt American Cop. While Quinlan is the villain, Welles also makes him the victim also. He is a victim of himself, and from the police work that has consumed his life and humanity. Welles intentionally creates these characters to break free from the chains that often bind him and other film directors of the time. There is not a clear cut plot that can be seen and set up in the first few minutes of the film, the viewers are taken from crime scenes to mobster run hotels before they glimpse at the corrupt American police at work. The main plot cannot be set up very easily in this film without the proper introduction to the characters. For example, the viewer must understand why the Grandi mob family wants Vargas dead. Without this knowledge that the film provides in the action leading up to the reveal of police activities, the viewers would be left wondering why the mob family is so eager to be involved in American police business. This complex plot combined with Welles' dynamic and intriguing cinematography creates a thrilling game of wits between American and Mexican police.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dynamite Opening Crane Shot
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    romanorum1
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A shadowy man places a time-bomb in the trunk of a new Chrysler and runs away just before another man and a woman enter and drive off. In the darkness, among the sounds of traffic and seedy strip clubs and gaudy hotels in the Mexican border town of Los Robles, the auto meanders across the border into the USA. We see crumbling arches and peeling walls. For more than three minutes we wonder what will happen. Tick  tick  tick  The Chrysler passes by mustached Charlton Heston (Mike Vargas) and stunning Janet Leigh (Susan Vargas). As Mike stops to kiss his new wife, we hear the explosion, and there is a cut to the burning vehicle. "This could be very bad for us, utters Mike." Vargas, as a police investigator (and Chairman of the Pan-American Narcotics Commission), was returning to Mexico to testify against Vic Grandi's Mexican crime family. As the explosion occurred on the American side of the border, police chief Harry Quinlan (Orson Welles) is called in to investigate. Bloated, stubbly, puffy-faced Quinlan has a history of planting evidence to convict those whom he wants. Sweating, he oozes corruption from every pore. "You're a mess," fortune-teller Tana (Marlene Dietrich) would later tell him. To Quinlan's displeasure, Vargas decides to hang around because of his concern that his native Mexico may be involved in an international incident. He tells his wife to return to the hotel. She gets intercepted by a gang who takes her to "visit" Uncle Joe Grandi (Akim Tamiroff). He warns her to tell her husband to desist from the Grandi trial, or else. The man who died in the car explosion was Rudolph Linnekar, a wealthy contractor; his girl was a blonde night club dancer. Mexican Manelo Sanchez, a shoe clerk, who had been dating Linnekar's daughter Marcia against her father's wishes, is visited by Quinlan. Now Sanchez does not really care for Marcia, but, as he freely admits, likes only her money. Quinlan, who maintains that Sanchez murdered Rudolph Linnekar because the latter disapproved of Sanchez's marriage to Marcia, plants two sticks of dynamite in a box in Sanchez's bathroom. As Vargas knows that Quinlan planted the evidence, he does not abide by the arrest. He decides to gather evidence against him, and begins working with honest assistant DA Schwartz. Meanwhile Susan Vargas is in danger; as her husband had inconceivably left her alone. She moved to the Mirador Motel, which consists of a number of uninhabited cabins in the desert. Neither her husband nor she can imagine that the hotel is owned by Uncle Joe Grandi. She is the only customer, and he has plans for her, as his leather-jacketed gang of thugs often operates from there. Her only shield  and he really is not one  is neurotic Dennis Weaver, the night man. He acts more psycho than Norman Bates, without the latter's murders. Since Quinlan is quickly onto Mike's intention, he is forced to work with Uncle Joe to frame wife Susan as a druggie. So Susan, besieged in her room, is easy prey for the gang. She is drugged and apparently gang-raped while lesbian leader Mercedes McCambridge watches. Then Susan is brought to a different hotel where she lies unconscious while surrounded by drug paraphernalia. Both Uncle Joe and Quinlan arrive there, but Quinlan turns against him and strangles Joe and leaves evidence to implicate Susan. But he inexplicably leaves his cane in the room, which his sergeant, Pete Menzies (Joseph Calleia) later finds. Menzies has been Quinlan's stooge for years, and although he probably could not exist without Quinlan, soon decides to reverse his previous deeds. Before long, Menzies and Vargas are working together to tape record Quinlan admission of his decadence among the pumping oil derricks and garbage heaps at a canal. Bullets will be fired, and only one of the three will walk away. And only in the end is it confirmed for certain who placed the bomb in the car trunk (although the culprit is obvious). Orson Welles was already a giant for his excellent portrayal in "Citizen Kane" (1942), considered by many critics as the greatest movie of all time. Those who feel that Charlton Heston was miscast should be aware that he portrayed various historical figures. They include Moses, Marc Antony, John the Baptist, El Cid, Michelangelo, both Henry VIII and Sir Thomas More (!), Cardinal Richelieu, Lt. William Clark (of Lewis and Clark fame), Thomas Jefferson, Andrew Jackson, Abe Lincoln, Brigham Young, General "Chinese" Gordon, and Buffalo Bill Cody. Heston could pass as a Mexican of European heritage. Vivacious Janet Leigh was already famous; she had starred in "Angels in the Outfield" (1951), "Scaramouche" (1952), and "The Naked Spur" (1953). The last one is considered by Leonard Maltin to be one of the greatest westerns ever made. Psycho would follow (1960), and Manchurian Candidate after that (1962). The greatness of the movie is not its message; in fact, one may even identify several peculiar settings. Those who hate the movie generally dislike the material. But the film's prominence is in HOW the story is told. It is like "Citizen Kane," which has a rather thin plot, but an incredible revelation. Take the hotel room scene where Welles takes Janet Leigh's nylon stocking and wraps it around his fingers. He looks menacingly at Akim Tamiroff while the neon lights flash from outside. It is a hungry lion facing a trapped antelope. Uncle Joe is finished, and he knows it. "Touch of Evil" has high-level technical qualities of expressionist lighting and shadow, low camera angles, wide-angle lens, and dark, brooding photography. The movie has atmosphere in miles. Henry Mancini's dazzling sound track hits the spot (and works very well even in the truncated 95-minute version of the movie). As "Touch of Evil" is recognized by enthusiasts as one of the greatest movies made in world cinema history, it appears on many Top 100 Lists.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    strange gem
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vincentiu
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    a special form of masterpiece. common story. minimalist scenes. but seed of genius. not a surprise - Orson Welles can be himself - but the joy to discover an admirable construction remains. secret - the cast. Marlene Dietrich in a role of few lines who preserves mystery and seduction, Janet Leigh as innocent victim of dark business, Charlton Heston as Charlton Heston and Welles in a role like a fascinating puzzle. it is more than a film. it is not exactly a masterpiece for usual definition. it is a gem. why ? after see it, you may be have an answer. or, only, a sketch about this precise exercise of precision in each of details.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just a touch
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kosmasp
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Orson Welles did have a "magic touch" (no pun intended), although it didn't always translate into commercial success. Which of course had to do with the studios being reluctant giving him the free reign he had on his Citizen Kane classic. There are quite a few versions out there of this movie and we got treated to one of them (close to what Welles imagined at the time as biographer told us) at the Berlin International Festival. When I say close, it does mean that it's as close to what Welles would have wanted in the movie (from the footage that was shot), especially concerning the audio in the beginning. He had a vision in his head and the studio bosses wouldn't always agree with him. Another problem might have been that he himself wasn't always satisfied and would change things. So while the version I saw, was close to a memo he send to the studio (suggesting cuts and especially the audio change in the beginning), he might have changed all that at a later time, if he had the chance (at least he might have written another memo after watching it the way, he wanted it to be). Having said and written all that, the movie has a powerful performance by Charlton Heston as well. Characters reactions to some things might feel dated or clich&eacute;, but that is just because we have seen other films copying some of the working formula that is being used here. B&W it might be, but it still has quite a punch to it ... morally and otherwise
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The best Film Noir & one of the all-time greatest films.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stephen-scott83
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I first watched Touch of Evil I was absolutely astounded. I was mesmerised by Orson and the simply remarkable depth of his character. I rank this movie as the greatest film noir ever made and one of the greatest movies ever made. It's that simple. I watch this movie at least 2-3 times a month. Orson's character, Hank Quinlan is the ultimate crooked, bigot cop. This character is like a monster that no one seems to know how to stop. That's the easy description, the true genius is in the script, mannerisms and camera angles. You could not make this film in color, it wouldn't work. One of my favorite aspects about this movie is the subtle use of sarcasm - especially Quinlan's Sargeant - that leads to the overall mood of arrogance spread out in this amazing movie. This movie requires multiple viewings if you really want to appreciate the stunning script and superlative camera shots/angles. Dennis Weaver's character is in my opinion, one of the most bizarre in movie history especially considering there was no development his hyper-manic oddball character. Truly bizarre - but so entertaining! The cameo by Zsa Zsa Gabor is neat but the extended "cameo" by Marlene Dietrich is stunning. I bought this movie after 1 viewing - safe to say, you will too. Orson, thank you, thank you, thank you for making this CLASSIC!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "You don't have a future."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Red-125
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Touch of Evil (1958), scripted and directed by Orson Welles, is deservedly one of IMDb's top 250 movies. The story of the movie as a movie is almost as dramatic as the plot of the film. Before the editing took place, Welles was removed from the project. He responded with a long, detailed memo about how the film should be edited. This memo was mostly ignored, and an inferior short version of Touch of Evil was released in theaters and later for the small screen. Fortunately, years later, with immense effort, most of the original footage was salvaged, and the film was reconstructed almost in the way Welles had envisioned it. This longer version was what we saw in the excellent--and newly refurbished-- Dryden Theatre at Eastman House in Rochester, NY. The film seems dated today, but it's still powerful and engrossing. Charlton Heston plays Mike Vargas, a high-ranking Mexican police official. He has just married an American, Susan, played by Janet Leigh. They become involved in a murder investigation because someone dies when dynamite is placed in a car in Mexico, but the explosion takes place across the border in the U.S. It's at this point that Vargas has to interact with Police Captain Hank Quinlan, played by Welles. Quinlan is an overweight, limping, unshaven bully. However, he has almost magical powers to detect criminals, who are then invariably convicted. The means he uses in his investigations are not found in a police manual. So, it's clear from the beginning that Vargas wears the white hat and Quinlan wears the black hat. Janet Leigh is wasted in her role as naive and gullible young wife. Heston does a good job as the straight arrow cop. Welles, of course, is perfect for the role of a (really) bad cop. Quinlan has built his whole career based on his larger-than-life personality, and no one in his town is going to try to change his techniques. Welles was born to play this role. Two supporting characters deserve mention: Dennis Weaver as the Mirador Motel Night Manager. He turns in a brilliant performance that combines stupidity, timidity, and rigidity in equal parts. Marlene Dietrich plays Tanya, a former flame of Quinlan's from the days when he was young and handsome. Dietrich--who looks sad, cynical, and very beautiful--delivers the best line of the film. Quinlan asks her to read his future in her Tarot cards. She tells him, "You haven't got any. Your future is all used up." This is a movie worth seeking out and seeing. It will work better on a large screen. However, even in DVD, it's a must-see film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Way He Sees and Lets Us See
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Antti Keisala
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Orson Welles is one director to whom I'm drawn time and again for refreshment and reinvigoration. He's leagues beyond me, and in the words of Fran&ccedil;ois Truffaut, "When you come out of 'Touch of Evil' you feel less intelligent than before but gratified anyhow by the poetry and art."* Yet there are certain things I always know to look for, whether the film in question is "Citizen Kane" (1941), "The Tragedy of Othello: The Moor of Venice" (1952), "Mr. Arkadin" (1955) or "F for Fake" (1973): the narrative is going to be free-flowingly evasive and explorative, always interested not finding out the truth but rather becoming aware of all the layers of fabrication within the narrative; and the way he sees and lets us see the world will be breathtaking. And so it is. His way of moving the camera with absolute effortlessness astonishes each time, so does the lighting of the interiors and the way he shoots claustrophobic closed spaces. Heston and Welles play wonderfully together, and Welles' performance is among the highlights of his career. Dietrich's character refers to Von Sternberg's "Der Blaue Engel" (1930), a satire about a sexual free fall, a strong undersong in this film. The film's production history, as that of many other films by Welles, is closely linked to the film itself. As such, "Touch of Evil" is also rewarding as an artifact of film history. It's interesting to read Welles' 58-page memo (available online) and compare to any of the versions available. Watching them either chronologically or in reverse order is great fun. So is comparing the aspect ratios. The Region B Blu-ray released by the Masters of Cinema series is most certainly at the summit of the format and what can be done with it. On two Blu-rays there are the three existing versions of the film (the 1958 theatrical version, the 1958 preview version and the 1998 reconstructed version), the 1958 theatrical and the 1998 reconstruction presented in two aspect ratios. They are beautiful transfers, and host interesting and informative commentary tracks. I see myself revisiting this, and then revisiting it again. And again. * The review "Touch of Evil", by Fran&ccedil;ois Truffaut, originally published in "Arts" (June 4, 1958), available in the collection "Les films de ma vie" (1975) and translated into English as "The Films of My Life" (1978). I read this review in the booklet of the Masters of Cinema Blu-ray (p. 5).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    holy cow is this a good movie!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    xhearto
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    thrills! chills! Welles! if you feel like you've seen this movie a thousand times upon first viewing, it's probably because almost every moment has been "borrowed" by filmmakers for over half a century. And then copied by people who saw the borrowings. journey to the dark heart of man? Check. Marlene smoking over a crystal ball? Check. Janet terrorized in a motel? Check. Orson at the pinnacle of his game? Check. a shining example of what defines the difference between a film and a "movie" check. top ten list.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Macho Man?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gamay9
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Film noir at its' best....and, what a cast! The only unlikely scene is where Susie (Janet Leigh) is screaming for help from a fire escape and Vargas (Charleton Heston) drives right by, heads for a bar and roughs up the thugs....meanwhile Susie is arrested and jailed. Wouldn't a macho guy like Heston aid his wife first and then confront the thugs? After all, this is 1958 when guys rolled cigarette packs into their t-shirt sleeves. That was a lame scene. One of the actors, Calleia, was the director; not Hitchcock. It would have been easy for Heston to have the script changed to a more likely scenario. Otherwise, I enjoyed the film; anytime one can see Janet Leigh, Charleton Heston, Orson Welles, Marlene Deitrich (dark-haired Mexican) and Dennis Weaver in the same film, it's a blast!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Touch of Evil
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Directed by and starring Orson Welles, I may remember watching the first ten or something minutes of this film but giving up on it, I was certainly up for giving it another chance when I saw it listed and recommended as one of the 1001 Movies You Must See Before You Die in the book. Basically on the border between the United States of America and Mexico a time bomb is planted in the boot of a car, and it is drives to cross the border, and a couple of times newlyweds Ramon Miguel 'Mike' Vargas (Charlton Heston) and Susan 'Susie' (Janet Leigh) pass the vehicle before it crosses, and after doing so it blows up and kills the passengers. Mike works for the Mexican government as a drug enforcement official, and knowing the implications of bombs from Mexico to America exploding he decides to join in any investigation he can, and also looking into it are police Chief Gould (Harry Shannon) and District Attorney Adair (Ray Collins), but also the peculiar Police Captain Hank Quinlan (Orson Welles) and his long time partner Police Sergeant Pete Menzies (Joseph Calleia). Young Mexican man Manelo Sanchez (Victor Millan) is the prime suspect for Quinlan and Menzies, as he was secretly married to the daughter of one of the victims in the explosion, Mike is there during the interrogation, he accidentally knocks over an empty shoebox, and in moments this same box two sticks of dynamite are in it, so Mike suspects Quinlan has been planting evidence to help with his convictions over the years. Although Quinlan denies this Vargas still wants to see his public case records, so Al Schwartz (Mort Mills), the District Attorney's assistant lets him study them, and Gould and Adair are shown the findings as well, but Quinlan himself comes in and threatens resignation in anger over their discussion. There is a risk of the brother of a man Mike was investigating, 'Uncle' Joe Grandi (Akim Tamiroff) trying to expose things, so Susie moves from their Mexican hotel to a motel in America, one that Menzies recommended, staffed by mentally challenged Night Manager (Duel's Dennis Weaver) and with no other guests staying, but family members of Grandi take over the motel. Mike becomes worried when he tries telephoning Susie and she does not answer, in fact Quinlan has arrangement with Grandi that his gang will kidnap her, inject her with drugs and taken to another motel out of town, and indeed this happens, Quinlan murders Grandi and Susie is framed for the murder to give her husband a bad name. Mike goes to have a word with Menzies about the history of the cases he and Quinlan investigating and "found" evidence in, he dismisses any conspiracy he has, and then he goes looking for his wife at the motel but she and her gun have gone, so he goes to the other motel that Grandi owns and confronts his gang, they refuse to answer questions so he beats them up. Schwartz tells him that Susie was arrested for murder, but when he finds her she is barely conscious, and then Menzies comes to tell him that Quinlan's cane was found at the scene of Grandi's murder, so Mike fits him with a wire so he can go to see his partner and hear a conversation between them. At an oil field is where Quinlan and Menzies meet to discuss their activities while Mike records everything, the traitor cop admits he planted evidence on people to make them guiltier than they already were, but the tapping is uncovered by the sound of static. Quinlan knows that Mike is there watching and listening, and in the heat of the moment he shoots Menzies with Vargas's gun, but before he can shoot Mike dead Menzies gets up and shoots Quinlan, Menzies dies and eventually so does Quinlan, Sanchez is revealed to have admitted to the crime of planting the car bomb, and Mike leaves town with a recovered Susie. Also starring Joanna Moore as Marcia Linnekar , Valentin De Vargas as Pancho, Lalo Rios as Risto , Marlene Dietrich as Tanya, Zsa Zsa Gabor as Strip-Club Owner, The Third Man's Joseph Cotten as Coroner and The Exorcist's Mercedes McCambridge as Gang Leader. Heston gives a good performance as the man determined to get to the truth of the matter, Leigh gets her moments as the wife pulled into the situations, but obviously Welles is best part of this film as the treacherous cop with the villainous dark side, and his direction is well paced as well, some supporting cast members, especially Dietrich, are terrific as well. The film opens with one of the most famous long shots in cinema which is played out so well with clever tracking, and the film is filled with interesting material about conspiracy, double-crossing, murder and melodrama, it is one of the last true film noir style pictures, I admit I lost track of plot on occasions, but overall it is a watchable classic crime thriller. Very good!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just a Touch of American Stereotypes
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rexx Villotti
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    During his honeymoon, Mexican police officer Mike Vargas (Charlton Heston) is dragged into a deadly battler with the respected-but- corrupted American Police Captain Hank Quinlan (Orson Welles). While protecting his wife, avoiding prejudice, and trying to uncover the truth, Vargas has more foes to deal with than he thinks. Involving Mexican drug smugglers, kidnappers, and the dimwitted American police force, Quinlan tries to discredit and stop his attempt to uncover the truth. One of the Film Noirs, Orson Welles' "Touch of Evil" is a Mexican border town mystery unlike any other. In other movies with the same setting, "A Fist Full of Dollars" for example, the hero would be an attractive American cowboy and the villain would be a dirty, greedy Mexican. In typical Welles fashion of breaking film norms, he flips the American image of good and evil. The villain, portrayed by Welles himself, is a fat, corrupt American Cop. While Quinlan is the villain, Welles also makes him the victim also. He is a victim of himself, and from the police work that has consumed his life and humanity. Welles intentionally creates these characters to break free from the chains that often bind him and other film directors of the time. There is not a clear cut plot that can be seen and set up in the first few minutes of the film, the viewers are taken from crime scenes to mobster run hotels before they glimpse at the corrupt American police at work. The main plot cannot be set up very easily in this film without the proper introduction to the characters. For example, the viewer must understand why the Grandi mob family wants Vargas dead. Without this knowledge that the film provides in the action leading up to the reveal of police activities, the viewers would be left wondering why the mob family is so eager to be involved in American police business. This complex plot combined with Welles' dynamic and intriguing cinematography creates a thrilling game of wits between American and Mexican police.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dynamite Opening Crane Shot
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    romanorum1
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A shadowy man places a time-bomb in the trunk of a new Chrysler and runs away just before another man and a woman enter and drive off. In the darkness, among the sounds of traffic and seedy strip clubs and gaudy hotels in the Mexican border town of Los Robles, the auto meanders across the border into the USA. We see crumbling arches and peeling walls. For more than three minutes we wonder what will happen. Tick  tick  tick  The Chrysler passes by mustached Charlton Heston (Mike Vargas) and stunning Janet Leigh (Susan Vargas). As Mike stops to kiss his new wife, we hear the explosion, and there is a cut to the burning vehicle. "This could be very bad for us, utters Mike." Vargas, as a police investigator (and Chairman of the Pan-American Narcotics Commission), was returning to Mexico to testify against Vic Grandi's Mexican crime family. As the explosion occurred on the American side of the border, police chief Harry Quinlan (Orson Welles) is called in to investigate. Bloated, stubbly, puffy-faced Quinlan has a history of planting evidence to convict those whom he wants. Sweating, he oozes corruption from every pore. "You're a mess," fortune-teller Tana (Marlene Dietrich) would later tell him. To Quinlan's displeasure, Vargas decides to hang around because of his concern that his native Mexico may be involved in an international incident. He tells his wife to return to the hotel. She gets intercepted by a gang who takes her to "visit" Uncle Joe Grandi (Akim Tamiroff). He warns her to tell her husband to desist from the Grandi trial, or else. The man who died in the car explosion was Rudolph Linnekar, a wealthy contractor; his girl was a blonde night club dancer. Mexican Manelo Sanchez, a shoe clerk, who had been dating Linnekar's daughter Marcia against her father's wishes, is visited by Quinlan. Now Sanchez does not really care for Marcia, but, as he freely admits, likes only her money. Quinlan, who maintains that Sanchez murdered Rudolph Linnekar because the latter disapproved of Sanchez's marriage to Marcia, plants two sticks of dynamite in a box in Sanchez's bathroom. As Vargas knows that Quinlan planted the evidence, he does not abide by the arrest. He decides to gather evidence against him, and begins working with honest assistant DA Schwartz. Meanwhile Susan Vargas is in danger; as her husband had inconceivably left her alone. She moved to the Mirador Motel, which consists of a number of uninhabited cabins in the desert. Neither her husband nor she can imagine that the hotel is owned by Uncle Joe Grandi. She is the only customer, and he has plans for her, as his leather-jacketed gang of thugs often operates from there. Her only shield  and he really is not one  is neurotic Dennis Weaver, the night man. He acts more psycho than Norman Bates, without the latter's murders. Since Quinlan is quickly onto Mike's intention, he is forced to work with Uncle Joe to frame wife Susan as a druggie. So Susan, besieged in her room, is easy prey for the gang. She is drugged and apparently gang-raped while lesbian leader Mercedes McCambridge watches. Then Susan is brought to a different hotel where she lies unconscious while surrounded by drug paraphernalia. Both Uncle Joe and Quinlan arrive there, but Quinlan turns against him and strangles Joe and leaves evidence to implicate Susan. But he inexplicably leaves his cane in the room, which his sergeant, Pete Menzies (Joseph Calleia) later finds. Menzies has been Quinlan's stooge for years, and although he probably could not exist without Quinlan, soon decides to reverse his previous deeds. Before long, Menzies and Vargas are working together to tape record Quinlan admission of his decadence among the pumping oil derricks and garbage heaps at a canal. Bullets will be fired, and only one of the three will walk away. And only in the end is it confirmed for certain who placed the bomb in the car trunk (although the culprit is obvious). Orson Welles was already a giant for his excellent portrayal in "Citizen Kane" (1942), considered by many critics as the greatest movie of all time. Those who feel that Charlton Heston was miscast should be aware that he portrayed various historical figures. They include Moses, Marc Antony, John the Baptist, El Cid, Michelangelo, both Henry VIII and Sir Thomas More (!), Cardinal Richelieu, Lt. William Clark (of Lewis and Clark fame), Thomas Jefferson, Andrew Jackson, Abe Lincoln, Brigham Young, General "Chinese" Gordon, and Buffalo Bill Cody. Heston could pass as a Mexican of European heritage. Vivacious Janet Leigh was already famous; she had starred in "Angels in the Outfield" (1951), "Scaramouche" (1952), and "The Naked Spur" (1953). The last one is considered by Leonard Maltin to be one of the greatest westerns ever made. Psycho would follow (1960), and Manchurian Candidate after that (1962). The greatness of the movie is not its message; in fact, one may even identify several peculiar settings. Those who hate the movie generally dislike the material. But the film's prominence is in HOW the story is told. It is like "Citizen Kane," which has a rather thin plot, but an incredible revelation. Take the hotel room scene where Welles takes Janet Leigh's nylon stocking and wraps it around his fingers. He looks menacingly at Akim Tamiroff while the neon lights flash from outside. It is a hungry lion facing a trapped antelope. Uncle Joe is finished, and he knows it. "Touch of Evil" has high-level technical qualities of expressionist lighting and shadow, low camera angles, wide-angle lens, and dark, brooding photography. The movie has atmosphere in miles. Henry Mancini's dazzling sound track hits the spot (and works very well even in the truncated 95-minute version of the movie). As "Touch of Evil" is recognized by enthusiasts as one of the greatest movies made in world cinema history, it appears on many Top 100 Lists.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    strange gem
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vincentiu
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    a special form of masterpiece. common story. minimalist scenes. but seed of genius. not a surprise - Orson Welles can be himself - but the joy to discover an admirable construction remains. secret - the cast. Marlene Dietrich in a role of few lines who preserves mystery and seduction, Janet Leigh as innocent victim of dark business, Charlton Heston as Charlton Heston and Welles in a role like a fascinating puzzle. it is more than a film. it is not exactly a masterpiece for usual definition. it is a gem. why ? after see it, you may be have an answer. or, only, a sketch about this precise exercise of precision in each of details.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just a touch
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kosmasp
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Orson Welles did have a "magic touch" (no pun intended), although it didn't always translate into commercial success. Which of course had to do with the studios being reluctant giving him the free reign he had on his Citizen Kane classic. There are quite a few versions out there of this movie and we got treated to one of them (close to what Welles imagined at the time as biographer told us) at the Berlin International Festival. When I say close, it does mean that it's as close to what Welles would have wanted in the movie (from the footage that was shot), especially concerning the audio in the beginning. He had a vision in his head and the studio bosses wouldn't always agree with him. Another problem might have been that he himself wasn't always satisfied and would change things. So while the version I saw, was close to a memo he send to the studio (suggesting cuts and especially the audio change in the beginning), he might have changed all that at a later time, if he had the chance (at least he might have written another memo after watching it the way, he wanted it to be). Having said and written all that, the movie has a powerful performance by Charlton Heston as well. Characters reactions to some things might feel dated or clich&eacute;, but that is just because we have seen other films copying some of the working formula that is being used here. B&W it might be, but it still has quite a punch to it ... morally and otherwise
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The best Film Noir & one of the all-time greatest films.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stephen-scott83
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I first watched Touch of Evil I was absolutely astounded. I was mesmerised by Orson and the simply remarkable depth of his character. I rank this movie as the greatest film noir ever made and one of the greatest movies ever made. It's that simple. I watch this movie at least 2-3 times a month. Orson's character, Hank Quinlan is the ultimate crooked, bigot cop. This character is like a monster that no one seems to know how to stop. That's the easy description, the true genius is in the script, mannerisms and camera angles. You could not make this film in color, it wouldn't work. One of my favorite aspects about this movie is the subtle use of sarcasm - especially Quinlan's Sargeant - that leads to the overall mood of arrogance spread out in this amazing movie. This movie requires multiple viewings if you really want to appreciate the stunning script and superlative camera shots/angles. Dennis Weaver's character is in my opinion, one of the most bizarre in movie history especially considering there was no development his hyper-manic oddball character. Truly bizarre - but so entertaining! The cameo by Zsa Zsa Gabor is neat but the extended "cameo" by Marlene Dietrich is stunning. I bought this movie after 1 viewing - safe to say, you will too. Orson, thank you, thank you, thank you for making this CLASSIC!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "You don't have a future."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Red-125
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Touch of Evil (1958), scripted and directed by Orson Welles, is deservedly one of IMDb's top 250 movies. The story of the movie as a movie is almost as dramatic as the plot of the film. Before the editing took place, Welles was removed from the project. He responded with a long, detailed memo about how the film should be edited. This memo was mostly ignored, and an inferior short version of Touch of Evil was released in theaters and later for the small screen. Fortunately, years later, with immense effort, most of the original footage was salvaged, and the film was reconstructed almost in the way Welles had envisioned it. This longer version was what we saw in the excellent--and newly refurbished-- Dryden Theatre at Eastman House in Rochester, NY. The film seems dated today, but it's still powerful and engrossing. Charlton Heston plays Mike Vargas, a high-ranking Mexican police official. He has just married an American, Susan, played by Janet Leigh. They become involved in a murder investigation because someone dies when dynamite is placed in a car in Mexico, but the explosion takes place across the border in the U.S. It's at this point that Vargas has to interact with Police Captain Hank Quinlan, played by Welles. Quinlan is an overweight, limping, unshaven bully. However, he has almost magical powers to detect criminals, who are then invariably convicted. The means he uses in his investigations are not found in a police manual. So, it's clear from the beginning that Vargas wears the white hat and Quinlan wears the black hat. Janet Leigh is wasted in her role as naive and gullible young wife. Heston does a good job as the straight arrow cop. Welles, of course, is perfect for the role of a (really) bad cop. Quinlan has built his whole career based on his larger-than-life personality, and no one in his town is going to try to change his techniques. Welles was born to play this role. Two supporting characters deserve mention: Dennis Weaver as the Mirador Motel Night Manager. He turns in a brilliant performance that combines stupidity, timidity, and rigidity in equal parts. Marlene Dietrich plays Tanya, a former flame of Quinlan's from the days when he was young and handsome. Dietrich--who looks sad, cynical, and very beautiful--delivers the best line of the film. Quinlan asks her to read his future in her Tarot cards. She tells him, "You haven't got any. Your future is all used up." This is a movie worth seeking out and seeing. It will work better on a large screen. However, even in DVD, it's a must-see film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Way He Sees and Lets Us See
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Antti Keisala
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Orson Welles is one director to whom I'm drawn time and again for refreshment and reinvigoration. He's leagues beyond me, and in the words of Fran&ccedil;ois Truffaut, "When you come out of 'Touch of Evil' you feel less intelligent than before but gratified anyhow by the poetry and art."* Yet there are certain things I always know to look for, whether the film in question is "Citizen Kane" (1941), "The Tragedy of Othello: The Moor of Venice" (1952), "Mr. Arkadin" (1955) or "F for Fake" (1973): the narrative is going to be free-flowingly evasive and explorative, always interested not finding out the truth but rather becoming aware of all the layers of fabrication within the narrative; and the way he sees and lets us see the world will be breathtaking. And so it is. His way of moving the camera with absolute effortlessness astonishes each time, so does the lighting of the interiors and the way he shoots claustrophobic closed spaces. Heston and Welles play wonderfully together, and Welles' performance is among the highlights of his career. Dietrich's character refers to Von Sternberg's "Der Blaue Engel" (1930), a satire about a sexual free fall, a strong undersong in this film. The film's production history, as that of many other films by Welles, is closely linked to the film itself. As such, "Touch of Evil" is also rewarding as an artifact of film history. It's interesting to read Welles' 58-page memo (available online) and compare to any of the versions available. Watching them either chronologically or in reverse order is great fun. So is comparing the aspect ratios. The Region B Blu-ray released by the Masters of Cinema series is most certainly at the summit of the format and what can be done with it. On two Blu-rays there are the three existing versions of the film (the 1958 theatrical version, the 1958 preview version and the 1998 reconstructed version), the 1958 theatrical and the 1998 reconstruction presented in two aspect ratios. They are beautiful transfers, and host interesting and informative commentary tracks. I see myself revisiting this, and then revisiting it again. And again. * The review "Touch of Evil", by Fran&ccedil;ois Truffaut, originally published in "Arts" (June 4, 1958), available in the collection "Les films de ma vie" (1975) and translated into English as "The Films of My Life" (1978). I read this review in the booklet of the Masters of Cinema Blu-ray (p. 5).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    holy cow is this a good movie!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    xhearto
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    thrills! chills! Welles! if you feel like you've seen this movie a thousand times upon first viewing, it's probably because almost every moment has been "borrowed" by filmmakers for over half a century. And then copied by people who saw the borrowings. journey to the dark heart of man? Check. Marlene smoking over a crystal ball? Check. Janet terrorized in a motel? Check. Orson at the pinnacle of his game? Check. a shining example of what defines the difference between a film and a "movie" check. top ten list.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Macho Man?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gamay9
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Film noir at its' best....and, what a cast! The only unlikely scene is where Susie (Janet Leigh) is screaming for help from a fire escape and Vargas (Charleton Heston) drives right by, heads for a bar and roughs up the thugs....meanwhile Susie is arrested and jailed. Wouldn't a macho guy like Heston aid his wife first and then confront the thugs? After all, this is 1958 when guys rolled cigarette packs into their t-shirt sleeves. That was a lame scene. One of the actors, Calleia, was the director; not Hitchcock. It would have been easy for Heston to have the script changed to a more likely scenario. Otherwise, I enjoyed the film; anytime one can see Janet Leigh, Charleton Heston, Orson Welles, Marlene Deitrich (dark-haired Mexican) and Dennis Weaver in the same film, it's a blast!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Touch of Evil
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Directed by and starring Orson Welles, I may remember watching the first ten or something minutes of this film but giving up on it, I was certainly up for giving it another chance when I saw it listed and recommended as one of the 1001 Movies You Must See Before You Die in the book. Basically on the border between the United States of America and Mexico a time bomb is planted in the boot of a car, and it is drives to cross the border, and a couple of times newlyweds Ramon Miguel 'Mike' Vargas (Charlton Heston) and Susan 'Susie' (Janet Leigh) pass the vehicle before it crosses, and after doing so it blows up and kills the passengers. Mike works for the Mexican government as a drug enforcement official, and knowing the implications of bombs from Mexico to America exploding he decides to join in any investigation he can, and also looking into it are police Chief Gould (Harry Shannon) and District Attorney Adair (Ray Collins), but also the peculiar Police Captain Hank Quinlan (Orson Welles) and his long time partner Police Sergeant Pete Menzies (Joseph Calleia). Young Mexican man Manelo Sanchez (Victor Millan) is the prime suspect for Quinlan and Menzies, as he was secretly married to the daughter of one of the victims in the explosion, Mike is there during the interrogation, he accidentally knocks over an empty shoebox, and in moments this same box two sticks of dynamite are in it, so Mike suspects Quinlan has been planting evidence to help with his convictions over the years. Although Quinlan denies this Vargas still wants to see his public case records, so Al Schwartz (Mort Mills), the District Attorney's assistant lets him study them, and Gould and Adair are shown the findings as well, but Quinlan himself comes in and threatens resignation in anger over their discussion. There is a risk of the brother of a man Mike was investigating, 'Uncle' Joe Grandi (Akim Tamiroff) trying to expose things, so Susie moves from their Mexican hotel to a motel in America, one that Menzies recommended, staffed by mentally challenged Night Manager (Duel's Dennis Weaver) and with no other guests staying, but family members of Grandi take over the motel. Mike becomes worried when he tries telephoning Susie and she does not answer, in fact Quinlan has arrangement with Grandi that his gang will kidnap her, inject her with drugs and taken to another motel out of town, and indeed this happens, Quinlan murders Grandi and Susie is framed for the murder to give her husband a bad name. Mike goes to have a word with Menzies about the history of the cases he and Quinlan investigating and "found" evidence in, he dismisses any conspiracy he has, and then he goes looking for his wife at the motel but she and her gun have gone, so he goes to the other motel that Grandi owns and confronts his gang, they refuse to answer questions so he beats them up. Schwartz tells him that Susie was arrested for murder, but when he finds her she is barely conscious, and then Menzies comes to tell him that Quinlan's cane was found at the scene of Grandi's murder, so Mike fits him with a wire so he can go to see his partner and hear a conversation between them. At an oil field is where Quinlan and Menzies meet to discuss their activities while Mike records everything, the traitor cop admits he planted evidence on people to make them guiltier than they already were, but the tapping is uncovered by the sound of static. Quinlan knows that Mike is there watching and listening, and in the heat of the moment he shoots Menzies with Vargas's gun, but before he can shoot Mike dead Menzies gets up and shoots Quinlan, Menzies dies and eventually so does Quinlan, Sanchez is revealed to have admitted to the crime of planting the car bomb, and Mike leaves town with a recovered Susie. Also starring Joanna Moore as Marcia Linnekar , Valentin De Vargas as Pancho, Lalo Rios as Risto , Marlene Dietrich as Tanya, Zsa Zsa Gabor as Strip-Club Owner, The Third Man's Joseph Cotten as Coroner and The Exorcist's Mercedes McCambridge as Gang Leader. Heston gives a good performance as the man determined to get to the truth of the matter, Leigh gets her moments as the wife pulled into the situations, but obviously Welles is best part of this film as the treacherous cop with the villainous dark side, and his direction is well paced as well, some supporting cast members, especially Dietrich, are terrific as well. The film opens with one of the most famous long shots in cinema which is played out so well with clever tracking, and the film is filled with interesting material about conspiracy, double-crossing, murder and melodrama, it is one of the last true film noir style pictures, I admit I lost track of plot on occasions, but overall it is a watchable classic crime thriller. Very good!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just a Touch of American Stereotypes
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rexx Villotti
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    During his honeymoon, Mexican police officer Mike Vargas (Charlton Heston) is dragged into a deadly battler with the respected-but- corrupted American Police Captain Hank Quinlan (Orson Welles). While protecting his wife, avoiding prejudice, and trying to uncover the truth, Vargas has more foes to deal with than he thinks. Involving Mexican drug smugglers, kidnappers, and the dimwitted American police force, Quinlan tries to discredit and stop his attempt to uncover the truth. One of the Film Noirs, Orson Welles' "Touch of Evil" is a Mexican border town mystery unlike any other. In other movies with the same setting, "A Fist Full of Dollars" for example, the hero would be an attractive American cowboy and the villain would be a dirty, greedy Mexican. In typical Welles fashion of breaking film norms, he flips the American image of good and evil. The villain, portrayed by Welles himself, is a fat, corrupt American Cop. While Quinlan is the villain, Welles also makes him the victim also. He is a victim of himself, and from the police work that has consumed his life and humanity. Welles intentionally creates these characters to break free from the chains that often bind him and other film directors of the time. There is not a clear cut plot that can be seen and set up in the first few minutes of the film, the viewers are taken from crime scenes to mobster run hotels before they glimpse at the corrupt American police at work. The main plot cannot be set up very easily in this film without the proper introduction to the characters. For example, the viewer must understand why the Grandi mob family wants Vargas dead. Without this knowledge that the film provides in the action leading up to the reveal of police activities, the viewers would be left wondering why the mob family is so eager to be involved in American police business. This complex plot combined with Welles' dynamic and intriguing cinematography creates a thrilling game of wits between American and Mexican police.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dynamite Opening Crane Shot
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    romanorum1
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A shadowy man places a time-bomb in the trunk of a new Chrysler and runs away just before another man and a woman enter and drive off. In the darkness, among the sounds of traffic and seedy strip clubs and gaudy hotels in the Mexican border town of Los Robles, the auto meanders across the border into the USA. We see crumbling arches and peeling walls. For more than three minutes we wonder what will happen. Tick  tick  tick  The Chrysler passes by mustached Charlton Heston (Mike Vargas) and stunning Janet Leigh (Susan Vargas). As Mike stops to kiss his new wife, we hear the explosion, and there is a cut to the burning vehicle. "This could be very bad for us, utters Mike." Vargas, as a police investigator (and Chairman of the Pan-American Narcotics Commission), was returning to Mexico to testify against Vic Grandi's Mexican crime family. As the explosion occurred on the American side of the border, police chief Harry Quinlan (Orson Welles) is called in to investigate. Bloated, stubbly, puffy-faced Quinlan has a history of planting evidence to convict those whom he wants. Sweating, he oozes corruption from every pore. "You're a mess," fortune-teller Tana (Marlene Dietrich) would later tell him. To Quinlan's displeasure, Vargas decides to hang around because of his concern that his native Mexico may be involved in an international incident. He tells his wife to return to the hotel. She gets intercepted by a gang who takes her to "visit" Uncle Joe Grandi (Akim Tamiroff). He warns her to tell her husband to desist from the Grandi trial, or else. The man who died in the car explosion was Rudolph Linnekar, a wealthy contractor; his girl was a blonde night club dancer. Mexican Manelo Sanchez, a shoe clerk, who had been dating Linnekar's daughter Marcia against her father's wishes, is visited by Quinlan. Now Sanchez does not really care for Marcia, but, as he freely admits, likes only her money. Quinlan, who maintains that Sanchez murdered Rudolph Linnekar because the latter disapproved of Sanchez's marriage to Marcia, plants two sticks of dynamite in a box in Sanchez's bathroom. As Vargas knows that Quinlan planted the evidence, he does not abide by the arrest. He decides to gather evidence against him, and begins working with honest assistant DA Schwartz. Meanwhile Susan Vargas is in danger; as her husband had inconceivably left her alone. She moved to the Mirador Motel, which consists of a number of uninhabited cabins in the desert. Neither her husband nor she can imagine that the hotel is owned by Uncle Joe Grandi. She is the only customer, and he has plans for her, as his leather-jacketed gang of thugs often operates from there. Her only shield  and he really is not one  is neurotic Dennis Weaver, the night man. He acts more psycho than Norman Bates, without the latter's murders. Since Quinlan is quickly onto Mike's intention, he is forced to work with Uncle Joe to frame wife Susan as a druggie. So Susan, besieged in her room, is easy prey for the gang. She is drugged and apparently gang-raped while lesbian leader Mercedes McCambridge watches. Then Susan is brought to a different hotel where she lies unconscious while surrounded by drug paraphernalia. Both Uncle Joe and Quinlan arrive there, but Quinlan turns against him and strangles Joe and leaves evidence to implicate Susan. But he inexplicably leaves his cane in the room, which his sergeant, Pete Menzies (Joseph Calleia) later finds. Menzies has been Quinlan's stooge for years, and although he probably could not exist without Quinlan, soon decides to reverse his previous deeds. Before long, Menzies and Vargas are working together to tape record Quinlan admission of his decadence among the pumping oil derricks and garbage heaps at a canal. Bullets will be fired, and only one of the three will walk away. And only in the end is it confirmed for certain who placed the bomb in the car trunk (although the culprit is obvious). Orson Welles was already a giant for his excellent portrayal in "Citizen Kane" (1942), considered by many critics as the greatest movie of all time. Those who feel that Charlton Heston was miscast should be aware that he portrayed various historical figures. They include Moses, Marc Antony, John the Baptist, El Cid, Michelangelo, both Henry VIII and Sir Thomas More (!), Cardinal Richelieu, Lt. William Clark (of Lewis and Clark fame), Thomas Jefferson, Andrew Jackson, Abe Lincoln, Brigham Young, General "Chinese" Gordon, and Buffalo Bill Cody. Heston could pass as a Mexican of European heritage. Vivacious Janet Leigh was already famous; she had starred in "Angels in the Outfield" (1951), "Scaramouche" (1952), and "The Naked Spur" (1953). The last one is considered by Leonard Maltin to be one of the greatest westerns ever made. Psycho would follow (1960), and Manchurian Candidate after that (1962). The greatness of the movie is not its message; in fact, one may even identify several peculiar settings. Those who hate the movie generally dislike the material. But the film's prominence is in HOW the story is told. It is like "Citizen Kane," which has a rather thin plot, but an incredible revelation. Take the hotel room scene where Welles takes Janet Leigh's nylon stocking and wraps it around his fingers. He looks menacingly at Akim Tamiroff while the neon lights flash from outside. It is a hungry lion facing a trapped antelope. Uncle Joe is finished, and he knows it. "Touch of Evil" has high-level technical qualities of expressionist lighting and shadow, low camera angles, wide-angle lens, and dark, brooding photography. The movie has atmosphere in miles. Henry Mancini's dazzling sound track hits the spot (and works very well even in the truncated 95-minute version of the movie). As "Touch of Evil" is recognized by enthusiasts as one of the greatest movies made in world cinema history, it appears on many Top 100 Lists.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    strange gem
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vincentiu
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    a special form of masterpiece. common story. minimalist scenes. but seed of genius. not a surprise - Orson Welles can be himself - but the joy to discover an admirable construction remains. secret - the cast. Marlene Dietrich in a role of few lines who preserves mystery and seduction, Janet Leigh as innocent victim of dark business, Charlton Heston as Charlton Heston and Welles in a role like a fascinating puzzle. it is more than a film. it is not exactly a masterpiece for usual definition. it is a gem. why ? after see it, you may be have an answer. or, only, a sketch about this precise exercise of precision in each of details.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just a touch
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kosmasp
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Orson Welles did have a "magic touch" (no pun intended), although it didn't always translate into commercial success. Which of course had to do with the studios being reluctant giving him the free reign he had on his Citizen Kane classic. There are quite a few versions out there of this movie and we got treated to one of them (close to what Welles imagined at the time as biographer told us) at the Berlin International Festival. When I say close, it does mean that it's as close to what Welles would have wanted in the movie (from the footage that was shot), especially concerning the audio in the beginning. He had a vision in his head and the studio bosses wouldn't always agree with him. Another problem might have been that he himself wasn't always satisfied and would change things. So while the version I saw, was close to a memo he send to the studio (suggesting cuts and especially the audio change in the beginning), he might have changed all that at a later time, if he had the chance (at least he might have written another memo after watching it the way, he wanted it to be). Having said and written all that, the movie has a powerful performance by Charlton Heston as well. Characters reactions to some things might feel dated or clich&eacute;, but that is just because we have seen other films copying some of the working formula that is being used here. B&W it might be, but it still has quite a punch to it ... morally and otherwise
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The best Film Noir & one of the all-time greatest films.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stephen-scott83
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I first watched Touch of Evil I was absolutely astounded. I was mesmerised by Orson and the simply remarkable depth of his character. I rank this movie as the greatest film noir ever made and one of the greatest movies ever made. It's that simple. I watch this movie at least 2-3 times a month. Orson's character, Hank Quinlan is the ultimate crooked, bigot cop. This character is like a monster that no one seems to know how to stop. That's the easy description, the true genius is in the script, mannerisms and camera angles. You could not make this film in color, it wouldn't work. One of my favorite aspects about this movie is the subtle use of sarcasm - especially Quinlan's Sargeant - that leads to the overall mood of arrogance spread out in this amazing movie. This movie requires multiple viewings if you really want to appreciate the stunning script and superlative camera shots/angles. Dennis Weaver's character is in my opinion, one of the most bizarre in movie history especially considering there was no development his hyper-manic oddball character. Truly bizarre - but so entertaining! The cameo by Zsa Zsa Gabor is neat but the extended "cameo" by Marlene Dietrich is stunning. I bought this movie after 1 viewing - safe to say, you will too. Orson, thank you, thank you, thank you for making this CLASSIC!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "You don't have a future."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Red-125
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Touch of Evil (1958), scripted and directed by Orson Welles, is deservedly one of IMDb's top 250 movies. The story of the movie as a movie is almost as dramatic as the plot of the film. Before the editing took place, Welles was removed from the project. He responded with a long, detailed memo about how the film should be edited. This memo was mostly ignored, and an inferior short version of Touch of Evil was released in theaters and later for the small screen. Fortunately, years later, with immense effort, most of the original footage was salvaged, and the film was reconstructed almost in the way Welles had envisioned it. This longer version was what we saw in the excellent--and newly refurbished-- Dryden Theatre at Eastman House in Rochester, NY. The film seems dated today, but it's still powerful and engrossing. Charlton Heston plays Mike Vargas, a high-ranking Mexican police official. He has just married an American, Susan, played by Janet Leigh. They become involved in a murder investigation because someone dies when dynamite is placed in a car in Mexico, but the explosion takes place across the border in the U.S. It's at this point that Vargas has to interact with Police Captain Hank Quinlan, played by Welles. Quinlan is an overweight, limping, unshaven bully. However, he has almost magical powers to detect criminals, who are then invariably convicted. The means he uses in his investigations are not found in a police manual. So, it's clear from the beginning that Vargas wears the white hat and Quinlan wears the black hat. Janet Leigh is wasted in her role as naive and gullible young wife. Heston does a good job as the straight arrow cop. Welles, of course, is perfect for the role of a (really) bad cop. Quinlan has built his whole career based on his larger-than-life personality, and no one in his town is going to try to change his techniques. Welles was born to play this role. Two supporting characters deserve mention: Dennis Weaver as the Mirador Motel Night Manager. He turns in a brilliant performance that combines stupidity, timidity, and rigidity in equal parts. Marlene Dietrich plays Tanya, a former flame of Quinlan's from the days when he was young and handsome. Dietrich--who looks sad, cynical, and very beautiful--delivers the best line of the film. Quinlan asks her to read his future in her Tarot cards. She tells him, "You haven't got any. Your future is all used up." This is a movie worth seeking out and seeing. It will work better on a large screen. However, even in DVD, it's a must-see film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Way He Sees and Lets Us See
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Antti Keisala
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Orson Welles is one director to whom I'm drawn time and again for refreshment and reinvigoration. He's leagues beyond me, and in the words of Fran&ccedil;ois Truffaut, "When you come out of 'Touch of Evil' you feel less intelligent than before but gratified anyhow by the poetry and art."* Yet there are certain things I always know to look for, whether the film in question is "Citizen Kane" (1941), "The Tragedy of Othello: The Moor of Venice" (1952), "Mr. Arkadin" (1955) or "F for Fake" (1973): the narrative is going to be free-flowingly evasive and explorative, always interested not finding out the truth but rather becoming aware of all the layers of fabrication within the narrative; and the way he sees and lets us see the world will be breathtaking. And so it is. His way of moving the camera with absolute effortlessness astonishes each time, so does the lighting of the interiors and the way he shoots claustrophobic closed spaces. Heston and Welles play wonderfully together, and Welles' performance is among the highlights of his career. Dietrich's character refers to Von Sternberg's "Der Blaue Engel" (1930), a satire about a sexual free fall, a strong undersong in this film. The film's production history, as that of many other films by Welles, is closely linked to the film itself. As such, "Touch of Evil" is also rewarding as an artifact of film history. It's interesting to read Welles' 58-page memo (available online) and compare to any of the versions available. Watching them either chronologically or in reverse order is great fun. So is comparing the aspect ratios. The Region B Blu-ray released by the Masters of Cinema series is most certainly at the summit of the format and what can be done with it. On two Blu-rays there are the three existing versions of the film (the 1958 theatrical version, the 1958 preview version and the 1998 reconstructed version), the 1958 theatrical and the 1998 reconstruction presented in two aspect ratios. They are beautiful transfers, and host interesting and informative commentary tracks. I see myself revisiting this, and then revisiting it again. And again. * The review "Touch of Evil", by Fran&ccedil;ois Truffaut, originally published in "Arts" (June 4, 1958), available in the collection "Les films de ma vie" (1975) and translated into English as "The Films of My Life" (1978). I read this review in the booklet of the Masters of Cinema Blu-ray (p. 5).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    holy cow is this a good movie!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    xhearto
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    thrills! chills! Welles! if you feel like you've seen this movie a thousand times upon first viewing, it's probably because almost every moment has been "borrowed" by filmmakers for over half a century. And then copied by people who saw the borrowings. journey to the dark heart of man? Check. Marlene smoking over a crystal ball? Check. Janet terrorized in a motel? Check. Orson at the pinnacle of his game? Check. a shining example of what defines the difference between a film and a "movie" check. top ten list.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Macho Man?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gamay9
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Film noir at its' best....and, what a cast! The only unlikely scene is where Susie (Janet Leigh) is screaming for help from a fire escape and Vargas (Charleton Heston) drives right by, heads for a bar and roughs up the thugs....meanwhile Susie is arrested and jailed. Wouldn't a macho guy like Heston aid his wife first and then confront the thugs? After all, this is 1958 when guys rolled cigarette packs into their t-shirt sleeves. That was a lame scene. One of the actors, Calleia, was the director; not Hitchcock. It would have been easy for Heston to have the script changed to a more likely scenario. Otherwise, I enjoyed the film; anytime one can see Janet Leigh, Charleton Heston, Orson Welles, Marlene Deitrich (dark-haired Mexican) and Dennis Weaver in the same film, it's a blast!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Touch of Evil
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Directed by and starring Orson Welles, I may remember watching the first ten or something minutes of this film but giving up on it, I was certainly up for giving it another chance when I saw it listed and recommended as one of the 1001 Movies You Must See Before You Die in the book. Basically on the border between the United States of America and Mexico a time bomb is planted in the boot of a car, and it is drives to cross the border, and a couple of times newlyweds Ramon Miguel 'Mike' Vargas (Charlton Heston) and Susan 'Susie' (Janet Leigh) pass the vehicle before it crosses, and after doing so it blows up and kills the passengers. Mike works for the Mexican government as a drug enforcement official, and knowing the implications of bombs from Mexico to America exploding he decides to join in any investigation he can, and also looking into it are police Chief Gould (Harry Shannon) and District Attorney Adair (Ray Collins), but also the peculiar Police Captain Hank Quinlan (Orson Welles) and his long time partner Police Sergeant Pete Menzies (Joseph Calleia). Young Mexican man Manelo Sanchez (Victor Millan) is the prime suspect for Quinlan and Menzies, as he was secretly married to the daughter of one of the victims in the explosion, Mike is there during the interrogation, he accidentally knocks over an empty shoebox, and in moments this same box two sticks of dynamite are in it, so Mike suspects Quinlan has been planting evidence to help with his convictions over the years. Although Quinlan denies this Vargas still wants to see his public case records, so Al Schwartz (Mort Mills), the District Attorney's assistant lets him study them, and Gould and Adair are shown the findings as well, but Quinlan himself comes in and threatens resignation in anger over their discussion. There is a risk of the brother of a man Mike was investigating, 'Uncle' Joe Grandi (Akim Tamiroff) trying to expose things, so Susie moves from their Mexican hotel to a motel in America, one that Menzies recommended, staffed by mentally challenged Night Manager (Duel's Dennis Weaver) and with no other guests staying, but family members of Grandi take over the motel. Mike becomes worried when he tries telephoning Susie and she does not answer, in fact Quinlan has arrangement with Grandi that his gang will kidnap her, inject her with drugs and taken to another motel out of town, and indeed this happens, Quinlan murders Grandi and Susie is framed for the murder to give her husband a bad name. Mike goes to have a word with Menzies about the history of the cases he and Quinlan investigating and "found" evidence in, he dismisses any conspiracy he has, and then he goes looking for his wife at the motel but she and her gun have gone, so he goes to the other motel that Grandi owns and confronts his gang, they refuse to answer questions so he beats them up. Schwartz tells him that Susie was arrested for murder, but when he finds her she is barely conscious, and then Menzies comes to tell him that Quinlan's cane was found at the scene of Grandi's murder, so Mike fits him with a wire so he can go to see his partner and hear a conversation between them. At an oil field is where Quinlan and Menzies meet to discuss their activities while Mike records everything, the traitor cop admits he planted evidence on people to make them guiltier than they already were, but the tapping is uncovered by the sound of static. Quinlan knows that Mike is there watching and listening, and in the heat of the moment he shoots Menzies with Vargas's gun, but before he can shoot Mike dead Menzies gets up and shoots Quinlan, Menzies dies and eventually so does Quinlan, Sanchez is revealed to have admitted to the crime of planting the car bomb, and Mike leaves town with a recovered Susie. Also starring Joanna Moore as Marcia Linnekar , Valentin De Vargas as Pancho, Lalo Rios as Risto , Marlene Dietrich as Tanya, Zsa Zsa Gabor as Strip-Club Owner, The Third Man's Joseph Cotten as Coroner and The Exorcist's Mercedes McCambridge as Gang Leader. Heston gives a good performance as the man determined to get to the truth of the matter, Leigh gets her moments as the wife pulled into the situations, but obviously Welles is best part of this film as the treacherous cop with the villainous dark side, and his direction is well paced as well, some supporting cast members, especially Dietrich, are terrific as well. The film opens with one of the most famous long shots in cinema which is played out so well with clever tracking, and the film is filled with interesting material about conspiracy, double-crossing, murder and melodrama, it is one of the last true film noir style pictures, I admit I lost track of plot on occasions, but overall it is a watchable classic crime thriller. Very good!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
