<filme>
 <id>
  659
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0036613
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1944
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Esse Mundo &eacute; um Hosp&iacute;cio
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  8.0
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  A drama critic learns on his wedding day that his beloved maiden aunts are homicidal maniacs, and that insanity runs in his family.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Mortimer Brewster is a newspaperman and author known for his diatribes against marriage. We watch him being married at city hall in the opening scene. Now all that is required is a quick trip home to tell Mortimer's two maiden aunts. While trying to break the news, he finds out his aunts' hobby; killing lonely old men and burying them in the cellar. It gets worse.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Crime
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Romance
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   cellar
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   critic
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   insanity
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   poison
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   cemetery
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Frank Capra
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Julius J. Epstein
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Philip G. Epstein
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Cary Grant
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Priscilla Lane
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Raymond Massey
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wouldn't You Be A Little Manic, If Your Two Elderly Aunts Were Murderers ?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    PamelaShort
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film version of the classic play "Arsenic And Old Lace" is absolutely superb. Every single player in this amazing comedy, all perform first rate renditions of their characters. Dear Priscilla Lane is lovely in her small role as Cary Grant's bewildered bride. Josephine Hull and Jean Adair are totally convincing as the elderly Brewster Aunts, only trying to help their lonely elderly male boarders by poisoning them. Raymond Massey plays the fiendish Cousin Jonathan to a tee, with his equally creepy sidekick Peter Lorre. Edward Everett Horton is so ideal as Mr. Witherspoon of the Happy Dale Sanitarium, coming to claim the eccentric Uncle Teddy Brewster, who believes he is President Roosevelt. Jack Carson is funny as the dense police officer O'Hara. Cary Grant is a complete riot as nephew Mortimer Brewster, who so vainly tries to resolve the predicament his kooky Aunts have placed him in. Grant never misses a beat, and his facial expressions are priceless. I believe it to be one of his most winning-est performances. Frank Capra pulls it all together into one deliriously enjoyable comedy. I never tire of watching this classic movie, a favourite of mine to start off every Halloween.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    you can't 'live' without it
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    theoneandonlyjimmypage
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ONCE UPON A TIME....it's a Sunday afternoon and it is raining...there's nothing to do...nobody's home,the ballgame isn t on until this evening....you ve finished your work and your chores,you ve showered and you set out to make an omelette-so of course you will break some eggs..and no...there isn t 'a penguin'on the tele there's 'arsenic and old lace' (on the tele-).something to do...a great old movie...and funny...still.THE FIRST TIME AND THE SECOND AND THIRD AND FOURTH AND FOURTH the second time or fifth,the thing about breaking a few eggs-its a kind of a 'mad-cap' tale-he did what/she said that/they really this/allthat another that but this....etc,etc,etc AND SXTH AND SEVENTH AND EIGHTH AND NINTH AND TENTH...WATCH 'ARSENIC AND OLD LACE'--you can t live without it!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Oh, Mortimer...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MalteseRambo
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie showcases the finest of Frank Capra and frequent collaborator Cary Grant. It has the perfect combination of genres: Hilariously funny, just the right amount of romance, and the apparent main theme of crime. The greatest part of this movie is definitely the vast array of facial expressions shown by Grant, especially the priceless look of surprise when he sees the dead man in the window seat. The wonderful supporting cast is comprised of the blonde bombshell love interest played by Priscilla Lane. The dimwitted aunts played by Josephine Hull & Jean Adair. The unhinged brother played by John Alexander. And the sinister fugitives, his brother played by Boris Karloff, I mean Raymond Massey; and his doctor played by Peter Lorre. Without question, this is one of my favourite comedies, my favourite Capra film, my favourite Grant film, and one of my favourite film released before 1950. This is definitely Frank Capra at his greatest, and it should appear a hell of a lot higher on the IMDb Top 250. This movie should already be in the National Film Registry, but unfortunately it isn't. "You  get out of here! D'ya wanna be poisoned? D'ya wanna be murdered? D'ya wanna be killed?" - Mortimer Brewster
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent story collision
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Electro Bear
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Cary Grant stars in this absurd black comedy, featuring some of his most entertaining acting put to film. It also features some creative shots at points, but it's long takes respect the actors involved, and lets each scene grow at a pace taken by its actors. The writing is phenomenal, the setup for each character and their purpose drives the story forwards, and its hilarious to watch the actors enter each scene and complicate things further. The self-contained irony, the black humour, the absurdity, is all suddenly compounded towards the end, when Cary Grant himself accepts the insanity of the entire situation. It is also amazing to see a movie with such honestly dark patches, also be so family safe, a tribute to the great writing, and Frank Capra's direction. Not only is this movie hilarious, but it also has some genuinely horrifying moments. The monstrous Jonathan Brewster, played by Raymond Massey, coupled with his terrible facial scars is an honestly scary figure and has some oddly striking scenes mixed in with the all of the humour. Peter Lorre puts in a great mousy performance, and takes plenty of amusing abuse from all of the characters. Recommended viewing. Especially for fans of Cary Grant.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Nutcase Evening
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nick-leonardi
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Major theatre critic Mortimer Brewster (Cary Grant) on Halloween gets married to Elaine. He goes back to his two aunts' house to tell the good news. Mortimer later that day discovers accidentally a dead body in the window seat of his aunts' house, and the old aunts admit that they are the cause, as they have made killing old, lonely men their secret business. Things get more complicated when Mortimer's long gone brother Jonathan returns home unexpectedly after decades, with also a dead body with him. Almost universally hailed as a Black Comedy classic, this adaptation of the play of the same name contains numerous memorable characters, situations and dialogue, the main ingredients of a typical American classic. Its non-stop frenzy is highlighted by the fact that most of the film is set in the living room of the house, so that there is not only a much greater focus on the various storyline twist and turns, but also so that it feels much more like the original play itself. One of Frank Capra's most famous and successful works.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Is That a Body in Your Window Seat or Are You Just Happy to See Me?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brocksilvey
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Cary Grant works his tail off in this morbid comedy with an unusually high body count. Grant brings his brand-new wife (a perky Priscilla Lane) home to meet his two spinster aunts -- only to make the grisly discovery that his aunts have been murdering lonely male boarders and burying them in the basement. If this weren't stressful enough, Grant's sociopathic brother (played humorously by Raymond Massey) shows up with a body of his own to get rid of. What's a man to do? Frank Capra does a pretty good job of blending the screwball with the macabre, and nearly every joke and bit of physical comedy falls to Grant, who breezes through the whole movie with aplomb. It's a bit longer than it needs to be (o.k. so maybe it's a LOT longer than it needs to be), but it's still a lot of fun. Grade: A-
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Frank Capra And Cary Grant Comedy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Arsenic and Old Lace is a film directed by Frank Capra based on Joseph Kesselring's play of the same title. The screenplay adaptation was by Julius J. Epstein and Philip G. Epstein.Ti features Cary Grant and Josephine Hull together with Jean Adair and Raymond Massey.The movie is about the sweet old Brewster sisters, beloved in their genteel Brooklyn neighborhood for their many charitable acts. One charity which the ladies don't advertise is their ongoing effort to permit lonely bachelors to die with smiles on their faces by serving said bachelors elderberry wine spiked with arsenic. When the sisters' drama-critic nephew Mortimer stumbles onto their secret, he is understandably put out especially since he has just married the lovely Elaine Harper. Given the homicidal tendencies of his aunts, the sinister activities of his escaped-convict older brother Jonathan and the disruptive behavior of younger brother Teddy who is convinced that he's really Theodore Roosevelt, and runs around the house yelling and Mortimer isn't keen on starting a family with his new bride. "Insanity runs in my family," he explains. "It practically gallops." Further complications ensue when the murderous Jonathan Brewster arrives home, with his sniveling accomplice Dr. Einstein in tow. When Jonathan learns that his darling aunts have killed twelve men, he is incensed and they're challenging his own record of murders. Despite the fact that picture runs almost two hours, Frank Capra has expanded on the original play to a sufficient extent to maintain a steady, consistent pace.Also,unable to conceal the film's theatrical origins, Capra misfires as a director and misguides Cary Garnt, who's too mannered, but the time, the combo of horror and comedy was new and the old ladies' gruesome hobby was shocking to audiences.But nevertheless,Capra encourages the cast, especially Grant, to give a somewhat more out-sized performance than one might expect. But made during the war years as it was, this overstated comic approach to killing was probably cathartic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Epic Performance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    k-keith
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Plays and books always seem to be better than movies to me, but this is one of the exceptions. It's comedic genius, in large part because of the overly dramatic acting. Cary Grant is quoted as disliking his acting because of this, but the movie would never have been as good without that quality of being a little too much. All of the characters are meant to be a little too much, and this creates a balance within the movie between the panicked Mortimer, the peaceful aunts and the psychotic Jonathan. I love the descriptive dialogue by both Mortimer and the police officer at the end of the movie foreshadowing what steps Jonathan will take. It is also amusing the way that Mortimer's love story is cast aside in favor of handling the aunts, Teddy and Jonathan.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Extraordinary funny masterpiece of black comedy.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    psagray
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Movie filmed in 1941 by the great Sicilian-born filmmaker, Frank Capra, is based on the play, "Arsenic and Old Lace" written by novelist and playwright German born American, Joseph Kesselring, and was not yet premiered in 1944, when it had its last performance in the Broadway stage. It is adapted to the screen by the Epstein brothers (the writers of the famed "Casablanca"), is brilliantly narrated and tone of black comedy is elegantly showing each of its excellent frames, serve as a clear inspiration for the staging and conducting post as another big movie was "the Ladykillers" 1955 by Alexander MacKendrick, eleven years later ... It has an extraordinary staging and a dazzling black and white photography by renowned Sol Polito and a soundtrack of the most suggestive by another prominent author, Max Steiner, the film is a sign, yet another, the principal of "It Happened One Night" . This film is among the best of Gary Grant, although the actor himself was not happy with his own performance due to the strong character of his character histrionic mandated by Capra, the truth is that it is essential for this action film. The performance of the brother of "Mortimer" (Gary Grant), "Jonathan" (Raymond Massey) undoubtedly contributes to the tone of black comedy that is in every frame ... maybe its majestic presence make him starring as historical emblematic and enigmatic as Abraham Lincoln's own ... along with such great performances from Peter Lorre had just filmed "Casablanca" doing this mysterious and peculiar of Dr. Einstein, and the interpretation of John Alexander doing that unforgettable role crazy guy "Teddy Brewster", believing Theodore Roosevelt's famous cry of "(Charge!)!" (Roosevelt made famous during charging San Juan Hill) upstairs and unscrewing clockwise wall ... make this movie a masterpiece to consider.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Incredibly strange but very funny
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Terrell Howell (KnightsofNi11)
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What would you do if you found out that your own dear aunts were homicidal maniacs? There's a variety of ways to deal with the situation but Cary Grant probably picks the most unorthodox and unconventional solutions in Arsenic and Old Lace, a classic Frank Capra comedy from 1944. Grant stars as Mortimer Brewster, a drama critique who, at the opening of the film, marries his girlfriend. He goes home to tell his aunts and prepare for his honeymoon to Niagra Falls. However, while at home he finds out his aunts have poisoned twelve men over the past few months and they are all buried in the cellar. This news sends Mortimer racing around trying to hide the fact that his aunts are homicidal, while also dealing with a variety of other problems as this kind of insanity runs in his family. At the same time as he is dealing with his aunts Mortimer has one brother who thinks he's Teddy Roosevelt and another a deformed serial killer who, after being gone for twenty years, decides to return home at the most inopportune time. It's a wild and bizarre ride that is chock full of innocently delightful laughs. Arsenic and Old Lace represents the Golden Age of the American comedy. Some of the most classic comedies were made during World War II in order to ease the troubled times America was involved in. Arsenic and Old Lace falls right in with these films, having been released in 1944. Therefore, it's only purpose is just to make us laugh. It aims to entertain and delight, and I would say it does just that. It's got a cavalcade of wacky and eccentric characters played by a fantastic cast of hilarious actors and actresses. The duo of Aunt Abby and Aunt Martha is one of the most hilarious on screen pairings I've ever seen and the two actresses, Josephine Hull and Jean Adair respectively, play the part so perfectly. They come off as the sweetest old ladies you could ever meet who just don't understand what all the fuss is about concerning the twelve dead bodies they have buried in their cellar. It's certainly comedy at its most intelligent. The whole point of Arsenic and Old Lace is to be incredibly weird in a very entertaining way. And that is definitely what it does. This is a very strange film with all sorts of moments that make you scratch your head in confusion and chuckle at the same time. It's an incredibly offbeat film for its time, and this adds to the humor. As far as comedy goes this isn't quite my cup of tea, but I have the utmost respect for what a quality comedy film this is. Personally my taste leans towards more modern comedy stilings, but Arsenic and Old Lace is representative of a great era of comedy and just film in general. It's a great film that shouldn't be missed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wouldn't You Be A Little Manic, If Your Two Elderly Aunts Were Murderers ?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    PamelaShort
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film version of the classic play "Arsenic And Old Lace" is absolutely superb. Every single player in this amazing comedy, all perform first rate renditions of their characters. Dear Priscilla Lane is lovely in her small role as Cary Grant's bewildered bride. Josephine Hull and Jean Adair are totally convincing as the elderly Brewster Aunts, only trying to help their lonely elderly male boarders by poisoning them. Raymond Massey plays the fiendish Cousin Jonathan to a tee, with his equally creepy sidekick Peter Lorre. Edward Everett Horton is so ideal as Mr. Witherspoon of the Happy Dale Sanitarium, coming to claim the eccentric Uncle Teddy Brewster, who believes he is President Roosevelt. Jack Carson is funny as the dense police officer O'Hara. Cary Grant is a complete riot as nephew Mortimer Brewster, who so vainly tries to resolve the predicament his kooky Aunts have placed him in. Grant never misses a beat, and his facial expressions are priceless. I believe it to be one of his most winning-est performances. Frank Capra pulls it all together into one deliriously enjoyable comedy. I never tire of watching this classic movie, a favourite of mine to start off every Halloween.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    you can't 'live' without it
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    theoneandonlyjimmypage
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ONCE UPON A TIME....it's a Sunday afternoon and it is raining...there's nothing to do...nobody's home,the ballgame isn t on until this evening....you ve finished your work and your chores,you ve showered and you set out to make an omelette-so of course you will break some eggs..and no...there isn t 'a penguin'on the tele there's 'arsenic and old lace' (on the tele-).something to do...a great old movie...and funny...still.THE FIRST TIME AND THE SECOND AND THIRD AND FOURTH AND FOURTH the second time or fifth,the thing about breaking a few eggs-its a kind of a 'mad-cap' tale-he did what/she said that/they really this/allthat another that but this....etc,etc,etc AND SXTH AND SEVENTH AND EIGHTH AND NINTH AND TENTH...WATCH 'ARSENIC AND OLD LACE'--you can t live without it!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Oh, Mortimer...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MalteseRambo
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie showcases the finest of Frank Capra and frequent collaborator Cary Grant. It has the perfect combination of genres: Hilariously funny, just the right amount of romance, and the apparent main theme of crime. The greatest part of this movie is definitely the vast array of facial expressions shown by Grant, especially the priceless look of surprise when he sees the dead man in the window seat. The wonderful supporting cast is comprised of the blonde bombshell love interest played by Priscilla Lane. The dimwitted aunts played by Josephine Hull & Jean Adair. The unhinged brother played by John Alexander. And the sinister fugitives, his brother played by Boris Karloff, I mean Raymond Massey; and his doctor played by Peter Lorre. Without question, this is one of my favourite comedies, my favourite Capra film, my favourite Grant film, and one of my favourite film released before 1950. This is definitely Frank Capra at his greatest, and it should appear a hell of a lot higher on the IMDb Top 250. This movie should already be in the National Film Registry, but unfortunately it isn't. "You  get out of here! D'ya wanna be poisoned? D'ya wanna be murdered? D'ya wanna be killed?" - Mortimer Brewster
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent story collision
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Electro Bear
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Cary Grant stars in this absurd black comedy, featuring some of his most entertaining acting put to film. It also features some creative shots at points, but it's long takes respect the actors involved, and lets each scene grow at a pace taken by its actors. The writing is phenomenal, the setup for each character and their purpose drives the story forwards, and its hilarious to watch the actors enter each scene and complicate things further. The self-contained irony, the black humour, the absurdity, is all suddenly compounded towards the end, when Cary Grant himself accepts the insanity of the entire situation. It is also amazing to see a movie with such honestly dark patches, also be so family safe, a tribute to the great writing, and Frank Capra's direction. Not only is this movie hilarious, but it also has some genuinely horrifying moments. The monstrous Jonathan Brewster, played by Raymond Massey, coupled with his terrible facial scars is an honestly scary figure and has some oddly striking scenes mixed in with the all of the humour. Peter Lorre puts in a great mousy performance, and takes plenty of amusing abuse from all of the characters. Recommended viewing. Especially for fans of Cary Grant.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Nutcase Evening
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nick-leonardi
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Major theatre critic Mortimer Brewster (Cary Grant) on Halloween gets married to Elaine. He goes back to his two aunts' house to tell the good news. Mortimer later that day discovers accidentally a dead body in the window seat of his aunts' house, and the old aunts admit that they are the cause, as they have made killing old, lonely men their secret business. Things get more complicated when Mortimer's long gone brother Jonathan returns home unexpectedly after decades, with also a dead body with him. Almost universally hailed as a Black Comedy classic, this adaptation of the play of the same name contains numerous memorable characters, situations and dialogue, the main ingredients of a typical American classic. Its non-stop frenzy is highlighted by the fact that most of the film is set in the living room of the house, so that there is not only a much greater focus on the various storyline twist and turns, but also so that it feels much more like the original play itself. One of Frank Capra's most famous and successful works.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Is That a Body in Your Window Seat or Are You Just Happy to See Me?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brocksilvey
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Cary Grant works his tail off in this morbid comedy with an unusually high body count. Grant brings his brand-new wife (a perky Priscilla Lane) home to meet his two spinster aunts -- only to make the grisly discovery that his aunts have been murdering lonely male boarders and burying them in the basement. If this weren't stressful enough, Grant's sociopathic brother (played humorously by Raymond Massey) shows up with a body of his own to get rid of. What's a man to do? Frank Capra does a pretty good job of blending the screwball with the macabre, and nearly every joke and bit of physical comedy falls to Grant, who breezes through the whole movie with aplomb. It's a bit longer than it needs to be (o.k. so maybe it's a LOT longer than it needs to be), but it's still a lot of fun. Grade: A-
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Frank Capra And Cary Grant Comedy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Arsenic and Old Lace is a film directed by Frank Capra based on Joseph Kesselring's play of the same title. The screenplay adaptation was by Julius J. Epstein and Philip G. Epstein.Ti features Cary Grant and Josephine Hull together with Jean Adair and Raymond Massey.The movie is about the sweet old Brewster sisters, beloved in their genteel Brooklyn neighborhood for their many charitable acts. One charity which the ladies don't advertise is their ongoing effort to permit lonely bachelors to die with smiles on their faces by serving said bachelors elderberry wine spiked with arsenic. When the sisters' drama-critic nephew Mortimer stumbles onto their secret, he is understandably put out especially since he has just married the lovely Elaine Harper. Given the homicidal tendencies of his aunts, the sinister activities of his escaped-convict older brother Jonathan and the disruptive behavior of younger brother Teddy who is convinced that he's really Theodore Roosevelt, and runs around the house yelling and Mortimer isn't keen on starting a family with his new bride. "Insanity runs in my family," he explains. "It practically gallops." Further complications ensue when the murderous Jonathan Brewster arrives home, with his sniveling accomplice Dr. Einstein in tow. When Jonathan learns that his darling aunts have killed twelve men, he is incensed and they're challenging his own record of murders. Despite the fact that picture runs almost two hours, Frank Capra has expanded on the original play to a sufficient extent to maintain a steady, consistent pace.Also,unable to conceal the film's theatrical origins, Capra misfires as a director and misguides Cary Garnt, who's too mannered, but the time, the combo of horror and comedy was new and the old ladies' gruesome hobby was shocking to audiences.But nevertheless,Capra encourages the cast, especially Grant, to give a somewhat more out-sized performance than one might expect. But made during the war years as it was, this overstated comic approach to killing was probably cathartic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Epic Performance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    k-keith
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Plays and books always seem to be better than movies to me, but this is one of the exceptions. It's comedic genius, in large part because of the overly dramatic acting. Cary Grant is quoted as disliking his acting because of this, but the movie would never have been as good without that quality of being a little too much. All of the characters are meant to be a little too much, and this creates a balance within the movie between the panicked Mortimer, the peaceful aunts and the psychotic Jonathan. I love the descriptive dialogue by both Mortimer and the police officer at the end of the movie foreshadowing what steps Jonathan will take. It is also amusing the way that Mortimer's love story is cast aside in favor of handling the aunts, Teddy and Jonathan.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Extraordinary funny masterpiece of black comedy.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    psagray
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Movie filmed in 1941 by the great Sicilian-born filmmaker, Frank Capra, is based on the play, "Arsenic and Old Lace" written by novelist and playwright German born American, Joseph Kesselring, and was not yet premiered in 1944, when it had its last performance in the Broadway stage. It is adapted to the screen by the Epstein brothers (the writers of the famed "Casablanca"), is brilliantly narrated and tone of black comedy is elegantly showing each of its excellent frames, serve as a clear inspiration for the staging and conducting post as another big movie was "the Ladykillers" 1955 by Alexander MacKendrick, eleven years later ... It has an extraordinary staging and a dazzling black and white photography by renowned Sol Polito and a soundtrack of the most suggestive by another prominent author, Max Steiner, the film is a sign, yet another, the principal of "It Happened One Night" . This film is among the best of Gary Grant, although the actor himself was not happy with his own performance due to the strong character of his character histrionic mandated by Capra, the truth is that it is essential for this action film. The performance of the brother of "Mortimer" (Gary Grant), "Jonathan" (Raymond Massey) undoubtedly contributes to the tone of black comedy that is in every frame ... maybe its majestic presence make him starring as historical emblematic and enigmatic as Abraham Lincoln's own ... along with such great performances from Peter Lorre had just filmed "Casablanca" doing this mysterious and peculiar of Dr. Einstein, and the interpretation of John Alexander doing that unforgettable role crazy guy "Teddy Brewster", believing Theodore Roosevelt's famous cry of "(Charge!)!" (Roosevelt made famous during charging San Juan Hill) upstairs and unscrewing clockwise wall ... make this movie a masterpiece to consider.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Incredibly strange but very funny
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Terrell Howell (KnightsofNi11)
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What would you do if you found out that your own dear aunts were homicidal maniacs? There's a variety of ways to deal with the situation but Cary Grant probably picks the most unorthodox and unconventional solutions in Arsenic and Old Lace, a classic Frank Capra comedy from 1944. Grant stars as Mortimer Brewster, a drama critique who, at the opening of the film, marries his girlfriend. He goes home to tell his aunts and prepare for his honeymoon to Niagra Falls. However, while at home he finds out his aunts have poisoned twelve men over the past few months and they are all buried in the cellar. This news sends Mortimer racing around trying to hide the fact that his aunts are homicidal, while also dealing with a variety of other problems as this kind of insanity runs in his family. At the same time as he is dealing with his aunts Mortimer has one brother who thinks he's Teddy Roosevelt and another a deformed serial killer who, after being gone for twenty years, decides to return home at the most inopportune time. It's a wild and bizarre ride that is chock full of innocently delightful laughs. Arsenic and Old Lace represents the Golden Age of the American comedy. Some of the most classic comedies were made during World War II in order to ease the troubled times America was involved in. Arsenic and Old Lace falls right in with these films, having been released in 1944. Therefore, it's only purpose is just to make us laugh. It aims to entertain and delight, and I would say it does just that. It's got a cavalcade of wacky and eccentric characters played by a fantastic cast of hilarious actors and actresses. The duo of Aunt Abby and Aunt Martha is one of the most hilarious on screen pairings I've ever seen and the two actresses, Josephine Hull and Jean Adair respectively, play the part so perfectly. They come off as the sweetest old ladies you could ever meet who just don't understand what all the fuss is about concerning the twelve dead bodies they have buried in their cellar. It's certainly comedy at its most intelligent. The whole point of Arsenic and Old Lace is to be incredibly weird in a very entertaining way. And that is definitely what it does. This is a very strange film with all sorts of moments that make you scratch your head in confusion and chuckle at the same time. It's an incredibly offbeat film for its time, and this adds to the humor. As far as comedy goes this isn't quite my cup of tea, but I have the utmost respect for what a quality comedy film this is. Personally my taste leans towards more modern comedy stilings, but Arsenic and Old Lace is representative of a great era of comedy and just film in general. It's a great film that shouldn't be missed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wouldn't You Be A Little Manic, If Your Two Elderly Aunts Were Murderers ?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    PamelaShort
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film version of the classic play "Arsenic And Old Lace" is absolutely superb. Every single player in this amazing comedy, all perform first rate renditions of their characters. Dear Priscilla Lane is lovely in her small role as Cary Grant's bewildered bride. Josephine Hull and Jean Adair are totally convincing as the elderly Brewster Aunts, only trying to help their lonely elderly male boarders by poisoning them. Raymond Massey plays the fiendish Cousin Jonathan to a tee, with his equally creepy sidekick Peter Lorre. Edward Everett Horton is so ideal as Mr. Witherspoon of the Happy Dale Sanitarium, coming to claim the eccentric Uncle Teddy Brewster, who believes he is President Roosevelt. Jack Carson is funny as the dense police officer O'Hara. Cary Grant is a complete riot as nephew Mortimer Brewster, who so vainly tries to resolve the predicament his kooky Aunts have placed him in. Grant never misses a beat, and his facial expressions are priceless. I believe it to be one of his most winning-est performances. Frank Capra pulls it all together into one deliriously enjoyable comedy. I never tire of watching this classic movie, a favourite of mine to start off every Halloween.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    you can't 'live' without it
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    theoneandonlyjimmypage
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ONCE UPON A TIME....it's a Sunday afternoon and it is raining...there's nothing to do...nobody's home,the ballgame isn t on until this evening....you ve finished your work and your chores,you ve showered and you set out to make an omelette-so of course you will break some eggs..and no...there isn t 'a penguin'on the tele there's 'arsenic and old lace' (on the tele-).something to do...a great old movie...and funny...still.THE FIRST TIME AND THE SECOND AND THIRD AND FOURTH AND FOURTH the second time or fifth,the thing about breaking a few eggs-its a kind of a 'mad-cap' tale-he did what/she said that/they really this/allthat another that but this....etc,etc,etc AND SXTH AND SEVENTH AND EIGHTH AND NINTH AND TENTH...WATCH 'ARSENIC AND OLD LACE'--you can t live without it!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Oh, Mortimer...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MalteseRambo
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie showcases the finest of Frank Capra and frequent collaborator Cary Grant. It has the perfect combination of genres: Hilariously funny, just the right amount of romance, and the apparent main theme of crime. The greatest part of this movie is definitely the vast array of facial expressions shown by Grant, especially the priceless look of surprise when he sees the dead man in the window seat. The wonderful supporting cast is comprised of the blonde bombshell love interest played by Priscilla Lane. The dimwitted aunts played by Josephine Hull & Jean Adair. The unhinged brother played by John Alexander. And the sinister fugitives, his brother played by Boris Karloff, I mean Raymond Massey; and his doctor played by Peter Lorre. Without question, this is one of my favourite comedies, my favourite Capra film, my favourite Grant film, and one of my favourite film released before 1950. This is definitely Frank Capra at his greatest, and it should appear a hell of a lot higher on the IMDb Top 250. This movie should already be in the National Film Registry, but unfortunately it isn't. "You  get out of here! D'ya wanna be poisoned? D'ya wanna be murdered? D'ya wanna be killed?" - Mortimer Brewster
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent story collision
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Electro Bear
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Cary Grant stars in this absurd black comedy, featuring some of his most entertaining acting put to film. It also features some creative shots at points, but it's long takes respect the actors involved, and lets each scene grow at a pace taken by its actors. The writing is phenomenal, the setup for each character and their purpose drives the story forwards, and its hilarious to watch the actors enter each scene and complicate things further. The self-contained irony, the black humour, the absurdity, is all suddenly compounded towards the end, when Cary Grant himself accepts the insanity of the entire situation. It is also amazing to see a movie with such honestly dark patches, also be so family safe, a tribute to the great writing, and Frank Capra's direction. Not only is this movie hilarious, but it also has some genuinely horrifying moments. The monstrous Jonathan Brewster, played by Raymond Massey, coupled with his terrible facial scars is an honestly scary figure and has some oddly striking scenes mixed in with the all of the humour. Peter Lorre puts in a great mousy performance, and takes plenty of amusing abuse from all of the characters. Recommended viewing. Especially for fans of Cary Grant.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Nutcase Evening
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nick-leonardi
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Major theatre critic Mortimer Brewster (Cary Grant) on Halloween gets married to Elaine. He goes back to his two aunts' house to tell the good news. Mortimer later that day discovers accidentally a dead body in the window seat of his aunts' house, and the old aunts admit that they are the cause, as they have made killing old, lonely men their secret business. Things get more complicated when Mortimer's long gone brother Jonathan returns home unexpectedly after decades, with also a dead body with him. Almost universally hailed as a Black Comedy classic, this adaptation of the play of the same name contains numerous memorable characters, situations and dialogue, the main ingredients of a typical American classic. Its non-stop frenzy is highlighted by the fact that most of the film is set in the living room of the house, so that there is not only a much greater focus on the various storyline twist and turns, but also so that it feels much more like the original play itself. One of Frank Capra's most famous and successful works.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Is That a Body in Your Window Seat or Are You Just Happy to See Me?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brocksilvey
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Cary Grant works his tail off in this morbid comedy with an unusually high body count. Grant brings his brand-new wife (a perky Priscilla Lane) home to meet his two spinster aunts -- only to make the grisly discovery that his aunts have been murdering lonely male boarders and burying them in the basement. If this weren't stressful enough, Grant's sociopathic brother (played humorously by Raymond Massey) shows up with a body of his own to get rid of. What's a man to do? Frank Capra does a pretty good job of blending the screwball with the macabre, and nearly every joke and bit of physical comedy falls to Grant, who breezes through the whole movie with aplomb. It's a bit longer than it needs to be (o.k. so maybe it's a LOT longer than it needs to be), but it's still a lot of fun. Grade: A-
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Frank Capra And Cary Grant Comedy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Arsenic and Old Lace is a film directed by Frank Capra based on Joseph Kesselring's play of the same title. The screenplay adaptation was by Julius J. Epstein and Philip G. Epstein.Ti features Cary Grant and Josephine Hull together with Jean Adair and Raymond Massey.The movie is about the sweet old Brewster sisters, beloved in their genteel Brooklyn neighborhood for their many charitable acts. One charity which the ladies don't advertise is their ongoing effort to permit lonely bachelors to die with smiles on their faces by serving said bachelors elderberry wine spiked with arsenic. When the sisters' drama-critic nephew Mortimer stumbles onto their secret, he is understandably put out especially since he has just married the lovely Elaine Harper. Given the homicidal tendencies of his aunts, the sinister activities of his escaped-convict older brother Jonathan and the disruptive behavior of younger brother Teddy who is convinced that he's really Theodore Roosevelt, and runs around the house yelling and Mortimer isn't keen on starting a family with his new bride. "Insanity runs in my family," he explains. "It practically gallops." Further complications ensue when the murderous Jonathan Brewster arrives home, with his sniveling accomplice Dr. Einstein in tow. When Jonathan learns that his darling aunts have killed twelve men, he is incensed and they're challenging his own record of murders. Despite the fact that picture runs almost two hours, Frank Capra has expanded on the original play to a sufficient extent to maintain a steady, consistent pace.Also,unable to conceal the film's theatrical origins, Capra misfires as a director and misguides Cary Garnt, who's too mannered, but the time, the combo of horror and comedy was new and the old ladies' gruesome hobby was shocking to audiences.But nevertheless,Capra encourages the cast, especially Grant, to give a somewhat more out-sized performance than one might expect. But made during the war years as it was, this overstated comic approach to killing was probably cathartic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Epic Performance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    k-keith
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Plays and books always seem to be better than movies to me, but this is one of the exceptions. It's comedic genius, in large part because of the overly dramatic acting. Cary Grant is quoted as disliking his acting because of this, but the movie would never have been as good without that quality of being a little too much. All of the characters are meant to be a little too much, and this creates a balance within the movie between the panicked Mortimer, the peaceful aunts and the psychotic Jonathan. I love the descriptive dialogue by both Mortimer and the police officer at the end of the movie foreshadowing what steps Jonathan will take. It is also amusing the way that Mortimer's love story is cast aside in favor of handling the aunts, Teddy and Jonathan.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Extraordinary funny masterpiece of black comedy.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    psagray
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Movie filmed in 1941 by the great Sicilian-born filmmaker, Frank Capra, is based on the play, "Arsenic and Old Lace" written by novelist and playwright German born American, Joseph Kesselring, and was not yet premiered in 1944, when it had its last performance in the Broadway stage. It is adapted to the screen by the Epstein brothers (the writers of the famed "Casablanca"), is brilliantly narrated and tone of black comedy is elegantly showing each of its excellent frames, serve as a clear inspiration for the staging and conducting post as another big movie was "the Ladykillers" 1955 by Alexander MacKendrick, eleven years later ... It has an extraordinary staging and a dazzling black and white photography by renowned Sol Polito and a soundtrack of the most suggestive by another prominent author, Max Steiner, the film is a sign, yet another, the principal of "It Happened One Night" . This film is among the best of Gary Grant, although the actor himself was not happy with his own performance due to the strong character of his character histrionic mandated by Capra, the truth is that it is essential for this action film. The performance of the brother of "Mortimer" (Gary Grant), "Jonathan" (Raymond Massey) undoubtedly contributes to the tone of black comedy that is in every frame ... maybe its majestic presence make him starring as historical emblematic and enigmatic as Abraham Lincoln's own ... along with such great performances from Peter Lorre had just filmed "Casablanca" doing this mysterious and peculiar of Dr. Einstein, and the interpretation of John Alexander doing that unforgettable role crazy guy "Teddy Brewster", believing Theodore Roosevelt's famous cry of "(Charge!)!" (Roosevelt made famous during charging San Juan Hill) upstairs and unscrewing clockwise wall ... make this movie a masterpiece to consider.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Incredibly strange but very funny
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Terrell Howell (KnightsofNi11)
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What would you do if you found out that your own dear aunts were homicidal maniacs? There's a variety of ways to deal with the situation but Cary Grant probably picks the most unorthodox and unconventional solutions in Arsenic and Old Lace, a classic Frank Capra comedy from 1944. Grant stars as Mortimer Brewster, a drama critique who, at the opening of the film, marries his girlfriend. He goes home to tell his aunts and prepare for his honeymoon to Niagra Falls. However, while at home he finds out his aunts have poisoned twelve men over the past few months and they are all buried in the cellar. This news sends Mortimer racing around trying to hide the fact that his aunts are homicidal, while also dealing with a variety of other problems as this kind of insanity runs in his family. At the same time as he is dealing with his aunts Mortimer has one brother who thinks he's Teddy Roosevelt and another a deformed serial killer who, after being gone for twenty years, decides to return home at the most inopportune time. It's a wild and bizarre ride that is chock full of innocently delightful laughs. Arsenic and Old Lace represents the Golden Age of the American comedy. Some of the most classic comedies were made during World War II in order to ease the troubled times America was involved in. Arsenic and Old Lace falls right in with these films, having been released in 1944. Therefore, it's only purpose is just to make us laugh. It aims to entertain and delight, and I would say it does just that. It's got a cavalcade of wacky and eccentric characters played by a fantastic cast of hilarious actors and actresses. The duo of Aunt Abby and Aunt Martha is one of the most hilarious on screen pairings I've ever seen and the two actresses, Josephine Hull and Jean Adair respectively, play the part so perfectly. They come off as the sweetest old ladies you could ever meet who just don't understand what all the fuss is about concerning the twelve dead bodies they have buried in their cellar. It's certainly comedy at its most intelligent. The whole point of Arsenic and Old Lace is to be incredibly weird in a very entertaining way. And that is definitely what it does. This is a very strange film with all sorts of moments that make you scratch your head in confusion and chuckle at the same time. It's an incredibly offbeat film for its time, and this adds to the humor. As far as comedy goes this isn't quite my cup of tea, but I have the utmost respect for what a quality comedy film this is. Personally my taste leans towards more modern comedy stilings, but Arsenic and Old Lace is representative of a great era of comedy and just film in general. It's a great film that shouldn't be missed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wouldn't You Be A Little Manic, If Your Two Elderly Aunts Were Murderers ?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    PamelaShort
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film version of the classic play "Arsenic And Old Lace" is absolutely superb. Every single player in this amazing comedy, all perform first rate renditions of their characters. Dear Priscilla Lane is lovely in her small role as Cary Grant's bewildered bride. Josephine Hull and Jean Adair are totally convincing as the elderly Brewster Aunts, only trying to help their lonely elderly male boarders by poisoning them. Raymond Massey plays the fiendish Cousin Jonathan to a tee, with his equally creepy sidekick Peter Lorre. Edward Everett Horton is so ideal as Mr. Witherspoon of the Happy Dale Sanitarium, coming to claim the eccentric Uncle Teddy Brewster, who believes he is President Roosevelt. Jack Carson is funny as the dense police officer O'Hara. Cary Grant is a complete riot as nephew Mortimer Brewster, who so vainly tries to resolve the predicament his kooky Aunts have placed him in. Grant never misses a beat, and his facial expressions are priceless. I believe it to be one of his most winning-est performances. Frank Capra pulls it all together into one deliriously enjoyable comedy. I never tire of watching this classic movie, a favourite of mine to start off every Halloween.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    you can't 'live' without it
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    theoneandonlyjimmypage
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ONCE UPON A TIME....it's a Sunday afternoon and it is raining...there's nothing to do...nobody's home,the ballgame isn t on until this evening....you ve finished your work and your chores,you ve showered and you set out to make an omelette-so of course you will break some eggs..and no...there isn t 'a penguin'on the tele there's 'arsenic and old lace' (on the tele-).something to do...a great old movie...and funny...still.THE FIRST TIME AND THE SECOND AND THIRD AND FOURTH AND FOURTH the second time or fifth,the thing about breaking a few eggs-its a kind of a 'mad-cap' tale-he did what/she said that/they really this/allthat another that but this....etc,etc,etc AND SXTH AND SEVENTH AND EIGHTH AND NINTH AND TENTH...WATCH 'ARSENIC AND OLD LACE'--you can t live without it!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Oh, Mortimer...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MalteseRambo
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie showcases the finest of Frank Capra and frequent collaborator Cary Grant. It has the perfect combination of genres: Hilariously funny, just the right amount of romance, and the apparent main theme of crime. The greatest part of this movie is definitely the vast array of facial expressions shown by Grant, especially the priceless look of surprise when he sees the dead man in the window seat. The wonderful supporting cast is comprised of the blonde bombshell love interest played by Priscilla Lane. The dimwitted aunts played by Josephine Hull & Jean Adair. The unhinged brother played by John Alexander. And the sinister fugitives, his brother played by Boris Karloff, I mean Raymond Massey; and his doctor played by Peter Lorre. Without question, this is one of my favourite comedies, my favourite Capra film, my favourite Grant film, and one of my favourite film released before 1950. This is definitely Frank Capra at his greatest, and it should appear a hell of a lot higher on the IMDb Top 250. This movie should already be in the National Film Registry, but unfortunately it isn't. "You  get out of here! D'ya wanna be poisoned? D'ya wanna be murdered? D'ya wanna be killed?" - Mortimer Brewster
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent story collision
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Electro Bear
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Cary Grant stars in this absurd black comedy, featuring some of his most entertaining acting put to film. It also features some creative shots at points, but it's long takes respect the actors involved, and lets each scene grow at a pace taken by its actors. The writing is phenomenal, the setup for each character and their purpose drives the story forwards, and its hilarious to watch the actors enter each scene and complicate things further. The self-contained irony, the black humour, the absurdity, is all suddenly compounded towards the end, when Cary Grant himself accepts the insanity of the entire situation. It is also amazing to see a movie with such honestly dark patches, also be so family safe, a tribute to the great writing, and Frank Capra's direction. Not only is this movie hilarious, but it also has some genuinely horrifying moments. The monstrous Jonathan Brewster, played by Raymond Massey, coupled with his terrible facial scars is an honestly scary figure and has some oddly striking scenes mixed in with the all of the humour. Peter Lorre puts in a great mousy performance, and takes plenty of amusing abuse from all of the characters. Recommended viewing. Especially for fans of Cary Grant.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Nutcase Evening
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nick-leonardi
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Major theatre critic Mortimer Brewster (Cary Grant) on Halloween gets married to Elaine. He goes back to his two aunts' house to tell the good news. Mortimer later that day discovers accidentally a dead body in the window seat of his aunts' house, and the old aunts admit that they are the cause, as they have made killing old, lonely men their secret business. Things get more complicated when Mortimer's long gone brother Jonathan returns home unexpectedly after decades, with also a dead body with him. Almost universally hailed as a Black Comedy classic, this adaptation of the play of the same name contains numerous memorable characters, situations and dialogue, the main ingredients of a typical American classic. Its non-stop frenzy is highlighted by the fact that most of the film is set in the living room of the house, so that there is not only a much greater focus on the various storyline twist and turns, but also so that it feels much more like the original play itself. One of Frank Capra's most famous and successful works.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Is That a Body in Your Window Seat or Are You Just Happy to See Me?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brocksilvey
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Cary Grant works his tail off in this morbid comedy with an unusually high body count. Grant brings his brand-new wife (a perky Priscilla Lane) home to meet his two spinster aunts -- only to make the grisly discovery that his aunts have been murdering lonely male boarders and burying them in the basement. If this weren't stressful enough, Grant's sociopathic brother (played humorously by Raymond Massey) shows up with a body of his own to get rid of. What's a man to do? Frank Capra does a pretty good job of blending the screwball with the macabre, and nearly every joke and bit of physical comedy falls to Grant, who breezes through the whole movie with aplomb. It's a bit longer than it needs to be (o.k. so maybe it's a LOT longer than it needs to be), but it's still a lot of fun. Grade: A-
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Frank Capra And Cary Grant Comedy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Arsenic and Old Lace is a film directed by Frank Capra based on Joseph Kesselring's play of the same title. The screenplay adaptation was by Julius J. Epstein and Philip G. Epstein.Ti features Cary Grant and Josephine Hull together with Jean Adair and Raymond Massey.The movie is about the sweet old Brewster sisters, beloved in their genteel Brooklyn neighborhood for their many charitable acts. One charity which the ladies don't advertise is their ongoing effort to permit lonely bachelors to die with smiles on their faces by serving said bachelors elderberry wine spiked with arsenic. When the sisters' drama-critic nephew Mortimer stumbles onto their secret, he is understandably put out especially since he has just married the lovely Elaine Harper. Given the homicidal tendencies of his aunts, the sinister activities of his escaped-convict older brother Jonathan and the disruptive behavior of younger brother Teddy who is convinced that he's really Theodore Roosevelt, and runs around the house yelling and Mortimer isn't keen on starting a family with his new bride. "Insanity runs in my family," he explains. "It practically gallops." Further complications ensue when the murderous Jonathan Brewster arrives home, with his sniveling accomplice Dr. Einstein in tow. When Jonathan learns that his darling aunts have killed twelve men, he is incensed and they're challenging his own record of murders. Despite the fact that picture runs almost two hours, Frank Capra has expanded on the original play to a sufficient extent to maintain a steady, consistent pace.Also,unable to conceal the film's theatrical origins, Capra misfires as a director and misguides Cary Garnt, who's too mannered, but the time, the combo of horror and comedy was new and the old ladies' gruesome hobby was shocking to audiences.But nevertheless,Capra encourages the cast, especially Grant, to give a somewhat more out-sized performance than one might expect. But made during the war years as it was, this overstated comic approach to killing was probably cathartic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Epic Performance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    k-keith
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Plays and books always seem to be better than movies to me, but this is one of the exceptions. It's comedic genius, in large part because of the overly dramatic acting. Cary Grant is quoted as disliking his acting because of this, but the movie would never have been as good without that quality of being a little too much. All of the characters are meant to be a little too much, and this creates a balance within the movie between the panicked Mortimer, the peaceful aunts and the psychotic Jonathan. I love the descriptive dialogue by both Mortimer and the police officer at the end of the movie foreshadowing what steps Jonathan will take. It is also amusing the way that Mortimer's love story is cast aside in favor of handling the aunts, Teddy and Jonathan.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Extraordinary funny masterpiece of black comedy.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    psagray
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Movie filmed in 1941 by the great Sicilian-born filmmaker, Frank Capra, is based on the play, "Arsenic and Old Lace" written by novelist and playwright German born American, Joseph Kesselring, and was not yet premiered in 1944, when it had its last performance in the Broadway stage. It is adapted to the screen by the Epstein brothers (the writers of the famed "Casablanca"), is brilliantly narrated and tone of black comedy is elegantly showing each of its excellent frames, serve as a clear inspiration for the staging and conducting post as another big movie was "the Ladykillers" 1955 by Alexander MacKendrick, eleven years later ... It has an extraordinary staging and a dazzling black and white photography by renowned Sol Polito and a soundtrack of the most suggestive by another prominent author, Max Steiner, the film is a sign, yet another, the principal of "It Happened One Night" . This film is among the best of Gary Grant, although the actor himself was not happy with his own performance due to the strong character of his character histrionic mandated by Capra, the truth is that it is essential for this action film. The performance of the brother of "Mortimer" (Gary Grant), "Jonathan" (Raymond Massey) undoubtedly contributes to the tone of black comedy that is in every frame ... maybe its majestic presence make him starring as historical emblematic and enigmatic as Abraham Lincoln's own ... along with such great performances from Peter Lorre had just filmed "Casablanca" doing this mysterious and peculiar of Dr. Einstein, and the interpretation of John Alexander doing that unforgettable role crazy guy "Teddy Brewster", believing Theodore Roosevelt's famous cry of "(Charge!)!" (Roosevelt made famous during charging San Juan Hill) upstairs and unscrewing clockwise wall ... make this movie a masterpiece to consider.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Incredibly strange but very funny
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Terrell Howell (KnightsofNi11)
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What would you do if you found out that your own dear aunts were homicidal maniacs? There's a variety of ways to deal with the situation but Cary Grant probably picks the most unorthodox and unconventional solutions in Arsenic and Old Lace, a classic Frank Capra comedy from 1944. Grant stars as Mortimer Brewster, a drama critique who, at the opening of the film, marries his girlfriend. He goes home to tell his aunts and prepare for his honeymoon to Niagra Falls. However, while at home he finds out his aunts have poisoned twelve men over the past few months and they are all buried in the cellar. This news sends Mortimer racing around trying to hide the fact that his aunts are homicidal, while also dealing with a variety of other problems as this kind of insanity runs in his family. At the same time as he is dealing with his aunts Mortimer has one brother who thinks he's Teddy Roosevelt and another a deformed serial killer who, after being gone for twenty years, decides to return home at the most inopportune time. It's a wild and bizarre ride that is chock full of innocently delightful laughs. Arsenic and Old Lace represents the Golden Age of the American comedy. Some of the most classic comedies were made during World War II in order to ease the troubled times America was involved in. Arsenic and Old Lace falls right in with these films, having been released in 1944. Therefore, it's only purpose is just to make us laugh. It aims to entertain and delight, and I would say it does just that. It's got a cavalcade of wacky and eccentric characters played by a fantastic cast of hilarious actors and actresses. The duo of Aunt Abby and Aunt Martha is one of the most hilarious on screen pairings I've ever seen and the two actresses, Josephine Hull and Jean Adair respectively, play the part so perfectly. They come off as the sweetest old ladies you could ever meet who just don't understand what all the fuss is about concerning the twelve dead bodies they have buried in their cellar. It's certainly comedy at its most intelligent. The whole point of Arsenic and Old Lace is to be incredibly weird in a very entertaining way. And that is definitely what it does. This is a very strange film with all sorts of moments that make you scratch your head in confusion and chuckle at the same time. It's an incredibly offbeat film for its time, and this adds to the humor. As far as comedy goes this isn't quite my cup of tea, but I have the utmost respect for what a quality comedy film this is. Personally my taste leans towards more modern comedy stilings, but Arsenic and Old Lace is representative of a great era of comedy and just film in general. It's a great film that shouldn't be missed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wouldn't You Be A Little Manic, If Your Two Elderly Aunts Were Murderers ?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    PamelaShort
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film version of the classic play "Arsenic And Old Lace" is absolutely superb. Every single player in this amazing comedy, all perform first rate renditions of their characters. Dear Priscilla Lane is lovely in her small role as Cary Grant's bewildered bride. Josephine Hull and Jean Adair are totally convincing as the elderly Brewster Aunts, only trying to help their lonely elderly male boarders by poisoning them. Raymond Massey plays the fiendish Cousin Jonathan to a tee, with his equally creepy sidekick Peter Lorre. Edward Everett Horton is so ideal as Mr. Witherspoon of the Happy Dale Sanitarium, coming to claim the eccentric Uncle Teddy Brewster, who believes he is President Roosevelt. Jack Carson is funny as the dense police officer O'Hara. Cary Grant is a complete riot as nephew Mortimer Brewster, who so vainly tries to resolve the predicament his kooky Aunts have placed him in. Grant never misses a beat, and his facial expressions are priceless. I believe it to be one of his most winning-est performances. Frank Capra pulls it all together into one deliriously enjoyable comedy. I never tire of watching this classic movie, a favourite of mine to start off every Halloween.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    you can't 'live' without it
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    theoneandonlyjimmypage
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ONCE UPON A TIME....it's a Sunday afternoon and it is raining...there's nothing to do...nobody's home,the ballgame isn t on until this evening....you ve finished your work and your chores,you ve showered and you set out to make an omelette-so of course you will break some eggs..and no...there isn t 'a penguin'on the tele there's 'arsenic and old lace' (on the tele-).something to do...a great old movie...and funny...still.THE FIRST TIME AND THE SECOND AND THIRD AND FOURTH AND FOURTH the second time or fifth,the thing about breaking a few eggs-its a kind of a 'mad-cap' tale-he did what/she said that/they really this/allthat another that but this....etc,etc,etc AND SXTH AND SEVENTH AND EIGHTH AND NINTH AND TENTH...WATCH 'ARSENIC AND OLD LACE'--you can t live without it!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Oh, Mortimer...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MalteseRambo
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie showcases the finest of Frank Capra and frequent collaborator Cary Grant. It has the perfect combination of genres: Hilariously funny, just the right amount of romance, and the apparent main theme of crime. The greatest part of this movie is definitely the vast array of facial expressions shown by Grant, especially the priceless look of surprise when he sees the dead man in the window seat. The wonderful supporting cast is comprised of the blonde bombshell love interest played by Priscilla Lane. The dimwitted aunts played by Josephine Hull & Jean Adair. The unhinged brother played by John Alexander. And the sinister fugitives, his brother played by Boris Karloff, I mean Raymond Massey; and his doctor played by Peter Lorre. Without question, this is one of my favourite comedies, my favourite Capra film, my favourite Grant film, and one of my favourite film released before 1950. This is definitely Frank Capra at his greatest, and it should appear a hell of a lot higher on the IMDb Top 250. This movie should already be in the National Film Registry, but unfortunately it isn't. "You  get out of here! D'ya wanna be poisoned? D'ya wanna be murdered? D'ya wanna be killed?" - Mortimer Brewster
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent story collision
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Electro Bear
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Cary Grant stars in this absurd black comedy, featuring some of his most entertaining acting put to film. It also features some creative shots at points, but it's long takes respect the actors involved, and lets each scene grow at a pace taken by its actors. The writing is phenomenal, the setup for each character and their purpose drives the story forwards, and its hilarious to watch the actors enter each scene and complicate things further. The self-contained irony, the black humour, the absurdity, is all suddenly compounded towards the end, when Cary Grant himself accepts the insanity of the entire situation. It is also amazing to see a movie with such honestly dark patches, also be so family safe, a tribute to the great writing, and Frank Capra's direction. Not only is this movie hilarious, but it also has some genuinely horrifying moments. The monstrous Jonathan Brewster, played by Raymond Massey, coupled with his terrible facial scars is an honestly scary figure and has some oddly striking scenes mixed in with the all of the humour. Peter Lorre puts in a great mousy performance, and takes plenty of amusing abuse from all of the characters. Recommended viewing. Especially for fans of Cary Grant.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Nutcase Evening
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nick-leonardi
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Major theatre critic Mortimer Brewster (Cary Grant) on Halloween gets married to Elaine. He goes back to his two aunts' house to tell the good news. Mortimer later that day discovers accidentally a dead body in the window seat of his aunts' house, and the old aunts admit that they are the cause, as they have made killing old, lonely men their secret business. Things get more complicated when Mortimer's long gone brother Jonathan returns home unexpectedly after decades, with also a dead body with him. Almost universally hailed as a Black Comedy classic, this adaptation of the play of the same name contains numerous memorable characters, situations and dialogue, the main ingredients of a typical American classic. Its non-stop frenzy is highlighted by the fact that most of the film is set in the living room of the house, so that there is not only a much greater focus on the various storyline twist and turns, but also so that it feels much more like the original play itself. One of Frank Capra's most famous and successful works.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Is That a Body in Your Window Seat or Are You Just Happy to See Me?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brocksilvey
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Cary Grant works his tail off in this morbid comedy with an unusually high body count. Grant brings his brand-new wife (a perky Priscilla Lane) home to meet his two spinster aunts -- only to make the grisly discovery that his aunts have been murdering lonely male boarders and burying them in the basement. If this weren't stressful enough, Grant's sociopathic brother (played humorously by Raymond Massey) shows up with a body of his own to get rid of. What's a man to do? Frank Capra does a pretty good job of blending the screwball with the macabre, and nearly every joke and bit of physical comedy falls to Grant, who breezes through the whole movie with aplomb. It's a bit longer than it needs to be (o.k. so maybe it's a LOT longer than it needs to be), but it's still a lot of fun. Grade: A-
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Frank Capra And Cary Grant Comedy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Arsenic and Old Lace is a film directed by Frank Capra based on Joseph Kesselring's play of the same title. The screenplay adaptation was by Julius J. Epstein and Philip G. Epstein.Ti features Cary Grant and Josephine Hull together with Jean Adair and Raymond Massey.The movie is about the sweet old Brewster sisters, beloved in their genteel Brooklyn neighborhood for their many charitable acts. One charity which the ladies don't advertise is their ongoing effort to permit lonely bachelors to die with smiles on their faces by serving said bachelors elderberry wine spiked with arsenic. When the sisters' drama-critic nephew Mortimer stumbles onto their secret, he is understandably put out especially since he has just married the lovely Elaine Harper. Given the homicidal tendencies of his aunts, the sinister activities of his escaped-convict older brother Jonathan and the disruptive behavior of younger brother Teddy who is convinced that he's really Theodore Roosevelt, and runs around the house yelling and Mortimer isn't keen on starting a family with his new bride. "Insanity runs in my family," he explains. "It practically gallops." Further complications ensue when the murderous Jonathan Brewster arrives home, with his sniveling accomplice Dr. Einstein in tow. When Jonathan learns that his darling aunts have killed twelve men, he is incensed and they're challenging his own record of murders. Despite the fact that picture runs almost two hours, Frank Capra has expanded on the original play to a sufficient extent to maintain a steady, consistent pace.Also,unable to conceal the film's theatrical origins, Capra misfires as a director and misguides Cary Garnt, who's too mannered, but the time, the combo of horror and comedy was new and the old ladies' gruesome hobby was shocking to audiences.But nevertheless,Capra encourages the cast, especially Grant, to give a somewhat more out-sized performance than one might expect. But made during the war years as it was, this overstated comic approach to killing was probably cathartic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Epic Performance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    k-keith
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Plays and books always seem to be better than movies to me, but this is one of the exceptions. It's comedic genius, in large part because of the overly dramatic acting. Cary Grant is quoted as disliking his acting because of this, but the movie would never have been as good without that quality of being a little too much. All of the characters are meant to be a little too much, and this creates a balance within the movie between the panicked Mortimer, the peaceful aunts and the psychotic Jonathan. I love the descriptive dialogue by both Mortimer and the police officer at the end of the movie foreshadowing what steps Jonathan will take. It is also amusing the way that Mortimer's love story is cast aside in favor of handling the aunts, Teddy and Jonathan.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Extraordinary funny masterpiece of black comedy.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    psagray
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Movie filmed in 1941 by the great Sicilian-born filmmaker, Frank Capra, is based on the play, "Arsenic and Old Lace" written by novelist and playwright German born American, Joseph Kesselring, and was not yet premiered in 1944, when it had its last performance in the Broadway stage. It is adapted to the screen by the Epstein brothers (the writers of the famed "Casablanca"), is brilliantly narrated and tone of black comedy is elegantly showing each of its excellent frames, serve as a clear inspiration for the staging and conducting post as another big movie was "the Ladykillers" 1955 by Alexander MacKendrick, eleven years later ... It has an extraordinary staging and a dazzling black and white photography by renowned Sol Polito and a soundtrack of the most suggestive by another prominent author, Max Steiner, the film is a sign, yet another, the principal of "It Happened One Night" . This film is among the best of Gary Grant, although the actor himself was not happy with his own performance due to the strong character of his character histrionic mandated by Capra, the truth is that it is essential for this action film. The performance of the brother of "Mortimer" (Gary Grant), "Jonathan" (Raymond Massey) undoubtedly contributes to the tone of black comedy that is in every frame ... maybe its majestic presence make him starring as historical emblematic and enigmatic as Abraham Lincoln's own ... along with such great performances from Peter Lorre had just filmed "Casablanca" doing this mysterious and peculiar of Dr. Einstein, and the interpretation of John Alexander doing that unforgettable role crazy guy "Teddy Brewster", believing Theodore Roosevelt's famous cry of "(Charge!)!" (Roosevelt made famous during charging San Juan Hill) upstairs and unscrewing clockwise wall ... make this movie a masterpiece to consider.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Incredibly strange but very funny
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Terrell Howell (KnightsofNi11)
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What would you do if you found out that your own dear aunts were homicidal maniacs? There's a variety of ways to deal with the situation but Cary Grant probably picks the most unorthodox and unconventional solutions in Arsenic and Old Lace, a classic Frank Capra comedy from 1944. Grant stars as Mortimer Brewster, a drama critique who, at the opening of the film, marries his girlfriend. He goes home to tell his aunts and prepare for his honeymoon to Niagra Falls. However, while at home he finds out his aunts have poisoned twelve men over the past few months and they are all buried in the cellar. This news sends Mortimer racing around trying to hide the fact that his aunts are homicidal, while also dealing with a variety of other problems as this kind of insanity runs in his family. At the same time as he is dealing with his aunts Mortimer has one brother who thinks he's Teddy Roosevelt and another a deformed serial killer who, after being gone for twenty years, decides to return home at the most inopportune time. It's a wild and bizarre ride that is chock full of innocently delightful laughs. Arsenic and Old Lace represents the Golden Age of the American comedy. Some of the most classic comedies were made during World War II in order to ease the troubled times America was involved in. Arsenic and Old Lace falls right in with these films, having been released in 1944. Therefore, it's only purpose is just to make us laugh. It aims to entertain and delight, and I would say it does just that. It's got a cavalcade of wacky and eccentric characters played by a fantastic cast of hilarious actors and actresses. The duo of Aunt Abby and Aunt Martha is one of the most hilarious on screen pairings I've ever seen and the two actresses, Josephine Hull and Jean Adair respectively, play the part so perfectly. They come off as the sweetest old ladies you could ever meet who just don't understand what all the fuss is about concerning the twelve dead bodies they have buried in their cellar. It's certainly comedy at its most intelligent. The whole point of Arsenic and Old Lace is to be incredibly weird in a very entertaining way. And that is definitely what it does. This is a very strange film with all sorts of moments that make you scratch your head in confusion and chuckle at the same time. It's an incredibly offbeat film for its time, and this adds to the humor. As far as comedy goes this isn't quite my cup of tea, but I have the utmost respect for what a quality comedy film this is. Personally my taste leans towards more modern comedy stilings, but Arsenic and Old Lace is representative of a great era of comedy and just film in general. It's a great film that shouldn't be missed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wouldn't You Be A Little Manic, If Your Two Elderly Aunts Were Murderers ?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    PamelaShort
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film version of the classic play "Arsenic And Old Lace" is absolutely superb. Every single player in this amazing comedy, all perform first rate renditions of their characters. Dear Priscilla Lane is lovely in her small role as Cary Grant's bewildered bride. Josephine Hull and Jean Adair are totally convincing as the elderly Brewster Aunts, only trying to help their lonely elderly male boarders by poisoning them. Raymond Massey plays the fiendish Cousin Jonathan to a tee, with his equally creepy sidekick Peter Lorre. Edward Everett Horton is so ideal as Mr. Witherspoon of the Happy Dale Sanitarium, coming to claim the eccentric Uncle Teddy Brewster, who believes he is President Roosevelt. Jack Carson is funny as the dense police officer O'Hara. Cary Grant is a complete riot as nephew Mortimer Brewster, who so vainly tries to resolve the predicament his kooky Aunts have placed him in. Grant never misses a beat, and his facial expressions are priceless. I believe it to be one of his most winning-est performances. Frank Capra pulls it all together into one deliriously enjoyable comedy. I never tire of watching this classic movie, a favourite of mine to start off every Halloween.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    you can't 'live' without it
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    theoneandonlyjimmypage
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ONCE UPON A TIME....it's a Sunday afternoon and it is raining...there's nothing to do...nobody's home,the ballgame isn t on until this evening....you ve finished your work and your chores,you ve showered and you set out to make an omelette-so of course you will break some eggs..and no...there isn t 'a penguin'on the tele there's 'arsenic and old lace' (on the tele-).something to do...a great old movie...and funny...still.THE FIRST TIME AND THE SECOND AND THIRD AND FOURTH AND FOURTH the second time or fifth,the thing about breaking a few eggs-its a kind of a 'mad-cap' tale-he did what/she said that/they really this/allthat another that but this....etc,etc,etc AND SXTH AND SEVENTH AND EIGHTH AND NINTH AND TENTH...WATCH 'ARSENIC AND OLD LACE'--you can t live without it!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Oh, Mortimer...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MalteseRambo
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie showcases the finest of Frank Capra and frequent collaborator Cary Grant. It has the perfect combination of genres: Hilariously funny, just the right amount of romance, and the apparent main theme of crime. The greatest part of this movie is definitely the vast array of facial expressions shown by Grant, especially the priceless look of surprise when he sees the dead man in the window seat. The wonderful supporting cast is comprised of the blonde bombshell love interest played by Priscilla Lane. The dimwitted aunts played by Josephine Hull & Jean Adair. The unhinged brother played by John Alexander. And the sinister fugitives, his brother played by Boris Karloff, I mean Raymond Massey; and his doctor played by Peter Lorre. Without question, this is one of my favourite comedies, my favourite Capra film, my favourite Grant film, and one of my favourite film released before 1950. This is definitely Frank Capra at his greatest, and it should appear a hell of a lot higher on the IMDb Top 250. This movie should already be in the National Film Registry, but unfortunately it isn't. "You  get out of here! D'ya wanna be poisoned? D'ya wanna be murdered? D'ya wanna be killed?" - Mortimer Brewster
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent story collision
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Electro Bear
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Cary Grant stars in this absurd black comedy, featuring some of his most entertaining acting put to film. It also features some creative shots at points, but it's long takes respect the actors involved, and lets each scene grow at a pace taken by its actors. The writing is phenomenal, the setup for each character and their purpose drives the story forwards, and its hilarious to watch the actors enter each scene and complicate things further. The self-contained irony, the black humour, the absurdity, is all suddenly compounded towards the end, when Cary Grant himself accepts the insanity of the entire situation. It is also amazing to see a movie with such honestly dark patches, also be so family safe, a tribute to the great writing, and Frank Capra's direction. Not only is this movie hilarious, but it also has some genuinely horrifying moments. The monstrous Jonathan Brewster, played by Raymond Massey, coupled with his terrible facial scars is an honestly scary figure and has some oddly striking scenes mixed in with the all of the humour. Peter Lorre puts in a great mousy performance, and takes plenty of amusing abuse from all of the characters. Recommended viewing. Especially for fans of Cary Grant.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Nutcase Evening
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nick-leonardi
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Major theatre critic Mortimer Brewster (Cary Grant) on Halloween gets married to Elaine. He goes back to his two aunts' house to tell the good news. Mortimer later that day discovers accidentally a dead body in the window seat of his aunts' house, and the old aunts admit that they are the cause, as they have made killing old, lonely men their secret business. Things get more complicated when Mortimer's long gone brother Jonathan returns home unexpectedly after decades, with also a dead body with him. Almost universally hailed as a Black Comedy classic, this adaptation of the play of the same name contains numerous memorable characters, situations and dialogue, the main ingredients of a typical American classic. Its non-stop frenzy is highlighted by the fact that most of the film is set in the living room of the house, so that there is not only a much greater focus on the various storyline twist and turns, but also so that it feels much more like the original play itself. One of Frank Capra's most famous and successful works.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Is That a Body in Your Window Seat or Are You Just Happy to See Me?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brocksilvey
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Cary Grant works his tail off in this morbid comedy with an unusually high body count. Grant brings his brand-new wife (a perky Priscilla Lane) home to meet his two spinster aunts -- only to make the grisly discovery that his aunts have been murdering lonely male boarders and burying them in the basement. If this weren't stressful enough, Grant's sociopathic brother (played humorously by Raymond Massey) shows up with a body of his own to get rid of. What's a man to do? Frank Capra does a pretty good job of blending the screwball with the macabre, and nearly every joke and bit of physical comedy falls to Grant, who breezes through the whole movie with aplomb. It's a bit longer than it needs to be (o.k. so maybe it's a LOT longer than it needs to be), but it's still a lot of fun. Grade: A-
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Frank Capra And Cary Grant Comedy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Arsenic and Old Lace is a film directed by Frank Capra based on Joseph Kesselring's play of the same title. The screenplay adaptation was by Julius J. Epstein and Philip G. Epstein.Ti features Cary Grant and Josephine Hull together with Jean Adair and Raymond Massey.The movie is about the sweet old Brewster sisters, beloved in their genteel Brooklyn neighborhood for their many charitable acts. One charity which the ladies don't advertise is their ongoing effort to permit lonely bachelors to die with smiles on their faces by serving said bachelors elderberry wine spiked with arsenic. When the sisters' drama-critic nephew Mortimer stumbles onto their secret, he is understandably put out especially since he has just married the lovely Elaine Harper. Given the homicidal tendencies of his aunts, the sinister activities of his escaped-convict older brother Jonathan and the disruptive behavior of younger brother Teddy who is convinced that he's really Theodore Roosevelt, and runs around the house yelling and Mortimer isn't keen on starting a family with his new bride. "Insanity runs in my family," he explains. "It practically gallops." Further complications ensue when the murderous Jonathan Brewster arrives home, with his sniveling accomplice Dr. Einstein in tow. When Jonathan learns that his darling aunts have killed twelve men, he is incensed and they're challenging his own record of murders. Despite the fact that picture runs almost two hours, Frank Capra has expanded on the original play to a sufficient extent to maintain a steady, consistent pace.Also,unable to conceal the film's theatrical origins, Capra misfires as a director and misguides Cary Garnt, who's too mannered, but the time, the combo of horror and comedy was new and the old ladies' gruesome hobby was shocking to audiences.But nevertheless,Capra encourages the cast, especially Grant, to give a somewhat more out-sized performance than one might expect. But made during the war years as it was, this overstated comic approach to killing was probably cathartic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Epic Performance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    k-keith
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Plays and books always seem to be better than movies to me, but this is one of the exceptions. It's comedic genius, in large part because of the overly dramatic acting. Cary Grant is quoted as disliking his acting because of this, but the movie would never have been as good without that quality of being a little too much. All of the characters are meant to be a little too much, and this creates a balance within the movie between the panicked Mortimer, the peaceful aunts and the psychotic Jonathan. I love the descriptive dialogue by both Mortimer and the police officer at the end of the movie foreshadowing what steps Jonathan will take. It is also amusing the way that Mortimer's love story is cast aside in favor of handling the aunts, Teddy and Jonathan.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Extraordinary funny masterpiece of black comedy.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    psagray
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Movie filmed in 1941 by the great Sicilian-born filmmaker, Frank Capra, is based on the play, "Arsenic and Old Lace" written by novelist and playwright German born American, Joseph Kesselring, and was not yet premiered in 1944, when it had its last performance in the Broadway stage. It is adapted to the screen by the Epstein brothers (the writers of the famed "Casablanca"), is brilliantly narrated and tone of black comedy is elegantly showing each of its excellent frames, serve as a clear inspiration for the staging and conducting post as another big movie was "the Ladykillers" 1955 by Alexander MacKendrick, eleven years later ... It has an extraordinary staging and a dazzling black and white photography by renowned Sol Polito and a soundtrack of the most suggestive by another prominent author, Max Steiner, the film is a sign, yet another, the principal of "It Happened One Night" . This film is among the best of Gary Grant, although the actor himself was not happy with his own performance due to the strong character of his character histrionic mandated by Capra, the truth is that it is essential for this action film. The performance of the brother of "Mortimer" (Gary Grant), "Jonathan" (Raymond Massey) undoubtedly contributes to the tone of black comedy that is in every frame ... maybe its majestic presence make him starring as historical emblematic and enigmatic as Abraham Lincoln's own ... along with such great performances from Peter Lorre had just filmed "Casablanca" doing this mysterious and peculiar of Dr. Einstein, and the interpretation of John Alexander doing that unforgettable role crazy guy "Teddy Brewster", believing Theodore Roosevelt's famous cry of "(Charge!)!" (Roosevelt made famous during charging San Juan Hill) upstairs and unscrewing clockwise wall ... make this movie a masterpiece to consider.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Incredibly strange but very funny
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Terrell Howell (KnightsofNi11)
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What would you do if you found out that your own dear aunts were homicidal maniacs? There's a variety of ways to deal with the situation but Cary Grant probably picks the most unorthodox and unconventional solutions in Arsenic and Old Lace, a classic Frank Capra comedy from 1944. Grant stars as Mortimer Brewster, a drama critique who, at the opening of the film, marries his girlfriend. He goes home to tell his aunts and prepare for his honeymoon to Niagra Falls. However, while at home he finds out his aunts have poisoned twelve men over the past few months and they are all buried in the cellar. This news sends Mortimer racing around trying to hide the fact that his aunts are homicidal, while also dealing with a variety of other problems as this kind of insanity runs in his family. At the same time as he is dealing with his aunts Mortimer has one brother who thinks he's Teddy Roosevelt and another a deformed serial killer who, after being gone for twenty years, decides to return home at the most inopportune time. It's a wild and bizarre ride that is chock full of innocently delightful laughs. Arsenic and Old Lace represents the Golden Age of the American comedy. Some of the most classic comedies were made during World War II in order to ease the troubled times America was involved in. Arsenic and Old Lace falls right in with these films, having been released in 1944. Therefore, it's only purpose is just to make us laugh. It aims to entertain and delight, and I would say it does just that. It's got a cavalcade of wacky and eccentric characters played by a fantastic cast of hilarious actors and actresses. The duo of Aunt Abby and Aunt Martha is one of the most hilarious on screen pairings I've ever seen and the two actresses, Josephine Hull and Jean Adair respectively, play the part so perfectly. They come off as the sweetest old ladies you could ever meet who just don't understand what all the fuss is about concerning the twelve dead bodies they have buried in their cellar. It's certainly comedy at its most intelligent. The whole point of Arsenic and Old Lace is to be incredibly weird in a very entertaining way. And that is definitely what it does. This is a very strange film with all sorts of moments that make you scratch your head in confusion and chuckle at the same time. It's an incredibly offbeat film for its time, and this adds to the humor. As far as comedy goes this isn't quite my cup of tea, but I have the utmost respect for what a quality comedy film this is. Personally my taste leans towards more modern comedy stilings, but Arsenic and Old Lace is representative of a great era of comedy and just film in general. It's a great film that shouldn't be missed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wouldn't You Be A Little Manic, If Your Two Elderly Aunts Were Murderers ?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    PamelaShort
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film version of the classic play "Arsenic And Old Lace" is absolutely superb. Every single player in this amazing comedy, all perform first rate renditions of their characters. Dear Priscilla Lane is lovely in her small role as Cary Grant's bewildered bride. Josephine Hull and Jean Adair are totally convincing as the elderly Brewster Aunts, only trying to help their lonely elderly male boarders by poisoning them. Raymond Massey plays the fiendish Cousin Jonathan to a tee, with his equally creepy sidekick Peter Lorre. Edward Everett Horton is so ideal as Mr. Witherspoon of the Happy Dale Sanitarium, coming to claim the eccentric Uncle Teddy Brewster, who believes he is President Roosevelt. Jack Carson is funny as the dense police officer O'Hara. Cary Grant is a complete riot as nephew Mortimer Brewster, who so vainly tries to resolve the predicament his kooky Aunts have placed him in. Grant never misses a beat, and his facial expressions are priceless. I believe it to be one of his most winning-est performances. Frank Capra pulls it all together into one deliriously enjoyable comedy. I never tire of watching this classic movie, a favourite of mine to start off every Halloween.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    you can't 'live' without it
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    theoneandonlyjimmypage
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ONCE UPON A TIME....it's a Sunday afternoon and it is raining...there's nothing to do...nobody's home,the ballgame isn t on until this evening....you ve finished your work and your chores,you ve showered and you set out to make an omelette-so of course you will break some eggs..and no...there isn t 'a penguin'on the tele there's 'arsenic and old lace' (on the tele-).something to do...a great old movie...and funny...still.THE FIRST TIME AND THE SECOND AND THIRD AND FOURTH AND FOURTH the second time or fifth,the thing about breaking a few eggs-its a kind of a 'mad-cap' tale-he did what/she said that/they really this/allthat another that but this....etc,etc,etc AND SXTH AND SEVENTH AND EIGHTH AND NINTH AND TENTH...WATCH 'ARSENIC AND OLD LACE'--you can t live without it!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Oh, Mortimer...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MalteseRambo
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie showcases the finest of Frank Capra and frequent collaborator Cary Grant. It has the perfect combination of genres: Hilariously funny, just the right amount of romance, and the apparent main theme of crime. The greatest part of this movie is definitely the vast array of facial expressions shown by Grant, especially the priceless look of surprise when he sees the dead man in the window seat. The wonderful supporting cast is comprised of the blonde bombshell love interest played by Priscilla Lane. The dimwitted aunts played by Josephine Hull & Jean Adair. The unhinged brother played by John Alexander. And the sinister fugitives, his brother played by Boris Karloff, I mean Raymond Massey; and his doctor played by Peter Lorre. Without question, this is one of my favourite comedies, my favourite Capra film, my favourite Grant film, and one of my favourite film released before 1950. This is definitely Frank Capra at his greatest, and it should appear a hell of a lot higher on the IMDb Top 250. This movie should already be in the National Film Registry, but unfortunately it isn't. "You  get out of here! D'ya wanna be poisoned? D'ya wanna be murdered? D'ya wanna be killed?" - Mortimer Brewster
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent story collision
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Electro Bear
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Cary Grant stars in this absurd black comedy, featuring some of his most entertaining acting put to film. It also features some creative shots at points, but it's long takes respect the actors involved, and lets each scene grow at a pace taken by its actors. The writing is phenomenal, the setup for each character and their purpose drives the story forwards, and its hilarious to watch the actors enter each scene and complicate things further. The self-contained irony, the black humour, the absurdity, is all suddenly compounded towards the end, when Cary Grant himself accepts the insanity of the entire situation. It is also amazing to see a movie with such honestly dark patches, also be so family safe, a tribute to the great writing, and Frank Capra's direction. Not only is this movie hilarious, but it also has some genuinely horrifying moments. The monstrous Jonathan Brewster, played by Raymond Massey, coupled with his terrible facial scars is an honestly scary figure and has some oddly striking scenes mixed in with the all of the humour. Peter Lorre puts in a great mousy performance, and takes plenty of amusing abuse from all of the characters. Recommended viewing. Especially for fans of Cary Grant.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Nutcase Evening
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nick-leonardi
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Major theatre critic Mortimer Brewster (Cary Grant) on Halloween gets married to Elaine. He goes back to his two aunts' house to tell the good news. Mortimer later that day discovers accidentally a dead body in the window seat of his aunts' house, and the old aunts admit that they are the cause, as they have made killing old, lonely men their secret business. Things get more complicated when Mortimer's long gone brother Jonathan returns home unexpectedly after decades, with also a dead body with him. Almost universally hailed as a Black Comedy classic, this adaptation of the play of the same name contains numerous memorable characters, situations and dialogue, the main ingredients of a typical American classic. Its non-stop frenzy is highlighted by the fact that most of the film is set in the living room of the house, so that there is not only a much greater focus on the various storyline twist and turns, but also so that it feels much more like the original play itself. One of Frank Capra's most famous and successful works.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Is That a Body in Your Window Seat or Are You Just Happy to See Me?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brocksilvey
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Cary Grant works his tail off in this morbid comedy with an unusually high body count. Grant brings his brand-new wife (a perky Priscilla Lane) home to meet his two spinster aunts -- only to make the grisly discovery that his aunts have been murdering lonely male boarders and burying them in the basement. If this weren't stressful enough, Grant's sociopathic brother (played humorously by Raymond Massey) shows up with a body of his own to get rid of. What's a man to do? Frank Capra does a pretty good job of blending the screwball with the macabre, and nearly every joke and bit of physical comedy falls to Grant, who breezes through the whole movie with aplomb. It's a bit longer than it needs to be (o.k. so maybe it's a LOT longer than it needs to be), but it's still a lot of fun. Grade: A-
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Frank Capra And Cary Grant Comedy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Arsenic and Old Lace is a film directed by Frank Capra based on Joseph Kesselring's play of the same title. The screenplay adaptation was by Julius J. Epstein and Philip G. Epstein.Ti features Cary Grant and Josephine Hull together with Jean Adair and Raymond Massey.The movie is about the sweet old Brewster sisters, beloved in their genteel Brooklyn neighborhood for their many charitable acts. One charity which the ladies don't advertise is their ongoing effort to permit lonely bachelors to die with smiles on their faces by serving said bachelors elderberry wine spiked with arsenic. When the sisters' drama-critic nephew Mortimer stumbles onto their secret, he is understandably put out especially since he has just married the lovely Elaine Harper. Given the homicidal tendencies of his aunts, the sinister activities of his escaped-convict older brother Jonathan and the disruptive behavior of younger brother Teddy who is convinced that he's really Theodore Roosevelt, and runs around the house yelling and Mortimer isn't keen on starting a family with his new bride. "Insanity runs in my family," he explains. "It practically gallops." Further complications ensue when the murderous Jonathan Brewster arrives home, with his sniveling accomplice Dr. Einstein in tow. When Jonathan learns that his darling aunts have killed twelve men, he is incensed and they're challenging his own record of murders. Despite the fact that picture runs almost two hours, Frank Capra has expanded on the original play to a sufficient extent to maintain a steady, consistent pace.Also,unable to conceal the film's theatrical origins, Capra misfires as a director and misguides Cary Garnt, who's too mannered, but the time, the combo of horror and comedy was new and the old ladies' gruesome hobby was shocking to audiences.But nevertheless,Capra encourages the cast, especially Grant, to give a somewhat more out-sized performance than one might expect. But made during the war years as it was, this overstated comic approach to killing was probably cathartic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Epic Performance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    k-keith
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Plays and books always seem to be better than movies to me, but this is one of the exceptions. It's comedic genius, in large part because of the overly dramatic acting. Cary Grant is quoted as disliking his acting because of this, but the movie would never have been as good without that quality of being a little too much. All of the characters are meant to be a little too much, and this creates a balance within the movie between the panicked Mortimer, the peaceful aunts and the psychotic Jonathan. I love the descriptive dialogue by both Mortimer and the police officer at the end of the movie foreshadowing what steps Jonathan will take. It is also amusing the way that Mortimer's love story is cast aside in favor of handling the aunts, Teddy and Jonathan.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Extraordinary funny masterpiece of black comedy.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    psagray
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Movie filmed in 1941 by the great Sicilian-born filmmaker, Frank Capra, is based on the play, "Arsenic and Old Lace" written by novelist and playwright German born American, Joseph Kesselring, and was not yet premiered in 1944, when it had its last performance in the Broadway stage. It is adapted to the screen by the Epstein brothers (the writers of the famed "Casablanca"), is brilliantly narrated and tone of black comedy is elegantly showing each of its excellent frames, serve as a clear inspiration for the staging and conducting post as another big movie was "the Ladykillers" 1955 by Alexander MacKendrick, eleven years later ... It has an extraordinary staging and a dazzling black and white photography by renowned Sol Polito and a soundtrack of the most suggestive by another prominent author, Max Steiner, the film is a sign, yet another, the principal of "It Happened One Night" . This film is among the best of Gary Grant, although the actor himself was not happy with his own performance due to the strong character of his character histrionic mandated by Capra, the truth is that it is essential for this action film. The performance of the brother of "Mortimer" (Gary Grant), "Jonathan" (Raymond Massey) undoubtedly contributes to the tone of black comedy that is in every frame ... maybe its majestic presence make him starring as historical emblematic and enigmatic as Abraham Lincoln's own ... along with such great performances from Peter Lorre had just filmed "Casablanca" doing this mysterious and peculiar of Dr. Einstein, and the interpretation of John Alexander doing that unforgettable role crazy guy "Teddy Brewster", believing Theodore Roosevelt's famous cry of "(Charge!)!" (Roosevelt made famous during charging San Juan Hill) upstairs and unscrewing clockwise wall ... make this movie a masterpiece to consider.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Incredibly strange but very funny
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Terrell Howell (KnightsofNi11)
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What would you do if you found out that your own dear aunts were homicidal maniacs? There's a variety of ways to deal with the situation but Cary Grant probably picks the most unorthodox and unconventional solutions in Arsenic and Old Lace, a classic Frank Capra comedy from 1944. Grant stars as Mortimer Brewster, a drama critique who, at the opening of the film, marries his girlfriend. He goes home to tell his aunts and prepare for his honeymoon to Niagra Falls. However, while at home he finds out his aunts have poisoned twelve men over the past few months and they are all buried in the cellar. This news sends Mortimer racing around trying to hide the fact that his aunts are homicidal, while also dealing with a variety of other problems as this kind of insanity runs in his family. At the same time as he is dealing with his aunts Mortimer has one brother who thinks he's Teddy Roosevelt and another a deformed serial killer who, after being gone for twenty years, decides to return home at the most inopportune time. It's a wild and bizarre ride that is chock full of innocently delightful laughs. Arsenic and Old Lace represents the Golden Age of the American comedy. Some of the most classic comedies were made during World War II in order to ease the troubled times America was involved in. Arsenic and Old Lace falls right in with these films, having been released in 1944. Therefore, it's only purpose is just to make us laugh. It aims to entertain and delight, and I would say it does just that. It's got a cavalcade of wacky and eccentric characters played by a fantastic cast of hilarious actors and actresses. The duo of Aunt Abby and Aunt Martha is one of the most hilarious on screen pairings I've ever seen and the two actresses, Josephine Hull and Jean Adair respectively, play the part so perfectly. They come off as the sweetest old ladies you could ever meet who just don't understand what all the fuss is about concerning the twelve dead bodies they have buried in their cellar. It's certainly comedy at its most intelligent. The whole point of Arsenic and Old Lace is to be incredibly weird in a very entertaining way. And that is definitely what it does. This is a very strange film with all sorts of moments that make you scratch your head in confusion and chuckle at the same time. It's an incredibly offbeat film for its time, and this adds to the humor. As far as comedy goes this isn't quite my cup of tea, but I have the utmost respect for what a quality comedy film this is. Personally my taste leans towards more modern comedy stilings, but Arsenic and Old Lace is representative of a great era of comedy and just film in general. It's a great film that shouldn't be missed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wouldn't You Be A Little Manic, If Your Two Elderly Aunts Were Murderers ?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    PamelaShort
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film version of the classic play "Arsenic And Old Lace" is absolutely superb. Every single player in this amazing comedy, all perform first rate renditions of their characters. Dear Priscilla Lane is lovely in her small role as Cary Grant's bewildered bride. Josephine Hull and Jean Adair are totally convincing as the elderly Brewster Aunts, only trying to help their lonely elderly male boarders by poisoning them. Raymond Massey plays the fiendish Cousin Jonathan to a tee, with his equally creepy sidekick Peter Lorre. Edward Everett Horton is so ideal as Mr. Witherspoon of the Happy Dale Sanitarium, coming to claim the eccentric Uncle Teddy Brewster, who believes he is President Roosevelt. Jack Carson is funny as the dense police officer O'Hara. Cary Grant is a complete riot as nephew Mortimer Brewster, who so vainly tries to resolve the predicament his kooky Aunts have placed him in. Grant never misses a beat, and his facial expressions are priceless. I believe it to be one of his most winning-est performances. Frank Capra pulls it all together into one deliriously enjoyable comedy. I never tire of watching this classic movie, a favourite of mine to start off every Halloween.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    you can't 'live' without it
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    theoneandonlyjimmypage
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ONCE UPON A TIME....it's a Sunday afternoon and it is raining...there's nothing to do...nobody's home,the ballgame isn t on until this evening....you ve finished your work and your chores,you ve showered and you set out to make an omelette-so of course you will break some eggs..and no...there isn t 'a penguin'on the tele there's 'arsenic and old lace' (on the tele-).something to do...a great old movie...and funny...still.THE FIRST TIME AND THE SECOND AND THIRD AND FOURTH AND FOURTH the second time or fifth,the thing about breaking a few eggs-its a kind of a 'mad-cap' tale-he did what/she said that/they really this/allthat another that but this....etc,etc,etc AND SXTH AND SEVENTH AND EIGHTH AND NINTH AND TENTH...WATCH 'ARSENIC AND OLD LACE'--you can t live without it!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Oh, Mortimer...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MalteseRambo
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie showcases the finest of Frank Capra and frequent collaborator Cary Grant. It has the perfect combination of genres: Hilariously funny, just the right amount of romance, and the apparent main theme of crime. The greatest part of this movie is definitely the vast array of facial expressions shown by Grant, especially the priceless look of surprise when he sees the dead man in the window seat. The wonderful supporting cast is comprised of the blonde bombshell love interest played by Priscilla Lane. The dimwitted aunts played by Josephine Hull & Jean Adair. The unhinged brother played by John Alexander. And the sinister fugitives, his brother played by Boris Karloff, I mean Raymond Massey; and his doctor played by Peter Lorre. Without question, this is one of my favourite comedies, my favourite Capra film, my favourite Grant film, and one of my favourite film released before 1950. This is definitely Frank Capra at his greatest, and it should appear a hell of a lot higher on the IMDb Top 250. This movie should already be in the National Film Registry, but unfortunately it isn't. "You  get out of here! D'ya wanna be poisoned? D'ya wanna be murdered? D'ya wanna be killed?" - Mortimer Brewster
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent story collision
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Electro Bear
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Cary Grant stars in this absurd black comedy, featuring some of his most entertaining acting put to film. It also features some creative shots at points, but it's long takes respect the actors involved, and lets each scene grow at a pace taken by its actors. The writing is phenomenal, the setup for each character and their purpose drives the story forwards, and its hilarious to watch the actors enter each scene and complicate things further. The self-contained irony, the black humour, the absurdity, is all suddenly compounded towards the end, when Cary Grant himself accepts the insanity of the entire situation. It is also amazing to see a movie with such honestly dark patches, also be so family safe, a tribute to the great writing, and Frank Capra's direction. Not only is this movie hilarious, but it also has some genuinely horrifying moments. The monstrous Jonathan Brewster, played by Raymond Massey, coupled with his terrible facial scars is an honestly scary figure and has some oddly striking scenes mixed in with the all of the humour. Peter Lorre puts in a great mousy performance, and takes plenty of amusing abuse from all of the characters. Recommended viewing. Especially for fans of Cary Grant.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Nutcase Evening
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nick-leonardi
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Major theatre critic Mortimer Brewster (Cary Grant) on Halloween gets married to Elaine. He goes back to his two aunts' house to tell the good news. Mortimer later that day discovers accidentally a dead body in the window seat of his aunts' house, and the old aunts admit that they are the cause, as they have made killing old, lonely men their secret business. Things get more complicated when Mortimer's long gone brother Jonathan returns home unexpectedly after decades, with also a dead body with him. Almost universally hailed as a Black Comedy classic, this adaptation of the play of the same name contains numerous memorable characters, situations and dialogue, the main ingredients of a typical American classic. Its non-stop frenzy is highlighted by the fact that most of the film is set in the living room of the house, so that there is not only a much greater focus on the various storyline twist and turns, but also so that it feels much more like the original play itself. One of Frank Capra's most famous and successful works.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Is That a Body in Your Window Seat or Are You Just Happy to See Me?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brocksilvey
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Cary Grant works his tail off in this morbid comedy with an unusually high body count. Grant brings his brand-new wife (a perky Priscilla Lane) home to meet his two spinster aunts -- only to make the grisly discovery that his aunts have been murdering lonely male boarders and burying them in the basement. If this weren't stressful enough, Grant's sociopathic brother (played humorously by Raymond Massey) shows up with a body of his own to get rid of. What's a man to do? Frank Capra does a pretty good job of blending the screwball with the macabre, and nearly every joke and bit of physical comedy falls to Grant, who breezes through the whole movie with aplomb. It's a bit longer than it needs to be (o.k. so maybe it's a LOT longer than it needs to be), but it's still a lot of fun. Grade: A-
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Frank Capra And Cary Grant Comedy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Arsenic and Old Lace is a film directed by Frank Capra based on Joseph Kesselring's play of the same title. The screenplay adaptation was by Julius J. Epstein and Philip G. Epstein.Ti features Cary Grant and Josephine Hull together with Jean Adair and Raymond Massey.The movie is about the sweet old Brewster sisters, beloved in their genteel Brooklyn neighborhood for their many charitable acts. One charity which the ladies don't advertise is their ongoing effort to permit lonely bachelors to die with smiles on their faces by serving said bachelors elderberry wine spiked with arsenic. When the sisters' drama-critic nephew Mortimer stumbles onto their secret, he is understandably put out especially since he has just married the lovely Elaine Harper. Given the homicidal tendencies of his aunts, the sinister activities of his escaped-convict older brother Jonathan and the disruptive behavior of younger brother Teddy who is convinced that he's really Theodore Roosevelt, and runs around the house yelling and Mortimer isn't keen on starting a family with his new bride. "Insanity runs in my family," he explains. "It practically gallops." Further complications ensue when the murderous Jonathan Brewster arrives home, with his sniveling accomplice Dr. Einstein in tow. When Jonathan learns that his darling aunts have killed twelve men, he is incensed and they're challenging his own record of murders. Despite the fact that picture runs almost two hours, Frank Capra has expanded on the original play to a sufficient extent to maintain a steady, consistent pace.Also,unable to conceal the film's theatrical origins, Capra misfires as a director and misguides Cary Garnt, who's too mannered, but the time, the combo of horror and comedy was new and the old ladies' gruesome hobby was shocking to audiences.But nevertheless,Capra encourages the cast, especially Grant, to give a somewhat more out-sized performance than one might expect. But made during the war years as it was, this overstated comic approach to killing was probably cathartic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Epic Performance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    k-keith
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Plays and books always seem to be better than movies to me, but this is one of the exceptions. It's comedic genius, in large part because of the overly dramatic acting. Cary Grant is quoted as disliking his acting because of this, but the movie would never have been as good without that quality of being a little too much. All of the characters are meant to be a little too much, and this creates a balance within the movie between the panicked Mortimer, the peaceful aunts and the psychotic Jonathan. I love the descriptive dialogue by both Mortimer and the police officer at the end of the movie foreshadowing what steps Jonathan will take. It is also amusing the way that Mortimer's love story is cast aside in favor of handling the aunts, Teddy and Jonathan.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Extraordinary funny masterpiece of black comedy.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    psagray
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Movie filmed in 1941 by the great Sicilian-born filmmaker, Frank Capra, is based on the play, "Arsenic and Old Lace" written by novelist and playwright German born American, Joseph Kesselring, and was not yet premiered in 1944, when it had its last performance in the Broadway stage. It is adapted to the screen by the Epstein brothers (the writers of the famed "Casablanca"), is brilliantly narrated and tone of black comedy is elegantly showing each of its excellent frames, serve as a clear inspiration for the staging and conducting post as another big movie was "the Ladykillers" 1955 by Alexander MacKendrick, eleven years later ... It has an extraordinary staging and a dazzling black and white photography by renowned Sol Polito and a soundtrack of the most suggestive by another prominent author, Max Steiner, the film is a sign, yet another, the principal of "It Happened One Night" . This film is among the best of Gary Grant, although the actor himself was not happy with his own performance due to the strong character of his character histrionic mandated by Capra, the truth is that it is essential for this action film. The performance of the brother of "Mortimer" (Gary Grant), "Jonathan" (Raymond Massey) undoubtedly contributes to the tone of black comedy that is in every frame ... maybe its majestic presence make him starring as historical emblematic and enigmatic as Abraham Lincoln's own ... along with such great performances from Peter Lorre had just filmed "Casablanca" doing this mysterious and peculiar of Dr. Einstein, and the interpretation of John Alexander doing that unforgettable role crazy guy "Teddy Brewster", believing Theodore Roosevelt's famous cry of "(Charge!)!" (Roosevelt made famous during charging San Juan Hill) upstairs and unscrewing clockwise wall ... make this movie a masterpiece to consider.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Incredibly strange but very funny
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Terrell Howell (KnightsofNi11)
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What would you do if you found out that your own dear aunts were homicidal maniacs? There's a variety of ways to deal with the situation but Cary Grant probably picks the most unorthodox and unconventional solutions in Arsenic and Old Lace, a classic Frank Capra comedy from 1944. Grant stars as Mortimer Brewster, a drama critique who, at the opening of the film, marries his girlfriend. He goes home to tell his aunts and prepare for his honeymoon to Niagra Falls. However, while at home he finds out his aunts have poisoned twelve men over the past few months and they are all buried in the cellar. This news sends Mortimer racing around trying to hide the fact that his aunts are homicidal, while also dealing with a variety of other problems as this kind of insanity runs in his family. At the same time as he is dealing with his aunts Mortimer has one brother who thinks he's Teddy Roosevelt and another a deformed serial killer who, after being gone for twenty years, decides to return home at the most inopportune time. It's a wild and bizarre ride that is chock full of innocently delightful laughs. Arsenic and Old Lace represents the Golden Age of the American comedy. Some of the most classic comedies were made during World War II in order to ease the troubled times America was involved in. Arsenic and Old Lace falls right in with these films, having been released in 1944. Therefore, it's only purpose is just to make us laugh. It aims to entertain and delight, and I would say it does just that. It's got a cavalcade of wacky and eccentric characters played by a fantastic cast of hilarious actors and actresses. The duo of Aunt Abby and Aunt Martha is one of the most hilarious on screen pairings I've ever seen and the two actresses, Josephine Hull and Jean Adair respectively, play the part so perfectly. They come off as the sweetest old ladies you could ever meet who just don't understand what all the fuss is about concerning the twelve dead bodies they have buried in their cellar. It's certainly comedy at its most intelligent. The whole point of Arsenic and Old Lace is to be incredibly weird in a very entertaining way. And that is definitely what it does. This is a very strange film with all sorts of moments that make you scratch your head in confusion and chuckle at the same time. It's an incredibly offbeat film for its time, and this adds to the humor. As far as comedy goes this isn't quite my cup of tea, but I have the utmost respect for what a quality comedy film this is. Personally my taste leans towards more modern comedy stilings, but Arsenic and Old Lace is representative of a great era of comedy and just film in general. It's a great film that shouldn't be missed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wouldn't You Be A Little Manic, If Your Two Elderly Aunts Were Murderers ?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    PamelaShort
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film version of the classic play "Arsenic And Old Lace" is absolutely superb. Every single player in this amazing comedy, all perform first rate renditions of their characters. Dear Priscilla Lane is lovely in her small role as Cary Grant's bewildered bride. Josephine Hull and Jean Adair are totally convincing as the elderly Brewster Aunts, only trying to help their lonely elderly male boarders by poisoning them. Raymond Massey plays the fiendish Cousin Jonathan to a tee, with his equally creepy sidekick Peter Lorre. Edward Everett Horton is so ideal as Mr. Witherspoon of the Happy Dale Sanitarium, coming to claim the eccentric Uncle Teddy Brewster, who believes he is President Roosevelt. Jack Carson is funny as the dense police officer O'Hara. Cary Grant is a complete riot as nephew Mortimer Brewster, who so vainly tries to resolve the predicament his kooky Aunts have placed him in. Grant never misses a beat, and his facial expressions are priceless. I believe it to be one of his most winning-est performances. Frank Capra pulls it all together into one deliriously enjoyable comedy. I never tire of watching this classic movie, a favourite of mine to start off every Halloween.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    you can't 'live' without it
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    theoneandonlyjimmypage
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ONCE UPON A TIME....it's a Sunday afternoon and it is raining...there's nothing to do...nobody's home,the ballgame isn t on until this evening....you ve finished your work and your chores,you ve showered and you set out to make an omelette-so of course you will break some eggs..and no...there isn t 'a penguin'on the tele there's 'arsenic and old lace' (on the tele-).something to do...a great old movie...and funny...still.THE FIRST TIME AND THE SECOND AND THIRD AND FOURTH AND FOURTH the second time or fifth,the thing about breaking a few eggs-its a kind of a 'mad-cap' tale-he did what/she said that/they really this/allthat another that but this....etc,etc,etc AND SXTH AND SEVENTH AND EIGHTH AND NINTH AND TENTH...WATCH 'ARSENIC AND OLD LACE'--you can t live without it!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Oh, Mortimer...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MalteseRambo
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie showcases the finest of Frank Capra and frequent collaborator Cary Grant. It has the perfect combination of genres: Hilariously funny, just the right amount of romance, and the apparent main theme of crime. The greatest part of this movie is definitely the vast array of facial expressions shown by Grant, especially the priceless look of surprise when he sees the dead man in the window seat. The wonderful supporting cast is comprised of the blonde bombshell love interest played by Priscilla Lane. The dimwitted aunts played by Josephine Hull & Jean Adair. The unhinged brother played by John Alexander. And the sinister fugitives, his brother played by Boris Karloff, I mean Raymond Massey; and his doctor played by Peter Lorre. Without question, this is one of my favourite comedies, my favourite Capra film, my favourite Grant film, and one of my favourite film released before 1950. This is definitely Frank Capra at his greatest, and it should appear a hell of a lot higher on the IMDb Top 250. This movie should already be in the National Film Registry, but unfortunately it isn't. "You  get out of here! D'ya wanna be poisoned? D'ya wanna be murdered? D'ya wanna be killed?" - Mortimer Brewster
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent story collision
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Electro Bear
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Cary Grant stars in this absurd black comedy, featuring some of his most entertaining acting put to film. It also features some creative shots at points, but it's long takes respect the actors involved, and lets each scene grow at a pace taken by its actors. The writing is phenomenal, the setup for each character and their purpose drives the story forwards, and its hilarious to watch the actors enter each scene and complicate things further. The self-contained irony, the black humour, the absurdity, is all suddenly compounded towards the end, when Cary Grant himself accepts the insanity of the entire situation. It is also amazing to see a movie with such honestly dark patches, also be so family safe, a tribute to the great writing, and Frank Capra's direction. Not only is this movie hilarious, but it also has some genuinely horrifying moments. The monstrous Jonathan Brewster, played by Raymond Massey, coupled with his terrible facial scars is an honestly scary figure and has some oddly striking scenes mixed in with the all of the humour. Peter Lorre puts in a great mousy performance, and takes plenty of amusing abuse from all of the characters. Recommended viewing. Especially for fans of Cary Grant.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Nutcase Evening
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nick-leonardi
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Major theatre critic Mortimer Brewster (Cary Grant) on Halloween gets married to Elaine. He goes back to his two aunts' house to tell the good news. Mortimer later that day discovers accidentally a dead body in the window seat of his aunts' house, and the old aunts admit that they are the cause, as they have made killing old, lonely men their secret business. Things get more complicated when Mortimer's long gone brother Jonathan returns home unexpectedly after decades, with also a dead body with him. Almost universally hailed as a Black Comedy classic, this adaptation of the play of the same name contains numerous memorable characters, situations and dialogue, the main ingredients of a typical American classic. Its non-stop frenzy is highlighted by the fact that most of the film is set in the living room of the house, so that there is not only a much greater focus on the various storyline twist and turns, but also so that it feels much more like the original play itself. One of Frank Capra's most famous and successful works.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Is That a Body in Your Window Seat or Are You Just Happy to See Me?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brocksilvey
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Cary Grant works his tail off in this morbid comedy with an unusually high body count. Grant brings his brand-new wife (a perky Priscilla Lane) home to meet his two spinster aunts -- only to make the grisly discovery that his aunts have been murdering lonely male boarders and burying them in the basement. If this weren't stressful enough, Grant's sociopathic brother (played humorously by Raymond Massey) shows up with a body of his own to get rid of. What's a man to do? Frank Capra does a pretty good job of blending the screwball with the macabre, and nearly every joke and bit of physical comedy falls to Grant, who breezes through the whole movie with aplomb. It's a bit longer than it needs to be (o.k. so maybe it's a LOT longer than it needs to be), but it's still a lot of fun. Grade: A-
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Frank Capra And Cary Grant Comedy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Arsenic and Old Lace is a film directed by Frank Capra based on Joseph Kesselring's play of the same title. The screenplay adaptation was by Julius J. Epstein and Philip G. Epstein.Ti features Cary Grant and Josephine Hull together with Jean Adair and Raymond Massey.The movie is about the sweet old Brewster sisters, beloved in their genteel Brooklyn neighborhood for their many charitable acts. One charity which the ladies don't advertise is their ongoing effort to permit lonely bachelors to die with smiles on their faces by serving said bachelors elderberry wine spiked with arsenic. When the sisters' drama-critic nephew Mortimer stumbles onto their secret, he is understandably put out especially since he has just married the lovely Elaine Harper. Given the homicidal tendencies of his aunts, the sinister activities of his escaped-convict older brother Jonathan and the disruptive behavior of younger brother Teddy who is convinced that he's really Theodore Roosevelt, and runs around the house yelling and Mortimer isn't keen on starting a family with his new bride. "Insanity runs in my family," he explains. "It practically gallops." Further complications ensue when the murderous Jonathan Brewster arrives home, with his sniveling accomplice Dr. Einstein in tow. When Jonathan learns that his darling aunts have killed twelve men, he is incensed and they're challenging his own record of murders. Despite the fact that picture runs almost two hours, Frank Capra has expanded on the original play to a sufficient extent to maintain a steady, consistent pace.Also,unable to conceal the film's theatrical origins, Capra misfires as a director and misguides Cary Garnt, who's too mannered, but the time, the combo of horror and comedy was new and the old ladies' gruesome hobby was shocking to audiences.But nevertheless,Capra encourages the cast, especially Grant, to give a somewhat more out-sized performance than one might expect. But made during the war years as it was, this overstated comic approach to killing was probably cathartic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Epic Performance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    k-keith
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Plays and books always seem to be better than movies to me, but this is one of the exceptions. It's comedic genius, in large part because of the overly dramatic acting. Cary Grant is quoted as disliking his acting because of this, but the movie would never have been as good without that quality of being a little too much. All of the characters are meant to be a little too much, and this creates a balance within the movie between the panicked Mortimer, the peaceful aunts and the psychotic Jonathan. I love the descriptive dialogue by both Mortimer and the police officer at the end of the movie foreshadowing what steps Jonathan will take. It is also amusing the way that Mortimer's love story is cast aside in favor of handling the aunts, Teddy and Jonathan.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Extraordinary funny masterpiece of black comedy.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    psagray
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Movie filmed in 1941 by the great Sicilian-born filmmaker, Frank Capra, is based on the play, "Arsenic and Old Lace" written by novelist and playwright German born American, Joseph Kesselring, and was not yet premiered in 1944, when it had its last performance in the Broadway stage. It is adapted to the screen by the Epstein brothers (the writers of the famed "Casablanca"), is brilliantly narrated and tone of black comedy is elegantly showing each of its excellent frames, serve as a clear inspiration for the staging and conducting post as another big movie was "the Ladykillers" 1955 by Alexander MacKendrick, eleven years later ... It has an extraordinary staging and a dazzling black and white photography by renowned Sol Polito and a soundtrack of the most suggestive by another prominent author, Max Steiner, the film is a sign, yet another, the principal of "It Happened One Night" . This film is among the best of Gary Grant, although the actor himself was not happy with his own performance due to the strong character of his character histrionic mandated by Capra, the truth is that it is essential for this action film. The performance of the brother of "Mortimer" (Gary Grant), "Jonathan" (Raymond Massey) undoubtedly contributes to the tone of black comedy that is in every frame ... maybe its majestic presence make him starring as historical emblematic and enigmatic as Abraham Lincoln's own ... along with such great performances from Peter Lorre had just filmed "Casablanca" doing this mysterious and peculiar of Dr. Einstein, and the interpretation of John Alexander doing that unforgettable role crazy guy "Teddy Brewster", believing Theodore Roosevelt's famous cry of "(Charge!)!" (Roosevelt made famous during charging San Juan Hill) upstairs and unscrewing clockwise wall ... make this movie a masterpiece to consider.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Incredibly strange but very funny
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Terrell Howell (KnightsofNi11)
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What would you do if you found out that your own dear aunts were homicidal maniacs? There's a variety of ways to deal with the situation but Cary Grant probably picks the most unorthodox and unconventional solutions in Arsenic and Old Lace, a classic Frank Capra comedy from 1944. Grant stars as Mortimer Brewster, a drama critique who, at the opening of the film, marries his girlfriend. He goes home to tell his aunts and prepare for his honeymoon to Niagra Falls. However, while at home he finds out his aunts have poisoned twelve men over the past few months and they are all buried in the cellar. This news sends Mortimer racing around trying to hide the fact that his aunts are homicidal, while also dealing with a variety of other problems as this kind of insanity runs in his family. At the same time as he is dealing with his aunts Mortimer has one brother who thinks he's Teddy Roosevelt and another a deformed serial killer who, after being gone for twenty years, decides to return home at the most inopportune time. It's a wild and bizarre ride that is chock full of innocently delightful laughs. Arsenic and Old Lace represents the Golden Age of the American comedy. Some of the most classic comedies were made during World War II in order to ease the troubled times America was involved in. Arsenic and Old Lace falls right in with these films, having been released in 1944. Therefore, it's only purpose is just to make us laugh. It aims to entertain and delight, and I would say it does just that. It's got a cavalcade of wacky and eccentric characters played by a fantastic cast of hilarious actors and actresses. The duo of Aunt Abby and Aunt Martha is one of the most hilarious on screen pairings I've ever seen and the two actresses, Josephine Hull and Jean Adair respectively, play the part so perfectly. They come off as the sweetest old ladies you could ever meet who just don't understand what all the fuss is about concerning the twelve dead bodies they have buried in their cellar. It's certainly comedy at its most intelligent. The whole point of Arsenic and Old Lace is to be incredibly weird in a very entertaining way. And that is definitely what it does. This is a very strange film with all sorts of moments that make you scratch your head in confusion and chuckle at the same time. It's an incredibly offbeat film for its time, and this adds to the humor. As far as comedy goes this isn't quite my cup of tea, but I have the utmost respect for what a quality comedy film this is. Personally my taste leans towards more modern comedy stilings, but Arsenic and Old Lace is representative of a great era of comedy and just film in general. It's a great film that shouldn't be missed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wouldn't You Be A Little Manic, If Your Two Elderly Aunts Were Murderers ?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    PamelaShort
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film version of the classic play "Arsenic And Old Lace" is absolutely superb. Every single player in this amazing comedy, all perform first rate renditions of their characters. Dear Priscilla Lane is lovely in her small role as Cary Grant's bewildered bride. Josephine Hull and Jean Adair are totally convincing as the elderly Brewster Aunts, only trying to help their lonely elderly male boarders by poisoning them. Raymond Massey plays the fiendish Cousin Jonathan to a tee, with his equally creepy sidekick Peter Lorre. Edward Everett Horton is so ideal as Mr. Witherspoon of the Happy Dale Sanitarium, coming to claim the eccentric Uncle Teddy Brewster, who believes he is President Roosevelt. Jack Carson is funny as the dense police officer O'Hara. Cary Grant is a complete riot as nephew Mortimer Brewster, who so vainly tries to resolve the predicament his kooky Aunts have placed him in. Grant never misses a beat, and his facial expressions are priceless. I believe it to be one of his most winning-est performances. Frank Capra pulls it all together into one deliriously enjoyable comedy. I never tire of watching this classic movie, a favourite of mine to start off every Halloween.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    you can't 'live' without it
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    theoneandonlyjimmypage
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ONCE UPON A TIME....it's a Sunday afternoon and it is raining...there's nothing to do...nobody's home,the ballgame isn t on until this evening....you ve finished your work and your chores,you ve showered and you set out to make an omelette-so of course you will break some eggs..and no...there isn t 'a penguin'on the tele there's 'arsenic and old lace' (on the tele-).something to do...a great old movie...and funny...still.THE FIRST TIME AND THE SECOND AND THIRD AND FOURTH AND FOURTH the second time or fifth,the thing about breaking a few eggs-its a kind of a 'mad-cap' tale-he did what/she said that/they really this/allthat another that but this....etc,etc,etc AND SXTH AND SEVENTH AND EIGHTH AND NINTH AND TENTH...WATCH 'ARSENIC AND OLD LACE'--you can t live without it!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Oh, Mortimer...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MalteseRambo
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie showcases the finest of Frank Capra and frequent collaborator Cary Grant. It has the perfect combination of genres: Hilariously funny, just the right amount of romance, and the apparent main theme of crime. The greatest part of this movie is definitely the vast array of facial expressions shown by Grant, especially the priceless look of surprise when he sees the dead man in the window seat. The wonderful supporting cast is comprised of the blonde bombshell love interest played by Priscilla Lane. The dimwitted aunts played by Josephine Hull & Jean Adair. The unhinged brother played by John Alexander. And the sinister fugitives, his brother played by Boris Karloff, I mean Raymond Massey; and his doctor played by Peter Lorre. Without question, this is one of my favourite comedies, my favourite Capra film, my favourite Grant film, and one of my favourite film released before 1950. This is definitely Frank Capra at his greatest, and it should appear a hell of a lot higher on the IMDb Top 250. This movie should already be in the National Film Registry, but unfortunately it isn't. "You  get out of here! D'ya wanna be poisoned? D'ya wanna be murdered? D'ya wanna be killed?" - Mortimer Brewster
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Excellent story collision
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Electro Bear
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Cary Grant stars in this absurd black comedy, featuring some of his most entertaining acting put to film. It also features some creative shots at points, but it's long takes respect the actors involved, and lets each scene grow at a pace taken by its actors. The writing is phenomenal, the setup for each character and their purpose drives the story forwards, and its hilarious to watch the actors enter each scene and complicate things further. The self-contained irony, the black humour, the absurdity, is all suddenly compounded towards the end, when Cary Grant himself accepts the insanity of the entire situation. It is also amazing to see a movie with such honestly dark patches, also be so family safe, a tribute to the great writing, and Frank Capra's direction. Not only is this movie hilarious, but it also has some genuinely horrifying moments. The monstrous Jonathan Brewster, played by Raymond Massey, coupled with his terrible facial scars is an honestly scary figure and has some oddly striking scenes mixed in with the all of the humour. Peter Lorre puts in a great mousy performance, and takes plenty of amusing abuse from all of the characters. Recommended viewing. Especially for fans of Cary Grant.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Nutcase Evening
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nick-leonardi
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Major theatre critic Mortimer Brewster (Cary Grant) on Halloween gets married to Elaine. He goes back to his two aunts' house to tell the good news. Mortimer later that day discovers accidentally a dead body in the window seat of his aunts' house, and the old aunts admit that they are the cause, as they have made killing old, lonely men their secret business. Things get more complicated when Mortimer's long gone brother Jonathan returns home unexpectedly after decades, with also a dead body with him. Almost universally hailed as a Black Comedy classic, this adaptation of the play of the same name contains numerous memorable characters, situations and dialogue, the main ingredients of a typical American classic. Its non-stop frenzy is highlighted by the fact that most of the film is set in the living room of the house, so that there is not only a much greater focus on the various storyline twist and turns, but also so that it feels much more like the original play itself. One of Frank Capra's most famous and successful works.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Is That a Body in Your Window Seat or Are You Just Happy to See Me?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brocksilvey
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Cary Grant works his tail off in this morbid comedy with an unusually high body count. Grant brings his brand-new wife (a perky Priscilla Lane) home to meet his two spinster aunts -- only to make the grisly discovery that his aunts have been murdering lonely male boarders and burying them in the basement. If this weren't stressful enough, Grant's sociopathic brother (played humorously by Raymond Massey) shows up with a body of his own to get rid of. What's a man to do? Frank Capra does a pretty good job of blending the screwball with the macabre, and nearly every joke and bit of physical comedy falls to Grant, who breezes through the whole movie with aplomb. It's a bit longer than it needs to be (o.k. so maybe it's a LOT longer than it needs to be), but it's still a lot of fun. Grade: A-
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Frank Capra And Cary Grant Comedy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Arsenic and Old Lace is a film directed by Frank Capra based on Joseph Kesselring's play of the same title. The screenplay adaptation was by Julius J. Epstein and Philip G. Epstein.Ti features Cary Grant and Josephine Hull together with Jean Adair and Raymond Massey.The movie is about the sweet old Brewster sisters, beloved in their genteel Brooklyn neighborhood for their many charitable acts. One charity which the ladies don't advertise is their ongoing effort to permit lonely bachelors to die with smiles on their faces by serving said bachelors elderberry wine spiked with arsenic. When the sisters' drama-critic nephew Mortimer stumbles onto their secret, he is understandably put out especially since he has just married the lovely Elaine Harper. Given the homicidal tendencies of his aunts, the sinister activities of his escaped-convict older brother Jonathan and the disruptive behavior of younger brother Teddy who is convinced that he's really Theodore Roosevelt, and runs around the house yelling and Mortimer isn't keen on starting a family with his new bride. "Insanity runs in my family," he explains. "It practically gallops." Further complications ensue when the murderous Jonathan Brewster arrives home, with his sniveling accomplice Dr. Einstein in tow. When Jonathan learns that his darling aunts have killed twelve men, he is incensed and they're challenging his own record of murders. Despite the fact that picture runs almost two hours, Frank Capra has expanded on the original play to a sufficient extent to maintain a steady, consistent pace.Also,unable to conceal the film's theatrical origins, Capra misfires as a director and misguides Cary Garnt, who's too mannered, but the time, the combo of horror and comedy was new and the old ladies' gruesome hobby was shocking to audiences.But nevertheless,Capra encourages the cast, especially Grant, to give a somewhat more out-sized performance than one might expect. But made during the war years as it was, this overstated comic approach to killing was probably cathartic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Epic Performance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    k-keith
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Plays and books always seem to be better than movies to me, but this is one of the exceptions. It's comedic genius, in large part because of the overly dramatic acting. Cary Grant is quoted as disliking his acting because of this, but the movie would never have been as good without that quality of being a little too much. All of the characters are meant to be a little too much, and this creates a balance within the movie between the panicked Mortimer, the peaceful aunts and the psychotic Jonathan. I love the descriptive dialogue by both Mortimer and the police officer at the end of the movie foreshadowing what steps Jonathan will take. It is also amusing the way that Mortimer's love story is cast aside in favor of handling the aunts, Teddy and Jonathan.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Extraordinary funny masterpiece of black comedy.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    psagray
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Movie filmed in 1941 by the great Sicilian-born filmmaker, Frank Capra, is based on the play, "Arsenic and Old Lace" written by novelist and playwright German born American, Joseph Kesselring, and was not yet premiered in 1944, when it had its last performance in the Broadway stage. It is adapted to the screen by the Epstein brothers (the writers of the famed "Casablanca"), is brilliantly narrated and tone of black comedy is elegantly showing each of its excellent frames, serve as a clear inspiration for the staging and conducting post as another big movie was "the Ladykillers" 1955 by Alexander MacKendrick, eleven years later ... It has an extraordinary staging and a dazzling black and white photography by renowned Sol Polito and a soundtrack of the most suggestive by another prominent author, Max Steiner, the film is a sign, yet another, the principal of "It Happened One Night" . This film is among the best of Gary Grant, although the actor himself was not happy with his own performance due to the strong character of his character histrionic mandated by Capra, the truth is that it is essential for this action film. The performance of the brother of "Mortimer" (Gary Grant), "Jonathan" (Raymond Massey) undoubtedly contributes to the tone of black comedy that is in every frame ... maybe its majestic presence make him starring as historical emblematic and enigmatic as Abraham Lincoln's own ... along with such great performances from Peter Lorre had just filmed "Casablanca" doing this mysterious and peculiar of Dr. Einstein, and the interpretation of John Alexander doing that unforgettable role crazy guy "Teddy Brewster", believing Theodore Roosevelt's famous cry of "(Charge!)!" (Roosevelt made famous during charging San Juan Hill) upstairs and unscrewing clockwise wall ... make this movie a masterpiece to consider.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Incredibly strange but very funny
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Terrell Howell (KnightsofNi11)
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What would you do if you found out that your own dear aunts were homicidal maniacs? There's a variety of ways to deal with the situation but Cary Grant probably picks the most unorthodox and unconventional solutions in Arsenic and Old Lace, a classic Frank Capra comedy from 1944. Grant stars as Mortimer Brewster, a drama critique who, at the opening of the film, marries his girlfriend. He goes home to tell his aunts and prepare for his honeymoon to Niagra Falls. However, while at home he finds out his aunts have poisoned twelve men over the past few months and they are all buried in the cellar. This news sends Mortimer racing around trying to hide the fact that his aunts are homicidal, while also dealing with a variety of other problems as this kind of insanity runs in his family. At the same time as he is dealing with his aunts Mortimer has one brother who thinks he's Teddy Roosevelt and another a deformed serial killer who, after being gone for twenty years, decides to return home at the most inopportune time. It's a wild and bizarre ride that is chock full of innocently delightful laughs. Arsenic and Old Lace represents the Golden Age of the American comedy. Some of the most classic comedies were made during World War II in order to ease the troubled times America was involved in. Arsenic and Old Lace falls right in with these films, having been released in 1944. Therefore, it's only purpose is just to make us laugh. It aims to entertain and delight, and I would say it does just that. It's got a cavalcade of wacky and eccentric characters played by a fantastic cast of hilarious actors and actresses. The duo of Aunt Abby and Aunt Martha is one of the most hilarious on screen pairings I've ever seen and the two actresses, Josephine Hull and Jean Adair respectively, play the part so perfectly. They come off as the sweetest old ladies you could ever meet who just don't understand what all the fuss is about concerning the twelve dead bodies they have buried in their cellar. It's certainly comedy at its most intelligent. The whole point of Arsenic and Old Lace is to be incredibly weird in a very entertaining way. And that is definitely what it does. This is a very strange film with all sorts of moments that make you scratch your head in confusion and chuckle at the same time. It's an incredibly offbeat film for its time, and this adds to the humor. As far as comedy goes this isn't quite my cup of tea, but I have the utmost respect for what a quality comedy film this is. Personally my taste leans towards more modern comedy stilings, but Arsenic and Old Lace is representative of a great era of comedy and just film in general. It's a great film that shouldn't be missed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
