<filme>
 <id>
  660
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0101921
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1991
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Tomates Verdes Fritos
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  7.4
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  A housewife who is unhappy with her life befriends an old lady in a nursing home and is enthralled by the tales she tells of people she used to know.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Evelyn Couch is having trouble in her marriage, and no one seems to take her seriously. While in a nursing home visiting relatives, she meets Ninny Threadgoode, an outgoing old woman, who tells her the story of Idgie Threadgoode, a young woman in 1920's Alabama. Through Idgie's inspiring life, Evelyn learns to be more assertive and builds a lasting friendship of her own with Ninny.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   nursing home
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   1920s
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   stories
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   friendship
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   alabama
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Jon Avnet
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Fannie Flagg
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Carol Sobieski
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Kathy Bates
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Jessica Tandy
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Mary Stuart Masterson
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Story of friendship
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SnoopyStyle
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is based on a novel that takes place in Alabama. The modern story has timid housewife Evelyn Couch (Kathy Bates) who befriends an old woman Ninny Threadgoode (Jessica Tandy) at a retirement home. She recounts an old story from depression era. She tells the story of Idgie Threadgoode (Mary Stuart Masterson) and her friendship with Ruth Jamison (Mary-Louise Parker). Their lives are forever linked by the death of Idgie's brother who was Ruth's boyfriend. The modern story doesn't have quite the punch. The old time story exceeds it in almost every way. It may have been an important part of the novel, but I don't know if the modern story necessarily added anything to the movie. Both Marys are outstanding in their roles. Their characters are truly the center of this movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very very good writing,Wonderful movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Wadejohnson1970
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As a young man growing up in the Country of my home town of Hawkinsville Pulaski County Georgia, I had saw the movie in rental stores, however I was just never quite interested in watching a movie called Fried Green Tomatoes!!! However one night while watching TV with my family I was flicking through the Chanel's and came upon this very net resting movie that just so,happens to be..yes you guessed it...Fried Green Tomatoes!!! Well right here in the middle of my review I get a knock on my door, some guy tells me that he had just hit a little black dog out in front of my home, we live on a dirt road and people drive on it as if it were a damn Interstate Highway!!!! Sure enough it is my late fathers dog Buster!!! One of the last things my Daddy said was son look out for my dog!!! Now I feel really bad!!! He is not dead yet, he has his wits about him, just a bit loopy, but catching one of those full size Chevy Silverado's ain't good for a 4 pound dog!!! Anyway please pray for Buster!!!! Now back to the Movie review... As I began to watch this movie I just got more and more intertwined into the story!!! I couldn't tell who was more intrigued by Iggies story, me or Evelyne Couch. The story about Frank Bennett was so interesting!!! Heck there wasn't anything about the entire movie that Wasn't interesting!!!! The most interesting part of the entire movie was the fact that Frank Bennett's body was never found!!! And even more the reason WHY IT EAS NEVER FOUND!!!! Big George Put him on the grill and made BBQ out of him and they fed him to the guy from Georgia that was so stern to Iggies that he WAS THE LAW!!!! And you can't beat the law!!!! So to sum it up in a few words!!!! Fried Green Tomatoes is by far one of the best movies I ever saw, most important I. Was working with Georgia Power and happened upon this little Cafe out in Julliett Ga. And before I knew it I was sitting right in the middle of where one of my favorite movies was made..The Whistle Stop Cafe!!!!! You can't imagine my excitement and couldn't wait to tell my wife that I had sat and eat right there where the story played out!!! Now I'm gonna take my wife there to have some of those world famous FRIED GREEN TOMATOES!!!! And if you never watched this MASTERPIECE PLEASE DO!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Secret's in the Sauce
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    C_Hardrick
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Oscar winner Kathy Bates stars as Evelyn Couch, who one day while visiting her husbands ailing aunt in a nursing home, stumbles onto Mrs. Threadgoode, a resident of the same nursing home, played by Oscar winner Jessica Tandy. As Mrs. Threadgoode tells her story to Evelyn, we learn a vivid story of a young charismatic girl named Idgie spanning the years before World War One through the Depression. The film is set in the Deep South. Alabama to be exact in a small town called Whistle Stop. The film also stars a young Chris O'Donnell as Buddy Threadgoode, Idgie's brother. When Buddy is tragically killed in front of her eyes, Idgie sets out on a life to live to the fullest, even against her mother's wishes and the town preacher's wishes as well. As she grows, so does her relationship with family friend Ruth Jamison, played by Mary-Louise Parker. Eventually they become an inseparable duo, until Ruth marries Frank Bennett, played by Nick Searcy. Frank Bennett ends up being the plot point of the second half of Mrs. Threadgoode's story, and how Idgie may have or may not have killed him. We may not know what happened to Frank, however, "the secrets in the sauce."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brilliant sweet modern classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    misskellyvalente
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film was at times hysterical and at other times tugged at your heart strings. The film was based on a book. The film looked great and was well written and had wonderful actors portraying some great characters that you could really get attached to. I was a little disappointed that the film watered down the relationship of the two female characters. I realize that it would have never made it to main-stream America if the filmmakers hadn't. It was still very clear that there is a relationship in the film if you are paying attention for the simple little clues. Mary Stuart Masterson and Mary-Louise Parker did an amazing job capturing the chemistry between these two female characters. It's always amazing to watch Jessica Tandy act as she brings such heart to any character she portrays. Kathy Bates plays Evelyn and makes her so truthful and funny. The film is marketed as a feel good film and it does contain those moments, but it leans more toward drama side than the comedy side. Don't let anything stop you from watching this brilliant sweet modern classic. You'll be glad you did.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An authentic classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    robert-temple-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have just seen this wonderful film for the third time, after many years, and it is such a classic, and has not lost any of its interest or appeal. Indeed, it is more relevant now than it ever was, considering that it is about the plight of women and how they cope with their various life situations. It is based on a novel, and has a screenplay by, Fannie Flagg. It is set in Alabama where she comes from, and the story presumably has some basis in truth. Not many people know that Fannie Flagg used to be a brilliant comedienne. I knew her in the mid 1960s when she was a stand-up comic, and she was hilarious. She used to perform at a marvellous comedy cabaret night club in Manhattan, now long gone, which had two floors. The upstairs was called Upstairs at the Downstairs, and the downstairs was called Downstairs at the Upstairs. It was at 37 West 56th Street and was run by an amusing and eccentric woman whose name I have forgotten, alas. Fannie played there at the same time as Madeline ('Maddy') Kahn, who was also wildly funny. Fannie told me she had wanted to perform under her own real name of Patricia Neal, but was told by her agent or manager, I believe, that she could not do that because there was a famous film actress of that name already, so she invented the name Fannie Flagg for herself. It was only years later that she wrote this marvellous heart-felt novel, which was rejected by many publishers, but which finally came out and then resulted in this film. And it is this which really made Fannie Flag famous. The film was shot in Georgia, which is next door to Alabama. But the story is mostly set in Alabama in a little town called Whistle Stop. That name arose because it was a settlement situated beside the railroad. Many small Southern towns fell into desuetude (i.e. withered away) when the railroads started collapsing, after the construction of the interstate highway system, which shifted so much travel and freight transport onto roads and destroyed the rail industry, from the 1950s onwards. In this film which takes place at two different times, during the pre-War period which constitutes the earlier story, the two young women, Idgie and Ruth, open a railside caf&eacute; called The Whistle Stop Caf&eacute;. In those years, it thrived and became the heart of the town, where everyone went to eat real home cooking, which included the favourite local delicacy, fried green tomatoes, which were sliced and fried in batter in what in the South is called a skillet, which is an old 17th century English word for a frying pan, the word surviving only in the American South and nowhere else. (I still fry my eggs and bacon in an old iron family skillet which was cast in the family forge at Taunton, Massachusetts, in the 17th or 18th century. We have been using that skillet for many generations. Just imagine how many bacon fat molecules survive in the crystalline interstices of the cast iron after those centuries of use every morning. The outside of the skillet looks like something dug up by an archaeologist, but the inside is shiny and ready for anything. But this question arises: can bacon fat go rancid after a century or two? It does seem to improve the flavour anyway. However, I am ashamed to say that I have never fried any green tomatoes, which is doubtless a great personal failing of mine. The skillet has thus been deprived of what Ruth and Idgie would perhaps consider to be its main function, to deal with those green tomatoes.) Idgie, who is a hopeless cook, cannot prepare them, so Ruth has to do it. Throughout the film people keep tasting them to see if they are up to standard. The modern story of the film consists of tales told by an old lady in a retirement home to a much younger woman, and the effect this has on transforming her life. That younger woman is played by Kathy Bates, whose performance is breathtaking in its sensitivity and brilliance. But then, Kathy Bates has always been one of everybody's favourite and most endearing actresses, and we all know what a genius she is. The old woman is played equally brilliantly by the famous Jessica Tandy, veteran of a lifetime of superlative achievements in both stage and screen. Before TV wiped all the brains of the public as clean as a virgin hard disc, people used to tell stories, and there was such a thing as verbal communication. (And people didn't even have to use their thumbs to communicate, like today's simian-thumbed and simian-brained text messagers.) This film is all about the power of stories to stir the imagination and transform lives. Even as late as the 1960s, some old women still survived in the South who could tell stories for hours on end. They are all gone now, and it is like what happened after the time of Homer, when the last of the bards died. The best rendering in fiction of the 'power of stories' is probably the novella by Mircea Eliade entitled THE OLD MAN AND THE BUREAUCRATS. (Eliade wrote the story of Coppola's film YOUTH WITHOUT YOUTH, 2007, though that film was very disappointing and a poor adaptation.) The stories told by Jessica Tandy are about Idgie and Ruth. In those lengthy flashback sequences, the two young women are brilliantly portrayed by the two Mary's, Mary Stuart Masterson, and Mary-Louise Parker. Certainly this is one of the greatest 'sisterhood' films ever made. Their story is full of love, pain, pathos, loss, tragedy, and joy. Not unlike life. If you can see this without shedding a tear, then there is no hope for you. Good old Fannie, may she long keep flying her Flagg.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cannibalism And Gendercidal Hatred
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Louis B Maybe
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    OK, so here's why this film is the opposite of everything you've ever been told it is: It's not a wonderful feel-good movie for the girls, it's an ugly, violent fantasy in which justice is confused with revenge. Let's break it down: There are no primary male characters in this movie. Of the secondary and tertiary ones, it could be said that all the (white) males are evil or inadequate. Buddy is good, of course, but inadequate. His own foolishness destroys him. Buddy Junior is equally good but equally inadequate. Frank, on the other hand is just plain evil, and in between are more ambiguous male characters. The police chief is willing to help Idgie, it's true, but only because of his lecherous interest in her, and his mentality is thoroughly racist. Of the male characters, only Big George is unambiguously both good and adequate. But Big George is a black man. And black men are oppressed men. In effect, they are not men at all: exempt on political grounds from the critique levelled at white men, they are honorary women. This movie, couched in soft colours and sweet music, is one of the most casually misandric movies ever made. First of all, & most obviously, there is the EATING of her Evelyn's murdered husband. But it happens throughout the movie, as well, such as when Evelyn tells Frank "if I was going to kill you, I'd use my fists". She fantasizes about putting bombs in copies of Playboy and Hustler. "I'll take all the wife-beaters," she says, "and I'll machine gun their genitals!" "You didn't kill Ed, did you?" asks Ninny when Evelyn turns up late. "Not yet," answers Evelyn with a smile. The problem here is not that women will leave theatres and go on killing sprees. The problem is simply the convincing presentation of a cinematic world in which only women have a 'right' to be angry, in which all women are victims, & all men - all white men,anyway - are evil oppressors or inadequate burdens. To the extent that both women and men consciously or subconsciously adopt this worldview, the mutual hostility that now characterizes relations between the sexes will be exacerbated instead of questioned or healed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Interesting But Not Overpowering
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sddavis63 (revsdd@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watching the progression of the relationship between Idgie (Mary Stuart Masterson) and Ruth (Mary-Louise Parker) is fairly interesting. The story is a flashback; a story related by Ninny Threadgoode (Jessica Tandy) to Evelyn (Kathy Bates) who befriends Ninny in a local nursing home. So right off the top you can see that there's a pretty decent cast. Also almost from the start you realize that Ninny is a bit of an enigmatic character. Is she or is she not Idgie relating her own story? The movie seems to lead in that direction but never actually makes it explicit, so in the end it's left to the viewer to decide. Basically, this ends up as a murder mystery from the past. Ruth's abusive husband is murdered, and the question is who killed him. Idgie is put on trial for the crime, but the charges are dismissed. The mystery is held pretty well until the end of the movie. The movie begins with Idgie as a child, and with Ruth as her older brother Buddy's love interest. After Buddy's tragic death, Idgie and Ruth develop a very close friendship - the movie bobs and weaves around the issue of what the nature of their relationship was. Was it just a close friendship? Was it more? My feeling from the movie is that Idgie wanted more than a friendship; Ruth's interests were less clear. I haven't read the book, but I understand that the novel is quite clear in making the point that there was a lesbian romance between the two. Perhaps Hollywood in 1991 was still too nervous about such an issue to make it front and centre; ambiguity was as much as the studios could stomach apparently. We follow both of them through the ups and downs of life as they open a cafe together, whose menu specialty is - you guessed it - fried green tomatoes. Kathy Bates provided some comedy to the movie as the modern day housewife who goes through a rebirth after meeting Ninny - a rebirth that totally confuses her husband Ed (Gailard Sartain), who doesn't have a clue why Evelyn is changing so much and upsetting their comfortable existence. While she provided comedy, I wasn't really taken in by Bates' character in this. I thought the constant switching between present and past was overdone and not particularly well done to be honest; in a lot of ways the two parts of the stories didn't mesh that well. Aside from Bates, there were a lot of very likable characters from the past, such as Big George (Stan Shaw) and Smokey Lonesome (Timothy Scott.) The identity of Ruth's husband's killer in the end took me by surprise, so that was well done. My final reaction to this was that it was a basically well made and well acted movie, and at times even an interesting movie as the story unfolded - but that it also seemed like a movie that was anything but overpowering. It didn't leave me awestruck. (5/10)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fantastic Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lencad
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I think I have seen the movie at least 5 or more times. I love it. You see something each time you watch it that you missed the first time. My friend and I also went to the Whistle Cafe Stop Cafe in Juliette, Ga and had lunch. It was terrific. We had Peach Cobbler for desert and we could have gone back for more. I bought candy and soap in the Honeycomb Store and today I ordered some more. The soap is so nice you can smell it all over my house. The candy is awesome. Take time to see the movie. Be sure to visit the Whistle Stop Cafe in Juliette, Ga and to also stop in at the Honeycomb and what ever other stores are open. I love places like this that are still there for others to see. It makes the movie seem even more real.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This film is what movies should be about...!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vonschweissguth
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have viewed this marvelous film at least 2 dozen times. As with all great movies, you will always catch something "new" with each watching. If you want to be charmed, enchanted, moved, and find yourself wishing.... This is a film you will cherish. I won't belabor more than others have written so well. It is a film that resides in my permanent library on my top shelf. When I watch it again, I find myself wishing that I knew the characters personally and somehow find that I do. This film is one of the only that I esteem. It adds to your life. It hugs the heart and enriches who you are. I want to thank all the marvelous actors. If they ever wondered why they chose their profession, this film is why. 200 years from now it will be loved and valued. The test of time is guaranteed with Fried Green Tomatoes!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Overly Sentimental FIlm
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Supachewy
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/9/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The drama Fried Green Tomatoes is directed by Jon Avnet and stars Kathy Bates, Jessica Tandy, Mary Stuart Masterson, and Mary-Luise Parker. The film takes place in modern day Alabama with flashbacks from 1920 Alabama. The film starts off with a little girl in 1920s Alabama named Idgie Threadgood who does not want to be a part of her sister's wedding. After being talked to by her older brother she agrees to go to it and then afterward the two of them plus the girl the brother likes, Ruth (Parker) go on a walk around the area. When Ruth's hat flies off Idgie's brother goes and gets it for her but his foot ends up stuck in a train track and he is tragically killed. Idgie is extremely disturbed by her brother's death and is never the same again. This is all told from her sister Ninny Threadgood (Tandy) to Evelyn Couch (Bates). Couch is a middle aged woman who does not believe that she has any power or purpose and she met Ninny in a nursing home while visiting her husband's aunt. As the film goes on it develops the relationship between Idgie and Ruth and also Ninny and Evelyn and it is very sentimental... The script was written by Fannie Flagg who also wrote the book which the film is based on. Personally I thought the writing was weak for one main reason. That reason is that the film bounced between two different stories. The story with Idgie and Ruth was quite interesting but the story with Evelyn and Ninny was a complete bore that lacked depth. It was basically Evelyn just saying I have no purpose and then becoming a crazy woman that just tears apart her home and it is all supposedly because of Ninny's story. It is just not believable. It would have been better if it was more like Ninny just telling the story to Evelyn and Evelyn not having a story of her own. The first feature film for the big screen of Jon Avnet proved that he is a decent director. Avnet got solid performances by all his leads which is hard to do in a cast with four leads. The shots in the film were not really impressive and he did not really make me care much for any of the characters. I would have said that he did a poor job if he did not get the performances that he did, but then again it was only his first film even though he has not proved to be much of a director today in any way. The acting in this film was the best part of it. All four of the leads gave great performances. Even Kathy Bates, whose character I thought to be the weakest written still was able to bring a great performance out of it. Yet she is one of the greatest actresses who ever lived. Jessica Tandy even earned an Oscar nomination for her performance just because she was so great being an eccentric old lady. Parker and Masterson are sort of newcomers to the lead position and they really pulled it off as well. The acting made this film bearable. Overall I give this film a 5/10, I would have gave lower if it was not for the strong performances. I would recommend this to anyone who likes period pieces or films with strong female leads.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Story of friendship
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SnoopyStyle
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is based on a novel that takes place in Alabama. The modern story has timid housewife Evelyn Couch (Kathy Bates) who befriends an old woman Ninny Threadgoode (Jessica Tandy) at a retirement home. She recounts an old story from depression era. She tells the story of Idgie Threadgoode (Mary Stuart Masterson) and her friendship with Ruth Jamison (Mary-Louise Parker). Their lives are forever linked by the death of Idgie's brother who was Ruth's boyfriend. The modern story doesn't have quite the punch. The old time story exceeds it in almost every way. It may have been an important part of the novel, but I don't know if the modern story necessarily added anything to the movie. Both Marys are outstanding in their roles. Their characters are truly the center of this movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very very good writing,Wonderful movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Wadejohnson1970
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As a young man growing up in the Country of my home town of Hawkinsville Pulaski County Georgia, I had saw the movie in rental stores, however I was just never quite interested in watching a movie called Fried Green Tomatoes!!! However one night while watching TV with my family I was flicking through the Chanel's and came upon this very net resting movie that just so,happens to be..yes you guessed it...Fried Green Tomatoes!!! Well right here in the middle of my review I get a knock on my door, some guy tells me that he had just hit a little black dog out in front of my home, we live on a dirt road and people drive on it as if it were a damn Interstate Highway!!!! Sure enough it is my late fathers dog Buster!!! One of the last things my Daddy said was son look out for my dog!!! Now I feel really bad!!! He is not dead yet, he has his wits about him, just a bit loopy, but catching one of those full size Chevy Silverado's ain't good for a 4 pound dog!!! Anyway please pray for Buster!!!! Now back to the Movie review... As I began to watch this movie I just got more and more intertwined into the story!!! I couldn't tell who was more intrigued by Iggies story, me or Evelyne Couch. The story about Frank Bennett was so interesting!!! Heck there wasn't anything about the entire movie that Wasn't interesting!!!! The most interesting part of the entire movie was the fact that Frank Bennett's body was never found!!! And even more the reason WHY IT EAS NEVER FOUND!!!! Big George Put him on the grill and made BBQ out of him and they fed him to the guy from Georgia that was so stern to Iggies that he WAS THE LAW!!!! And you can't beat the law!!!! So to sum it up in a few words!!!! Fried Green Tomatoes is by far one of the best movies I ever saw, most important I. Was working with Georgia Power and happened upon this little Cafe out in Julliett Ga. And before I knew it I was sitting right in the middle of where one of my favorite movies was made..The Whistle Stop Cafe!!!!! You can't imagine my excitement and couldn't wait to tell my wife that I had sat and eat right there where the story played out!!! Now I'm gonna take my wife there to have some of those world famous FRIED GREEN TOMATOES!!!! And if you never watched this MASTERPIECE PLEASE DO!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Secret's in the Sauce
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    C_Hardrick
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Oscar winner Kathy Bates stars as Evelyn Couch, who one day while visiting her husbands ailing aunt in a nursing home, stumbles onto Mrs. Threadgoode, a resident of the same nursing home, played by Oscar winner Jessica Tandy. As Mrs. Threadgoode tells her story to Evelyn, we learn a vivid story of a young charismatic girl named Idgie spanning the years before World War One through the Depression. The film is set in the Deep South. Alabama to be exact in a small town called Whistle Stop. The film also stars a young Chris O'Donnell as Buddy Threadgoode, Idgie's brother. When Buddy is tragically killed in front of her eyes, Idgie sets out on a life to live to the fullest, even against her mother's wishes and the town preacher's wishes as well. As she grows, so does her relationship with family friend Ruth Jamison, played by Mary-Louise Parker. Eventually they become an inseparable duo, until Ruth marries Frank Bennett, played by Nick Searcy. Frank Bennett ends up being the plot point of the second half of Mrs. Threadgoode's story, and how Idgie may have or may not have killed him. We may not know what happened to Frank, however, "the secrets in the sauce."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brilliant sweet modern classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    misskellyvalente
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film was at times hysterical and at other times tugged at your heart strings. The film was based on a book. The film looked great and was well written and had wonderful actors portraying some great characters that you could really get attached to. I was a little disappointed that the film watered down the relationship of the two female characters. I realize that it would have never made it to main-stream America if the filmmakers hadn't. It was still very clear that there is a relationship in the film if you are paying attention for the simple little clues. Mary Stuart Masterson and Mary-Louise Parker did an amazing job capturing the chemistry between these two female characters. It's always amazing to watch Jessica Tandy act as she brings such heart to any character she portrays. Kathy Bates plays Evelyn and makes her so truthful and funny. The film is marketed as a feel good film and it does contain those moments, but it leans more toward drama side than the comedy side. Don't let anything stop you from watching this brilliant sweet modern classic. You'll be glad you did.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An authentic classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    robert-temple-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have just seen this wonderful film for the third time, after many years, and it is such a classic, and has not lost any of its interest or appeal. Indeed, it is more relevant now than it ever was, considering that it is about the plight of women and how they cope with their various life situations. It is based on a novel, and has a screenplay by, Fannie Flagg. It is set in Alabama where she comes from, and the story presumably has some basis in truth. Not many people know that Fannie Flagg used to be a brilliant comedienne. I knew her in the mid 1960s when she was a stand-up comic, and she was hilarious. She used to perform at a marvellous comedy cabaret night club in Manhattan, now long gone, which had two floors. The upstairs was called Upstairs at the Downstairs, and the downstairs was called Downstairs at the Upstairs. It was at 37 West 56th Street and was run by an amusing and eccentric woman whose name I have forgotten, alas. Fannie played there at the same time as Madeline ('Maddy') Kahn, who was also wildly funny. Fannie told me she had wanted to perform under her own real name of Patricia Neal, but was told by her agent or manager, I believe, that she could not do that because there was a famous film actress of that name already, so she invented the name Fannie Flagg for herself. It was only years later that she wrote this marvellous heart-felt novel, which was rejected by many publishers, but which finally came out and then resulted in this film. And it is this which really made Fannie Flag famous. The film was shot in Georgia, which is next door to Alabama. But the story is mostly set in Alabama in a little town called Whistle Stop. That name arose because it was a settlement situated beside the railroad. Many small Southern towns fell into desuetude (i.e. withered away) when the railroads started collapsing, after the construction of the interstate highway system, which shifted so much travel and freight transport onto roads and destroyed the rail industry, from the 1950s onwards. In this film which takes place at two different times, during the pre-War period which constitutes the earlier story, the two young women, Idgie and Ruth, open a railside caf&eacute; called The Whistle Stop Caf&eacute;. In those years, it thrived and became the heart of the town, where everyone went to eat real home cooking, which included the favourite local delicacy, fried green tomatoes, which were sliced and fried in batter in what in the South is called a skillet, which is an old 17th century English word for a frying pan, the word surviving only in the American South and nowhere else. (I still fry my eggs and bacon in an old iron family skillet which was cast in the family forge at Taunton, Massachusetts, in the 17th or 18th century. We have been using that skillet for many generations. Just imagine how many bacon fat molecules survive in the crystalline interstices of the cast iron after those centuries of use every morning. The outside of the skillet looks like something dug up by an archaeologist, but the inside is shiny and ready for anything. But this question arises: can bacon fat go rancid after a century or two? It does seem to improve the flavour anyway. However, I am ashamed to say that I have never fried any green tomatoes, which is doubtless a great personal failing of mine. The skillet has thus been deprived of what Ruth and Idgie would perhaps consider to be its main function, to deal with those green tomatoes.) Idgie, who is a hopeless cook, cannot prepare them, so Ruth has to do it. Throughout the film people keep tasting them to see if they are up to standard. The modern story of the film consists of tales told by an old lady in a retirement home to a much younger woman, and the effect this has on transforming her life. That younger woman is played by Kathy Bates, whose performance is breathtaking in its sensitivity and brilliance. But then, Kathy Bates has always been one of everybody's favourite and most endearing actresses, and we all know what a genius she is. The old woman is played equally brilliantly by the famous Jessica Tandy, veteran of a lifetime of superlative achievements in both stage and screen. Before TV wiped all the brains of the public as clean as a virgin hard disc, people used to tell stories, and there was such a thing as verbal communication. (And people didn't even have to use their thumbs to communicate, like today's simian-thumbed and simian-brained text messagers.) This film is all about the power of stories to stir the imagination and transform lives. Even as late as the 1960s, some old women still survived in the South who could tell stories for hours on end. They are all gone now, and it is like what happened after the time of Homer, when the last of the bards died. The best rendering in fiction of the 'power of stories' is probably the novella by Mircea Eliade entitled THE OLD MAN AND THE BUREAUCRATS. (Eliade wrote the story of Coppola's film YOUTH WITHOUT YOUTH, 2007, though that film was very disappointing and a poor adaptation.) The stories told by Jessica Tandy are about Idgie and Ruth. In those lengthy flashback sequences, the two young women are brilliantly portrayed by the two Mary's, Mary Stuart Masterson, and Mary-Louise Parker. Certainly this is one of the greatest 'sisterhood' films ever made. Their story is full of love, pain, pathos, loss, tragedy, and joy. Not unlike life. If you can see this without shedding a tear, then there is no hope for you. Good old Fannie, may she long keep flying her Flagg.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cannibalism And Gendercidal Hatred
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Louis B Maybe
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    OK, so here's why this film is the opposite of everything you've ever been told it is: It's not a wonderful feel-good movie for the girls, it's an ugly, violent fantasy in which justice is confused with revenge. Let's break it down: There are no primary male characters in this movie. Of the secondary and tertiary ones, it could be said that all the (white) males are evil or inadequate. Buddy is good, of course, but inadequate. His own foolishness destroys him. Buddy Junior is equally good but equally inadequate. Frank, on the other hand is just plain evil, and in between are more ambiguous male characters. The police chief is willing to help Idgie, it's true, but only because of his lecherous interest in her, and his mentality is thoroughly racist. Of the male characters, only Big George is unambiguously both good and adequate. But Big George is a black man. And black men are oppressed men. In effect, they are not men at all: exempt on political grounds from the critique levelled at white men, they are honorary women. This movie, couched in soft colours and sweet music, is one of the most casually misandric movies ever made. First of all, & most obviously, there is the EATING of her Evelyn's murdered husband. But it happens throughout the movie, as well, such as when Evelyn tells Frank "if I was going to kill you, I'd use my fists". She fantasizes about putting bombs in copies of Playboy and Hustler. "I'll take all the wife-beaters," she says, "and I'll machine gun their genitals!" "You didn't kill Ed, did you?" asks Ninny when Evelyn turns up late. "Not yet," answers Evelyn with a smile. The problem here is not that women will leave theatres and go on killing sprees. The problem is simply the convincing presentation of a cinematic world in which only women have a 'right' to be angry, in which all women are victims, & all men - all white men,anyway - are evil oppressors or inadequate burdens. To the extent that both women and men consciously or subconsciously adopt this worldview, the mutual hostility that now characterizes relations between the sexes will be exacerbated instead of questioned or healed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Interesting But Not Overpowering
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sddavis63 (revsdd@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watching the progression of the relationship between Idgie (Mary Stuart Masterson) and Ruth (Mary-Louise Parker) is fairly interesting. The story is a flashback; a story related by Ninny Threadgoode (Jessica Tandy) to Evelyn (Kathy Bates) who befriends Ninny in a local nursing home. So right off the top you can see that there's a pretty decent cast. Also almost from the start you realize that Ninny is a bit of an enigmatic character. Is she or is she not Idgie relating her own story? The movie seems to lead in that direction but never actually makes it explicit, so in the end it's left to the viewer to decide. Basically, this ends up as a murder mystery from the past. Ruth's abusive husband is murdered, and the question is who killed him. Idgie is put on trial for the crime, but the charges are dismissed. The mystery is held pretty well until the end of the movie. The movie begins with Idgie as a child, and with Ruth as her older brother Buddy's love interest. After Buddy's tragic death, Idgie and Ruth develop a very close friendship - the movie bobs and weaves around the issue of what the nature of their relationship was. Was it just a close friendship? Was it more? My feeling from the movie is that Idgie wanted more than a friendship; Ruth's interests were less clear. I haven't read the book, but I understand that the novel is quite clear in making the point that there was a lesbian romance between the two. Perhaps Hollywood in 1991 was still too nervous about such an issue to make it front and centre; ambiguity was as much as the studios could stomach apparently. We follow both of them through the ups and downs of life as they open a cafe together, whose menu specialty is - you guessed it - fried green tomatoes. Kathy Bates provided some comedy to the movie as the modern day housewife who goes through a rebirth after meeting Ninny - a rebirth that totally confuses her husband Ed (Gailard Sartain), who doesn't have a clue why Evelyn is changing so much and upsetting their comfortable existence. While she provided comedy, I wasn't really taken in by Bates' character in this. I thought the constant switching between present and past was overdone and not particularly well done to be honest; in a lot of ways the two parts of the stories didn't mesh that well. Aside from Bates, there were a lot of very likable characters from the past, such as Big George (Stan Shaw) and Smokey Lonesome (Timothy Scott.) The identity of Ruth's husband's killer in the end took me by surprise, so that was well done. My final reaction to this was that it was a basically well made and well acted movie, and at times even an interesting movie as the story unfolded - but that it also seemed like a movie that was anything but overpowering. It didn't leave me awestruck. (5/10)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fantastic Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lencad
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I think I have seen the movie at least 5 or more times. I love it. You see something each time you watch it that you missed the first time. My friend and I also went to the Whistle Cafe Stop Cafe in Juliette, Ga and had lunch. It was terrific. We had Peach Cobbler for desert and we could have gone back for more. I bought candy and soap in the Honeycomb Store and today I ordered some more. The soap is so nice you can smell it all over my house. The candy is awesome. Take time to see the movie. Be sure to visit the Whistle Stop Cafe in Juliette, Ga and to also stop in at the Honeycomb and what ever other stores are open. I love places like this that are still there for others to see. It makes the movie seem even more real.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This film is what movies should be about...!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vonschweissguth
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have viewed this marvelous film at least 2 dozen times. As with all great movies, you will always catch something "new" with each watching. If you want to be charmed, enchanted, moved, and find yourself wishing.... This is a film you will cherish. I won't belabor more than others have written so well. It is a film that resides in my permanent library on my top shelf. When I watch it again, I find myself wishing that I knew the characters personally and somehow find that I do. This film is one of the only that I esteem. It adds to your life. It hugs the heart and enriches who you are. I want to thank all the marvelous actors. If they ever wondered why they chose their profession, this film is why. 200 years from now it will be loved and valued. The test of time is guaranteed with Fried Green Tomatoes!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Overly Sentimental FIlm
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Supachewy
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/9/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The drama Fried Green Tomatoes is directed by Jon Avnet and stars Kathy Bates, Jessica Tandy, Mary Stuart Masterson, and Mary-Luise Parker. The film takes place in modern day Alabama with flashbacks from 1920 Alabama. The film starts off with a little girl in 1920s Alabama named Idgie Threadgood who does not want to be a part of her sister's wedding. After being talked to by her older brother she agrees to go to it and then afterward the two of them plus the girl the brother likes, Ruth (Parker) go on a walk around the area. When Ruth's hat flies off Idgie's brother goes and gets it for her but his foot ends up stuck in a train track and he is tragically killed. Idgie is extremely disturbed by her brother's death and is never the same again. This is all told from her sister Ninny Threadgood (Tandy) to Evelyn Couch (Bates). Couch is a middle aged woman who does not believe that she has any power or purpose and she met Ninny in a nursing home while visiting her husband's aunt. As the film goes on it develops the relationship between Idgie and Ruth and also Ninny and Evelyn and it is very sentimental... The script was written by Fannie Flagg who also wrote the book which the film is based on. Personally I thought the writing was weak for one main reason. That reason is that the film bounced between two different stories. The story with Idgie and Ruth was quite interesting but the story with Evelyn and Ninny was a complete bore that lacked depth. It was basically Evelyn just saying I have no purpose and then becoming a crazy woman that just tears apart her home and it is all supposedly because of Ninny's story. It is just not believable. It would have been better if it was more like Ninny just telling the story to Evelyn and Evelyn not having a story of her own. The first feature film for the big screen of Jon Avnet proved that he is a decent director. Avnet got solid performances by all his leads which is hard to do in a cast with four leads. The shots in the film were not really impressive and he did not really make me care much for any of the characters. I would have said that he did a poor job if he did not get the performances that he did, but then again it was only his first film even though he has not proved to be much of a director today in any way. The acting in this film was the best part of it. All four of the leads gave great performances. Even Kathy Bates, whose character I thought to be the weakest written still was able to bring a great performance out of it. Yet she is one of the greatest actresses who ever lived. Jessica Tandy even earned an Oscar nomination for her performance just because she was so great being an eccentric old lady. Parker and Masterson are sort of newcomers to the lead position and they really pulled it off as well. The acting made this film bearable. Overall I give this film a 5/10, I would have gave lower if it was not for the strong performances. I would recommend this to anyone who likes period pieces or films with strong female leads.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Story of friendship
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SnoopyStyle
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is based on a novel that takes place in Alabama. The modern story has timid housewife Evelyn Couch (Kathy Bates) who befriends an old woman Ninny Threadgoode (Jessica Tandy) at a retirement home. She recounts an old story from depression era. She tells the story of Idgie Threadgoode (Mary Stuart Masterson) and her friendship with Ruth Jamison (Mary-Louise Parker). Their lives are forever linked by the death of Idgie's brother who was Ruth's boyfriend. The modern story doesn't have quite the punch. The old time story exceeds it in almost every way. It may have been an important part of the novel, but I don't know if the modern story necessarily added anything to the movie. Both Marys are outstanding in their roles. Their characters are truly the center of this movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very very good writing,Wonderful movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Wadejohnson1970
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As a young man growing up in the Country of my home town of Hawkinsville Pulaski County Georgia, I had saw the movie in rental stores, however I was just never quite interested in watching a movie called Fried Green Tomatoes!!! However one night while watching TV with my family I was flicking through the Chanel's and came upon this very net resting movie that just so,happens to be..yes you guessed it...Fried Green Tomatoes!!! Well right here in the middle of my review I get a knock on my door, some guy tells me that he had just hit a little black dog out in front of my home, we live on a dirt road and people drive on it as if it were a damn Interstate Highway!!!! Sure enough it is my late fathers dog Buster!!! One of the last things my Daddy said was son look out for my dog!!! Now I feel really bad!!! He is not dead yet, he has his wits about him, just a bit loopy, but catching one of those full size Chevy Silverado's ain't good for a 4 pound dog!!! Anyway please pray for Buster!!!! Now back to the Movie review... As I began to watch this movie I just got more and more intertwined into the story!!! I couldn't tell who was more intrigued by Iggies story, me or Evelyne Couch. The story about Frank Bennett was so interesting!!! Heck there wasn't anything about the entire movie that Wasn't interesting!!!! The most interesting part of the entire movie was the fact that Frank Bennett's body was never found!!! And even more the reason WHY IT EAS NEVER FOUND!!!! Big George Put him on the grill and made BBQ out of him and they fed him to the guy from Georgia that was so stern to Iggies that he WAS THE LAW!!!! And you can't beat the law!!!! So to sum it up in a few words!!!! Fried Green Tomatoes is by far one of the best movies I ever saw, most important I. Was working with Georgia Power and happened upon this little Cafe out in Julliett Ga. And before I knew it I was sitting right in the middle of where one of my favorite movies was made..The Whistle Stop Cafe!!!!! You can't imagine my excitement and couldn't wait to tell my wife that I had sat and eat right there where the story played out!!! Now I'm gonna take my wife there to have some of those world famous FRIED GREEN TOMATOES!!!! And if you never watched this MASTERPIECE PLEASE DO!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Secret's in the Sauce
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    C_Hardrick
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Oscar winner Kathy Bates stars as Evelyn Couch, who one day while visiting her husbands ailing aunt in a nursing home, stumbles onto Mrs. Threadgoode, a resident of the same nursing home, played by Oscar winner Jessica Tandy. As Mrs. Threadgoode tells her story to Evelyn, we learn a vivid story of a young charismatic girl named Idgie spanning the years before World War One through the Depression. The film is set in the Deep South. Alabama to be exact in a small town called Whistle Stop. The film also stars a young Chris O'Donnell as Buddy Threadgoode, Idgie's brother. When Buddy is tragically killed in front of her eyes, Idgie sets out on a life to live to the fullest, even against her mother's wishes and the town preacher's wishes as well. As she grows, so does her relationship with family friend Ruth Jamison, played by Mary-Louise Parker. Eventually they become an inseparable duo, until Ruth marries Frank Bennett, played by Nick Searcy. Frank Bennett ends up being the plot point of the second half of Mrs. Threadgoode's story, and how Idgie may have or may not have killed him. We may not know what happened to Frank, however, "the secrets in the sauce."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brilliant sweet modern classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    misskellyvalente
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film was at times hysterical and at other times tugged at your heart strings. The film was based on a book. The film looked great and was well written and had wonderful actors portraying some great characters that you could really get attached to. I was a little disappointed that the film watered down the relationship of the two female characters. I realize that it would have never made it to main-stream America if the filmmakers hadn't. It was still very clear that there is a relationship in the film if you are paying attention for the simple little clues. Mary Stuart Masterson and Mary-Louise Parker did an amazing job capturing the chemistry between these two female characters. It's always amazing to watch Jessica Tandy act as she brings such heart to any character she portrays. Kathy Bates plays Evelyn and makes her so truthful and funny. The film is marketed as a feel good film and it does contain those moments, but it leans more toward drama side than the comedy side. Don't let anything stop you from watching this brilliant sweet modern classic. You'll be glad you did.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An authentic classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    robert-temple-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have just seen this wonderful film for the third time, after many years, and it is such a classic, and has not lost any of its interest or appeal. Indeed, it is more relevant now than it ever was, considering that it is about the plight of women and how they cope with their various life situations. It is based on a novel, and has a screenplay by, Fannie Flagg. It is set in Alabama where she comes from, and the story presumably has some basis in truth. Not many people know that Fannie Flagg used to be a brilliant comedienne. I knew her in the mid 1960s when she was a stand-up comic, and she was hilarious. She used to perform at a marvellous comedy cabaret night club in Manhattan, now long gone, which had two floors. The upstairs was called Upstairs at the Downstairs, and the downstairs was called Downstairs at the Upstairs. It was at 37 West 56th Street and was run by an amusing and eccentric woman whose name I have forgotten, alas. Fannie played there at the same time as Madeline ('Maddy') Kahn, who was also wildly funny. Fannie told me she had wanted to perform under her own real name of Patricia Neal, but was told by her agent or manager, I believe, that she could not do that because there was a famous film actress of that name already, so she invented the name Fannie Flagg for herself. It was only years later that she wrote this marvellous heart-felt novel, which was rejected by many publishers, but which finally came out and then resulted in this film. And it is this which really made Fannie Flag famous. The film was shot in Georgia, which is next door to Alabama. But the story is mostly set in Alabama in a little town called Whistle Stop. That name arose because it was a settlement situated beside the railroad. Many small Southern towns fell into desuetude (i.e. withered away) when the railroads started collapsing, after the construction of the interstate highway system, which shifted so much travel and freight transport onto roads and destroyed the rail industry, from the 1950s onwards. In this film which takes place at two different times, during the pre-War period which constitutes the earlier story, the two young women, Idgie and Ruth, open a railside caf&eacute; called The Whistle Stop Caf&eacute;. In those years, it thrived and became the heart of the town, where everyone went to eat real home cooking, which included the favourite local delicacy, fried green tomatoes, which were sliced and fried in batter in what in the South is called a skillet, which is an old 17th century English word for a frying pan, the word surviving only in the American South and nowhere else. (I still fry my eggs and bacon in an old iron family skillet which was cast in the family forge at Taunton, Massachusetts, in the 17th or 18th century. We have been using that skillet for many generations. Just imagine how many bacon fat molecules survive in the crystalline interstices of the cast iron after those centuries of use every morning. The outside of the skillet looks like something dug up by an archaeologist, but the inside is shiny and ready for anything. But this question arises: can bacon fat go rancid after a century or two? It does seem to improve the flavour anyway. However, I am ashamed to say that I have never fried any green tomatoes, which is doubtless a great personal failing of mine. The skillet has thus been deprived of what Ruth and Idgie would perhaps consider to be its main function, to deal with those green tomatoes.) Idgie, who is a hopeless cook, cannot prepare them, so Ruth has to do it. Throughout the film people keep tasting them to see if they are up to standard. The modern story of the film consists of tales told by an old lady in a retirement home to a much younger woman, and the effect this has on transforming her life. That younger woman is played by Kathy Bates, whose performance is breathtaking in its sensitivity and brilliance. But then, Kathy Bates has always been one of everybody's favourite and most endearing actresses, and we all know what a genius she is. The old woman is played equally brilliantly by the famous Jessica Tandy, veteran of a lifetime of superlative achievements in both stage and screen. Before TV wiped all the brains of the public as clean as a virgin hard disc, people used to tell stories, and there was such a thing as verbal communication. (And people didn't even have to use their thumbs to communicate, like today's simian-thumbed and simian-brained text messagers.) This film is all about the power of stories to stir the imagination and transform lives. Even as late as the 1960s, some old women still survived in the South who could tell stories for hours on end. They are all gone now, and it is like what happened after the time of Homer, when the last of the bards died. The best rendering in fiction of the 'power of stories' is probably the novella by Mircea Eliade entitled THE OLD MAN AND THE BUREAUCRATS. (Eliade wrote the story of Coppola's film YOUTH WITHOUT YOUTH, 2007, though that film was very disappointing and a poor adaptation.) The stories told by Jessica Tandy are about Idgie and Ruth. In those lengthy flashback sequences, the two young women are brilliantly portrayed by the two Mary's, Mary Stuart Masterson, and Mary-Louise Parker. Certainly this is one of the greatest 'sisterhood' films ever made. Their story is full of love, pain, pathos, loss, tragedy, and joy. Not unlike life. If you can see this without shedding a tear, then there is no hope for you. Good old Fannie, may she long keep flying her Flagg.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cannibalism And Gendercidal Hatred
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Louis B Maybe
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    OK, so here's why this film is the opposite of everything you've ever been told it is: It's not a wonderful feel-good movie for the girls, it's an ugly, violent fantasy in which justice is confused with revenge. Let's break it down: There are no primary male characters in this movie. Of the secondary and tertiary ones, it could be said that all the (white) males are evil or inadequate. Buddy is good, of course, but inadequate. His own foolishness destroys him. Buddy Junior is equally good but equally inadequate. Frank, on the other hand is just plain evil, and in between are more ambiguous male characters. The police chief is willing to help Idgie, it's true, but only because of his lecherous interest in her, and his mentality is thoroughly racist. Of the male characters, only Big George is unambiguously both good and adequate. But Big George is a black man. And black men are oppressed men. In effect, they are not men at all: exempt on political grounds from the critique levelled at white men, they are honorary women. This movie, couched in soft colours and sweet music, is one of the most casually misandric movies ever made. First of all, & most obviously, there is the EATING of her Evelyn's murdered husband. But it happens throughout the movie, as well, such as when Evelyn tells Frank "if I was going to kill you, I'd use my fists". She fantasizes about putting bombs in copies of Playboy and Hustler. "I'll take all the wife-beaters," she says, "and I'll machine gun their genitals!" "You didn't kill Ed, did you?" asks Ninny when Evelyn turns up late. "Not yet," answers Evelyn with a smile. The problem here is not that women will leave theatres and go on killing sprees. The problem is simply the convincing presentation of a cinematic world in which only women have a 'right' to be angry, in which all women are victims, & all men - all white men,anyway - are evil oppressors or inadequate burdens. To the extent that both women and men consciously or subconsciously adopt this worldview, the mutual hostility that now characterizes relations between the sexes will be exacerbated instead of questioned or healed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Interesting But Not Overpowering
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sddavis63 (revsdd@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watching the progression of the relationship between Idgie (Mary Stuart Masterson) and Ruth (Mary-Louise Parker) is fairly interesting. The story is a flashback; a story related by Ninny Threadgoode (Jessica Tandy) to Evelyn (Kathy Bates) who befriends Ninny in a local nursing home. So right off the top you can see that there's a pretty decent cast. Also almost from the start you realize that Ninny is a bit of an enigmatic character. Is she or is she not Idgie relating her own story? The movie seems to lead in that direction but never actually makes it explicit, so in the end it's left to the viewer to decide. Basically, this ends up as a murder mystery from the past. Ruth's abusive husband is murdered, and the question is who killed him. Idgie is put on trial for the crime, but the charges are dismissed. The mystery is held pretty well until the end of the movie. The movie begins with Idgie as a child, and with Ruth as her older brother Buddy's love interest. After Buddy's tragic death, Idgie and Ruth develop a very close friendship - the movie bobs and weaves around the issue of what the nature of their relationship was. Was it just a close friendship? Was it more? My feeling from the movie is that Idgie wanted more than a friendship; Ruth's interests were less clear. I haven't read the book, but I understand that the novel is quite clear in making the point that there was a lesbian romance between the two. Perhaps Hollywood in 1991 was still too nervous about such an issue to make it front and centre; ambiguity was as much as the studios could stomach apparently. We follow both of them through the ups and downs of life as they open a cafe together, whose menu specialty is - you guessed it - fried green tomatoes. Kathy Bates provided some comedy to the movie as the modern day housewife who goes through a rebirth after meeting Ninny - a rebirth that totally confuses her husband Ed (Gailard Sartain), who doesn't have a clue why Evelyn is changing so much and upsetting their comfortable existence. While she provided comedy, I wasn't really taken in by Bates' character in this. I thought the constant switching between present and past was overdone and not particularly well done to be honest; in a lot of ways the two parts of the stories didn't mesh that well. Aside from Bates, there were a lot of very likable characters from the past, such as Big George (Stan Shaw) and Smokey Lonesome (Timothy Scott.) The identity of Ruth's husband's killer in the end took me by surprise, so that was well done. My final reaction to this was that it was a basically well made and well acted movie, and at times even an interesting movie as the story unfolded - but that it also seemed like a movie that was anything but overpowering. It didn't leave me awestruck. (5/10)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fantastic Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lencad
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I think I have seen the movie at least 5 or more times. I love it. You see something each time you watch it that you missed the first time. My friend and I also went to the Whistle Cafe Stop Cafe in Juliette, Ga and had lunch. It was terrific. We had Peach Cobbler for desert and we could have gone back for more. I bought candy and soap in the Honeycomb Store and today I ordered some more. The soap is so nice you can smell it all over my house. The candy is awesome. Take time to see the movie. Be sure to visit the Whistle Stop Cafe in Juliette, Ga and to also stop in at the Honeycomb and what ever other stores are open. I love places like this that are still there for others to see. It makes the movie seem even more real.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This film is what movies should be about...!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vonschweissguth
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have viewed this marvelous film at least 2 dozen times. As with all great movies, you will always catch something "new" with each watching. If you want to be charmed, enchanted, moved, and find yourself wishing.... This is a film you will cherish. I won't belabor more than others have written so well. It is a film that resides in my permanent library on my top shelf. When I watch it again, I find myself wishing that I knew the characters personally and somehow find that I do. This film is one of the only that I esteem. It adds to your life. It hugs the heart and enriches who you are. I want to thank all the marvelous actors. If they ever wondered why they chose their profession, this film is why. 200 years from now it will be loved and valued. The test of time is guaranteed with Fried Green Tomatoes!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Overly Sentimental FIlm
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Supachewy
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/9/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The drama Fried Green Tomatoes is directed by Jon Avnet and stars Kathy Bates, Jessica Tandy, Mary Stuart Masterson, and Mary-Luise Parker. The film takes place in modern day Alabama with flashbacks from 1920 Alabama. The film starts off with a little girl in 1920s Alabama named Idgie Threadgood who does not want to be a part of her sister's wedding. After being talked to by her older brother she agrees to go to it and then afterward the two of them plus the girl the brother likes, Ruth (Parker) go on a walk around the area. When Ruth's hat flies off Idgie's brother goes and gets it for her but his foot ends up stuck in a train track and he is tragically killed. Idgie is extremely disturbed by her brother's death and is never the same again. This is all told from her sister Ninny Threadgood (Tandy) to Evelyn Couch (Bates). Couch is a middle aged woman who does not believe that she has any power or purpose and she met Ninny in a nursing home while visiting her husband's aunt. As the film goes on it develops the relationship between Idgie and Ruth and also Ninny and Evelyn and it is very sentimental... The script was written by Fannie Flagg who also wrote the book which the film is based on. Personally I thought the writing was weak for one main reason. That reason is that the film bounced between two different stories. The story with Idgie and Ruth was quite interesting but the story with Evelyn and Ninny was a complete bore that lacked depth. It was basically Evelyn just saying I have no purpose and then becoming a crazy woman that just tears apart her home and it is all supposedly because of Ninny's story. It is just not believable. It would have been better if it was more like Ninny just telling the story to Evelyn and Evelyn not having a story of her own. The first feature film for the big screen of Jon Avnet proved that he is a decent director. Avnet got solid performances by all his leads which is hard to do in a cast with four leads. The shots in the film were not really impressive and he did not really make me care much for any of the characters. I would have said that he did a poor job if he did not get the performances that he did, but then again it was only his first film even though he has not proved to be much of a director today in any way. The acting in this film was the best part of it. All four of the leads gave great performances. Even Kathy Bates, whose character I thought to be the weakest written still was able to bring a great performance out of it. Yet she is one of the greatest actresses who ever lived. Jessica Tandy even earned an Oscar nomination for her performance just because she was so great being an eccentric old lady. Parker and Masterson are sort of newcomers to the lead position and they really pulled it off as well. The acting made this film bearable. Overall I give this film a 5/10, I would have gave lower if it was not for the strong performances. I would recommend this to anyone who likes period pieces or films with strong female leads.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Story of friendship
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SnoopyStyle
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is based on a novel that takes place in Alabama. The modern story has timid housewife Evelyn Couch (Kathy Bates) who befriends an old woman Ninny Threadgoode (Jessica Tandy) at a retirement home. She recounts an old story from depression era. She tells the story of Idgie Threadgoode (Mary Stuart Masterson) and her friendship with Ruth Jamison (Mary-Louise Parker). Their lives are forever linked by the death of Idgie's brother who was Ruth's boyfriend. The modern story doesn't have quite the punch. The old time story exceeds it in almost every way. It may have been an important part of the novel, but I don't know if the modern story necessarily added anything to the movie. Both Marys are outstanding in their roles. Their characters are truly the center of this movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very very good writing,Wonderful movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Wadejohnson1970
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As a young man growing up in the Country of my home town of Hawkinsville Pulaski County Georgia, I had saw the movie in rental stores, however I was just never quite interested in watching a movie called Fried Green Tomatoes!!! However one night while watching TV with my family I was flicking through the Chanel's and came upon this very net resting movie that just so,happens to be..yes you guessed it...Fried Green Tomatoes!!! Well right here in the middle of my review I get a knock on my door, some guy tells me that he had just hit a little black dog out in front of my home, we live on a dirt road and people drive on it as if it were a damn Interstate Highway!!!! Sure enough it is my late fathers dog Buster!!! One of the last things my Daddy said was son look out for my dog!!! Now I feel really bad!!! He is not dead yet, he has his wits about him, just a bit loopy, but catching one of those full size Chevy Silverado's ain't good for a 4 pound dog!!! Anyway please pray for Buster!!!! Now back to the Movie review... As I began to watch this movie I just got more and more intertwined into the story!!! I couldn't tell who was more intrigued by Iggies story, me or Evelyne Couch. The story about Frank Bennett was so interesting!!! Heck there wasn't anything about the entire movie that Wasn't interesting!!!! The most interesting part of the entire movie was the fact that Frank Bennett's body was never found!!! And even more the reason WHY IT EAS NEVER FOUND!!!! Big George Put him on the grill and made BBQ out of him and they fed him to the guy from Georgia that was so stern to Iggies that he WAS THE LAW!!!! And you can't beat the law!!!! So to sum it up in a few words!!!! Fried Green Tomatoes is by far one of the best movies I ever saw, most important I. Was working with Georgia Power and happened upon this little Cafe out in Julliett Ga. And before I knew it I was sitting right in the middle of where one of my favorite movies was made..The Whistle Stop Cafe!!!!! You can't imagine my excitement and couldn't wait to tell my wife that I had sat and eat right there where the story played out!!! Now I'm gonna take my wife there to have some of those world famous FRIED GREEN TOMATOES!!!! And if you never watched this MASTERPIECE PLEASE DO!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Secret's in the Sauce
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    C_Hardrick
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Oscar winner Kathy Bates stars as Evelyn Couch, who one day while visiting her husbands ailing aunt in a nursing home, stumbles onto Mrs. Threadgoode, a resident of the same nursing home, played by Oscar winner Jessica Tandy. As Mrs. Threadgoode tells her story to Evelyn, we learn a vivid story of a young charismatic girl named Idgie spanning the years before World War One through the Depression. The film is set in the Deep South. Alabama to be exact in a small town called Whistle Stop. The film also stars a young Chris O'Donnell as Buddy Threadgoode, Idgie's brother. When Buddy is tragically killed in front of her eyes, Idgie sets out on a life to live to the fullest, even against her mother's wishes and the town preacher's wishes as well. As she grows, so does her relationship with family friend Ruth Jamison, played by Mary-Louise Parker. Eventually they become an inseparable duo, until Ruth marries Frank Bennett, played by Nick Searcy. Frank Bennett ends up being the plot point of the second half of Mrs. Threadgoode's story, and how Idgie may have or may not have killed him. We may not know what happened to Frank, however, "the secrets in the sauce."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brilliant sweet modern classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    misskellyvalente
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film was at times hysterical and at other times tugged at your heart strings. The film was based on a book. The film looked great and was well written and had wonderful actors portraying some great characters that you could really get attached to. I was a little disappointed that the film watered down the relationship of the two female characters. I realize that it would have never made it to main-stream America if the filmmakers hadn't. It was still very clear that there is a relationship in the film if you are paying attention for the simple little clues. Mary Stuart Masterson and Mary-Louise Parker did an amazing job capturing the chemistry between these two female characters. It's always amazing to watch Jessica Tandy act as she brings such heart to any character she portrays. Kathy Bates plays Evelyn and makes her so truthful and funny. The film is marketed as a feel good film and it does contain those moments, but it leans more toward drama side than the comedy side. Don't let anything stop you from watching this brilliant sweet modern classic. You'll be glad you did.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An authentic classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    robert-temple-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have just seen this wonderful film for the third time, after many years, and it is such a classic, and has not lost any of its interest or appeal. Indeed, it is more relevant now than it ever was, considering that it is about the plight of women and how they cope with their various life situations. It is based on a novel, and has a screenplay by, Fannie Flagg. It is set in Alabama where she comes from, and the story presumably has some basis in truth. Not many people know that Fannie Flagg used to be a brilliant comedienne. I knew her in the mid 1960s when she was a stand-up comic, and she was hilarious. She used to perform at a marvellous comedy cabaret night club in Manhattan, now long gone, which had two floors. The upstairs was called Upstairs at the Downstairs, and the downstairs was called Downstairs at the Upstairs. It was at 37 West 56th Street and was run by an amusing and eccentric woman whose name I have forgotten, alas. Fannie played there at the same time as Madeline ('Maddy') Kahn, who was also wildly funny. Fannie told me she had wanted to perform under her own real name of Patricia Neal, but was told by her agent or manager, I believe, that she could not do that because there was a famous film actress of that name already, so she invented the name Fannie Flagg for herself. It was only years later that she wrote this marvellous heart-felt novel, which was rejected by many publishers, but which finally came out and then resulted in this film. And it is this which really made Fannie Flag famous. The film was shot in Georgia, which is next door to Alabama. But the story is mostly set in Alabama in a little town called Whistle Stop. That name arose because it was a settlement situated beside the railroad. Many small Southern towns fell into desuetude (i.e. withered away) when the railroads started collapsing, after the construction of the interstate highway system, which shifted so much travel and freight transport onto roads and destroyed the rail industry, from the 1950s onwards. In this film which takes place at two different times, during the pre-War period which constitutes the earlier story, the two young women, Idgie and Ruth, open a railside caf&eacute; called The Whistle Stop Caf&eacute;. In those years, it thrived and became the heart of the town, where everyone went to eat real home cooking, which included the favourite local delicacy, fried green tomatoes, which were sliced and fried in batter in what in the South is called a skillet, which is an old 17th century English word for a frying pan, the word surviving only in the American South and nowhere else. (I still fry my eggs and bacon in an old iron family skillet which was cast in the family forge at Taunton, Massachusetts, in the 17th or 18th century. We have been using that skillet for many generations. Just imagine how many bacon fat molecules survive in the crystalline interstices of the cast iron after those centuries of use every morning. The outside of the skillet looks like something dug up by an archaeologist, but the inside is shiny and ready for anything. But this question arises: can bacon fat go rancid after a century or two? It does seem to improve the flavour anyway. However, I am ashamed to say that I have never fried any green tomatoes, which is doubtless a great personal failing of mine. The skillet has thus been deprived of what Ruth and Idgie would perhaps consider to be its main function, to deal with those green tomatoes.) Idgie, who is a hopeless cook, cannot prepare them, so Ruth has to do it. Throughout the film people keep tasting them to see if they are up to standard. The modern story of the film consists of tales told by an old lady in a retirement home to a much younger woman, and the effect this has on transforming her life. That younger woman is played by Kathy Bates, whose performance is breathtaking in its sensitivity and brilliance. But then, Kathy Bates has always been one of everybody's favourite and most endearing actresses, and we all know what a genius she is. The old woman is played equally brilliantly by the famous Jessica Tandy, veteran of a lifetime of superlative achievements in both stage and screen. Before TV wiped all the brains of the public as clean as a virgin hard disc, people used to tell stories, and there was such a thing as verbal communication. (And people didn't even have to use their thumbs to communicate, like today's simian-thumbed and simian-brained text messagers.) This film is all about the power of stories to stir the imagination and transform lives. Even as late as the 1960s, some old women still survived in the South who could tell stories for hours on end. They are all gone now, and it is like what happened after the time of Homer, when the last of the bards died. The best rendering in fiction of the 'power of stories' is probably the novella by Mircea Eliade entitled THE OLD MAN AND THE BUREAUCRATS. (Eliade wrote the story of Coppola's film YOUTH WITHOUT YOUTH, 2007, though that film was very disappointing and a poor adaptation.) The stories told by Jessica Tandy are about Idgie and Ruth. In those lengthy flashback sequences, the two young women are brilliantly portrayed by the two Mary's, Mary Stuart Masterson, and Mary-Louise Parker. Certainly this is one of the greatest 'sisterhood' films ever made. Their story is full of love, pain, pathos, loss, tragedy, and joy. Not unlike life. If you can see this without shedding a tear, then there is no hope for you. Good old Fannie, may she long keep flying her Flagg.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cannibalism And Gendercidal Hatred
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Louis B Maybe
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    OK, so here's why this film is the opposite of everything you've ever been told it is: It's not a wonderful feel-good movie for the girls, it's an ugly, violent fantasy in which justice is confused with revenge. Let's break it down: There are no primary male characters in this movie. Of the secondary and tertiary ones, it could be said that all the (white) males are evil or inadequate. Buddy is good, of course, but inadequate. His own foolishness destroys him. Buddy Junior is equally good but equally inadequate. Frank, on the other hand is just plain evil, and in between are more ambiguous male characters. The police chief is willing to help Idgie, it's true, but only because of his lecherous interest in her, and his mentality is thoroughly racist. Of the male characters, only Big George is unambiguously both good and adequate. But Big George is a black man. And black men are oppressed men. In effect, they are not men at all: exempt on political grounds from the critique levelled at white men, they are honorary women. This movie, couched in soft colours and sweet music, is one of the most casually misandric movies ever made. First of all, & most obviously, there is the EATING of her Evelyn's murdered husband. But it happens throughout the movie, as well, such as when Evelyn tells Frank "if I was going to kill you, I'd use my fists". She fantasizes about putting bombs in copies of Playboy and Hustler. "I'll take all the wife-beaters," she says, "and I'll machine gun their genitals!" "You didn't kill Ed, did you?" asks Ninny when Evelyn turns up late. "Not yet," answers Evelyn with a smile. The problem here is not that women will leave theatres and go on killing sprees. The problem is simply the convincing presentation of a cinematic world in which only women have a 'right' to be angry, in which all women are victims, & all men - all white men,anyway - are evil oppressors or inadequate burdens. To the extent that both women and men consciously or subconsciously adopt this worldview, the mutual hostility that now characterizes relations between the sexes will be exacerbated instead of questioned or healed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Interesting But Not Overpowering
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sddavis63 (revsdd@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watching the progression of the relationship between Idgie (Mary Stuart Masterson) and Ruth (Mary-Louise Parker) is fairly interesting. The story is a flashback; a story related by Ninny Threadgoode (Jessica Tandy) to Evelyn (Kathy Bates) who befriends Ninny in a local nursing home. So right off the top you can see that there's a pretty decent cast. Also almost from the start you realize that Ninny is a bit of an enigmatic character. Is she or is she not Idgie relating her own story? The movie seems to lead in that direction but never actually makes it explicit, so in the end it's left to the viewer to decide. Basically, this ends up as a murder mystery from the past. Ruth's abusive husband is murdered, and the question is who killed him. Idgie is put on trial for the crime, but the charges are dismissed. The mystery is held pretty well until the end of the movie. The movie begins with Idgie as a child, and with Ruth as her older brother Buddy's love interest. After Buddy's tragic death, Idgie and Ruth develop a very close friendship - the movie bobs and weaves around the issue of what the nature of their relationship was. Was it just a close friendship? Was it more? My feeling from the movie is that Idgie wanted more than a friendship; Ruth's interests were less clear. I haven't read the book, but I understand that the novel is quite clear in making the point that there was a lesbian romance between the two. Perhaps Hollywood in 1991 was still too nervous about such an issue to make it front and centre; ambiguity was as much as the studios could stomach apparently. We follow both of them through the ups and downs of life as they open a cafe together, whose menu specialty is - you guessed it - fried green tomatoes. Kathy Bates provided some comedy to the movie as the modern day housewife who goes through a rebirth after meeting Ninny - a rebirth that totally confuses her husband Ed (Gailard Sartain), who doesn't have a clue why Evelyn is changing so much and upsetting their comfortable existence. While she provided comedy, I wasn't really taken in by Bates' character in this. I thought the constant switching between present and past was overdone and not particularly well done to be honest; in a lot of ways the two parts of the stories didn't mesh that well. Aside from Bates, there were a lot of very likable characters from the past, such as Big George (Stan Shaw) and Smokey Lonesome (Timothy Scott.) The identity of Ruth's husband's killer in the end took me by surprise, so that was well done. My final reaction to this was that it was a basically well made and well acted movie, and at times even an interesting movie as the story unfolded - but that it also seemed like a movie that was anything but overpowering. It didn't leave me awestruck. (5/10)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fantastic Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lencad
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I think I have seen the movie at least 5 or more times. I love it. You see something each time you watch it that you missed the first time. My friend and I also went to the Whistle Cafe Stop Cafe in Juliette, Ga and had lunch. It was terrific. We had Peach Cobbler for desert and we could have gone back for more. I bought candy and soap in the Honeycomb Store and today I ordered some more. The soap is so nice you can smell it all over my house. The candy is awesome. Take time to see the movie. Be sure to visit the Whistle Stop Cafe in Juliette, Ga and to also stop in at the Honeycomb and what ever other stores are open. I love places like this that are still there for others to see. It makes the movie seem even more real.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This film is what movies should be about...!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vonschweissguth
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have viewed this marvelous film at least 2 dozen times. As with all great movies, you will always catch something "new" with each watching. If you want to be charmed, enchanted, moved, and find yourself wishing.... This is a film you will cherish. I won't belabor more than others have written so well. It is a film that resides in my permanent library on my top shelf. When I watch it again, I find myself wishing that I knew the characters personally and somehow find that I do. This film is one of the only that I esteem. It adds to your life. It hugs the heart and enriches who you are. I want to thank all the marvelous actors. If they ever wondered why they chose their profession, this film is why. 200 years from now it will be loved and valued. The test of time is guaranteed with Fried Green Tomatoes!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Overly Sentimental FIlm
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Supachewy
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/9/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The drama Fried Green Tomatoes is directed by Jon Avnet and stars Kathy Bates, Jessica Tandy, Mary Stuart Masterson, and Mary-Luise Parker. The film takes place in modern day Alabama with flashbacks from 1920 Alabama. The film starts off with a little girl in 1920s Alabama named Idgie Threadgood who does not want to be a part of her sister's wedding. After being talked to by her older brother she agrees to go to it and then afterward the two of them plus the girl the brother likes, Ruth (Parker) go on a walk around the area. When Ruth's hat flies off Idgie's brother goes and gets it for her but his foot ends up stuck in a train track and he is tragically killed. Idgie is extremely disturbed by her brother's death and is never the same again. This is all told from her sister Ninny Threadgood (Tandy) to Evelyn Couch (Bates). Couch is a middle aged woman who does not believe that she has any power or purpose and she met Ninny in a nursing home while visiting her husband's aunt. As the film goes on it develops the relationship between Idgie and Ruth and also Ninny and Evelyn and it is very sentimental... The script was written by Fannie Flagg who also wrote the book which the film is based on. Personally I thought the writing was weak for one main reason. That reason is that the film bounced between two different stories. The story with Idgie and Ruth was quite interesting but the story with Evelyn and Ninny was a complete bore that lacked depth. It was basically Evelyn just saying I have no purpose and then becoming a crazy woman that just tears apart her home and it is all supposedly because of Ninny's story. It is just not believable. It would have been better if it was more like Ninny just telling the story to Evelyn and Evelyn not having a story of her own. The first feature film for the big screen of Jon Avnet proved that he is a decent director. Avnet got solid performances by all his leads which is hard to do in a cast with four leads. The shots in the film were not really impressive and he did not really make me care much for any of the characters. I would have said that he did a poor job if he did not get the performances that he did, but then again it was only his first film even though he has not proved to be much of a director today in any way. The acting in this film was the best part of it. All four of the leads gave great performances. Even Kathy Bates, whose character I thought to be the weakest written still was able to bring a great performance out of it. Yet she is one of the greatest actresses who ever lived. Jessica Tandy even earned an Oscar nomination for her performance just because she was so great being an eccentric old lady. Parker and Masterson are sort of newcomers to the lead position and they really pulled it off as well. The acting made this film bearable. Overall I give this film a 5/10, I would have gave lower if it was not for the strong performances. I would recommend this to anyone who likes period pieces or films with strong female leads.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Story of friendship
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SnoopyStyle
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is based on a novel that takes place in Alabama. The modern story has timid housewife Evelyn Couch (Kathy Bates) who befriends an old woman Ninny Threadgoode (Jessica Tandy) at a retirement home. She recounts an old story from depression era. She tells the story of Idgie Threadgoode (Mary Stuart Masterson) and her friendship with Ruth Jamison (Mary-Louise Parker). Their lives are forever linked by the death of Idgie's brother who was Ruth's boyfriend. The modern story doesn't have quite the punch. The old time story exceeds it in almost every way. It may have been an important part of the novel, but I don't know if the modern story necessarily added anything to the movie. Both Marys are outstanding in their roles. Their characters are truly the center of this movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very very good writing,Wonderful movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Wadejohnson1970
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As a young man growing up in the Country of my home town of Hawkinsville Pulaski County Georgia, I had saw the movie in rental stores, however I was just never quite interested in watching a movie called Fried Green Tomatoes!!! However one night while watching TV with my family I was flicking through the Chanel's and came upon this very net resting movie that just so,happens to be..yes you guessed it...Fried Green Tomatoes!!! Well right here in the middle of my review I get a knock on my door, some guy tells me that he had just hit a little black dog out in front of my home, we live on a dirt road and people drive on it as if it were a damn Interstate Highway!!!! Sure enough it is my late fathers dog Buster!!! One of the last things my Daddy said was son look out for my dog!!! Now I feel really bad!!! He is not dead yet, he has his wits about him, just a bit loopy, but catching one of those full size Chevy Silverado's ain't good for a 4 pound dog!!! Anyway please pray for Buster!!!! Now back to the Movie review... As I began to watch this movie I just got more and more intertwined into the story!!! I couldn't tell who was more intrigued by Iggies story, me or Evelyne Couch. The story about Frank Bennett was so interesting!!! Heck there wasn't anything about the entire movie that Wasn't interesting!!!! The most interesting part of the entire movie was the fact that Frank Bennett's body was never found!!! And even more the reason WHY IT EAS NEVER FOUND!!!! Big George Put him on the grill and made BBQ out of him and they fed him to the guy from Georgia that was so stern to Iggies that he WAS THE LAW!!!! And you can't beat the law!!!! So to sum it up in a few words!!!! Fried Green Tomatoes is by far one of the best movies I ever saw, most important I. Was working with Georgia Power and happened upon this little Cafe out in Julliett Ga. And before I knew it I was sitting right in the middle of where one of my favorite movies was made..The Whistle Stop Cafe!!!!! You can't imagine my excitement and couldn't wait to tell my wife that I had sat and eat right there where the story played out!!! Now I'm gonna take my wife there to have some of those world famous FRIED GREEN TOMATOES!!!! And if you never watched this MASTERPIECE PLEASE DO!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Secret's in the Sauce
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    C_Hardrick
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Oscar winner Kathy Bates stars as Evelyn Couch, who one day while visiting her husbands ailing aunt in a nursing home, stumbles onto Mrs. Threadgoode, a resident of the same nursing home, played by Oscar winner Jessica Tandy. As Mrs. Threadgoode tells her story to Evelyn, we learn a vivid story of a young charismatic girl named Idgie spanning the years before World War One through the Depression. The film is set in the Deep South. Alabama to be exact in a small town called Whistle Stop. The film also stars a young Chris O'Donnell as Buddy Threadgoode, Idgie's brother. When Buddy is tragically killed in front of her eyes, Idgie sets out on a life to live to the fullest, even against her mother's wishes and the town preacher's wishes as well. As she grows, so does her relationship with family friend Ruth Jamison, played by Mary-Louise Parker. Eventually they become an inseparable duo, until Ruth marries Frank Bennett, played by Nick Searcy. Frank Bennett ends up being the plot point of the second half of Mrs. Threadgoode's story, and how Idgie may have or may not have killed him. We may not know what happened to Frank, however, "the secrets in the sauce."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brilliant sweet modern classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    misskellyvalente
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film was at times hysterical and at other times tugged at your heart strings. The film was based on a book. The film looked great and was well written and had wonderful actors portraying some great characters that you could really get attached to. I was a little disappointed that the film watered down the relationship of the two female characters. I realize that it would have never made it to main-stream America if the filmmakers hadn't. It was still very clear that there is a relationship in the film if you are paying attention for the simple little clues. Mary Stuart Masterson and Mary-Louise Parker did an amazing job capturing the chemistry between these two female characters. It's always amazing to watch Jessica Tandy act as she brings such heart to any character she portrays. Kathy Bates plays Evelyn and makes her so truthful and funny. The film is marketed as a feel good film and it does contain those moments, but it leans more toward drama side than the comedy side. Don't let anything stop you from watching this brilliant sweet modern classic. You'll be glad you did.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An authentic classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    robert-temple-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have just seen this wonderful film for the third time, after many years, and it is such a classic, and has not lost any of its interest or appeal. Indeed, it is more relevant now than it ever was, considering that it is about the plight of women and how they cope with their various life situations. It is based on a novel, and has a screenplay by, Fannie Flagg. It is set in Alabama where she comes from, and the story presumably has some basis in truth. Not many people know that Fannie Flagg used to be a brilliant comedienne. I knew her in the mid 1960s when she was a stand-up comic, and she was hilarious. She used to perform at a marvellous comedy cabaret night club in Manhattan, now long gone, which had two floors. The upstairs was called Upstairs at the Downstairs, and the downstairs was called Downstairs at the Upstairs. It was at 37 West 56th Street and was run by an amusing and eccentric woman whose name I have forgotten, alas. Fannie played there at the same time as Madeline ('Maddy') Kahn, who was also wildly funny. Fannie told me she had wanted to perform under her own real name of Patricia Neal, but was told by her agent or manager, I believe, that she could not do that because there was a famous film actress of that name already, so she invented the name Fannie Flagg for herself. It was only years later that she wrote this marvellous heart-felt novel, which was rejected by many publishers, but which finally came out and then resulted in this film. And it is this which really made Fannie Flag famous. The film was shot in Georgia, which is next door to Alabama. But the story is mostly set in Alabama in a little town called Whistle Stop. That name arose because it was a settlement situated beside the railroad. Many small Southern towns fell into desuetude (i.e. withered away) when the railroads started collapsing, after the construction of the interstate highway system, which shifted so much travel and freight transport onto roads and destroyed the rail industry, from the 1950s onwards. In this film which takes place at two different times, during the pre-War period which constitutes the earlier story, the two young women, Idgie and Ruth, open a railside caf&eacute; called The Whistle Stop Caf&eacute;. In those years, it thrived and became the heart of the town, where everyone went to eat real home cooking, which included the favourite local delicacy, fried green tomatoes, which were sliced and fried in batter in what in the South is called a skillet, which is an old 17th century English word for a frying pan, the word surviving only in the American South and nowhere else. (I still fry my eggs and bacon in an old iron family skillet which was cast in the family forge at Taunton, Massachusetts, in the 17th or 18th century. We have been using that skillet for many generations. Just imagine how many bacon fat molecules survive in the crystalline interstices of the cast iron after those centuries of use every morning. The outside of the skillet looks like something dug up by an archaeologist, but the inside is shiny and ready for anything. But this question arises: can bacon fat go rancid after a century or two? It does seem to improve the flavour anyway. However, I am ashamed to say that I have never fried any green tomatoes, which is doubtless a great personal failing of mine. The skillet has thus been deprived of what Ruth and Idgie would perhaps consider to be its main function, to deal with those green tomatoes.) Idgie, who is a hopeless cook, cannot prepare them, so Ruth has to do it. Throughout the film people keep tasting them to see if they are up to standard. The modern story of the film consists of tales told by an old lady in a retirement home to a much younger woman, and the effect this has on transforming her life. That younger woman is played by Kathy Bates, whose performance is breathtaking in its sensitivity and brilliance. But then, Kathy Bates has always been one of everybody's favourite and most endearing actresses, and we all know what a genius she is. The old woman is played equally brilliantly by the famous Jessica Tandy, veteran of a lifetime of superlative achievements in both stage and screen. Before TV wiped all the brains of the public as clean as a virgin hard disc, people used to tell stories, and there was such a thing as verbal communication. (And people didn't even have to use their thumbs to communicate, like today's simian-thumbed and simian-brained text messagers.) This film is all about the power of stories to stir the imagination and transform lives. Even as late as the 1960s, some old women still survived in the South who could tell stories for hours on end. They are all gone now, and it is like what happened after the time of Homer, when the last of the bards died. The best rendering in fiction of the 'power of stories' is probably the novella by Mircea Eliade entitled THE OLD MAN AND THE BUREAUCRATS. (Eliade wrote the story of Coppola's film YOUTH WITHOUT YOUTH, 2007, though that film was very disappointing and a poor adaptation.) The stories told by Jessica Tandy are about Idgie and Ruth. In those lengthy flashback sequences, the two young women are brilliantly portrayed by the two Mary's, Mary Stuart Masterson, and Mary-Louise Parker. Certainly this is one of the greatest 'sisterhood' films ever made. Their story is full of love, pain, pathos, loss, tragedy, and joy. Not unlike life. If you can see this without shedding a tear, then there is no hope for you. Good old Fannie, may she long keep flying her Flagg.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cannibalism And Gendercidal Hatred
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Louis B Maybe
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    OK, so here's why this film is the opposite of everything you've ever been told it is: It's not a wonderful feel-good movie for the girls, it's an ugly, violent fantasy in which justice is confused with revenge. Let's break it down: There are no primary male characters in this movie. Of the secondary and tertiary ones, it could be said that all the (white) males are evil or inadequate. Buddy is good, of course, but inadequate. His own foolishness destroys him. Buddy Junior is equally good but equally inadequate. Frank, on the other hand is just plain evil, and in between are more ambiguous male characters. The police chief is willing to help Idgie, it's true, but only because of his lecherous interest in her, and his mentality is thoroughly racist. Of the male characters, only Big George is unambiguously both good and adequate. But Big George is a black man. And black men are oppressed men. In effect, they are not men at all: exempt on political grounds from the critique levelled at white men, they are honorary women. This movie, couched in soft colours and sweet music, is one of the most casually misandric movies ever made. First of all, & most obviously, there is the EATING of her Evelyn's murdered husband. But it happens throughout the movie, as well, such as when Evelyn tells Frank "if I was going to kill you, I'd use my fists". She fantasizes about putting bombs in copies of Playboy and Hustler. "I'll take all the wife-beaters," she says, "and I'll machine gun their genitals!" "You didn't kill Ed, did you?" asks Ninny when Evelyn turns up late. "Not yet," answers Evelyn with a smile. The problem here is not that women will leave theatres and go on killing sprees. The problem is simply the convincing presentation of a cinematic world in which only women have a 'right' to be angry, in which all women are victims, & all men - all white men,anyway - are evil oppressors or inadequate burdens. To the extent that both women and men consciously or subconsciously adopt this worldview, the mutual hostility that now characterizes relations between the sexes will be exacerbated instead of questioned or healed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Interesting But Not Overpowering
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sddavis63 (revsdd@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watching the progression of the relationship between Idgie (Mary Stuart Masterson) and Ruth (Mary-Louise Parker) is fairly interesting. The story is a flashback; a story related by Ninny Threadgoode (Jessica Tandy) to Evelyn (Kathy Bates) who befriends Ninny in a local nursing home. So right off the top you can see that there's a pretty decent cast. Also almost from the start you realize that Ninny is a bit of an enigmatic character. Is she or is she not Idgie relating her own story? The movie seems to lead in that direction but never actually makes it explicit, so in the end it's left to the viewer to decide. Basically, this ends up as a murder mystery from the past. Ruth's abusive husband is murdered, and the question is who killed him. Idgie is put on trial for the crime, but the charges are dismissed. The mystery is held pretty well until the end of the movie. The movie begins with Idgie as a child, and with Ruth as her older brother Buddy's love interest. After Buddy's tragic death, Idgie and Ruth develop a very close friendship - the movie bobs and weaves around the issue of what the nature of their relationship was. Was it just a close friendship? Was it more? My feeling from the movie is that Idgie wanted more than a friendship; Ruth's interests were less clear. I haven't read the book, but I understand that the novel is quite clear in making the point that there was a lesbian romance between the two. Perhaps Hollywood in 1991 was still too nervous about such an issue to make it front and centre; ambiguity was as much as the studios could stomach apparently. We follow both of them through the ups and downs of life as they open a cafe together, whose menu specialty is - you guessed it - fried green tomatoes. Kathy Bates provided some comedy to the movie as the modern day housewife who goes through a rebirth after meeting Ninny - a rebirth that totally confuses her husband Ed (Gailard Sartain), who doesn't have a clue why Evelyn is changing so much and upsetting their comfortable existence. While she provided comedy, I wasn't really taken in by Bates' character in this. I thought the constant switching between present and past was overdone and not particularly well done to be honest; in a lot of ways the two parts of the stories didn't mesh that well. Aside from Bates, there were a lot of very likable characters from the past, such as Big George (Stan Shaw) and Smokey Lonesome (Timothy Scott.) The identity of Ruth's husband's killer in the end took me by surprise, so that was well done. My final reaction to this was that it was a basically well made and well acted movie, and at times even an interesting movie as the story unfolded - but that it also seemed like a movie that was anything but overpowering. It didn't leave me awestruck. (5/10)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fantastic Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lencad
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I think I have seen the movie at least 5 or more times. I love it. You see something each time you watch it that you missed the first time. My friend and I also went to the Whistle Cafe Stop Cafe in Juliette, Ga and had lunch. It was terrific. We had Peach Cobbler for desert and we could have gone back for more. I bought candy and soap in the Honeycomb Store and today I ordered some more. The soap is so nice you can smell it all over my house. The candy is awesome. Take time to see the movie. Be sure to visit the Whistle Stop Cafe in Juliette, Ga and to also stop in at the Honeycomb and what ever other stores are open. I love places like this that are still there for others to see. It makes the movie seem even more real.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This film is what movies should be about...!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vonschweissguth
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have viewed this marvelous film at least 2 dozen times. As with all great movies, you will always catch something "new" with each watching. If you want to be charmed, enchanted, moved, and find yourself wishing.... This is a film you will cherish. I won't belabor more than others have written so well. It is a film that resides in my permanent library on my top shelf. When I watch it again, I find myself wishing that I knew the characters personally and somehow find that I do. This film is one of the only that I esteem. It adds to your life. It hugs the heart and enriches who you are. I want to thank all the marvelous actors. If they ever wondered why they chose their profession, this film is why. 200 years from now it will be loved and valued. The test of time is guaranteed with Fried Green Tomatoes!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Overly Sentimental FIlm
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Supachewy
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/9/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The drama Fried Green Tomatoes is directed by Jon Avnet and stars Kathy Bates, Jessica Tandy, Mary Stuart Masterson, and Mary-Luise Parker. The film takes place in modern day Alabama with flashbacks from 1920 Alabama. The film starts off with a little girl in 1920s Alabama named Idgie Threadgood who does not want to be a part of her sister's wedding. After being talked to by her older brother she agrees to go to it and then afterward the two of them plus the girl the brother likes, Ruth (Parker) go on a walk around the area. When Ruth's hat flies off Idgie's brother goes and gets it for her but his foot ends up stuck in a train track and he is tragically killed. Idgie is extremely disturbed by her brother's death and is never the same again. This is all told from her sister Ninny Threadgood (Tandy) to Evelyn Couch (Bates). Couch is a middle aged woman who does not believe that she has any power or purpose and she met Ninny in a nursing home while visiting her husband's aunt. As the film goes on it develops the relationship between Idgie and Ruth and also Ninny and Evelyn and it is very sentimental... The script was written by Fannie Flagg who also wrote the book which the film is based on. Personally I thought the writing was weak for one main reason. That reason is that the film bounced between two different stories. The story with Idgie and Ruth was quite interesting but the story with Evelyn and Ninny was a complete bore that lacked depth. It was basically Evelyn just saying I have no purpose and then becoming a crazy woman that just tears apart her home and it is all supposedly because of Ninny's story. It is just not believable. It would have been better if it was more like Ninny just telling the story to Evelyn and Evelyn not having a story of her own. The first feature film for the big screen of Jon Avnet proved that he is a decent director. Avnet got solid performances by all his leads which is hard to do in a cast with four leads. The shots in the film were not really impressive and he did not really make me care much for any of the characters. I would have said that he did a poor job if he did not get the performances that he did, but then again it was only his first film even though he has not proved to be much of a director today in any way. The acting in this film was the best part of it. All four of the leads gave great performances. Even Kathy Bates, whose character I thought to be the weakest written still was able to bring a great performance out of it. Yet she is one of the greatest actresses who ever lived. Jessica Tandy even earned an Oscar nomination for her performance just because she was so great being an eccentric old lady. Parker and Masterson are sort of newcomers to the lead position and they really pulled it off as well. The acting made this film bearable. Overall I give this film a 5/10, I would have gave lower if it was not for the strong performances. I would recommend this to anyone who likes period pieces or films with strong female leads.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Story of friendship
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SnoopyStyle
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is based on a novel that takes place in Alabama. The modern story has timid housewife Evelyn Couch (Kathy Bates) who befriends an old woman Ninny Threadgoode (Jessica Tandy) at a retirement home. She recounts an old story from depression era. She tells the story of Idgie Threadgoode (Mary Stuart Masterson) and her friendship with Ruth Jamison (Mary-Louise Parker). Their lives are forever linked by the death of Idgie's brother who was Ruth's boyfriend. The modern story doesn't have quite the punch. The old time story exceeds it in almost every way. It may have been an important part of the novel, but I don't know if the modern story necessarily added anything to the movie. Both Marys are outstanding in their roles. Their characters are truly the center of this movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very very good writing,Wonderful movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Wadejohnson1970
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As a young man growing up in the Country of my home town of Hawkinsville Pulaski County Georgia, I had saw the movie in rental stores, however I was just never quite interested in watching a movie called Fried Green Tomatoes!!! However one night while watching TV with my family I was flicking through the Chanel's and came upon this very net resting movie that just so,happens to be..yes you guessed it...Fried Green Tomatoes!!! Well right here in the middle of my review I get a knock on my door, some guy tells me that he had just hit a little black dog out in front of my home, we live on a dirt road and people drive on it as if it were a damn Interstate Highway!!!! Sure enough it is my late fathers dog Buster!!! One of the last things my Daddy said was son look out for my dog!!! Now I feel really bad!!! He is not dead yet, he has his wits about him, just a bit loopy, but catching one of those full size Chevy Silverado's ain't good for a 4 pound dog!!! Anyway please pray for Buster!!!! Now back to the Movie review... As I began to watch this movie I just got more and more intertwined into the story!!! I couldn't tell who was more intrigued by Iggies story, me or Evelyne Couch. The story about Frank Bennett was so interesting!!! Heck there wasn't anything about the entire movie that Wasn't interesting!!!! The most interesting part of the entire movie was the fact that Frank Bennett's body was never found!!! And even more the reason WHY IT EAS NEVER FOUND!!!! Big George Put him on the grill and made BBQ out of him and they fed him to the guy from Georgia that was so stern to Iggies that he WAS THE LAW!!!! And you can't beat the law!!!! So to sum it up in a few words!!!! Fried Green Tomatoes is by far one of the best movies I ever saw, most important I. Was working with Georgia Power and happened upon this little Cafe out in Julliett Ga. And before I knew it I was sitting right in the middle of where one of my favorite movies was made..The Whistle Stop Cafe!!!!! You can't imagine my excitement and couldn't wait to tell my wife that I had sat and eat right there where the story played out!!! Now I'm gonna take my wife there to have some of those world famous FRIED GREEN TOMATOES!!!! And if you never watched this MASTERPIECE PLEASE DO!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Secret's in the Sauce
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    C_Hardrick
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Oscar winner Kathy Bates stars as Evelyn Couch, who one day while visiting her husbands ailing aunt in a nursing home, stumbles onto Mrs. Threadgoode, a resident of the same nursing home, played by Oscar winner Jessica Tandy. As Mrs. Threadgoode tells her story to Evelyn, we learn a vivid story of a young charismatic girl named Idgie spanning the years before World War One through the Depression. The film is set in the Deep South. Alabama to be exact in a small town called Whistle Stop. The film also stars a young Chris O'Donnell as Buddy Threadgoode, Idgie's brother. When Buddy is tragically killed in front of her eyes, Idgie sets out on a life to live to the fullest, even against her mother's wishes and the town preacher's wishes as well. As she grows, so does her relationship with family friend Ruth Jamison, played by Mary-Louise Parker. Eventually they become an inseparable duo, until Ruth marries Frank Bennett, played by Nick Searcy. Frank Bennett ends up being the plot point of the second half of Mrs. Threadgoode's story, and how Idgie may have or may not have killed him. We may not know what happened to Frank, however, "the secrets in the sauce."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brilliant sweet modern classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    misskellyvalente
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film was at times hysterical and at other times tugged at your heart strings. The film was based on a book. The film looked great and was well written and had wonderful actors portraying some great characters that you could really get attached to. I was a little disappointed that the film watered down the relationship of the two female characters. I realize that it would have never made it to main-stream America if the filmmakers hadn't. It was still very clear that there is a relationship in the film if you are paying attention for the simple little clues. Mary Stuart Masterson and Mary-Louise Parker did an amazing job capturing the chemistry between these two female characters. It's always amazing to watch Jessica Tandy act as she brings such heart to any character she portrays. Kathy Bates plays Evelyn and makes her so truthful and funny. The film is marketed as a feel good film and it does contain those moments, but it leans more toward drama side than the comedy side. Don't let anything stop you from watching this brilliant sweet modern classic. You'll be glad you did.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An authentic classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    robert-temple-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have just seen this wonderful film for the third time, after many years, and it is such a classic, and has not lost any of its interest or appeal. Indeed, it is more relevant now than it ever was, considering that it is about the plight of women and how they cope with their various life situations. It is based on a novel, and has a screenplay by, Fannie Flagg. It is set in Alabama where she comes from, and the story presumably has some basis in truth. Not many people know that Fannie Flagg used to be a brilliant comedienne. I knew her in the mid 1960s when she was a stand-up comic, and she was hilarious. She used to perform at a marvellous comedy cabaret night club in Manhattan, now long gone, which had two floors. The upstairs was called Upstairs at the Downstairs, and the downstairs was called Downstairs at the Upstairs. It was at 37 West 56th Street and was run by an amusing and eccentric woman whose name I have forgotten, alas. Fannie played there at the same time as Madeline ('Maddy') Kahn, who was also wildly funny. Fannie told me she had wanted to perform under her own real name of Patricia Neal, but was told by her agent or manager, I believe, that she could not do that because there was a famous film actress of that name already, so she invented the name Fannie Flagg for herself. It was only years later that she wrote this marvellous heart-felt novel, which was rejected by many publishers, but which finally came out and then resulted in this film. And it is this which really made Fannie Flag famous. The film was shot in Georgia, which is next door to Alabama. But the story is mostly set in Alabama in a little town called Whistle Stop. That name arose because it was a settlement situated beside the railroad. Many small Southern towns fell into desuetude (i.e. withered away) when the railroads started collapsing, after the construction of the interstate highway system, which shifted so much travel and freight transport onto roads and destroyed the rail industry, from the 1950s onwards. In this film which takes place at two different times, during the pre-War period which constitutes the earlier story, the two young women, Idgie and Ruth, open a railside caf&eacute; called The Whistle Stop Caf&eacute;. In those years, it thrived and became the heart of the town, where everyone went to eat real home cooking, which included the favourite local delicacy, fried green tomatoes, which were sliced and fried in batter in what in the South is called a skillet, which is an old 17th century English word for a frying pan, the word surviving only in the American South and nowhere else. (I still fry my eggs and bacon in an old iron family skillet which was cast in the family forge at Taunton, Massachusetts, in the 17th or 18th century. We have been using that skillet for many generations. Just imagine how many bacon fat molecules survive in the crystalline interstices of the cast iron after those centuries of use every morning. The outside of the skillet looks like something dug up by an archaeologist, but the inside is shiny and ready for anything. But this question arises: can bacon fat go rancid after a century or two? It does seem to improve the flavour anyway. However, I am ashamed to say that I have never fried any green tomatoes, which is doubtless a great personal failing of mine. The skillet has thus been deprived of what Ruth and Idgie would perhaps consider to be its main function, to deal with those green tomatoes.) Idgie, who is a hopeless cook, cannot prepare them, so Ruth has to do it. Throughout the film people keep tasting them to see if they are up to standard. The modern story of the film consists of tales told by an old lady in a retirement home to a much younger woman, and the effect this has on transforming her life. That younger woman is played by Kathy Bates, whose performance is breathtaking in its sensitivity and brilliance. But then, Kathy Bates has always been one of everybody's favourite and most endearing actresses, and we all know what a genius she is. The old woman is played equally brilliantly by the famous Jessica Tandy, veteran of a lifetime of superlative achievements in both stage and screen. Before TV wiped all the brains of the public as clean as a virgin hard disc, people used to tell stories, and there was such a thing as verbal communication. (And people didn't even have to use their thumbs to communicate, like today's simian-thumbed and simian-brained text messagers.) This film is all about the power of stories to stir the imagination and transform lives. Even as late as the 1960s, some old women still survived in the South who could tell stories for hours on end. They are all gone now, and it is like what happened after the time of Homer, when the last of the bards died. The best rendering in fiction of the 'power of stories' is probably the novella by Mircea Eliade entitled THE OLD MAN AND THE BUREAUCRATS. (Eliade wrote the story of Coppola's film YOUTH WITHOUT YOUTH, 2007, though that film was very disappointing and a poor adaptation.) The stories told by Jessica Tandy are about Idgie and Ruth. In those lengthy flashback sequences, the two young women are brilliantly portrayed by the two Mary's, Mary Stuart Masterson, and Mary-Louise Parker. Certainly this is one of the greatest 'sisterhood' films ever made. Their story is full of love, pain, pathos, loss, tragedy, and joy. Not unlike life. If you can see this without shedding a tear, then there is no hope for you. Good old Fannie, may she long keep flying her Flagg.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cannibalism And Gendercidal Hatred
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Louis B Maybe
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    OK, so here's why this film is the opposite of everything you've ever been told it is: It's not a wonderful feel-good movie for the girls, it's an ugly, violent fantasy in which justice is confused with revenge. Let's break it down: There are no primary male characters in this movie. Of the secondary and tertiary ones, it could be said that all the (white) males are evil or inadequate. Buddy is good, of course, but inadequate. His own foolishness destroys him. Buddy Junior is equally good but equally inadequate. Frank, on the other hand is just plain evil, and in between are more ambiguous male characters. The police chief is willing to help Idgie, it's true, but only because of his lecherous interest in her, and his mentality is thoroughly racist. Of the male characters, only Big George is unambiguously both good and adequate. But Big George is a black man. And black men are oppressed men. In effect, they are not men at all: exempt on political grounds from the critique levelled at white men, they are honorary women. This movie, couched in soft colours and sweet music, is one of the most casually misandric movies ever made. First of all, & most obviously, there is the EATING of her Evelyn's murdered husband. But it happens throughout the movie, as well, such as when Evelyn tells Frank "if I was going to kill you, I'd use my fists". She fantasizes about putting bombs in copies of Playboy and Hustler. "I'll take all the wife-beaters," she says, "and I'll machine gun their genitals!" "You didn't kill Ed, did you?" asks Ninny when Evelyn turns up late. "Not yet," answers Evelyn with a smile. The problem here is not that women will leave theatres and go on killing sprees. The problem is simply the convincing presentation of a cinematic world in which only women have a 'right' to be angry, in which all women are victims, & all men - all white men,anyway - are evil oppressors or inadequate burdens. To the extent that both women and men consciously or subconsciously adopt this worldview, the mutual hostility that now characterizes relations between the sexes will be exacerbated instead of questioned or healed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Interesting But Not Overpowering
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sddavis63 (revsdd@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watching the progression of the relationship between Idgie (Mary Stuart Masterson) and Ruth (Mary-Louise Parker) is fairly interesting. The story is a flashback; a story related by Ninny Threadgoode (Jessica Tandy) to Evelyn (Kathy Bates) who befriends Ninny in a local nursing home. So right off the top you can see that there's a pretty decent cast. Also almost from the start you realize that Ninny is a bit of an enigmatic character. Is she or is she not Idgie relating her own story? The movie seems to lead in that direction but never actually makes it explicit, so in the end it's left to the viewer to decide. Basically, this ends up as a murder mystery from the past. Ruth's abusive husband is murdered, and the question is who killed him. Idgie is put on trial for the crime, but the charges are dismissed. The mystery is held pretty well until the end of the movie. The movie begins with Idgie as a child, and with Ruth as her older brother Buddy's love interest. After Buddy's tragic death, Idgie and Ruth develop a very close friendship - the movie bobs and weaves around the issue of what the nature of their relationship was. Was it just a close friendship? Was it more? My feeling from the movie is that Idgie wanted more than a friendship; Ruth's interests were less clear. I haven't read the book, but I understand that the novel is quite clear in making the point that there was a lesbian romance between the two. Perhaps Hollywood in 1991 was still too nervous about such an issue to make it front and centre; ambiguity was as much as the studios could stomach apparently. We follow both of them through the ups and downs of life as they open a cafe together, whose menu specialty is - you guessed it - fried green tomatoes. Kathy Bates provided some comedy to the movie as the modern day housewife who goes through a rebirth after meeting Ninny - a rebirth that totally confuses her husband Ed (Gailard Sartain), who doesn't have a clue why Evelyn is changing so much and upsetting their comfortable existence. While she provided comedy, I wasn't really taken in by Bates' character in this. I thought the constant switching between present and past was overdone and not particularly well done to be honest; in a lot of ways the two parts of the stories didn't mesh that well. Aside from Bates, there were a lot of very likable characters from the past, such as Big George (Stan Shaw) and Smokey Lonesome (Timothy Scott.) The identity of Ruth's husband's killer in the end took me by surprise, so that was well done. My final reaction to this was that it was a basically well made and well acted movie, and at times even an interesting movie as the story unfolded - but that it also seemed like a movie that was anything but overpowering. It didn't leave me awestruck. (5/10)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fantastic Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lencad
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I think I have seen the movie at least 5 or more times. I love it. You see something each time you watch it that you missed the first time. My friend and I also went to the Whistle Cafe Stop Cafe in Juliette, Ga and had lunch. It was terrific. We had Peach Cobbler for desert and we could have gone back for more. I bought candy and soap in the Honeycomb Store and today I ordered some more. The soap is so nice you can smell it all over my house. The candy is awesome. Take time to see the movie. Be sure to visit the Whistle Stop Cafe in Juliette, Ga and to also stop in at the Honeycomb and what ever other stores are open. I love places like this that are still there for others to see. It makes the movie seem even more real.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This film is what movies should be about...!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vonschweissguth
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have viewed this marvelous film at least 2 dozen times. As with all great movies, you will always catch something "new" with each watching. If you want to be charmed, enchanted, moved, and find yourself wishing.... This is a film you will cherish. I won't belabor more than others have written so well. It is a film that resides in my permanent library on my top shelf. When I watch it again, I find myself wishing that I knew the characters personally and somehow find that I do. This film is one of the only that I esteem. It adds to your life. It hugs the heart and enriches who you are. I want to thank all the marvelous actors. If they ever wondered why they chose their profession, this film is why. 200 years from now it will be loved and valued. The test of time is guaranteed with Fried Green Tomatoes!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Overly Sentimental FIlm
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Supachewy
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/9/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The drama Fried Green Tomatoes is directed by Jon Avnet and stars Kathy Bates, Jessica Tandy, Mary Stuart Masterson, and Mary-Luise Parker. The film takes place in modern day Alabama with flashbacks from 1920 Alabama. The film starts off with a little girl in 1920s Alabama named Idgie Threadgood who does not want to be a part of her sister's wedding. After being talked to by her older brother she agrees to go to it and then afterward the two of them plus the girl the brother likes, Ruth (Parker) go on a walk around the area. When Ruth's hat flies off Idgie's brother goes and gets it for her but his foot ends up stuck in a train track and he is tragically killed. Idgie is extremely disturbed by her brother's death and is never the same again. This is all told from her sister Ninny Threadgood (Tandy) to Evelyn Couch (Bates). Couch is a middle aged woman who does not believe that she has any power or purpose and she met Ninny in a nursing home while visiting her husband's aunt. As the film goes on it develops the relationship between Idgie and Ruth and also Ninny and Evelyn and it is very sentimental... The script was written by Fannie Flagg who also wrote the book which the film is based on. Personally I thought the writing was weak for one main reason. That reason is that the film bounced between two different stories. The story with Idgie and Ruth was quite interesting but the story with Evelyn and Ninny was a complete bore that lacked depth. It was basically Evelyn just saying I have no purpose and then becoming a crazy woman that just tears apart her home and it is all supposedly because of Ninny's story. It is just not believable. It would have been better if it was more like Ninny just telling the story to Evelyn and Evelyn not having a story of her own. The first feature film for the big screen of Jon Avnet proved that he is a decent director. Avnet got solid performances by all his leads which is hard to do in a cast with four leads. The shots in the film were not really impressive and he did not really make me care much for any of the characters. I would have said that he did a poor job if he did not get the performances that he did, but then again it was only his first film even though he has not proved to be much of a director today in any way. The acting in this film was the best part of it. All four of the leads gave great performances. Even Kathy Bates, whose character I thought to be the weakest written still was able to bring a great performance out of it. Yet she is one of the greatest actresses who ever lived. Jessica Tandy even earned an Oscar nomination for her performance just because she was so great being an eccentric old lady. Parker and Masterson are sort of newcomers to the lead position and they really pulled it off as well. The acting made this film bearable. Overall I give this film a 5/10, I would have gave lower if it was not for the strong performances. I would recommend this to anyone who likes period pieces or films with strong female leads.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Story of friendship
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SnoopyStyle
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is based on a novel that takes place in Alabama. The modern story has timid housewife Evelyn Couch (Kathy Bates) who befriends an old woman Ninny Threadgoode (Jessica Tandy) at a retirement home. She recounts an old story from depression era. She tells the story of Idgie Threadgoode (Mary Stuart Masterson) and her friendship with Ruth Jamison (Mary-Louise Parker). Their lives are forever linked by the death of Idgie's brother who was Ruth's boyfriend. The modern story doesn't have quite the punch. The old time story exceeds it in almost every way. It may have been an important part of the novel, but I don't know if the modern story necessarily added anything to the movie. Both Marys are outstanding in their roles. Their characters are truly the center of this movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very very good writing,Wonderful movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Wadejohnson1970
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As a young man growing up in the Country of my home town of Hawkinsville Pulaski County Georgia, I had saw the movie in rental stores, however I was just never quite interested in watching a movie called Fried Green Tomatoes!!! However one night while watching TV with my family I was flicking through the Chanel's and came upon this very net resting movie that just so,happens to be..yes you guessed it...Fried Green Tomatoes!!! Well right here in the middle of my review I get a knock on my door, some guy tells me that he had just hit a little black dog out in front of my home, we live on a dirt road and people drive on it as if it were a damn Interstate Highway!!!! Sure enough it is my late fathers dog Buster!!! One of the last things my Daddy said was son look out for my dog!!! Now I feel really bad!!! He is not dead yet, he has his wits about him, just a bit loopy, but catching one of those full size Chevy Silverado's ain't good for a 4 pound dog!!! Anyway please pray for Buster!!!! Now back to the Movie review... As I began to watch this movie I just got more and more intertwined into the story!!! I couldn't tell who was more intrigued by Iggies story, me or Evelyne Couch. The story about Frank Bennett was so interesting!!! Heck there wasn't anything about the entire movie that Wasn't interesting!!!! The most interesting part of the entire movie was the fact that Frank Bennett's body was never found!!! And even more the reason WHY IT EAS NEVER FOUND!!!! Big George Put him on the grill and made BBQ out of him and they fed him to the guy from Georgia that was so stern to Iggies that he WAS THE LAW!!!! And you can't beat the law!!!! So to sum it up in a few words!!!! Fried Green Tomatoes is by far one of the best movies I ever saw, most important I. Was working with Georgia Power and happened upon this little Cafe out in Julliett Ga. And before I knew it I was sitting right in the middle of where one of my favorite movies was made..The Whistle Stop Cafe!!!!! You can't imagine my excitement and couldn't wait to tell my wife that I had sat and eat right there where the story played out!!! Now I'm gonna take my wife there to have some of those world famous FRIED GREEN TOMATOES!!!! And if you never watched this MASTERPIECE PLEASE DO!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Secret's in the Sauce
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    C_Hardrick
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Oscar winner Kathy Bates stars as Evelyn Couch, who one day while visiting her husbands ailing aunt in a nursing home, stumbles onto Mrs. Threadgoode, a resident of the same nursing home, played by Oscar winner Jessica Tandy. As Mrs. Threadgoode tells her story to Evelyn, we learn a vivid story of a young charismatic girl named Idgie spanning the years before World War One through the Depression. The film is set in the Deep South. Alabama to be exact in a small town called Whistle Stop. The film also stars a young Chris O'Donnell as Buddy Threadgoode, Idgie's brother. When Buddy is tragically killed in front of her eyes, Idgie sets out on a life to live to the fullest, even against her mother's wishes and the town preacher's wishes as well. As she grows, so does her relationship with family friend Ruth Jamison, played by Mary-Louise Parker. Eventually they become an inseparable duo, until Ruth marries Frank Bennett, played by Nick Searcy. Frank Bennett ends up being the plot point of the second half of Mrs. Threadgoode's story, and how Idgie may have or may not have killed him. We may not know what happened to Frank, however, "the secrets in the sauce."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brilliant sweet modern classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    misskellyvalente
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film was at times hysterical and at other times tugged at your heart strings. The film was based on a book. The film looked great and was well written and had wonderful actors portraying some great characters that you could really get attached to. I was a little disappointed that the film watered down the relationship of the two female characters. I realize that it would have never made it to main-stream America if the filmmakers hadn't. It was still very clear that there is a relationship in the film if you are paying attention for the simple little clues. Mary Stuart Masterson and Mary-Louise Parker did an amazing job capturing the chemistry between these two female characters. It's always amazing to watch Jessica Tandy act as she brings such heart to any character she portrays. Kathy Bates plays Evelyn and makes her so truthful and funny. The film is marketed as a feel good film and it does contain those moments, but it leans more toward drama side than the comedy side. Don't let anything stop you from watching this brilliant sweet modern classic. You'll be glad you did.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An authentic classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    robert-temple-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have just seen this wonderful film for the third time, after many years, and it is such a classic, and has not lost any of its interest or appeal. Indeed, it is more relevant now than it ever was, considering that it is about the plight of women and how they cope with their various life situations. It is based on a novel, and has a screenplay by, Fannie Flagg. It is set in Alabama where she comes from, and the story presumably has some basis in truth. Not many people know that Fannie Flagg used to be a brilliant comedienne. I knew her in the mid 1960s when she was a stand-up comic, and she was hilarious. She used to perform at a marvellous comedy cabaret night club in Manhattan, now long gone, which had two floors. The upstairs was called Upstairs at the Downstairs, and the downstairs was called Downstairs at the Upstairs. It was at 37 West 56th Street and was run by an amusing and eccentric woman whose name I have forgotten, alas. Fannie played there at the same time as Madeline ('Maddy') Kahn, who was also wildly funny. Fannie told me she had wanted to perform under her own real name of Patricia Neal, but was told by her agent or manager, I believe, that she could not do that because there was a famous film actress of that name already, so she invented the name Fannie Flagg for herself. It was only years later that she wrote this marvellous heart-felt novel, which was rejected by many publishers, but which finally came out and then resulted in this film. And it is this which really made Fannie Flag famous. The film was shot in Georgia, which is next door to Alabama. But the story is mostly set in Alabama in a little town called Whistle Stop. That name arose because it was a settlement situated beside the railroad. Many small Southern towns fell into desuetude (i.e. withered away) when the railroads started collapsing, after the construction of the interstate highway system, which shifted so much travel and freight transport onto roads and destroyed the rail industry, from the 1950s onwards. In this film which takes place at two different times, during the pre-War period which constitutes the earlier story, the two young women, Idgie and Ruth, open a railside caf&eacute; called The Whistle Stop Caf&eacute;. In those years, it thrived and became the heart of the town, where everyone went to eat real home cooking, which included the favourite local delicacy, fried green tomatoes, which were sliced and fried in batter in what in the South is called a skillet, which is an old 17th century English word for a frying pan, the word surviving only in the American South and nowhere else. (I still fry my eggs and bacon in an old iron family skillet which was cast in the family forge at Taunton, Massachusetts, in the 17th or 18th century. We have been using that skillet for many generations. Just imagine how many bacon fat molecules survive in the crystalline interstices of the cast iron after those centuries of use every morning. The outside of the skillet looks like something dug up by an archaeologist, but the inside is shiny and ready for anything. But this question arises: can bacon fat go rancid after a century or two? It does seem to improve the flavour anyway. However, I am ashamed to say that I have never fried any green tomatoes, which is doubtless a great personal failing of mine. The skillet has thus been deprived of what Ruth and Idgie would perhaps consider to be its main function, to deal with those green tomatoes.) Idgie, who is a hopeless cook, cannot prepare them, so Ruth has to do it. Throughout the film people keep tasting them to see if they are up to standard. The modern story of the film consists of tales told by an old lady in a retirement home to a much younger woman, and the effect this has on transforming her life. That younger woman is played by Kathy Bates, whose performance is breathtaking in its sensitivity and brilliance. But then, Kathy Bates has always been one of everybody's favourite and most endearing actresses, and we all know what a genius she is. The old woman is played equally brilliantly by the famous Jessica Tandy, veteran of a lifetime of superlative achievements in both stage and screen. Before TV wiped all the brains of the public as clean as a virgin hard disc, people used to tell stories, and there was such a thing as verbal communication. (And people didn't even have to use their thumbs to communicate, like today's simian-thumbed and simian-brained text messagers.) This film is all about the power of stories to stir the imagination and transform lives. Even as late as the 1960s, some old women still survived in the South who could tell stories for hours on end. They are all gone now, and it is like what happened after the time of Homer, when the last of the bards died. The best rendering in fiction of the 'power of stories' is probably the novella by Mircea Eliade entitled THE OLD MAN AND THE BUREAUCRATS. (Eliade wrote the story of Coppola's film YOUTH WITHOUT YOUTH, 2007, though that film was very disappointing and a poor adaptation.) The stories told by Jessica Tandy are about Idgie and Ruth. In those lengthy flashback sequences, the two young women are brilliantly portrayed by the two Mary's, Mary Stuart Masterson, and Mary-Louise Parker. Certainly this is one of the greatest 'sisterhood' films ever made. Their story is full of love, pain, pathos, loss, tragedy, and joy. Not unlike life. If you can see this without shedding a tear, then there is no hope for you. Good old Fannie, may she long keep flying her Flagg.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cannibalism And Gendercidal Hatred
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Louis B Maybe
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    OK, so here's why this film is the opposite of everything you've ever been told it is: It's not a wonderful feel-good movie for the girls, it's an ugly, violent fantasy in which justice is confused with revenge. Let's break it down: There are no primary male characters in this movie. Of the secondary and tertiary ones, it could be said that all the (white) males are evil or inadequate. Buddy is good, of course, but inadequate. His own foolishness destroys him. Buddy Junior is equally good but equally inadequate. Frank, on the other hand is just plain evil, and in between are more ambiguous male characters. The police chief is willing to help Idgie, it's true, but only because of his lecherous interest in her, and his mentality is thoroughly racist. Of the male characters, only Big George is unambiguously both good and adequate. But Big George is a black man. And black men are oppressed men. In effect, they are not men at all: exempt on political grounds from the critique levelled at white men, they are honorary women. This movie, couched in soft colours and sweet music, is one of the most casually misandric movies ever made. First of all, & most obviously, there is the EATING of her Evelyn's murdered husband. But it happens throughout the movie, as well, such as when Evelyn tells Frank "if I was going to kill you, I'd use my fists". She fantasizes about putting bombs in copies of Playboy and Hustler. "I'll take all the wife-beaters," she says, "and I'll machine gun their genitals!" "You didn't kill Ed, did you?" asks Ninny when Evelyn turns up late. "Not yet," answers Evelyn with a smile. The problem here is not that women will leave theatres and go on killing sprees. The problem is simply the convincing presentation of a cinematic world in which only women have a 'right' to be angry, in which all women are victims, & all men - all white men,anyway - are evil oppressors or inadequate burdens. To the extent that both women and men consciously or subconsciously adopt this worldview, the mutual hostility that now characterizes relations between the sexes will be exacerbated instead of questioned or healed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Interesting But Not Overpowering
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sddavis63 (revsdd@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watching the progression of the relationship between Idgie (Mary Stuart Masterson) and Ruth (Mary-Louise Parker) is fairly interesting. The story is a flashback; a story related by Ninny Threadgoode (Jessica Tandy) to Evelyn (Kathy Bates) who befriends Ninny in a local nursing home. So right off the top you can see that there's a pretty decent cast. Also almost from the start you realize that Ninny is a bit of an enigmatic character. Is she or is she not Idgie relating her own story? The movie seems to lead in that direction but never actually makes it explicit, so in the end it's left to the viewer to decide. Basically, this ends up as a murder mystery from the past. Ruth's abusive husband is murdered, and the question is who killed him. Idgie is put on trial for the crime, but the charges are dismissed. The mystery is held pretty well until the end of the movie. The movie begins with Idgie as a child, and with Ruth as her older brother Buddy's love interest. After Buddy's tragic death, Idgie and Ruth develop a very close friendship - the movie bobs and weaves around the issue of what the nature of their relationship was. Was it just a close friendship? Was it more? My feeling from the movie is that Idgie wanted more than a friendship; Ruth's interests were less clear. I haven't read the book, but I understand that the novel is quite clear in making the point that there was a lesbian romance between the two. Perhaps Hollywood in 1991 was still too nervous about such an issue to make it front and centre; ambiguity was as much as the studios could stomach apparently. We follow both of them through the ups and downs of life as they open a cafe together, whose menu specialty is - you guessed it - fried green tomatoes. Kathy Bates provided some comedy to the movie as the modern day housewife who goes through a rebirth after meeting Ninny - a rebirth that totally confuses her husband Ed (Gailard Sartain), who doesn't have a clue why Evelyn is changing so much and upsetting their comfortable existence. While she provided comedy, I wasn't really taken in by Bates' character in this. I thought the constant switching between present and past was overdone and not particularly well done to be honest; in a lot of ways the two parts of the stories didn't mesh that well. Aside from Bates, there were a lot of very likable characters from the past, such as Big George (Stan Shaw) and Smokey Lonesome (Timothy Scott.) The identity of Ruth's husband's killer in the end took me by surprise, so that was well done. My final reaction to this was that it was a basically well made and well acted movie, and at times even an interesting movie as the story unfolded - but that it also seemed like a movie that was anything but overpowering. It didn't leave me awestruck. (5/10)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fantastic Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lencad
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I think I have seen the movie at least 5 or more times. I love it. You see something each time you watch it that you missed the first time. My friend and I also went to the Whistle Cafe Stop Cafe in Juliette, Ga and had lunch. It was terrific. We had Peach Cobbler for desert and we could have gone back for more. I bought candy and soap in the Honeycomb Store and today I ordered some more. The soap is so nice you can smell it all over my house. The candy is awesome. Take time to see the movie. Be sure to visit the Whistle Stop Cafe in Juliette, Ga and to also stop in at the Honeycomb and what ever other stores are open. I love places like this that are still there for others to see. It makes the movie seem even more real.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This film is what movies should be about...!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vonschweissguth
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have viewed this marvelous film at least 2 dozen times. As with all great movies, you will always catch something "new" with each watching. If you want to be charmed, enchanted, moved, and find yourself wishing.... This is a film you will cherish. I won't belabor more than others have written so well. It is a film that resides in my permanent library on my top shelf. When I watch it again, I find myself wishing that I knew the characters personally and somehow find that I do. This film is one of the only that I esteem. It adds to your life. It hugs the heart and enriches who you are. I want to thank all the marvelous actors. If they ever wondered why they chose their profession, this film is why. 200 years from now it will be loved and valued. The test of time is guaranteed with Fried Green Tomatoes!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Overly Sentimental FIlm
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Supachewy
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/9/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The drama Fried Green Tomatoes is directed by Jon Avnet and stars Kathy Bates, Jessica Tandy, Mary Stuart Masterson, and Mary-Luise Parker. The film takes place in modern day Alabama with flashbacks from 1920 Alabama. The film starts off with a little girl in 1920s Alabama named Idgie Threadgood who does not want to be a part of her sister's wedding. After being talked to by her older brother she agrees to go to it and then afterward the two of them plus the girl the brother likes, Ruth (Parker) go on a walk around the area. When Ruth's hat flies off Idgie's brother goes and gets it for her but his foot ends up stuck in a train track and he is tragically killed. Idgie is extremely disturbed by her brother's death and is never the same again. This is all told from her sister Ninny Threadgood (Tandy) to Evelyn Couch (Bates). Couch is a middle aged woman who does not believe that she has any power or purpose and she met Ninny in a nursing home while visiting her husband's aunt. As the film goes on it develops the relationship between Idgie and Ruth and also Ninny and Evelyn and it is very sentimental... The script was written by Fannie Flagg who also wrote the book which the film is based on. Personally I thought the writing was weak for one main reason. That reason is that the film bounced between two different stories. The story with Idgie and Ruth was quite interesting but the story with Evelyn and Ninny was a complete bore that lacked depth. It was basically Evelyn just saying I have no purpose and then becoming a crazy woman that just tears apart her home and it is all supposedly because of Ninny's story. It is just not believable. It would have been better if it was more like Ninny just telling the story to Evelyn and Evelyn not having a story of her own. The first feature film for the big screen of Jon Avnet proved that he is a decent director. Avnet got solid performances by all his leads which is hard to do in a cast with four leads. The shots in the film were not really impressive and he did not really make me care much for any of the characters. I would have said that he did a poor job if he did not get the performances that he did, but then again it was only his first film even though he has not proved to be much of a director today in any way. The acting in this film was the best part of it. All four of the leads gave great performances. Even Kathy Bates, whose character I thought to be the weakest written still was able to bring a great performance out of it. Yet she is one of the greatest actresses who ever lived. Jessica Tandy even earned an Oscar nomination for her performance just because she was so great being an eccentric old lady. Parker and Masterson are sort of newcomers to the lead position and they really pulled it off as well. The acting made this film bearable. Overall I give this film a 5/10, I would have gave lower if it was not for the strong performances. I would recommend this to anyone who likes period pieces or films with strong female leads.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Story of friendship
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SnoopyStyle
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is based on a novel that takes place in Alabama. The modern story has timid housewife Evelyn Couch (Kathy Bates) who befriends an old woman Ninny Threadgoode (Jessica Tandy) at a retirement home. She recounts an old story from depression era. She tells the story of Idgie Threadgoode (Mary Stuart Masterson) and her friendship with Ruth Jamison (Mary-Louise Parker). Their lives are forever linked by the death of Idgie's brother who was Ruth's boyfriend. The modern story doesn't have quite the punch. The old time story exceeds it in almost every way. It may have been an important part of the novel, but I don't know if the modern story necessarily added anything to the movie. Both Marys are outstanding in their roles. Their characters are truly the center of this movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very very good writing,Wonderful movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Wadejohnson1970
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As a young man growing up in the Country of my home town of Hawkinsville Pulaski County Georgia, I had saw the movie in rental stores, however I was just never quite interested in watching a movie called Fried Green Tomatoes!!! However one night while watching TV with my family I was flicking through the Chanel's and came upon this very net resting movie that just so,happens to be..yes you guessed it...Fried Green Tomatoes!!! Well right here in the middle of my review I get a knock on my door, some guy tells me that he had just hit a little black dog out in front of my home, we live on a dirt road and people drive on it as if it were a damn Interstate Highway!!!! Sure enough it is my late fathers dog Buster!!! One of the last things my Daddy said was son look out for my dog!!! Now I feel really bad!!! He is not dead yet, he has his wits about him, just a bit loopy, but catching one of those full size Chevy Silverado's ain't good for a 4 pound dog!!! Anyway please pray for Buster!!!! Now back to the Movie review... As I began to watch this movie I just got more and more intertwined into the story!!! I couldn't tell who was more intrigued by Iggies story, me or Evelyne Couch. The story about Frank Bennett was so interesting!!! Heck there wasn't anything about the entire movie that Wasn't interesting!!!! The most interesting part of the entire movie was the fact that Frank Bennett's body was never found!!! And even more the reason WHY IT EAS NEVER FOUND!!!! Big George Put him on the grill and made BBQ out of him and they fed him to the guy from Georgia that was so stern to Iggies that he WAS THE LAW!!!! And you can't beat the law!!!! So to sum it up in a few words!!!! Fried Green Tomatoes is by far one of the best movies I ever saw, most important I. Was working with Georgia Power and happened upon this little Cafe out in Julliett Ga. And before I knew it I was sitting right in the middle of where one of my favorite movies was made..The Whistle Stop Cafe!!!!! You can't imagine my excitement and couldn't wait to tell my wife that I had sat and eat right there where the story played out!!! Now I'm gonna take my wife there to have some of those world famous FRIED GREEN TOMATOES!!!! And if you never watched this MASTERPIECE PLEASE DO!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Secret's in the Sauce
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    C_Hardrick
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Oscar winner Kathy Bates stars as Evelyn Couch, who one day while visiting her husbands ailing aunt in a nursing home, stumbles onto Mrs. Threadgoode, a resident of the same nursing home, played by Oscar winner Jessica Tandy. As Mrs. Threadgoode tells her story to Evelyn, we learn a vivid story of a young charismatic girl named Idgie spanning the years before World War One through the Depression. The film is set in the Deep South. Alabama to be exact in a small town called Whistle Stop. The film also stars a young Chris O'Donnell as Buddy Threadgoode, Idgie's brother. When Buddy is tragically killed in front of her eyes, Idgie sets out on a life to live to the fullest, even against her mother's wishes and the town preacher's wishes as well. As she grows, so does her relationship with family friend Ruth Jamison, played by Mary-Louise Parker. Eventually they become an inseparable duo, until Ruth marries Frank Bennett, played by Nick Searcy. Frank Bennett ends up being the plot point of the second half of Mrs. Threadgoode's story, and how Idgie may have or may not have killed him. We may not know what happened to Frank, however, "the secrets in the sauce."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brilliant sweet modern classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    misskellyvalente
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film was at times hysterical and at other times tugged at your heart strings. The film was based on a book. The film looked great and was well written and had wonderful actors portraying some great characters that you could really get attached to. I was a little disappointed that the film watered down the relationship of the two female characters. I realize that it would have never made it to main-stream America if the filmmakers hadn't. It was still very clear that there is a relationship in the film if you are paying attention for the simple little clues. Mary Stuart Masterson and Mary-Louise Parker did an amazing job capturing the chemistry between these two female characters. It's always amazing to watch Jessica Tandy act as she brings such heart to any character she portrays. Kathy Bates plays Evelyn and makes her so truthful and funny. The film is marketed as a feel good film and it does contain those moments, but it leans more toward drama side than the comedy side. Don't let anything stop you from watching this brilliant sweet modern classic. You'll be glad you did.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An authentic classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    robert-temple-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have just seen this wonderful film for the third time, after many years, and it is such a classic, and has not lost any of its interest or appeal. Indeed, it is more relevant now than it ever was, considering that it is about the plight of women and how they cope with their various life situations. It is based on a novel, and has a screenplay by, Fannie Flagg. It is set in Alabama where she comes from, and the story presumably has some basis in truth. Not many people know that Fannie Flagg used to be a brilliant comedienne. I knew her in the mid 1960s when she was a stand-up comic, and she was hilarious. She used to perform at a marvellous comedy cabaret night club in Manhattan, now long gone, which had two floors. The upstairs was called Upstairs at the Downstairs, and the downstairs was called Downstairs at the Upstairs. It was at 37 West 56th Street and was run by an amusing and eccentric woman whose name I have forgotten, alas. Fannie played there at the same time as Madeline ('Maddy') Kahn, who was also wildly funny. Fannie told me she had wanted to perform under her own real name of Patricia Neal, but was told by her agent or manager, I believe, that she could not do that because there was a famous film actress of that name already, so she invented the name Fannie Flagg for herself. It was only years later that she wrote this marvellous heart-felt novel, which was rejected by many publishers, but which finally came out and then resulted in this film. And it is this which really made Fannie Flag famous. The film was shot in Georgia, which is next door to Alabama. But the story is mostly set in Alabama in a little town called Whistle Stop. That name arose because it was a settlement situated beside the railroad. Many small Southern towns fell into desuetude (i.e. withered away) when the railroads started collapsing, after the construction of the interstate highway system, which shifted so much travel and freight transport onto roads and destroyed the rail industry, from the 1950s onwards. In this film which takes place at two different times, during the pre-War period which constitutes the earlier story, the two young women, Idgie and Ruth, open a railside caf&eacute; called The Whistle Stop Caf&eacute;. In those years, it thrived and became the heart of the town, where everyone went to eat real home cooking, which included the favourite local delicacy, fried green tomatoes, which were sliced and fried in batter in what in the South is called a skillet, which is an old 17th century English word for a frying pan, the word surviving only in the American South and nowhere else. (I still fry my eggs and bacon in an old iron family skillet which was cast in the family forge at Taunton, Massachusetts, in the 17th or 18th century. We have been using that skillet for many generations. Just imagine how many bacon fat molecules survive in the crystalline interstices of the cast iron after those centuries of use every morning. The outside of the skillet looks like something dug up by an archaeologist, but the inside is shiny and ready for anything. But this question arises: can bacon fat go rancid after a century or two? It does seem to improve the flavour anyway. However, I am ashamed to say that I have never fried any green tomatoes, which is doubtless a great personal failing of mine. The skillet has thus been deprived of what Ruth and Idgie would perhaps consider to be its main function, to deal with those green tomatoes.) Idgie, who is a hopeless cook, cannot prepare them, so Ruth has to do it. Throughout the film people keep tasting them to see if they are up to standard. The modern story of the film consists of tales told by an old lady in a retirement home to a much younger woman, and the effect this has on transforming her life. That younger woman is played by Kathy Bates, whose performance is breathtaking in its sensitivity and brilliance. But then, Kathy Bates has always been one of everybody's favourite and most endearing actresses, and we all know what a genius she is. The old woman is played equally brilliantly by the famous Jessica Tandy, veteran of a lifetime of superlative achievements in both stage and screen. Before TV wiped all the brains of the public as clean as a virgin hard disc, people used to tell stories, and there was such a thing as verbal communication. (And people didn't even have to use their thumbs to communicate, like today's simian-thumbed and simian-brained text messagers.) This film is all about the power of stories to stir the imagination and transform lives. Even as late as the 1960s, some old women still survived in the South who could tell stories for hours on end. They are all gone now, and it is like what happened after the time of Homer, when the last of the bards died. The best rendering in fiction of the 'power of stories' is probably the novella by Mircea Eliade entitled THE OLD MAN AND THE BUREAUCRATS. (Eliade wrote the story of Coppola's film YOUTH WITHOUT YOUTH, 2007, though that film was very disappointing and a poor adaptation.) The stories told by Jessica Tandy are about Idgie and Ruth. In those lengthy flashback sequences, the two young women are brilliantly portrayed by the two Mary's, Mary Stuart Masterson, and Mary-Louise Parker. Certainly this is one of the greatest 'sisterhood' films ever made. Their story is full of love, pain, pathos, loss, tragedy, and joy. Not unlike life. If you can see this without shedding a tear, then there is no hope for you. Good old Fannie, may she long keep flying her Flagg.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cannibalism And Gendercidal Hatred
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Louis B Maybe
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    OK, so here's why this film is the opposite of everything you've ever been told it is: It's not a wonderful feel-good movie for the girls, it's an ugly, violent fantasy in which justice is confused with revenge. Let's break it down: There are no primary male characters in this movie. Of the secondary and tertiary ones, it could be said that all the (white) males are evil or inadequate. Buddy is good, of course, but inadequate. His own foolishness destroys him. Buddy Junior is equally good but equally inadequate. Frank, on the other hand is just plain evil, and in between are more ambiguous male characters. The police chief is willing to help Idgie, it's true, but only because of his lecherous interest in her, and his mentality is thoroughly racist. Of the male characters, only Big George is unambiguously both good and adequate. But Big George is a black man. And black men are oppressed men. In effect, they are not men at all: exempt on political grounds from the critique levelled at white men, they are honorary women. This movie, couched in soft colours and sweet music, is one of the most casually misandric movies ever made. First of all, & most obviously, there is the EATING of her Evelyn's murdered husband. But it happens throughout the movie, as well, such as when Evelyn tells Frank "if I was going to kill you, I'd use my fists". She fantasizes about putting bombs in copies of Playboy and Hustler. "I'll take all the wife-beaters," she says, "and I'll machine gun their genitals!" "You didn't kill Ed, did you?" asks Ninny when Evelyn turns up late. "Not yet," answers Evelyn with a smile. The problem here is not that women will leave theatres and go on killing sprees. The problem is simply the convincing presentation of a cinematic world in which only women have a 'right' to be angry, in which all women are victims, & all men - all white men,anyway - are evil oppressors or inadequate burdens. To the extent that both women and men consciously or subconsciously adopt this worldview, the mutual hostility that now characterizes relations between the sexes will be exacerbated instead of questioned or healed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Interesting But Not Overpowering
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sddavis63 (revsdd@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watching the progression of the relationship between Idgie (Mary Stuart Masterson) and Ruth (Mary-Louise Parker) is fairly interesting. The story is a flashback; a story related by Ninny Threadgoode (Jessica Tandy) to Evelyn (Kathy Bates) who befriends Ninny in a local nursing home. So right off the top you can see that there's a pretty decent cast. Also almost from the start you realize that Ninny is a bit of an enigmatic character. Is she or is she not Idgie relating her own story? The movie seems to lead in that direction but never actually makes it explicit, so in the end it's left to the viewer to decide. Basically, this ends up as a murder mystery from the past. Ruth's abusive husband is murdered, and the question is who killed him. Idgie is put on trial for the crime, but the charges are dismissed. The mystery is held pretty well until the end of the movie. The movie begins with Idgie as a child, and with Ruth as her older brother Buddy's love interest. After Buddy's tragic death, Idgie and Ruth develop a very close friendship - the movie bobs and weaves around the issue of what the nature of their relationship was. Was it just a close friendship? Was it more? My feeling from the movie is that Idgie wanted more than a friendship; Ruth's interests were less clear. I haven't read the book, but I understand that the novel is quite clear in making the point that there was a lesbian romance between the two. Perhaps Hollywood in 1991 was still too nervous about such an issue to make it front and centre; ambiguity was as much as the studios could stomach apparently. We follow both of them through the ups and downs of life as they open a cafe together, whose menu specialty is - you guessed it - fried green tomatoes. Kathy Bates provided some comedy to the movie as the modern day housewife who goes through a rebirth after meeting Ninny - a rebirth that totally confuses her husband Ed (Gailard Sartain), who doesn't have a clue why Evelyn is changing so much and upsetting their comfortable existence. While she provided comedy, I wasn't really taken in by Bates' character in this. I thought the constant switching between present and past was overdone and not particularly well done to be honest; in a lot of ways the two parts of the stories didn't mesh that well. Aside from Bates, there were a lot of very likable characters from the past, such as Big George (Stan Shaw) and Smokey Lonesome (Timothy Scott.) The identity of Ruth's husband's killer in the end took me by surprise, so that was well done. My final reaction to this was that it was a basically well made and well acted movie, and at times even an interesting movie as the story unfolded - but that it also seemed like a movie that was anything but overpowering. It didn't leave me awestruck. (5/10)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fantastic Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lencad
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I think I have seen the movie at least 5 or more times. I love it. You see something each time you watch it that you missed the first time. My friend and I also went to the Whistle Cafe Stop Cafe in Juliette, Ga and had lunch. It was terrific. We had Peach Cobbler for desert and we could have gone back for more. I bought candy and soap in the Honeycomb Store and today I ordered some more. The soap is so nice you can smell it all over my house. The candy is awesome. Take time to see the movie. Be sure to visit the Whistle Stop Cafe in Juliette, Ga and to also stop in at the Honeycomb and what ever other stores are open. I love places like this that are still there for others to see. It makes the movie seem even more real.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This film is what movies should be about...!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vonschweissguth
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have viewed this marvelous film at least 2 dozen times. As with all great movies, you will always catch something "new" with each watching. If you want to be charmed, enchanted, moved, and find yourself wishing.... This is a film you will cherish. I won't belabor more than others have written so well. It is a film that resides in my permanent library on my top shelf. When I watch it again, I find myself wishing that I knew the characters personally and somehow find that I do. This film is one of the only that I esteem. It adds to your life. It hugs the heart and enriches who you are. I want to thank all the marvelous actors. If they ever wondered why they chose their profession, this film is why. 200 years from now it will be loved and valued. The test of time is guaranteed with Fried Green Tomatoes!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Overly Sentimental FIlm
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Supachewy
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/9/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The drama Fried Green Tomatoes is directed by Jon Avnet and stars Kathy Bates, Jessica Tandy, Mary Stuart Masterson, and Mary-Luise Parker. The film takes place in modern day Alabama with flashbacks from 1920 Alabama. The film starts off with a little girl in 1920s Alabama named Idgie Threadgood who does not want to be a part of her sister's wedding. After being talked to by her older brother she agrees to go to it and then afterward the two of them plus the girl the brother likes, Ruth (Parker) go on a walk around the area. When Ruth's hat flies off Idgie's brother goes and gets it for her but his foot ends up stuck in a train track and he is tragically killed. Idgie is extremely disturbed by her brother's death and is never the same again. This is all told from her sister Ninny Threadgood (Tandy) to Evelyn Couch (Bates). Couch is a middle aged woman who does not believe that she has any power or purpose and she met Ninny in a nursing home while visiting her husband's aunt. As the film goes on it develops the relationship between Idgie and Ruth and also Ninny and Evelyn and it is very sentimental... The script was written by Fannie Flagg who also wrote the book which the film is based on. Personally I thought the writing was weak for one main reason. That reason is that the film bounced between two different stories. The story with Idgie and Ruth was quite interesting but the story with Evelyn and Ninny was a complete bore that lacked depth. It was basically Evelyn just saying I have no purpose and then becoming a crazy woman that just tears apart her home and it is all supposedly because of Ninny's story. It is just not believable. It would have been better if it was more like Ninny just telling the story to Evelyn and Evelyn not having a story of her own. The first feature film for the big screen of Jon Avnet proved that he is a decent director. Avnet got solid performances by all his leads which is hard to do in a cast with four leads. The shots in the film were not really impressive and he did not really make me care much for any of the characters. I would have said that he did a poor job if he did not get the performances that he did, but then again it was only his first film even though he has not proved to be much of a director today in any way. The acting in this film was the best part of it. All four of the leads gave great performances. Even Kathy Bates, whose character I thought to be the weakest written still was able to bring a great performance out of it. Yet she is one of the greatest actresses who ever lived. Jessica Tandy even earned an Oscar nomination for her performance just because she was so great being an eccentric old lady. Parker and Masterson are sort of newcomers to the lead position and they really pulled it off as well. The acting made this film bearable. Overall I give this film a 5/10, I would have gave lower if it was not for the strong performances. I would recommend this to anyone who likes period pieces or films with strong female leads.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Story of friendship
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SnoopyStyle
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is based on a novel that takes place in Alabama. The modern story has timid housewife Evelyn Couch (Kathy Bates) who befriends an old woman Ninny Threadgoode (Jessica Tandy) at a retirement home. She recounts an old story from depression era. She tells the story of Idgie Threadgoode (Mary Stuart Masterson) and her friendship with Ruth Jamison (Mary-Louise Parker). Their lives are forever linked by the death of Idgie's brother who was Ruth's boyfriend. The modern story doesn't have quite the punch. The old time story exceeds it in almost every way. It may have been an important part of the novel, but I don't know if the modern story necessarily added anything to the movie. Both Marys are outstanding in their roles. Their characters are truly the center of this movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very very good writing,Wonderful movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Wadejohnson1970
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As a young man growing up in the Country of my home town of Hawkinsville Pulaski County Georgia, I had saw the movie in rental stores, however I was just never quite interested in watching a movie called Fried Green Tomatoes!!! However one night while watching TV with my family I was flicking through the Chanel's and came upon this very net resting movie that just so,happens to be..yes you guessed it...Fried Green Tomatoes!!! Well right here in the middle of my review I get a knock on my door, some guy tells me that he had just hit a little black dog out in front of my home, we live on a dirt road and people drive on it as if it were a damn Interstate Highway!!!! Sure enough it is my late fathers dog Buster!!! One of the last things my Daddy said was son look out for my dog!!! Now I feel really bad!!! He is not dead yet, he has his wits about him, just a bit loopy, but catching one of those full size Chevy Silverado's ain't good for a 4 pound dog!!! Anyway please pray for Buster!!!! Now back to the Movie review... As I began to watch this movie I just got more and more intertwined into the story!!! I couldn't tell who was more intrigued by Iggies story, me or Evelyne Couch. The story about Frank Bennett was so interesting!!! Heck there wasn't anything about the entire movie that Wasn't interesting!!!! The most interesting part of the entire movie was the fact that Frank Bennett's body was never found!!! And even more the reason WHY IT EAS NEVER FOUND!!!! Big George Put him on the grill and made BBQ out of him and they fed him to the guy from Georgia that was so stern to Iggies that he WAS THE LAW!!!! And you can't beat the law!!!! So to sum it up in a few words!!!! Fried Green Tomatoes is by far one of the best movies I ever saw, most important I. Was working with Georgia Power and happened upon this little Cafe out in Julliett Ga. And before I knew it I was sitting right in the middle of where one of my favorite movies was made..The Whistle Stop Cafe!!!!! You can't imagine my excitement and couldn't wait to tell my wife that I had sat and eat right there where the story played out!!! Now I'm gonna take my wife there to have some of those world famous FRIED GREEN TOMATOES!!!! And if you never watched this MASTERPIECE PLEASE DO!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Secret's in the Sauce
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    C_Hardrick
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Oscar winner Kathy Bates stars as Evelyn Couch, who one day while visiting her husbands ailing aunt in a nursing home, stumbles onto Mrs. Threadgoode, a resident of the same nursing home, played by Oscar winner Jessica Tandy. As Mrs. Threadgoode tells her story to Evelyn, we learn a vivid story of a young charismatic girl named Idgie spanning the years before World War One through the Depression. The film is set in the Deep South. Alabama to be exact in a small town called Whistle Stop. The film also stars a young Chris O'Donnell as Buddy Threadgoode, Idgie's brother. When Buddy is tragically killed in front of her eyes, Idgie sets out on a life to live to the fullest, even against her mother's wishes and the town preacher's wishes as well. As she grows, so does her relationship with family friend Ruth Jamison, played by Mary-Louise Parker. Eventually they become an inseparable duo, until Ruth marries Frank Bennett, played by Nick Searcy. Frank Bennett ends up being the plot point of the second half of Mrs. Threadgoode's story, and how Idgie may have or may not have killed him. We may not know what happened to Frank, however, "the secrets in the sauce."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brilliant sweet modern classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    misskellyvalente
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film was at times hysterical and at other times tugged at your heart strings. The film was based on a book. The film looked great and was well written and had wonderful actors portraying some great characters that you could really get attached to. I was a little disappointed that the film watered down the relationship of the two female characters. I realize that it would have never made it to main-stream America if the filmmakers hadn't. It was still very clear that there is a relationship in the film if you are paying attention for the simple little clues. Mary Stuart Masterson and Mary-Louise Parker did an amazing job capturing the chemistry between these two female characters. It's always amazing to watch Jessica Tandy act as she brings such heart to any character she portrays. Kathy Bates plays Evelyn and makes her so truthful and funny. The film is marketed as a feel good film and it does contain those moments, but it leans more toward drama side than the comedy side. Don't let anything stop you from watching this brilliant sweet modern classic. You'll be glad you did.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An authentic classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    robert-temple-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have just seen this wonderful film for the third time, after many years, and it is such a classic, and has not lost any of its interest or appeal. Indeed, it is more relevant now than it ever was, considering that it is about the plight of women and how they cope with their various life situations. It is based on a novel, and has a screenplay by, Fannie Flagg. It is set in Alabama where she comes from, and the story presumably has some basis in truth. Not many people know that Fannie Flagg used to be a brilliant comedienne. I knew her in the mid 1960s when she was a stand-up comic, and she was hilarious. She used to perform at a marvellous comedy cabaret night club in Manhattan, now long gone, which had two floors. The upstairs was called Upstairs at the Downstairs, and the downstairs was called Downstairs at the Upstairs. It was at 37 West 56th Street and was run by an amusing and eccentric woman whose name I have forgotten, alas. Fannie played there at the same time as Madeline ('Maddy') Kahn, who was also wildly funny. Fannie told me she had wanted to perform under her own real name of Patricia Neal, but was told by her agent or manager, I believe, that she could not do that because there was a famous film actress of that name already, so she invented the name Fannie Flagg for herself. It was only years later that she wrote this marvellous heart-felt novel, which was rejected by many publishers, but which finally came out and then resulted in this film. And it is this which really made Fannie Flag famous. The film was shot in Georgia, which is next door to Alabama. But the story is mostly set in Alabama in a little town called Whistle Stop. That name arose because it was a settlement situated beside the railroad. Many small Southern towns fell into desuetude (i.e. withered away) when the railroads started collapsing, after the construction of the interstate highway system, which shifted so much travel and freight transport onto roads and destroyed the rail industry, from the 1950s onwards. In this film which takes place at two different times, during the pre-War period which constitutes the earlier story, the two young women, Idgie and Ruth, open a railside caf&eacute; called The Whistle Stop Caf&eacute;. In those years, it thrived and became the heart of the town, where everyone went to eat real home cooking, which included the favourite local delicacy, fried green tomatoes, which were sliced and fried in batter in what in the South is called a skillet, which is an old 17th century English word for a frying pan, the word surviving only in the American South and nowhere else. (I still fry my eggs and bacon in an old iron family skillet which was cast in the family forge at Taunton, Massachusetts, in the 17th or 18th century. We have been using that skillet for many generations. Just imagine how many bacon fat molecules survive in the crystalline interstices of the cast iron after those centuries of use every morning. The outside of the skillet looks like something dug up by an archaeologist, but the inside is shiny and ready for anything. But this question arises: can bacon fat go rancid after a century or two? It does seem to improve the flavour anyway. However, I am ashamed to say that I have never fried any green tomatoes, which is doubtless a great personal failing of mine. The skillet has thus been deprived of what Ruth and Idgie would perhaps consider to be its main function, to deal with those green tomatoes.) Idgie, who is a hopeless cook, cannot prepare them, so Ruth has to do it. Throughout the film people keep tasting them to see if they are up to standard. The modern story of the film consists of tales told by an old lady in a retirement home to a much younger woman, and the effect this has on transforming her life. That younger woman is played by Kathy Bates, whose performance is breathtaking in its sensitivity and brilliance. But then, Kathy Bates has always been one of everybody's favourite and most endearing actresses, and we all know what a genius she is. The old woman is played equally brilliantly by the famous Jessica Tandy, veteran of a lifetime of superlative achievements in both stage and screen. Before TV wiped all the brains of the public as clean as a virgin hard disc, people used to tell stories, and there was such a thing as verbal communication. (And people didn't even have to use their thumbs to communicate, like today's simian-thumbed and simian-brained text messagers.) This film is all about the power of stories to stir the imagination and transform lives. Even as late as the 1960s, some old women still survived in the South who could tell stories for hours on end. They are all gone now, and it is like what happened after the time of Homer, when the last of the bards died. The best rendering in fiction of the 'power of stories' is probably the novella by Mircea Eliade entitled THE OLD MAN AND THE BUREAUCRATS. (Eliade wrote the story of Coppola's film YOUTH WITHOUT YOUTH, 2007, though that film was very disappointing and a poor adaptation.) The stories told by Jessica Tandy are about Idgie and Ruth. In those lengthy flashback sequences, the two young women are brilliantly portrayed by the two Mary's, Mary Stuart Masterson, and Mary-Louise Parker. Certainly this is one of the greatest 'sisterhood' films ever made. Their story is full of love, pain, pathos, loss, tragedy, and joy. Not unlike life. If you can see this without shedding a tear, then there is no hope for you. Good old Fannie, may she long keep flying her Flagg.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cannibalism And Gendercidal Hatred
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Louis B Maybe
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    OK, so here's why this film is the opposite of everything you've ever been told it is: It's not a wonderful feel-good movie for the girls, it's an ugly, violent fantasy in which justice is confused with revenge. Let's break it down: There are no primary male characters in this movie. Of the secondary and tertiary ones, it could be said that all the (white) males are evil or inadequate. Buddy is good, of course, but inadequate. His own foolishness destroys him. Buddy Junior is equally good but equally inadequate. Frank, on the other hand is just plain evil, and in between are more ambiguous male characters. The police chief is willing to help Idgie, it's true, but only because of his lecherous interest in her, and his mentality is thoroughly racist. Of the male characters, only Big George is unambiguously both good and adequate. But Big George is a black man. And black men are oppressed men. In effect, they are not men at all: exempt on political grounds from the critique levelled at white men, they are honorary women. This movie, couched in soft colours and sweet music, is one of the most casually misandric movies ever made. First of all, & most obviously, there is the EATING of her Evelyn's murdered husband. But it happens throughout the movie, as well, such as when Evelyn tells Frank "if I was going to kill you, I'd use my fists". She fantasizes about putting bombs in copies of Playboy and Hustler. "I'll take all the wife-beaters," she says, "and I'll machine gun their genitals!" "You didn't kill Ed, did you?" asks Ninny when Evelyn turns up late. "Not yet," answers Evelyn with a smile. The problem here is not that women will leave theatres and go on killing sprees. The problem is simply the convincing presentation of a cinematic world in which only women have a 'right' to be angry, in which all women are victims, & all men - all white men,anyway - are evil oppressors or inadequate burdens. To the extent that both women and men consciously or subconsciously adopt this worldview, the mutual hostility that now characterizes relations between the sexes will be exacerbated instead of questioned or healed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Interesting But Not Overpowering
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sddavis63 (revsdd@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watching the progression of the relationship between Idgie (Mary Stuart Masterson) and Ruth (Mary-Louise Parker) is fairly interesting. The story is a flashback; a story related by Ninny Threadgoode (Jessica Tandy) to Evelyn (Kathy Bates) who befriends Ninny in a local nursing home. So right off the top you can see that there's a pretty decent cast. Also almost from the start you realize that Ninny is a bit of an enigmatic character. Is she or is she not Idgie relating her own story? The movie seems to lead in that direction but never actually makes it explicit, so in the end it's left to the viewer to decide. Basically, this ends up as a murder mystery from the past. Ruth's abusive husband is murdered, and the question is who killed him. Idgie is put on trial for the crime, but the charges are dismissed. The mystery is held pretty well until the end of the movie. The movie begins with Idgie as a child, and with Ruth as her older brother Buddy's love interest. After Buddy's tragic death, Idgie and Ruth develop a very close friendship - the movie bobs and weaves around the issue of what the nature of their relationship was. Was it just a close friendship? Was it more? My feeling from the movie is that Idgie wanted more than a friendship; Ruth's interests were less clear. I haven't read the book, but I understand that the novel is quite clear in making the point that there was a lesbian romance between the two. Perhaps Hollywood in 1991 was still too nervous about such an issue to make it front and centre; ambiguity was as much as the studios could stomach apparently. We follow both of them through the ups and downs of life as they open a cafe together, whose menu specialty is - you guessed it - fried green tomatoes. Kathy Bates provided some comedy to the movie as the modern day housewife who goes through a rebirth after meeting Ninny - a rebirth that totally confuses her husband Ed (Gailard Sartain), who doesn't have a clue why Evelyn is changing so much and upsetting their comfortable existence. While she provided comedy, I wasn't really taken in by Bates' character in this. I thought the constant switching between present and past was overdone and not particularly well done to be honest; in a lot of ways the two parts of the stories didn't mesh that well. Aside from Bates, there were a lot of very likable characters from the past, such as Big George (Stan Shaw) and Smokey Lonesome (Timothy Scott.) The identity of Ruth's husband's killer in the end took me by surprise, so that was well done. My final reaction to this was that it was a basically well made and well acted movie, and at times even an interesting movie as the story unfolded - but that it also seemed like a movie that was anything but overpowering. It didn't leave me awestruck. (5/10)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fantastic Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lencad
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I think I have seen the movie at least 5 or more times. I love it. You see something each time you watch it that you missed the first time. My friend and I also went to the Whistle Cafe Stop Cafe in Juliette, Ga and had lunch. It was terrific. We had Peach Cobbler for desert and we could have gone back for more. I bought candy and soap in the Honeycomb Store and today I ordered some more. The soap is so nice you can smell it all over my house. The candy is awesome. Take time to see the movie. Be sure to visit the Whistle Stop Cafe in Juliette, Ga and to also stop in at the Honeycomb and what ever other stores are open. I love places like this that are still there for others to see. It makes the movie seem even more real.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This film is what movies should be about...!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vonschweissguth
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have viewed this marvelous film at least 2 dozen times. As with all great movies, you will always catch something "new" with each watching. If you want to be charmed, enchanted, moved, and find yourself wishing.... This is a film you will cherish. I won't belabor more than others have written so well. It is a film that resides in my permanent library on my top shelf. When I watch it again, I find myself wishing that I knew the characters personally and somehow find that I do. This film is one of the only that I esteem. It adds to your life. It hugs the heart and enriches who you are. I want to thank all the marvelous actors. If they ever wondered why they chose their profession, this film is why. 200 years from now it will be loved and valued. The test of time is guaranteed with Fried Green Tomatoes!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Overly Sentimental FIlm
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Supachewy
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/9/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The drama Fried Green Tomatoes is directed by Jon Avnet and stars Kathy Bates, Jessica Tandy, Mary Stuart Masterson, and Mary-Luise Parker. The film takes place in modern day Alabama with flashbacks from 1920 Alabama. The film starts off with a little girl in 1920s Alabama named Idgie Threadgood who does not want to be a part of her sister's wedding. After being talked to by her older brother she agrees to go to it and then afterward the two of them plus the girl the brother likes, Ruth (Parker) go on a walk around the area. When Ruth's hat flies off Idgie's brother goes and gets it for her but his foot ends up stuck in a train track and he is tragically killed. Idgie is extremely disturbed by her brother's death and is never the same again. This is all told from her sister Ninny Threadgood (Tandy) to Evelyn Couch (Bates). Couch is a middle aged woman who does not believe that she has any power or purpose and she met Ninny in a nursing home while visiting her husband's aunt. As the film goes on it develops the relationship between Idgie and Ruth and also Ninny and Evelyn and it is very sentimental... The script was written by Fannie Flagg who also wrote the book which the film is based on. Personally I thought the writing was weak for one main reason. That reason is that the film bounced between two different stories. The story with Idgie and Ruth was quite interesting but the story with Evelyn and Ninny was a complete bore that lacked depth. It was basically Evelyn just saying I have no purpose and then becoming a crazy woman that just tears apart her home and it is all supposedly because of Ninny's story. It is just not believable. It would have been better if it was more like Ninny just telling the story to Evelyn and Evelyn not having a story of her own. The first feature film for the big screen of Jon Avnet proved that he is a decent director. Avnet got solid performances by all his leads which is hard to do in a cast with four leads. The shots in the film were not really impressive and he did not really make me care much for any of the characters. I would have said that he did a poor job if he did not get the performances that he did, but then again it was only his first film even though he has not proved to be much of a director today in any way. The acting in this film was the best part of it. All four of the leads gave great performances. Even Kathy Bates, whose character I thought to be the weakest written still was able to bring a great performance out of it. Yet she is one of the greatest actresses who ever lived. Jessica Tandy even earned an Oscar nomination for her performance just because she was so great being an eccentric old lady. Parker and Masterson are sort of newcomers to the lead position and they really pulled it off as well. The acting made this film bearable. Overall I give this film a 5/10, I would have gave lower if it was not for the strong performances. I would recommend this to anyone who likes period pieces or films with strong female leads.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Story of friendship
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SnoopyStyle
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is based on a novel that takes place in Alabama. The modern story has timid housewife Evelyn Couch (Kathy Bates) who befriends an old woman Ninny Threadgoode (Jessica Tandy) at a retirement home. She recounts an old story from depression era. She tells the story of Idgie Threadgoode (Mary Stuart Masterson) and her friendship with Ruth Jamison (Mary-Louise Parker). Their lives are forever linked by the death of Idgie's brother who was Ruth's boyfriend. The modern story doesn't have quite the punch. The old time story exceeds it in almost every way. It may have been an important part of the novel, but I don't know if the modern story necessarily added anything to the movie. Both Marys are outstanding in their roles. Their characters are truly the center of this movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very very good writing,Wonderful movie.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Wadejohnson1970
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As a young man growing up in the Country of my home town of Hawkinsville Pulaski County Georgia, I had saw the movie in rental stores, however I was just never quite interested in watching a movie called Fried Green Tomatoes!!! However one night while watching TV with my family I was flicking through the Chanel's and came upon this very net resting movie that just so,happens to be..yes you guessed it...Fried Green Tomatoes!!! Well right here in the middle of my review I get a knock on my door, some guy tells me that he had just hit a little black dog out in front of my home, we live on a dirt road and people drive on it as if it were a damn Interstate Highway!!!! Sure enough it is my late fathers dog Buster!!! One of the last things my Daddy said was son look out for my dog!!! Now I feel really bad!!! He is not dead yet, he has his wits about him, just a bit loopy, but catching one of those full size Chevy Silverado's ain't good for a 4 pound dog!!! Anyway please pray for Buster!!!! Now back to the Movie review... As I began to watch this movie I just got more and more intertwined into the story!!! I couldn't tell who was more intrigued by Iggies story, me or Evelyne Couch. The story about Frank Bennett was so interesting!!! Heck there wasn't anything about the entire movie that Wasn't interesting!!!! The most interesting part of the entire movie was the fact that Frank Bennett's body was never found!!! And even more the reason WHY IT EAS NEVER FOUND!!!! Big George Put him on the grill and made BBQ out of him and they fed him to the guy from Georgia that was so stern to Iggies that he WAS THE LAW!!!! And you can't beat the law!!!! So to sum it up in a few words!!!! Fried Green Tomatoes is by far one of the best movies I ever saw, most important I. Was working with Georgia Power and happened upon this little Cafe out in Julliett Ga. And before I knew it I was sitting right in the middle of where one of my favorite movies was made..The Whistle Stop Cafe!!!!! You can't imagine my excitement and couldn't wait to tell my wife that I had sat and eat right there where the story played out!!! Now I'm gonna take my wife there to have some of those world famous FRIED GREEN TOMATOES!!!! And if you never watched this MASTERPIECE PLEASE DO!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Secret's in the Sauce
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    C_Hardrick
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Oscar winner Kathy Bates stars as Evelyn Couch, who one day while visiting her husbands ailing aunt in a nursing home, stumbles onto Mrs. Threadgoode, a resident of the same nursing home, played by Oscar winner Jessica Tandy. As Mrs. Threadgoode tells her story to Evelyn, we learn a vivid story of a young charismatic girl named Idgie spanning the years before World War One through the Depression. The film is set in the Deep South. Alabama to be exact in a small town called Whistle Stop. The film also stars a young Chris O'Donnell as Buddy Threadgoode, Idgie's brother. When Buddy is tragically killed in front of her eyes, Idgie sets out on a life to live to the fullest, even against her mother's wishes and the town preacher's wishes as well. As she grows, so does her relationship with family friend Ruth Jamison, played by Mary-Louise Parker. Eventually they become an inseparable duo, until Ruth marries Frank Bennett, played by Nick Searcy. Frank Bennett ends up being the plot point of the second half of Mrs. Threadgoode's story, and how Idgie may have or may not have killed him. We may not know what happened to Frank, however, "the secrets in the sauce."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Brilliant sweet modern classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    misskellyvalente
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film was at times hysterical and at other times tugged at your heart strings. The film was based on a book. The film looked great and was well written and had wonderful actors portraying some great characters that you could really get attached to. I was a little disappointed that the film watered down the relationship of the two female characters. I realize that it would have never made it to main-stream America if the filmmakers hadn't. It was still very clear that there is a relationship in the film if you are paying attention for the simple little clues. Mary Stuart Masterson and Mary-Louise Parker did an amazing job capturing the chemistry between these two female characters. It's always amazing to watch Jessica Tandy act as she brings such heart to any character she portrays. Kathy Bates plays Evelyn and makes her so truthful and funny. The film is marketed as a feel good film and it does contain those moments, but it leans more toward drama side than the comedy side. Don't let anything stop you from watching this brilliant sweet modern classic. You'll be glad you did.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An authentic classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    robert-temple-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have just seen this wonderful film for the third time, after many years, and it is such a classic, and has not lost any of its interest or appeal. Indeed, it is more relevant now than it ever was, considering that it is about the plight of women and how they cope with their various life situations. It is based on a novel, and has a screenplay by, Fannie Flagg. It is set in Alabama where she comes from, and the story presumably has some basis in truth. Not many people know that Fannie Flagg used to be a brilliant comedienne. I knew her in the mid 1960s when she was a stand-up comic, and she was hilarious. She used to perform at a marvellous comedy cabaret night club in Manhattan, now long gone, which had two floors. The upstairs was called Upstairs at the Downstairs, and the downstairs was called Downstairs at the Upstairs. It was at 37 West 56th Street and was run by an amusing and eccentric woman whose name I have forgotten, alas. Fannie played there at the same time as Madeline ('Maddy') Kahn, who was also wildly funny. Fannie told me she had wanted to perform under her own real name of Patricia Neal, but was told by her agent or manager, I believe, that she could not do that because there was a famous film actress of that name already, so she invented the name Fannie Flagg for herself. It was only years later that she wrote this marvellous heart-felt novel, which was rejected by many publishers, but which finally came out and then resulted in this film. And it is this which really made Fannie Flag famous. The film was shot in Georgia, which is next door to Alabama. But the story is mostly set in Alabama in a little town called Whistle Stop. That name arose because it was a settlement situated beside the railroad. Many small Southern towns fell into desuetude (i.e. withered away) when the railroads started collapsing, after the construction of the interstate highway system, which shifted so much travel and freight transport onto roads and destroyed the rail industry, from the 1950s onwards. In this film which takes place at two different times, during the pre-War period which constitutes the earlier story, the two young women, Idgie and Ruth, open a railside caf&eacute; called The Whistle Stop Caf&eacute;. In those years, it thrived and became the heart of the town, where everyone went to eat real home cooking, which included the favourite local delicacy, fried green tomatoes, which were sliced and fried in batter in what in the South is called a skillet, which is an old 17th century English word for a frying pan, the word surviving only in the American South and nowhere else. (I still fry my eggs and bacon in an old iron family skillet which was cast in the family forge at Taunton, Massachusetts, in the 17th or 18th century. We have been using that skillet for many generations. Just imagine how many bacon fat molecules survive in the crystalline interstices of the cast iron after those centuries of use every morning. The outside of the skillet looks like something dug up by an archaeologist, but the inside is shiny and ready for anything. But this question arises: can bacon fat go rancid after a century or two? It does seem to improve the flavour anyway. However, I am ashamed to say that I have never fried any green tomatoes, which is doubtless a great personal failing of mine. The skillet has thus been deprived of what Ruth and Idgie would perhaps consider to be its main function, to deal with those green tomatoes.) Idgie, who is a hopeless cook, cannot prepare them, so Ruth has to do it. Throughout the film people keep tasting them to see if they are up to standard. The modern story of the film consists of tales told by an old lady in a retirement home to a much younger woman, and the effect this has on transforming her life. That younger woman is played by Kathy Bates, whose performance is breathtaking in its sensitivity and brilliance. But then, Kathy Bates has always been one of everybody's favourite and most endearing actresses, and we all know what a genius she is. The old woman is played equally brilliantly by the famous Jessica Tandy, veteran of a lifetime of superlative achievements in both stage and screen. Before TV wiped all the brains of the public as clean as a virgin hard disc, people used to tell stories, and there was such a thing as verbal communication. (And people didn't even have to use their thumbs to communicate, like today's simian-thumbed and simian-brained text messagers.) This film is all about the power of stories to stir the imagination and transform lives. Even as late as the 1960s, some old women still survived in the South who could tell stories for hours on end. They are all gone now, and it is like what happened after the time of Homer, when the last of the bards died. The best rendering in fiction of the 'power of stories' is probably the novella by Mircea Eliade entitled THE OLD MAN AND THE BUREAUCRATS. (Eliade wrote the story of Coppola's film YOUTH WITHOUT YOUTH, 2007, though that film was very disappointing and a poor adaptation.) The stories told by Jessica Tandy are about Idgie and Ruth. In those lengthy flashback sequences, the two young women are brilliantly portrayed by the two Mary's, Mary Stuart Masterson, and Mary-Louise Parker. Certainly this is one of the greatest 'sisterhood' films ever made. Their story is full of love, pain, pathos, loss, tragedy, and joy. Not unlike life. If you can see this without shedding a tear, then there is no hope for you. Good old Fannie, may she long keep flying her Flagg.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Cannibalism And Gendercidal Hatred
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Louis B Maybe
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    OK, so here's why this film is the opposite of everything you've ever been told it is: It's not a wonderful feel-good movie for the girls, it's an ugly, violent fantasy in which justice is confused with revenge. Let's break it down: There are no primary male characters in this movie. Of the secondary and tertiary ones, it could be said that all the (white) males are evil or inadequate. Buddy is good, of course, but inadequate. His own foolishness destroys him. Buddy Junior is equally good but equally inadequate. Frank, on the other hand is just plain evil, and in between are more ambiguous male characters. The police chief is willing to help Idgie, it's true, but only because of his lecherous interest in her, and his mentality is thoroughly racist. Of the male characters, only Big George is unambiguously both good and adequate. But Big George is a black man. And black men are oppressed men. In effect, they are not men at all: exempt on political grounds from the critique levelled at white men, they are honorary women. This movie, couched in soft colours and sweet music, is one of the most casually misandric movies ever made. First of all, & most obviously, there is the EATING of her Evelyn's murdered husband. But it happens throughout the movie, as well, such as when Evelyn tells Frank "if I was going to kill you, I'd use my fists". She fantasizes about putting bombs in copies of Playboy and Hustler. "I'll take all the wife-beaters," she says, "and I'll machine gun their genitals!" "You didn't kill Ed, did you?" asks Ninny when Evelyn turns up late. "Not yet," answers Evelyn with a smile. The problem here is not that women will leave theatres and go on killing sprees. The problem is simply the convincing presentation of a cinematic world in which only women have a 'right' to be angry, in which all women are victims, & all men - all white men,anyway - are evil oppressors or inadequate burdens. To the extent that both women and men consciously or subconsciously adopt this worldview, the mutual hostility that now characterizes relations between the sexes will be exacerbated instead of questioned or healed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Interesting But Not Overpowering
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sddavis63 (revsdd@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watching the progression of the relationship between Idgie (Mary Stuart Masterson) and Ruth (Mary-Louise Parker) is fairly interesting. The story is a flashback; a story related by Ninny Threadgoode (Jessica Tandy) to Evelyn (Kathy Bates) who befriends Ninny in a local nursing home. So right off the top you can see that there's a pretty decent cast. Also almost from the start you realize that Ninny is a bit of an enigmatic character. Is she or is she not Idgie relating her own story? The movie seems to lead in that direction but never actually makes it explicit, so in the end it's left to the viewer to decide. Basically, this ends up as a murder mystery from the past. Ruth's abusive husband is murdered, and the question is who killed him. Idgie is put on trial for the crime, but the charges are dismissed. The mystery is held pretty well until the end of the movie. The movie begins with Idgie as a child, and with Ruth as her older brother Buddy's love interest. After Buddy's tragic death, Idgie and Ruth develop a very close friendship - the movie bobs and weaves around the issue of what the nature of their relationship was. Was it just a close friendship? Was it more? My feeling from the movie is that Idgie wanted more than a friendship; Ruth's interests were less clear. I haven't read the book, but I understand that the novel is quite clear in making the point that there was a lesbian romance between the two. Perhaps Hollywood in 1991 was still too nervous about such an issue to make it front and centre; ambiguity was as much as the studios could stomach apparently. We follow both of them through the ups and downs of life as they open a cafe together, whose menu specialty is - you guessed it - fried green tomatoes. Kathy Bates provided some comedy to the movie as the modern day housewife who goes through a rebirth after meeting Ninny - a rebirth that totally confuses her husband Ed (Gailard Sartain), who doesn't have a clue why Evelyn is changing so much and upsetting their comfortable existence. While she provided comedy, I wasn't really taken in by Bates' character in this. I thought the constant switching between present and past was overdone and not particularly well done to be honest; in a lot of ways the two parts of the stories didn't mesh that well. Aside from Bates, there were a lot of very likable characters from the past, such as Big George (Stan Shaw) and Smokey Lonesome (Timothy Scott.) The identity of Ruth's husband's killer in the end took me by surprise, so that was well done. My final reaction to this was that it was a basically well made and well acted movie, and at times even an interesting movie as the story unfolded - but that it also seemed like a movie that was anything but overpowering. It didn't leave me awestruck. (5/10)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fantastic Movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lencad
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I think I have seen the movie at least 5 or more times. I love it. You see something each time you watch it that you missed the first time. My friend and I also went to the Whistle Cafe Stop Cafe in Juliette, Ga and had lunch. It was terrific. We had Peach Cobbler for desert and we could have gone back for more. I bought candy and soap in the Honeycomb Store and today I ordered some more. The soap is so nice you can smell it all over my house. The candy is awesome. Take time to see the movie. Be sure to visit the Whistle Stop Cafe in Juliette, Ga and to also stop in at the Honeycomb and what ever other stores are open. I love places like this that are still there for others to see. It makes the movie seem even more real.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This film is what movies should be about...!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    vonschweissguth
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have viewed this marvelous film at least 2 dozen times. As with all great movies, you will always catch something "new" with each watching. If you want to be charmed, enchanted, moved, and find yourself wishing.... This is a film you will cherish. I won't belabor more than others have written so well. It is a film that resides in my permanent library on my top shelf. When I watch it again, I find myself wishing that I knew the characters personally and somehow find that I do. This film is one of the only that I esteem. It adds to your life. It hugs the heart and enriches who you are. I want to thank all the marvelous actors. If they ever wondered why they chose their profession, this film is why. 200 years from now it will be loved and valued. The test of time is guaranteed with Fried Green Tomatoes!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Overly Sentimental FIlm
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Supachewy
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/9/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The drama Fried Green Tomatoes is directed by Jon Avnet and stars Kathy Bates, Jessica Tandy, Mary Stuart Masterson, and Mary-Luise Parker. The film takes place in modern day Alabama with flashbacks from 1920 Alabama. The film starts off with a little girl in 1920s Alabama named Idgie Threadgood who does not want to be a part of her sister's wedding. After being talked to by her older brother she agrees to go to it and then afterward the two of them plus the girl the brother likes, Ruth (Parker) go on a walk around the area. When Ruth's hat flies off Idgie's brother goes and gets it for her but his foot ends up stuck in a train track and he is tragically killed. Idgie is extremely disturbed by her brother's death and is never the same again. This is all told from her sister Ninny Threadgood (Tandy) to Evelyn Couch (Bates). Couch is a middle aged woman who does not believe that she has any power or purpose and she met Ninny in a nursing home while visiting her husband's aunt. As the film goes on it develops the relationship between Idgie and Ruth and also Ninny and Evelyn and it is very sentimental... The script was written by Fannie Flagg who also wrote the book which the film is based on. Personally I thought the writing was weak for one main reason. That reason is that the film bounced between two different stories. The story with Idgie and Ruth was quite interesting but the story with Evelyn and Ninny was a complete bore that lacked depth. It was basically Evelyn just saying I have no purpose and then becoming a crazy woman that just tears apart her home and it is all supposedly because of Ninny's story. It is just not believable. It would have been better if it was more like Ninny just telling the story to Evelyn and Evelyn not having a story of her own. The first feature film for the big screen of Jon Avnet proved that he is a decent director. Avnet got solid performances by all his leads which is hard to do in a cast with four leads. The shots in the film were not really impressive and he did not really make me care much for any of the characters. I would have said that he did a poor job if he did not get the performances that he did, but then again it was only his first film even though he has not proved to be much of a director today in any way. The acting in this film was the best part of it. All four of the leads gave great performances. Even Kathy Bates, whose character I thought to be the weakest written still was able to bring a great performance out of it. Yet she is one of the greatest actresses who ever lived. Jessica Tandy even earned an Oscar nomination for her performance just because she was so great being an eccentric old lady. Parker and Masterson are sort of newcomers to the lead position and they really pulled it off as well. The acting made this film bearable. Overall I give this film a 5/10, I would have gave lower if it was not for the strong performances. I would recommend this to anyone who likes period pieces or films with strong female leads.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
