<filme>
 <id>
  663
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0078841
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1979
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Muito Al&eacute;m do Jardim
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  8.0
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Chance, a simple gardener, has never left the estate until his employer dies. His simple TV-informed utterances are mistaken for profundity.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  A simple-minded gardener named Chance has spent all his life in the Washington D.C. house of an old man. When the man dies, Chance is put out on the street with no knowledge of the world except what he has learned from television. After a run in with a limousine, he ends up a guest of a woman (Eve) and her husband Ben, an influential but sickly businessman. Now called Chauncey Gardner, Chance becomes friend and confidante to Ben, and an unlikely political insider.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   gardener
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   washington d.c.
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   businessman
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   television
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   u.s. president
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Hal Ashby
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Jerzy Kosinski
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Peter Sellers
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Shirley MacLaine
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Melvyn Douglas
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Must See
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mickmerivel
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    By far one of the best films of Peter Sellers. Too often overshadowed by the Pink Panther, this film brings you something completely different. For the modern audience and the younger viewer let it be known that this film does not move at the pace you are probably accustomed to, though if you truly do love a good story and are a fan of film and its telling, then you will love Being There. I find it absolutely hysterical, and upon each view I see something I've missed before. And a very many times I hear a line or see something I've missed before as well. Great films that both are entertaining and subtle in their delivery can be the best of entertainment, and this is such a film. I don't want to ruin the fantastic experience of seeing such an amazing flick, so I'll simply say, see It. Remember not to turn it off half way through, though you may feel it a bit slow, it'll be worth your wait and something you'll love to discuss with others'. That attribute is very often what makes the best films. You won't be disappointed if you are a fan of the little film gems some people too often forget. You'll be glad you went "there."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A dry film is about ignorance and politics and when are they not to be mentioned in the same breath
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Marc Israel
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A twist on the old adage "everything we ever need to know we learned in kindergarten", "Being There" holds forth that American politics, underwritten by polls, commercials and pop culture, would benefit and bite the hook of a simple gardeners' working words. Plant the seed, water it and watch it grow. Based in the same city that brought us Watergate, and pitted against the television backdrop of American social awareness and commercialization, the film captures the time quite well. Love the Diadario music scoring Chances coming out scene and love Peter Sellers as Chance Gardener as his optimism is born and running viral, as it was in 1979. Of course it wouldn't go far without the connected but tainted Shirley McLaine and her flirtatious endeavors.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A sweet/sad surrealist fantasy, profound and delightful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    middleburg
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I LOVE Being There. Captivated the first time i saw it, I probably have watched this film a dozen times since -- each time immersed in the fantasy world of Chance and Eve and her billionaire beau, and the President of the United States, and the Russian Ambassador and all of the loony/quirky/needy/flawed/normal/outlandish characters eager, even desperate, to connect, to understand, to cope with and ultimately love and embrace a too-often incomprehensible world, thanks to the "insight" of the magical Chance. There are countless moments to cherish in this film, thanks to the subtle, surprising, carefully calibrated direction of the one and only Hal Ashby and the impeccable comic timing of the seasoned pros Melvyn Douglas and Shirley MacLaine, playing the magisterial Benjamin Rand and his beautiful sexy "concubine" Eve, with a script that keeps the viewer endlessly intrigued, with a combination of laugh-out-loud moments, moments of genuine suspense, and scenes of tenderness and even a few tears. Ultimately the film belongs to Peter Seller's brilliant character, Chance, with his sweet/calming, genuine/wise spirit; Chance -- on the street, in the elevator, at dinner, in a car, at a party, on TV, providing the laughs, but also the comfort, insight, warmth and wisdom. An unforgettable character in an unforgettable film. You know, it's time for me to see this film again!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A sweet/sad surrealist fantasy, profound and delightful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    middleburg
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I LOVE Being There. Captivated the first time i saw it, I probably have watched this film a dozen times since -- each time immersed in the fantasy world of Chance and Eve and her billionaire beau, and the President of the United States, and the Russian Ambassador and all of the loony/quirky/needy/flawed/normal/outlandish characters eager, even desperate, to connect, to understand, to cope with and ultimately love and embrace a too-often incomprehensible world, thanks to the "insight" of the magical Chance. There are countless moments to cherish in this film, thanks to the subtle, surprising, carefully calibrated direction of the one and only Hal Ashby and the impeccable comic timing of the seasoned pros Melvyn Douglas and Shirley MacLaine, playing the magisterial Benjamin Rand and his beautiful sexy "concubine" Eve, with a script that keeps the viewer endlessly intrigued, with a combination of laugh-out-loud moments, moments of genuine suspense, and scenes of tenderness and even a few tears. Ultimately the film belongs to Peter Seller's brilliant character, Chance, with his sweet/calming, genuine/wise spirit; Chance -- on the street, in the elevator, at dinner, in a car, at a party, on TV, providing the laughs, but also the comfort, insight, warmth and wisdom. An unforgettable character in an unforgettable film. You know, it's time for me to see this film again!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The last performance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cedde6
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Long before Forrest Gump there was another simple man who changed the world he lived in. Not by design of course but by simply being there. Written by Jerzy Kozinski from his own novel and beautifully directed by Hal Ashby "Being There" tells the story of Chance, a simpleton gardener who has never been allowed out of the house in which he has lived in and worked for all his life. When the "old man" who owns the house passes away, Chance is then forced to leave and face the outside world where his innocence and simplicity are mistaken for financial savvy and wisdom with a penchant for gardening metaphors. Hal Ashby, one of the most underestimated director of the New Hollywood period delivered in its tail end (1979) this little gem which I watched, caught between bouts of laughter and consternation; each and every single cringe induced not by Chance but the inability of the people who meet him to see the man for what he truly is. Chance never claims (quite literally) to be anything is not and only people's assumptions propel this film from one absurdity to the next, and in the midst of all this, Chance strolls along, innocent, detached and somewhat weightless, to a quiet conclusion where the world keeps on guessing and plotting. And so, Hal Ashby pokes gentle fun at the establishment through his characters' delusions and, for some, the frenzy they get themselves into but he and Kozinski never let any political stance overshadow a story which in nature is both heart-warming and melancholic. What the film boils down to is however jaded and so-called sophisticated people are, in their heart of hardened hearts, they all are ultimately attracted, in some way or the other, to the simplicity, the kindness and the innocence of Chance the gardener. Needless to say Peter Sellers' performance is absolutely incredible giving the fact that it is so subdued, delicate and seemingly effortless. This was his last performance and it is truly the stuff of legend. Shirley McLaine is equally amazing in her comedic timing as a wife soon to be widow finding solace and romance in Chance's soft approach to life in general. In the end, this is both an emotional comedy and a light-hearted drama. This defies labels. This is a work of sheer brilliance from Hal Ashby, and an astounding conclusion to Peter Sellers' incredible career.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stupendous. Sellers' Best Performance.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Humphrey Fish
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Chance, a simple gardener, has never left the estate until his employer dies. His simple TV-informed utterances are mistaken for profundity. This was the last movie that Peter Sellers made before his death (The Fiendish Plot of Dr. Fu Manchu doesn't really count), and it is without a doubt his best role, as great as he was in The Pink Panther films, this film is his best performance, he was absolutely stupendous, or even better, the whole movie was stupendous! That's right. Being There is a stupendous movie, in which everybody in it is wonderful. This movie is a comedy-drama film, meaning that while it does have some laughs in it, it is mostly a serious movie, in some parts, the movie is even worth shedding a few tears. Peter Sellers really surprised me, because I was used to seeing him in comedy roles, such as the Pink Panther movies, and Dr. Strangelove, but here, he was in a class by himself, he was absolutely, totally, and completely incredible! It just goes to show what a great actor he truly was, and it is such a pity that he had to die so young, oh well, he may be gone, but he certainly will not be forgotten. While Peter Sellers gave the best performance in the movie, everyone else was also fabulous. Jack Warden gave a wonderful performance as The President, and Shirley MacLaine was marvelous as Eve Rand. However, Melvyn Douglas as Benjamin Rand was something else. Douglas was second only to Peter Sellers in the acting department, he was old, but he could still act, and fabulously too. He won his second Academy Award For Best Supporting Actor for his role in Being There (his first was for Hud in 1963), and it was a very well deserved win, as he was outstanding. Peter Sellers was nominated for Best Actor, and I could see where he would be, because this is his best performance in my opinion. All in all, this is an excellent movie, it is one of the best movies of 1979, and one of the best movies of the 1970's. And therefore, I could say that this movie is one of the greatest movies that I have ever seen. Being There is like no Peter Sellers movie that I have ever seen, rather than playing a comedy role, he plays a serious role, and he does an absolutely wonderful job at it too. All in all, Being There is a movie that has got everything that you would expect to see in a great movie, great acting, great writing, and great directing. Sadly, Peter Sellers would die not long after making this movie at the young age of 54, just think of what he could have accomplished if he would have lived longer. But anyway, this movie is one of the greatest movies ever made, it's a masterpiece brought to us by Hal Ashby. Sellers, Douglas, Warden, and MacLaine all did remarkable jobs with their acting, but Sellers and Douglas being the best of the four. When you watch this movie, you will see Peter Sellers in a role like you've never seen him before, a role that proves what a really talented actor he was. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Life is a state of mind
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Artimidor Federkiel
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The maid Louise describes the main character of this most unusual film as "stuffed with rice pudding between his ears". He can't read or write and is "short-changed by the Lord and dumb as a jackass". His window to the world is the TV, which he enjoys to imitate, other than that he is nothing more than a walking mirror: flat, reflecting what everybody wants to see in him, talking back what they want to hear. The gardener Chance - or, as some who misheard like to call him, Chancey Gardiner - is just there, in suit and tie, an empty mind, alas, sans garden. But being there is enough if you're in the right place and actually are as shallow as others consider you profound. Filmed right Jerzy Kosinski's engaging novel makes the perfect mix for a highly intelligent, though intentionally slow comedy for those who like to have it the more thoughtful way. The film benefits greatly from Peter Seller's complete immersion in the straightness of his character, which is arguably his best role. And Eumir Deodato's version of Strauss' "Also Sprach Zarathustra" as he steps out of the house for the first time in years is nearly as striking as when Kubrick opened "2001" with the original. Unforgettable is the superb ending, which breaks out of the comedic back and forth and goes a decisive, daring step further. It reminds me of another king of comedy, Bill Cosby, and the joke in his stand-up routine where he relates that he wasn't quite sure about his name when he was little. Quite often his parents used to shout out when they saw him: "Jesus Christ!" In the same innocent way our gardener Chance appears to the viewer as the savior himself when the movie ends and when we can still hear the film's final message ringing in our ears: "Life is a state of mind." Well, and ignorance is bliss.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Don't waste your time on Being There
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bluejacquet
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Being There starts with a clever and promising plot that disintegrates into nothingness, leaving the viewer with no answers - only questions. If you like movies with weird, unexplained endings and unfinished story lines, then by all means go see it. It seems that Peter Sellers is often lauded for his 'brilliant' acting in this movie, but really anyone could pull off the role of Chance The Gardener. As Chance is just a simpleton, all one needs to do is to stare blankly ahead and speak softly without inflection, emotion nor enthusiasm in your voice and, presto, you're acting brilliantly. Give me a break.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Classic!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Adapted from the 1971 novella written by Jerzy Kosinski, 'Being There' is A Classic. A Deliciously Written film, that comes in-tact with Tight Direction & Memorable Performances. 'Being There' Synopsis: Chance, a simple gardener, has never left the estate until his employer dies. His simple TV-informed utterances are mistaken for profundity. 'Being There' is A Classic, because it is unforgettable. The humor, the characters, the entire set-up, everything, comes across as flawless & incomparable. Kosinski and Robert C. Jones.'s Screenplay is Delicious. It narrates a wonderful story, with loads of humor. Hal Ashby's Direction is Tight. Cinematography is perfect. Editing & Art Design, are good. Performance-Wise: Peter Sellers as Chance, delivers one of his best performances. The legendary actor sinks his teeth into the character & brings it out with flying colors. Melvyn Douglas, in an Oscar-Winning Performance, is memorable. Shirley MacLaine is fantastic, as always. Jack Warden does wonders. Richard A. Dysart is pleasant. David Clennon leaves a mark. On the whole, 'Being There' is a Winner All The Way. Two Thumbs Up!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Seller's best work
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jerzy kozinsky wrote this brilliant political satire and adapted it for the big screen. Chance Gardner is played with subtle genius by Peter Sellers in what I consider his most complete performance. Chance is a man from nowhere with no history and a childlike innocence in a world of corruption and cynicism. He is accidentally hit by a limousine carrying a Washington D.C. king maker. Chance is put up in an estate and through a series of events becomes a media darling for reciting simplistic remarks which are taken for being pearls of deep wisdom, a variation of "the emperor has no clothes." Seller's is Forrest Gump on steroids, one of the most incredible performances ever captured on film. This should be required viewing at all acting classes. The final scene is beautiful and will fill you with a sense of wonderment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Must See
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mickmerivel
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    By far one of the best films of Peter Sellers. Too often overshadowed by the Pink Panther, this film brings you something completely different. For the modern audience and the younger viewer let it be known that this film does not move at the pace you are probably accustomed to, though if you truly do love a good story and are a fan of film and its telling, then you will love Being There. I find it absolutely hysterical, and upon each view I see something I've missed before. And a very many times I hear a line or see something I've missed before as well. Great films that both are entertaining and subtle in their delivery can be the best of entertainment, and this is such a film. I don't want to ruin the fantastic experience of seeing such an amazing flick, so I'll simply say, see It. Remember not to turn it off half way through, though you may feel it a bit slow, it'll be worth your wait and something you'll love to discuss with others'. That attribute is very often what makes the best films. You won't be disappointed if you are a fan of the little film gems some people too often forget. You'll be glad you went "there."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A dry film is about ignorance and politics and when are they not to be mentioned in the same breath
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Marc Israel
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A twist on the old adage "everything we ever need to know we learned in kindergarten", "Being There" holds forth that American politics, underwritten by polls, commercials and pop culture, would benefit and bite the hook of a simple gardeners' working words. Plant the seed, water it and watch it grow. Based in the same city that brought us Watergate, and pitted against the television backdrop of American social awareness and commercialization, the film captures the time quite well. Love the Diadario music scoring Chances coming out scene and love Peter Sellers as Chance Gardener as his optimism is born and running viral, as it was in 1979. Of course it wouldn't go far without the connected but tainted Shirley McLaine and her flirtatious endeavors.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A sweet/sad surrealist fantasy, profound and delightful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    middleburg
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I LOVE Being There. Captivated the first time i saw it, I probably have watched this film a dozen times since -- each time immersed in the fantasy world of Chance and Eve and her billionaire beau, and the President of the United States, and the Russian Ambassador and all of the loony/quirky/needy/flawed/normal/outlandish characters eager, even desperate, to connect, to understand, to cope with and ultimately love and embrace a too-often incomprehensible world, thanks to the "insight" of the magical Chance. There are countless moments to cherish in this film, thanks to the subtle, surprising, carefully calibrated direction of the one and only Hal Ashby and the impeccable comic timing of the seasoned pros Melvyn Douglas and Shirley MacLaine, playing the magisterial Benjamin Rand and his beautiful sexy "concubine" Eve, with a script that keeps the viewer endlessly intrigued, with a combination of laugh-out-loud moments, moments of genuine suspense, and scenes of tenderness and even a few tears. Ultimately the film belongs to Peter Seller's brilliant character, Chance, with his sweet/calming, genuine/wise spirit; Chance -- on the street, in the elevator, at dinner, in a car, at a party, on TV, providing the laughs, but also the comfort, insight, warmth and wisdom. An unforgettable character in an unforgettable film. You know, it's time for me to see this film again!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A sweet/sad surrealist fantasy, profound and delightful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    middleburg
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I LOVE Being There. Captivated the first time i saw it, I probably have watched this film a dozen times since -- each time immersed in the fantasy world of Chance and Eve and her billionaire beau, and the President of the United States, and the Russian Ambassador and all of the loony/quirky/needy/flawed/normal/outlandish characters eager, even desperate, to connect, to understand, to cope with and ultimately love and embrace a too-often incomprehensible world, thanks to the "insight" of the magical Chance. There are countless moments to cherish in this film, thanks to the subtle, surprising, carefully calibrated direction of the one and only Hal Ashby and the impeccable comic timing of the seasoned pros Melvyn Douglas and Shirley MacLaine, playing the magisterial Benjamin Rand and his beautiful sexy "concubine" Eve, with a script that keeps the viewer endlessly intrigued, with a combination of laugh-out-loud moments, moments of genuine suspense, and scenes of tenderness and even a few tears. Ultimately the film belongs to Peter Seller's brilliant character, Chance, with his sweet/calming, genuine/wise spirit; Chance -- on the street, in the elevator, at dinner, in a car, at a party, on TV, providing the laughs, but also the comfort, insight, warmth and wisdom. An unforgettable character in an unforgettable film. You know, it's time for me to see this film again!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The last performance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cedde6
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Long before Forrest Gump there was another simple man who changed the world he lived in. Not by design of course but by simply being there. Written by Jerzy Kozinski from his own novel and beautifully directed by Hal Ashby "Being There" tells the story of Chance, a simpleton gardener who has never been allowed out of the house in which he has lived in and worked for all his life. When the "old man" who owns the house passes away, Chance is then forced to leave and face the outside world where his innocence and simplicity are mistaken for financial savvy and wisdom with a penchant for gardening metaphors. Hal Ashby, one of the most underestimated director of the New Hollywood period delivered in its tail end (1979) this little gem which I watched, caught between bouts of laughter and consternation; each and every single cringe induced not by Chance but the inability of the people who meet him to see the man for what he truly is. Chance never claims (quite literally) to be anything is not and only people's assumptions propel this film from one absurdity to the next, and in the midst of all this, Chance strolls along, innocent, detached and somewhat weightless, to a quiet conclusion where the world keeps on guessing and plotting. And so, Hal Ashby pokes gentle fun at the establishment through his characters' delusions and, for some, the frenzy they get themselves into but he and Kozinski never let any political stance overshadow a story which in nature is both heart-warming and melancholic. What the film boils down to is however jaded and so-called sophisticated people are, in their heart of hardened hearts, they all are ultimately attracted, in some way or the other, to the simplicity, the kindness and the innocence of Chance the gardener. Needless to say Peter Sellers' performance is absolutely incredible giving the fact that it is so subdued, delicate and seemingly effortless. This was his last performance and it is truly the stuff of legend. Shirley McLaine is equally amazing in her comedic timing as a wife soon to be widow finding solace and romance in Chance's soft approach to life in general. In the end, this is both an emotional comedy and a light-hearted drama. This defies labels. This is a work of sheer brilliance from Hal Ashby, and an astounding conclusion to Peter Sellers' incredible career.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stupendous. Sellers' Best Performance.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Humphrey Fish
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Chance, a simple gardener, has never left the estate until his employer dies. His simple TV-informed utterances are mistaken for profundity. This was the last movie that Peter Sellers made before his death (The Fiendish Plot of Dr. Fu Manchu doesn't really count), and it is without a doubt his best role, as great as he was in The Pink Panther films, this film is his best performance, he was absolutely stupendous, or even better, the whole movie was stupendous! That's right. Being There is a stupendous movie, in which everybody in it is wonderful. This movie is a comedy-drama film, meaning that while it does have some laughs in it, it is mostly a serious movie, in some parts, the movie is even worth shedding a few tears. Peter Sellers really surprised me, because I was used to seeing him in comedy roles, such as the Pink Panther movies, and Dr. Strangelove, but here, he was in a class by himself, he was absolutely, totally, and completely incredible! It just goes to show what a great actor he truly was, and it is such a pity that he had to die so young, oh well, he may be gone, but he certainly will not be forgotten. While Peter Sellers gave the best performance in the movie, everyone else was also fabulous. Jack Warden gave a wonderful performance as The President, and Shirley MacLaine was marvelous as Eve Rand. However, Melvyn Douglas as Benjamin Rand was something else. Douglas was second only to Peter Sellers in the acting department, he was old, but he could still act, and fabulously too. He won his second Academy Award For Best Supporting Actor for his role in Being There (his first was for Hud in 1963), and it was a very well deserved win, as he was outstanding. Peter Sellers was nominated for Best Actor, and I could see where he would be, because this is his best performance in my opinion. All in all, this is an excellent movie, it is one of the best movies of 1979, and one of the best movies of the 1970's. And therefore, I could say that this movie is one of the greatest movies that I have ever seen. Being There is like no Peter Sellers movie that I have ever seen, rather than playing a comedy role, he plays a serious role, and he does an absolutely wonderful job at it too. All in all, Being There is a movie that has got everything that you would expect to see in a great movie, great acting, great writing, and great directing. Sadly, Peter Sellers would die not long after making this movie at the young age of 54, just think of what he could have accomplished if he would have lived longer. But anyway, this movie is one of the greatest movies ever made, it's a masterpiece brought to us by Hal Ashby. Sellers, Douglas, Warden, and MacLaine all did remarkable jobs with their acting, but Sellers and Douglas being the best of the four. When you watch this movie, you will see Peter Sellers in a role like you've never seen him before, a role that proves what a really talented actor he was. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Life is a state of mind
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Artimidor Federkiel
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The maid Louise describes the main character of this most unusual film as "stuffed with rice pudding between his ears". He can't read or write and is "short-changed by the Lord and dumb as a jackass". His window to the world is the TV, which he enjoys to imitate, other than that he is nothing more than a walking mirror: flat, reflecting what everybody wants to see in him, talking back what they want to hear. The gardener Chance - or, as some who misheard like to call him, Chancey Gardiner - is just there, in suit and tie, an empty mind, alas, sans garden. But being there is enough if you're in the right place and actually are as shallow as others consider you profound. Filmed right Jerzy Kosinski's engaging novel makes the perfect mix for a highly intelligent, though intentionally slow comedy for those who like to have it the more thoughtful way. The film benefits greatly from Peter Seller's complete immersion in the straightness of his character, which is arguably his best role. And Eumir Deodato's version of Strauss' "Also Sprach Zarathustra" as he steps out of the house for the first time in years is nearly as striking as when Kubrick opened "2001" with the original. Unforgettable is the superb ending, which breaks out of the comedic back and forth and goes a decisive, daring step further. It reminds me of another king of comedy, Bill Cosby, and the joke in his stand-up routine where he relates that he wasn't quite sure about his name when he was little. Quite often his parents used to shout out when they saw him: "Jesus Christ!" In the same innocent way our gardener Chance appears to the viewer as the savior himself when the movie ends and when we can still hear the film's final message ringing in our ears: "Life is a state of mind." Well, and ignorance is bliss.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Don't waste your time on Being There
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bluejacquet
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Being There starts with a clever and promising plot that disintegrates into nothingness, leaving the viewer with no answers - only questions. If you like movies with weird, unexplained endings and unfinished story lines, then by all means go see it. It seems that Peter Sellers is often lauded for his 'brilliant' acting in this movie, but really anyone could pull off the role of Chance The Gardener. As Chance is just a simpleton, all one needs to do is to stare blankly ahead and speak softly without inflection, emotion nor enthusiasm in your voice and, presto, you're acting brilliantly. Give me a break.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Classic!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Adapted from the 1971 novella written by Jerzy Kosinski, 'Being There' is A Classic. A Deliciously Written film, that comes in-tact with Tight Direction & Memorable Performances. 'Being There' Synopsis: Chance, a simple gardener, has never left the estate until his employer dies. His simple TV-informed utterances are mistaken for profundity. 'Being There' is A Classic, because it is unforgettable. The humor, the characters, the entire set-up, everything, comes across as flawless & incomparable. Kosinski and Robert C. Jones.'s Screenplay is Delicious. It narrates a wonderful story, with loads of humor. Hal Ashby's Direction is Tight. Cinematography is perfect. Editing & Art Design, are good. Performance-Wise: Peter Sellers as Chance, delivers one of his best performances. The legendary actor sinks his teeth into the character & brings it out with flying colors. Melvyn Douglas, in an Oscar-Winning Performance, is memorable. Shirley MacLaine is fantastic, as always. Jack Warden does wonders. Richard A. Dysart is pleasant. David Clennon leaves a mark. On the whole, 'Being There' is a Winner All The Way. Two Thumbs Up!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Seller's best work
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jerzy kozinsky wrote this brilliant political satire and adapted it for the big screen. Chance Gardner is played with subtle genius by Peter Sellers in what I consider his most complete performance. Chance is a man from nowhere with no history and a childlike innocence in a world of corruption and cynicism. He is accidentally hit by a limousine carrying a Washington D.C. king maker. Chance is put up in an estate and through a series of events becomes a media darling for reciting simplistic remarks which are taken for being pearls of deep wisdom, a variation of "the emperor has no clothes." Seller's is Forrest Gump on steroids, one of the most incredible performances ever captured on film. This should be required viewing at all acting classes. The final scene is beautiful and will fill you with a sense of wonderment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Must See
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mickmerivel
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    By far one of the best films of Peter Sellers. Too often overshadowed by the Pink Panther, this film brings you something completely different. For the modern audience and the younger viewer let it be known that this film does not move at the pace you are probably accustomed to, though if you truly do love a good story and are a fan of film and its telling, then you will love Being There. I find it absolutely hysterical, and upon each view I see something I've missed before. And a very many times I hear a line or see something I've missed before as well. Great films that both are entertaining and subtle in their delivery can be the best of entertainment, and this is such a film. I don't want to ruin the fantastic experience of seeing such an amazing flick, so I'll simply say, see It. Remember not to turn it off half way through, though you may feel it a bit slow, it'll be worth your wait and something you'll love to discuss with others'. That attribute is very often what makes the best films. You won't be disappointed if you are a fan of the little film gems some people too often forget. You'll be glad you went "there."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A dry film is about ignorance and politics and when are they not to be mentioned in the same breath
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Marc Israel
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A twist on the old adage "everything we ever need to know we learned in kindergarten", "Being There" holds forth that American politics, underwritten by polls, commercials and pop culture, would benefit and bite the hook of a simple gardeners' working words. Plant the seed, water it and watch it grow. Based in the same city that brought us Watergate, and pitted against the television backdrop of American social awareness and commercialization, the film captures the time quite well. Love the Diadario music scoring Chances coming out scene and love Peter Sellers as Chance Gardener as his optimism is born and running viral, as it was in 1979. Of course it wouldn't go far without the connected but tainted Shirley McLaine and her flirtatious endeavors.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A sweet/sad surrealist fantasy, profound and delightful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    middleburg
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I LOVE Being There. Captivated the first time i saw it, I probably have watched this film a dozen times since -- each time immersed in the fantasy world of Chance and Eve and her billionaire beau, and the President of the United States, and the Russian Ambassador and all of the loony/quirky/needy/flawed/normal/outlandish characters eager, even desperate, to connect, to understand, to cope with and ultimately love and embrace a too-often incomprehensible world, thanks to the "insight" of the magical Chance. There are countless moments to cherish in this film, thanks to the subtle, surprising, carefully calibrated direction of the one and only Hal Ashby and the impeccable comic timing of the seasoned pros Melvyn Douglas and Shirley MacLaine, playing the magisterial Benjamin Rand and his beautiful sexy "concubine" Eve, with a script that keeps the viewer endlessly intrigued, with a combination of laugh-out-loud moments, moments of genuine suspense, and scenes of tenderness and even a few tears. Ultimately the film belongs to Peter Seller's brilliant character, Chance, with his sweet/calming, genuine/wise spirit; Chance -- on the street, in the elevator, at dinner, in a car, at a party, on TV, providing the laughs, but also the comfort, insight, warmth and wisdom. An unforgettable character in an unforgettable film. You know, it's time for me to see this film again!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A sweet/sad surrealist fantasy, profound and delightful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    middleburg
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I LOVE Being There. Captivated the first time i saw it, I probably have watched this film a dozen times since -- each time immersed in the fantasy world of Chance and Eve and her billionaire beau, and the President of the United States, and the Russian Ambassador and all of the loony/quirky/needy/flawed/normal/outlandish characters eager, even desperate, to connect, to understand, to cope with and ultimately love and embrace a too-often incomprehensible world, thanks to the "insight" of the magical Chance. There are countless moments to cherish in this film, thanks to the subtle, surprising, carefully calibrated direction of the one and only Hal Ashby and the impeccable comic timing of the seasoned pros Melvyn Douglas and Shirley MacLaine, playing the magisterial Benjamin Rand and his beautiful sexy "concubine" Eve, with a script that keeps the viewer endlessly intrigued, with a combination of laugh-out-loud moments, moments of genuine suspense, and scenes of tenderness and even a few tears. Ultimately the film belongs to Peter Seller's brilliant character, Chance, with his sweet/calming, genuine/wise spirit; Chance -- on the street, in the elevator, at dinner, in a car, at a party, on TV, providing the laughs, but also the comfort, insight, warmth and wisdom. An unforgettable character in an unforgettable film. You know, it's time for me to see this film again!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The last performance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cedde6
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Long before Forrest Gump there was another simple man who changed the world he lived in. Not by design of course but by simply being there. Written by Jerzy Kozinski from his own novel and beautifully directed by Hal Ashby "Being There" tells the story of Chance, a simpleton gardener who has never been allowed out of the house in which he has lived in and worked for all his life. When the "old man" who owns the house passes away, Chance is then forced to leave and face the outside world where his innocence and simplicity are mistaken for financial savvy and wisdom with a penchant for gardening metaphors. Hal Ashby, one of the most underestimated director of the New Hollywood period delivered in its tail end (1979) this little gem which I watched, caught between bouts of laughter and consternation; each and every single cringe induced not by Chance but the inability of the people who meet him to see the man for what he truly is. Chance never claims (quite literally) to be anything is not and only people's assumptions propel this film from one absurdity to the next, and in the midst of all this, Chance strolls along, innocent, detached and somewhat weightless, to a quiet conclusion where the world keeps on guessing and plotting. And so, Hal Ashby pokes gentle fun at the establishment through his characters' delusions and, for some, the frenzy they get themselves into but he and Kozinski never let any political stance overshadow a story which in nature is both heart-warming and melancholic. What the film boils down to is however jaded and so-called sophisticated people are, in their heart of hardened hearts, they all are ultimately attracted, in some way or the other, to the simplicity, the kindness and the innocence of Chance the gardener. Needless to say Peter Sellers' performance is absolutely incredible giving the fact that it is so subdued, delicate and seemingly effortless. This was his last performance and it is truly the stuff of legend. Shirley McLaine is equally amazing in her comedic timing as a wife soon to be widow finding solace and romance in Chance's soft approach to life in general. In the end, this is both an emotional comedy and a light-hearted drama. This defies labels. This is a work of sheer brilliance from Hal Ashby, and an astounding conclusion to Peter Sellers' incredible career.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stupendous. Sellers' Best Performance.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Humphrey Fish
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Chance, a simple gardener, has never left the estate until his employer dies. His simple TV-informed utterances are mistaken for profundity. This was the last movie that Peter Sellers made before his death (The Fiendish Plot of Dr. Fu Manchu doesn't really count), and it is without a doubt his best role, as great as he was in The Pink Panther films, this film is his best performance, he was absolutely stupendous, or even better, the whole movie was stupendous! That's right. Being There is a stupendous movie, in which everybody in it is wonderful. This movie is a comedy-drama film, meaning that while it does have some laughs in it, it is mostly a serious movie, in some parts, the movie is even worth shedding a few tears. Peter Sellers really surprised me, because I was used to seeing him in comedy roles, such as the Pink Panther movies, and Dr. Strangelove, but here, he was in a class by himself, he was absolutely, totally, and completely incredible! It just goes to show what a great actor he truly was, and it is such a pity that he had to die so young, oh well, he may be gone, but he certainly will not be forgotten. While Peter Sellers gave the best performance in the movie, everyone else was also fabulous. Jack Warden gave a wonderful performance as The President, and Shirley MacLaine was marvelous as Eve Rand. However, Melvyn Douglas as Benjamin Rand was something else. Douglas was second only to Peter Sellers in the acting department, he was old, but he could still act, and fabulously too. He won his second Academy Award For Best Supporting Actor for his role in Being There (his first was for Hud in 1963), and it was a very well deserved win, as he was outstanding. Peter Sellers was nominated for Best Actor, and I could see where he would be, because this is his best performance in my opinion. All in all, this is an excellent movie, it is one of the best movies of 1979, and one of the best movies of the 1970's. And therefore, I could say that this movie is one of the greatest movies that I have ever seen. Being There is like no Peter Sellers movie that I have ever seen, rather than playing a comedy role, he plays a serious role, and he does an absolutely wonderful job at it too. All in all, Being There is a movie that has got everything that you would expect to see in a great movie, great acting, great writing, and great directing. Sadly, Peter Sellers would die not long after making this movie at the young age of 54, just think of what he could have accomplished if he would have lived longer. But anyway, this movie is one of the greatest movies ever made, it's a masterpiece brought to us by Hal Ashby. Sellers, Douglas, Warden, and MacLaine all did remarkable jobs with their acting, but Sellers and Douglas being the best of the four. When you watch this movie, you will see Peter Sellers in a role like you've never seen him before, a role that proves what a really talented actor he was. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Life is a state of mind
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Artimidor Federkiel
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The maid Louise describes the main character of this most unusual film as "stuffed with rice pudding between his ears". He can't read or write and is "short-changed by the Lord and dumb as a jackass". His window to the world is the TV, which he enjoys to imitate, other than that he is nothing more than a walking mirror: flat, reflecting what everybody wants to see in him, talking back what they want to hear. The gardener Chance - or, as some who misheard like to call him, Chancey Gardiner - is just there, in suit and tie, an empty mind, alas, sans garden. But being there is enough if you're in the right place and actually are as shallow as others consider you profound. Filmed right Jerzy Kosinski's engaging novel makes the perfect mix for a highly intelligent, though intentionally slow comedy for those who like to have it the more thoughtful way. The film benefits greatly from Peter Seller's complete immersion in the straightness of his character, which is arguably his best role. And Eumir Deodato's version of Strauss' "Also Sprach Zarathustra" as he steps out of the house for the first time in years is nearly as striking as when Kubrick opened "2001" with the original. Unforgettable is the superb ending, which breaks out of the comedic back and forth and goes a decisive, daring step further. It reminds me of another king of comedy, Bill Cosby, and the joke in his stand-up routine where he relates that he wasn't quite sure about his name when he was little. Quite often his parents used to shout out when they saw him: "Jesus Christ!" In the same innocent way our gardener Chance appears to the viewer as the savior himself when the movie ends and when we can still hear the film's final message ringing in our ears: "Life is a state of mind." Well, and ignorance is bliss.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Don't waste your time on Being There
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bluejacquet
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Being There starts with a clever and promising plot that disintegrates into nothingness, leaving the viewer with no answers - only questions. If you like movies with weird, unexplained endings and unfinished story lines, then by all means go see it. It seems that Peter Sellers is often lauded for his 'brilliant' acting in this movie, but really anyone could pull off the role of Chance The Gardener. As Chance is just a simpleton, all one needs to do is to stare blankly ahead and speak softly without inflection, emotion nor enthusiasm in your voice and, presto, you're acting brilliantly. Give me a break.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Classic!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Adapted from the 1971 novella written by Jerzy Kosinski, 'Being There' is A Classic. A Deliciously Written film, that comes in-tact with Tight Direction & Memorable Performances. 'Being There' Synopsis: Chance, a simple gardener, has never left the estate until his employer dies. His simple TV-informed utterances are mistaken for profundity. 'Being There' is A Classic, because it is unforgettable. The humor, the characters, the entire set-up, everything, comes across as flawless & incomparable. Kosinski and Robert C. Jones.'s Screenplay is Delicious. It narrates a wonderful story, with loads of humor. Hal Ashby's Direction is Tight. Cinematography is perfect. Editing & Art Design, are good. Performance-Wise: Peter Sellers as Chance, delivers one of his best performances. The legendary actor sinks his teeth into the character & brings it out with flying colors. Melvyn Douglas, in an Oscar-Winning Performance, is memorable. Shirley MacLaine is fantastic, as always. Jack Warden does wonders. Richard A. Dysart is pleasant. David Clennon leaves a mark. On the whole, 'Being There' is a Winner All The Way. Two Thumbs Up!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Seller's best work
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jerzy kozinsky wrote this brilliant political satire and adapted it for the big screen. Chance Gardner is played with subtle genius by Peter Sellers in what I consider his most complete performance. Chance is a man from nowhere with no history and a childlike innocence in a world of corruption and cynicism. He is accidentally hit by a limousine carrying a Washington D.C. king maker. Chance is put up in an estate and through a series of events becomes a media darling for reciting simplistic remarks which are taken for being pearls of deep wisdom, a variation of "the emperor has no clothes." Seller's is Forrest Gump on steroids, one of the most incredible performances ever captured on film. This should be required viewing at all acting classes. The final scene is beautiful and will fill you with a sense of wonderment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Must See
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mickmerivel
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    By far one of the best films of Peter Sellers. Too often overshadowed by the Pink Panther, this film brings you something completely different. For the modern audience and the younger viewer let it be known that this film does not move at the pace you are probably accustomed to, though if you truly do love a good story and are a fan of film and its telling, then you will love Being There. I find it absolutely hysterical, and upon each view I see something I've missed before. And a very many times I hear a line or see something I've missed before as well. Great films that both are entertaining and subtle in their delivery can be the best of entertainment, and this is such a film. I don't want to ruin the fantastic experience of seeing such an amazing flick, so I'll simply say, see It. Remember not to turn it off half way through, though you may feel it a bit slow, it'll be worth your wait and something you'll love to discuss with others'. That attribute is very often what makes the best films. You won't be disappointed if you are a fan of the little film gems some people too often forget. You'll be glad you went "there."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A dry film is about ignorance and politics and when are they not to be mentioned in the same breath
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Marc Israel
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A twist on the old adage "everything we ever need to know we learned in kindergarten", "Being There" holds forth that American politics, underwritten by polls, commercials and pop culture, would benefit and bite the hook of a simple gardeners' working words. Plant the seed, water it and watch it grow. Based in the same city that brought us Watergate, and pitted against the television backdrop of American social awareness and commercialization, the film captures the time quite well. Love the Diadario music scoring Chances coming out scene and love Peter Sellers as Chance Gardener as his optimism is born and running viral, as it was in 1979. Of course it wouldn't go far without the connected but tainted Shirley McLaine and her flirtatious endeavors.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A sweet/sad surrealist fantasy, profound and delightful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    middleburg
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I LOVE Being There. Captivated the first time i saw it, I probably have watched this film a dozen times since -- each time immersed in the fantasy world of Chance and Eve and her billionaire beau, and the President of the United States, and the Russian Ambassador and all of the loony/quirky/needy/flawed/normal/outlandish characters eager, even desperate, to connect, to understand, to cope with and ultimately love and embrace a too-often incomprehensible world, thanks to the "insight" of the magical Chance. There are countless moments to cherish in this film, thanks to the subtle, surprising, carefully calibrated direction of the one and only Hal Ashby and the impeccable comic timing of the seasoned pros Melvyn Douglas and Shirley MacLaine, playing the magisterial Benjamin Rand and his beautiful sexy "concubine" Eve, with a script that keeps the viewer endlessly intrigued, with a combination of laugh-out-loud moments, moments of genuine suspense, and scenes of tenderness and even a few tears. Ultimately the film belongs to Peter Seller's brilliant character, Chance, with his sweet/calming, genuine/wise spirit; Chance -- on the street, in the elevator, at dinner, in a car, at a party, on TV, providing the laughs, but also the comfort, insight, warmth and wisdom. An unforgettable character in an unforgettable film. You know, it's time for me to see this film again!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A sweet/sad surrealist fantasy, profound and delightful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    middleburg
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I LOVE Being There. Captivated the first time i saw it, I probably have watched this film a dozen times since -- each time immersed in the fantasy world of Chance and Eve and her billionaire beau, and the President of the United States, and the Russian Ambassador and all of the loony/quirky/needy/flawed/normal/outlandish characters eager, even desperate, to connect, to understand, to cope with and ultimately love and embrace a too-often incomprehensible world, thanks to the "insight" of the magical Chance. There are countless moments to cherish in this film, thanks to the subtle, surprising, carefully calibrated direction of the one and only Hal Ashby and the impeccable comic timing of the seasoned pros Melvyn Douglas and Shirley MacLaine, playing the magisterial Benjamin Rand and his beautiful sexy "concubine" Eve, with a script that keeps the viewer endlessly intrigued, with a combination of laugh-out-loud moments, moments of genuine suspense, and scenes of tenderness and even a few tears. Ultimately the film belongs to Peter Seller's brilliant character, Chance, with his sweet/calming, genuine/wise spirit; Chance -- on the street, in the elevator, at dinner, in a car, at a party, on TV, providing the laughs, but also the comfort, insight, warmth and wisdom. An unforgettable character in an unforgettable film. You know, it's time for me to see this film again!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The last performance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cedde6
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Long before Forrest Gump there was another simple man who changed the world he lived in. Not by design of course but by simply being there. Written by Jerzy Kozinski from his own novel and beautifully directed by Hal Ashby "Being There" tells the story of Chance, a simpleton gardener who has never been allowed out of the house in which he has lived in and worked for all his life. When the "old man" who owns the house passes away, Chance is then forced to leave and face the outside world where his innocence and simplicity are mistaken for financial savvy and wisdom with a penchant for gardening metaphors. Hal Ashby, one of the most underestimated director of the New Hollywood period delivered in its tail end (1979) this little gem which I watched, caught between bouts of laughter and consternation; each and every single cringe induced not by Chance but the inability of the people who meet him to see the man for what he truly is. Chance never claims (quite literally) to be anything is not and only people's assumptions propel this film from one absurdity to the next, and in the midst of all this, Chance strolls along, innocent, detached and somewhat weightless, to a quiet conclusion where the world keeps on guessing and plotting. And so, Hal Ashby pokes gentle fun at the establishment through his characters' delusions and, for some, the frenzy they get themselves into but he and Kozinski never let any political stance overshadow a story which in nature is both heart-warming and melancholic. What the film boils down to is however jaded and so-called sophisticated people are, in their heart of hardened hearts, they all are ultimately attracted, in some way or the other, to the simplicity, the kindness and the innocence of Chance the gardener. Needless to say Peter Sellers' performance is absolutely incredible giving the fact that it is so subdued, delicate and seemingly effortless. This was his last performance and it is truly the stuff of legend. Shirley McLaine is equally amazing in her comedic timing as a wife soon to be widow finding solace and romance in Chance's soft approach to life in general. In the end, this is both an emotional comedy and a light-hearted drama. This defies labels. This is a work of sheer brilliance from Hal Ashby, and an astounding conclusion to Peter Sellers' incredible career.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stupendous. Sellers' Best Performance.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Humphrey Fish
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Chance, a simple gardener, has never left the estate until his employer dies. His simple TV-informed utterances are mistaken for profundity. This was the last movie that Peter Sellers made before his death (The Fiendish Plot of Dr. Fu Manchu doesn't really count), and it is without a doubt his best role, as great as he was in The Pink Panther films, this film is his best performance, he was absolutely stupendous, or even better, the whole movie was stupendous! That's right. Being There is a stupendous movie, in which everybody in it is wonderful. This movie is a comedy-drama film, meaning that while it does have some laughs in it, it is mostly a serious movie, in some parts, the movie is even worth shedding a few tears. Peter Sellers really surprised me, because I was used to seeing him in comedy roles, such as the Pink Panther movies, and Dr. Strangelove, but here, he was in a class by himself, he was absolutely, totally, and completely incredible! It just goes to show what a great actor he truly was, and it is such a pity that he had to die so young, oh well, he may be gone, but he certainly will not be forgotten. While Peter Sellers gave the best performance in the movie, everyone else was also fabulous. Jack Warden gave a wonderful performance as The President, and Shirley MacLaine was marvelous as Eve Rand. However, Melvyn Douglas as Benjamin Rand was something else. Douglas was second only to Peter Sellers in the acting department, he was old, but he could still act, and fabulously too. He won his second Academy Award For Best Supporting Actor for his role in Being There (his first was for Hud in 1963), and it was a very well deserved win, as he was outstanding. Peter Sellers was nominated for Best Actor, and I could see where he would be, because this is his best performance in my opinion. All in all, this is an excellent movie, it is one of the best movies of 1979, and one of the best movies of the 1970's. And therefore, I could say that this movie is one of the greatest movies that I have ever seen. Being There is like no Peter Sellers movie that I have ever seen, rather than playing a comedy role, he plays a serious role, and he does an absolutely wonderful job at it too. All in all, Being There is a movie that has got everything that you would expect to see in a great movie, great acting, great writing, and great directing. Sadly, Peter Sellers would die not long after making this movie at the young age of 54, just think of what he could have accomplished if he would have lived longer. But anyway, this movie is one of the greatest movies ever made, it's a masterpiece brought to us by Hal Ashby. Sellers, Douglas, Warden, and MacLaine all did remarkable jobs with their acting, but Sellers and Douglas being the best of the four. When you watch this movie, you will see Peter Sellers in a role like you've never seen him before, a role that proves what a really talented actor he was. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Life is a state of mind
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Artimidor Federkiel
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The maid Louise describes the main character of this most unusual film as "stuffed with rice pudding between his ears". He can't read or write and is "short-changed by the Lord and dumb as a jackass". His window to the world is the TV, which he enjoys to imitate, other than that he is nothing more than a walking mirror: flat, reflecting what everybody wants to see in him, talking back what they want to hear. The gardener Chance - or, as some who misheard like to call him, Chancey Gardiner - is just there, in suit and tie, an empty mind, alas, sans garden. But being there is enough if you're in the right place and actually are as shallow as others consider you profound. Filmed right Jerzy Kosinski's engaging novel makes the perfect mix for a highly intelligent, though intentionally slow comedy for those who like to have it the more thoughtful way. The film benefits greatly from Peter Seller's complete immersion in the straightness of his character, which is arguably his best role. And Eumir Deodato's version of Strauss' "Also Sprach Zarathustra" as he steps out of the house for the first time in years is nearly as striking as when Kubrick opened "2001" with the original. Unforgettable is the superb ending, which breaks out of the comedic back and forth and goes a decisive, daring step further. It reminds me of another king of comedy, Bill Cosby, and the joke in his stand-up routine where he relates that he wasn't quite sure about his name when he was little. Quite often his parents used to shout out when they saw him: "Jesus Christ!" In the same innocent way our gardener Chance appears to the viewer as the savior himself when the movie ends and when we can still hear the film's final message ringing in our ears: "Life is a state of mind." Well, and ignorance is bliss.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Don't waste your time on Being There
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bluejacquet
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Being There starts with a clever and promising plot that disintegrates into nothingness, leaving the viewer with no answers - only questions. If you like movies with weird, unexplained endings and unfinished story lines, then by all means go see it. It seems that Peter Sellers is often lauded for his 'brilliant' acting in this movie, but really anyone could pull off the role of Chance The Gardener. As Chance is just a simpleton, all one needs to do is to stare blankly ahead and speak softly without inflection, emotion nor enthusiasm in your voice and, presto, you're acting brilliantly. Give me a break.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Classic!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Adapted from the 1971 novella written by Jerzy Kosinski, 'Being There' is A Classic. A Deliciously Written film, that comes in-tact with Tight Direction & Memorable Performances. 'Being There' Synopsis: Chance, a simple gardener, has never left the estate until his employer dies. His simple TV-informed utterances are mistaken for profundity. 'Being There' is A Classic, because it is unforgettable. The humor, the characters, the entire set-up, everything, comes across as flawless & incomparable. Kosinski and Robert C. Jones.'s Screenplay is Delicious. It narrates a wonderful story, with loads of humor. Hal Ashby's Direction is Tight. Cinematography is perfect. Editing & Art Design, are good. Performance-Wise: Peter Sellers as Chance, delivers one of his best performances. The legendary actor sinks his teeth into the character & brings it out with flying colors. Melvyn Douglas, in an Oscar-Winning Performance, is memorable. Shirley MacLaine is fantastic, as always. Jack Warden does wonders. Richard A. Dysart is pleasant. David Clennon leaves a mark. On the whole, 'Being There' is a Winner All The Way. Two Thumbs Up!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Seller's best work
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jerzy kozinsky wrote this brilliant political satire and adapted it for the big screen. Chance Gardner is played with subtle genius by Peter Sellers in what I consider his most complete performance. Chance is a man from nowhere with no history and a childlike innocence in a world of corruption and cynicism. He is accidentally hit by a limousine carrying a Washington D.C. king maker. Chance is put up in an estate and through a series of events becomes a media darling for reciting simplistic remarks which are taken for being pearls of deep wisdom, a variation of "the emperor has no clothes." Seller's is Forrest Gump on steroids, one of the most incredible performances ever captured on film. This should be required viewing at all acting classes. The final scene is beautiful and will fill you with a sense of wonderment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Must See
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mickmerivel
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    By far one of the best films of Peter Sellers. Too often overshadowed by the Pink Panther, this film brings you something completely different. For the modern audience and the younger viewer let it be known that this film does not move at the pace you are probably accustomed to, though if you truly do love a good story and are a fan of film and its telling, then you will love Being There. I find it absolutely hysterical, and upon each view I see something I've missed before. And a very many times I hear a line or see something I've missed before as well. Great films that both are entertaining and subtle in their delivery can be the best of entertainment, and this is such a film. I don't want to ruin the fantastic experience of seeing such an amazing flick, so I'll simply say, see It. Remember not to turn it off half way through, though you may feel it a bit slow, it'll be worth your wait and something you'll love to discuss with others'. That attribute is very often what makes the best films. You won't be disappointed if you are a fan of the little film gems some people too often forget. You'll be glad you went "there."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A dry film is about ignorance and politics and when are they not to be mentioned in the same breath
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Marc Israel
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A twist on the old adage "everything we ever need to know we learned in kindergarten", "Being There" holds forth that American politics, underwritten by polls, commercials and pop culture, would benefit and bite the hook of a simple gardeners' working words. Plant the seed, water it and watch it grow. Based in the same city that brought us Watergate, and pitted against the television backdrop of American social awareness and commercialization, the film captures the time quite well. Love the Diadario music scoring Chances coming out scene and love Peter Sellers as Chance Gardener as his optimism is born and running viral, as it was in 1979. Of course it wouldn't go far without the connected but tainted Shirley McLaine and her flirtatious endeavors.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A sweet/sad surrealist fantasy, profound and delightful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    middleburg
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I LOVE Being There. Captivated the first time i saw it, I probably have watched this film a dozen times since -- each time immersed in the fantasy world of Chance and Eve and her billionaire beau, and the President of the United States, and the Russian Ambassador and all of the loony/quirky/needy/flawed/normal/outlandish characters eager, even desperate, to connect, to understand, to cope with and ultimately love and embrace a too-often incomprehensible world, thanks to the "insight" of the magical Chance. There are countless moments to cherish in this film, thanks to the subtle, surprising, carefully calibrated direction of the one and only Hal Ashby and the impeccable comic timing of the seasoned pros Melvyn Douglas and Shirley MacLaine, playing the magisterial Benjamin Rand and his beautiful sexy "concubine" Eve, with a script that keeps the viewer endlessly intrigued, with a combination of laugh-out-loud moments, moments of genuine suspense, and scenes of tenderness and even a few tears. Ultimately the film belongs to Peter Seller's brilliant character, Chance, with his sweet/calming, genuine/wise spirit; Chance -- on the street, in the elevator, at dinner, in a car, at a party, on TV, providing the laughs, but also the comfort, insight, warmth and wisdom. An unforgettable character in an unforgettable film. You know, it's time for me to see this film again!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A sweet/sad surrealist fantasy, profound and delightful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    middleburg
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I LOVE Being There. Captivated the first time i saw it, I probably have watched this film a dozen times since -- each time immersed in the fantasy world of Chance and Eve and her billionaire beau, and the President of the United States, and the Russian Ambassador and all of the loony/quirky/needy/flawed/normal/outlandish characters eager, even desperate, to connect, to understand, to cope with and ultimately love and embrace a too-often incomprehensible world, thanks to the "insight" of the magical Chance. There are countless moments to cherish in this film, thanks to the subtle, surprising, carefully calibrated direction of the one and only Hal Ashby and the impeccable comic timing of the seasoned pros Melvyn Douglas and Shirley MacLaine, playing the magisterial Benjamin Rand and his beautiful sexy "concubine" Eve, with a script that keeps the viewer endlessly intrigued, with a combination of laugh-out-loud moments, moments of genuine suspense, and scenes of tenderness and even a few tears. Ultimately the film belongs to Peter Seller's brilliant character, Chance, with his sweet/calming, genuine/wise spirit; Chance -- on the street, in the elevator, at dinner, in a car, at a party, on TV, providing the laughs, but also the comfort, insight, warmth and wisdom. An unforgettable character in an unforgettable film. You know, it's time for me to see this film again!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The last performance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cedde6
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Long before Forrest Gump there was another simple man who changed the world he lived in. Not by design of course but by simply being there. Written by Jerzy Kozinski from his own novel and beautifully directed by Hal Ashby "Being There" tells the story of Chance, a simpleton gardener who has never been allowed out of the house in which he has lived in and worked for all his life. When the "old man" who owns the house passes away, Chance is then forced to leave and face the outside world where his innocence and simplicity are mistaken for financial savvy and wisdom with a penchant for gardening metaphors. Hal Ashby, one of the most underestimated director of the New Hollywood period delivered in its tail end (1979) this little gem which I watched, caught between bouts of laughter and consternation; each and every single cringe induced not by Chance but the inability of the people who meet him to see the man for what he truly is. Chance never claims (quite literally) to be anything is not and only people's assumptions propel this film from one absurdity to the next, and in the midst of all this, Chance strolls along, innocent, detached and somewhat weightless, to a quiet conclusion where the world keeps on guessing and plotting. And so, Hal Ashby pokes gentle fun at the establishment through his characters' delusions and, for some, the frenzy they get themselves into but he and Kozinski never let any political stance overshadow a story which in nature is both heart-warming and melancholic. What the film boils down to is however jaded and so-called sophisticated people are, in their heart of hardened hearts, they all are ultimately attracted, in some way or the other, to the simplicity, the kindness and the innocence of Chance the gardener. Needless to say Peter Sellers' performance is absolutely incredible giving the fact that it is so subdued, delicate and seemingly effortless. This was his last performance and it is truly the stuff of legend. Shirley McLaine is equally amazing in her comedic timing as a wife soon to be widow finding solace and romance in Chance's soft approach to life in general. In the end, this is both an emotional comedy and a light-hearted drama. This defies labels. This is a work of sheer brilliance from Hal Ashby, and an astounding conclusion to Peter Sellers' incredible career.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stupendous. Sellers' Best Performance.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Humphrey Fish
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Chance, a simple gardener, has never left the estate until his employer dies. His simple TV-informed utterances are mistaken for profundity. This was the last movie that Peter Sellers made before his death (The Fiendish Plot of Dr. Fu Manchu doesn't really count), and it is without a doubt his best role, as great as he was in The Pink Panther films, this film is his best performance, he was absolutely stupendous, or even better, the whole movie was stupendous! That's right. Being There is a stupendous movie, in which everybody in it is wonderful. This movie is a comedy-drama film, meaning that while it does have some laughs in it, it is mostly a serious movie, in some parts, the movie is even worth shedding a few tears. Peter Sellers really surprised me, because I was used to seeing him in comedy roles, such as the Pink Panther movies, and Dr. Strangelove, but here, he was in a class by himself, he was absolutely, totally, and completely incredible! It just goes to show what a great actor he truly was, and it is such a pity that he had to die so young, oh well, he may be gone, but he certainly will not be forgotten. While Peter Sellers gave the best performance in the movie, everyone else was also fabulous. Jack Warden gave a wonderful performance as The President, and Shirley MacLaine was marvelous as Eve Rand. However, Melvyn Douglas as Benjamin Rand was something else. Douglas was second only to Peter Sellers in the acting department, he was old, but he could still act, and fabulously too. He won his second Academy Award For Best Supporting Actor for his role in Being There (his first was for Hud in 1963), and it was a very well deserved win, as he was outstanding. Peter Sellers was nominated for Best Actor, and I could see where he would be, because this is his best performance in my opinion. All in all, this is an excellent movie, it is one of the best movies of 1979, and one of the best movies of the 1970's. And therefore, I could say that this movie is one of the greatest movies that I have ever seen. Being There is like no Peter Sellers movie that I have ever seen, rather than playing a comedy role, he plays a serious role, and he does an absolutely wonderful job at it too. All in all, Being There is a movie that has got everything that you would expect to see in a great movie, great acting, great writing, and great directing. Sadly, Peter Sellers would die not long after making this movie at the young age of 54, just think of what he could have accomplished if he would have lived longer. But anyway, this movie is one of the greatest movies ever made, it's a masterpiece brought to us by Hal Ashby. Sellers, Douglas, Warden, and MacLaine all did remarkable jobs with their acting, but Sellers and Douglas being the best of the four. When you watch this movie, you will see Peter Sellers in a role like you've never seen him before, a role that proves what a really talented actor he was. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Life is a state of mind
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Artimidor Federkiel
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The maid Louise describes the main character of this most unusual film as "stuffed with rice pudding between his ears". He can't read or write and is "short-changed by the Lord and dumb as a jackass". His window to the world is the TV, which he enjoys to imitate, other than that he is nothing more than a walking mirror: flat, reflecting what everybody wants to see in him, talking back what they want to hear. The gardener Chance - or, as some who misheard like to call him, Chancey Gardiner - is just there, in suit and tie, an empty mind, alas, sans garden. But being there is enough if you're in the right place and actually are as shallow as others consider you profound. Filmed right Jerzy Kosinski's engaging novel makes the perfect mix for a highly intelligent, though intentionally slow comedy for those who like to have it the more thoughtful way. The film benefits greatly from Peter Seller's complete immersion in the straightness of his character, which is arguably his best role. And Eumir Deodato's version of Strauss' "Also Sprach Zarathustra" as he steps out of the house for the first time in years is nearly as striking as when Kubrick opened "2001" with the original. Unforgettable is the superb ending, which breaks out of the comedic back and forth and goes a decisive, daring step further. It reminds me of another king of comedy, Bill Cosby, and the joke in his stand-up routine where he relates that he wasn't quite sure about his name when he was little. Quite often his parents used to shout out when they saw him: "Jesus Christ!" In the same innocent way our gardener Chance appears to the viewer as the savior himself when the movie ends and when we can still hear the film's final message ringing in our ears: "Life is a state of mind." Well, and ignorance is bliss.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Don't waste your time on Being There
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bluejacquet
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Being There starts with a clever and promising plot that disintegrates into nothingness, leaving the viewer with no answers - only questions. If you like movies with weird, unexplained endings and unfinished story lines, then by all means go see it. It seems that Peter Sellers is often lauded for his 'brilliant' acting in this movie, but really anyone could pull off the role of Chance The Gardener. As Chance is just a simpleton, all one needs to do is to stare blankly ahead and speak softly without inflection, emotion nor enthusiasm in your voice and, presto, you're acting brilliantly. Give me a break.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Classic!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Adapted from the 1971 novella written by Jerzy Kosinski, 'Being There' is A Classic. A Deliciously Written film, that comes in-tact with Tight Direction & Memorable Performances. 'Being There' Synopsis: Chance, a simple gardener, has never left the estate until his employer dies. His simple TV-informed utterances are mistaken for profundity. 'Being There' is A Classic, because it is unforgettable. The humor, the characters, the entire set-up, everything, comes across as flawless & incomparable. Kosinski and Robert C. Jones.'s Screenplay is Delicious. It narrates a wonderful story, with loads of humor. Hal Ashby's Direction is Tight. Cinematography is perfect. Editing & Art Design, are good. Performance-Wise: Peter Sellers as Chance, delivers one of his best performances. The legendary actor sinks his teeth into the character & brings it out with flying colors. Melvyn Douglas, in an Oscar-Winning Performance, is memorable. Shirley MacLaine is fantastic, as always. Jack Warden does wonders. Richard A. Dysart is pleasant. David Clennon leaves a mark. On the whole, 'Being There' is a Winner All The Way. Two Thumbs Up!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Seller's best work
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jerzy kozinsky wrote this brilliant political satire and adapted it for the big screen. Chance Gardner is played with subtle genius by Peter Sellers in what I consider his most complete performance. Chance is a man from nowhere with no history and a childlike innocence in a world of corruption and cynicism. He is accidentally hit by a limousine carrying a Washington D.C. king maker. Chance is put up in an estate and through a series of events becomes a media darling for reciting simplistic remarks which are taken for being pearls of deep wisdom, a variation of "the emperor has no clothes." Seller's is Forrest Gump on steroids, one of the most incredible performances ever captured on film. This should be required viewing at all acting classes. The final scene is beautiful and will fill you with a sense of wonderment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Must See
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mickmerivel
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    By far one of the best films of Peter Sellers. Too often overshadowed by the Pink Panther, this film brings you something completely different. For the modern audience and the younger viewer let it be known that this film does not move at the pace you are probably accustomed to, though if you truly do love a good story and are a fan of film and its telling, then you will love Being There. I find it absolutely hysterical, and upon each view I see something I've missed before. And a very many times I hear a line or see something I've missed before as well. Great films that both are entertaining and subtle in their delivery can be the best of entertainment, and this is such a film. I don't want to ruin the fantastic experience of seeing such an amazing flick, so I'll simply say, see It. Remember not to turn it off half way through, though you may feel it a bit slow, it'll be worth your wait and something you'll love to discuss with others'. That attribute is very often what makes the best films. You won't be disappointed if you are a fan of the little film gems some people too often forget. You'll be glad you went "there."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A dry film is about ignorance and politics and when are they not to be mentioned in the same breath
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Marc Israel
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A twist on the old adage "everything we ever need to know we learned in kindergarten", "Being There" holds forth that American politics, underwritten by polls, commercials and pop culture, would benefit and bite the hook of a simple gardeners' working words. Plant the seed, water it and watch it grow. Based in the same city that brought us Watergate, and pitted against the television backdrop of American social awareness and commercialization, the film captures the time quite well. Love the Diadario music scoring Chances coming out scene and love Peter Sellers as Chance Gardener as his optimism is born and running viral, as it was in 1979. Of course it wouldn't go far without the connected but tainted Shirley McLaine and her flirtatious endeavors.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A sweet/sad surrealist fantasy, profound and delightful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    middleburg
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I LOVE Being There. Captivated the first time i saw it, I probably have watched this film a dozen times since -- each time immersed in the fantasy world of Chance and Eve and her billionaire beau, and the President of the United States, and the Russian Ambassador and all of the loony/quirky/needy/flawed/normal/outlandish characters eager, even desperate, to connect, to understand, to cope with and ultimately love and embrace a too-often incomprehensible world, thanks to the "insight" of the magical Chance. There are countless moments to cherish in this film, thanks to the subtle, surprising, carefully calibrated direction of the one and only Hal Ashby and the impeccable comic timing of the seasoned pros Melvyn Douglas and Shirley MacLaine, playing the magisterial Benjamin Rand and his beautiful sexy "concubine" Eve, with a script that keeps the viewer endlessly intrigued, with a combination of laugh-out-loud moments, moments of genuine suspense, and scenes of tenderness and even a few tears. Ultimately the film belongs to Peter Seller's brilliant character, Chance, with his sweet/calming, genuine/wise spirit; Chance -- on the street, in the elevator, at dinner, in a car, at a party, on TV, providing the laughs, but also the comfort, insight, warmth and wisdom. An unforgettable character in an unforgettable film. You know, it's time for me to see this film again!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A sweet/sad surrealist fantasy, profound and delightful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    middleburg
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I LOVE Being There. Captivated the first time i saw it, I probably have watched this film a dozen times since -- each time immersed in the fantasy world of Chance and Eve and her billionaire beau, and the President of the United States, and the Russian Ambassador and all of the loony/quirky/needy/flawed/normal/outlandish characters eager, even desperate, to connect, to understand, to cope with and ultimately love and embrace a too-often incomprehensible world, thanks to the "insight" of the magical Chance. There are countless moments to cherish in this film, thanks to the subtle, surprising, carefully calibrated direction of the one and only Hal Ashby and the impeccable comic timing of the seasoned pros Melvyn Douglas and Shirley MacLaine, playing the magisterial Benjamin Rand and his beautiful sexy "concubine" Eve, with a script that keeps the viewer endlessly intrigued, with a combination of laugh-out-loud moments, moments of genuine suspense, and scenes of tenderness and even a few tears. Ultimately the film belongs to Peter Seller's brilliant character, Chance, with his sweet/calming, genuine/wise spirit; Chance -- on the street, in the elevator, at dinner, in a car, at a party, on TV, providing the laughs, but also the comfort, insight, warmth and wisdom. An unforgettable character in an unforgettable film. You know, it's time for me to see this film again!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The last performance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cedde6
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Long before Forrest Gump there was another simple man who changed the world he lived in. Not by design of course but by simply being there. Written by Jerzy Kozinski from his own novel and beautifully directed by Hal Ashby "Being There" tells the story of Chance, a simpleton gardener who has never been allowed out of the house in which he has lived in and worked for all his life. When the "old man" who owns the house passes away, Chance is then forced to leave and face the outside world where his innocence and simplicity are mistaken for financial savvy and wisdom with a penchant for gardening metaphors. Hal Ashby, one of the most underestimated director of the New Hollywood period delivered in its tail end (1979) this little gem which I watched, caught between bouts of laughter and consternation; each and every single cringe induced not by Chance but the inability of the people who meet him to see the man for what he truly is. Chance never claims (quite literally) to be anything is not and only people's assumptions propel this film from one absurdity to the next, and in the midst of all this, Chance strolls along, innocent, detached and somewhat weightless, to a quiet conclusion where the world keeps on guessing and plotting. And so, Hal Ashby pokes gentle fun at the establishment through his characters' delusions and, for some, the frenzy they get themselves into but he and Kozinski never let any political stance overshadow a story which in nature is both heart-warming and melancholic. What the film boils down to is however jaded and so-called sophisticated people are, in their heart of hardened hearts, they all are ultimately attracted, in some way or the other, to the simplicity, the kindness and the innocence of Chance the gardener. Needless to say Peter Sellers' performance is absolutely incredible giving the fact that it is so subdued, delicate and seemingly effortless. This was his last performance and it is truly the stuff of legend. Shirley McLaine is equally amazing in her comedic timing as a wife soon to be widow finding solace and romance in Chance's soft approach to life in general. In the end, this is both an emotional comedy and a light-hearted drama. This defies labels. This is a work of sheer brilliance from Hal Ashby, and an astounding conclusion to Peter Sellers' incredible career.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stupendous. Sellers' Best Performance.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Humphrey Fish
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Chance, a simple gardener, has never left the estate until his employer dies. His simple TV-informed utterances are mistaken for profundity. This was the last movie that Peter Sellers made before his death (The Fiendish Plot of Dr. Fu Manchu doesn't really count), and it is without a doubt his best role, as great as he was in The Pink Panther films, this film is his best performance, he was absolutely stupendous, or even better, the whole movie was stupendous! That's right. Being There is a stupendous movie, in which everybody in it is wonderful. This movie is a comedy-drama film, meaning that while it does have some laughs in it, it is mostly a serious movie, in some parts, the movie is even worth shedding a few tears. Peter Sellers really surprised me, because I was used to seeing him in comedy roles, such as the Pink Panther movies, and Dr. Strangelove, but here, he was in a class by himself, he was absolutely, totally, and completely incredible! It just goes to show what a great actor he truly was, and it is such a pity that he had to die so young, oh well, he may be gone, but he certainly will not be forgotten. While Peter Sellers gave the best performance in the movie, everyone else was also fabulous. Jack Warden gave a wonderful performance as The President, and Shirley MacLaine was marvelous as Eve Rand. However, Melvyn Douglas as Benjamin Rand was something else. Douglas was second only to Peter Sellers in the acting department, he was old, but he could still act, and fabulously too. He won his second Academy Award For Best Supporting Actor for his role in Being There (his first was for Hud in 1963), and it was a very well deserved win, as he was outstanding. Peter Sellers was nominated for Best Actor, and I could see where he would be, because this is his best performance in my opinion. All in all, this is an excellent movie, it is one of the best movies of 1979, and one of the best movies of the 1970's. And therefore, I could say that this movie is one of the greatest movies that I have ever seen. Being There is like no Peter Sellers movie that I have ever seen, rather than playing a comedy role, he plays a serious role, and he does an absolutely wonderful job at it too. All in all, Being There is a movie that has got everything that you would expect to see in a great movie, great acting, great writing, and great directing. Sadly, Peter Sellers would die not long after making this movie at the young age of 54, just think of what he could have accomplished if he would have lived longer. But anyway, this movie is one of the greatest movies ever made, it's a masterpiece brought to us by Hal Ashby. Sellers, Douglas, Warden, and MacLaine all did remarkable jobs with their acting, but Sellers and Douglas being the best of the four. When you watch this movie, you will see Peter Sellers in a role like you've never seen him before, a role that proves what a really talented actor he was. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Life is a state of mind
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Artimidor Federkiel
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The maid Louise describes the main character of this most unusual film as "stuffed with rice pudding between his ears". He can't read or write and is "short-changed by the Lord and dumb as a jackass". His window to the world is the TV, which he enjoys to imitate, other than that he is nothing more than a walking mirror: flat, reflecting what everybody wants to see in him, talking back what they want to hear. The gardener Chance - or, as some who misheard like to call him, Chancey Gardiner - is just there, in suit and tie, an empty mind, alas, sans garden. But being there is enough if you're in the right place and actually are as shallow as others consider you profound. Filmed right Jerzy Kosinski's engaging novel makes the perfect mix for a highly intelligent, though intentionally slow comedy for those who like to have it the more thoughtful way. The film benefits greatly from Peter Seller's complete immersion in the straightness of his character, which is arguably his best role. And Eumir Deodato's version of Strauss' "Also Sprach Zarathustra" as he steps out of the house for the first time in years is nearly as striking as when Kubrick opened "2001" with the original. Unforgettable is the superb ending, which breaks out of the comedic back and forth and goes a decisive, daring step further. It reminds me of another king of comedy, Bill Cosby, and the joke in his stand-up routine where he relates that he wasn't quite sure about his name when he was little. Quite often his parents used to shout out when they saw him: "Jesus Christ!" In the same innocent way our gardener Chance appears to the viewer as the savior himself when the movie ends and when we can still hear the film's final message ringing in our ears: "Life is a state of mind." Well, and ignorance is bliss.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Don't waste your time on Being There
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bluejacquet
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Being There starts with a clever and promising plot that disintegrates into nothingness, leaving the viewer with no answers - only questions. If you like movies with weird, unexplained endings and unfinished story lines, then by all means go see it. It seems that Peter Sellers is often lauded for his 'brilliant' acting in this movie, but really anyone could pull off the role of Chance The Gardener. As Chance is just a simpleton, all one needs to do is to stare blankly ahead and speak softly without inflection, emotion nor enthusiasm in your voice and, presto, you're acting brilliantly. Give me a break.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Classic!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Adapted from the 1971 novella written by Jerzy Kosinski, 'Being There' is A Classic. A Deliciously Written film, that comes in-tact with Tight Direction & Memorable Performances. 'Being There' Synopsis: Chance, a simple gardener, has never left the estate until his employer dies. His simple TV-informed utterances are mistaken for profundity. 'Being There' is A Classic, because it is unforgettable. The humor, the characters, the entire set-up, everything, comes across as flawless & incomparable. Kosinski and Robert C. Jones.'s Screenplay is Delicious. It narrates a wonderful story, with loads of humor. Hal Ashby's Direction is Tight. Cinematography is perfect. Editing & Art Design, are good. Performance-Wise: Peter Sellers as Chance, delivers one of his best performances. The legendary actor sinks his teeth into the character & brings it out with flying colors. Melvyn Douglas, in an Oscar-Winning Performance, is memorable. Shirley MacLaine is fantastic, as always. Jack Warden does wonders. Richard A. Dysart is pleasant. David Clennon leaves a mark. On the whole, 'Being There' is a Winner All The Way. Two Thumbs Up!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Seller's best work
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jerzy kozinsky wrote this brilliant political satire and adapted it for the big screen. Chance Gardner is played with subtle genius by Peter Sellers in what I consider his most complete performance. Chance is a man from nowhere with no history and a childlike innocence in a world of corruption and cynicism. He is accidentally hit by a limousine carrying a Washington D.C. king maker. Chance is put up in an estate and through a series of events becomes a media darling for reciting simplistic remarks which are taken for being pearls of deep wisdom, a variation of "the emperor has no clothes." Seller's is Forrest Gump on steroids, one of the most incredible performances ever captured on film. This should be required viewing at all acting classes. The final scene is beautiful and will fill you with a sense of wonderment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Must See
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mickmerivel
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    By far one of the best films of Peter Sellers. Too often overshadowed by the Pink Panther, this film brings you something completely different. For the modern audience and the younger viewer let it be known that this film does not move at the pace you are probably accustomed to, though if you truly do love a good story and are a fan of film and its telling, then you will love Being There. I find it absolutely hysterical, and upon each view I see something I've missed before. And a very many times I hear a line or see something I've missed before as well. Great films that both are entertaining and subtle in their delivery can be the best of entertainment, and this is such a film. I don't want to ruin the fantastic experience of seeing such an amazing flick, so I'll simply say, see It. Remember not to turn it off half way through, though you may feel it a bit slow, it'll be worth your wait and something you'll love to discuss with others'. That attribute is very often what makes the best films. You won't be disappointed if you are a fan of the little film gems some people too often forget. You'll be glad you went "there."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A dry film is about ignorance and politics and when are they not to be mentioned in the same breath
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Marc Israel
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A twist on the old adage "everything we ever need to know we learned in kindergarten", "Being There" holds forth that American politics, underwritten by polls, commercials and pop culture, would benefit and bite the hook of a simple gardeners' working words. Plant the seed, water it and watch it grow. Based in the same city that brought us Watergate, and pitted against the television backdrop of American social awareness and commercialization, the film captures the time quite well. Love the Diadario music scoring Chances coming out scene and love Peter Sellers as Chance Gardener as his optimism is born and running viral, as it was in 1979. Of course it wouldn't go far without the connected but tainted Shirley McLaine and her flirtatious endeavors.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A sweet/sad surrealist fantasy, profound and delightful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    middleburg
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I LOVE Being There. Captivated the first time i saw it, I probably have watched this film a dozen times since -- each time immersed in the fantasy world of Chance and Eve and her billionaire beau, and the President of the United States, and the Russian Ambassador and all of the loony/quirky/needy/flawed/normal/outlandish characters eager, even desperate, to connect, to understand, to cope with and ultimately love and embrace a too-often incomprehensible world, thanks to the "insight" of the magical Chance. There are countless moments to cherish in this film, thanks to the subtle, surprising, carefully calibrated direction of the one and only Hal Ashby and the impeccable comic timing of the seasoned pros Melvyn Douglas and Shirley MacLaine, playing the magisterial Benjamin Rand and his beautiful sexy "concubine" Eve, with a script that keeps the viewer endlessly intrigued, with a combination of laugh-out-loud moments, moments of genuine suspense, and scenes of tenderness and even a few tears. Ultimately the film belongs to Peter Seller's brilliant character, Chance, with his sweet/calming, genuine/wise spirit; Chance -- on the street, in the elevator, at dinner, in a car, at a party, on TV, providing the laughs, but also the comfort, insight, warmth and wisdom. An unforgettable character in an unforgettable film. You know, it's time for me to see this film again!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A sweet/sad surrealist fantasy, profound and delightful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    middleburg
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I LOVE Being There. Captivated the first time i saw it, I probably have watched this film a dozen times since -- each time immersed in the fantasy world of Chance and Eve and her billionaire beau, and the President of the United States, and the Russian Ambassador and all of the loony/quirky/needy/flawed/normal/outlandish characters eager, even desperate, to connect, to understand, to cope with and ultimately love and embrace a too-often incomprehensible world, thanks to the "insight" of the magical Chance. There are countless moments to cherish in this film, thanks to the subtle, surprising, carefully calibrated direction of the one and only Hal Ashby and the impeccable comic timing of the seasoned pros Melvyn Douglas and Shirley MacLaine, playing the magisterial Benjamin Rand and his beautiful sexy "concubine" Eve, with a script that keeps the viewer endlessly intrigued, with a combination of laugh-out-loud moments, moments of genuine suspense, and scenes of tenderness and even a few tears. Ultimately the film belongs to Peter Seller's brilliant character, Chance, with his sweet/calming, genuine/wise spirit; Chance -- on the street, in the elevator, at dinner, in a car, at a party, on TV, providing the laughs, but also the comfort, insight, warmth and wisdom. An unforgettable character in an unforgettable film. You know, it's time for me to see this film again!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The last performance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cedde6
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Long before Forrest Gump there was another simple man who changed the world he lived in. Not by design of course but by simply being there. Written by Jerzy Kozinski from his own novel and beautifully directed by Hal Ashby "Being There" tells the story of Chance, a simpleton gardener who has never been allowed out of the house in which he has lived in and worked for all his life. When the "old man" who owns the house passes away, Chance is then forced to leave and face the outside world where his innocence and simplicity are mistaken for financial savvy and wisdom with a penchant for gardening metaphors. Hal Ashby, one of the most underestimated director of the New Hollywood period delivered in its tail end (1979) this little gem which I watched, caught between bouts of laughter and consternation; each and every single cringe induced not by Chance but the inability of the people who meet him to see the man for what he truly is. Chance never claims (quite literally) to be anything is not and only people's assumptions propel this film from one absurdity to the next, and in the midst of all this, Chance strolls along, innocent, detached and somewhat weightless, to a quiet conclusion where the world keeps on guessing and plotting. And so, Hal Ashby pokes gentle fun at the establishment through his characters' delusions and, for some, the frenzy they get themselves into but he and Kozinski never let any political stance overshadow a story which in nature is both heart-warming and melancholic. What the film boils down to is however jaded and so-called sophisticated people are, in their heart of hardened hearts, they all are ultimately attracted, in some way or the other, to the simplicity, the kindness and the innocence of Chance the gardener. Needless to say Peter Sellers' performance is absolutely incredible giving the fact that it is so subdued, delicate and seemingly effortless. This was his last performance and it is truly the stuff of legend. Shirley McLaine is equally amazing in her comedic timing as a wife soon to be widow finding solace and romance in Chance's soft approach to life in general. In the end, this is both an emotional comedy and a light-hearted drama. This defies labels. This is a work of sheer brilliance from Hal Ashby, and an astounding conclusion to Peter Sellers' incredible career.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stupendous. Sellers' Best Performance.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Humphrey Fish
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Chance, a simple gardener, has never left the estate until his employer dies. His simple TV-informed utterances are mistaken for profundity. This was the last movie that Peter Sellers made before his death (The Fiendish Plot of Dr. Fu Manchu doesn't really count), and it is without a doubt his best role, as great as he was in The Pink Panther films, this film is his best performance, he was absolutely stupendous, or even better, the whole movie was stupendous! That's right. Being There is a stupendous movie, in which everybody in it is wonderful. This movie is a comedy-drama film, meaning that while it does have some laughs in it, it is mostly a serious movie, in some parts, the movie is even worth shedding a few tears. Peter Sellers really surprised me, because I was used to seeing him in comedy roles, such as the Pink Panther movies, and Dr. Strangelove, but here, he was in a class by himself, he was absolutely, totally, and completely incredible! It just goes to show what a great actor he truly was, and it is such a pity that he had to die so young, oh well, he may be gone, but he certainly will not be forgotten. While Peter Sellers gave the best performance in the movie, everyone else was also fabulous. Jack Warden gave a wonderful performance as The President, and Shirley MacLaine was marvelous as Eve Rand. However, Melvyn Douglas as Benjamin Rand was something else. Douglas was second only to Peter Sellers in the acting department, he was old, but he could still act, and fabulously too. He won his second Academy Award For Best Supporting Actor for his role in Being There (his first was for Hud in 1963), and it was a very well deserved win, as he was outstanding. Peter Sellers was nominated for Best Actor, and I could see where he would be, because this is his best performance in my opinion. All in all, this is an excellent movie, it is one of the best movies of 1979, and one of the best movies of the 1970's. And therefore, I could say that this movie is one of the greatest movies that I have ever seen. Being There is like no Peter Sellers movie that I have ever seen, rather than playing a comedy role, he plays a serious role, and he does an absolutely wonderful job at it too. All in all, Being There is a movie that has got everything that you would expect to see in a great movie, great acting, great writing, and great directing. Sadly, Peter Sellers would die not long after making this movie at the young age of 54, just think of what he could have accomplished if he would have lived longer. But anyway, this movie is one of the greatest movies ever made, it's a masterpiece brought to us by Hal Ashby. Sellers, Douglas, Warden, and MacLaine all did remarkable jobs with their acting, but Sellers and Douglas being the best of the four. When you watch this movie, you will see Peter Sellers in a role like you've never seen him before, a role that proves what a really talented actor he was. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Life is a state of mind
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Artimidor Federkiel
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The maid Louise describes the main character of this most unusual film as "stuffed with rice pudding between his ears". He can't read or write and is "short-changed by the Lord and dumb as a jackass". His window to the world is the TV, which he enjoys to imitate, other than that he is nothing more than a walking mirror: flat, reflecting what everybody wants to see in him, talking back what they want to hear. The gardener Chance - or, as some who misheard like to call him, Chancey Gardiner - is just there, in suit and tie, an empty mind, alas, sans garden. But being there is enough if you're in the right place and actually are as shallow as others consider you profound. Filmed right Jerzy Kosinski's engaging novel makes the perfect mix for a highly intelligent, though intentionally slow comedy for those who like to have it the more thoughtful way. The film benefits greatly from Peter Seller's complete immersion in the straightness of his character, which is arguably his best role. And Eumir Deodato's version of Strauss' "Also Sprach Zarathustra" as he steps out of the house for the first time in years is nearly as striking as when Kubrick opened "2001" with the original. Unforgettable is the superb ending, which breaks out of the comedic back and forth and goes a decisive, daring step further. It reminds me of another king of comedy, Bill Cosby, and the joke in his stand-up routine where he relates that he wasn't quite sure about his name when he was little. Quite often his parents used to shout out when they saw him: "Jesus Christ!" In the same innocent way our gardener Chance appears to the viewer as the savior himself when the movie ends and when we can still hear the film's final message ringing in our ears: "Life is a state of mind." Well, and ignorance is bliss.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Don't waste your time on Being There
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bluejacquet
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Being There starts with a clever and promising plot that disintegrates into nothingness, leaving the viewer with no answers - only questions. If you like movies with weird, unexplained endings and unfinished story lines, then by all means go see it. It seems that Peter Sellers is often lauded for his 'brilliant' acting in this movie, but really anyone could pull off the role of Chance The Gardener. As Chance is just a simpleton, all one needs to do is to stare blankly ahead and speak softly without inflection, emotion nor enthusiasm in your voice and, presto, you're acting brilliantly. Give me a break.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Classic!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Adapted from the 1971 novella written by Jerzy Kosinski, 'Being There' is A Classic. A Deliciously Written film, that comes in-tact with Tight Direction & Memorable Performances. 'Being There' Synopsis: Chance, a simple gardener, has never left the estate until his employer dies. His simple TV-informed utterances are mistaken for profundity. 'Being There' is A Classic, because it is unforgettable. The humor, the characters, the entire set-up, everything, comes across as flawless & incomparable. Kosinski and Robert C. Jones.'s Screenplay is Delicious. It narrates a wonderful story, with loads of humor. Hal Ashby's Direction is Tight. Cinematography is perfect. Editing & Art Design, are good. Performance-Wise: Peter Sellers as Chance, delivers one of his best performances. The legendary actor sinks his teeth into the character & brings it out with flying colors. Melvyn Douglas, in an Oscar-Winning Performance, is memorable. Shirley MacLaine is fantastic, as always. Jack Warden does wonders. Richard A. Dysart is pleasant. David Clennon leaves a mark. On the whole, 'Being There' is a Winner All The Way. Two Thumbs Up!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Seller's best work
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jerzy kozinsky wrote this brilliant political satire and adapted it for the big screen. Chance Gardner is played with subtle genius by Peter Sellers in what I consider his most complete performance. Chance is a man from nowhere with no history and a childlike innocence in a world of corruption and cynicism. He is accidentally hit by a limousine carrying a Washington D.C. king maker. Chance is put up in an estate and through a series of events becomes a media darling for reciting simplistic remarks which are taken for being pearls of deep wisdom, a variation of "the emperor has no clothes." Seller's is Forrest Gump on steroids, one of the most incredible performances ever captured on film. This should be required viewing at all acting classes. The final scene is beautiful and will fill you with a sense of wonderment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Must See
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mickmerivel
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    By far one of the best films of Peter Sellers. Too often overshadowed by the Pink Panther, this film brings you something completely different. For the modern audience and the younger viewer let it be known that this film does not move at the pace you are probably accustomed to, though if you truly do love a good story and are a fan of film and its telling, then you will love Being There. I find it absolutely hysterical, and upon each view I see something I've missed before. And a very many times I hear a line or see something I've missed before as well. Great films that both are entertaining and subtle in their delivery can be the best of entertainment, and this is such a film. I don't want to ruin the fantastic experience of seeing such an amazing flick, so I'll simply say, see It. Remember not to turn it off half way through, though you may feel it a bit slow, it'll be worth your wait and something you'll love to discuss with others'. That attribute is very often what makes the best films. You won't be disappointed if you are a fan of the little film gems some people too often forget. You'll be glad you went "there."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A dry film is about ignorance and politics and when are they not to be mentioned in the same breath
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Marc Israel
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A twist on the old adage "everything we ever need to know we learned in kindergarten", "Being There" holds forth that American politics, underwritten by polls, commercials and pop culture, would benefit and bite the hook of a simple gardeners' working words. Plant the seed, water it and watch it grow. Based in the same city that brought us Watergate, and pitted against the television backdrop of American social awareness and commercialization, the film captures the time quite well. Love the Diadario music scoring Chances coming out scene and love Peter Sellers as Chance Gardener as his optimism is born and running viral, as it was in 1979. Of course it wouldn't go far without the connected but tainted Shirley McLaine and her flirtatious endeavors.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A sweet/sad surrealist fantasy, profound and delightful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    middleburg
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I LOVE Being There. Captivated the first time i saw it, I probably have watched this film a dozen times since -- each time immersed in the fantasy world of Chance and Eve and her billionaire beau, and the President of the United States, and the Russian Ambassador and all of the loony/quirky/needy/flawed/normal/outlandish characters eager, even desperate, to connect, to understand, to cope with and ultimately love and embrace a too-often incomprehensible world, thanks to the "insight" of the magical Chance. There are countless moments to cherish in this film, thanks to the subtle, surprising, carefully calibrated direction of the one and only Hal Ashby and the impeccable comic timing of the seasoned pros Melvyn Douglas and Shirley MacLaine, playing the magisterial Benjamin Rand and his beautiful sexy "concubine" Eve, with a script that keeps the viewer endlessly intrigued, with a combination of laugh-out-loud moments, moments of genuine suspense, and scenes of tenderness and even a few tears. Ultimately the film belongs to Peter Seller's brilliant character, Chance, with his sweet/calming, genuine/wise spirit; Chance -- on the street, in the elevator, at dinner, in a car, at a party, on TV, providing the laughs, but also the comfort, insight, warmth and wisdom. An unforgettable character in an unforgettable film. You know, it's time for me to see this film again!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A sweet/sad surrealist fantasy, profound and delightful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    middleburg
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I LOVE Being There. Captivated the first time i saw it, I probably have watched this film a dozen times since -- each time immersed in the fantasy world of Chance and Eve and her billionaire beau, and the President of the United States, and the Russian Ambassador and all of the loony/quirky/needy/flawed/normal/outlandish characters eager, even desperate, to connect, to understand, to cope with and ultimately love and embrace a too-often incomprehensible world, thanks to the "insight" of the magical Chance. There are countless moments to cherish in this film, thanks to the subtle, surprising, carefully calibrated direction of the one and only Hal Ashby and the impeccable comic timing of the seasoned pros Melvyn Douglas and Shirley MacLaine, playing the magisterial Benjamin Rand and his beautiful sexy "concubine" Eve, with a script that keeps the viewer endlessly intrigued, with a combination of laugh-out-loud moments, moments of genuine suspense, and scenes of tenderness and even a few tears. Ultimately the film belongs to Peter Seller's brilliant character, Chance, with his sweet/calming, genuine/wise spirit; Chance -- on the street, in the elevator, at dinner, in a car, at a party, on TV, providing the laughs, but also the comfort, insight, warmth and wisdom. An unforgettable character in an unforgettable film. You know, it's time for me to see this film again!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The last performance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cedde6
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Long before Forrest Gump there was another simple man who changed the world he lived in. Not by design of course but by simply being there. Written by Jerzy Kozinski from his own novel and beautifully directed by Hal Ashby "Being There" tells the story of Chance, a simpleton gardener who has never been allowed out of the house in which he has lived in and worked for all his life. When the "old man" who owns the house passes away, Chance is then forced to leave and face the outside world where his innocence and simplicity are mistaken for financial savvy and wisdom with a penchant for gardening metaphors. Hal Ashby, one of the most underestimated director of the New Hollywood period delivered in its tail end (1979) this little gem which I watched, caught between bouts of laughter and consternation; each and every single cringe induced not by Chance but the inability of the people who meet him to see the man for what he truly is. Chance never claims (quite literally) to be anything is not and only people's assumptions propel this film from one absurdity to the next, and in the midst of all this, Chance strolls along, innocent, detached and somewhat weightless, to a quiet conclusion where the world keeps on guessing and plotting. And so, Hal Ashby pokes gentle fun at the establishment through his characters' delusions and, for some, the frenzy they get themselves into but he and Kozinski never let any political stance overshadow a story which in nature is both heart-warming and melancholic. What the film boils down to is however jaded and so-called sophisticated people are, in their heart of hardened hearts, they all are ultimately attracted, in some way or the other, to the simplicity, the kindness and the innocence of Chance the gardener. Needless to say Peter Sellers' performance is absolutely incredible giving the fact that it is so subdued, delicate and seemingly effortless. This was his last performance and it is truly the stuff of legend. Shirley McLaine is equally amazing in her comedic timing as a wife soon to be widow finding solace and romance in Chance's soft approach to life in general. In the end, this is both an emotional comedy and a light-hearted drama. This defies labels. This is a work of sheer brilliance from Hal Ashby, and an astounding conclusion to Peter Sellers' incredible career.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stupendous. Sellers' Best Performance.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Humphrey Fish
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Chance, a simple gardener, has never left the estate until his employer dies. His simple TV-informed utterances are mistaken for profundity. This was the last movie that Peter Sellers made before his death (The Fiendish Plot of Dr. Fu Manchu doesn't really count), and it is without a doubt his best role, as great as he was in The Pink Panther films, this film is his best performance, he was absolutely stupendous, or even better, the whole movie was stupendous! That's right. Being There is a stupendous movie, in which everybody in it is wonderful. This movie is a comedy-drama film, meaning that while it does have some laughs in it, it is mostly a serious movie, in some parts, the movie is even worth shedding a few tears. Peter Sellers really surprised me, because I was used to seeing him in comedy roles, such as the Pink Panther movies, and Dr. Strangelove, but here, he was in a class by himself, he was absolutely, totally, and completely incredible! It just goes to show what a great actor he truly was, and it is such a pity that he had to die so young, oh well, he may be gone, but he certainly will not be forgotten. While Peter Sellers gave the best performance in the movie, everyone else was also fabulous. Jack Warden gave a wonderful performance as The President, and Shirley MacLaine was marvelous as Eve Rand. However, Melvyn Douglas as Benjamin Rand was something else. Douglas was second only to Peter Sellers in the acting department, he was old, but he could still act, and fabulously too. He won his second Academy Award For Best Supporting Actor for his role in Being There (his first was for Hud in 1963), and it was a very well deserved win, as he was outstanding. Peter Sellers was nominated for Best Actor, and I could see where he would be, because this is his best performance in my opinion. All in all, this is an excellent movie, it is one of the best movies of 1979, and one of the best movies of the 1970's. And therefore, I could say that this movie is one of the greatest movies that I have ever seen. Being There is like no Peter Sellers movie that I have ever seen, rather than playing a comedy role, he plays a serious role, and he does an absolutely wonderful job at it too. All in all, Being There is a movie that has got everything that you would expect to see in a great movie, great acting, great writing, and great directing. Sadly, Peter Sellers would die not long after making this movie at the young age of 54, just think of what he could have accomplished if he would have lived longer. But anyway, this movie is one of the greatest movies ever made, it's a masterpiece brought to us by Hal Ashby. Sellers, Douglas, Warden, and MacLaine all did remarkable jobs with their acting, but Sellers and Douglas being the best of the four. When you watch this movie, you will see Peter Sellers in a role like you've never seen him before, a role that proves what a really talented actor he was. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Life is a state of mind
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Artimidor Federkiel
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The maid Louise describes the main character of this most unusual film as "stuffed with rice pudding between his ears". He can't read or write and is "short-changed by the Lord and dumb as a jackass". His window to the world is the TV, which he enjoys to imitate, other than that he is nothing more than a walking mirror: flat, reflecting what everybody wants to see in him, talking back what they want to hear. The gardener Chance - or, as some who misheard like to call him, Chancey Gardiner - is just there, in suit and tie, an empty mind, alas, sans garden. But being there is enough if you're in the right place and actually are as shallow as others consider you profound. Filmed right Jerzy Kosinski's engaging novel makes the perfect mix for a highly intelligent, though intentionally slow comedy for those who like to have it the more thoughtful way. The film benefits greatly from Peter Seller's complete immersion in the straightness of his character, which is arguably his best role. And Eumir Deodato's version of Strauss' "Also Sprach Zarathustra" as he steps out of the house for the first time in years is nearly as striking as when Kubrick opened "2001" with the original. Unforgettable is the superb ending, which breaks out of the comedic back and forth and goes a decisive, daring step further. It reminds me of another king of comedy, Bill Cosby, and the joke in his stand-up routine where he relates that he wasn't quite sure about his name when he was little. Quite often his parents used to shout out when they saw him: "Jesus Christ!" In the same innocent way our gardener Chance appears to the viewer as the savior himself when the movie ends and when we can still hear the film's final message ringing in our ears: "Life is a state of mind." Well, and ignorance is bliss.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Don't waste your time on Being There
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bluejacquet
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Being There starts with a clever and promising plot that disintegrates into nothingness, leaving the viewer with no answers - only questions. If you like movies with weird, unexplained endings and unfinished story lines, then by all means go see it. It seems that Peter Sellers is often lauded for his 'brilliant' acting in this movie, but really anyone could pull off the role of Chance The Gardener. As Chance is just a simpleton, all one needs to do is to stare blankly ahead and speak softly without inflection, emotion nor enthusiasm in your voice and, presto, you're acting brilliantly. Give me a break.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Classic!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Adapted from the 1971 novella written by Jerzy Kosinski, 'Being There' is A Classic. A Deliciously Written film, that comes in-tact with Tight Direction & Memorable Performances. 'Being There' Synopsis: Chance, a simple gardener, has never left the estate until his employer dies. His simple TV-informed utterances are mistaken for profundity. 'Being There' is A Classic, because it is unforgettable. The humor, the characters, the entire set-up, everything, comes across as flawless & incomparable. Kosinski and Robert C. Jones.'s Screenplay is Delicious. It narrates a wonderful story, with loads of humor. Hal Ashby's Direction is Tight. Cinematography is perfect. Editing & Art Design, are good. Performance-Wise: Peter Sellers as Chance, delivers one of his best performances. The legendary actor sinks his teeth into the character & brings it out with flying colors. Melvyn Douglas, in an Oscar-Winning Performance, is memorable. Shirley MacLaine is fantastic, as always. Jack Warden does wonders. Richard A. Dysart is pleasant. David Clennon leaves a mark. On the whole, 'Being There' is a Winner All The Way. Two Thumbs Up!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Seller's best work
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jerzy kozinsky wrote this brilliant political satire and adapted it for the big screen. Chance Gardner is played with subtle genius by Peter Sellers in what I consider his most complete performance. Chance is a man from nowhere with no history and a childlike innocence in a world of corruption and cynicism. He is accidentally hit by a limousine carrying a Washington D.C. king maker. Chance is put up in an estate and through a series of events becomes a media darling for reciting simplistic remarks which are taken for being pearls of deep wisdom, a variation of "the emperor has no clothes." Seller's is Forrest Gump on steroids, one of the most incredible performances ever captured on film. This should be required viewing at all acting classes. The final scene is beautiful and will fill you with a sense of wonderment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Must See
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mickmerivel
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    By far one of the best films of Peter Sellers. Too often overshadowed by the Pink Panther, this film brings you something completely different. For the modern audience and the younger viewer let it be known that this film does not move at the pace you are probably accustomed to, though if you truly do love a good story and are a fan of film and its telling, then you will love Being There. I find it absolutely hysterical, and upon each view I see something I've missed before. And a very many times I hear a line or see something I've missed before as well. Great films that both are entertaining and subtle in their delivery can be the best of entertainment, and this is such a film. I don't want to ruin the fantastic experience of seeing such an amazing flick, so I'll simply say, see It. Remember not to turn it off half way through, though you may feel it a bit slow, it'll be worth your wait and something you'll love to discuss with others'. That attribute is very often what makes the best films. You won't be disappointed if you are a fan of the little film gems some people too often forget. You'll be glad you went "there."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A dry film is about ignorance and politics and when are they not to be mentioned in the same breath
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Marc Israel
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A twist on the old adage "everything we ever need to know we learned in kindergarten", "Being There" holds forth that American politics, underwritten by polls, commercials and pop culture, would benefit and bite the hook of a simple gardeners' working words. Plant the seed, water it and watch it grow. Based in the same city that brought us Watergate, and pitted against the television backdrop of American social awareness and commercialization, the film captures the time quite well. Love the Diadario music scoring Chances coming out scene and love Peter Sellers as Chance Gardener as his optimism is born and running viral, as it was in 1979. Of course it wouldn't go far without the connected but tainted Shirley McLaine and her flirtatious endeavors.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A sweet/sad surrealist fantasy, profound and delightful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    middleburg
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I LOVE Being There. Captivated the first time i saw it, I probably have watched this film a dozen times since -- each time immersed in the fantasy world of Chance and Eve and her billionaire beau, and the President of the United States, and the Russian Ambassador and all of the loony/quirky/needy/flawed/normal/outlandish characters eager, even desperate, to connect, to understand, to cope with and ultimately love and embrace a too-often incomprehensible world, thanks to the "insight" of the magical Chance. There are countless moments to cherish in this film, thanks to the subtle, surprising, carefully calibrated direction of the one and only Hal Ashby and the impeccable comic timing of the seasoned pros Melvyn Douglas and Shirley MacLaine, playing the magisterial Benjamin Rand and his beautiful sexy "concubine" Eve, with a script that keeps the viewer endlessly intrigued, with a combination of laugh-out-loud moments, moments of genuine suspense, and scenes of tenderness and even a few tears. Ultimately the film belongs to Peter Seller's brilliant character, Chance, with his sweet/calming, genuine/wise spirit; Chance -- on the street, in the elevator, at dinner, in a car, at a party, on TV, providing the laughs, but also the comfort, insight, warmth and wisdom. An unforgettable character in an unforgettable film. You know, it's time for me to see this film again!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A sweet/sad surrealist fantasy, profound and delightful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    middleburg
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I LOVE Being There. Captivated the first time i saw it, I probably have watched this film a dozen times since -- each time immersed in the fantasy world of Chance and Eve and her billionaire beau, and the President of the United States, and the Russian Ambassador and all of the loony/quirky/needy/flawed/normal/outlandish characters eager, even desperate, to connect, to understand, to cope with and ultimately love and embrace a too-often incomprehensible world, thanks to the "insight" of the magical Chance. There are countless moments to cherish in this film, thanks to the subtle, surprising, carefully calibrated direction of the one and only Hal Ashby and the impeccable comic timing of the seasoned pros Melvyn Douglas and Shirley MacLaine, playing the magisterial Benjamin Rand and his beautiful sexy "concubine" Eve, with a script that keeps the viewer endlessly intrigued, with a combination of laugh-out-loud moments, moments of genuine suspense, and scenes of tenderness and even a few tears. Ultimately the film belongs to Peter Seller's brilliant character, Chance, with his sweet/calming, genuine/wise spirit; Chance -- on the street, in the elevator, at dinner, in a car, at a party, on TV, providing the laughs, but also the comfort, insight, warmth and wisdom. An unforgettable character in an unforgettable film. You know, it's time for me to see this film again!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The last performance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cedde6
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Long before Forrest Gump there was another simple man who changed the world he lived in. Not by design of course but by simply being there. Written by Jerzy Kozinski from his own novel and beautifully directed by Hal Ashby "Being There" tells the story of Chance, a simpleton gardener who has never been allowed out of the house in which he has lived in and worked for all his life. When the "old man" who owns the house passes away, Chance is then forced to leave and face the outside world where his innocence and simplicity are mistaken for financial savvy and wisdom with a penchant for gardening metaphors. Hal Ashby, one of the most underestimated director of the New Hollywood period delivered in its tail end (1979) this little gem which I watched, caught between bouts of laughter and consternation; each and every single cringe induced not by Chance but the inability of the people who meet him to see the man for what he truly is. Chance never claims (quite literally) to be anything is not and only people's assumptions propel this film from one absurdity to the next, and in the midst of all this, Chance strolls along, innocent, detached and somewhat weightless, to a quiet conclusion where the world keeps on guessing and plotting. And so, Hal Ashby pokes gentle fun at the establishment through his characters' delusions and, for some, the frenzy they get themselves into but he and Kozinski never let any political stance overshadow a story which in nature is both heart-warming and melancholic. What the film boils down to is however jaded and so-called sophisticated people are, in their heart of hardened hearts, they all are ultimately attracted, in some way or the other, to the simplicity, the kindness and the innocence of Chance the gardener. Needless to say Peter Sellers' performance is absolutely incredible giving the fact that it is so subdued, delicate and seemingly effortless. This was his last performance and it is truly the stuff of legend. Shirley McLaine is equally amazing in her comedic timing as a wife soon to be widow finding solace and romance in Chance's soft approach to life in general. In the end, this is both an emotional comedy and a light-hearted drama. This defies labels. This is a work of sheer brilliance from Hal Ashby, and an astounding conclusion to Peter Sellers' incredible career.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stupendous. Sellers' Best Performance.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Humphrey Fish
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Chance, a simple gardener, has never left the estate until his employer dies. His simple TV-informed utterances are mistaken for profundity. This was the last movie that Peter Sellers made before his death (The Fiendish Plot of Dr. Fu Manchu doesn't really count), and it is without a doubt his best role, as great as he was in The Pink Panther films, this film is his best performance, he was absolutely stupendous, or even better, the whole movie was stupendous! That's right. Being There is a stupendous movie, in which everybody in it is wonderful. This movie is a comedy-drama film, meaning that while it does have some laughs in it, it is mostly a serious movie, in some parts, the movie is even worth shedding a few tears. Peter Sellers really surprised me, because I was used to seeing him in comedy roles, such as the Pink Panther movies, and Dr. Strangelove, but here, he was in a class by himself, he was absolutely, totally, and completely incredible! It just goes to show what a great actor he truly was, and it is such a pity that he had to die so young, oh well, he may be gone, but he certainly will not be forgotten. While Peter Sellers gave the best performance in the movie, everyone else was also fabulous. Jack Warden gave a wonderful performance as The President, and Shirley MacLaine was marvelous as Eve Rand. However, Melvyn Douglas as Benjamin Rand was something else. Douglas was second only to Peter Sellers in the acting department, he was old, but he could still act, and fabulously too. He won his second Academy Award For Best Supporting Actor for his role in Being There (his first was for Hud in 1963), and it was a very well deserved win, as he was outstanding. Peter Sellers was nominated for Best Actor, and I could see where he would be, because this is his best performance in my opinion. All in all, this is an excellent movie, it is one of the best movies of 1979, and one of the best movies of the 1970's. And therefore, I could say that this movie is one of the greatest movies that I have ever seen. Being There is like no Peter Sellers movie that I have ever seen, rather than playing a comedy role, he plays a serious role, and he does an absolutely wonderful job at it too. All in all, Being There is a movie that has got everything that you would expect to see in a great movie, great acting, great writing, and great directing. Sadly, Peter Sellers would die not long after making this movie at the young age of 54, just think of what he could have accomplished if he would have lived longer. But anyway, this movie is one of the greatest movies ever made, it's a masterpiece brought to us by Hal Ashby. Sellers, Douglas, Warden, and MacLaine all did remarkable jobs with their acting, but Sellers and Douglas being the best of the four. When you watch this movie, you will see Peter Sellers in a role like you've never seen him before, a role that proves what a really talented actor he was. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Life is a state of mind
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Artimidor Federkiel
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The maid Louise describes the main character of this most unusual film as "stuffed with rice pudding between his ears". He can't read or write and is "short-changed by the Lord and dumb as a jackass". His window to the world is the TV, which he enjoys to imitate, other than that he is nothing more than a walking mirror: flat, reflecting what everybody wants to see in him, talking back what they want to hear. The gardener Chance - or, as some who misheard like to call him, Chancey Gardiner - is just there, in suit and tie, an empty mind, alas, sans garden. But being there is enough if you're in the right place and actually are as shallow as others consider you profound. Filmed right Jerzy Kosinski's engaging novel makes the perfect mix for a highly intelligent, though intentionally slow comedy for those who like to have it the more thoughtful way. The film benefits greatly from Peter Seller's complete immersion in the straightness of his character, which is arguably his best role. And Eumir Deodato's version of Strauss' "Also Sprach Zarathustra" as he steps out of the house for the first time in years is nearly as striking as when Kubrick opened "2001" with the original. Unforgettable is the superb ending, which breaks out of the comedic back and forth and goes a decisive, daring step further. It reminds me of another king of comedy, Bill Cosby, and the joke in his stand-up routine where he relates that he wasn't quite sure about his name when he was little. Quite often his parents used to shout out when they saw him: "Jesus Christ!" In the same innocent way our gardener Chance appears to the viewer as the savior himself when the movie ends and when we can still hear the film's final message ringing in our ears: "Life is a state of mind." Well, and ignorance is bliss.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Don't waste your time on Being There
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bluejacquet
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Being There starts with a clever and promising plot that disintegrates into nothingness, leaving the viewer with no answers - only questions. If you like movies with weird, unexplained endings and unfinished story lines, then by all means go see it. It seems that Peter Sellers is often lauded for his 'brilliant' acting in this movie, but really anyone could pull off the role of Chance The Gardener. As Chance is just a simpleton, all one needs to do is to stare blankly ahead and speak softly without inflection, emotion nor enthusiasm in your voice and, presto, you're acting brilliantly. Give me a break.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Classic!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Adapted from the 1971 novella written by Jerzy Kosinski, 'Being There' is A Classic. A Deliciously Written film, that comes in-tact with Tight Direction & Memorable Performances. 'Being There' Synopsis: Chance, a simple gardener, has never left the estate until his employer dies. His simple TV-informed utterances are mistaken for profundity. 'Being There' is A Classic, because it is unforgettable. The humor, the characters, the entire set-up, everything, comes across as flawless & incomparable. Kosinski and Robert C. Jones.'s Screenplay is Delicious. It narrates a wonderful story, with loads of humor. Hal Ashby's Direction is Tight. Cinematography is perfect. Editing & Art Design, are good. Performance-Wise: Peter Sellers as Chance, delivers one of his best performances. The legendary actor sinks his teeth into the character & brings it out with flying colors. Melvyn Douglas, in an Oscar-Winning Performance, is memorable. Shirley MacLaine is fantastic, as always. Jack Warden does wonders. Richard A. Dysart is pleasant. David Clennon leaves a mark. On the whole, 'Being There' is a Winner All The Way. Two Thumbs Up!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Seller's best work
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jerzy kozinsky wrote this brilliant political satire and adapted it for the big screen. Chance Gardner is played with subtle genius by Peter Sellers in what I consider his most complete performance. Chance is a man from nowhere with no history and a childlike innocence in a world of corruption and cynicism. He is accidentally hit by a limousine carrying a Washington D.C. king maker. Chance is put up in an estate and through a series of events becomes a media darling for reciting simplistic remarks which are taken for being pearls of deep wisdom, a variation of "the emperor has no clothes." Seller's is Forrest Gump on steroids, one of the most incredible performances ever captured on film. This should be required viewing at all acting classes. The final scene is beautiful and will fill you with a sense of wonderment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Must See
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mickmerivel
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    By far one of the best films of Peter Sellers. Too often overshadowed by the Pink Panther, this film brings you something completely different. For the modern audience and the younger viewer let it be known that this film does not move at the pace you are probably accustomed to, though if you truly do love a good story and are a fan of film and its telling, then you will love Being There. I find it absolutely hysterical, and upon each view I see something I've missed before. And a very many times I hear a line or see something I've missed before as well. Great films that both are entertaining and subtle in their delivery can be the best of entertainment, and this is such a film. I don't want to ruin the fantastic experience of seeing such an amazing flick, so I'll simply say, see It. Remember not to turn it off half way through, though you may feel it a bit slow, it'll be worth your wait and something you'll love to discuss with others'. That attribute is very often what makes the best films. You won't be disappointed if you are a fan of the little film gems some people too often forget. You'll be glad you went "there."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A dry film is about ignorance and politics and when are they not to be mentioned in the same breath
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Marc Israel
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A twist on the old adage "everything we ever need to know we learned in kindergarten", "Being There" holds forth that American politics, underwritten by polls, commercials and pop culture, would benefit and bite the hook of a simple gardeners' working words. Plant the seed, water it and watch it grow. Based in the same city that brought us Watergate, and pitted against the television backdrop of American social awareness and commercialization, the film captures the time quite well. Love the Diadario music scoring Chances coming out scene and love Peter Sellers as Chance Gardener as his optimism is born and running viral, as it was in 1979. Of course it wouldn't go far without the connected but tainted Shirley McLaine and her flirtatious endeavors.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A sweet/sad surrealist fantasy, profound and delightful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    middleburg
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I LOVE Being There. Captivated the first time i saw it, I probably have watched this film a dozen times since -- each time immersed in the fantasy world of Chance and Eve and her billionaire beau, and the President of the United States, and the Russian Ambassador and all of the loony/quirky/needy/flawed/normal/outlandish characters eager, even desperate, to connect, to understand, to cope with and ultimately love and embrace a too-often incomprehensible world, thanks to the "insight" of the magical Chance. There are countless moments to cherish in this film, thanks to the subtle, surprising, carefully calibrated direction of the one and only Hal Ashby and the impeccable comic timing of the seasoned pros Melvyn Douglas and Shirley MacLaine, playing the magisterial Benjamin Rand and his beautiful sexy "concubine" Eve, with a script that keeps the viewer endlessly intrigued, with a combination of laugh-out-loud moments, moments of genuine suspense, and scenes of tenderness and even a few tears. Ultimately the film belongs to Peter Seller's brilliant character, Chance, with his sweet/calming, genuine/wise spirit; Chance -- on the street, in the elevator, at dinner, in a car, at a party, on TV, providing the laughs, but also the comfort, insight, warmth and wisdom. An unforgettable character in an unforgettable film. You know, it's time for me to see this film again!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A sweet/sad surrealist fantasy, profound and delightful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    middleburg
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I LOVE Being There. Captivated the first time i saw it, I probably have watched this film a dozen times since -- each time immersed in the fantasy world of Chance and Eve and her billionaire beau, and the President of the United States, and the Russian Ambassador and all of the loony/quirky/needy/flawed/normal/outlandish characters eager, even desperate, to connect, to understand, to cope with and ultimately love and embrace a too-often incomprehensible world, thanks to the "insight" of the magical Chance. There are countless moments to cherish in this film, thanks to the subtle, surprising, carefully calibrated direction of the one and only Hal Ashby and the impeccable comic timing of the seasoned pros Melvyn Douglas and Shirley MacLaine, playing the magisterial Benjamin Rand and his beautiful sexy "concubine" Eve, with a script that keeps the viewer endlessly intrigued, with a combination of laugh-out-loud moments, moments of genuine suspense, and scenes of tenderness and even a few tears. Ultimately the film belongs to Peter Seller's brilliant character, Chance, with his sweet/calming, genuine/wise spirit; Chance -- on the street, in the elevator, at dinner, in a car, at a party, on TV, providing the laughs, but also the comfort, insight, warmth and wisdom. An unforgettable character in an unforgettable film. You know, it's time for me to see this film again!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The last performance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cedde6
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Long before Forrest Gump there was another simple man who changed the world he lived in. Not by design of course but by simply being there. Written by Jerzy Kozinski from his own novel and beautifully directed by Hal Ashby "Being There" tells the story of Chance, a simpleton gardener who has never been allowed out of the house in which he has lived in and worked for all his life. When the "old man" who owns the house passes away, Chance is then forced to leave and face the outside world where his innocence and simplicity are mistaken for financial savvy and wisdom with a penchant for gardening metaphors. Hal Ashby, one of the most underestimated director of the New Hollywood period delivered in its tail end (1979) this little gem which I watched, caught between bouts of laughter and consternation; each and every single cringe induced not by Chance but the inability of the people who meet him to see the man for what he truly is. Chance never claims (quite literally) to be anything is not and only people's assumptions propel this film from one absurdity to the next, and in the midst of all this, Chance strolls along, innocent, detached and somewhat weightless, to a quiet conclusion where the world keeps on guessing and plotting. And so, Hal Ashby pokes gentle fun at the establishment through his characters' delusions and, for some, the frenzy they get themselves into but he and Kozinski never let any political stance overshadow a story which in nature is both heart-warming and melancholic. What the film boils down to is however jaded and so-called sophisticated people are, in their heart of hardened hearts, they all are ultimately attracted, in some way or the other, to the simplicity, the kindness and the innocence of Chance the gardener. Needless to say Peter Sellers' performance is absolutely incredible giving the fact that it is so subdued, delicate and seemingly effortless. This was his last performance and it is truly the stuff of legend. Shirley McLaine is equally amazing in her comedic timing as a wife soon to be widow finding solace and romance in Chance's soft approach to life in general. In the end, this is both an emotional comedy and a light-hearted drama. This defies labels. This is a work of sheer brilliance from Hal Ashby, and an astounding conclusion to Peter Sellers' incredible career.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Stupendous. Sellers' Best Performance.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Humphrey Fish
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Chance, a simple gardener, has never left the estate until his employer dies. His simple TV-informed utterances are mistaken for profundity. This was the last movie that Peter Sellers made before his death (The Fiendish Plot of Dr. Fu Manchu doesn't really count), and it is without a doubt his best role, as great as he was in The Pink Panther films, this film is his best performance, he was absolutely stupendous, or even better, the whole movie was stupendous! That's right. Being There is a stupendous movie, in which everybody in it is wonderful. This movie is a comedy-drama film, meaning that while it does have some laughs in it, it is mostly a serious movie, in some parts, the movie is even worth shedding a few tears. Peter Sellers really surprised me, because I was used to seeing him in comedy roles, such as the Pink Panther movies, and Dr. Strangelove, but here, he was in a class by himself, he was absolutely, totally, and completely incredible! It just goes to show what a great actor he truly was, and it is such a pity that he had to die so young, oh well, he may be gone, but he certainly will not be forgotten. While Peter Sellers gave the best performance in the movie, everyone else was also fabulous. Jack Warden gave a wonderful performance as The President, and Shirley MacLaine was marvelous as Eve Rand. However, Melvyn Douglas as Benjamin Rand was something else. Douglas was second only to Peter Sellers in the acting department, he was old, but he could still act, and fabulously too. He won his second Academy Award For Best Supporting Actor for his role in Being There (his first was for Hud in 1963), and it was a very well deserved win, as he was outstanding. Peter Sellers was nominated for Best Actor, and I could see where he would be, because this is his best performance in my opinion. All in all, this is an excellent movie, it is one of the best movies of 1979, and one of the best movies of the 1970's. And therefore, I could say that this movie is one of the greatest movies that I have ever seen. Being There is like no Peter Sellers movie that I have ever seen, rather than playing a comedy role, he plays a serious role, and he does an absolutely wonderful job at it too. All in all, Being There is a movie that has got everything that you would expect to see in a great movie, great acting, great writing, and great directing. Sadly, Peter Sellers would die not long after making this movie at the young age of 54, just think of what he could have accomplished if he would have lived longer. But anyway, this movie is one of the greatest movies ever made, it's a masterpiece brought to us by Hal Ashby. Sellers, Douglas, Warden, and MacLaine all did remarkable jobs with their acting, but Sellers and Douglas being the best of the four. When you watch this movie, you will see Peter Sellers in a role like you've never seen him before, a role that proves what a really talented actor he was. 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Life is a state of mind
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Artimidor Federkiel
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The maid Louise describes the main character of this most unusual film as "stuffed with rice pudding between his ears". He can't read or write and is "short-changed by the Lord and dumb as a jackass". His window to the world is the TV, which he enjoys to imitate, other than that he is nothing more than a walking mirror: flat, reflecting what everybody wants to see in him, talking back what they want to hear. The gardener Chance - or, as some who misheard like to call him, Chancey Gardiner - is just there, in suit and tie, an empty mind, alas, sans garden. But being there is enough if you're in the right place and actually are as shallow as others consider you profound. Filmed right Jerzy Kosinski's engaging novel makes the perfect mix for a highly intelligent, though intentionally slow comedy for those who like to have it the more thoughtful way. The film benefits greatly from Peter Seller's complete immersion in the straightness of his character, which is arguably his best role. And Eumir Deodato's version of Strauss' "Also Sprach Zarathustra" as he steps out of the house for the first time in years is nearly as striking as when Kubrick opened "2001" with the original. Unforgettable is the superb ending, which breaks out of the comedic back and forth and goes a decisive, daring step further. It reminds me of another king of comedy, Bill Cosby, and the joke in his stand-up routine where he relates that he wasn't quite sure about his name when he was little. Quite often his parents used to shout out when they saw him: "Jesus Christ!" In the same innocent way our gardener Chance appears to the viewer as the savior himself when the movie ends and when we can still hear the film's final message ringing in our ears: "Life is a state of mind." Well, and ignorance is bliss.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Don't waste your time on Being There
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bluejacquet
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Being There starts with a clever and promising plot that disintegrates into nothingness, leaving the viewer with no answers - only questions. If you like movies with weird, unexplained endings and unfinished story lines, then by all means go see it. It seems that Peter Sellers is often lauded for his 'brilliant' acting in this movie, but really anyone could pull off the role of Chance The Gardener. As Chance is just a simpleton, all one needs to do is to stare blankly ahead and speak softly without inflection, emotion nor enthusiasm in your voice and, presto, you're acting brilliantly. Give me a break.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Classic!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nama chakravorty
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Adapted from the 1971 novella written by Jerzy Kosinski, 'Being There' is A Classic. A Deliciously Written film, that comes in-tact with Tight Direction & Memorable Performances. 'Being There' Synopsis: Chance, a simple gardener, has never left the estate until his employer dies. His simple TV-informed utterances are mistaken for profundity. 'Being There' is A Classic, because it is unforgettable. The humor, the characters, the entire set-up, everything, comes across as flawless & incomparable. Kosinski and Robert C. Jones.'s Screenplay is Delicious. It narrates a wonderful story, with loads of humor. Hal Ashby's Direction is Tight. Cinematography is perfect. Editing & Art Design, are good. Performance-Wise: Peter Sellers as Chance, delivers one of his best performances. The legendary actor sinks his teeth into the character & brings it out with flying colors. Melvyn Douglas, in an Oscar-Winning Performance, is memorable. Shirley MacLaine is fantastic, as always. Jack Warden does wonders. Richard A. Dysart is pleasant. David Clennon leaves a mark. On the whole, 'Being There' is a Winner All The Way. Two Thumbs Up!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Seller's best work
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billcr12
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jerzy kozinsky wrote this brilliant political satire and adapted it for the big screen. Chance Gardner is played with subtle genius by Peter Sellers in what I consider his most complete performance. Chance is a man from nowhere with no history and a childlike innocence in a world of corruption and cynicism. He is accidentally hit by a limousine carrying a Washington D.C. king maker. Chance is put up in an estate and through a series of events becomes a media darling for reciting simplistic remarks which are taken for being pearls of deep wisdom, a variation of "the emperor has no clothes." Seller's is Forrest Gump on steroids, one of the most incredible performances ever captured on film. This should be required viewing at all acting classes. The final scene is beautiful and will fill you with a sense of wonderment.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
