<filme>
 <id>
  669
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0101492
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1991
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Anatomia de um Assassino
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  5.2
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  After losing his arm in a car accident, a criminal psychologist has it replaced with a limb that belonged to a serial killer.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  When Bill Chrashank loses his arm in a car accident, the arm of an executed death row inmate is grafted on in its place. The only problem, as Bill soon discovers, is that the arm is possessed by a force he cannot control.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Horror
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Thriller
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   car accident
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   death row
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   serial killer
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   death row inmate
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   psychologist
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Eric Red
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Pierre Boileau
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Thomas Narcejac
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Jeff Fahey
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Lindsay Duncan
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Kim Delaney
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Watching this unravel was fun, even if logic was thrown out the window. Fahey is terrific!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    callanvass
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw this quite a few years ago when I was younger, and I remembered being fairly unimpressed with it. How do I feel about it now?? I kinda dug it actually, it's got some balls. They really don't make them like this anymore. Not only does it have a car crash scene that makes some of the scenes in a Final Destination movie look weak in comparison. Watching Jeff Fahey go all unruly with everybody is always a treat to watch. I also really dug the family values in this one. Fahey's family really acted like a natural family, and I really felt for Fahey's descent into craziness. There are some things that I questioned, though. I didn't buy how Bill's (Fahey) kids were all nice to Bill, despite the fact that he knocks his son around, and yells a lot. You would think the kids would learn not to go around him. I also felt the finale was overblown. It was entertaining, don't get me wrong, but it was a bit too chaotic for my liking. It also has some pointless characters as well; Zakes Mokae as the detective being one of them. Jeff Fahey is a criminally underrated actor. He has always been one of my favorites, and why this man is stuck in DTV hell right now is beyond me. Stop being stupid Hollywood and recognize this man's talents! His unpredictable show is a main reason why this film is so entertaining. Kim Delaney lends able support as the caring wife, I dug her a lot. She's not too hard to look at either. Brad Douriff plays a likable role for once. That was rather fun Final Thoughts: It has its faults, but I simply cannot deny the entertainment it provides. Go in with low expectations and have a blast with this puppy. If you like gore, Fahey going nuts like nobody else can, I would check this one out. 6/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This was really good gruesome thriller.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    atinder
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was really good gruesome thriller. Story is self was not all that great, A Guy loses his arm and He get's Killer Arm, which is can not control's at times. I like the fact movie flowed really well, there were not boring at all, there were some very gruesome deaths scenes near the end of the movie, which I did not expect all at all. I really enjoyed the whole movie, I liked how the story ended. The acting from everyone in cast, well some of cast were really good, there could have been better. I don't know if was the acting or not, his wife really annoyed me at times. Overall I give this movie 7 out of 10 really Good movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Body parts behaving badly ........
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    merklekranz
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Although much of "Body Parts" spirals way out of control sacrificing any smidge of believability, the film is never dull, and has definite entertainment value. The presence of Brad Dourif is another plus, as he is always a most interesting character actor. The movie features a couple spectacular car wrecks, an unbelievable chase scene featuring handcuffs, and some unexpected plot twists. All I can say is that this definitely did not go in the direction I expected. If you go in anticipating something original for a change, and are willing to have a complete believability blackout, then you will not be disappointed. - MERK
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bloody hands and the dark side of genius...A scalpel sharp forgotten horror gem of the early 90's
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Foreverisacastironmess
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Effectively uses it's gruesome premise... Jeff Fahey is a great actor, calling him awful is just plain ignorant. Awful actors don't get to be in 118 different features. He is not one of my absolute favourites, but I have always appreciated his laid back, yet edgy style of acting. Brad Dourif! Dourif by name, somewhat dour-looking by nature! Brad is one of my all time favourite horror actors. It is always great to see him, even in small parts in movies like this. I found it really cool to see him and Jeff Fahey acting together, as they are two actors I really like, and they usually play intense, occasionally mad dudes. Brad plays it with his usual manic flair, and Jeff mostly plays it straight, but I love it cause' I know that Jeff could outdo Brad in terms of insanity if he wanted to. People moan that the film copies golden oldies like The Hand and The Hands Of Orloc...So? Know a lot of films about evil body parts, do you? Because I could count them on one hand(!) There's not enough body-part themed horror movies out there... I love the music theme that plays at the beginning, a few times in between, and right at the end. It starts out kind of silly, and then becomes booming and ominous. To me the music represents the film's grotesque sense of fun, and it's shock value. The film has a very good, slow build up of tension. In my opinion it is not until approximately 44 minutes and 38 seconds in that something actually happens. This film is certainly gory, but not very. It doesn't have too many bloody moments, but the one that I find really gross is at the beginning when Bill has had his operation. The way that his arm looks, all freshly stitched, raw and pink...ew!!! I thought it was an okay, average horror movie for quite a while, but my interest had a boost when it came to the scene where Bill discovers that someone has been grafted new legs.(I know that that one is still an impossibility) The film's main antagonist is the dastardly Doctor Agatha Webb. It is made very clear early on that Dr.Webb has her own dark agenda. It is indeed confirmed later on that Webb is indeed a real psycho bitch who will not give up no matter what and cares not a damn that people have to die for her experiment to reach it's insane conclusion. The two kids in the movie are not very interesting or effective, as they were both such bad little actor's! I remember the boy from Are You Afraid Of The Dark? There is a sequence in a bar that's pretty cool. The three transplantees are philosophizing. Brad and Jeff are sitting there with the other guy in the middle, which struck me as funny, as everyone knows who the other two are and no one knows who he is. Sorry other guy, you were good, too! I actually thought he was kinda cute, despite those ears! There is also an awesome fighty bit where Bill, responding to the pestering and insult of a drunk,(Ouch! That one would get anyone ticked off!)proceeds to take on all newcomers with his super-strong evil arm!!! When it comes to the big finale at the end, I don't agree that it's crap, but it does seem to run out of steam a bit. They could have done it better. It turns out that the evil mantis doctor of death Dr Webb's master plan has been, in layman's terms, to amputate the arms, legs, and head(?)of a serial killer?!, transplant them to "lucky" recipients, while still keeping the original torso alive, to later restore, whether the current owners like it or not, the parts back to the original body. Furthermore, she has an enforcer for this, in the killer, who she has kept alive as a head on an unidentified body. All this is for the purpose of proving some great medical advancement in body part manipulation procedures, or some-such. The seen is very impressive because you see all the reclaimed parts strung up in a chamber around the still breathing disembodied torso, awaiting reattachment. I saw what I thought was a very similar and for me far more effective scene in another surgery based horror movie that came out 15 years after this one, and that movie was Autopsy. I bet a lot of people hated or were very unsatisfied with the ending, and I could see why, but I personally loved the ending. I thought it was a different and perfect way to end the picture. It ends like this: the nightmare is over and Bill and his wife are relaxing in a peaceful outdoor scene. He is writing in his journal,(Something that is kind of interwoven that I thought added a lot)reflecting on his experience, and how the arm is now finally truly his. Anyway, they're just sitting there and...nothing happens. No big, last minute fright,(A very nice change)and the credits begin rolling, while lingering on the two, to the film's theme tune. And it's bizarre, and funny, and creepy as hell, and to me it really brings it home that the film was never meant to be taken too seriously. A cool, weird little movie, one that makes you wish you never lose a limb and become ensnared in the evil machinations of a mad doctor! Right on the limb!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This Frankenstein revisited picture, is a B+++ movie!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rbrb
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The film is enjoyable and is good fun. The main character loses his arm in an accident, and gets a replacement from a dubious source leading to all sorts of macabre events, and the play includes having a mad scientist/doctor. What I like about this picture is that even though the story spirals into absurdity and is preposterous, all the lead actors take themselves and the story very seriously making the movie even more hilarious. Everyone gives full throttle performances which keeps the viewer nicely entertained! I wonder if we have or will get a body Parts II?! Worthy of a solid: 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Serial Killer Limbs on Sale! Everything must go!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Coventry
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/2/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is more or less a 90's film version of the famous and often retold tale "The Hands of Orloc". Normally that would worry me, as I'm generally speaking not a big fan of the 90's when it comes to horror and I don't really like seeing classic horror stories ruined by this decade, but for some reason I had a fairly good feeling about this one. Perhaps because co-writer/director Eric Red proved already that he knows a thing or two about creating suspense and atmosphere with his previous achievements "The Hitcher" and "Near Dark". Or maybe because the only truly great version of the tale was "Mad Love" starring Peter Lorre and that movie is already over 70 years of age. "Body Parts" is a reasonably good thriller with a handful of memorable suspense-laden moments and gooey Grand Guignol effects; particularly near the end. The film starts at out somewhat as a serious toned medical drama, but gradually escalates into an outrageous mad scientist horror flick. When family man and criminology shrink Bill Crushank gets involved in a dramatic car accident, his wife Karen has very little time to decide whether or not Dr. Agatha Webb is allowed to try her groundbreaking method of transplanting a donor arm on Bill. The operation is a success and Bill can slowly pick up his career and family life again, until suddenly the donor arm begins to develop a sinister behavior on its own. Bill discovers he got the arm from an executed serial killer and fears that he inherited his murderous tendencies with it. Nobody believes Bill, not even the other patients who received donor parts from the same serial killer, at least not under some murders occur. The first half hour is talkative; the middle section is mainly tense and mysterious (with as a highlight a unique and adrenalin-rushing car chase) and the climax is grotesque and gory with a few very delirious twists. Eric Red's direction is surefooted enough and, although Jeff Fahey definitely isn't bad in the lead role, the show is obviously stolen by an overacting Brad Dourif. 90's B-movie queen Kim Delaney is underused as Fahey's devoted wife. Masterful score by Loek Dikker.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unusual horror film nicely blends with thriller and science fiction
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lucien Lessard
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/11/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Criminal psychologist Bill Chrushank (Jeff Fahey) survived from an horrible car accident but he loses his arm. But when a gifted mysterious Dr. Agatha Webb (Lindsay Duncan) manages to find a donor to have a new arm for Bill. When his wife Karen (Kim Delaney) agrees with the doctor for the operation. When the operation is a success and then its takes weeks for Bill's new arm to be working. In fact, he finds his new arm to be much better than his old one. But then, it's starts doing things that he doesn't want to do and being having vivid nightmares. He finds out that his arm belongs to Charley Fletcher (John Walsh). A violent serial killer, who got executed on the operation table. When Bill got his new arm from. But Bill finds out that he's not the only one, who got spear parts from the infamous murderer. Then after meeting two people (Brad Dourif and Peter Murnik), who got spear body parts from Charley. But when Bill wants his arm off, the Dr. Webb refused to do it. Bill has a feeling or two that Dr. Webb is not what she seems to be and he feels, there's something out there is coming for him. Directed by Eric Red (Bad Moon, Cohen and Tate, Undertow) made an intriguing horror film with some effective moments of suspense and thrills. This was an box office disappointment, when it was released in the summer of 1991. The critics were not kind to this movie as well. Sure, the premise isn't original anymore. But director Red tries to make something different here by adding some neat ideals to the already often filmed premise of the picture. The underrated Fahey gives an strong performance. Dourif gives an memorable small role as the artist, who finds sudden success with his paintings. Red does his best work so far as a filmmaker here. Red wasn't made a movie or wrote a script in years but it seems, he trying to make a comeback with his latest work "100 Feet". That film will be released sometime in 2008. Like most of Red's works, "Body Parts" has become a cult classic. It's certainly one of the most underrated horror movies of the 1990's. Effective music score by Loek Dikker. Insipred from the novel "Choice Cuts" by Pierre Boileau and Thomas Narcejac (Which they wrote the classic book together "Diabolique"). Co-scripted by the director and Norman Snider (Dead Ringers, Rated X). Screen-story by Patricia Herskovic (Producer of cult classics like "Deadly Blessing", "Mother's Boys" and "Toy Soldiers") and Joyce Taylor. Don't miss it. Panavision. (****/*****).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Remember "The Hand"?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Brian T. Whitlock (GOWBTW)
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/10/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Losing a body part can cause a psychological effect on a person, somehow it can be more extreme than this. In the movie "Body Parts", a man loses his right arm when a tanker truck rear ends him, ejecting him through the windshield. The Results has good news and bad news: The Good News; he gets a new right arm. The Bad News; it belongs to an death row inmate who was executed. Worse News; he wants it back, along with his left arm and legs! Hold it! if he's supposed to be dead, how did he come back to life? The individual would donated the parts has got a lot of explaining to do. I liked the part where Bill Chrushank(Jeff Fahey) told her off. Then she later gets killed by the killer. Then there's the scene where he cuffs Bill and tries to drive his arm off. No success. Having his arm scared him and his family, after the killer is unsuccessful of getting his arm back, the curse has lifted. Life is back to normal for Bill and his family. Unlike "The Hand", "Body Parts" is more intense. So if anyone loses a limb, check the donor before surgery starts, and beware of seedy doctors. 2 out of 5 stars!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You must own this Horror to make others watch it at gunpoint.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RabbitMayhem
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/9/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is what happens when the two best movie genres in the world meet each other and have passionate sex. It's SCI-FI mixed in with sick old fashioned HORROR. It's the most beautiful mix ever and it was done in this ERIC RED masterpiece. All the best aspects for a good horror/sci-fi were perfectly aligned for this one. An outstanding lead actor, JEFF FAHEY (The Lawnmower Man), a great movie maker, ERIC RED, and a good book, "CHOICE CUTS" from BOILEAU-NARCEJAC. It's starts off good, then it gets better, but it doesn't stop there. It becomes eerie, then sick, then crazy, and all of a sudden you end up watching a violent twisted ending. Once you get passed the "yeah right" idea of the body grafting, you're in and hooked. You cannot expect CGI, or witty modern dialogue, due to the fact that it was made in 1991 just before the big change between good old-fashioned bloody gore and the new commercial stuff you see today. You will, at the very least, be moved by the fact that you saw it and can make a constructive criticism yourself without outside judgment. It was missed by the popular audience but will always be remembered by HORROR fanatics everywhere. It's a definite keeper.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Quite mediocre but still watchable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    slayrrr666 (slayrrr666@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/7/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Body Parts" isn't that bad, but not quite that good either. **SPOILERS** Assigned to a new case, Psychologist Bill Chrushank, (Jeff Fahey) takes on prison inmate Ray Kolberg, (Paul Ben-Victor) after he murders a fellow prisoner. Talking it over with wife Karen, (Kim Delaney) in an attempt to prove he's redeemable, only to be involved in a horrendous accident on the way to work that takes one of his arms in the process. Attempting a radical operation, Dr. Agatha Webb, (Lindsay Duncan) is able to graph a new arm into it's space. Successfully undergoing rehab, he goes back to his regular life and career like before. Discovering that the arm belonged to an executed serial killer, he begins to feel that it's taking control of him, which everyone else dismisses as ludicrous. Still convinced that something's wrong with the experiment, including talking to other participants of it, and finally determining a way to stop it from taking control, sets out to stop it from happening. The Good News: This here wasn't all that bad. One of it's better features is that it builds up to the realization. It's a noticeable one fairly early on, but the fact that the film bothers to fudge the issue at all is commendable. The beginning after the surgery is filled with ideas that are really quite disturbing. From the sheer amount of ease that it manages to resort to physical violence without physical provocation and the great way that their sudden jerking leads to really suspenseful encounters. The best one is the car experiment that leads to a pretty creepy scene during traffic hours. Initially, the car-wreck that started everything is quite impressive, being horrific without looking overblown like so many other examples. The film's best moments, though, come from it's final half-hour. It's practically wall-to-wall action, including lots of brutal kills, some big action showdowns and an overall satisfying ending. With a spectacular car chase that has a few twists on it that work in it's favor of upping the excitement and suspense, to a brawl inside a medical facility and several subsequent deaths spread throughout, this one here really justifies itself. The kills are great, including some wicked head-shots, a brutal showing of an arm being ripped out of it's socket and another victim having both legs being cut off, among more including lots of property damage from gunshots that literally destroy everything around them, this ending half-hour is unbridled fury of the grandest order. The other last thing that works is that it certainly feels real in most senses. The payoff takes a while, it's a slow process to figure out the truth and there's really a sense of it being a real-life event played out with a horror twist to it. This one here is more than capable of being entertaining when it wanted to be. The Bad News: There's a few problems with this one that can't be overlooked. The biggest one is that this one takes forever to really get to it's good point. The situation is quite apparent early on to just about everyone and yet it still proceeds to drag itself out forever. The fact that it's filled with endless scenes of them moping about over the problematic symptoms over and over again with the different sources takes up way too much time of the film. These are pretty hard to take for the sheer amount of time that is used to get through them all. That they all pretty much end up the same way basically makes them even harder, especially since it becomes obvious that they'll be the same. Another factor that really hurts the film is it's slow pacing. When it finally gets to the good portions of the film, it's already pretty deep into the film due to all the stretching out with the symptoms taking it up. There's very little action up until the ending, and it's a result of having all the talking beforehand. With a little bit more spread out throughout the film, then it would be a little more bearable. The only other thing that doesn't really work is the relatively small amount of good-looking gore in here. With all the bloody, brutal deaths in here, there isn't a whole lot that actually looks that good. The gunshot wounds are absolutely horrendous, and the stitching on the arm wounds aren't all that good looking and don't really look professional. The rest of the gore isn't all that great, and holds it down with the other flaws. The Final Verdict: With a few pretty intriguing areas of interest and a couple small problems, this one's a little tough to call. Some might be more intrigued by it's positives over it's negatives and will give it a shot, while others might think the negatives will overcome it and will be the film's downfall. Rated R: Graphic Language and Graphic Violence
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Watching this unravel was fun, even if logic was thrown out the window. Fahey is terrific!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    callanvass
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw this quite a few years ago when I was younger, and I remembered being fairly unimpressed with it. How do I feel about it now?? I kinda dug it actually, it's got some balls. They really don't make them like this anymore. Not only does it have a car crash scene that makes some of the scenes in a Final Destination movie look weak in comparison. Watching Jeff Fahey go all unruly with everybody is always a treat to watch. I also really dug the family values in this one. Fahey's family really acted like a natural family, and I really felt for Fahey's descent into craziness. There are some things that I questioned, though. I didn't buy how Bill's (Fahey) kids were all nice to Bill, despite the fact that he knocks his son around, and yells a lot. You would think the kids would learn not to go around him. I also felt the finale was overblown. It was entertaining, don't get me wrong, but it was a bit too chaotic for my liking. It also has some pointless characters as well; Zakes Mokae as the detective being one of them. Jeff Fahey is a criminally underrated actor. He has always been one of my favorites, and why this man is stuck in DTV hell right now is beyond me. Stop being stupid Hollywood and recognize this man's talents! His unpredictable show is a main reason why this film is so entertaining. Kim Delaney lends able support as the caring wife, I dug her a lot. She's not too hard to look at either. Brad Douriff plays a likable role for once. That was rather fun Final Thoughts: It has its faults, but I simply cannot deny the entertainment it provides. Go in with low expectations and have a blast with this puppy. If you like gore, Fahey going nuts like nobody else can, I would check this one out. 6/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This was really good gruesome thriller.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    atinder
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was really good gruesome thriller. Story is self was not all that great, A Guy loses his arm and He get's Killer Arm, which is can not control's at times. I like the fact movie flowed really well, there were not boring at all, there were some very gruesome deaths scenes near the end of the movie, which I did not expect all at all. I really enjoyed the whole movie, I liked how the story ended. The acting from everyone in cast, well some of cast were really good, there could have been better. I don't know if was the acting or not, his wife really annoyed me at times. Overall I give this movie 7 out of 10 really Good movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Body parts behaving badly ........
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    merklekranz
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Although much of "Body Parts" spirals way out of control sacrificing any smidge of believability, the film is never dull, and has definite entertainment value. The presence of Brad Dourif is another plus, as he is always a most interesting character actor. The movie features a couple spectacular car wrecks, an unbelievable chase scene featuring handcuffs, and some unexpected plot twists. All I can say is that this definitely did not go in the direction I expected. If you go in anticipating something original for a change, and are willing to have a complete believability blackout, then you will not be disappointed. - MERK
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bloody hands and the dark side of genius...A scalpel sharp forgotten horror gem of the early 90's
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Foreverisacastironmess
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Effectively uses it's gruesome premise... Jeff Fahey is a great actor, calling him awful is just plain ignorant. Awful actors don't get to be in 118 different features. He is not one of my absolute favourites, but I have always appreciated his laid back, yet edgy style of acting. Brad Dourif! Dourif by name, somewhat dour-looking by nature! Brad is one of my all time favourite horror actors. It is always great to see him, even in small parts in movies like this. I found it really cool to see him and Jeff Fahey acting together, as they are two actors I really like, and they usually play intense, occasionally mad dudes. Brad plays it with his usual manic flair, and Jeff mostly plays it straight, but I love it cause' I know that Jeff could outdo Brad in terms of insanity if he wanted to. People moan that the film copies golden oldies like The Hand and The Hands Of Orloc...So? Know a lot of films about evil body parts, do you? Because I could count them on one hand(!) There's not enough body-part themed horror movies out there... I love the music theme that plays at the beginning, a few times in between, and right at the end. It starts out kind of silly, and then becomes booming and ominous. To me the music represents the film's grotesque sense of fun, and it's shock value. The film has a very good, slow build up of tension. In my opinion it is not until approximately 44 minutes and 38 seconds in that something actually happens. This film is certainly gory, but not very. It doesn't have too many bloody moments, but the one that I find really gross is at the beginning when Bill has had his operation. The way that his arm looks, all freshly stitched, raw and pink...ew!!! I thought it was an okay, average horror movie for quite a while, but my interest had a boost when it came to the scene where Bill discovers that someone has been grafted new legs.(I know that that one is still an impossibility) The film's main antagonist is the dastardly Doctor Agatha Webb. It is made very clear early on that Dr.Webb has her own dark agenda. It is indeed confirmed later on that Webb is indeed a real psycho bitch who will not give up no matter what and cares not a damn that people have to die for her experiment to reach it's insane conclusion. The two kids in the movie are not very interesting or effective, as they were both such bad little actor's! I remember the boy from Are You Afraid Of The Dark? There is a sequence in a bar that's pretty cool. The three transplantees are philosophizing. Brad and Jeff are sitting there with the other guy in the middle, which struck me as funny, as everyone knows who the other two are and no one knows who he is. Sorry other guy, you were good, too! I actually thought he was kinda cute, despite those ears! There is also an awesome fighty bit where Bill, responding to the pestering and insult of a drunk,(Ouch! That one would get anyone ticked off!)proceeds to take on all newcomers with his super-strong evil arm!!! When it comes to the big finale at the end, I don't agree that it's crap, but it does seem to run out of steam a bit. They could have done it better. It turns out that the evil mantis doctor of death Dr Webb's master plan has been, in layman's terms, to amputate the arms, legs, and head(?)of a serial killer?!, transplant them to "lucky" recipients, while still keeping the original torso alive, to later restore, whether the current owners like it or not, the parts back to the original body. Furthermore, she has an enforcer for this, in the killer, who she has kept alive as a head on an unidentified body. All this is for the purpose of proving some great medical advancement in body part manipulation procedures, or some-such. The seen is very impressive because you see all the reclaimed parts strung up in a chamber around the still breathing disembodied torso, awaiting reattachment. I saw what I thought was a very similar and for me far more effective scene in another surgery based horror movie that came out 15 years after this one, and that movie was Autopsy. I bet a lot of people hated or were very unsatisfied with the ending, and I could see why, but I personally loved the ending. I thought it was a different and perfect way to end the picture. It ends like this: the nightmare is over and Bill and his wife are relaxing in a peaceful outdoor scene. He is writing in his journal,(Something that is kind of interwoven that I thought added a lot)reflecting on his experience, and how the arm is now finally truly his. Anyway, they're just sitting there and...nothing happens. No big, last minute fright,(A very nice change)and the credits begin rolling, while lingering on the two, to the film's theme tune. And it's bizarre, and funny, and creepy as hell, and to me it really brings it home that the film was never meant to be taken too seriously. A cool, weird little movie, one that makes you wish you never lose a limb and become ensnared in the evil machinations of a mad doctor! Right on the limb!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This Frankenstein revisited picture, is a B+++ movie!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rbrb
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The film is enjoyable and is good fun. The main character loses his arm in an accident, and gets a replacement from a dubious source leading to all sorts of macabre events, and the play includes having a mad scientist/doctor. What I like about this picture is that even though the story spirals into absurdity and is preposterous, all the lead actors take themselves and the story very seriously making the movie even more hilarious. Everyone gives full throttle performances which keeps the viewer nicely entertained! I wonder if we have or will get a body Parts II?! Worthy of a solid: 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Serial Killer Limbs on Sale! Everything must go!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Coventry
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/2/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is more or less a 90's film version of the famous and often retold tale "The Hands of Orloc". Normally that would worry me, as I'm generally speaking not a big fan of the 90's when it comes to horror and I don't really like seeing classic horror stories ruined by this decade, but for some reason I had a fairly good feeling about this one. Perhaps because co-writer/director Eric Red proved already that he knows a thing or two about creating suspense and atmosphere with his previous achievements "The Hitcher" and "Near Dark". Or maybe because the only truly great version of the tale was "Mad Love" starring Peter Lorre and that movie is already over 70 years of age. "Body Parts" is a reasonably good thriller with a handful of memorable suspense-laden moments and gooey Grand Guignol effects; particularly near the end. The film starts at out somewhat as a serious toned medical drama, but gradually escalates into an outrageous mad scientist horror flick. When family man and criminology shrink Bill Crushank gets involved in a dramatic car accident, his wife Karen has very little time to decide whether or not Dr. Agatha Webb is allowed to try her groundbreaking method of transplanting a donor arm on Bill. The operation is a success and Bill can slowly pick up his career and family life again, until suddenly the donor arm begins to develop a sinister behavior on its own. Bill discovers he got the arm from an executed serial killer and fears that he inherited his murderous tendencies with it. Nobody believes Bill, not even the other patients who received donor parts from the same serial killer, at least not under some murders occur. The first half hour is talkative; the middle section is mainly tense and mysterious (with as a highlight a unique and adrenalin-rushing car chase) and the climax is grotesque and gory with a few very delirious twists. Eric Red's direction is surefooted enough and, although Jeff Fahey definitely isn't bad in the lead role, the show is obviously stolen by an overacting Brad Dourif. 90's B-movie queen Kim Delaney is underused as Fahey's devoted wife. Masterful score by Loek Dikker.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unusual horror film nicely blends with thriller and science fiction
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lucien Lessard
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/11/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Criminal psychologist Bill Chrushank (Jeff Fahey) survived from an horrible car accident but he loses his arm. But when a gifted mysterious Dr. Agatha Webb (Lindsay Duncan) manages to find a donor to have a new arm for Bill. When his wife Karen (Kim Delaney) agrees with the doctor for the operation. When the operation is a success and then its takes weeks for Bill's new arm to be working. In fact, he finds his new arm to be much better than his old one. But then, it's starts doing things that he doesn't want to do and being having vivid nightmares. He finds out that his arm belongs to Charley Fletcher (John Walsh). A violent serial killer, who got executed on the operation table. When Bill got his new arm from. But Bill finds out that he's not the only one, who got spear parts from the infamous murderer. Then after meeting two people (Brad Dourif and Peter Murnik), who got spear body parts from Charley. But when Bill wants his arm off, the Dr. Webb refused to do it. Bill has a feeling or two that Dr. Webb is not what she seems to be and he feels, there's something out there is coming for him. Directed by Eric Red (Bad Moon, Cohen and Tate, Undertow) made an intriguing horror film with some effective moments of suspense and thrills. This was an box office disappointment, when it was released in the summer of 1991. The critics were not kind to this movie as well. Sure, the premise isn't original anymore. But director Red tries to make something different here by adding some neat ideals to the already often filmed premise of the picture. The underrated Fahey gives an strong performance. Dourif gives an memorable small role as the artist, who finds sudden success with his paintings. Red does his best work so far as a filmmaker here. Red wasn't made a movie or wrote a script in years but it seems, he trying to make a comeback with his latest work "100 Feet". That film will be released sometime in 2008. Like most of Red's works, "Body Parts" has become a cult classic. It's certainly one of the most underrated horror movies of the 1990's. Effective music score by Loek Dikker. Insipred from the novel "Choice Cuts" by Pierre Boileau and Thomas Narcejac (Which they wrote the classic book together "Diabolique"). Co-scripted by the director and Norman Snider (Dead Ringers, Rated X). Screen-story by Patricia Herskovic (Producer of cult classics like "Deadly Blessing", "Mother's Boys" and "Toy Soldiers") and Joyce Taylor. Don't miss it. Panavision. (****/*****).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Remember "The Hand"?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Brian T. Whitlock (GOWBTW)
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/10/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Losing a body part can cause a psychological effect on a person, somehow it can be more extreme than this. In the movie "Body Parts", a man loses his right arm when a tanker truck rear ends him, ejecting him through the windshield. The Results has good news and bad news: The Good News; he gets a new right arm. The Bad News; it belongs to an death row inmate who was executed. Worse News; he wants it back, along with his left arm and legs! Hold it! if he's supposed to be dead, how did he come back to life? The individual would donated the parts has got a lot of explaining to do. I liked the part where Bill Chrushank(Jeff Fahey) told her off. Then she later gets killed by the killer. Then there's the scene where he cuffs Bill and tries to drive his arm off. No success. Having his arm scared him and his family, after the killer is unsuccessful of getting his arm back, the curse has lifted. Life is back to normal for Bill and his family. Unlike "The Hand", "Body Parts" is more intense. So if anyone loses a limb, check the donor before surgery starts, and beware of seedy doctors. 2 out of 5 stars!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You must own this Horror to make others watch it at gunpoint.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RabbitMayhem
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/9/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is what happens when the two best movie genres in the world meet each other and have passionate sex. It's SCI-FI mixed in with sick old fashioned HORROR. It's the most beautiful mix ever and it was done in this ERIC RED masterpiece. All the best aspects for a good horror/sci-fi were perfectly aligned for this one. An outstanding lead actor, JEFF FAHEY (The Lawnmower Man), a great movie maker, ERIC RED, and a good book, "CHOICE CUTS" from BOILEAU-NARCEJAC. It's starts off good, then it gets better, but it doesn't stop there. It becomes eerie, then sick, then crazy, and all of a sudden you end up watching a violent twisted ending. Once you get passed the "yeah right" idea of the body grafting, you're in and hooked. You cannot expect CGI, or witty modern dialogue, due to the fact that it was made in 1991 just before the big change between good old-fashioned bloody gore and the new commercial stuff you see today. You will, at the very least, be moved by the fact that you saw it and can make a constructive criticism yourself without outside judgment. It was missed by the popular audience but will always be remembered by HORROR fanatics everywhere. It's a definite keeper.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Quite mediocre but still watchable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    slayrrr666 (slayrrr666@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/7/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Body Parts" isn't that bad, but not quite that good either. **SPOILERS** Assigned to a new case, Psychologist Bill Chrushank, (Jeff Fahey) takes on prison inmate Ray Kolberg, (Paul Ben-Victor) after he murders a fellow prisoner. Talking it over with wife Karen, (Kim Delaney) in an attempt to prove he's redeemable, only to be involved in a horrendous accident on the way to work that takes one of his arms in the process. Attempting a radical operation, Dr. Agatha Webb, (Lindsay Duncan) is able to graph a new arm into it's space. Successfully undergoing rehab, he goes back to his regular life and career like before. Discovering that the arm belonged to an executed serial killer, he begins to feel that it's taking control of him, which everyone else dismisses as ludicrous. Still convinced that something's wrong with the experiment, including talking to other participants of it, and finally determining a way to stop it from taking control, sets out to stop it from happening. The Good News: This here wasn't all that bad. One of it's better features is that it builds up to the realization. It's a noticeable one fairly early on, but the fact that the film bothers to fudge the issue at all is commendable. The beginning after the surgery is filled with ideas that are really quite disturbing. From the sheer amount of ease that it manages to resort to physical violence without physical provocation and the great way that their sudden jerking leads to really suspenseful encounters. The best one is the car experiment that leads to a pretty creepy scene during traffic hours. Initially, the car-wreck that started everything is quite impressive, being horrific without looking overblown like so many other examples. The film's best moments, though, come from it's final half-hour. It's practically wall-to-wall action, including lots of brutal kills, some big action showdowns and an overall satisfying ending. With a spectacular car chase that has a few twists on it that work in it's favor of upping the excitement and suspense, to a brawl inside a medical facility and several subsequent deaths spread throughout, this one here really justifies itself. The kills are great, including some wicked head-shots, a brutal showing of an arm being ripped out of it's socket and another victim having both legs being cut off, among more including lots of property damage from gunshots that literally destroy everything around them, this ending half-hour is unbridled fury of the grandest order. The other last thing that works is that it certainly feels real in most senses. The payoff takes a while, it's a slow process to figure out the truth and there's really a sense of it being a real-life event played out with a horror twist to it. This one here is more than capable of being entertaining when it wanted to be. The Bad News: There's a few problems with this one that can't be overlooked. The biggest one is that this one takes forever to really get to it's good point. The situation is quite apparent early on to just about everyone and yet it still proceeds to drag itself out forever. The fact that it's filled with endless scenes of them moping about over the problematic symptoms over and over again with the different sources takes up way too much time of the film. These are pretty hard to take for the sheer amount of time that is used to get through them all. That they all pretty much end up the same way basically makes them even harder, especially since it becomes obvious that they'll be the same. Another factor that really hurts the film is it's slow pacing. When it finally gets to the good portions of the film, it's already pretty deep into the film due to all the stretching out with the symptoms taking it up. There's very little action up until the ending, and it's a result of having all the talking beforehand. With a little bit more spread out throughout the film, then it would be a little more bearable. The only other thing that doesn't really work is the relatively small amount of good-looking gore in here. With all the bloody, brutal deaths in here, there isn't a whole lot that actually looks that good. The gunshot wounds are absolutely horrendous, and the stitching on the arm wounds aren't all that good looking and don't really look professional. The rest of the gore isn't all that great, and holds it down with the other flaws. The Final Verdict: With a few pretty intriguing areas of interest and a couple small problems, this one's a little tough to call. Some might be more intrigued by it's positives over it's negatives and will give it a shot, while others might think the negatives will overcome it and will be the film's downfall. Rated R: Graphic Language and Graphic Violence
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Watching this unravel was fun, even if logic was thrown out the window. Fahey is terrific!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    callanvass
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw this quite a few years ago when I was younger, and I remembered being fairly unimpressed with it. How do I feel about it now?? I kinda dug it actually, it's got some balls. They really don't make them like this anymore. Not only does it have a car crash scene that makes some of the scenes in a Final Destination movie look weak in comparison. Watching Jeff Fahey go all unruly with everybody is always a treat to watch. I also really dug the family values in this one. Fahey's family really acted like a natural family, and I really felt for Fahey's descent into craziness. There are some things that I questioned, though. I didn't buy how Bill's (Fahey) kids were all nice to Bill, despite the fact that he knocks his son around, and yells a lot. You would think the kids would learn not to go around him. I also felt the finale was overblown. It was entertaining, don't get me wrong, but it was a bit too chaotic for my liking. It also has some pointless characters as well; Zakes Mokae as the detective being one of them. Jeff Fahey is a criminally underrated actor. He has always been one of my favorites, and why this man is stuck in DTV hell right now is beyond me. Stop being stupid Hollywood and recognize this man's talents! His unpredictable show is a main reason why this film is so entertaining. Kim Delaney lends able support as the caring wife, I dug her a lot. She's not too hard to look at either. Brad Douriff plays a likable role for once. That was rather fun Final Thoughts: It has its faults, but I simply cannot deny the entertainment it provides. Go in with low expectations and have a blast with this puppy. If you like gore, Fahey going nuts like nobody else can, I would check this one out. 6/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This was really good gruesome thriller.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    atinder
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was really good gruesome thriller. Story is self was not all that great, A Guy loses his arm and He get's Killer Arm, which is can not control's at times. I like the fact movie flowed really well, there were not boring at all, there were some very gruesome deaths scenes near the end of the movie, which I did not expect all at all. I really enjoyed the whole movie, I liked how the story ended. The acting from everyone in cast, well some of cast were really good, there could have been better. I don't know if was the acting or not, his wife really annoyed me at times. Overall I give this movie 7 out of 10 really Good movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Body parts behaving badly ........
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    merklekranz
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Although much of "Body Parts" spirals way out of control sacrificing any smidge of believability, the film is never dull, and has definite entertainment value. The presence of Brad Dourif is another plus, as he is always a most interesting character actor. The movie features a couple spectacular car wrecks, an unbelievable chase scene featuring handcuffs, and some unexpected plot twists. All I can say is that this definitely did not go in the direction I expected. If you go in anticipating something original for a change, and are willing to have a complete believability blackout, then you will not be disappointed. - MERK
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bloody hands and the dark side of genius...A scalpel sharp forgotten horror gem of the early 90's
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Foreverisacastironmess
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Effectively uses it's gruesome premise... Jeff Fahey is a great actor, calling him awful is just plain ignorant. Awful actors don't get to be in 118 different features. He is not one of my absolute favourites, but I have always appreciated his laid back, yet edgy style of acting. Brad Dourif! Dourif by name, somewhat dour-looking by nature! Brad is one of my all time favourite horror actors. It is always great to see him, even in small parts in movies like this. I found it really cool to see him and Jeff Fahey acting together, as they are two actors I really like, and they usually play intense, occasionally mad dudes. Brad plays it with his usual manic flair, and Jeff mostly plays it straight, but I love it cause' I know that Jeff could outdo Brad in terms of insanity if he wanted to. People moan that the film copies golden oldies like The Hand and The Hands Of Orloc...So? Know a lot of films about evil body parts, do you? Because I could count them on one hand(!) There's not enough body-part themed horror movies out there... I love the music theme that plays at the beginning, a few times in between, and right at the end. It starts out kind of silly, and then becomes booming and ominous. To me the music represents the film's grotesque sense of fun, and it's shock value. The film has a very good, slow build up of tension. In my opinion it is not until approximately 44 minutes and 38 seconds in that something actually happens. This film is certainly gory, but not very. It doesn't have too many bloody moments, but the one that I find really gross is at the beginning when Bill has had his operation. The way that his arm looks, all freshly stitched, raw and pink...ew!!! I thought it was an okay, average horror movie for quite a while, but my interest had a boost when it came to the scene where Bill discovers that someone has been grafted new legs.(I know that that one is still an impossibility) The film's main antagonist is the dastardly Doctor Agatha Webb. It is made very clear early on that Dr.Webb has her own dark agenda. It is indeed confirmed later on that Webb is indeed a real psycho bitch who will not give up no matter what and cares not a damn that people have to die for her experiment to reach it's insane conclusion. The two kids in the movie are not very interesting or effective, as they were both such bad little actor's! I remember the boy from Are You Afraid Of The Dark? There is a sequence in a bar that's pretty cool. The three transplantees are philosophizing. Brad and Jeff are sitting there with the other guy in the middle, which struck me as funny, as everyone knows who the other two are and no one knows who he is. Sorry other guy, you were good, too! I actually thought he was kinda cute, despite those ears! There is also an awesome fighty bit where Bill, responding to the pestering and insult of a drunk,(Ouch! That one would get anyone ticked off!)proceeds to take on all newcomers with his super-strong evil arm!!! When it comes to the big finale at the end, I don't agree that it's crap, but it does seem to run out of steam a bit. They could have done it better. It turns out that the evil mantis doctor of death Dr Webb's master plan has been, in layman's terms, to amputate the arms, legs, and head(?)of a serial killer?!, transplant them to "lucky" recipients, while still keeping the original torso alive, to later restore, whether the current owners like it or not, the parts back to the original body. Furthermore, she has an enforcer for this, in the killer, who she has kept alive as a head on an unidentified body. All this is for the purpose of proving some great medical advancement in body part manipulation procedures, or some-such. The seen is very impressive because you see all the reclaimed parts strung up in a chamber around the still breathing disembodied torso, awaiting reattachment. I saw what I thought was a very similar and for me far more effective scene in another surgery based horror movie that came out 15 years after this one, and that movie was Autopsy. I bet a lot of people hated or were very unsatisfied with the ending, and I could see why, but I personally loved the ending. I thought it was a different and perfect way to end the picture. It ends like this: the nightmare is over and Bill and his wife are relaxing in a peaceful outdoor scene. He is writing in his journal,(Something that is kind of interwoven that I thought added a lot)reflecting on his experience, and how the arm is now finally truly his. Anyway, they're just sitting there and...nothing happens. No big, last minute fright,(A very nice change)and the credits begin rolling, while lingering on the two, to the film's theme tune. And it's bizarre, and funny, and creepy as hell, and to me it really brings it home that the film was never meant to be taken too seriously. A cool, weird little movie, one that makes you wish you never lose a limb and become ensnared in the evil machinations of a mad doctor! Right on the limb!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This Frankenstein revisited picture, is a B+++ movie!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rbrb
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The film is enjoyable and is good fun. The main character loses his arm in an accident, and gets a replacement from a dubious source leading to all sorts of macabre events, and the play includes having a mad scientist/doctor. What I like about this picture is that even though the story spirals into absurdity and is preposterous, all the lead actors take themselves and the story very seriously making the movie even more hilarious. Everyone gives full throttle performances which keeps the viewer nicely entertained! I wonder if we have or will get a body Parts II?! Worthy of a solid: 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Serial Killer Limbs on Sale! Everything must go!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Coventry
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/2/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is more or less a 90's film version of the famous and often retold tale "The Hands of Orloc". Normally that would worry me, as I'm generally speaking not a big fan of the 90's when it comes to horror and I don't really like seeing classic horror stories ruined by this decade, but for some reason I had a fairly good feeling about this one. Perhaps because co-writer/director Eric Red proved already that he knows a thing or two about creating suspense and atmosphere with his previous achievements "The Hitcher" and "Near Dark". Or maybe because the only truly great version of the tale was "Mad Love" starring Peter Lorre and that movie is already over 70 years of age. "Body Parts" is a reasonably good thriller with a handful of memorable suspense-laden moments and gooey Grand Guignol effects; particularly near the end. The film starts at out somewhat as a serious toned medical drama, but gradually escalates into an outrageous mad scientist horror flick. When family man and criminology shrink Bill Crushank gets involved in a dramatic car accident, his wife Karen has very little time to decide whether or not Dr. Agatha Webb is allowed to try her groundbreaking method of transplanting a donor arm on Bill. The operation is a success and Bill can slowly pick up his career and family life again, until suddenly the donor arm begins to develop a sinister behavior on its own. Bill discovers he got the arm from an executed serial killer and fears that he inherited his murderous tendencies with it. Nobody believes Bill, not even the other patients who received donor parts from the same serial killer, at least not under some murders occur. The first half hour is talkative; the middle section is mainly tense and mysterious (with as a highlight a unique and adrenalin-rushing car chase) and the climax is grotesque and gory with a few very delirious twists. Eric Red's direction is surefooted enough and, although Jeff Fahey definitely isn't bad in the lead role, the show is obviously stolen by an overacting Brad Dourif. 90's B-movie queen Kim Delaney is underused as Fahey's devoted wife. Masterful score by Loek Dikker.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unusual horror film nicely blends with thriller and science fiction
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lucien Lessard
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/11/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Criminal psychologist Bill Chrushank (Jeff Fahey) survived from an horrible car accident but he loses his arm. But when a gifted mysterious Dr. Agatha Webb (Lindsay Duncan) manages to find a donor to have a new arm for Bill. When his wife Karen (Kim Delaney) agrees with the doctor for the operation. When the operation is a success and then its takes weeks for Bill's new arm to be working. In fact, he finds his new arm to be much better than his old one. But then, it's starts doing things that he doesn't want to do and being having vivid nightmares. He finds out that his arm belongs to Charley Fletcher (John Walsh). A violent serial killer, who got executed on the operation table. When Bill got his new arm from. But Bill finds out that he's not the only one, who got spear parts from the infamous murderer. Then after meeting two people (Brad Dourif and Peter Murnik), who got spear body parts from Charley. But when Bill wants his arm off, the Dr. Webb refused to do it. Bill has a feeling or two that Dr. Webb is not what she seems to be and he feels, there's something out there is coming for him. Directed by Eric Red (Bad Moon, Cohen and Tate, Undertow) made an intriguing horror film with some effective moments of suspense and thrills. This was an box office disappointment, when it was released in the summer of 1991. The critics were not kind to this movie as well. Sure, the premise isn't original anymore. But director Red tries to make something different here by adding some neat ideals to the already often filmed premise of the picture. The underrated Fahey gives an strong performance. Dourif gives an memorable small role as the artist, who finds sudden success with his paintings. Red does his best work so far as a filmmaker here. Red wasn't made a movie or wrote a script in years but it seems, he trying to make a comeback with his latest work "100 Feet". That film will be released sometime in 2008. Like most of Red's works, "Body Parts" has become a cult classic. It's certainly one of the most underrated horror movies of the 1990's. Effective music score by Loek Dikker. Insipred from the novel "Choice Cuts" by Pierre Boileau and Thomas Narcejac (Which they wrote the classic book together "Diabolique"). Co-scripted by the director and Norman Snider (Dead Ringers, Rated X). Screen-story by Patricia Herskovic (Producer of cult classics like "Deadly Blessing", "Mother's Boys" and "Toy Soldiers") and Joyce Taylor. Don't miss it. Panavision. (****/*****).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Remember "The Hand"?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Brian T. Whitlock (GOWBTW)
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/10/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Losing a body part can cause a psychological effect on a person, somehow it can be more extreme than this. In the movie "Body Parts", a man loses his right arm when a tanker truck rear ends him, ejecting him through the windshield. The Results has good news and bad news: The Good News; he gets a new right arm. The Bad News; it belongs to an death row inmate who was executed. Worse News; he wants it back, along with his left arm and legs! Hold it! if he's supposed to be dead, how did he come back to life? The individual would donated the parts has got a lot of explaining to do. I liked the part where Bill Chrushank(Jeff Fahey) told her off. Then she later gets killed by the killer. Then there's the scene where he cuffs Bill and tries to drive his arm off. No success. Having his arm scared him and his family, after the killer is unsuccessful of getting his arm back, the curse has lifted. Life is back to normal for Bill and his family. Unlike "The Hand", "Body Parts" is more intense. So if anyone loses a limb, check the donor before surgery starts, and beware of seedy doctors. 2 out of 5 stars!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You must own this Horror to make others watch it at gunpoint.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RabbitMayhem
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/9/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is what happens when the two best movie genres in the world meet each other and have passionate sex. It's SCI-FI mixed in with sick old fashioned HORROR. It's the most beautiful mix ever and it was done in this ERIC RED masterpiece. All the best aspects for a good horror/sci-fi were perfectly aligned for this one. An outstanding lead actor, JEFF FAHEY (The Lawnmower Man), a great movie maker, ERIC RED, and a good book, "CHOICE CUTS" from BOILEAU-NARCEJAC. It's starts off good, then it gets better, but it doesn't stop there. It becomes eerie, then sick, then crazy, and all of a sudden you end up watching a violent twisted ending. Once you get passed the "yeah right" idea of the body grafting, you're in and hooked. You cannot expect CGI, or witty modern dialogue, due to the fact that it was made in 1991 just before the big change between good old-fashioned bloody gore and the new commercial stuff you see today. You will, at the very least, be moved by the fact that you saw it and can make a constructive criticism yourself without outside judgment. It was missed by the popular audience but will always be remembered by HORROR fanatics everywhere. It's a definite keeper.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Quite mediocre but still watchable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    slayrrr666 (slayrrr666@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/7/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Body Parts" isn't that bad, but not quite that good either. **SPOILERS** Assigned to a new case, Psychologist Bill Chrushank, (Jeff Fahey) takes on prison inmate Ray Kolberg, (Paul Ben-Victor) after he murders a fellow prisoner. Talking it over with wife Karen, (Kim Delaney) in an attempt to prove he's redeemable, only to be involved in a horrendous accident on the way to work that takes one of his arms in the process. Attempting a radical operation, Dr. Agatha Webb, (Lindsay Duncan) is able to graph a new arm into it's space. Successfully undergoing rehab, he goes back to his regular life and career like before. Discovering that the arm belonged to an executed serial killer, he begins to feel that it's taking control of him, which everyone else dismisses as ludicrous. Still convinced that something's wrong with the experiment, including talking to other participants of it, and finally determining a way to stop it from taking control, sets out to stop it from happening. The Good News: This here wasn't all that bad. One of it's better features is that it builds up to the realization. It's a noticeable one fairly early on, but the fact that the film bothers to fudge the issue at all is commendable. The beginning after the surgery is filled with ideas that are really quite disturbing. From the sheer amount of ease that it manages to resort to physical violence without physical provocation and the great way that their sudden jerking leads to really suspenseful encounters. The best one is the car experiment that leads to a pretty creepy scene during traffic hours. Initially, the car-wreck that started everything is quite impressive, being horrific without looking overblown like so many other examples. The film's best moments, though, come from it's final half-hour. It's practically wall-to-wall action, including lots of brutal kills, some big action showdowns and an overall satisfying ending. With a spectacular car chase that has a few twists on it that work in it's favor of upping the excitement and suspense, to a brawl inside a medical facility and several subsequent deaths spread throughout, this one here really justifies itself. The kills are great, including some wicked head-shots, a brutal showing of an arm being ripped out of it's socket and another victim having both legs being cut off, among more including lots of property damage from gunshots that literally destroy everything around them, this ending half-hour is unbridled fury of the grandest order. The other last thing that works is that it certainly feels real in most senses. The payoff takes a while, it's a slow process to figure out the truth and there's really a sense of it being a real-life event played out with a horror twist to it. This one here is more than capable of being entertaining when it wanted to be. The Bad News: There's a few problems with this one that can't be overlooked. The biggest one is that this one takes forever to really get to it's good point. The situation is quite apparent early on to just about everyone and yet it still proceeds to drag itself out forever. The fact that it's filled with endless scenes of them moping about over the problematic symptoms over and over again with the different sources takes up way too much time of the film. These are pretty hard to take for the sheer amount of time that is used to get through them all. That they all pretty much end up the same way basically makes them even harder, especially since it becomes obvious that they'll be the same. Another factor that really hurts the film is it's slow pacing. When it finally gets to the good portions of the film, it's already pretty deep into the film due to all the stretching out with the symptoms taking it up. There's very little action up until the ending, and it's a result of having all the talking beforehand. With a little bit more spread out throughout the film, then it would be a little more bearable. The only other thing that doesn't really work is the relatively small amount of good-looking gore in here. With all the bloody, brutal deaths in here, there isn't a whole lot that actually looks that good. The gunshot wounds are absolutely horrendous, and the stitching on the arm wounds aren't all that good looking and don't really look professional. The rest of the gore isn't all that great, and holds it down with the other flaws. The Final Verdict: With a few pretty intriguing areas of interest and a couple small problems, this one's a little tough to call. Some might be more intrigued by it's positives over it's negatives and will give it a shot, while others might think the negatives will overcome it and will be the film's downfall. Rated R: Graphic Language and Graphic Violence
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Watching this unravel was fun, even if logic was thrown out the window. Fahey is terrific!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    callanvass
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw this quite a few years ago when I was younger, and I remembered being fairly unimpressed with it. How do I feel about it now?? I kinda dug it actually, it's got some balls. They really don't make them like this anymore. Not only does it have a car crash scene that makes some of the scenes in a Final Destination movie look weak in comparison. Watching Jeff Fahey go all unruly with everybody is always a treat to watch. I also really dug the family values in this one. Fahey's family really acted like a natural family, and I really felt for Fahey's descent into craziness. There are some things that I questioned, though. I didn't buy how Bill's (Fahey) kids were all nice to Bill, despite the fact that he knocks his son around, and yells a lot. You would think the kids would learn not to go around him. I also felt the finale was overblown. It was entertaining, don't get me wrong, but it was a bit too chaotic for my liking. It also has some pointless characters as well; Zakes Mokae as the detective being one of them. Jeff Fahey is a criminally underrated actor. He has always been one of my favorites, and why this man is stuck in DTV hell right now is beyond me. Stop being stupid Hollywood and recognize this man's talents! His unpredictable show is a main reason why this film is so entertaining. Kim Delaney lends able support as the caring wife, I dug her a lot. She's not too hard to look at either. Brad Douriff plays a likable role for once. That was rather fun Final Thoughts: It has its faults, but I simply cannot deny the entertainment it provides. Go in with low expectations and have a blast with this puppy. If you like gore, Fahey going nuts like nobody else can, I would check this one out. 6/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This was really good gruesome thriller.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    atinder
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was really good gruesome thriller. Story is self was not all that great, A Guy loses his arm and He get's Killer Arm, which is can not control's at times. I like the fact movie flowed really well, there were not boring at all, there were some very gruesome deaths scenes near the end of the movie, which I did not expect all at all. I really enjoyed the whole movie, I liked how the story ended. The acting from everyone in cast, well some of cast were really good, there could have been better. I don't know if was the acting or not, his wife really annoyed me at times. Overall I give this movie 7 out of 10 really Good movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Body parts behaving badly ........
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    merklekranz
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Although much of "Body Parts" spirals way out of control sacrificing any smidge of believability, the film is never dull, and has definite entertainment value. The presence of Brad Dourif is another plus, as he is always a most interesting character actor. The movie features a couple spectacular car wrecks, an unbelievable chase scene featuring handcuffs, and some unexpected plot twists. All I can say is that this definitely did not go in the direction I expected. If you go in anticipating something original for a change, and are willing to have a complete believability blackout, then you will not be disappointed. - MERK
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bloody hands and the dark side of genius...A scalpel sharp forgotten horror gem of the early 90's
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Foreverisacastironmess
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Effectively uses it's gruesome premise... Jeff Fahey is a great actor, calling him awful is just plain ignorant. Awful actors don't get to be in 118 different features. He is not one of my absolute favourites, but I have always appreciated his laid back, yet edgy style of acting. Brad Dourif! Dourif by name, somewhat dour-looking by nature! Brad is one of my all time favourite horror actors. It is always great to see him, even in small parts in movies like this. I found it really cool to see him and Jeff Fahey acting together, as they are two actors I really like, and they usually play intense, occasionally mad dudes. Brad plays it with his usual manic flair, and Jeff mostly plays it straight, but I love it cause' I know that Jeff could outdo Brad in terms of insanity if he wanted to. People moan that the film copies golden oldies like The Hand and The Hands Of Orloc...So? Know a lot of films about evil body parts, do you? Because I could count them on one hand(!) There's not enough body-part themed horror movies out there... I love the music theme that plays at the beginning, a few times in between, and right at the end. It starts out kind of silly, and then becomes booming and ominous. To me the music represents the film's grotesque sense of fun, and it's shock value. The film has a very good, slow build up of tension. In my opinion it is not until approximately 44 minutes and 38 seconds in that something actually happens. This film is certainly gory, but not very. It doesn't have too many bloody moments, but the one that I find really gross is at the beginning when Bill has had his operation. The way that his arm looks, all freshly stitched, raw and pink...ew!!! I thought it was an okay, average horror movie for quite a while, but my interest had a boost when it came to the scene where Bill discovers that someone has been grafted new legs.(I know that that one is still an impossibility) The film's main antagonist is the dastardly Doctor Agatha Webb. It is made very clear early on that Dr.Webb has her own dark agenda. It is indeed confirmed later on that Webb is indeed a real psycho bitch who will not give up no matter what and cares not a damn that people have to die for her experiment to reach it's insane conclusion. The two kids in the movie are not very interesting or effective, as they were both such bad little actor's! I remember the boy from Are You Afraid Of The Dark? There is a sequence in a bar that's pretty cool. The three transplantees are philosophizing. Brad and Jeff are sitting there with the other guy in the middle, which struck me as funny, as everyone knows who the other two are and no one knows who he is. Sorry other guy, you were good, too! I actually thought he was kinda cute, despite those ears! There is also an awesome fighty bit where Bill, responding to the pestering and insult of a drunk,(Ouch! That one would get anyone ticked off!)proceeds to take on all newcomers with his super-strong evil arm!!! When it comes to the big finale at the end, I don't agree that it's crap, but it does seem to run out of steam a bit. They could have done it better. It turns out that the evil mantis doctor of death Dr Webb's master plan has been, in layman's terms, to amputate the arms, legs, and head(?)of a serial killer?!, transplant them to "lucky" recipients, while still keeping the original torso alive, to later restore, whether the current owners like it or not, the parts back to the original body. Furthermore, she has an enforcer for this, in the killer, who she has kept alive as a head on an unidentified body. All this is for the purpose of proving some great medical advancement in body part manipulation procedures, or some-such. The seen is very impressive because you see all the reclaimed parts strung up in a chamber around the still breathing disembodied torso, awaiting reattachment. I saw what I thought was a very similar and for me far more effective scene in another surgery based horror movie that came out 15 years after this one, and that movie was Autopsy. I bet a lot of people hated or were very unsatisfied with the ending, and I could see why, but I personally loved the ending. I thought it was a different and perfect way to end the picture. It ends like this: the nightmare is over and Bill and his wife are relaxing in a peaceful outdoor scene. He is writing in his journal,(Something that is kind of interwoven that I thought added a lot)reflecting on his experience, and how the arm is now finally truly his. Anyway, they're just sitting there and...nothing happens. No big, last minute fright,(A very nice change)and the credits begin rolling, while lingering on the two, to the film's theme tune. And it's bizarre, and funny, and creepy as hell, and to me it really brings it home that the film was never meant to be taken too seriously. A cool, weird little movie, one that makes you wish you never lose a limb and become ensnared in the evil machinations of a mad doctor! Right on the limb!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This Frankenstein revisited picture, is a B+++ movie!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rbrb
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The film is enjoyable and is good fun. The main character loses his arm in an accident, and gets a replacement from a dubious source leading to all sorts of macabre events, and the play includes having a mad scientist/doctor. What I like about this picture is that even though the story spirals into absurdity and is preposterous, all the lead actors take themselves and the story very seriously making the movie even more hilarious. Everyone gives full throttle performances which keeps the viewer nicely entertained! I wonder if we have or will get a body Parts II?! Worthy of a solid: 7/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Serial Killer Limbs on Sale! Everything must go!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Coventry
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/2/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is more or less a 90's film version of the famous and often retold tale "The Hands of Orloc". Normally that would worry me, as I'm generally speaking not a big fan of the 90's when it comes to horror and I don't really like seeing classic horror stories ruined by this decade, but for some reason I had a fairly good feeling about this one. Perhaps because co-writer/director Eric Red proved already that he knows a thing or two about creating suspense and atmosphere with his previous achievements "The Hitcher" and "Near Dark". Or maybe because the only truly great version of the tale was "Mad Love" starring Peter Lorre and that movie is already over 70 years of age. "Body Parts" is a reasonably good thriller with a handful of memorable suspense-laden moments and gooey Grand Guignol effects; particularly near the end. The film starts at out somewhat as a serious toned medical drama, but gradually escalates into an outrageous mad scientist horror flick. When family man and criminology shrink Bill Crushank gets involved in a dramatic car accident, his wife Karen has very little time to decide whether or not Dr. Agatha Webb is allowed to try her groundbreaking method of transplanting a donor arm on Bill. The operation is a success and Bill can slowly pick up his career and family life again, until suddenly the donor arm begins to develop a sinister behavior on its own. Bill discovers he got the arm from an executed serial killer and fears that he inherited his murderous tendencies with it. Nobody believes Bill, not even the other patients who received donor parts from the same serial killer, at least not under some murders occur. The first half hour is talkative; the middle section is mainly tense and mysterious (with as a highlight a unique and adrenalin-rushing car chase) and the climax is grotesque and gory with a few very delirious twists. Eric Red's direction is surefooted enough and, although Jeff Fahey definitely isn't bad in the lead role, the show is obviously stolen by an overacting Brad Dourif. 90's B-movie queen Kim Delaney is underused as Fahey's devoted wife. Masterful score by Loek Dikker.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unusual horror film nicely blends with thriller and science fiction
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lucien Lessard
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/11/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Criminal psychologist Bill Chrushank (Jeff Fahey) survived from an horrible car accident but he loses his arm. But when a gifted mysterious Dr. Agatha Webb (Lindsay Duncan) manages to find a donor to have a new arm for Bill. When his wife Karen (Kim Delaney) agrees with the doctor for the operation. When the operation is a success and then its takes weeks for Bill's new arm to be working. In fact, he finds his new arm to be much better than his old one. But then, it's starts doing things that he doesn't want to do and being having vivid nightmares. He finds out that his arm belongs to Charley Fletcher (John Walsh). A violent serial killer, who got executed on the operation table. When Bill got his new arm from. But Bill finds out that he's not the only one, who got spear parts from the infamous murderer. Then after meeting two people (Brad Dourif and Peter Murnik), who got spear body parts from Charley. But when Bill wants his arm off, the Dr. Webb refused to do it. Bill has a feeling or two that Dr. Webb is not what she seems to be and he feels, there's something out there is coming for him. Directed by Eric Red (Bad Moon, Cohen and Tate, Undertow) made an intriguing horror film with some effective moments of suspense and thrills. This was an box office disappointment, when it was released in the summer of 1991. The critics were not kind to this movie as well. Sure, the premise isn't original anymore. But director Red tries to make something different here by adding some neat ideals to the already often filmed premise of the picture. The underrated Fahey gives an strong performance. Dourif gives an memorable small role as the artist, who finds sudden success with his paintings. Red does his best work so far as a filmmaker here. Red wasn't made a movie or wrote a script in years but it seems, he trying to make a comeback with his latest work "100 Feet". That film will be released sometime in 2008. Like most of Red's works, "Body Parts" has become a cult classic. It's certainly one of the most underrated horror movies of the 1990's. Effective music score by Loek Dikker. Insipred from the novel "Choice Cuts" by Pierre Boileau and Thomas Narcejac (Which they wrote the classic book together "Diabolique"). Co-scripted by the director and Norman Snider (Dead Ringers, Rated X). Screen-story by Patricia Herskovic (Producer of cult classics like "Deadly Blessing", "Mother's Boys" and "Toy Soldiers") and Joyce Taylor. Don't miss it. Panavision. (****/*****).
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Remember "The Hand"?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Brian T. Whitlock (GOWBTW)
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/10/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Losing a body part can cause a psychological effect on a person, somehow it can be more extreme than this. In the movie "Body Parts", a man loses his right arm when a tanker truck rear ends him, ejecting him through the windshield. The Results has good news and bad news: The Good News; he gets a new right arm. The Bad News; it belongs to an death row inmate who was executed. Worse News; he wants it back, along with his left arm and legs! Hold it! if he's supposed to be dead, how did he come back to life? The individual would donated the parts has got a lot of explaining to do. I liked the part where Bill Chrushank(Jeff Fahey) told her off. Then she later gets killed by the killer. Then there's the scene where he cuffs Bill and tries to drive his arm off. No success. Having his arm scared him and his family, after the killer is unsuccessful of getting his arm back, the curse has lifted. Life is back to normal for Bill and his family. Unlike "The Hand", "Body Parts" is more intense. So if anyone loses a limb, check the donor before surgery starts, and beware of seedy doctors. 2 out of 5 stars!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    You must own this Horror to make others watch it at gunpoint.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RabbitMayhem
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/9/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is what happens when the two best movie genres in the world meet each other and have passionate sex. It's SCI-FI mixed in with sick old fashioned HORROR. It's the most beautiful mix ever and it was done in this ERIC RED masterpiece. All the best aspects for a good horror/sci-fi were perfectly aligned for this one. An outstanding lead actor, JEFF FAHEY (The Lawnmower Man), a great movie maker, ERIC RED, and a good book, "CHOICE CUTS" from BOILEAU-NARCEJAC. It's starts off good, then it gets better, but it doesn't stop there. It becomes eerie, then sick, then crazy, and all of a sudden you end up watching a violent twisted ending. Once you get passed the "yeah right" idea of the body grafting, you're in and hooked. You cannot expect CGI, or witty modern dialogue, due to the fact that it was made in 1991 just before the big change between good old-fashioned bloody gore and the new commercial stuff you see today. You will, at the very least, be moved by the fact that you saw it and can make a constructive criticism yourself without outside judgment. It was missed by the popular audience but will always be remembered by HORROR fanatics everywhere. It's a definite keeper.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Quite mediocre but still watchable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    slayrrr666 (slayrrr666@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/7/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Body Parts" isn't that bad, but not quite that good either. **SPOILERS** Assigned to a new case, Psychologist Bill Chrushank, (Jeff Fahey) takes on prison inmate Ray Kolberg, (Paul Ben-Victor) after he murders a fellow prisoner. Talking it over with wife Karen, (Kim Delaney) in an attempt to prove he's redeemable, only to be involved in a horrendous accident on the way to work that takes one of his arms in the process. Attempting a radical operation, Dr. Agatha Webb, (Lindsay Duncan) is able to graph a new arm into it's space. Successfully undergoing rehab, he goes back to his regular life and career like before. Discovering that the arm belonged to an executed serial killer, he begins to feel that it's taking control of him, which everyone else dismisses as ludicrous. Still convinced that something's wrong with the experiment, including talking to other participants of it, and finally determining a way to stop it from taking control, sets out to stop it from happening. The Good News: This here wasn't all that bad. One of it's better features is that it builds up to the realization. It's a noticeable one fairly early on, but the fact that the film bothers to fudge the issue at all is commendable. The beginning after the surgery is filled with ideas that are really quite disturbing. From the sheer amount of ease that it manages to resort to physical violence without physical provocation and the great way that their sudden jerking leads to really suspenseful encounters. The best one is the car experiment that leads to a pretty creepy scene during traffic hours. Initially, the car-wreck that started everything is quite impressive, being horrific without looking overblown like so many other examples. The film's best moments, though, come from it's final half-hour. It's practically wall-to-wall action, including lots of brutal kills, some big action showdowns and an overall satisfying ending. With a spectacular car chase that has a few twists on it that work in it's favor of upping the excitement and suspense, to a brawl inside a medical facility and several subsequent deaths spread throughout, this one here really justifies itself. The kills are great, including some wicked head-shots, a brutal showing of an arm being ripped out of it's socket and another victim having both legs being cut off, among more including lots of property damage from gunshots that literally destroy everything around them, this ending half-hour is unbridled fury of the grandest order. The other last thing that works is that it certainly feels real in most senses. The payoff takes a while, it's a slow process to figure out the truth and there's really a sense of it being a real-life event played out with a horror twist to it. This one here is more than capable of being entertaining when it wanted to be. The Bad News: There's a few problems with this one that can't be overlooked. The biggest one is that this one takes forever to really get to it's good point. The situation is quite apparent early on to just about everyone and yet it still proceeds to drag itself out forever. The fact that it's filled with endless scenes of them moping about over the problematic symptoms over and over again with the different sources takes up way too much time of the film. These are pretty hard to take for the sheer amount of time that is used to get through them all. That they all pretty much end up the same way basically makes them even harder, especially since it becomes obvious that they'll be the same. Another factor that really hurts the film is it's slow pacing. When it finally gets to the good portions of the film, it's already pretty deep into the film due to all the stretching out with the symptoms taking it up. There's very little action up until the ending, and it's a result of having all the talking beforehand. With a little bit more spread out throughout the film, then it would be a little more bearable. The only other thing that doesn't really work is the relatively small amount of good-looking gore in here. With all the bloody, brutal deaths in here, there isn't a whole lot that actually looks that good. The gunshot wounds are absolutely horrendous, and the stitching on the arm wounds aren't all that good looking and don't really look professional. The rest of the gore isn't all that great, and holds it down with the other flaws. The Final Verdict: With a few pretty intriguing areas of interest and a couple small problems, this one's a little tough to call. Some might be more intrigued by it's positives over it's negatives and will give it a shot, while others might think the negatives will overcome it and will be the film's downfall. Rated R: Graphic Language and Graphic Violence
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
