<filme>
 <id>
  672
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0103919
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1992
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  O Mist&eacute;rio de Candyman
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.5
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  The Candyman, a murderous soul with a hook for a hand, is accidentally summoned to reality by a skeptic grad student researching the monster's myth.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Helen Lyle is a student who decides to write a thesis about local legends and myths. She visits a part of the town, where she learns about the legend of the Candyman, a one-armed man who appears when you say his name five times, in front of a mirror. Of course, Helen doesn't believe all this stuff, but the people of the area are really afraid. When she ignores their warnings and begins her investigation in the places that he is rumored to appear, a series of horrible murders begins. Could the legend be true?
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Horror
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   candyman
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   mirror
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   urban legend
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   hook
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   investigation
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Bernard Rose
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Clive Barker
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Bernard Rose
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Virginia Madsen
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Xander Berkeley
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Tony Todd
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Best Horror Film of 1992
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    robert haynes
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Candyman is undoubtedly the best horror film of 1992. Released with very little fanfare the film became a surprise hit and I remember why. Having been one of those lucky individuals to see the film five, yes five times on its initial theatrical run, I think it's safe to say that I'm a fan. The ability that director Bernard Rose has to create a palpable sense of dread is evident in every frame of this film. This is what true horror is all about. Candyman is extremely suspenseful and intensely creepy, in fact just writing about it I can already feel the hairs on my arms standing up again. It's that affecting! Virginia Madsen is superbly cast as Helen, a flawed but likable heroine the audience cares deeply about. Her journey into madness is one that we empathize with every brutal step of the way. You don't want bad things to happen to her because you've fallen in love with her. How Madsen wasn't nominated for an Oscar for this performance is still beyond me. Tony Todd is also an antihero with a personality and a rich one at that. The film is violent but the gore never becomes comedic. It sets the perfect tone of brutality. Candyman cannot come more highly recommended. It's a truly terrifying psychological art-house horror with standout performances and a deeply haunting score by Philip Glass. Horror films DO NOT get any better than this. Prepared to be scared. A terrific 10!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bees out of hive
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leoperu
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An above-average romantic horror movie with implausible, inconsistent storyline,atmospheric,but unnecessarily gory, adorned with fine photography of city textures (Anthony Richmond was the man behind the camera in three of the four best movies by Nicolas Roeg - but Rose isn't Roeg, so we cannot expect any visionary qualities here), music of Philip Glass, and charms of Virginia Madsen (it seems to me that whoever did admire her in the movie should avoid bonus interviews where an artificial puppet takes the place of our gorgeous go-getter turned victim). The makers let us know that Chicago instead of Liverpool was the right choice ; I wouldn't be so sure of that. And the bees.... well, they are simply out of the hive here.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Easy to Call This One a Classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Candyman (1992) *** (out of 4) Grad student Helen Lyle (Virginia Madsen) is doing research on why certain groups of people blame their violence on mythical legends when she comes across the name Candyman (Tony Todd). Soon Helen realizes that this figure with a hook for a hand is more than just a legend. CANDYMAN certainly stands as one of the best horror films of the 90s as it contains a great story, a creepy atmosphere, some great performances and of course many chilling moments. The story from Clive Barker is certainly something interesting to just think about because the idea of what an urban legend is and how it plays a part in people's lives who believe it is the best thing about the movie. I really loved how director Bernard Rose kept the viewing guessing at all times as to what was going on. Was it really Candyman doing all the killing or had Helen simply lost her mind while doing the research? It certainly helps that you've got such great actors in the leading roles and especially with Madsen. She does an extremely good job in the lead as she really makes you believe all of this stuff that is going on and it's a pretty deep character and the actress has no problems with it. Todd and that iconic voice makes Candyman one of the most memorable screen villains in horror history and that calm and cool nature of the actor really comes across extremely creepy. The film also features a very good score from Philip Glass and of course there's the striking images. I think the film does get a bit too long in the final act but there are just so many effective moments and killings here that you can't help but call this a classic of the genre.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dare You Say His Name, Dare You Watch This Film...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Juliet Raven
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Rarely do I give a film the golden ten rating. As much as I love films of all types, it takes something particularly memorable to get the coveted 10 stars. Candyman is one of those films that manages the impossible. It's clever in that we see an atypical setting, the urban streets, the high towers, the estates. It looks grim and feels it. Then we get into the arc of the story and everything changes to a degree. Yes the places shown remain the same but the story of the Candyman is enough to keep us transfixed, add to that some strong performances and it's a world we've never seen before. Even more powerful for the fact that the essential story itself derives partially from the urban legend of Bloody Mary. Plot: Helen Lyle (Virginia Madsen) is a graduate student who is conducting research for her own thesis on Urban Legends. Neither her nor her friend believing the story of the Candyman decide to jokingly say his name 5 times in Helen's mirror. Nothing happens. Yet soon after things go wrong and Helen realises some urban legends are anything but. Of the strongest abilities that this film possesses in heaps is the acting. From Xander Berkeley to Madsen and finally to Todd, the acting is of the highest quality and no one feels pushed into the shadows throughout this film. Yet it is primarily Madsen and Todd who stand out. Madsen was an actress I never really took much notice of until this film. She stands firm as the sole heroine trying to deal with the trauma and not buckling under the horror of it all. She carries that wonderful line between innocence and sharpness. Never too harsh, never too vanilla. She manages to be a great combination of both and come out fighting against the Candyman. It's hard not to love her in this role and furthermore not to love the scene at the end with the fire. It's heartbreaking for a multitude of reasons and why I adore her in this role. And then there was Tony Todd. The man, as we know, oozes charisma. He's recognisable for that voice alone but people have a tendency to forget he is not just that, he is also an actor of great skill. Able to take the simplest scene, just one line and instantly make it his own. When we first see him in the aforementioned role he does not disappoint. It's an eerie mixture of Gothic meets horror with that dash of elegance as he manages to make a monster who actually is compassionate and who we don't initially hate. He is the Candyman. The special effects. I heard a lot of negative on this and I'm not sure why if I am honest. If you watch this for the effects alone you miss the point of the film as they prove only part of the cog. For that matter though I thought they were done with grace and looked beautiful against the bland background. In a world where grey seems the prominent colour, the blood sticks out with the richness of its colour. To do it in such a setting was a clever little nod and adds to the overall tone of the film. Personally I liked Bernard Rose's score. It's charming and creepy without being ostentatious and those glassy moments really do send chills. Where the score reaches heights is when it begins seeping in just before the Candyman turns up. With the lights down, the darkness wrapping you and nothing but your imagination it leads your mind into a very twisted place. It's how Gothic horror should be. Not too much emphasis is placed on the special FX alone, a staple in most horror films, instead care is given to the characters and where they will go as the film draws on. It doesn't play it safe which I respect instead going for the jugular. And despite the ending being something we have seen before it doesn't suffer in the premise of the film. If anything the final scene adds another jolt to the scares born into this film. My only minor complaint is when Helen finds her other half setting up home with a new girlfriend after she was confined to the hospital. Not upsetting for him, despite Berkeley's obnoxious character, yet rather because you truly feel for the character of Helen. After everything she has endured you'd think there'd be some small hope on the horizon but it doesn't happen. Everything bad happens and yes it culminates in one of the most tragic scenes in Candyman. However that complaint could as much be a plus since you realise the depth of the acting and how she pulls you in, that itself is no small feat. And this is why Candyman is my baby. For every horror movie that ever has been, ever will be, this is my love. It encompasses the morals and fabrics of society into one and takes our preconceptions, throwing them away. Candyman is a wonderful horror film that deserves more recognition and I hope it gets it. I urge everyone to see this and embrace the beauty of Candyman. Lest you say his name and he comes for you...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Scary!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Gene Smith
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm surprised this movie isn't more famous or more looked up to compared to other horror movies there are out there, because I thought this movie was great! Virginia Madsen was great in this movie but the evil Candyman was just a great character, well acted, and a great, scary villain for a horror movie. The soundtrack is creepy and awesome and I remember this being one of the few horror movies that really really scared me back when I watched it. The sequels that I saw (there are at least three Candy Man movies that I have seen) were not nearly as good as this first one but it's a great movie for fans of horror films and you should definitely see it! It's a very original story and idea.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This didn't do anything for me
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    atinder
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A urban legend about Candyman is told to Helen, If you say he name 5 times in front of the mirror, it will be hide you and kill you. Helen who is doing a story about Candyman, Most of the people she talk to believe in the Candyman. When Helen play the game, she soon wish she didn't as Candyman end up framing her each death he cause and no one believes that she telling truth. I am not a fan of Candyman at all, I just do not find him scary all, the no of this scared him or it's did not even gross me out or even creep me out at all. However the story was good and the movie did not bore the hell out him, it was in-rusting for the whole movie and the movie was really good acting from everyone in this movie. 5 out of 10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Maybe the classiest slasher film ever conceived
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Red-Barracuda
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Candyman may very well be the most intelligent film to emerge from the slasher genre. Like A Nightmare On Elm Street before it, it has a supernatural killer from a netherworld who was killed by a mob of people and now comes back to the real world to enact a terrible revenge. However, where Freddie Krueger was a vile paedophile child killer, the Candyman was a black man killed for forming a sexual relationship with a white girl. So, a significant difference is that this is a slasher villain with a genuinely tragic back-story; he is a killer who is at once terrifying and poetic. This is one of the things that makes this film a somewhat unusual one of its type. It has a great sense of place too. The cold-looking Chicago setting is ideal, with the scenes in the projects especially well used. This aspect allows the movie to have an unexpected social-realist angle. The comparison between the squalor of the poor block with the one inhabited by the rich is done in an effective way. The social commentary isn't delivered in a ham-fisted way; it is just part of the story and seems quite natural. But of course this is a slasher film so how does it fare on that level? Well there are a number of gore-drenched scenes and several effective shock moments. The horror part of the film is certainly handled very well and it does have an effective and quite original killer. It has fine production values too. The haunting aerial photography is beautiful, while the score from Philip Glass is very evocative. Acting is universally good. Virginia Madsen as the principal character is great, while Tony Todd as the Candyman provides just the perfect balance of menace and melancholia. Candyman is a slasher film that offers up something different and, dare I say it, has some class. It's a very well executed horror film that also has other things to say as well. It's one of the strongest horror movies from the 1990's.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This 2 decade old Candy is still pretty sweet...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    oneguyrambling
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Time seems to have gone past Candyman but I remember when it was released in Australia in early 90s it was pretty far out stuff. A tall skinny black guy with a gruff voice gutting people with his hook hand was shocking back then  now we have the various tortures of Saw and Hostel. A pretty (being generous) blonde woman as the target of the baddie wasn't too prevalent (yeah-yeah Halloween!)  now it seems once you're a woman rated higher than an "8" you're practically assigned your own psychopathic serial killer The woman in this case is Sharon Stone-lite (ironically not where weight is concerned) Helen (Virginia Madsen), Tony Todd plays the titular Sugary Psycho that menaces her and her study-buddy Bernadette, among many others. Legend has it that the Candyman was the son of a slave who died badly after being tortured bees and other nastiness were involved after he had the temerity to nail the slave-owner's daughter. To summon the undead Candyman is simple, gaze into a mirror and repeat his name 5 times and he will appear instantly to well gut you like a fish if the movie is right, (why you would want this I'm not sure). The specifics of this seem to change a little depending on circumstances: - In one scene two people split the Candyman duties, splitting the 5 repeats between them he appears anyway. This would lead me to believe that every time you say Candyman to a mirror is a little like Russian roulette  as 4 other people could have said it once each elsewhere. - Further to this if you try to be clever and say it 4 times before chickening out depending on the count he could appear at any point in your sequence. - In some scenes Candy appears instantaneously, in others he seems to take a raincheck and pops up later. I guess there are either many people calling on him or the man is just busy doing other things Which could mean this is a chore to old Sweetums, and being summoned is like a doorbell; "AGAIN, I just finished killing two teens in Miami! Won't you guys give me 5 minutes to clean my hook? " Speculation and wonderment aside the mythology has become folklore in the local area where Helen and Bernadette are writing a paper on *DRUM ROLL Please!* Urban legends. This takes them to Cabrini Green, an urban ghetto area where word has it Candyman resides, after some faked contacts Helen writes off the legend as a fake. Not so fast Helen As people near and dear to Helen start dropping like flies in various bloody dismembered puddles, leaving her on the scene the investigators assume she had something to do with things and question her. Each subsequent step seems to implicate even more, and as she protests her innocence still more Candyman contacts and twists ensure she remains a suspect, and the police and her husband start to wonder if she might just be 110% nuts. There is some good simple music in Candyman which lends a bit of class to proceedings, including an effective piano loop that is instantly familiar when you hear it, some gore that may have been extreme in the 90s but hardly raises an eyebrow today, and it is always interesting to watch a "period piece" where almost everyone smokes and telephones still have cords. This year Natalie Portman put in a gonzo performance as the crizzazy Nena in Black Swan and was lauded for it. But really all she did was pretend to see things, scratch non-existent itches, yell a little and let CGI do most of the rest. As Helen Virginia Madsen gets her gear off a few times, fast-tracks a descent into insanity, emerges from several scenes covered in blood and bits of people, loses her hair and at times acts like a grade A looney. I see both Black Swan and Candyman as equally ludicrous yet one is being seen as somewhat visionary while Candyman was written off as just another slasher film. I guarantee in 10 years no-one will be studying Black Swan as a classic of the modern era Candyman is certainly no classic but here I am nigh 20 years later and it is still at least enjoyable. Final Rating  6 / 10. 20 year old Candy is probably not going to be as tasty as when it was new, but it still has a little flavour and is at least satisfying.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Candyman (1992)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SnakesOnAnAfricanPlain
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Candyman is one of those films I really should have seen by now. I remember the trailer on the Cinema Club trailer reel from a wide selection of videos I owned in the mid 90's. Anyway, I finally saw it and it was great horror. I forgot you could make powerful slasher movies and keep the teens well away. The movie is all about myths and how they can spread and take control. These days myths spread world wide and at a greater rate, thanks to the internet. Candyman really allows you to feel emotions for these characters. Madsen isn't going crazy, but we can't blame people for thinking she is. Tony Todd has a very dominating screen presence, not to mention a powerful voice. The kills all seem necessary in this film, as each one has an impact on our protagonist and the world she inhabits. Finally, we have Phillip Glass' incredible score, which adds a bizarre and haunting atmosphere to the movie. Great horror at an early 90's pace.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    First Great Horror Movie of the 90's
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    slasherstudios
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Helen Lyle is a graduate student conducting research for her thesis on urban legends. While interviewing freshmen about their superstitions, she hears about a local legend known as Candyman. The legend contains many thematic elements similar to the most well known urban legends, including endangered babysitters, spirits who appear in mirrors when fatally summoned, and maniac killers with unnatural deformities. The legend states that while Candyman was the son of a slave, he nevertheless became a well known artist. Yet, after falling in love with a white woman who becomes pregnant, Candyman is chased through the plantation and when caught, has his drawing hand cut off and replaced with a hook. He is then smeared with honey (prompting the locals to chant 'Candyman' a total of 5 times- hence the 'say his name 5 times into the mirror'), stolen from a nearby apiary, and the bees sting him to death. The legend also claims that Candyman is summoned by anyone who looks into a mirror and chants his name five times (similar to the Bloody Mary folkloric tale). Summoning him often costs the individual their own life. Later that evening, Helen and her friend Bernadette jokingly call Candyman's name into the mirror in Helen's bathroom but nothing happens. While conducting her research, Helen enters the notorious gang-ridden Cabrini-Green housing project, the site of a recent unsolved murder. There she meets Anne-Marie McCoy, one of the residents, as well as a young boy named Jake, who tells her a disturbing story of a child who was horribly mutilated in a public restroom near the projects, supposedly by Candyman. While exploring the run-down restroom, Helen is attacked by a gang member carrying a hook who has taken the Candyman moniker as his own to enhance his own street credibility by associating himself with the legend. Helen survives the assault and is able to later identify her attacker to the police. Helen later returns to school but hears a voice calling her name as she walks through a parking garage. Another man she encounters states he is the Candyman of the urban legend and because of Helen's disbelief in him, he must now prove to her that he is real. Helen blacks out and wakes up in Anne-Marie's apartment, covered in blood. Anne-Marie, whose Rottweiler has been decapitated and whose baby is also missing, attacks Helen and she is forced to defend herself from Anne-Marie using a meat cleaver. The police then enter the apartment and arrest Helen. Is Helen going crazy or will Candyman come for her next? Three words adequately describe "Candyman": Scary. As. Hell. I was twelve years old when I saw the movie for the first time and it hasn't left my mind since. From the haunting Phillip Glass score to the uncompromising promises by both Tony Todd as Candyman and Virginia Madsen (who has never looked better) as Helen, everything about this movie is sensationally scary. Madsen, in particular, seems to relish playing against time and causes the audience to be sympathetic with her character when a lesser actress would have just come across as annoying. A cheap "Carrie" rip-off of an ending is the only false beat in this superb thriller from one of the masters of the horror genre, Clive Barker.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Best Horror Film of 1992
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    robert haynes
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Candyman is undoubtedly the best horror film of 1992. Released with very little fanfare the film became a surprise hit and I remember why. Having been one of those lucky individuals to see the film five, yes five times on its initial theatrical run, I think it's safe to say that I'm a fan. The ability that director Bernard Rose has to create a palpable sense of dread is evident in every frame of this film. This is what true horror is all about. Candyman is extremely suspenseful and intensely creepy, in fact just writing about it I can already feel the hairs on my arms standing up again. It's that affecting! Virginia Madsen is superbly cast as Helen, a flawed but likable heroine the audience cares deeply about. Her journey into madness is one that we empathize with every brutal step of the way. You don't want bad things to happen to her because you've fallen in love with her. How Madsen wasn't nominated for an Oscar for this performance is still beyond me. Tony Todd is also an antihero with a personality and a rich one at that. The film is violent but the gore never becomes comedic. It sets the perfect tone of brutality. Candyman cannot come more highly recommended. It's a truly terrifying psychological art-house horror with standout performances and a deeply haunting score by Philip Glass. Horror films DO NOT get any better than this. Prepared to be scared. A terrific 10!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bees out of hive
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leoperu
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An above-average romantic horror movie with implausible, inconsistent storyline,atmospheric,but unnecessarily gory, adorned with fine photography of city textures (Anthony Richmond was the man behind the camera in three of the four best movies by Nicolas Roeg - but Rose isn't Roeg, so we cannot expect any visionary qualities here), music of Philip Glass, and charms of Virginia Madsen (it seems to me that whoever did admire her in the movie should avoid bonus interviews where an artificial puppet takes the place of our gorgeous go-getter turned victim). The makers let us know that Chicago instead of Liverpool was the right choice ; I wouldn't be so sure of that. And the bees.... well, they are simply out of the hive here.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Easy to Call This One a Classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Candyman (1992) *** (out of 4) Grad student Helen Lyle (Virginia Madsen) is doing research on why certain groups of people blame their violence on mythical legends when she comes across the name Candyman (Tony Todd). Soon Helen realizes that this figure with a hook for a hand is more than just a legend. CANDYMAN certainly stands as one of the best horror films of the 90s as it contains a great story, a creepy atmosphere, some great performances and of course many chilling moments. The story from Clive Barker is certainly something interesting to just think about because the idea of what an urban legend is and how it plays a part in people's lives who believe it is the best thing about the movie. I really loved how director Bernard Rose kept the viewing guessing at all times as to what was going on. Was it really Candyman doing all the killing or had Helen simply lost her mind while doing the research? It certainly helps that you've got such great actors in the leading roles and especially with Madsen. She does an extremely good job in the lead as she really makes you believe all of this stuff that is going on and it's a pretty deep character and the actress has no problems with it. Todd and that iconic voice makes Candyman one of the most memorable screen villains in horror history and that calm and cool nature of the actor really comes across extremely creepy. The film also features a very good score from Philip Glass and of course there's the striking images. I think the film does get a bit too long in the final act but there are just so many effective moments and killings here that you can't help but call this a classic of the genre.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dare You Say His Name, Dare You Watch This Film...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Juliet Raven
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Rarely do I give a film the golden ten rating. As much as I love films of all types, it takes something particularly memorable to get the coveted 10 stars. Candyman is one of those films that manages the impossible. It's clever in that we see an atypical setting, the urban streets, the high towers, the estates. It looks grim and feels it. Then we get into the arc of the story and everything changes to a degree. Yes the places shown remain the same but the story of the Candyman is enough to keep us transfixed, add to that some strong performances and it's a world we've never seen before. Even more powerful for the fact that the essential story itself derives partially from the urban legend of Bloody Mary. Plot: Helen Lyle (Virginia Madsen) is a graduate student who is conducting research for her own thesis on Urban Legends. Neither her nor her friend believing the story of the Candyman decide to jokingly say his name 5 times in Helen's mirror. Nothing happens. Yet soon after things go wrong and Helen realises some urban legends are anything but. Of the strongest abilities that this film possesses in heaps is the acting. From Xander Berkeley to Madsen and finally to Todd, the acting is of the highest quality and no one feels pushed into the shadows throughout this film. Yet it is primarily Madsen and Todd who stand out. Madsen was an actress I never really took much notice of until this film. She stands firm as the sole heroine trying to deal with the trauma and not buckling under the horror of it all. She carries that wonderful line between innocence and sharpness. Never too harsh, never too vanilla. She manages to be a great combination of both and come out fighting against the Candyman. It's hard not to love her in this role and furthermore not to love the scene at the end with the fire. It's heartbreaking for a multitude of reasons and why I adore her in this role. And then there was Tony Todd. The man, as we know, oozes charisma. He's recognisable for that voice alone but people have a tendency to forget he is not just that, he is also an actor of great skill. Able to take the simplest scene, just one line and instantly make it his own. When we first see him in the aforementioned role he does not disappoint. It's an eerie mixture of Gothic meets horror with that dash of elegance as he manages to make a monster who actually is compassionate and who we don't initially hate. He is the Candyman. The special effects. I heard a lot of negative on this and I'm not sure why if I am honest. If you watch this for the effects alone you miss the point of the film as they prove only part of the cog. For that matter though I thought they were done with grace and looked beautiful against the bland background. In a world where grey seems the prominent colour, the blood sticks out with the richness of its colour. To do it in such a setting was a clever little nod and adds to the overall tone of the film. Personally I liked Bernard Rose's score. It's charming and creepy without being ostentatious and those glassy moments really do send chills. Where the score reaches heights is when it begins seeping in just before the Candyman turns up. With the lights down, the darkness wrapping you and nothing but your imagination it leads your mind into a very twisted place. It's how Gothic horror should be. Not too much emphasis is placed on the special FX alone, a staple in most horror films, instead care is given to the characters and where they will go as the film draws on. It doesn't play it safe which I respect instead going for the jugular. And despite the ending being something we have seen before it doesn't suffer in the premise of the film. If anything the final scene adds another jolt to the scares born into this film. My only minor complaint is when Helen finds her other half setting up home with a new girlfriend after she was confined to the hospital. Not upsetting for him, despite Berkeley's obnoxious character, yet rather because you truly feel for the character of Helen. After everything she has endured you'd think there'd be some small hope on the horizon but it doesn't happen. Everything bad happens and yes it culminates in one of the most tragic scenes in Candyman. However that complaint could as much be a plus since you realise the depth of the acting and how she pulls you in, that itself is no small feat. And this is why Candyman is my baby. For every horror movie that ever has been, ever will be, this is my love. It encompasses the morals and fabrics of society into one and takes our preconceptions, throwing them away. Candyman is a wonderful horror film that deserves more recognition and I hope it gets it. I urge everyone to see this and embrace the beauty of Candyman. Lest you say his name and he comes for you...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Scary!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Gene Smith
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm surprised this movie isn't more famous or more looked up to compared to other horror movies there are out there, because I thought this movie was great! Virginia Madsen was great in this movie but the evil Candyman was just a great character, well acted, and a great, scary villain for a horror movie. The soundtrack is creepy and awesome and I remember this being one of the few horror movies that really really scared me back when I watched it. The sequels that I saw (there are at least three Candy Man movies that I have seen) were not nearly as good as this first one but it's a great movie for fans of horror films and you should definitely see it! It's a very original story and idea.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This didn't do anything for me
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    atinder
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A urban legend about Candyman is told to Helen, If you say he name 5 times in front of the mirror, it will be hide you and kill you. Helen who is doing a story about Candyman, Most of the people she talk to believe in the Candyman. When Helen play the game, she soon wish she didn't as Candyman end up framing her each death he cause and no one believes that she telling truth. I am not a fan of Candyman at all, I just do not find him scary all, the no of this scared him or it's did not even gross me out or even creep me out at all. However the story was good and the movie did not bore the hell out him, it was in-rusting for the whole movie and the movie was really good acting from everyone in this movie. 5 out of 10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Maybe the classiest slasher film ever conceived
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Red-Barracuda
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Candyman may very well be the most intelligent film to emerge from the slasher genre. Like A Nightmare On Elm Street before it, it has a supernatural killer from a netherworld who was killed by a mob of people and now comes back to the real world to enact a terrible revenge. However, where Freddie Krueger was a vile paedophile child killer, the Candyman was a black man killed for forming a sexual relationship with a white girl. So, a significant difference is that this is a slasher villain with a genuinely tragic back-story; he is a killer who is at once terrifying and poetic. This is one of the things that makes this film a somewhat unusual one of its type. It has a great sense of place too. The cold-looking Chicago setting is ideal, with the scenes in the projects especially well used. This aspect allows the movie to have an unexpected social-realist angle. The comparison between the squalor of the poor block with the one inhabited by the rich is done in an effective way. The social commentary isn't delivered in a ham-fisted way; it is just part of the story and seems quite natural. But of course this is a slasher film so how does it fare on that level? Well there are a number of gore-drenched scenes and several effective shock moments. The horror part of the film is certainly handled very well and it does have an effective and quite original killer. It has fine production values too. The haunting aerial photography is beautiful, while the score from Philip Glass is very evocative. Acting is universally good. Virginia Madsen as the principal character is great, while Tony Todd as the Candyman provides just the perfect balance of menace and melancholia. Candyman is a slasher film that offers up something different and, dare I say it, has some class. It's a very well executed horror film that also has other things to say as well. It's one of the strongest horror movies from the 1990's.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This 2 decade old Candy is still pretty sweet...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    oneguyrambling
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Time seems to have gone past Candyman but I remember when it was released in Australia in early 90s it was pretty far out stuff. A tall skinny black guy with a gruff voice gutting people with his hook hand was shocking back then  now we have the various tortures of Saw and Hostel. A pretty (being generous) blonde woman as the target of the baddie wasn't too prevalent (yeah-yeah Halloween!)  now it seems once you're a woman rated higher than an "8" you're practically assigned your own psychopathic serial killer The woman in this case is Sharon Stone-lite (ironically not where weight is concerned) Helen (Virginia Madsen), Tony Todd plays the titular Sugary Psycho that menaces her and her study-buddy Bernadette, among many others. Legend has it that the Candyman was the son of a slave who died badly after being tortured bees and other nastiness were involved after he had the temerity to nail the slave-owner's daughter. To summon the undead Candyman is simple, gaze into a mirror and repeat his name 5 times and he will appear instantly to well gut you like a fish if the movie is right, (why you would want this I'm not sure). The specifics of this seem to change a little depending on circumstances: - In one scene two people split the Candyman duties, splitting the 5 repeats between them he appears anyway. This would lead me to believe that every time you say Candyman to a mirror is a little like Russian roulette  as 4 other people could have said it once each elsewhere. - Further to this if you try to be clever and say it 4 times before chickening out depending on the count he could appear at any point in your sequence. - In some scenes Candy appears instantaneously, in others he seems to take a raincheck and pops up later. I guess there are either many people calling on him or the man is just busy doing other things Which could mean this is a chore to old Sweetums, and being summoned is like a doorbell; "AGAIN, I just finished killing two teens in Miami! Won't you guys give me 5 minutes to clean my hook? " Speculation and wonderment aside the mythology has become folklore in the local area where Helen and Bernadette are writing a paper on *DRUM ROLL Please!* Urban legends. This takes them to Cabrini Green, an urban ghetto area where word has it Candyman resides, after some faked contacts Helen writes off the legend as a fake. Not so fast Helen As people near and dear to Helen start dropping like flies in various bloody dismembered puddles, leaving her on the scene the investigators assume she had something to do with things and question her. Each subsequent step seems to implicate even more, and as she protests her innocence still more Candyman contacts and twists ensure she remains a suspect, and the police and her husband start to wonder if she might just be 110% nuts. There is some good simple music in Candyman which lends a bit of class to proceedings, including an effective piano loop that is instantly familiar when you hear it, some gore that may have been extreme in the 90s but hardly raises an eyebrow today, and it is always interesting to watch a "period piece" where almost everyone smokes and telephones still have cords. This year Natalie Portman put in a gonzo performance as the crizzazy Nena in Black Swan and was lauded for it. But really all she did was pretend to see things, scratch non-existent itches, yell a little and let CGI do most of the rest. As Helen Virginia Madsen gets her gear off a few times, fast-tracks a descent into insanity, emerges from several scenes covered in blood and bits of people, loses her hair and at times acts like a grade A looney. I see both Black Swan and Candyman as equally ludicrous yet one is being seen as somewhat visionary while Candyman was written off as just another slasher film. I guarantee in 10 years no-one will be studying Black Swan as a classic of the modern era Candyman is certainly no classic but here I am nigh 20 years later and it is still at least enjoyable. Final Rating  6 / 10. 20 year old Candy is probably not going to be as tasty as when it was new, but it still has a little flavour and is at least satisfying.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Candyman (1992)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SnakesOnAnAfricanPlain
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Candyman is one of those films I really should have seen by now. I remember the trailer on the Cinema Club trailer reel from a wide selection of videos I owned in the mid 90's. Anyway, I finally saw it and it was great horror. I forgot you could make powerful slasher movies and keep the teens well away. The movie is all about myths and how they can spread and take control. These days myths spread world wide and at a greater rate, thanks to the internet. Candyman really allows you to feel emotions for these characters. Madsen isn't going crazy, but we can't blame people for thinking she is. Tony Todd has a very dominating screen presence, not to mention a powerful voice. The kills all seem necessary in this film, as each one has an impact on our protagonist and the world she inhabits. Finally, we have Phillip Glass' incredible score, which adds a bizarre and haunting atmosphere to the movie. Great horror at an early 90's pace.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    First Great Horror Movie of the 90's
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    slasherstudios
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Helen Lyle is a graduate student conducting research for her thesis on urban legends. While interviewing freshmen about their superstitions, she hears about a local legend known as Candyman. The legend contains many thematic elements similar to the most well known urban legends, including endangered babysitters, spirits who appear in mirrors when fatally summoned, and maniac killers with unnatural deformities. The legend states that while Candyman was the son of a slave, he nevertheless became a well known artist. Yet, after falling in love with a white woman who becomes pregnant, Candyman is chased through the plantation and when caught, has his drawing hand cut off and replaced with a hook. He is then smeared with honey (prompting the locals to chant 'Candyman' a total of 5 times- hence the 'say his name 5 times into the mirror'), stolen from a nearby apiary, and the bees sting him to death. The legend also claims that Candyman is summoned by anyone who looks into a mirror and chants his name five times (similar to the Bloody Mary folkloric tale). Summoning him often costs the individual their own life. Later that evening, Helen and her friend Bernadette jokingly call Candyman's name into the mirror in Helen's bathroom but nothing happens. While conducting her research, Helen enters the notorious gang-ridden Cabrini-Green housing project, the site of a recent unsolved murder. There she meets Anne-Marie McCoy, one of the residents, as well as a young boy named Jake, who tells her a disturbing story of a child who was horribly mutilated in a public restroom near the projects, supposedly by Candyman. While exploring the run-down restroom, Helen is attacked by a gang member carrying a hook who has taken the Candyman moniker as his own to enhance his own street credibility by associating himself with the legend. Helen survives the assault and is able to later identify her attacker to the police. Helen later returns to school but hears a voice calling her name as she walks through a parking garage. Another man she encounters states he is the Candyman of the urban legend and because of Helen's disbelief in him, he must now prove to her that he is real. Helen blacks out and wakes up in Anne-Marie's apartment, covered in blood. Anne-Marie, whose Rottweiler has been decapitated and whose baby is also missing, attacks Helen and she is forced to defend herself from Anne-Marie using a meat cleaver. The police then enter the apartment and arrest Helen. Is Helen going crazy or will Candyman come for her next? Three words adequately describe "Candyman": Scary. As. Hell. I was twelve years old when I saw the movie for the first time and it hasn't left my mind since. From the haunting Phillip Glass score to the uncompromising promises by both Tony Todd as Candyman and Virginia Madsen (who has never looked better) as Helen, everything about this movie is sensationally scary. Madsen, in particular, seems to relish playing against time and causes the audience to be sympathetic with her character when a lesser actress would have just come across as annoying. A cheap "Carrie" rip-off of an ending is the only false beat in this superb thriller from one of the masters of the horror genre, Clive Barker.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Best Horror Film of 1992
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    robert haynes
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Candyman is undoubtedly the best horror film of 1992. Released with very little fanfare the film became a surprise hit and I remember why. Having been one of those lucky individuals to see the film five, yes five times on its initial theatrical run, I think it's safe to say that I'm a fan. The ability that director Bernard Rose has to create a palpable sense of dread is evident in every frame of this film. This is what true horror is all about. Candyman is extremely suspenseful and intensely creepy, in fact just writing about it I can already feel the hairs on my arms standing up again. It's that affecting! Virginia Madsen is superbly cast as Helen, a flawed but likable heroine the audience cares deeply about. Her journey into madness is one that we empathize with every brutal step of the way. You don't want bad things to happen to her because you've fallen in love with her. How Madsen wasn't nominated for an Oscar for this performance is still beyond me. Tony Todd is also an antihero with a personality and a rich one at that. The film is violent but the gore never becomes comedic. It sets the perfect tone of brutality. Candyman cannot come more highly recommended. It's a truly terrifying psychological art-house horror with standout performances and a deeply haunting score by Philip Glass. Horror films DO NOT get any better than this. Prepared to be scared. A terrific 10!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bees out of hive
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leoperu
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An above-average romantic horror movie with implausible, inconsistent storyline,atmospheric,but unnecessarily gory, adorned with fine photography of city textures (Anthony Richmond was the man behind the camera in three of the four best movies by Nicolas Roeg - but Rose isn't Roeg, so we cannot expect any visionary qualities here), music of Philip Glass, and charms of Virginia Madsen (it seems to me that whoever did admire her in the movie should avoid bonus interviews where an artificial puppet takes the place of our gorgeous go-getter turned victim). The makers let us know that Chicago instead of Liverpool was the right choice ; I wouldn't be so sure of that. And the bees.... well, they are simply out of the hive here.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Easy to Call This One a Classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Candyman (1992) *** (out of 4) Grad student Helen Lyle (Virginia Madsen) is doing research on why certain groups of people blame their violence on mythical legends when she comes across the name Candyman (Tony Todd). Soon Helen realizes that this figure with a hook for a hand is more than just a legend. CANDYMAN certainly stands as one of the best horror films of the 90s as it contains a great story, a creepy atmosphere, some great performances and of course many chilling moments. The story from Clive Barker is certainly something interesting to just think about because the idea of what an urban legend is and how it plays a part in people's lives who believe it is the best thing about the movie. I really loved how director Bernard Rose kept the viewing guessing at all times as to what was going on. Was it really Candyman doing all the killing or had Helen simply lost her mind while doing the research? It certainly helps that you've got such great actors in the leading roles and especially with Madsen. She does an extremely good job in the lead as she really makes you believe all of this stuff that is going on and it's a pretty deep character and the actress has no problems with it. Todd and that iconic voice makes Candyman one of the most memorable screen villains in horror history and that calm and cool nature of the actor really comes across extremely creepy. The film also features a very good score from Philip Glass and of course there's the striking images. I think the film does get a bit too long in the final act but there are just so many effective moments and killings here that you can't help but call this a classic of the genre.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dare You Say His Name, Dare You Watch This Film...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Juliet Raven
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Rarely do I give a film the golden ten rating. As much as I love films of all types, it takes something particularly memorable to get the coveted 10 stars. Candyman is one of those films that manages the impossible. It's clever in that we see an atypical setting, the urban streets, the high towers, the estates. It looks grim and feels it. Then we get into the arc of the story and everything changes to a degree. Yes the places shown remain the same but the story of the Candyman is enough to keep us transfixed, add to that some strong performances and it's a world we've never seen before. Even more powerful for the fact that the essential story itself derives partially from the urban legend of Bloody Mary. Plot: Helen Lyle (Virginia Madsen) is a graduate student who is conducting research for her own thesis on Urban Legends. Neither her nor her friend believing the story of the Candyman decide to jokingly say his name 5 times in Helen's mirror. Nothing happens. Yet soon after things go wrong and Helen realises some urban legends are anything but. Of the strongest abilities that this film possesses in heaps is the acting. From Xander Berkeley to Madsen and finally to Todd, the acting is of the highest quality and no one feels pushed into the shadows throughout this film. Yet it is primarily Madsen and Todd who stand out. Madsen was an actress I never really took much notice of until this film. She stands firm as the sole heroine trying to deal with the trauma and not buckling under the horror of it all. She carries that wonderful line between innocence and sharpness. Never too harsh, never too vanilla. She manages to be a great combination of both and come out fighting against the Candyman. It's hard not to love her in this role and furthermore not to love the scene at the end with the fire. It's heartbreaking for a multitude of reasons and why I adore her in this role. And then there was Tony Todd. The man, as we know, oozes charisma. He's recognisable for that voice alone but people have a tendency to forget he is not just that, he is also an actor of great skill. Able to take the simplest scene, just one line and instantly make it his own. When we first see him in the aforementioned role he does not disappoint. It's an eerie mixture of Gothic meets horror with that dash of elegance as he manages to make a monster who actually is compassionate and who we don't initially hate. He is the Candyman. The special effects. I heard a lot of negative on this and I'm not sure why if I am honest. If you watch this for the effects alone you miss the point of the film as they prove only part of the cog. For that matter though I thought they were done with grace and looked beautiful against the bland background. In a world where grey seems the prominent colour, the blood sticks out with the richness of its colour. To do it in such a setting was a clever little nod and adds to the overall tone of the film. Personally I liked Bernard Rose's score. It's charming and creepy without being ostentatious and those glassy moments really do send chills. Where the score reaches heights is when it begins seeping in just before the Candyman turns up. With the lights down, the darkness wrapping you and nothing but your imagination it leads your mind into a very twisted place. It's how Gothic horror should be. Not too much emphasis is placed on the special FX alone, a staple in most horror films, instead care is given to the characters and where they will go as the film draws on. It doesn't play it safe which I respect instead going for the jugular. And despite the ending being something we have seen before it doesn't suffer in the premise of the film. If anything the final scene adds another jolt to the scares born into this film. My only minor complaint is when Helen finds her other half setting up home with a new girlfriend after she was confined to the hospital. Not upsetting for him, despite Berkeley's obnoxious character, yet rather because you truly feel for the character of Helen. After everything she has endured you'd think there'd be some small hope on the horizon but it doesn't happen. Everything bad happens and yes it culminates in one of the most tragic scenes in Candyman. However that complaint could as much be a plus since you realise the depth of the acting and how she pulls you in, that itself is no small feat. And this is why Candyman is my baby. For every horror movie that ever has been, ever will be, this is my love. It encompasses the morals and fabrics of society into one and takes our preconceptions, throwing them away. Candyman is a wonderful horror film that deserves more recognition and I hope it gets it. I urge everyone to see this and embrace the beauty of Candyman. Lest you say his name and he comes for you...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Scary!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Gene Smith
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm surprised this movie isn't more famous or more looked up to compared to other horror movies there are out there, because I thought this movie was great! Virginia Madsen was great in this movie but the evil Candyman was just a great character, well acted, and a great, scary villain for a horror movie. The soundtrack is creepy and awesome and I remember this being one of the few horror movies that really really scared me back when I watched it. The sequels that I saw (there are at least three Candy Man movies that I have seen) were not nearly as good as this first one but it's a great movie for fans of horror films and you should definitely see it! It's a very original story and idea.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This didn't do anything for me
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    atinder
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A urban legend about Candyman is told to Helen, If you say he name 5 times in front of the mirror, it will be hide you and kill you. Helen who is doing a story about Candyman, Most of the people she talk to believe in the Candyman. When Helen play the game, she soon wish she didn't as Candyman end up framing her each death he cause and no one believes that she telling truth. I am not a fan of Candyman at all, I just do not find him scary all, the no of this scared him or it's did not even gross me out or even creep me out at all. However the story was good and the movie did not bore the hell out him, it was in-rusting for the whole movie and the movie was really good acting from everyone in this movie. 5 out of 10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Maybe the classiest slasher film ever conceived
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Red-Barracuda
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Candyman may very well be the most intelligent film to emerge from the slasher genre. Like A Nightmare On Elm Street before it, it has a supernatural killer from a netherworld who was killed by a mob of people and now comes back to the real world to enact a terrible revenge. However, where Freddie Krueger was a vile paedophile child killer, the Candyman was a black man killed for forming a sexual relationship with a white girl. So, a significant difference is that this is a slasher villain with a genuinely tragic back-story; he is a killer who is at once terrifying and poetic. This is one of the things that makes this film a somewhat unusual one of its type. It has a great sense of place too. The cold-looking Chicago setting is ideal, with the scenes in the projects especially well used. This aspect allows the movie to have an unexpected social-realist angle. The comparison between the squalor of the poor block with the one inhabited by the rich is done in an effective way. The social commentary isn't delivered in a ham-fisted way; it is just part of the story and seems quite natural. But of course this is a slasher film so how does it fare on that level? Well there are a number of gore-drenched scenes and several effective shock moments. The horror part of the film is certainly handled very well and it does have an effective and quite original killer. It has fine production values too. The haunting aerial photography is beautiful, while the score from Philip Glass is very evocative. Acting is universally good. Virginia Madsen as the principal character is great, while Tony Todd as the Candyman provides just the perfect balance of menace and melancholia. Candyman is a slasher film that offers up something different and, dare I say it, has some class. It's a very well executed horror film that also has other things to say as well. It's one of the strongest horror movies from the 1990's.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This 2 decade old Candy is still pretty sweet...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    oneguyrambling
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Time seems to have gone past Candyman but I remember when it was released in Australia in early 90s it was pretty far out stuff. A tall skinny black guy with a gruff voice gutting people with his hook hand was shocking back then  now we have the various tortures of Saw and Hostel. A pretty (being generous) blonde woman as the target of the baddie wasn't too prevalent (yeah-yeah Halloween!)  now it seems once you're a woman rated higher than an "8" you're practically assigned your own psychopathic serial killer The woman in this case is Sharon Stone-lite (ironically not where weight is concerned) Helen (Virginia Madsen), Tony Todd plays the titular Sugary Psycho that menaces her and her study-buddy Bernadette, among many others. Legend has it that the Candyman was the son of a slave who died badly after being tortured bees and other nastiness were involved after he had the temerity to nail the slave-owner's daughter. To summon the undead Candyman is simple, gaze into a mirror and repeat his name 5 times and he will appear instantly to well gut you like a fish if the movie is right, (why you would want this I'm not sure). The specifics of this seem to change a little depending on circumstances: - In one scene two people split the Candyman duties, splitting the 5 repeats between them he appears anyway. This would lead me to believe that every time you say Candyman to a mirror is a little like Russian roulette  as 4 other people could have said it once each elsewhere. - Further to this if you try to be clever and say it 4 times before chickening out depending on the count he could appear at any point in your sequence. - In some scenes Candy appears instantaneously, in others he seems to take a raincheck and pops up later. I guess there are either many people calling on him or the man is just busy doing other things Which could mean this is a chore to old Sweetums, and being summoned is like a doorbell; "AGAIN, I just finished killing two teens in Miami! Won't you guys give me 5 minutes to clean my hook? " Speculation and wonderment aside the mythology has become folklore in the local area where Helen and Bernadette are writing a paper on *DRUM ROLL Please!* Urban legends. This takes them to Cabrini Green, an urban ghetto area where word has it Candyman resides, after some faked contacts Helen writes off the legend as a fake. Not so fast Helen As people near and dear to Helen start dropping like flies in various bloody dismembered puddles, leaving her on the scene the investigators assume she had something to do with things and question her. Each subsequent step seems to implicate even more, and as she protests her innocence still more Candyman contacts and twists ensure she remains a suspect, and the police and her husband start to wonder if she might just be 110% nuts. There is some good simple music in Candyman which lends a bit of class to proceedings, including an effective piano loop that is instantly familiar when you hear it, some gore that may have been extreme in the 90s but hardly raises an eyebrow today, and it is always interesting to watch a "period piece" where almost everyone smokes and telephones still have cords. This year Natalie Portman put in a gonzo performance as the crizzazy Nena in Black Swan and was lauded for it. But really all she did was pretend to see things, scratch non-existent itches, yell a little and let CGI do most of the rest. As Helen Virginia Madsen gets her gear off a few times, fast-tracks a descent into insanity, emerges from several scenes covered in blood and bits of people, loses her hair and at times acts like a grade A looney. I see both Black Swan and Candyman as equally ludicrous yet one is being seen as somewhat visionary while Candyman was written off as just another slasher film. I guarantee in 10 years no-one will be studying Black Swan as a classic of the modern era Candyman is certainly no classic but here I am nigh 20 years later and it is still at least enjoyable. Final Rating  6 / 10. 20 year old Candy is probably not going to be as tasty as when it was new, but it still has a little flavour and is at least satisfying.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Candyman (1992)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SnakesOnAnAfricanPlain
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Candyman is one of those films I really should have seen by now. I remember the trailer on the Cinema Club trailer reel from a wide selection of videos I owned in the mid 90's. Anyway, I finally saw it and it was great horror. I forgot you could make powerful slasher movies and keep the teens well away. The movie is all about myths and how they can spread and take control. These days myths spread world wide and at a greater rate, thanks to the internet. Candyman really allows you to feel emotions for these characters. Madsen isn't going crazy, but we can't blame people for thinking she is. Tony Todd has a very dominating screen presence, not to mention a powerful voice. The kills all seem necessary in this film, as each one has an impact on our protagonist and the world she inhabits. Finally, we have Phillip Glass' incredible score, which adds a bizarre and haunting atmosphere to the movie. Great horror at an early 90's pace.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    First Great Horror Movie of the 90's
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    slasherstudios
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Helen Lyle is a graduate student conducting research for her thesis on urban legends. While interviewing freshmen about their superstitions, she hears about a local legend known as Candyman. The legend contains many thematic elements similar to the most well known urban legends, including endangered babysitters, spirits who appear in mirrors when fatally summoned, and maniac killers with unnatural deformities. The legend states that while Candyman was the son of a slave, he nevertheless became a well known artist. Yet, after falling in love with a white woman who becomes pregnant, Candyman is chased through the plantation and when caught, has his drawing hand cut off and replaced with a hook. He is then smeared with honey (prompting the locals to chant 'Candyman' a total of 5 times- hence the 'say his name 5 times into the mirror'), stolen from a nearby apiary, and the bees sting him to death. The legend also claims that Candyman is summoned by anyone who looks into a mirror and chants his name five times (similar to the Bloody Mary folkloric tale). Summoning him often costs the individual their own life. Later that evening, Helen and her friend Bernadette jokingly call Candyman's name into the mirror in Helen's bathroom but nothing happens. While conducting her research, Helen enters the notorious gang-ridden Cabrini-Green housing project, the site of a recent unsolved murder. There she meets Anne-Marie McCoy, one of the residents, as well as a young boy named Jake, who tells her a disturbing story of a child who was horribly mutilated in a public restroom near the projects, supposedly by Candyman. While exploring the run-down restroom, Helen is attacked by a gang member carrying a hook who has taken the Candyman moniker as his own to enhance his own street credibility by associating himself with the legend. Helen survives the assault and is able to later identify her attacker to the police. Helen later returns to school but hears a voice calling her name as she walks through a parking garage. Another man she encounters states he is the Candyman of the urban legend and because of Helen's disbelief in him, he must now prove to her that he is real. Helen blacks out and wakes up in Anne-Marie's apartment, covered in blood. Anne-Marie, whose Rottweiler has been decapitated and whose baby is also missing, attacks Helen and she is forced to defend herself from Anne-Marie using a meat cleaver. The police then enter the apartment and arrest Helen. Is Helen going crazy or will Candyman come for her next? Three words adequately describe "Candyman": Scary. As. Hell. I was twelve years old when I saw the movie for the first time and it hasn't left my mind since. From the haunting Phillip Glass score to the uncompromising promises by both Tony Todd as Candyman and Virginia Madsen (who has never looked better) as Helen, everything about this movie is sensationally scary. Madsen, in particular, seems to relish playing against time and causes the audience to be sympathetic with her character when a lesser actress would have just come across as annoying. A cheap "Carrie" rip-off of an ending is the only false beat in this superb thriller from one of the masters of the horror genre, Clive Barker.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Best Horror Film of 1992
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    robert haynes
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Candyman is undoubtedly the best horror film of 1992. Released with very little fanfare the film became a surprise hit and I remember why. Having been one of those lucky individuals to see the film five, yes five times on its initial theatrical run, I think it's safe to say that I'm a fan. The ability that director Bernard Rose has to create a palpable sense of dread is evident in every frame of this film. This is what true horror is all about. Candyman is extremely suspenseful and intensely creepy, in fact just writing about it I can already feel the hairs on my arms standing up again. It's that affecting! Virginia Madsen is superbly cast as Helen, a flawed but likable heroine the audience cares deeply about. Her journey into madness is one that we empathize with every brutal step of the way. You don't want bad things to happen to her because you've fallen in love with her. How Madsen wasn't nominated for an Oscar for this performance is still beyond me. Tony Todd is also an antihero with a personality and a rich one at that. The film is violent but the gore never becomes comedic. It sets the perfect tone of brutality. Candyman cannot come more highly recommended. It's a truly terrifying psychological art-house horror with standout performances and a deeply haunting score by Philip Glass. Horror films DO NOT get any better than this. Prepared to be scared. A terrific 10!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bees out of hive
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leoperu
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An above-average romantic horror movie with implausible, inconsistent storyline,atmospheric,but unnecessarily gory, adorned with fine photography of city textures (Anthony Richmond was the man behind the camera in three of the four best movies by Nicolas Roeg - but Rose isn't Roeg, so we cannot expect any visionary qualities here), music of Philip Glass, and charms of Virginia Madsen (it seems to me that whoever did admire her in the movie should avoid bonus interviews where an artificial puppet takes the place of our gorgeous go-getter turned victim). The makers let us know that Chicago instead of Liverpool was the right choice ; I wouldn't be so sure of that. And the bees.... well, they are simply out of the hive here.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Easy to Call This One a Classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Candyman (1992) *** (out of 4) Grad student Helen Lyle (Virginia Madsen) is doing research on why certain groups of people blame their violence on mythical legends when she comes across the name Candyman (Tony Todd). Soon Helen realizes that this figure with a hook for a hand is more than just a legend. CANDYMAN certainly stands as one of the best horror films of the 90s as it contains a great story, a creepy atmosphere, some great performances and of course many chilling moments. The story from Clive Barker is certainly something interesting to just think about because the idea of what an urban legend is and how it plays a part in people's lives who believe it is the best thing about the movie. I really loved how director Bernard Rose kept the viewing guessing at all times as to what was going on. Was it really Candyman doing all the killing or had Helen simply lost her mind while doing the research? It certainly helps that you've got such great actors in the leading roles and especially with Madsen. She does an extremely good job in the lead as she really makes you believe all of this stuff that is going on and it's a pretty deep character and the actress has no problems with it. Todd and that iconic voice makes Candyman one of the most memorable screen villains in horror history and that calm and cool nature of the actor really comes across extremely creepy. The film also features a very good score from Philip Glass and of course there's the striking images. I think the film does get a bit too long in the final act but there are just so many effective moments and killings here that you can't help but call this a classic of the genre.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dare You Say His Name, Dare You Watch This Film...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Juliet Raven
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Rarely do I give a film the golden ten rating. As much as I love films of all types, it takes something particularly memorable to get the coveted 10 stars. Candyman is one of those films that manages the impossible. It's clever in that we see an atypical setting, the urban streets, the high towers, the estates. It looks grim and feels it. Then we get into the arc of the story and everything changes to a degree. Yes the places shown remain the same but the story of the Candyman is enough to keep us transfixed, add to that some strong performances and it's a world we've never seen before. Even more powerful for the fact that the essential story itself derives partially from the urban legend of Bloody Mary. Plot: Helen Lyle (Virginia Madsen) is a graduate student who is conducting research for her own thesis on Urban Legends. Neither her nor her friend believing the story of the Candyman decide to jokingly say his name 5 times in Helen's mirror. Nothing happens. Yet soon after things go wrong and Helen realises some urban legends are anything but. Of the strongest abilities that this film possesses in heaps is the acting. From Xander Berkeley to Madsen and finally to Todd, the acting is of the highest quality and no one feels pushed into the shadows throughout this film. Yet it is primarily Madsen and Todd who stand out. Madsen was an actress I never really took much notice of until this film. She stands firm as the sole heroine trying to deal with the trauma and not buckling under the horror of it all. She carries that wonderful line between innocence and sharpness. Never too harsh, never too vanilla. She manages to be a great combination of both and come out fighting against the Candyman. It's hard not to love her in this role and furthermore not to love the scene at the end with the fire. It's heartbreaking for a multitude of reasons and why I adore her in this role. And then there was Tony Todd. The man, as we know, oozes charisma. He's recognisable for that voice alone but people have a tendency to forget he is not just that, he is also an actor of great skill. Able to take the simplest scene, just one line and instantly make it his own. When we first see him in the aforementioned role he does not disappoint. It's an eerie mixture of Gothic meets horror with that dash of elegance as he manages to make a monster who actually is compassionate and who we don't initially hate. He is the Candyman. The special effects. I heard a lot of negative on this and I'm not sure why if I am honest. If you watch this for the effects alone you miss the point of the film as they prove only part of the cog. For that matter though I thought they were done with grace and looked beautiful against the bland background. In a world where grey seems the prominent colour, the blood sticks out with the richness of its colour. To do it in such a setting was a clever little nod and adds to the overall tone of the film. Personally I liked Bernard Rose's score. It's charming and creepy without being ostentatious and those glassy moments really do send chills. Where the score reaches heights is when it begins seeping in just before the Candyman turns up. With the lights down, the darkness wrapping you and nothing but your imagination it leads your mind into a very twisted place. It's how Gothic horror should be. Not too much emphasis is placed on the special FX alone, a staple in most horror films, instead care is given to the characters and where they will go as the film draws on. It doesn't play it safe which I respect instead going for the jugular. And despite the ending being something we have seen before it doesn't suffer in the premise of the film. If anything the final scene adds another jolt to the scares born into this film. My only minor complaint is when Helen finds her other half setting up home with a new girlfriend after she was confined to the hospital. Not upsetting for him, despite Berkeley's obnoxious character, yet rather because you truly feel for the character of Helen. After everything she has endured you'd think there'd be some small hope on the horizon but it doesn't happen. Everything bad happens and yes it culminates in one of the most tragic scenes in Candyman. However that complaint could as much be a plus since you realise the depth of the acting and how she pulls you in, that itself is no small feat. And this is why Candyman is my baby. For every horror movie that ever has been, ever will be, this is my love. It encompasses the morals and fabrics of society into one and takes our preconceptions, throwing them away. Candyman is a wonderful horror film that deserves more recognition and I hope it gets it. I urge everyone to see this and embrace the beauty of Candyman. Lest you say his name and he comes for you...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Scary!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Gene Smith
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm surprised this movie isn't more famous or more looked up to compared to other horror movies there are out there, because I thought this movie was great! Virginia Madsen was great in this movie but the evil Candyman was just a great character, well acted, and a great, scary villain for a horror movie. The soundtrack is creepy and awesome and I remember this being one of the few horror movies that really really scared me back when I watched it. The sequels that I saw (there are at least three Candy Man movies that I have seen) were not nearly as good as this first one but it's a great movie for fans of horror films and you should definitely see it! It's a very original story and idea.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This didn't do anything for me
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    atinder
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A urban legend about Candyman is told to Helen, If you say he name 5 times in front of the mirror, it will be hide you and kill you. Helen who is doing a story about Candyman, Most of the people she talk to believe in the Candyman. When Helen play the game, she soon wish she didn't as Candyman end up framing her each death he cause and no one believes that she telling truth. I am not a fan of Candyman at all, I just do not find him scary all, the no of this scared him or it's did not even gross me out or even creep me out at all. However the story was good and the movie did not bore the hell out him, it was in-rusting for the whole movie and the movie was really good acting from everyone in this movie. 5 out of 10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Maybe the classiest slasher film ever conceived
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Red-Barracuda
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Candyman may very well be the most intelligent film to emerge from the slasher genre. Like A Nightmare On Elm Street before it, it has a supernatural killer from a netherworld who was killed by a mob of people and now comes back to the real world to enact a terrible revenge. However, where Freddie Krueger was a vile paedophile child killer, the Candyman was a black man killed for forming a sexual relationship with a white girl. So, a significant difference is that this is a slasher villain with a genuinely tragic back-story; he is a killer who is at once terrifying and poetic. This is one of the things that makes this film a somewhat unusual one of its type. It has a great sense of place too. The cold-looking Chicago setting is ideal, with the scenes in the projects especially well used. This aspect allows the movie to have an unexpected social-realist angle. The comparison between the squalor of the poor block with the one inhabited by the rich is done in an effective way. The social commentary isn't delivered in a ham-fisted way; it is just part of the story and seems quite natural. But of course this is a slasher film so how does it fare on that level? Well there are a number of gore-drenched scenes and several effective shock moments. The horror part of the film is certainly handled very well and it does have an effective and quite original killer. It has fine production values too. The haunting aerial photography is beautiful, while the score from Philip Glass is very evocative. Acting is universally good. Virginia Madsen as the principal character is great, while Tony Todd as the Candyman provides just the perfect balance of menace and melancholia. Candyman is a slasher film that offers up something different and, dare I say it, has some class. It's a very well executed horror film that also has other things to say as well. It's one of the strongest horror movies from the 1990's.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This 2 decade old Candy is still pretty sweet...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    oneguyrambling
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Time seems to have gone past Candyman but I remember when it was released in Australia in early 90s it was pretty far out stuff. A tall skinny black guy with a gruff voice gutting people with his hook hand was shocking back then  now we have the various tortures of Saw and Hostel. A pretty (being generous) blonde woman as the target of the baddie wasn't too prevalent (yeah-yeah Halloween!)  now it seems once you're a woman rated higher than an "8" you're practically assigned your own psychopathic serial killer The woman in this case is Sharon Stone-lite (ironically not where weight is concerned) Helen (Virginia Madsen), Tony Todd plays the titular Sugary Psycho that menaces her and her study-buddy Bernadette, among many others. Legend has it that the Candyman was the son of a slave who died badly after being tortured bees and other nastiness were involved after he had the temerity to nail the slave-owner's daughter. To summon the undead Candyman is simple, gaze into a mirror and repeat his name 5 times and he will appear instantly to well gut you like a fish if the movie is right, (why you would want this I'm not sure). The specifics of this seem to change a little depending on circumstances: - In one scene two people split the Candyman duties, splitting the 5 repeats between them he appears anyway. This would lead me to believe that every time you say Candyman to a mirror is a little like Russian roulette  as 4 other people could have said it once each elsewhere. - Further to this if you try to be clever and say it 4 times before chickening out depending on the count he could appear at any point in your sequence. - In some scenes Candy appears instantaneously, in others he seems to take a raincheck and pops up later. I guess there are either many people calling on him or the man is just busy doing other things Which could mean this is a chore to old Sweetums, and being summoned is like a doorbell; "AGAIN, I just finished killing two teens in Miami! Won't you guys give me 5 minutes to clean my hook? " Speculation and wonderment aside the mythology has become folklore in the local area where Helen and Bernadette are writing a paper on *DRUM ROLL Please!* Urban legends. This takes them to Cabrini Green, an urban ghetto area where word has it Candyman resides, after some faked contacts Helen writes off the legend as a fake. Not so fast Helen As people near and dear to Helen start dropping like flies in various bloody dismembered puddles, leaving her on the scene the investigators assume she had something to do with things and question her. Each subsequent step seems to implicate even more, and as she protests her innocence still more Candyman contacts and twists ensure she remains a suspect, and the police and her husband start to wonder if she might just be 110% nuts. There is some good simple music in Candyman which lends a bit of class to proceedings, including an effective piano loop that is instantly familiar when you hear it, some gore that may have been extreme in the 90s but hardly raises an eyebrow today, and it is always interesting to watch a "period piece" where almost everyone smokes and telephones still have cords. This year Natalie Portman put in a gonzo performance as the crizzazy Nena in Black Swan and was lauded for it. But really all she did was pretend to see things, scratch non-existent itches, yell a little and let CGI do most of the rest. As Helen Virginia Madsen gets her gear off a few times, fast-tracks a descent into insanity, emerges from several scenes covered in blood and bits of people, loses her hair and at times acts like a grade A looney. I see both Black Swan and Candyman as equally ludicrous yet one is being seen as somewhat visionary while Candyman was written off as just another slasher film. I guarantee in 10 years no-one will be studying Black Swan as a classic of the modern era Candyman is certainly no classic but here I am nigh 20 years later and it is still at least enjoyable. Final Rating  6 / 10. 20 year old Candy is probably not going to be as tasty as when it was new, but it still has a little flavour and is at least satisfying.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Candyman (1992)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SnakesOnAnAfricanPlain
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Candyman is one of those films I really should have seen by now. I remember the trailer on the Cinema Club trailer reel from a wide selection of videos I owned in the mid 90's. Anyway, I finally saw it and it was great horror. I forgot you could make powerful slasher movies and keep the teens well away. The movie is all about myths and how they can spread and take control. These days myths spread world wide and at a greater rate, thanks to the internet. Candyman really allows you to feel emotions for these characters. Madsen isn't going crazy, but we can't blame people for thinking she is. Tony Todd has a very dominating screen presence, not to mention a powerful voice. The kills all seem necessary in this film, as each one has an impact on our protagonist and the world she inhabits. Finally, we have Phillip Glass' incredible score, which adds a bizarre and haunting atmosphere to the movie. Great horror at an early 90's pace.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    First Great Horror Movie of the 90's
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    slasherstudios
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Helen Lyle is a graduate student conducting research for her thesis on urban legends. While interviewing freshmen about their superstitions, she hears about a local legend known as Candyman. The legend contains many thematic elements similar to the most well known urban legends, including endangered babysitters, spirits who appear in mirrors when fatally summoned, and maniac killers with unnatural deformities. The legend states that while Candyman was the son of a slave, he nevertheless became a well known artist. Yet, after falling in love with a white woman who becomes pregnant, Candyman is chased through the plantation and when caught, has his drawing hand cut off and replaced with a hook. He is then smeared with honey (prompting the locals to chant 'Candyman' a total of 5 times- hence the 'say his name 5 times into the mirror'), stolen from a nearby apiary, and the bees sting him to death. The legend also claims that Candyman is summoned by anyone who looks into a mirror and chants his name five times (similar to the Bloody Mary folkloric tale). Summoning him often costs the individual their own life. Later that evening, Helen and her friend Bernadette jokingly call Candyman's name into the mirror in Helen's bathroom but nothing happens. While conducting her research, Helen enters the notorious gang-ridden Cabrini-Green housing project, the site of a recent unsolved murder. There she meets Anne-Marie McCoy, one of the residents, as well as a young boy named Jake, who tells her a disturbing story of a child who was horribly mutilated in a public restroom near the projects, supposedly by Candyman. While exploring the run-down restroom, Helen is attacked by a gang member carrying a hook who has taken the Candyman moniker as his own to enhance his own street credibility by associating himself with the legend. Helen survives the assault and is able to later identify her attacker to the police. Helen later returns to school but hears a voice calling her name as she walks through a parking garage. Another man she encounters states he is the Candyman of the urban legend and because of Helen's disbelief in him, he must now prove to her that he is real. Helen blacks out and wakes up in Anne-Marie's apartment, covered in blood. Anne-Marie, whose Rottweiler has been decapitated and whose baby is also missing, attacks Helen and she is forced to defend herself from Anne-Marie using a meat cleaver. The police then enter the apartment and arrest Helen. Is Helen going crazy or will Candyman come for her next? Three words adequately describe "Candyman": Scary. As. Hell. I was twelve years old when I saw the movie for the first time and it hasn't left my mind since. From the haunting Phillip Glass score to the uncompromising promises by both Tony Todd as Candyman and Virginia Madsen (who has never looked better) as Helen, everything about this movie is sensationally scary. Madsen, in particular, seems to relish playing against time and causes the audience to be sympathetic with her character when a lesser actress would have just come across as annoying. A cheap "Carrie" rip-off of an ending is the only false beat in this superb thriller from one of the masters of the horror genre, Clive Barker.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Best Horror Film of 1992
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    robert haynes
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Candyman is undoubtedly the best horror film of 1992. Released with very little fanfare the film became a surprise hit and I remember why. Having been one of those lucky individuals to see the film five, yes five times on its initial theatrical run, I think it's safe to say that I'm a fan. The ability that director Bernard Rose has to create a palpable sense of dread is evident in every frame of this film. This is what true horror is all about. Candyman is extremely suspenseful and intensely creepy, in fact just writing about it I can already feel the hairs on my arms standing up again. It's that affecting! Virginia Madsen is superbly cast as Helen, a flawed but likable heroine the audience cares deeply about. Her journey into madness is one that we empathize with every brutal step of the way. You don't want bad things to happen to her because you've fallen in love with her. How Madsen wasn't nominated for an Oscar for this performance is still beyond me. Tony Todd is also an antihero with a personality and a rich one at that. The film is violent but the gore never becomes comedic. It sets the perfect tone of brutality. Candyman cannot come more highly recommended. It's a truly terrifying psychological art-house horror with standout performances and a deeply haunting score by Philip Glass. Horror films DO NOT get any better than this. Prepared to be scared. A terrific 10!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bees out of hive
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leoperu
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An above-average romantic horror movie with implausible, inconsistent storyline,atmospheric,but unnecessarily gory, adorned with fine photography of city textures (Anthony Richmond was the man behind the camera in three of the four best movies by Nicolas Roeg - but Rose isn't Roeg, so we cannot expect any visionary qualities here), music of Philip Glass, and charms of Virginia Madsen (it seems to me that whoever did admire her in the movie should avoid bonus interviews where an artificial puppet takes the place of our gorgeous go-getter turned victim). The makers let us know that Chicago instead of Liverpool was the right choice ; I wouldn't be so sure of that. And the bees.... well, they are simply out of the hive here.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Easy to Call This One a Classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Candyman (1992) *** (out of 4) Grad student Helen Lyle (Virginia Madsen) is doing research on why certain groups of people blame their violence on mythical legends when she comes across the name Candyman (Tony Todd). Soon Helen realizes that this figure with a hook for a hand is more than just a legend. CANDYMAN certainly stands as one of the best horror films of the 90s as it contains a great story, a creepy atmosphere, some great performances and of course many chilling moments. The story from Clive Barker is certainly something interesting to just think about because the idea of what an urban legend is and how it plays a part in people's lives who believe it is the best thing about the movie. I really loved how director Bernard Rose kept the viewing guessing at all times as to what was going on. Was it really Candyman doing all the killing or had Helen simply lost her mind while doing the research? It certainly helps that you've got such great actors in the leading roles and especially with Madsen. She does an extremely good job in the lead as she really makes you believe all of this stuff that is going on and it's a pretty deep character and the actress has no problems with it. Todd and that iconic voice makes Candyman one of the most memorable screen villains in horror history and that calm and cool nature of the actor really comes across extremely creepy. The film also features a very good score from Philip Glass and of course there's the striking images. I think the film does get a bit too long in the final act but there are just so many effective moments and killings here that you can't help but call this a classic of the genre.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dare You Say His Name, Dare You Watch This Film...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Juliet Raven
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Rarely do I give a film the golden ten rating. As much as I love films of all types, it takes something particularly memorable to get the coveted 10 stars. Candyman is one of those films that manages the impossible. It's clever in that we see an atypical setting, the urban streets, the high towers, the estates. It looks grim and feels it. Then we get into the arc of the story and everything changes to a degree. Yes the places shown remain the same but the story of the Candyman is enough to keep us transfixed, add to that some strong performances and it's a world we've never seen before. Even more powerful for the fact that the essential story itself derives partially from the urban legend of Bloody Mary. Plot: Helen Lyle (Virginia Madsen) is a graduate student who is conducting research for her own thesis on Urban Legends. Neither her nor her friend believing the story of the Candyman decide to jokingly say his name 5 times in Helen's mirror. Nothing happens. Yet soon after things go wrong and Helen realises some urban legends are anything but. Of the strongest abilities that this film possesses in heaps is the acting. From Xander Berkeley to Madsen and finally to Todd, the acting is of the highest quality and no one feels pushed into the shadows throughout this film. Yet it is primarily Madsen and Todd who stand out. Madsen was an actress I never really took much notice of until this film. She stands firm as the sole heroine trying to deal with the trauma and not buckling under the horror of it all. She carries that wonderful line between innocence and sharpness. Never too harsh, never too vanilla. She manages to be a great combination of both and come out fighting against the Candyman. It's hard not to love her in this role and furthermore not to love the scene at the end with the fire. It's heartbreaking for a multitude of reasons and why I adore her in this role. And then there was Tony Todd. The man, as we know, oozes charisma. He's recognisable for that voice alone but people have a tendency to forget he is not just that, he is also an actor of great skill. Able to take the simplest scene, just one line and instantly make it his own. When we first see him in the aforementioned role he does not disappoint. It's an eerie mixture of Gothic meets horror with that dash of elegance as he manages to make a monster who actually is compassionate and who we don't initially hate. He is the Candyman. The special effects. I heard a lot of negative on this and I'm not sure why if I am honest. If you watch this for the effects alone you miss the point of the film as they prove only part of the cog. For that matter though I thought they were done with grace and looked beautiful against the bland background. In a world where grey seems the prominent colour, the blood sticks out with the richness of its colour. To do it in such a setting was a clever little nod and adds to the overall tone of the film. Personally I liked Bernard Rose's score. It's charming and creepy without being ostentatious and those glassy moments really do send chills. Where the score reaches heights is when it begins seeping in just before the Candyman turns up. With the lights down, the darkness wrapping you and nothing but your imagination it leads your mind into a very twisted place. It's how Gothic horror should be. Not too much emphasis is placed on the special FX alone, a staple in most horror films, instead care is given to the characters and where they will go as the film draws on. It doesn't play it safe which I respect instead going for the jugular. And despite the ending being something we have seen before it doesn't suffer in the premise of the film. If anything the final scene adds another jolt to the scares born into this film. My only minor complaint is when Helen finds her other half setting up home with a new girlfriend after she was confined to the hospital. Not upsetting for him, despite Berkeley's obnoxious character, yet rather because you truly feel for the character of Helen. After everything she has endured you'd think there'd be some small hope on the horizon but it doesn't happen. Everything bad happens and yes it culminates in one of the most tragic scenes in Candyman. However that complaint could as much be a plus since you realise the depth of the acting and how she pulls you in, that itself is no small feat. And this is why Candyman is my baby. For every horror movie that ever has been, ever will be, this is my love. It encompasses the morals and fabrics of society into one and takes our preconceptions, throwing them away. Candyman is a wonderful horror film that deserves more recognition and I hope it gets it. I urge everyone to see this and embrace the beauty of Candyman. Lest you say his name and he comes for you...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Scary!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Gene Smith
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm surprised this movie isn't more famous or more looked up to compared to other horror movies there are out there, because I thought this movie was great! Virginia Madsen was great in this movie but the evil Candyman was just a great character, well acted, and a great, scary villain for a horror movie. The soundtrack is creepy and awesome and I remember this being one of the few horror movies that really really scared me back when I watched it. The sequels that I saw (there are at least three Candy Man movies that I have seen) were not nearly as good as this first one but it's a great movie for fans of horror films and you should definitely see it! It's a very original story and idea.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This didn't do anything for me
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    atinder
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A urban legend about Candyman is told to Helen, If you say he name 5 times in front of the mirror, it will be hide you and kill you. Helen who is doing a story about Candyman, Most of the people she talk to believe in the Candyman. When Helen play the game, she soon wish she didn't as Candyman end up framing her each death he cause and no one believes that she telling truth. I am not a fan of Candyman at all, I just do not find him scary all, the no of this scared him or it's did not even gross me out or even creep me out at all. However the story was good and the movie did not bore the hell out him, it was in-rusting for the whole movie and the movie was really good acting from everyone in this movie. 5 out of 10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Maybe the classiest slasher film ever conceived
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Red-Barracuda
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Candyman may very well be the most intelligent film to emerge from the slasher genre. Like A Nightmare On Elm Street before it, it has a supernatural killer from a netherworld who was killed by a mob of people and now comes back to the real world to enact a terrible revenge. However, where Freddie Krueger was a vile paedophile child killer, the Candyman was a black man killed for forming a sexual relationship with a white girl. So, a significant difference is that this is a slasher villain with a genuinely tragic back-story; he is a killer who is at once terrifying and poetic. This is one of the things that makes this film a somewhat unusual one of its type. It has a great sense of place too. The cold-looking Chicago setting is ideal, with the scenes in the projects especially well used. This aspect allows the movie to have an unexpected social-realist angle. The comparison between the squalor of the poor block with the one inhabited by the rich is done in an effective way. The social commentary isn't delivered in a ham-fisted way; it is just part of the story and seems quite natural. But of course this is a slasher film so how does it fare on that level? Well there are a number of gore-drenched scenes and several effective shock moments. The horror part of the film is certainly handled very well and it does have an effective and quite original killer. It has fine production values too. The haunting aerial photography is beautiful, while the score from Philip Glass is very evocative. Acting is universally good. Virginia Madsen as the principal character is great, while Tony Todd as the Candyman provides just the perfect balance of menace and melancholia. Candyman is a slasher film that offers up something different and, dare I say it, has some class. It's a very well executed horror film that also has other things to say as well. It's one of the strongest horror movies from the 1990's.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This 2 decade old Candy is still pretty sweet...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    oneguyrambling
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Time seems to have gone past Candyman but I remember when it was released in Australia in early 90s it was pretty far out stuff. A tall skinny black guy with a gruff voice gutting people with his hook hand was shocking back then  now we have the various tortures of Saw and Hostel. A pretty (being generous) blonde woman as the target of the baddie wasn't too prevalent (yeah-yeah Halloween!)  now it seems once you're a woman rated higher than an "8" you're practically assigned your own psychopathic serial killer The woman in this case is Sharon Stone-lite (ironically not where weight is concerned) Helen (Virginia Madsen), Tony Todd plays the titular Sugary Psycho that menaces her and her study-buddy Bernadette, among many others. Legend has it that the Candyman was the son of a slave who died badly after being tortured bees and other nastiness were involved after he had the temerity to nail the slave-owner's daughter. To summon the undead Candyman is simple, gaze into a mirror and repeat his name 5 times and he will appear instantly to well gut you like a fish if the movie is right, (why you would want this I'm not sure). The specifics of this seem to change a little depending on circumstances: - In one scene two people split the Candyman duties, splitting the 5 repeats between them he appears anyway. This would lead me to believe that every time you say Candyman to a mirror is a little like Russian roulette  as 4 other people could have said it once each elsewhere. - Further to this if you try to be clever and say it 4 times before chickening out depending on the count he could appear at any point in your sequence. - In some scenes Candy appears instantaneously, in others he seems to take a raincheck and pops up later. I guess there are either many people calling on him or the man is just busy doing other things Which could mean this is a chore to old Sweetums, and being summoned is like a doorbell; "AGAIN, I just finished killing two teens in Miami! Won't you guys give me 5 minutes to clean my hook? " Speculation and wonderment aside the mythology has become folklore in the local area where Helen and Bernadette are writing a paper on *DRUM ROLL Please!* Urban legends. This takes them to Cabrini Green, an urban ghetto area where word has it Candyman resides, after some faked contacts Helen writes off the legend as a fake. Not so fast Helen As people near and dear to Helen start dropping like flies in various bloody dismembered puddles, leaving her on the scene the investigators assume she had something to do with things and question her. Each subsequent step seems to implicate even more, and as she protests her innocence still more Candyman contacts and twists ensure she remains a suspect, and the police and her husband start to wonder if she might just be 110% nuts. There is some good simple music in Candyman which lends a bit of class to proceedings, including an effective piano loop that is instantly familiar when you hear it, some gore that may have been extreme in the 90s but hardly raises an eyebrow today, and it is always interesting to watch a "period piece" where almost everyone smokes and telephones still have cords. This year Natalie Portman put in a gonzo performance as the crizzazy Nena in Black Swan and was lauded for it. But really all she did was pretend to see things, scratch non-existent itches, yell a little and let CGI do most of the rest. As Helen Virginia Madsen gets her gear off a few times, fast-tracks a descent into insanity, emerges from several scenes covered in blood and bits of people, loses her hair and at times acts like a grade A looney. I see both Black Swan and Candyman as equally ludicrous yet one is being seen as somewhat visionary while Candyman was written off as just another slasher film. I guarantee in 10 years no-one will be studying Black Swan as a classic of the modern era Candyman is certainly no classic but here I am nigh 20 years later and it is still at least enjoyable. Final Rating  6 / 10. 20 year old Candy is probably not going to be as tasty as when it was new, but it still has a little flavour and is at least satisfying.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Candyman (1992)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SnakesOnAnAfricanPlain
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Candyman is one of those films I really should have seen by now. I remember the trailer on the Cinema Club trailer reel from a wide selection of videos I owned in the mid 90's. Anyway, I finally saw it and it was great horror. I forgot you could make powerful slasher movies and keep the teens well away. The movie is all about myths and how they can spread and take control. These days myths spread world wide and at a greater rate, thanks to the internet. Candyman really allows you to feel emotions for these characters. Madsen isn't going crazy, but we can't blame people for thinking she is. Tony Todd has a very dominating screen presence, not to mention a powerful voice. The kills all seem necessary in this film, as each one has an impact on our protagonist and the world she inhabits. Finally, we have Phillip Glass' incredible score, which adds a bizarre and haunting atmosphere to the movie. Great horror at an early 90's pace.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    First Great Horror Movie of the 90's
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    slasherstudios
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Helen Lyle is a graduate student conducting research for her thesis on urban legends. While interviewing freshmen about their superstitions, she hears about a local legend known as Candyman. The legend contains many thematic elements similar to the most well known urban legends, including endangered babysitters, spirits who appear in mirrors when fatally summoned, and maniac killers with unnatural deformities. The legend states that while Candyman was the son of a slave, he nevertheless became a well known artist. Yet, after falling in love with a white woman who becomes pregnant, Candyman is chased through the plantation and when caught, has his drawing hand cut off and replaced with a hook. He is then smeared with honey (prompting the locals to chant 'Candyman' a total of 5 times- hence the 'say his name 5 times into the mirror'), stolen from a nearby apiary, and the bees sting him to death. The legend also claims that Candyman is summoned by anyone who looks into a mirror and chants his name five times (similar to the Bloody Mary folkloric tale). Summoning him often costs the individual their own life. Later that evening, Helen and her friend Bernadette jokingly call Candyman's name into the mirror in Helen's bathroom but nothing happens. While conducting her research, Helen enters the notorious gang-ridden Cabrini-Green housing project, the site of a recent unsolved murder. There she meets Anne-Marie McCoy, one of the residents, as well as a young boy named Jake, who tells her a disturbing story of a child who was horribly mutilated in a public restroom near the projects, supposedly by Candyman. While exploring the run-down restroom, Helen is attacked by a gang member carrying a hook who has taken the Candyman moniker as his own to enhance his own street credibility by associating himself with the legend. Helen survives the assault and is able to later identify her attacker to the police. Helen later returns to school but hears a voice calling her name as she walks through a parking garage. Another man she encounters states he is the Candyman of the urban legend and because of Helen's disbelief in him, he must now prove to her that he is real. Helen blacks out and wakes up in Anne-Marie's apartment, covered in blood. Anne-Marie, whose Rottweiler has been decapitated and whose baby is also missing, attacks Helen and she is forced to defend herself from Anne-Marie using a meat cleaver. The police then enter the apartment and arrest Helen. Is Helen going crazy or will Candyman come for her next? Three words adequately describe "Candyman": Scary. As. Hell. I was twelve years old when I saw the movie for the first time and it hasn't left my mind since. From the haunting Phillip Glass score to the uncompromising promises by both Tony Todd as Candyman and Virginia Madsen (who has never looked better) as Helen, everything about this movie is sensationally scary. Madsen, in particular, seems to relish playing against time and causes the audience to be sympathetic with her character when a lesser actress would have just come across as annoying. A cheap "Carrie" rip-off of an ending is the only false beat in this superb thriller from one of the masters of the horror genre, Clive Barker.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Best Horror Film of 1992
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    robert haynes
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Candyman is undoubtedly the best horror film of 1992. Released with very little fanfare the film became a surprise hit and I remember why. Having been one of those lucky individuals to see the film five, yes five times on its initial theatrical run, I think it's safe to say that I'm a fan. The ability that director Bernard Rose has to create a palpable sense of dread is evident in every frame of this film. This is what true horror is all about. Candyman is extremely suspenseful and intensely creepy, in fact just writing about it I can already feel the hairs on my arms standing up again. It's that affecting! Virginia Madsen is superbly cast as Helen, a flawed but likable heroine the audience cares deeply about. Her journey into madness is one that we empathize with every brutal step of the way. You don't want bad things to happen to her because you've fallen in love with her. How Madsen wasn't nominated for an Oscar for this performance is still beyond me. Tony Todd is also an antihero with a personality and a rich one at that. The film is violent but the gore never becomes comedic. It sets the perfect tone of brutality. Candyman cannot come more highly recommended. It's a truly terrifying psychological art-house horror with standout performances and a deeply haunting score by Philip Glass. Horror films DO NOT get any better than this. Prepared to be scared. A terrific 10!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bees out of hive
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leoperu
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An above-average romantic horror movie with implausible, inconsistent storyline,atmospheric,but unnecessarily gory, adorned with fine photography of city textures (Anthony Richmond was the man behind the camera in three of the four best movies by Nicolas Roeg - but Rose isn't Roeg, so we cannot expect any visionary qualities here), music of Philip Glass, and charms of Virginia Madsen (it seems to me that whoever did admire her in the movie should avoid bonus interviews where an artificial puppet takes the place of our gorgeous go-getter turned victim). The makers let us know that Chicago instead of Liverpool was the right choice ; I wouldn't be so sure of that. And the bees.... well, they are simply out of the hive here.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Easy to Call This One a Classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Candyman (1992) *** (out of 4) Grad student Helen Lyle (Virginia Madsen) is doing research on why certain groups of people blame their violence on mythical legends when she comes across the name Candyman (Tony Todd). Soon Helen realizes that this figure with a hook for a hand is more than just a legend. CANDYMAN certainly stands as one of the best horror films of the 90s as it contains a great story, a creepy atmosphere, some great performances and of course many chilling moments. The story from Clive Barker is certainly something interesting to just think about because the idea of what an urban legend is and how it plays a part in people's lives who believe it is the best thing about the movie. I really loved how director Bernard Rose kept the viewing guessing at all times as to what was going on. Was it really Candyman doing all the killing or had Helen simply lost her mind while doing the research? It certainly helps that you've got such great actors in the leading roles and especially with Madsen. She does an extremely good job in the lead as she really makes you believe all of this stuff that is going on and it's a pretty deep character and the actress has no problems with it. Todd and that iconic voice makes Candyman one of the most memorable screen villains in horror history and that calm and cool nature of the actor really comes across extremely creepy. The film also features a very good score from Philip Glass and of course there's the striking images. I think the film does get a bit too long in the final act but there are just so many effective moments and killings here that you can't help but call this a classic of the genre.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dare You Say His Name, Dare You Watch This Film...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Juliet Raven
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Rarely do I give a film the golden ten rating. As much as I love films of all types, it takes something particularly memorable to get the coveted 10 stars. Candyman is one of those films that manages the impossible. It's clever in that we see an atypical setting, the urban streets, the high towers, the estates. It looks grim and feels it. Then we get into the arc of the story and everything changes to a degree. Yes the places shown remain the same but the story of the Candyman is enough to keep us transfixed, add to that some strong performances and it's a world we've never seen before. Even more powerful for the fact that the essential story itself derives partially from the urban legend of Bloody Mary. Plot: Helen Lyle (Virginia Madsen) is a graduate student who is conducting research for her own thesis on Urban Legends. Neither her nor her friend believing the story of the Candyman decide to jokingly say his name 5 times in Helen's mirror. Nothing happens. Yet soon after things go wrong and Helen realises some urban legends are anything but. Of the strongest abilities that this film possesses in heaps is the acting. From Xander Berkeley to Madsen and finally to Todd, the acting is of the highest quality and no one feels pushed into the shadows throughout this film. Yet it is primarily Madsen and Todd who stand out. Madsen was an actress I never really took much notice of until this film. She stands firm as the sole heroine trying to deal with the trauma and not buckling under the horror of it all. She carries that wonderful line between innocence and sharpness. Never too harsh, never too vanilla. She manages to be a great combination of both and come out fighting against the Candyman. It's hard not to love her in this role and furthermore not to love the scene at the end with the fire. It's heartbreaking for a multitude of reasons and why I adore her in this role. And then there was Tony Todd. The man, as we know, oozes charisma. He's recognisable for that voice alone but people have a tendency to forget he is not just that, he is also an actor of great skill. Able to take the simplest scene, just one line and instantly make it his own. When we first see him in the aforementioned role he does not disappoint. It's an eerie mixture of Gothic meets horror with that dash of elegance as he manages to make a monster who actually is compassionate and who we don't initially hate. He is the Candyman. The special effects. I heard a lot of negative on this and I'm not sure why if I am honest. If you watch this for the effects alone you miss the point of the film as they prove only part of the cog. For that matter though I thought they were done with grace and looked beautiful against the bland background. In a world where grey seems the prominent colour, the blood sticks out with the richness of its colour. To do it in such a setting was a clever little nod and adds to the overall tone of the film. Personally I liked Bernard Rose's score. It's charming and creepy without being ostentatious and those glassy moments really do send chills. Where the score reaches heights is when it begins seeping in just before the Candyman turns up. With the lights down, the darkness wrapping you and nothing but your imagination it leads your mind into a very twisted place. It's how Gothic horror should be. Not too much emphasis is placed on the special FX alone, a staple in most horror films, instead care is given to the characters and where they will go as the film draws on. It doesn't play it safe which I respect instead going for the jugular. And despite the ending being something we have seen before it doesn't suffer in the premise of the film. If anything the final scene adds another jolt to the scares born into this film. My only minor complaint is when Helen finds her other half setting up home with a new girlfriend after she was confined to the hospital. Not upsetting for him, despite Berkeley's obnoxious character, yet rather because you truly feel for the character of Helen. After everything she has endured you'd think there'd be some small hope on the horizon but it doesn't happen. Everything bad happens and yes it culminates in one of the most tragic scenes in Candyman. However that complaint could as much be a plus since you realise the depth of the acting and how she pulls you in, that itself is no small feat. And this is why Candyman is my baby. For every horror movie that ever has been, ever will be, this is my love. It encompasses the morals and fabrics of society into one and takes our preconceptions, throwing them away. Candyman is a wonderful horror film that deserves more recognition and I hope it gets it. I urge everyone to see this and embrace the beauty of Candyman. Lest you say his name and he comes for you...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Scary!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Gene Smith
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm surprised this movie isn't more famous or more looked up to compared to other horror movies there are out there, because I thought this movie was great! Virginia Madsen was great in this movie but the evil Candyman was just a great character, well acted, and a great, scary villain for a horror movie. The soundtrack is creepy and awesome and I remember this being one of the few horror movies that really really scared me back when I watched it. The sequels that I saw (there are at least three Candy Man movies that I have seen) were not nearly as good as this first one but it's a great movie for fans of horror films and you should definitely see it! It's a very original story and idea.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This didn't do anything for me
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    atinder
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A urban legend about Candyman is told to Helen, If you say he name 5 times in front of the mirror, it will be hide you and kill you. Helen who is doing a story about Candyman, Most of the people she talk to believe in the Candyman. When Helen play the game, she soon wish she didn't as Candyman end up framing her each death he cause and no one believes that she telling truth. I am not a fan of Candyman at all, I just do not find him scary all, the no of this scared him or it's did not even gross me out or even creep me out at all. However the story was good and the movie did not bore the hell out him, it was in-rusting for the whole movie and the movie was really good acting from everyone in this movie. 5 out of 10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Maybe the classiest slasher film ever conceived
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Red-Barracuda
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Candyman may very well be the most intelligent film to emerge from the slasher genre. Like A Nightmare On Elm Street before it, it has a supernatural killer from a netherworld who was killed by a mob of people and now comes back to the real world to enact a terrible revenge. However, where Freddie Krueger was a vile paedophile child killer, the Candyman was a black man killed for forming a sexual relationship with a white girl. So, a significant difference is that this is a slasher villain with a genuinely tragic back-story; he is a killer who is at once terrifying and poetic. This is one of the things that makes this film a somewhat unusual one of its type. It has a great sense of place too. The cold-looking Chicago setting is ideal, with the scenes in the projects especially well used. This aspect allows the movie to have an unexpected social-realist angle. The comparison between the squalor of the poor block with the one inhabited by the rich is done in an effective way. The social commentary isn't delivered in a ham-fisted way; it is just part of the story and seems quite natural. But of course this is a slasher film so how does it fare on that level? Well there are a number of gore-drenched scenes and several effective shock moments. The horror part of the film is certainly handled very well and it does have an effective and quite original killer. It has fine production values too. The haunting aerial photography is beautiful, while the score from Philip Glass is very evocative. Acting is universally good. Virginia Madsen as the principal character is great, while Tony Todd as the Candyman provides just the perfect balance of menace and melancholia. Candyman is a slasher film that offers up something different and, dare I say it, has some class. It's a very well executed horror film that also has other things to say as well. It's one of the strongest horror movies from the 1990's.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This 2 decade old Candy is still pretty sweet...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    oneguyrambling
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Time seems to have gone past Candyman but I remember when it was released in Australia in early 90s it was pretty far out stuff. A tall skinny black guy with a gruff voice gutting people with his hook hand was shocking back then  now we have the various tortures of Saw and Hostel. A pretty (being generous) blonde woman as the target of the baddie wasn't too prevalent (yeah-yeah Halloween!)  now it seems once you're a woman rated higher than an "8" you're practically assigned your own psychopathic serial killer The woman in this case is Sharon Stone-lite (ironically not where weight is concerned) Helen (Virginia Madsen), Tony Todd plays the titular Sugary Psycho that menaces her and her study-buddy Bernadette, among many others. Legend has it that the Candyman was the son of a slave who died badly after being tortured bees and other nastiness were involved after he had the temerity to nail the slave-owner's daughter. To summon the undead Candyman is simple, gaze into a mirror and repeat his name 5 times and he will appear instantly to well gut you like a fish if the movie is right, (why you would want this I'm not sure). The specifics of this seem to change a little depending on circumstances: - In one scene two people split the Candyman duties, splitting the 5 repeats between them he appears anyway. This would lead me to believe that every time you say Candyman to a mirror is a little like Russian roulette  as 4 other people could have said it once each elsewhere. - Further to this if you try to be clever and say it 4 times before chickening out depending on the count he could appear at any point in your sequence. - In some scenes Candy appears instantaneously, in others he seems to take a raincheck and pops up later. I guess there are either many people calling on him or the man is just busy doing other things Which could mean this is a chore to old Sweetums, and being summoned is like a doorbell; "AGAIN, I just finished killing two teens in Miami! Won't you guys give me 5 minutes to clean my hook? " Speculation and wonderment aside the mythology has become folklore in the local area where Helen and Bernadette are writing a paper on *DRUM ROLL Please!* Urban legends. This takes them to Cabrini Green, an urban ghetto area where word has it Candyman resides, after some faked contacts Helen writes off the legend as a fake. Not so fast Helen As people near and dear to Helen start dropping like flies in various bloody dismembered puddles, leaving her on the scene the investigators assume she had something to do with things and question her. Each subsequent step seems to implicate even more, and as she protests her innocence still more Candyman contacts and twists ensure she remains a suspect, and the police and her husband start to wonder if she might just be 110% nuts. There is some good simple music in Candyman which lends a bit of class to proceedings, including an effective piano loop that is instantly familiar when you hear it, some gore that may have been extreme in the 90s but hardly raises an eyebrow today, and it is always interesting to watch a "period piece" where almost everyone smokes and telephones still have cords. This year Natalie Portman put in a gonzo performance as the crizzazy Nena in Black Swan and was lauded for it. But really all she did was pretend to see things, scratch non-existent itches, yell a little and let CGI do most of the rest. As Helen Virginia Madsen gets her gear off a few times, fast-tracks a descent into insanity, emerges from several scenes covered in blood and bits of people, loses her hair and at times acts like a grade A looney. I see both Black Swan and Candyman as equally ludicrous yet one is being seen as somewhat visionary while Candyman was written off as just another slasher film. I guarantee in 10 years no-one will be studying Black Swan as a classic of the modern era Candyman is certainly no classic but here I am nigh 20 years later and it is still at least enjoyable. Final Rating  6 / 10. 20 year old Candy is probably not going to be as tasty as when it was new, but it still has a little flavour and is at least satisfying.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Candyman (1992)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SnakesOnAnAfricanPlain
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Candyman is one of those films I really should have seen by now. I remember the trailer on the Cinema Club trailer reel from a wide selection of videos I owned in the mid 90's. Anyway, I finally saw it and it was great horror. I forgot you could make powerful slasher movies and keep the teens well away. The movie is all about myths and how they can spread and take control. These days myths spread world wide and at a greater rate, thanks to the internet. Candyman really allows you to feel emotions for these characters. Madsen isn't going crazy, but we can't blame people for thinking she is. Tony Todd has a very dominating screen presence, not to mention a powerful voice. The kills all seem necessary in this film, as each one has an impact on our protagonist and the world she inhabits. Finally, we have Phillip Glass' incredible score, which adds a bizarre and haunting atmosphere to the movie. Great horror at an early 90's pace.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    First Great Horror Movie of the 90's
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    slasherstudios
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Helen Lyle is a graduate student conducting research for her thesis on urban legends. While interviewing freshmen about their superstitions, she hears about a local legend known as Candyman. The legend contains many thematic elements similar to the most well known urban legends, including endangered babysitters, spirits who appear in mirrors when fatally summoned, and maniac killers with unnatural deformities. The legend states that while Candyman was the son of a slave, he nevertheless became a well known artist. Yet, after falling in love with a white woman who becomes pregnant, Candyman is chased through the plantation and when caught, has his drawing hand cut off and replaced with a hook. He is then smeared with honey (prompting the locals to chant 'Candyman' a total of 5 times- hence the 'say his name 5 times into the mirror'), stolen from a nearby apiary, and the bees sting him to death. The legend also claims that Candyman is summoned by anyone who looks into a mirror and chants his name five times (similar to the Bloody Mary folkloric tale). Summoning him often costs the individual their own life. Later that evening, Helen and her friend Bernadette jokingly call Candyman's name into the mirror in Helen's bathroom but nothing happens. While conducting her research, Helen enters the notorious gang-ridden Cabrini-Green housing project, the site of a recent unsolved murder. There she meets Anne-Marie McCoy, one of the residents, as well as a young boy named Jake, who tells her a disturbing story of a child who was horribly mutilated in a public restroom near the projects, supposedly by Candyman. While exploring the run-down restroom, Helen is attacked by a gang member carrying a hook who has taken the Candyman moniker as his own to enhance his own street credibility by associating himself with the legend. Helen survives the assault and is able to later identify her attacker to the police. Helen later returns to school but hears a voice calling her name as she walks through a parking garage. Another man she encounters states he is the Candyman of the urban legend and because of Helen's disbelief in him, he must now prove to her that he is real. Helen blacks out and wakes up in Anne-Marie's apartment, covered in blood. Anne-Marie, whose Rottweiler has been decapitated and whose baby is also missing, attacks Helen and she is forced to defend herself from Anne-Marie using a meat cleaver. The police then enter the apartment and arrest Helen. Is Helen going crazy or will Candyman come for her next? Three words adequately describe "Candyman": Scary. As. Hell. I was twelve years old when I saw the movie for the first time and it hasn't left my mind since. From the haunting Phillip Glass score to the uncompromising promises by both Tony Todd as Candyman and Virginia Madsen (who has never looked better) as Helen, everything about this movie is sensationally scary. Madsen, in particular, seems to relish playing against time and causes the audience to be sympathetic with her character when a lesser actress would have just come across as annoying. A cheap "Carrie" rip-off of an ending is the only false beat in this superb thriller from one of the masters of the horror genre, Clive Barker.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Best Horror Film of 1992
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    robert haynes
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Candyman is undoubtedly the best horror film of 1992. Released with very little fanfare the film became a surprise hit and I remember why. Having been one of those lucky individuals to see the film five, yes five times on its initial theatrical run, I think it's safe to say that I'm a fan. The ability that director Bernard Rose has to create a palpable sense of dread is evident in every frame of this film. This is what true horror is all about. Candyman is extremely suspenseful and intensely creepy, in fact just writing about it I can already feel the hairs on my arms standing up again. It's that affecting! Virginia Madsen is superbly cast as Helen, a flawed but likable heroine the audience cares deeply about. Her journey into madness is one that we empathize with every brutal step of the way. You don't want bad things to happen to her because you've fallen in love with her. How Madsen wasn't nominated for an Oscar for this performance is still beyond me. Tony Todd is also an antihero with a personality and a rich one at that. The film is violent but the gore never becomes comedic. It sets the perfect tone of brutality. Candyman cannot come more highly recommended. It's a truly terrifying psychological art-house horror with standout performances and a deeply haunting score by Philip Glass. Horror films DO NOT get any better than this. Prepared to be scared. A terrific 10!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bees out of hive
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leoperu
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An above-average romantic horror movie with implausible, inconsistent storyline,atmospheric,but unnecessarily gory, adorned with fine photography of city textures (Anthony Richmond was the man behind the camera in three of the four best movies by Nicolas Roeg - but Rose isn't Roeg, so we cannot expect any visionary qualities here), music of Philip Glass, and charms of Virginia Madsen (it seems to me that whoever did admire her in the movie should avoid bonus interviews where an artificial puppet takes the place of our gorgeous go-getter turned victim). The makers let us know that Chicago instead of Liverpool was the right choice ; I wouldn't be so sure of that. And the bees.... well, they are simply out of the hive here.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Easy to Call This One a Classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Candyman (1992) *** (out of 4) Grad student Helen Lyle (Virginia Madsen) is doing research on why certain groups of people blame their violence on mythical legends when she comes across the name Candyman (Tony Todd). Soon Helen realizes that this figure with a hook for a hand is more than just a legend. CANDYMAN certainly stands as one of the best horror films of the 90s as it contains a great story, a creepy atmosphere, some great performances and of course many chilling moments. The story from Clive Barker is certainly something interesting to just think about because the idea of what an urban legend is and how it plays a part in people's lives who believe it is the best thing about the movie. I really loved how director Bernard Rose kept the viewing guessing at all times as to what was going on. Was it really Candyman doing all the killing or had Helen simply lost her mind while doing the research? It certainly helps that you've got such great actors in the leading roles and especially with Madsen. She does an extremely good job in the lead as she really makes you believe all of this stuff that is going on and it's a pretty deep character and the actress has no problems with it. Todd and that iconic voice makes Candyman one of the most memorable screen villains in horror history and that calm and cool nature of the actor really comes across extremely creepy. The film also features a very good score from Philip Glass and of course there's the striking images. I think the film does get a bit too long in the final act but there are just so many effective moments and killings here that you can't help but call this a classic of the genre.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dare You Say His Name, Dare You Watch This Film...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Juliet Raven
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Rarely do I give a film the golden ten rating. As much as I love films of all types, it takes something particularly memorable to get the coveted 10 stars. Candyman is one of those films that manages the impossible. It's clever in that we see an atypical setting, the urban streets, the high towers, the estates. It looks grim and feels it. Then we get into the arc of the story and everything changes to a degree. Yes the places shown remain the same but the story of the Candyman is enough to keep us transfixed, add to that some strong performances and it's a world we've never seen before. Even more powerful for the fact that the essential story itself derives partially from the urban legend of Bloody Mary. Plot: Helen Lyle (Virginia Madsen) is a graduate student who is conducting research for her own thesis on Urban Legends. Neither her nor her friend believing the story of the Candyman decide to jokingly say his name 5 times in Helen's mirror. Nothing happens. Yet soon after things go wrong and Helen realises some urban legends are anything but. Of the strongest abilities that this film possesses in heaps is the acting. From Xander Berkeley to Madsen and finally to Todd, the acting is of the highest quality and no one feels pushed into the shadows throughout this film. Yet it is primarily Madsen and Todd who stand out. Madsen was an actress I never really took much notice of until this film. She stands firm as the sole heroine trying to deal with the trauma and not buckling under the horror of it all. She carries that wonderful line between innocence and sharpness. Never too harsh, never too vanilla. She manages to be a great combination of both and come out fighting against the Candyman. It's hard not to love her in this role and furthermore not to love the scene at the end with the fire. It's heartbreaking for a multitude of reasons and why I adore her in this role. And then there was Tony Todd. The man, as we know, oozes charisma. He's recognisable for that voice alone but people have a tendency to forget he is not just that, he is also an actor of great skill. Able to take the simplest scene, just one line and instantly make it his own. When we first see him in the aforementioned role he does not disappoint. It's an eerie mixture of Gothic meets horror with that dash of elegance as he manages to make a monster who actually is compassionate and who we don't initially hate. He is the Candyman. The special effects. I heard a lot of negative on this and I'm not sure why if I am honest. If you watch this for the effects alone you miss the point of the film as they prove only part of the cog. For that matter though I thought they were done with grace and looked beautiful against the bland background. In a world where grey seems the prominent colour, the blood sticks out with the richness of its colour. To do it in such a setting was a clever little nod and adds to the overall tone of the film. Personally I liked Bernard Rose's score. It's charming and creepy without being ostentatious and those glassy moments really do send chills. Where the score reaches heights is when it begins seeping in just before the Candyman turns up. With the lights down, the darkness wrapping you and nothing but your imagination it leads your mind into a very twisted place. It's how Gothic horror should be. Not too much emphasis is placed on the special FX alone, a staple in most horror films, instead care is given to the characters and where they will go as the film draws on. It doesn't play it safe which I respect instead going for the jugular. And despite the ending being something we have seen before it doesn't suffer in the premise of the film. If anything the final scene adds another jolt to the scares born into this film. My only minor complaint is when Helen finds her other half setting up home with a new girlfriend after she was confined to the hospital. Not upsetting for him, despite Berkeley's obnoxious character, yet rather because you truly feel for the character of Helen. After everything she has endured you'd think there'd be some small hope on the horizon but it doesn't happen. Everything bad happens and yes it culminates in one of the most tragic scenes in Candyman. However that complaint could as much be a plus since you realise the depth of the acting and how she pulls you in, that itself is no small feat. And this is why Candyman is my baby. For every horror movie that ever has been, ever will be, this is my love. It encompasses the morals and fabrics of society into one and takes our preconceptions, throwing them away. Candyman is a wonderful horror film that deserves more recognition and I hope it gets it. I urge everyone to see this and embrace the beauty of Candyman. Lest you say his name and he comes for you...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Scary!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Gene Smith
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm surprised this movie isn't more famous or more looked up to compared to other horror movies there are out there, because I thought this movie was great! Virginia Madsen was great in this movie but the evil Candyman was just a great character, well acted, and a great, scary villain for a horror movie. The soundtrack is creepy and awesome and I remember this being one of the few horror movies that really really scared me back when I watched it. The sequels that I saw (there are at least three Candy Man movies that I have seen) were not nearly as good as this first one but it's a great movie for fans of horror films and you should definitely see it! It's a very original story and idea.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This didn't do anything for me
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    atinder
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A urban legend about Candyman is told to Helen, If you say he name 5 times in front of the mirror, it will be hide you and kill you. Helen who is doing a story about Candyman, Most of the people she talk to believe in the Candyman. When Helen play the game, she soon wish she didn't as Candyman end up framing her each death he cause and no one believes that she telling truth. I am not a fan of Candyman at all, I just do not find him scary all, the no of this scared him or it's did not even gross me out or even creep me out at all. However the story was good and the movie did not bore the hell out him, it was in-rusting for the whole movie and the movie was really good acting from everyone in this movie. 5 out of 10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Maybe the classiest slasher film ever conceived
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Red-Barracuda
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Candyman may very well be the most intelligent film to emerge from the slasher genre. Like A Nightmare On Elm Street before it, it has a supernatural killer from a netherworld who was killed by a mob of people and now comes back to the real world to enact a terrible revenge. However, where Freddie Krueger was a vile paedophile child killer, the Candyman was a black man killed for forming a sexual relationship with a white girl. So, a significant difference is that this is a slasher villain with a genuinely tragic back-story; he is a killer who is at once terrifying and poetic. This is one of the things that makes this film a somewhat unusual one of its type. It has a great sense of place too. The cold-looking Chicago setting is ideal, with the scenes in the projects especially well used. This aspect allows the movie to have an unexpected social-realist angle. The comparison between the squalor of the poor block with the one inhabited by the rich is done in an effective way. The social commentary isn't delivered in a ham-fisted way; it is just part of the story and seems quite natural. But of course this is a slasher film so how does it fare on that level? Well there are a number of gore-drenched scenes and several effective shock moments. The horror part of the film is certainly handled very well and it does have an effective and quite original killer. It has fine production values too. The haunting aerial photography is beautiful, while the score from Philip Glass is very evocative. Acting is universally good. Virginia Madsen as the principal character is great, while Tony Todd as the Candyman provides just the perfect balance of menace and melancholia. Candyman is a slasher film that offers up something different and, dare I say it, has some class. It's a very well executed horror film that also has other things to say as well. It's one of the strongest horror movies from the 1990's.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This 2 decade old Candy is still pretty sweet...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    oneguyrambling
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Time seems to have gone past Candyman but I remember when it was released in Australia in early 90s it was pretty far out stuff. A tall skinny black guy with a gruff voice gutting people with his hook hand was shocking back then  now we have the various tortures of Saw and Hostel. A pretty (being generous) blonde woman as the target of the baddie wasn't too prevalent (yeah-yeah Halloween!)  now it seems once you're a woman rated higher than an "8" you're practically assigned your own psychopathic serial killer The woman in this case is Sharon Stone-lite (ironically not where weight is concerned) Helen (Virginia Madsen), Tony Todd plays the titular Sugary Psycho that menaces her and her study-buddy Bernadette, among many others. Legend has it that the Candyman was the son of a slave who died badly after being tortured bees and other nastiness were involved after he had the temerity to nail the slave-owner's daughter. To summon the undead Candyman is simple, gaze into a mirror and repeat his name 5 times and he will appear instantly to well gut you like a fish if the movie is right, (why you would want this I'm not sure). The specifics of this seem to change a little depending on circumstances: - In one scene two people split the Candyman duties, splitting the 5 repeats between them he appears anyway. This would lead me to believe that every time you say Candyman to a mirror is a little like Russian roulette  as 4 other people could have said it once each elsewhere. - Further to this if you try to be clever and say it 4 times before chickening out depending on the count he could appear at any point in your sequence. - In some scenes Candy appears instantaneously, in others he seems to take a raincheck and pops up later. I guess there are either many people calling on him or the man is just busy doing other things Which could mean this is a chore to old Sweetums, and being summoned is like a doorbell; "AGAIN, I just finished killing two teens in Miami! Won't you guys give me 5 minutes to clean my hook? " Speculation and wonderment aside the mythology has become folklore in the local area where Helen and Bernadette are writing a paper on *DRUM ROLL Please!* Urban legends. This takes them to Cabrini Green, an urban ghetto area where word has it Candyman resides, after some faked contacts Helen writes off the legend as a fake. Not so fast Helen As people near and dear to Helen start dropping like flies in various bloody dismembered puddles, leaving her on the scene the investigators assume she had something to do with things and question her. Each subsequent step seems to implicate even more, and as she protests her innocence still more Candyman contacts and twists ensure she remains a suspect, and the police and her husband start to wonder if she might just be 110% nuts. There is some good simple music in Candyman which lends a bit of class to proceedings, including an effective piano loop that is instantly familiar when you hear it, some gore that may have been extreme in the 90s but hardly raises an eyebrow today, and it is always interesting to watch a "period piece" where almost everyone smokes and telephones still have cords. This year Natalie Portman put in a gonzo performance as the crizzazy Nena in Black Swan and was lauded for it. But really all she did was pretend to see things, scratch non-existent itches, yell a little and let CGI do most of the rest. As Helen Virginia Madsen gets her gear off a few times, fast-tracks a descent into insanity, emerges from several scenes covered in blood and bits of people, loses her hair and at times acts like a grade A looney. I see both Black Swan and Candyman as equally ludicrous yet one is being seen as somewhat visionary while Candyman was written off as just another slasher film. I guarantee in 10 years no-one will be studying Black Swan as a classic of the modern era Candyman is certainly no classic but here I am nigh 20 years later and it is still at least enjoyable. Final Rating  6 / 10. 20 year old Candy is probably not going to be as tasty as when it was new, but it still has a little flavour and is at least satisfying.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Candyman (1992)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SnakesOnAnAfricanPlain
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Candyman is one of those films I really should have seen by now. I remember the trailer on the Cinema Club trailer reel from a wide selection of videos I owned in the mid 90's. Anyway, I finally saw it and it was great horror. I forgot you could make powerful slasher movies and keep the teens well away. The movie is all about myths and how they can spread and take control. These days myths spread world wide and at a greater rate, thanks to the internet. Candyman really allows you to feel emotions for these characters. Madsen isn't going crazy, but we can't blame people for thinking she is. Tony Todd has a very dominating screen presence, not to mention a powerful voice. The kills all seem necessary in this film, as each one has an impact on our protagonist and the world she inhabits. Finally, we have Phillip Glass' incredible score, which adds a bizarre and haunting atmosphere to the movie. Great horror at an early 90's pace.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    First Great Horror Movie of the 90's
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    slasherstudios
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Helen Lyle is a graduate student conducting research for her thesis on urban legends. While interviewing freshmen about their superstitions, she hears about a local legend known as Candyman. The legend contains many thematic elements similar to the most well known urban legends, including endangered babysitters, spirits who appear in mirrors when fatally summoned, and maniac killers with unnatural deformities. The legend states that while Candyman was the son of a slave, he nevertheless became a well known artist. Yet, after falling in love with a white woman who becomes pregnant, Candyman is chased through the plantation and when caught, has his drawing hand cut off and replaced with a hook. He is then smeared with honey (prompting the locals to chant 'Candyman' a total of 5 times- hence the 'say his name 5 times into the mirror'), stolen from a nearby apiary, and the bees sting him to death. The legend also claims that Candyman is summoned by anyone who looks into a mirror and chants his name five times (similar to the Bloody Mary folkloric tale). Summoning him often costs the individual their own life. Later that evening, Helen and her friend Bernadette jokingly call Candyman's name into the mirror in Helen's bathroom but nothing happens. While conducting her research, Helen enters the notorious gang-ridden Cabrini-Green housing project, the site of a recent unsolved murder. There she meets Anne-Marie McCoy, one of the residents, as well as a young boy named Jake, who tells her a disturbing story of a child who was horribly mutilated in a public restroom near the projects, supposedly by Candyman. While exploring the run-down restroom, Helen is attacked by a gang member carrying a hook who has taken the Candyman moniker as his own to enhance his own street credibility by associating himself with the legend. Helen survives the assault and is able to later identify her attacker to the police. Helen later returns to school but hears a voice calling her name as she walks through a parking garage. Another man she encounters states he is the Candyman of the urban legend and because of Helen's disbelief in him, he must now prove to her that he is real. Helen blacks out and wakes up in Anne-Marie's apartment, covered in blood. Anne-Marie, whose Rottweiler has been decapitated and whose baby is also missing, attacks Helen and she is forced to defend herself from Anne-Marie using a meat cleaver. The police then enter the apartment and arrest Helen. Is Helen going crazy or will Candyman come for her next? Three words adequately describe "Candyman": Scary. As. Hell. I was twelve years old when I saw the movie for the first time and it hasn't left my mind since. From the haunting Phillip Glass score to the uncompromising promises by both Tony Todd as Candyman and Virginia Madsen (who has never looked better) as Helen, everything about this movie is sensationally scary. Madsen, in particular, seems to relish playing against time and causes the audience to be sympathetic with her character when a lesser actress would have just come across as annoying. A cheap "Carrie" rip-off of an ending is the only false beat in this superb thriller from one of the masters of the horror genre, Clive Barker.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Best Horror Film of 1992
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    robert haynes
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Candyman is undoubtedly the best horror film of 1992. Released with very little fanfare the film became a surprise hit and I remember why. Having been one of those lucky individuals to see the film five, yes five times on its initial theatrical run, I think it's safe to say that I'm a fan. The ability that director Bernard Rose has to create a palpable sense of dread is evident in every frame of this film. This is what true horror is all about. Candyman is extremely suspenseful and intensely creepy, in fact just writing about it I can already feel the hairs on my arms standing up again. It's that affecting! Virginia Madsen is superbly cast as Helen, a flawed but likable heroine the audience cares deeply about. Her journey into madness is one that we empathize with every brutal step of the way. You don't want bad things to happen to her because you've fallen in love with her. How Madsen wasn't nominated for an Oscar for this performance is still beyond me. Tony Todd is also an antihero with a personality and a rich one at that. The film is violent but the gore never becomes comedic. It sets the perfect tone of brutality. Candyman cannot come more highly recommended. It's a truly terrifying psychological art-house horror with standout performances and a deeply haunting score by Philip Glass. Horror films DO NOT get any better than this. Prepared to be scared. A terrific 10!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bees out of hive
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leoperu
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An above-average romantic horror movie with implausible, inconsistent storyline,atmospheric,but unnecessarily gory, adorned with fine photography of city textures (Anthony Richmond was the man behind the camera in three of the four best movies by Nicolas Roeg - but Rose isn't Roeg, so we cannot expect any visionary qualities here), music of Philip Glass, and charms of Virginia Madsen (it seems to me that whoever did admire her in the movie should avoid bonus interviews where an artificial puppet takes the place of our gorgeous go-getter turned victim). The makers let us know that Chicago instead of Liverpool was the right choice ; I wouldn't be so sure of that. And the bees.... well, they are simply out of the hive here.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Easy to Call This One a Classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Candyman (1992) *** (out of 4) Grad student Helen Lyle (Virginia Madsen) is doing research on why certain groups of people blame their violence on mythical legends when she comes across the name Candyman (Tony Todd). Soon Helen realizes that this figure with a hook for a hand is more than just a legend. CANDYMAN certainly stands as one of the best horror films of the 90s as it contains a great story, a creepy atmosphere, some great performances and of course many chilling moments. The story from Clive Barker is certainly something interesting to just think about because the idea of what an urban legend is and how it plays a part in people's lives who believe it is the best thing about the movie. I really loved how director Bernard Rose kept the viewing guessing at all times as to what was going on. Was it really Candyman doing all the killing or had Helen simply lost her mind while doing the research? It certainly helps that you've got such great actors in the leading roles and especially with Madsen. She does an extremely good job in the lead as she really makes you believe all of this stuff that is going on and it's a pretty deep character and the actress has no problems with it. Todd and that iconic voice makes Candyman one of the most memorable screen villains in horror history and that calm and cool nature of the actor really comes across extremely creepy. The film also features a very good score from Philip Glass and of course there's the striking images. I think the film does get a bit too long in the final act but there are just so many effective moments and killings here that you can't help but call this a classic of the genre.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dare You Say His Name, Dare You Watch This Film...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Juliet Raven
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Rarely do I give a film the golden ten rating. As much as I love films of all types, it takes something particularly memorable to get the coveted 10 stars. Candyman is one of those films that manages the impossible. It's clever in that we see an atypical setting, the urban streets, the high towers, the estates. It looks grim and feels it. Then we get into the arc of the story and everything changes to a degree. Yes the places shown remain the same but the story of the Candyman is enough to keep us transfixed, add to that some strong performances and it's a world we've never seen before. Even more powerful for the fact that the essential story itself derives partially from the urban legend of Bloody Mary. Plot: Helen Lyle (Virginia Madsen) is a graduate student who is conducting research for her own thesis on Urban Legends. Neither her nor her friend believing the story of the Candyman decide to jokingly say his name 5 times in Helen's mirror. Nothing happens. Yet soon after things go wrong and Helen realises some urban legends are anything but. Of the strongest abilities that this film possesses in heaps is the acting. From Xander Berkeley to Madsen and finally to Todd, the acting is of the highest quality and no one feels pushed into the shadows throughout this film. Yet it is primarily Madsen and Todd who stand out. Madsen was an actress I never really took much notice of until this film. She stands firm as the sole heroine trying to deal with the trauma and not buckling under the horror of it all. She carries that wonderful line between innocence and sharpness. Never too harsh, never too vanilla. She manages to be a great combination of both and come out fighting against the Candyman. It's hard not to love her in this role and furthermore not to love the scene at the end with the fire. It's heartbreaking for a multitude of reasons and why I adore her in this role. And then there was Tony Todd. The man, as we know, oozes charisma. He's recognisable for that voice alone but people have a tendency to forget he is not just that, he is also an actor of great skill. Able to take the simplest scene, just one line and instantly make it his own. When we first see him in the aforementioned role he does not disappoint. It's an eerie mixture of Gothic meets horror with that dash of elegance as he manages to make a monster who actually is compassionate and who we don't initially hate. He is the Candyman. The special effects. I heard a lot of negative on this and I'm not sure why if I am honest. If you watch this for the effects alone you miss the point of the film as they prove only part of the cog. For that matter though I thought they were done with grace and looked beautiful against the bland background. In a world where grey seems the prominent colour, the blood sticks out with the richness of its colour. To do it in such a setting was a clever little nod and adds to the overall tone of the film. Personally I liked Bernard Rose's score. It's charming and creepy without being ostentatious and those glassy moments really do send chills. Where the score reaches heights is when it begins seeping in just before the Candyman turns up. With the lights down, the darkness wrapping you and nothing but your imagination it leads your mind into a very twisted place. It's how Gothic horror should be. Not too much emphasis is placed on the special FX alone, a staple in most horror films, instead care is given to the characters and where they will go as the film draws on. It doesn't play it safe which I respect instead going for the jugular. And despite the ending being something we have seen before it doesn't suffer in the premise of the film. If anything the final scene adds another jolt to the scares born into this film. My only minor complaint is when Helen finds her other half setting up home with a new girlfriend after she was confined to the hospital. Not upsetting for him, despite Berkeley's obnoxious character, yet rather because you truly feel for the character of Helen. After everything she has endured you'd think there'd be some small hope on the horizon but it doesn't happen. Everything bad happens and yes it culminates in one of the most tragic scenes in Candyman. However that complaint could as much be a plus since you realise the depth of the acting and how she pulls you in, that itself is no small feat. And this is why Candyman is my baby. For every horror movie that ever has been, ever will be, this is my love. It encompasses the morals and fabrics of society into one and takes our preconceptions, throwing them away. Candyman is a wonderful horror film that deserves more recognition and I hope it gets it. I urge everyone to see this and embrace the beauty of Candyman. Lest you say his name and he comes for you...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Scary!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Gene Smith
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm surprised this movie isn't more famous or more looked up to compared to other horror movies there are out there, because I thought this movie was great! Virginia Madsen was great in this movie but the evil Candyman was just a great character, well acted, and a great, scary villain for a horror movie. The soundtrack is creepy and awesome and I remember this being one of the few horror movies that really really scared me back when I watched it. The sequels that I saw (there are at least three Candy Man movies that I have seen) were not nearly as good as this first one but it's a great movie for fans of horror films and you should definitely see it! It's a very original story and idea.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This didn't do anything for me
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    atinder
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A urban legend about Candyman is told to Helen, If you say he name 5 times in front of the mirror, it will be hide you and kill you. Helen who is doing a story about Candyman, Most of the people she talk to believe in the Candyman. When Helen play the game, she soon wish she didn't as Candyman end up framing her each death he cause and no one believes that she telling truth. I am not a fan of Candyman at all, I just do not find him scary all, the no of this scared him or it's did not even gross me out or even creep me out at all. However the story was good and the movie did not bore the hell out him, it was in-rusting for the whole movie and the movie was really good acting from everyone in this movie. 5 out of 10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Maybe the classiest slasher film ever conceived
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Red-Barracuda
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Candyman may very well be the most intelligent film to emerge from the slasher genre. Like A Nightmare On Elm Street before it, it has a supernatural killer from a netherworld who was killed by a mob of people and now comes back to the real world to enact a terrible revenge. However, where Freddie Krueger was a vile paedophile child killer, the Candyman was a black man killed for forming a sexual relationship with a white girl. So, a significant difference is that this is a slasher villain with a genuinely tragic back-story; he is a killer who is at once terrifying and poetic. This is one of the things that makes this film a somewhat unusual one of its type. It has a great sense of place too. The cold-looking Chicago setting is ideal, with the scenes in the projects especially well used. This aspect allows the movie to have an unexpected social-realist angle. The comparison between the squalor of the poor block with the one inhabited by the rich is done in an effective way. The social commentary isn't delivered in a ham-fisted way; it is just part of the story and seems quite natural. But of course this is a slasher film so how does it fare on that level? Well there are a number of gore-drenched scenes and several effective shock moments. The horror part of the film is certainly handled very well and it does have an effective and quite original killer. It has fine production values too. The haunting aerial photography is beautiful, while the score from Philip Glass is very evocative. Acting is universally good. Virginia Madsen as the principal character is great, while Tony Todd as the Candyman provides just the perfect balance of menace and melancholia. Candyman is a slasher film that offers up something different and, dare I say it, has some class. It's a very well executed horror film that also has other things to say as well. It's one of the strongest horror movies from the 1990's.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This 2 decade old Candy is still pretty sweet...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    oneguyrambling
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Time seems to have gone past Candyman but I remember when it was released in Australia in early 90s it was pretty far out stuff. A tall skinny black guy with a gruff voice gutting people with his hook hand was shocking back then  now we have the various tortures of Saw and Hostel. A pretty (being generous) blonde woman as the target of the baddie wasn't too prevalent (yeah-yeah Halloween!)  now it seems once you're a woman rated higher than an "8" you're practically assigned your own psychopathic serial killer The woman in this case is Sharon Stone-lite (ironically not where weight is concerned) Helen (Virginia Madsen), Tony Todd plays the titular Sugary Psycho that menaces her and her study-buddy Bernadette, among many others. Legend has it that the Candyman was the son of a slave who died badly after being tortured bees and other nastiness were involved after he had the temerity to nail the slave-owner's daughter. To summon the undead Candyman is simple, gaze into a mirror and repeat his name 5 times and he will appear instantly to well gut you like a fish if the movie is right, (why you would want this I'm not sure). The specifics of this seem to change a little depending on circumstances: - In one scene two people split the Candyman duties, splitting the 5 repeats between them he appears anyway. This would lead me to believe that every time you say Candyman to a mirror is a little like Russian roulette  as 4 other people could have said it once each elsewhere. - Further to this if you try to be clever and say it 4 times before chickening out depending on the count he could appear at any point in your sequence. - In some scenes Candy appears instantaneously, in others he seems to take a raincheck and pops up later. I guess there are either many people calling on him or the man is just busy doing other things Which could mean this is a chore to old Sweetums, and being summoned is like a doorbell; "AGAIN, I just finished killing two teens in Miami! Won't you guys give me 5 minutes to clean my hook? " Speculation and wonderment aside the mythology has become folklore in the local area where Helen and Bernadette are writing a paper on *DRUM ROLL Please!* Urban legends. This takes them to Cabrini Green, an urban ghetto area where word has it Candyman resides, after some faked contacts Helen writes off the legend as a fake. Not so fast Helen As people near and dear to Helen start dropping like flies in various bloody dismembered puddles, leaving her on the scene the investigators assume she had something to do with things and question her. Each subsequent step seems to implicate even more, and as she protests her innocence still more Candyman contacts and twists ensure she remains a suspect, and the police and her husband start to wonder if she might just be 110% nuts. There is some good simple music in Candyman which lends a bit of class to proceedings, including an effective piano loop that is instantly familiar when you hear it, some gore that may have been extreme in the 90s but hardly raises an eyebrow today, and it is always interesting to watch a "period piece" where almost everyone smokes and telephones still have cords. This year Natalie Portman put in a gonzo performance as the crizzazy Nena in Black Swan and was lauded for it. But really all she did was pretend to see things, scratch non-existent itches, yell a little and let CGI do most of the rest. As Helen Virginia Madsen gets her gear off a few times, fast-tracks a descent into insanity, emerges from several scenes covered in blood and bits of people, loses her hair and at times acts like a grade A looney. I see both Black Swan and Candyman as equally ludicrous yet one is being seen as somewhat visionary while Candyman was written off as just another slasher film. I guarantee in 10 years no-one will be studying Black Swan as a classic of the modern era Candyman is certainly no classic but here I am nigh 20 years later and it is still at least enjoyable. Final Rating  6 / 10. 20 year old Candy is probably not going to be as tasty as when it was new, but it still has a little flavour and is at least satisfying.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Candyman (1992)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SnakesOnAnAfricanPlain
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Candyman is one of those films I really should have seen by now. I remember the trailer on the Cinema Club trailer reel from a wide selection of videos I owned in the mid 90's. Anyway, I finally saw it and it was great horror. I forgot you could make powerful slasher movies and keep the teens well away. The movie is all about myths and how they can spread and take control. These days myths spread world wide and at a greater rate, thanks to the internet. Candyman really allows you to feel emotions for these characters. Madsen isn't going crazy, but we can't blame people for thinking she is. Tony Todd has a very dominating screen presence, not to mention a powerful voice. The kills all seem necessary in this film, as each one has an impact on our protagonist and the world she inhabits. Finally, we have Phillip Glass' incredible score, which adds a bizarre and haunting atmosphere to the movie. Great horror at an early 90's pace.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    First Great Horror Movie of the 90's
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    slasherstudios
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Helen Lyle is a graduate student conducting research for her thesis on urban legends. While interviewing freshmen about their superstitions, she hears about a local legend known as Candyman. The legend contains many thematic elements similar to the most well known urban legends, including endangered babysitters, spirits who appear in mirrors when fatally summoned, and maniac killers with unnatural deformities. The legend states that while Candyman was the son of a slave, he nevertheless became a well known artist. Yet, after falling in love with a white woman who becomes pregnant, Candyman is chased through the plantation and when caught, has his drawing hand cut off and replaced with a hook. He is then smeared with honey (prompting the locals to chant 'Candyman' a total of 5 times- hence the 'say his name 5 times into the mirror'), stolen from a nearby apiary, and the bees sting him to death. The legend also claims that Candyman is summoned by anyone who looks into a mirror and chants his name five times (similar to the Bloody Mary folkloric tale). Summoning him often costs the individual their own life. Later that evening, Helen and her friend Bernadette jokingly call Candyman's name into the mirror in Helen's bathroom but nothing happens. While conducting her research, Helen enters the notorious gang-ridden Cabrini-Green housing project, the site of a recent unsolved murder. There she meets Anne-Marie McCoy, one of the residents, as well as a young boy named Jake, who tells her a disturbing story of a child who was horribly mutilated in a public restroom near the projects, supposedly by Candyman. While exploring the run-down restroom, Helen is attacked by a gang member carrying a hook who has taken the Candyman moniker as his own to enhance his own street credibility by associating himself with the legend. Helen survives the assault and is able to later identify her attacker to the police. Helen later returns to school but hears a voice calling her name as she walks through a parking garage. Another man she encounters states he is the Candyman of the urban legend and because of Helen's disbelief in him, he must now prove to her that he is real. Helen blacks out and wakes up in Anne-Marie's apartment, covered in blood. Anne-Marie, whose Rottweiler has been decapitated and whose baby is also missing, attacks Helen and she is forced to defend herself from Anne-Marie using a meat cleaver. The police then enter the apartment and arrest Helen. Is Helen going crazy or will Candyman come for her next? Three words adequately describe "Candyman": Scary. As. Hell. I was twelve years old when I saw the movie for the first time and it hasn't left my mind since. From the haunting Phillip Glass score to the uncompromising promises by both Tony Todd as Candyman and Virginia Madsen (who has never looked better) as Helen, everything about this movie is sensationally scary. Madsen, in particular, seems to relish playing against time and causes the audience to be sympathetic with her character when a lesser actress would have just come across as annoying. A cheap "Carrie" rip-off of an ending is the only false beat in this superb thriller from one of the masters of the horror genre, Clive Barker.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Best Horror Film of 1992
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    robert haynes
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Candyman is undoubtedly the best horror film of 1992. Released with very little fanfare the film became a surprise hit and I remember why. Having been one of those lucky individuals to see the film five, yes five times on its initial theatrical run, I think it's safe to say that I'm a fan. The ability that director Bernard Rose has to create a palpable sense of dread is evident in every frame of this film. This is what true horror is all about. Candyman is extremely suspenseful and intensely creepy, in fact just writing about it I can already feel the hairs on my arms standing up again. It's that affecting! Virginia Madsen is superbly cast as Helen, a flawed but likable heroine the audience cares deeply about. Her journey into madness is one that we empathize with every brutal step of the way. You don't want bad things to happen to her because you've fallen in love with her. How Madsen wasn't nominated for an Oscar for this performance is still beyond me. Tony Todd is also an antihero with a personality and a rich one at that. The film is violent but the gore never becomes comedic. It sets the perfect tone of brutality. Candyman cannot come more highly recommended. It's a truly terrifying psychological art-house horror with standout performances and a deeply haunting score by Philip Glass. Horror films DO NOT get any better than this. Prepared to be scared. A terrific 10!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bees out of hive
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leoperu
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An above-average romantic horror movie with implausible, inconsistent storyline,atmospheric,but unnecessarily gory, adorned with fine photography of city textures (Anthony Richmond was the man behind the camera in three of the four best movies by Nicolas Roeg - but Rose isn't Roeg, so we cannot expect any visionary qualities here), music of Philip Glass, and charms of Virginia Madsen (it seems to me that whoever did admire her in the movie should avoid bonus interviews where an artificial puppet takes the place of our gorgeous go-getter turned victim). The makers let us know that Chicago instead of Liverpool was the right choice ; I wouldn't be so sure of that. And the bees.... well, they are simply out of the hive here.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Easy to Call This One a Classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Candyman (1992) *** (out of 4) Grad student Helen Lyle (Virginia Madsen) is doing research on why certain groups of people blame their violence on mythical legends when she comes across the name Candyman (Tony Todd). Soon Helen realizes that this figure with a hook for a hand is more than just a legend. CANDYMAN certainly stands as one of the best horror films of the 90s as it contains a great story, a creepy atmosphere, some great performances and of course many chilling moments. The story from Clive Barker is certainly something interesting to just think about because the idea of what an urban legend is and how it plays a part in people's lives who believe it is the best thing about the movie. I really loved how director Bernard Rose kept the viewing guessing at all times as to what was going on. Was it really Candyman doing all the killing or had Helen simply lost her mind while doing the research? It certainly helps that you've got such great actors in the leading roles and especially with Madsen. She does an extremely good job in the lead as she really makes you believe all of this stuff that is going on and it's a pretty deep character and the actress has no problems with it. Todd and that iconic voice makes Candyman one of the most memorable screen villains in horror history and that calm and cool nature of the actor really comes across extremely creepy. The film also features a very good score from Philip Glass and of course there's the striking images. I think the film does get a bit too long in the final act but there are just so many effective moments and killings here that you can't help but call this a classic of the genre.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dare You Say His Name, Dare You Watch This Film...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Juliet Raven
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Rarely do I give a film the golden ten rating. As much as I love films of all types, it takes something particularly memorable to get the coveted 10 stars. Candyman is one of those films that manages the impossible. It's clever in that we see an atypical setting, the urban streets, the high towers, the estates. It looks grim and feels it. Then we get into the arc of the story and everything changes to a degree. Yes the places shown remain the same but the story of the Candyman is enough to keep us transfixed, add to that some strong performances and it's a world we've never seen before. Even more powerful for the fact that the essential story itself derives partially from the urban legend of Bloody Mary. Plot: Helen Lyle (Virginia Madsen) is a graduate student who is conducting research for her own thesis on Urban Legends. Neither her nor her friend believing the story of the Candyman decide to jokingly say his name 5 times in Helen's mirror. Nothing happens. Yet soon after things go wrong and Helen realises some urban legends are anything but. Of the strongest abilities that this film possesses in heaps is the acting. From Xander Berkeley to Madsen and finally to Todd, the acting is of the highest quality and no one feels pushed into the shadows throughout this film. Yet it is primarily Madsen and Todd who stand out. Madsen was an actress I never really took much notice of until this film. She stands firm as the sole heroine trying to deal with the trauma and not buckling under the horror of it all. She carries that wonderful line between innocence and sharpness. Never too harsh, never too vanilla. She manages to be a great combination of both and come out fighting against the Candyman. It's hard not to love her in this role and furthermore not to love the scene at the end with the fire. It's heartbreaking for a multitude of reasons and why I adore her in this role. And then there was Tony Todd. The man, as we know, oozes charisma. He's recognisable for that voice alone but people have a tendency to forget he is not just that, he is also an actor of great skill. Able to take the simplest scene, just one line and instantly make it his own. When we first see him in the aforementioned role he does not disappoint. It's an eerie mixture of Gothic meets horror with that dash of elegance as he manages to make a monster who actually is compassionate and who we don't initially hate. He is the Candyman. The special effects. I heard a lot of negative on this and I'm not sure why if I am honest. If you watch this for the effects alone you miss the point of the film as they prove only part of the cog. For that matter though I thought they were done with grace and looked beautiful against the bland background. In a world where grey seems the prominent colour, the blood sticks out with the richness of its colour. To do it in such a setting was a clever little nod and adds to the overall tone of the film. Personally I liked Bernard Rose's score. It's charming and creepy without being ostentatious and those glassy moments really do send chills. Where the score reaches heights is when it begins seeping in just before the Candyman turns up. With the lights down, the darkness wrapping you and nothing but your imagination it leads your mind into a very twisted place. It's how Gothic horror should be. Not too much emphasis is placed on the special FX alone, a staple in most horror films, instead care is given to the characters and where they will go as the film draws on. It doesn't play it safe which I respect instead going for the jugular. And despite the ending being something we have seen before it doesn't suffer in the premise of the film. If anything the final scene adds another jolt to the scares born into this film. My only minor complaint is when Helen finds her other half setting up home with a new girlfriend after she was confined to the hospital. Not upsetting for him, despite Berkeley's obnoxious character, yet rather because you truly feel for the character of Helen. After everything she has endured you'd think there'd be some small hope on the horizon but it doesn't happen. Everything bad happens and yes it culminates in one of the most tragic scenes in Candyman. However that complaint could as much be a plus since you realise the depth of the acting and how she pulls you in, that itself is no small feat. And this is why Candyman is my baby. For every horror movie that ever has been, ever will be, this is my love. It encompasses the morals and fabrics of society into one and takes our preconceptions, throwing them away. Candyman is a wonderful horror film that deserves more recognition and I hope it gets it. I urge everyone to see this and embrace the beauty of Candyman. Lest you say his name and he comes for you...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Scary!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Gene Smith
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm surprised this movie isn't more famous or more looked up to compared to other horror movies there are out there, because I thought this movie was great! Virginia Madsen was great in this movie but the evil Candyman was just a great character, well acted, and a great, scary villain for a horror movie. The soundtrack is creepy and awesome and I remember this being one of the few horror movies that really really scared me back when I watched it. The sequels that I saw (there are at least three Candy Man movies that I have seen) were not nearly as good as this first one but it's a great movie for fans of horror films and you should definitely see it! It's a very original story and idea.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This didn't do anything for me
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    atinder
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A urban legend about Candyman is told to Helen, If you say he name 5 times in front of the mirror, it will be hide you and kill you. Helen who is doing a story about Candyman, Most of the people she talk to believe in the Candyman. When Helen play the game, she soon wish she didn't as Candyman end up framing her each death he cause and no one believes that she telling truth. I am not a fan of Candyman at all, I just do not find him scary all, the no of this scared him or it's did not even gross me out or even creep me out at all. However the story was good and the movie did not bore the hell out him, it was in-rusting for the whole movie and the movie was really good acting from everyone in this movie. 5 out of 10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Maybe the classiest slasher film ever conceived
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Red-Barracuda
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Candyman may very well be the most intelligent film to emerge from the slasher genre. Like A Nightmare On Elm Street before it, it has a supernatural killer from a netherworld who was killed by a mob of people and now comes back to the real world to enact a terrible revenge. However, where Freddie Krueger was a vile paedophile child killer, the Candyman was a black man killed for forming a sexual relationship with a white girl. So, a significant difference is that this is a slasher villain with a genuinely tragic back-story; he is a killer who is at once terrifying and poetic. This is one of the things that makes this film a somewhat unusual one of its type. It has a great sense of place too. The cold-looking Chicago setting is ideal, with the scenes in the projects especially well used. This aspect allows the movie to have an unexpected social-realist angle. The comparison between the squalor of the poor block with the one inhabited by the rich is done in an effective way. The social commentary isn't delivered in a ham-fisted way; it is just part of the story and seems quite natural. But of course this is a slasher film so how does it fare on that level? Well there are a number of gore-drenched scenes and several effective shock moments. The horror part of the film is certainly handled very well and it does have an effective and quite original killer. It has fine production values too. The haunting aerial photography is beautiful, while the score from Philip Glass is very evocative. Acting is universally good. Virginia Madsen as the principal character is great, while Tony Todd as the Candyman provides just the perfect balance of menace and melancholia. Candyman is a slasher film that offers up something different and, dare I say it, has some class. It's a very well executed horror film that also has other things to say as well. It's one of the strongest horror movies from the 1990's.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This 2 decade old Candy is still pretty sweet...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    oneguyrambling
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Time seems to have gone past Candyman but I remember when it was released in Australia in early 90s it was pretty far out stuff. A tall skinny black guy with a gruff voice gutting people with his hook hand was shocking back then  now we have the various tortures of Saw and Hostel. A pretty (being generous) blonde woman as the target of the baddie wasn't too prevalent (yeah-yeah Halloween!)  now it seems once you're a woman rated higher than an "8" you're practically assigned your own psychopathic serial killer The woman in this case is Sharon Stone-lite (ironically not where weight is concerned) Helen (Virginia Madsen), Tony Todd plays the titular Sugary Psycho that menaces her and her study-buddy Bernadette, among many others. Legend has it that the Candyman was the son of a slave who died badly after being tortured bees and other nastiness were involved after he had the temerity to nail the slave-owner's daughter. To summon the undead Candyman is simple, gaze into a mirror and repeat his name 5 times and he will appear instantly to well gut you like a fish if the movie is right, (why you would want this I'm not sure). The specifics of this seem to change a little depending on circumstances: - In one scene two people split the Candyman duties, splitting the 5 repeats between them he appears anyway. This would lead me to believe that every time you say Candyman to a mirror is a little like Russian roulette  as 4 other people could have said it once each elsewhere. - Further to this if you try to be clever and say it 4 times before chickening out depending on the count he could appear at any point in your sequence. - In some scenes Candy appears instantaneously, in others he seems to take a raincheck and pops up later. I guess there are either many people calling on him or the man is just busy doing other things Which could mean this is a chore to old Sweetums, and being summoned is like a doorbell; "AGAIN, I just finished killing two teens in Miami! Won't you guys give me 5 minutes to clean my hook? " Speculation and wonderment aside the mythology has become folklore in the local area where Helen and Bernadette are writing a paper on *DRUM ROLL Please!* Urban legends. This takes them to Cabrini Green, an urban ghetto area where word has it Candyman resides, after some faked contacts Helen writes off the legend as a fake. Not so fast Helen As people near and dear to Helen start dropping like flies in various bloody dismembered puddles, leaving her on the scene the investigators assume she had something to do with things and question her. Each subsequent step seems to implicate even more, and as she protests her innocence still more Candyman contacts and twists ensure she remains a suspect, and the police and her husband start to wonder if she might just be 110% nuts. There is some good simple music in Candyman which lends a bit of class to proceedings, including an effective piano loop that is instantly familiar when you hear it, some gore that may have been extreme in the 90s but hardly raises an eyebrow today, and it is always interesting to watch a "period piece" where almost everyone smokes and telephones still have cords. This year Natalie Portman put in a gonzo performance as the crizzazy Nena in Black Swan and was lauded for it. But really all she did was pretend to see things, scratch non-existent itches, yell a little and let CGI do most of the rest. As Helen Virginia Madsen gets her gear off a few times, fast-tracks a descent into insanity, emerges from several scenes covered in blood and bits of people, loses her hair and at times acts like a grade A looney. I see both Black Swan and Candyman as equally ludicrous yet one is being seen as somewhat visionary while Candyman was written off as just another slasher film. I guarantee in 10 years no-one will be studying Black Swan as a classic of the modern era Candyman is certainly no classic but here I am nigh 20 years later and it is still at least enjoyable. Final Rating  6 / 10. 20 year old Candy is probably not going to be as tasty as when it was new, but it still has a little flavour and is at least satisfying.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Candyman (1992)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SnakesOnAnAfricanPlain
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Candyman is one of those films I really should have seen by now. I remember the trailer on the Cinema Club trailer reel from a wide selection of videos I owned in the mid 90's. Anyway, I finally saw it and it was great horror. I forgot you could make powerful slasher movies and keep the teens well away. The movie is all about myths and how they can spread and take control. These days myths spread world wide and at a greater rate, thanks to the internet. Candyman really allows you to feel emotions for these characters. Madsen isn't going crazy, but we can't blame people for thinking she is. Tony Todd has a very dominating screen presence, not to mention a powerful voice. The kills all seem necessary in this film, as each one has an impact on our protagonist and the world she inhabits. Finally, we have Phillip Glass' incredible score, which adds a bizarre and haunting atmosphere to the movie. Great horror at an early 90's pace.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    First Great Horror Movie of the 90's
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    slasherstudios
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Helen Lyle is a graduate student conducting research for her thesis on urban legends. While interviewing freshmen about their superstitions, she hears about a local legend known as Candyman. The legend contains many thematic elements similar to the most well known urban legends, including endangered babysitters, spirits who appear in mirrors when fatally summoned, and maniac killers with unnatural deformities. The legend states that while Candyman was the son of a slave, he nevertheless became a well known artist. Yet, after falling in love with a white woman who becomes pregnant, Candyman is chased through the plantation and when caught, has his drawing hand cut off and replaced with a hook. He is then smeared with honey (prompting the locals to chant 'Candyman' a total of 5 times- hence the 'say his name 5 times into the mirror'), stolen from a nearby apiary, and the bees sting him to death. The legend also claims that Candyman is summoned by anyone who looks into a mirror and chants his name five times (similar to the Bloody Mary folkloric tale). Summoning him often costs the individual their own life. Later that evening, Helen and her friend Bernadette jokingly call Candyman's name into the mirror in Helen's bathroom but nothing happens. While conducting her research, Helen enters the notorious gang-ridden Cabrini-Green housing project, the site of a recent unsolved murder. There she meets Anne-Marie McCoy, one of the residents, as well as a young boy named Jake, who tells her a disturbing story of a child who was horribly mutilated in a public restroom near the projects, supposedly by Candyman. While exploring the run-down restroom, Helen is attacked by a gang member carrying a hook who has taken the Candyman moniker as his own to enhance his own street credibility by associating himself with the legend. Helen survives the assault and is able to later identify her attacker to the police. Helen later returns to school but hears a voice calling her name as she walks through a parking garage. Another man she encounters states he is the Candyman of the urban legend and because of Helen's disbelief in him, he must now prove to her that he is real. Helen blacks out and wakes up in Anne-Marie's apartment, covered in blood. Anne-Marie, whose Rottweiler has been decapitated and whose baby is also missing, attacks Helen and she is forced to defend herself from Anne-Marie using a meat cleaver. The police then enter the apartment and arrest Helen. Is Helen going crazy or will Candyman come for her next? Three words adequately describe "Candyman": Scary. As. Hell. I was twelve years old when I saw the movie for the first time and it hasn't left my mind since. From the haunting Phillip Glass score to the uncompromising promises by both Tony Todd as Candyman and Virginia Madsen (who has never looked better) as Helen, everything about this movie is sensationally scary. Madsen, in particular, seems to relish playing against time and causes the audience to be sympathetic with her character when a lesser actress would have just come across as annoying. A cheap "Carrie" rip-off of an ending is the only false beat in this superb thriller from one of the masters of the horror genre, Clive Barker.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Best Horror Film of 1992
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    robert haynes
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Candyman is undoubtedly the best horror film of 1992. Released with very little fanfare the film became a surprise hit and I remember why. Having been one of those lucky individuals to see the film five, yes five times on its initial theatrical run, I think it's safe to say that I'm a fan. The ability that director Bernard Rose has to create a palpable sense of dread is evident in every frame of this film. This is what true horror is all about. Candyman is extremely suspenseful and intensely creepy, in fact just writing about it I can already feel the hairs on my arms standing up again. It's that affecting! Virginia Madsen is superbly cast as Helen, a flawed but likable heroine the audience cares deeply about. Her journey into madness is one that we empathize with every brutal step of the way. You don't want bad things to happen to her because you've fallen in love with her. How Madsen wasn't nominated for an Oscar for this performance is still beyond me. Tony Todd is also an antihero with a personality and a rich one at that. The film is violent but the gore never becomes comedic. It sets the perfect tone of brutality. Candyman cannot come more highly recommended. It's a truly terrifying psychological art-house horror with standout performances and a deeply haunting score by Philip Glass. Horror films DO NOT get any better than this. Prepared to be scared. A terrific 10!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bees out of hive
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leoperu
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    An above-average romantic horror movie with implausible, inconsistent storyline,atmospheric,but unnecessarily gory, adorned with fine photography of city textures (Anthony Richmond was the man behind the camera in three of the four best movies by Nicolas Roeg - but Rose isn't Roeg, so we cannot expect any visionary qualities here), music of Philip Glass, and charms of Virginia Madsen (it seems to me that whoever did admire her in the movie should avoid bonus interviews where an artificial puppet takes the place of our gorgeous go-getter turned victim). The makers let us know that Chicago instead of Liverpool was the right choice ; I wouldn't be so sure of that. And the bees.... well, they are simply out of the hive here.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Easy to Call This One a Classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael_Elliott
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Candyman (1992) *** (out of 4) Grad student Helen Lyle (Virginia Madsen) is doing research on why certain groups of people blame their violence on mythical legends when she comes across the name Candyman (Tony Todd). Soon Helen realizes that this figure with a hook for a hand is more than just a legend. CANDYMAN certainly stands as one of the best horror films of the 90s as it contains a great story, a creepy atmosphere, some great performances and of course many chilling moments. The story from Clive Barker is certainly something interesting to just think about because the idea of what an urban legend is and how it plays a part in people's lives who believe it is the best thing about the movie. I really loved how director Bernard Rose kept the viewing guessing at all times as to what was going on. Was it really Candyman doing all the killing or had Helen simply lost her mind while doing the research? It certainly helps that you've got such great actors in the leading roles and especially with Madsen. She does an extremely good job in the lead as she really makes you believe all of this stuff that is going on and it's a pretty deep character and the actress has no problems with it. Todd and that iconic voice makes Candyman one of the most memorable screen villains in horror history and that calm and cool nature of the actor really comes across extremely creepy. The film also features a very good score from Philip Glass and of course there's the striking images. I think the film does get a bit too long in the final act but there are just so many effective moments and killings here that you can't help but call this a classic of the genre.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Dare You Say His Name, Dare You Watch This Film...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Juliet Raven
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Rarely do I give a film the golden ten rating. As much as I love films of all types, it takes something particularly memorable to get the coveted 10 stars. Candyman is one of those films that manages the impossible. It's clever in that we see an atypical setting, the urban streets, the high towers, the estates. It looks grim and feels it. Then we get into the arc of the story and everything changes to a degree. Yes the places shown remain the same but the story of the Candyman is enough to keep us transfixed, add to that some strong performances and it's a world we've never seen before. Even more powerful for the fact that the essential story itself derives partially from the urban legend of Bloody Mary. Plot: Helen Lyle (Virginia Madsen) is a graduate student who is conducting research for her own thesis on Urban Legends. Neither her nor her friend believing the story of the Candyman decide to jokingly say his name 5 times in Helen's mirror. Nothing happens. Yet soon after things go wrong and Helen realises some urban legends are anything but. Of the strongest abilities that this film possesses in heaps is the acting. From Xander Berkeley to Madsen and finally to Todd, the acting is of the highest quality and no one feels pushed into the shadows throughout this film. Yet it is primarily Madsen and Todd who stand out. Madsen was an actress I never really took much notice of until this film. She stands firm as the sole heroine trying to deal with the trauma and not buckling under the horror of it all. She carries that wonderful line between innocence and sharpness. Never too harsh, never too vanilla. She manages to be a great combination of both and come out fighting against the Candyman. It's hard not to love her in this role and furthermore not to love the scene at the end with the fire. It's heartbreaking for a multitude of reasons and why I adore her in this role. And then there was Tony Todd. The man, as we know, oozes charisma. He's recognisable for that voice alone but people have a tendency to forget he is not just that, he is also an actor of great skill. Able to take the simplest scene, just one line and instantly make it his own. When we first see him in the aforementioned role he does not disappoint. It's an eerie mixture of Gothic meets horror with that dash of elegance as he manages to make a monster who actually is compassionate and who we don't initially hate. He is the Candyman. The special effects. I heard a lot of negative on this and I'm not sure why if I am honest. If you watch this for the effects alone you miss the point of the film as they prove only part of the cog. For that matter though I thought they were done with grace and looked beautiful against the bland background. In a world where grey seems the prominent colour, the blood sticks out with the richness of its colour. To do it in such a setting was a clever little nod and adds to the overall tone of the film. Personally I liked Bernard Rose's score. It's charming and creepy without being ostentatious and those glassy moments really do send chills. Where the score reaches heights is when it begins seeping in just before the Candyman turns up. With the lights down, the darkness wrapping you and nothing but your imagination it leads your mind into a very twisted place. It's how Gothic horror should be. Not too much emphasis is placed on the special FX alone, a staple in most horror films, instead care is given to the characters and where they will go as the film draws on. It doesn't play it safe which I respect instead going for the jugular. And despite the ending being something we have seen before it doesn't suffer in the premise of the film. If anything the final scene adds another jolt to the scares born into this film. My only minor complaint is when Helen finds her other half setting up home with a new girlfriend after she was confined to the hospital. Not upsetting for him, despite Berkeley's obnoxious character, yet rather because you truly feel for the character of Helen. After everything she has endured you'd think there'd be some small hope on the horizon but it doesn't happen. Everything bad happens and yes it culminates in one of the most tragic scenes in Candyman. However that complaint could as much be a plus since you realise the depth of the acting and how she pulls you in, that itself is no small feat. And this is why Candyman is my baby. For every horror movie that ever has been, ever will be, this is my love. It encompasses the morals and fabrics of society into one and takes our preconceptions, throwing them away. Candyman is a wonderful horror film that deserves more recognition and I hope it gets it. I urge everyone to see this and embrace the beauty of Candyman. Lest you say his name and he comes for you...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Scary!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Gene Smith
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm surprised this movie isn't more famous or more looked up to compared to other horror movies there are out there, because I thought this movie was great! Virginia Madsen was great in this movie but the evil Candyman was just a great character, well acted, and a great, scary villain for a horror movie. The soundtrack is creepy and awesome and I remember this being one of the few horror movies that really really scared me back when I watched it. The sequels that I saw (there are at least three Candy Man movies that I have seen) were not nearly as good as this first one but it's a great movie for fans of horror films and you should definitely see it! It's a very original story and idea.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This didn't do anything for me
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    atinder
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A urban legend about Candyman is told to Helen, If you say he name 5 times in front of the mirror, it will be hide you and kill you. Helen who is doing a story about Candyman, Most of the people she talk to believe in the Candyman. When Helen play the game, she soon wish she didn't as Candyman end up framing her each death he cause and no one believes that she telling truth. I am not a fan of Candyman at all, I just do not find him scary all, the no of this scared him or it's did not even gross me out or even creep me out at all. However the story was good and the movie did not bore the hell out him, it was in-rusting for the whole movie and the movie was really good acting from everyone in this movie. 5 out of 10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Maybe the classiest slasher film ever conceived
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Red-Barracuda
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Candyman may very well be the most intelligent film to emerge from the slasher genre. Like A Nightmare On Elm Street before it, it has a supernatural killer from a netherworld who was killed by a mob of people and now comes back to the real world to enact a terrible revenge. However, where Freddie Krueger was a vile paedophile child killer, the Candyman was a black man killed for forming a sexual relationship with a white girl. So, a significant difference is that this is a slasher villain with a genuinely tragic back-story; he is a killer who is at once terrifying and poetic. This is one of the things that makes this film a somewhat unusual one of its type. It has a great sense of place too. The cold-looking Chicago setting is ideal, with the scenes in the projects especially well used. This aspect allows the movie to have an unexpected social-realist angle. The comparison between the squalor of the poor block with the one inhabited by the rich is done in an effective way. The social commentary isn't delivered in a ham-fisted way; it is just part of the story and seems quite natural. But of course this is a slasher film so how does it fare on that level? Well there are a number of gore-drenched scenes and several effective shock moments. The horror part of the film is certainly handled very well and it does have an effective and quite original killer. It has fine production values too. The haunting aerial photography is beautiful, while the score from Philip Glass is very evocative. Acting is universally good. Virginia Madsen as the principal character is great, while Tony Todd as the Candyman provides just the perfect balance of menace and melancholia. Candyman is a slasher film that offers up something different and, dare I say it, has some class. It's a very well executed horror film that also has other things to say as well. It's one of the strongest horror movies from the 1990's.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This 2 decade old Candy is still pretty sweet...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    oneguyrambling
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Time seems to have gone past Candyman but I remember when it was released in Australia in early 90s it was pretty far out stuff. A tall skinny black guy with a gruff voice gutting people with his hook hand was shocking back then  now we have the various tortures of Saw and Hostel. A pretty (being generous) blonde woman as the target of the baddie wasn't too prevalent (yeah-yeah Halloween!)  now it seems once you're a woman rated higher than an "8" you're practically assigned your own psychopathic serial killer The woman in this case is Sharon Stone-lite (ironically not where weight is concerned) Helen (Virginia Madsen), Tony Todd plays the titular Sugary Psycho that menaces her and her study-buddy Bernadette, among many others. Legend has it that the Candyman was the son of a slave who died badly after being tortured bees and other nastiness were involved after he had the temerity to nail the slave-owner's daughter. To summon the undead Candyman is simple, gaze into a mirror and repeat his name 5 times and he will appear instantly to well gut you like a fish if the movie is right, (why you would want this I'm not sure). The specifics of this seem to change a little depending on circumstances: - In one scene two people split the Candyman duties, splitting the 5 repeats between them he appears anyway. This would lead me to believe that every time you say Candyman to a mirror is a little like Russian roulette  as 4 other people could have said it once each elsewhere. - Further to this if you try to be clever and say it 4 times before chickening out depending on the count he could appear at any point in your sequence. - In some scenes Candy appears instantaneously, in others he seems to take a raincheck and pops up later. I guess there are either many people calling on him or the man is just busy doing other things Which could mean this is a chore to old Sweetums, and being summoned is like a doorbell; "AGAIN, I just finished killing two teens in Miami! Won't you guys give me 5 minutes to clean my hook? " Speculation and wonderment aside the mythology has become folklore in the local area where Helen and Bernadette are writing a paper on *DRUM ROLL Please!* Urban legends. This takes them to Cabrini Green, an urban ghetto area where word has it Candyman resides, after some faked contacts Helen writes off the legend as a fake. Not so fast Helen As people near and dear to Helen start dropping like flies in various bloody dismembered puddles, leaving her on the scene the investigators assume she had something to do with things and question her. Each subsequent step seems to implicate even more, and as she protests her innocence still more Candyman contacts and twists ensure she remains a suspect, and the police and her husband start to wonder if she might just be 110% nuts. There is some good simple music in Candyman which lends a bit of class to proceedings, including an effective piano loop that is instantly familiar when you hear it, some gore that may have been extreme in the 90s but hardly raises an eyebrow today, and it is always interesting to watch a "period piece" where almost everyone smokes and telephones still have cords. This year Natalie Portman put in a gonzo performance as the crizzazy Nena in Black Swan and was lauded for it. But really all she did was pretend to see things, scratch non-existent itches, yell a little and let CGI do most of the rest. As Helen Virginia Madsen gets her gear off a few times, fast-tracks a descent into insanity, emerges from several scenes covered in blood and bits of people, loses her hair and at times acts like a grade A looney. I see both Black Swan and Candyman as equally ludicrous yet one is being seen as somewhat visionary while Candyman was written off as just another slasher film. I guarantee in 10 years no-one will be studying Black Swan as a classic of the modern era Candyman is certainly no classic but here I am nigh 20 years later and it is still at least enjoyable. Final Rating  6 / 10. 20 year old Candy is probably not going to be as tasty as when it was new, but it still has a little flavour and is at least satisfying.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Candyman (1992)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SnakesOnAnAfricanPlain
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Candyman is one of those films I really should have seen by now. I remember the trailer on the Cinema Club trailer reel from a wide selection of videos I owned in the mid 90's. Anyway, I finally saw it and it was great horror. I forgot you could make powerful slasher movies and keep the teens well away. The movie is all about myths and how they can spread and take control. These days myths spread world wide and at a greater rate, thanks to the internet. Candyman really allows you to feel emotions for these characters. Madsen isn't going crazy, but we can't blame people for thinking she is. Tony Todd has a very dominating screen presence, not to mention a powerful voice. The kills all seem necessary in this film, as each one has an impact on our protagonist and the world she inhabits. Finally, we have Phillip Glass' incredible score, which adds a bizarre and haunting atmosphere to the movie. Great horror at an early 90's pace.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    First Great Horror Movie of the 90's
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    slasherstudios
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Helen Lyle is a graduate student conducting research for her thesis on urban legends. While interviewing freshmen about their superstitions, she hears about a local legend known as Candyman. The legend contains many thematic elements similar to the most well known urban legends, including endangered babysitters, spirits who appear in mirrors when fatally summoned, and maniac killers with unnatural deformities. The legend states that while Candyman was the son of a slave, he nevertheless became a well known artist. Yet, after falling in love with a white woman who becomes pregnant, Candyman is chased through the plantation and when caught, has his drawing hand cut off and replaced with a hook. He is then smeared with honey (prompting the locals to chant 'Candyman' a total of 5 times- hence the 'say his name 5 times into the mirror'), stolen from a nearby apiary, and the bees sting him to death. The legend also claims that Candyman is summoned by anyone who looks into a mirror and chants his name five times (similar to the Bloody Mary folkloric tale). Summoning him often costs the individual their own life. Later that evening, Helen and her friend Bernadette jokingly call Candyman's name into the mirror in Helen's bathroom but nothing happens. While conducting her research, Helen enters the notorious gang-ridden Cabrini-Green housing project, the site of a recent unsolved murder. There she meets Anne-Marie McCoy, one of the residents, as well as a young boy named Jake, who tells her a disturbing story of a child who was horribly mutilated in a public restroom near the projects, supposedly by Candyman. While exploring the run-down restroom, Helen is attacked by a gang member carrying a hook who has taken the Candyman moniker as his own to enhance his own street credibility by associating himself with the legend. Helen survives the assault and is able to later identify her attacker to the police. Helen later returns to school but hears a voice calling her name as she walks through a parking garage. Another man she encounters states he is the Candyman of the urban legend and because of Helen's disbelief in him, he must now prove to her that he is real. Helen blacks out and wakes up in Anne-Marie's apartment, covered in blood. Anne-Marie, whose Rottweiler has been decapitated and whose baby is also missing, attacks Helen and she is forced to defend herself from Anne-Marie using a meat cleaver. The police then enter the apartment and arrest Helen. Is Helen going crazy or will Candyman come for her next? Three words adequately describe "Candyman": Scary. As. Hell. I was twelve years old when I saw the movie for the first time and it hasn't left my mind since. From the haunting Phillip Glass score to the uncompromising promises by both Tony Todd as Candyman and Virginia Madsen (who has never looked better) as Helen, everything about this movie is sensationally scary. Madsen, in particular, seems to relish playing against time and causes the audience to be sympathetic with her character when a lesser actress would have just come across as annoying. A cheap "Carrie" rip-off of an ending is the only false beat in this superb thriller from one of the masters of the horror genre, Clive Barker.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
