<filme>
 <id>
  68
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0109506
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1994
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  O Corvo
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  7.6
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  A man brutally murdered comes back to life as an undead avenger of his and his fianc&eacute;e's murder.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  A poetic guitarist Eric Draven is brought back to life by a crow a year after he and his fianc&eacute;e are murdered. The crow guides him through the land of the living, and leads him to his killers: knife thrower Tin-tin, drugetic Funboy, car buff T-Bird, and the unsophisticated Skank. One by one, Eric gives these thugs a taste of their own medicine. However their leader Top-Dollar, a world-class crime lord who will dispatch his enemies with a Japanese sword and joke about it later, will soon learn the legend of the crow and the secret to the vigilante's invincibility.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Action
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Fantasy
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   crow
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   death
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   the crow
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   halloween
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   revenge
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Alex Proyas
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   James O'Barr
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   David J. Schow
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Brandon Lee
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Michael Wincott
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Rochelle Davis
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Crow
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rachelle Stern
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Crows Revenge This movie begins on a dark night in Detroit. The Crow , Shelly Webster (Sofia Shenas) and Eric Draven (Brandon Lee) are engaged to be married the next day on Devils Night, Halloween, the night of fires, vandalism, and crime. Unfortunately that day never came for them. Shelly was raped and murdered for trying to get a petition to help rid the neighborhood of people that weren't contributing to society and that were making it worse. Eric was also killed. One year after their deaths, Eric came back to life as the crow to seek revenge for Shelly's death. The crow makes Eric somewhat invincible to getting hurt or killed while getting the justice that is deserved. The theme of this film seems to be revenge and justice. I feel the directors of this film, Daniel J. Schow and Alex Proyas, are trying to show that even in the darkest of times and bleakness of the night justice can prevail. One must fight to make it happen though. Although Draven was turned into the crow, he still had limitations to his invincibility. The crow followed Eric around the city and was there at the times that Tin-Tin, Fun Boy and T-Bird were brought to their final doom. If the crow was hurt Eric was inevitably hurt also. Justice doesn't always come easy and it's something we have to be willing to fight for. I'm personally attracted to this film for several reasons. One being the way justice is served, another being the love between Shelly and Eric. Eric loved her so much that he was willing to die for her and bring her death to justice; their love as to die for. This film also has a certain attraction to it because it is somewhat of a thriller. It keeps us on edge and captivated. The darkness and costumes bring a certain mysterious quality to it also. Brandon Lee's skills as an actor also bring an attraction to the film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good Supernatural Thing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    manishnagi
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    what a great movie i watched today . The Crow . I had read the novel i like that so much Now i saw this movie its brilliant , it is awesome Like i said novel it is great work done by John O'Barr . Now movie is is very good adopted The acting of Brandon Lee is awesome , all the fight scenes , martial arts , everything is awesome . i feel sad for Brandon Lee that he died . R.I.P i also like the little girl Rochelle Davis who played Sarah , Her acting is good This film is very good directed an screen played . i like the way story is moving along and all this supernatural thing , It inspires me a lot I had fun watching this movie
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The is my fav movie ever!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ssj-nightwing
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A lot of people that know me know how much I love comic book movies and characters and this is true I do. Bearing in mind comic book movies are getting better and better I just can't shake how totally ninja The Crow is. I love everything about, the simple revenge plot, the dark Gothic feel, the cast, everything. I have also read the graphic novel which this movie was based on! James O' Barr is a genius! If your after a true original before Marvel and DC this is great. Forgot to mention the soundtrack is pretty good too! Burn by the Cure, Nine Inch Nails - Dead Soul and Jane Siberry's It Can't Rain all the time are spot on. Very intrigued to see what they do with the reboot!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    deveraux009-650-383191
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The film portrays a young rock guitarist who comes back from the dead to avenge the murders of himself and his fianc&eacute;e. Even as a kid I always enjoyed watching it, as I found Lee's Crow to be easily watchable and I couldn't help but sympathize with the character, thanks to Lee's performance. He truly shined as the character, and captured what James O' Barr worked hard to create in his graphic novels. The atmosphere of the film was damn perfect, and even though some of the dialogue was a bit hit-and-miss(Mainly Rochelle Davis as Sarah), the cast worked and went great together. Michael Wincott as 'Top Dollar' was easily one of the best villains interpreted on-screen, and had some of the best dialogue and scenes besides Lee. To touch up a bit about Brandon Lee as The Crow, the way Lee portrayed the title character was what made the film so great, with his powerful yet gentle charismatic presence, he made one of the best superheroes to ever hit the screen. The action in the film was alright, but without the film's good performances, it might not have carried as well. The direction of the film was practically flawless, and everything clicked just fine. Alex Proyas as director of the film was a fine choice.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sadness is the Main Character
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tjross-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is a tacit theme of sadness that is so ubiquitous throughout the entire movie that it should have been billed as the main character. It's raised to the next level when you remember that this was Brandon Lee's breakout movie and he died making it. I never read the comic so I do not know if it was true to it, but I do know that this movie had a tone that I've never felt before. Brandon Lee is simply amazing! The set design, writing, and directing are top notch--they truly transport you to the goth underbelly of a place you don't want to be. It will clearly be too violent and dark for many viewers, but if you can get over it, you will experience a brilliant film. i've seen this movie a few times and it gets better every time I see it. My only complaint is that I did not have the luxury of seeing it in a theater.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Genius
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Treyroo
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If the question were put to you, would you "go gently into that good night"? What if you weren't given the choice and, instead, were left with the more grisly task of balancing the scales? Would you take it? It's Mischief Night, or Devil's Night as it's referred to in this film, in Detroit and the night before musician Eric Draven (played by Brandon Lee) and Shelley Webster (played by Sofia Shinas) are to be married. Then, thanks to their efforts to fight eviction for themselves and their fellow tenants, their home is broken into. The invaders toss Draven (Lee) through a window and send him plummeting to the ground three stories below and savage his bride-to-be. The first officer on the scene is Sgt. Albrecht (played by Ernie Hudson) and when Shelley asks about her fianc&eacute;e, he spares her the truth and tells her he's fine. Then, when the latchkey kid that Eric and Shelley have taken under their wing stumbles upon the scene, Albrecht relays the lie once again. The child, Sarah (played by Rochelle Davis who also acts as the film's narrator), sees through the sergeant's reassuring fiction and departs soon after. Flash-forward one year, Sarah is visiting the graveyard where Shelly and Eric have been laid to rest and encounters a crow. After she'd left, the crow begins tapping on Eric's headstone with his beak. Then, that night, Eric emerges from his grave, shaking and traumatized. He returns to the apartment that he and Shelley once shared and finds that it is a ruin of the home he knew. While there, he begins experiencing flashbacks of the night one year before when he lost everything. Seeing the men responsible, who call themselves T-Bird (played by David Patrick Kelly), Tin-Tin (played by Laurence Mason), Funboy (played by Michael Massee), and Skank (played by Angel David). Still reeling from those memories, Eric grabs onto the frame that once held the apartment's only window and swings out and back in. He notices that he's cut himself on remnants on the window but, to his surprise, he heals almost immediately. With this new gift, he dons all black clothes, decorates his face in the style of a harlequin mask that was on the floor of his home, and sets out to seek revenge with the crow as his guide. I cannot adequately express how much I love this movie. The tone, the cinematography, the soundtrack, the antagonists. Everything about this movie is top-drawer. Fans of the graphic novel of the same name that inspired the film say that the master criminal in the film, known as Top Dollar in the novel and not actually given a name in the film, was far more ordinary than the evil genius Michael Wincott portrayed. Other critics say that the death of Brandon Lee gave this film a legacy it didn't earn, much the same way that critics claim Heath Ledger's death before the release of The Dark Knight added anticipation it wouldn't have gotten otherwise. As I was only ten when the film was first released, I was not aware of the film itself or Lee's death until much later. What I will say is that I cannot watch this film enough. Even so, if you haven't seen The Crow, shame on you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I don't know why this movie rated so high. Wast of time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    hdgunners
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I wasted 97 minutes of my life on this crap because of this IMDb rating. But I will advise who hasn't still seen this movie don't waste your time on this crap movie. I really wanted to see and like that movie but honestly speaking while watching the movie i dozed off a few times. Apart from the atmosphere, set design and photography everything is so dull and boring. Acting, screenplay, direction and every other thing about the movie are so poor and mediocre I cant help but to dislike the movie. Editing at some places seems rushed. and From Bruce Lee son you expect at least good action and martial arts skills but well what you get lifeless action and no martial arts. i amaze that i seen the same movie as the other. Awful movie not recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Crow  Revenge from beyond the grave on a human level and emotional
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Avid Climber
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Crow is by now a cult movie. Although it's getting a bit old for some of its special effects, it's still excellent. The soundtrack, especially the music, is exceptional. It's edgy, dark, and the emotions it stirs get you in the guts. It's a mirror image of the story. The revenge theme, certainly isn't new, not even one from beyond the grave, but the angle chosen here, is quite different. It's touching. You get a great mix of action, emotional drama, ghostly romance, and human relations, often dark and twisted, other times simple or basic. The sets are very dark and strongly Gothic. The acting is not perfect, but still strong and just. There are a few mistakes, not big, but at times noticeable, like some bad sound pickups. However, they seem to make the film into some sort of archaic rendition, which really works to its advantage. I recommend it if you don't mind its age.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I'm not sure why this movie is rated so high
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    elemari-365-648550
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Simply put, this movie is very mediocre. The storyline is weak. A rock star and his fianc&eacute; are murdered on Halloween night by a gang of thugs. The rock star then returns from the dead to seek revenge on the murder and rape of his fianc&eacute;. Honestly, this plot screams clich&eacute;. The whole rock star idea is extremely cheesy and just reminds me of the rock band KISS and their dreadful costumes. The acting is decent. I feel that Brandon Lee gives off too much of a "good guy" vibe for his role. Despite being dressed up as a menacing, undead badass seeking revenge, he somehow still gives off the impression that he's a nice guy. The gang thugs seem a bit like they're trying too hard. They seem to act how they think thugs would act instead of acting like thugs. I just didn't buy it. The highlight of this film is the special effects, which were well done for 1994. Even so, they fail to outshine a cheesy plot and mediocre acting. Don't get me wrong, the movie wasn't all bad, but it just wasn't good. The Crow lies out there in the vast gray area of mediocre action films.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The best of the them all
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lagudafuad
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Crow has reached an iconic high in the movie realm, mostly because it was the last movie that Brandon Lee stared him, as he Brandon died on set during the production of the film; his death was due to a gunshot. The gun was supposed to be loaded with blanks, but one life ammunition bullet was lodged in the gun that was then loaded with blanks. His death on set made the movie gross more than the producers could ever imagine and turned this movie to a cult classic. The movie is an adaptation of a comic book series of the same name, that was created by James O'Barr and it tells the tale of the life of Eric (Brandon Lee). Eric and his fianc&eacute;e were attacked at their home, Eric got shot and he was paralyzed, and could only watch as Shelly his fianc&eacute;e is savagely beaten and raped. The attackers finally kill Eric. But a year later Eric is resurrected by a crow, now he hunts the men that killed him and his fianc&eacute;e, Eric is now an undead, unable to be killed or hurt (as long as he stays on course, which is revenge on those who killed him and his fianc&eacute;e). The movie boasts of fast paced action, the movie adaption of the comic is seen by many to be near accurate. The movie's cinematography is engaging as we mostly are moving around with Eric in the night, the camera angles or light feed never make you wish that there were gotten from another shot or you needing more light. Then there is the score, the dark rocky score that brings you into the melancholy mood of Eric as you watch, the movie doesn't at any time take you to a high of good things happening then brings you back to the main dark theme Alex Proyas (the director, and also director of Dark City (1998) and I, Robot) made sure that from the get go of this movie you are introduced to a sad theme, a sad scene, a sad story and it the movie keeps to that till the end. The Crow goes places other hero movies don't want to go, no breather just darkness. The movies special effects were most rewarding and the story is very engaging a fit none of the other sequels after it has been able to accomplish, as more sequels were being released the worse the ratings they were getting, making this movie stand out the more. A remake of this said "untouchable classic" is being done, the argument is will this remake be as good as the original or is it just going to follow the way all the other sequels went. My take on this is, Hollywood filmmakers are now at the end of their rope, going back to remake movies or dragging them into trilogies just to make more money, the remake falls into this suit if you ask me (suit of not having an idea of what movie to do), because such movies like this should never be remade. That said, I will be watching the remake with high hopes, reason being times have changed, 1994 and now that is more than 18 years, enough technological advancement that could not be employed in 1994 will be used in this remake, I just hope it won't suck. www.lagsreviews.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Crow
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rachelle Stern
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Crows Revenge This movie begins on a dark night in Detroit. The Crow , Shelly Webster (Sofia Shenas) and Eric Draven (Brandon Lee) are engaged to be married the next day on Devils Night, Halloween, the night of fires, vandalism, and crime. Unfortunately that day never came for them. Shelly was raped and murdered for trying to get a petition to help rid the neighborhood of people that weren't contributing to society and that were making it worse. Eric was also killed. One year after their deaths, Eric came back to life as the crow to seek revenge for Shelly's death. The crow makes Eric somewhat invincible to getting hurt or killed while getting the justice that is deserved. The theme of this film seems to be revenge and justice. I feel the directors of this film, Daniel J. Schow and Alex Proyas, are trying to show that even in the darkest of times and bleakness of the night justice can prevail. One must fight to make it happen though. Although Draven was turned into the crow, he still had limitations to his invincibility. The crow followed Eric around the city and was there at the times that Tin-Tin, Fun Boy and T-Bird were brought to their final doom. If the crow was hurt Eric was inevitably hurt also. Justice doesn't always come easy and it's something we have to be willing to fight for. I'm personally attracted to this film for several reasons. One being the way justice is served, another being the love between Shelly and Eric. Eric loved her so much that he was willing to die for her and bring her death to justice; their love as to die for. This film also has a certain attraction to it because it is somewhat of a thriller. It keeps us on edge and captivated. The darkness and costumes bring a certain mysterious quality to it also. Brandon Lee's skills as an actor also bring an attraction to the film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good Supernatural Thing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    manishnagi
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    what a great movie i watched today . The Crow . I had read the novel i like that so much Now i saw this movie its brilliant , it is awesome Like i said novel it is great work done by John O'Barr . Now movie is is very good adopted The acting of Brandon Lee is awesome , all the fight scenes , martial arts , everything is awesome . i feel sad for Brandon Lee that he died . R.I.P i also like the little girl Rochelle Davis who played Sarah , Her acting is good This film is very good directed an screen played . i like the way story is moving along and all this supernatural thing , It inspires me a lot I had fun watching this movie
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The is my fav movie ever!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ssj-nightwing
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A lot of people that know me know how much I love comic book movies and characters and this is true I do. Bearing in mind comic book movies are getting better and better I just can't shake how totally ninja The Crow is. I love everything about, the simple revenge plot, the dark Gothic feel, the cast, everything. I have also read the graphic novel which this movie was based on! James O' Barr is a genius! If your after a true original before Marvel and DC this is great. Forgot to mention the soundtrack is pretty good too! Burn by the Cure, Nine Inch Nails - Dead Soul and Jane Siberry's It Can't Rain all the time are spot on. Very intrigued to see what they do with the reboot!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    deveraux009-650-383191
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The film portrays a young rock guitarist who comes back from the dead to avenge the murders of himself and his fianc&eacute;e. Even as a kid I always enjoyed watching it, as I found Lee's Crow to be easily watchable and I couldn't help but sympathize with the character, thanks to Lee's performance. He truly shined as the character, and captured what James O' Barr worked hard to create in his graphic novels. The atmosphere of the film was damn perfect, and even though some of the dialogue was a bit hit-and-miss(Mainly Rochelle Davis as Sarah), the cast worked and went great together. Michael Wincott as 'Top Dollar' was easily one of the best villains interpreted on-screen, and had some of the best dialogue and scenes besides Lee. To touch up a bit about Brandon Lee as The Crow, the way Lee portrayed the title character was what made the film so great, with his powerful yet gentle charismatic presence, he made one of the best superheroes to ever hit the screen. The action in the film was alright, but without the film's good performances, it might not have carried as well. The direction of the film was practically flawless, and everything clicked just fine. Alex Proyas as director of the film was a fine choice.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sadness is the Main Character
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tjross-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is a tacit theme of sadness that is so ubiquitous throughout the entire movie that it should have been billed as the main character. It's raised to the next level when you remember that this was Brandon Lee's breakout movie and he died making it. I never read the comic so I do not know if it was true to it, but I do know that this movie had a tone that I've never felt before. Brandon Lee is simply amazing! The set design, writing, and directing are top notch--they truly transport you to the goth underbelly of a place you don't want to be. It will clearly be too violent and dark for many viewers, but if you can get over it, you will experience a brilliant film. i've seen this movie a few times and it gets better every time I see it. My only complaint is that I did not have the luxury of seeing it in a theater.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Genius
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Treyroo
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If the question were put to you, would you "go gently into that good night"? What if you weren't given the choice and, instead, were left with the more grisly task of balancing the scales? Would you take it? It's Mischief Night, or Devil's Night as it's referred to in this film, in Detroit and the night before musician Eric Draven (played by Brandon Lee) and Shelley Webster (played by Sofia Shinas) are to be married. Then, thanks to their efforts to fight eviction for themselves and their fellow tenants, their home is broken into. The invaders toss Draven (Lee) through a window and send him plummeting to the ground three stories below and savage his bride-to-be. The first officer on the scene is Sgt. Albrecht (played by Ernie Hudson) and when Shelley asks about her fianc&eacute;e, he spares her the truth and tells her he's fine. Then, when the latchkey kid that Eric and Shelley have taken under their wing stumbles upon the scene, Albrecht relays the lie once again. The child, Sarah (played by Rochelle Davis who also acts as the film's narrator), sees through the sergeant's reassuring fiction and departs soon after. Flash-forward one year, Sarah is visiting the graveyard where Shelly and Eric have been laid to rest and encounters a crow. After she'd left, the crow begins tapping on Eric's headstone with his beak. Then, that night, Eric emerges from his grave, shaking and traumatized. He returns to the apartment that he and Shelley once shared and finds that it is a ruin of the home he knew. While there, he begins experiencing flashbacks of the night one year before when he lost everything. Seeing the men responsible, who call themselves T-Bird (played by David Patrick Kelly), Tin-Tin (played by Laurence Mason), Funboy (played by Michael Massee), and Skank (played by Angel David). Still reeling from those memories, Eric grabs onto the frame that once held the apartment's only window and swings out and back in. He notices that he's cut himself on remnants on the window but, to his surprise, he heals almost immediately. With this new gift, he dons all black clothes, decorates his face in the style of a harlequin mask that was on the floor of his home, and sets out to seek revenge with the crow as his guide. I cannot adequately express how much I love this movie. The tone, the cinematography, the soundtrack, the antagonists. Everything about this movie is top-drawer. Fans of the graphic novel of the same name that inspired the film say that the master criminal in the film, known as Top Dollar in the novel and not actually given a name in the film, was far more ordinary than the evil genius Michael Wincott portrayed. Other critics say that the death of Brandon Lee gave this film a legacy it didn't earn, much the same way that critics claim Heath Ledger's death before the release of The Dark Knight added anticipation it wouldn't have gotten otherwise. As I was only ten when the film was first released, I was not aware of the film itself or Lee's death until much later. What I will say is that I cannot watch this film enough. Even so, if you haven't seen The Crow, shame on you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I don't know why this movie rated so high. Wast of time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    hdgunners
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I wasted 97 minutes of my life on this crap because of this IMDb rating. But I will advise who hasn't still seen this movie don't waste your time on this crap movie. I really wanted to see and like that movie but honestly speaking while watching the movie i dozed off a few times. Apart from the atmosphere, set design and photography everything is so dull and boring. Acting, screenplay, direction and every other thing about the movie are so poor and mediocre I cant help but to dislike the movie. Editing at some places seems rushed. and From Bruce Lee son you expect at least good action and martial arts skills but well what you get lifeless action and no martial arts. i amaze that i seen the same movie as the other. Awful movie not recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Crow  Revenge from beyond the grave on a human level and emotional
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Avid Climber
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Crow is by now a cult movie. Although it's getting a bit old for some of its special effects, it's still excellent. The soundtrack, especially the music, is exceptional. It's edgy, dark, and the emotions it stirs get you in the guts. It's a mirror image of the story. The revenge theme, certainly isn't new, not even one from beyond the grave, but the angle chosen here, is quite different. It's touching. You get a great mix of action, emotional drama, ghostly romance, and human relations, often dark and twisted, other times simple or basic. The sets are very dark and strongly Gothic. The acting is not perfect, but still strong and just. There are a few mistakes, not big, but at times noticeable, like some bad sound pickups. However, they seem to make the film into some sort of archaic rendition, which really works to its advantage. I recommend it if you don't mind its age.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I'm not sure why this movie is rated so high
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    elemari-365-648550
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Simply put, this movie is very mediocre. The storyline is weak. A rock star and his fianc&eacute; are murdered on Halloween night by a gang of thugs. The rock star then returns from the dead to seek revenge on the murder and rape of his fianc&eacute;. Honestly, this plot screams clich&eacute;. The whole rock star idea is extremely cheesy and just reminds me of the rock band KISS and their dreadful costumes. The acting is decent. I feel that Brandon Lee gives off too much of a "good guy" vibe for his role. Despite being dressed up as a menacing, undead badass seeking revenge, he somehow still gives off the impression that he's a nice guy. The gang thugs seem a bit like they're trying too hard. They seem to act how they think thugs would act instead of acting like thugs. I just didn't buy it. The highlight of this film is the special effects, which were well done for 1994. Even so, they fail to outshine a cheesy plot and mediocre acting. Don't get me wrong, the movie wasn't all bad, but it just wasn't good. The Crow lies out there in the vast gray area of mediocre action films.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The best of the them all
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lagudafuad
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Crow has reached an iconic high in the movie realm, mostly because it was the last movie that Brandon Lee stared him, as he Brandon died on set during the production of the film; his death was due to a gunshot. The gun was supposed to be loaded with blanks, but one life ammunition bullet was lodged in the gun that was then loaded with blanks. His death on set made the movie gross more than the producers could ever imagine and turned this movie to a cult classic. The movie is an adaptation of a comic book series of the same name, that was created by James O'Barr and it tells the tale of the life of Eric (Brandon Lee). Eric and his fianc&eacute;e were attacked at their home, Eric got shot and he was paralyzed, and could only watch as Shelly his fianc&eacute;e is savagely beaten and raped. The attackers finally kill Eric. But a year later Eric is resurrected by a crow, now he hunts the men that killed him and his fianc&eacute;e, Eric is now an undead, unable to be killed or hurt (as long as he stays on course, which is revenge on those who killed him and his fianc&eacute;e). The movie boasts of fast paced action, the movie adaption of the comic is seen by many to be near accurate. The movie's cinematography is engaging as we mostly are moving around with Eric in the night, the camera angles or light feed never make you wish that there were gotten from another shot or you needing more light. Then there is the score, the dark rocky score that brings you into the melancholy mood of Eric as you watch, the movie doesn't at any time take you to a high of good things happening then brings you back to the main dark theme Alex Proyas (the director, and also director of Dark City (1998) and I, Robot) made sure that from the get go of this movie you are introduced to a sad theme, a sad scene, a sad story and it the movie keeps to that till the end. The Crow goes places other hero movies don't want to go, no breather just darkness. The movies special effects were most rewarding and the story is very engaging a fit none of the other sequels after it has been able to accomplish, as more sequels were being released the worse the ratings they were getting, making this movie stand out the more. A remake of this said "untouchable classic" is being done, the argument is will this remake be as good as the original or is it just going to follow the way all the other sequels went. My take on this is, Hollywood filmmakers are now at the end of their rope, going back to remake movies or dragging them into trilogies just to make more money, the remake falls into this suit if you ask me (suit of not having an idea of what movie to do), because such movies like this should never be remade. That said, I will be watching the remake with high hopes, reason being times have changed, 1994 and now that is more than 18 years, enough technological advancement that could not be employed in 1994 will be used in this remake, I just hope it won't suck. www.lagsreviews.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Crow
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rachelle Stern
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Crows Revenge This movie begins on a dark night in Detroit. The Crow , Shelly Webster (Sofia Shenas) and Eric Draven (Brandon Lee) are engaged to be married the next day on Devils Night, Halloween, the night of fires, vandalism, and crime. Unfortunately that day never came for them. Shelly was raped and murdered for trying to get a petition to help rid the neighborhood of people that weren't contributing to society and that were making it worse. Eric was also killed. One year after their deaths, Eric came back to life as the crow to seek revenge for Shelly's death. The crow makes Eric somewhat invincible to getting hurt or killed while getting the justice that is deserved. The theme of this film seems to be revenge and justice. I feel the directors of this film, Daniel J. Schow and Alex Proyas, are trying to show that even in the darkest of times and bleakness of the night justice can prevail. One must fight to make it happen though. Although Draven was turned into the crow, he still had limitations to his invincibility. The crow followed Eric around the city and was there at the times that Tin-Tin, Fun Boy and T-Bird were brought to their final doom. If the crow was hurt Eric was inevitably hurt also. Justice doesn't always come easy and it's something we have to be willing to fight for. I'm personally attracted to this film for several reasons. One being the way justice is served, another being the love between Shelly and Eric. Eric loved her so much that he was willing to die for her and bring her death to justice; their love as to die for. This film also has a certain attraction to it because it is somewhat of a thriller. It keeps us on edge and captivated. The darkness and costumes bring a certain mysterious quality to it also. Brandon Lee's skills as an actor also bring an attraction to the film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good Supernatural Thing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    manishnagi
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    what a great movie i watched today . The Crow . I had read the novel i like that so much Now i saw this movie its brilliant , it is awesome Like i said novel it is great work done by John O'Barr . Now movie is is very good adopted The acting of Brandon Lee is awesome , all the fight scenes , martial arts , everything is awesome . i feel sad for Brandon Lee that he died . R.I.P i also like the little girl Rochelle Davis who played Sarah , Her acting is good This film is very good directed an screen played . i like the way story is moving along and all this supernatural thing , It inspires me a lot I had fun watching this movie
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The is my fav movie ever!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ssj-nightwing
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A lot of people that know me know how much I love comic book movies and characters and this is true I do. Bearing in mind comic book movies are getting better and better I just can't shake how totally ninja The Crow is. I love everything about, the simple revenge plot, the dark Gothic feel, the cast, everything. I have also read the graphic novel which this movie was based on! James O' Barr is a genius! If your after a true original before Marvel and DC this is great. Forgot to mention the soundtrack is pretty good too! Burn by the Cure, Nine Inch Nails - Dead Soul and Jane Siberry's It Can't Rain all the time are spot on. Very intrigued to see what they do with the reboot!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    deveraux009-650-383191
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The film portrays a young rock guitarist who comes back from the dead to avenge the murders of himself and his fianc&eacute;e. Even as a kid I always enjoyed watching it, as I found Lee's Crow to be easily watchable and I couldn't help but sympathize with the character, thanks to Lee's performance. He truly shined as the character, and captured what James O' Barr worked hard to create in his graphic novels. The atmosphere of the film was damn perfect, and even though some of the dialogue was a bit hit-and-miss(Mainly Rochelle Davis as Sarah), the cast worked and went great together. Michael Wincott as 'Top Dollar' was easily one of the best villains interpreted on-screen, and had some of the best dialogue and scenes besides Lee. To touch up a bit about Brandon Lee as The Crow, the way Lee portrayed the title character was what made the film so great, with his powerful yet gentle charismatic presence, he made one of the best superheroes to ever hit the screen. The action in the film was alright, but without the film's good performances, it might not have carried as well. The direction of the film was practically flawless, and everything clicked just fine. Alex Proyas as director of the film was a fine choice.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sadness is the Main Character
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tjross-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is a tacit theme of sadness that is so ubiquitous throughout the entire movie that it should have been billed as the main character. It's raised to the next level when you remember that this was Brandon Lee's breakout movie and he died making it. I never read the comic so I do not know if it was true to it, but I do know that this movie had a tone that I've never felt before. Brandon Lee is simply amazing! The set design, writing, and directing are top notch--they truly transport you to the goth underbelly of a place you don't want to be. It will clearly be too violent and dark for many viewers, but if you can get over it, you will experience a brilliant film. i've seen this movie a few times and it gets better every time I see it. My only complaint is that I did not have the luxury of seeing it in a theater.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Genius
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Treyroo
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If the question were put to you, would you "go gently into that good night"? What if you weren't given the choice and, instead, were left with the more grisly task of balancing the scales? Would you take it? It's Mischief Night, or Devil's Night as it's referred to in this film, in Detroit and the night before musician Eric Draven (played by Brandon Lee) and Shelley Webster (played by Sofia Shinas) are to be married. Then, thanks to their efforts to fight eviction for themselves and their fellow tenants, their home is broken into. The invaders toss Draven (Lee) through a window and send him plummeting to the ground three stories below and savage his bride-to-be. The first officer on the scene is Sgt. Albrecht (played by Ernie Hudson) and when Shelley asks about her fianc&eacute;e, he spares her the truth and tells her he's fine. Then, when the latchkey kid that Eric and Shelley have taken under their wing stumbles upon the scene, Albrecht relays the lie once again. The child, Sarah (played by Rochelle Davis who also acts as the film's narrator), sees through the sergeant's reassuring fiction and departs soon after. Flash-forward one year, Sarah is visiting the graveyard where Shelly and Eric have been laid to rest and encounters a crow. After she'd left, the crow begins tapping on Eric's headstone with his beak. Then, that night, Eric emerges from his grave, shaking and traumatized. He returns to the apartment that he and Shelley once shared and finds that it is a ruin of the home he knew. While there, he begins experiencing flashbacks of the night one year before when he lost everything. Seeing the men responsible, who call themselves T-Bird (played by David Patrick Kelly), Tin-Tin (played by Laurence Mason), Funboy (played by Michael Massee), and Skank (played by Angel David). Still reeling from those memories, Eric grabs onto the frame that once held the apartment's only window and swings out and back in. He notices that he's cut himself on remnants on the window but, to his surprise, he heals almost immediately. With this new gift, he dons all black clothes, decorates his face in the style of a harlequin mask that was on the floor of his home, and sets out to seek revenge with the crow as his guide. I cannot adequately express how much I love this movie. The tone, the cinematography, the soundtrack, the antagonists. Everything about this movie is top-drawer. Fans of the graphic novel of the same name that inspired the film say that the master criminal in the film, known as Top Dollar in the novel and not actually given a name in the film, was far more ordinary than the evil genius Michael Wincott portrayed. Other critics say that the death of Brandon Lee gave this film a legacy it didn't earn, much the same way that critics claim Heath Ledger's death before the release of The Dark Knight added anticipation it wouldn't have gotten otherwise. As I was only ten when the film was first released, I was not aware of the film itself or Lee's death until much later. What I will say is that I cannot watch this film enough. Even so, if you haven't seen The Crow, shame on you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I don't know why this movie rated so high. Wast of time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    hdgunners
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I wasted 97 minutes of my life on this crap because of this IMDb rating. But I will advise who hasn't still seen this movie don't waste your time on this crap movie. I really wanted to see and like that movie but honestly speaking while watching the movie i dozed off a few times. Apart from the atmosphere, set design and photography everything is so dull and boring. Acting, screenplay, direction and every other thing about the movie are so poor and mediocre I cant help but to dislike the movie. Editing at some places seems rushed. and From Bruce Lee son you expect at least good action and martial arts skills but well what you get lifeless action and no martial arts. i amaze that i seen the same movie as the other. Awful movie not recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Crow  Revenge from beyond the grave on a human level and emotional
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Avid Climber
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Crow is by now a cult movie. Although it's getting a bit old for some of its special effects, it's still excellent. The soundtrack, especially the music, is exceptional. It's edgy, dark, and the emotions it stirs get you in the guts. It's a mirror image of the story. The revenge theme, certainly isn't new, not even one from beyond the grave, but the angle chosen here, is quite different. It's touching. You get a great mix of action, emotional drama, ghostly romance, and human relations, often dark and twisted, other times simple or basic. The sets are very dark and strongly Gothic. The acting is not perfect, but still strong and just. There are a few mistakes, not big, but at times noticeable, like some bad sound pickups. However, they seem to make the film into some sort of archaic rendition, which really works to its advantage. I recommend it if you don't mind its age.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I'm not sure why this movie is rated so high
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    elemari-365-648550
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Simply put, this movie is very mediocre. The storyline is weak. A rock star and his fianc&eacute; are murdered on Halloween night by a gang of thugs. The rock star then returns from the dead to seek revenge on the murder and rape of his fianc&eacute;. Honestly, this plot screams clich&eacute;. The whole rock star idea is extremely cheesy and just reminds me of the rock band KISS and their dreadful costumes. The acting is decent. I feel that Brandon Lee gives off too much of a "good guy" vibe for his role. Despite being dressed up as a menacing, undead badass seeking revenge, he somehow still gives off the impression that he's a nice guy. The gang thugs seem a bit like they're trying too hard. They seem to act how they think thugs would act instead of acting like thugs. I just didn't buy it. The highlight of this film is the special effects, which were well done for 1994. Even so, they fail to outshine a cheesy plot and mediocre acting. Don't get me wrong, the movie wasn't all bad, but it just wasn't good. The Crow lies out there in the vast gray area of mediocre action films.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The best of the them all
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lagudafuad
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Crow has reached an iconic high in the movie realm, mostly because it was the last movie that Brandon Lee stared him, as he Brandon died on set during the production of the film; his death was due to a gunshot. The gun was supposed to be loaded with blanks, but one life ammunition bullet was lodged in the gun that was then loaded with blanks. His death on set made the movie gross more than the producers could ever imagine and turned this movie to a cult classic. The movie is an adaptation of a comic book series of the same name, that was created by James O'Barr and it tells the tale of the life of Eric (Brandon Lee). Eric and his fianc&eacute;e were attacked at their home, Eric got shot and he was paralyzed, and could only watch as Shelly his fianc&eacute;e is savagely beaten and raped. The attackers finally kill Eric. But a year later Eric is resurrected by a crow, now he hunts the men that killed him and his fianc&eacute;e, Eric is now an undead, unable to be killed or hurt (as long as he stays on course, which is revenge on those who killed him and his fianc&eacute;e). The movie boasts of fast paced action, the movie adaption of the comic is seen by many to be near accurate. The movie's cinematography is engaging as we mostly are moving around with Eric in the night, the camera angles or light feed never make you wish that there were gotten from another shot or you needing more light. Then there is the score, the dark rocky score that brings you into the melancholy mood of Eric as you watch, the movie doesn't at any time take you to a high of good things happening then brings you back to the main dark theme Alex Proyas (the director, and also director of Dark City (1998) and I, Robot) made sure that from the get go of this movie you are introduced to a sad theme, a sad scene, a sad story and it the movie keeps to that till the end. The Crow goes places other hero movies don't want to go, no breather just darkness. The movies special effects were most rewarding and the story is very engaging a fit none of the other sequels after it has been able to accomplish, as more sequels were being released the worse the ratings they were getting, making this movie stand out the more. A remake of this said "untouchable classic" is being done, the argument is will this remake be as good as the original or is it just going to follow the way all the other sequels went. My take on this is, Hollywood filmmakers are now at the end of their rope, going back to remake movies or dragging them into trilogies just to make more money, the remake falls into this suit if you ask me (suit of not having an idea of what movie to do), because such movies like this should never be remade. That said, I will be watching the remake with high hopes, reason being times have changed, 1994 and now that is more than 18 years, enough technological advancement that could not be employed in 1994 will be used in this remake, I just hope it won't suck. www.lagsreviews.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Crow
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rachelle Stern
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Crows Revenge This movie begins on a dark night in Detroit. The Crow , Shelly Webster (Sofia Shenas) and Eric Draven (Brandon Lee) are engaged to be married the next day on Devils Night, Halloween, the night of fires, vandalism, and crime. Unfortunately that day never came for them. Shelly was raped and murdered for trying to get a petition to help rid the neighborhood of people that weren't contributing to society and that were making it worse. Eric was also killed. One year after their deaths, Eric came back to life as the crow to seek revenge for Shelly's death. The crow makes Eric somewhat invincible to getting hurt or killed while getting the justice that is deserved. The theme of this film seems to be revenge and justice. I feel the directors of this film, Daniel J. Schow and Alex Proyas, are trying to show that even in the darkest of times and bleakness of the night justice can prevail. One must fight to make it happen though. Although Draven was turned into the crow, he still had limitations to his invincibility. The crow followed Eric around the city and was there at the times that Tin-Tin, Fun Boy and T-Bird were brought to their final doom. If the crow was hurt Eric was inevitably hurt also. Justice doesn't always come easy and it's something we have to be willing to fight for. I'm personally attracted to this film for several reasons. One being the way justice is served, another being the love between Shelly and Eric. Eric loved her so much that he was willing to die for her and bring her death to justice; their love as to die for. This film also has a certain attraction to it because it is somewhat of a thriller. It keeps us on edge and captivated. The darkness and costumes bring a certain mysterious quality to it also. Brandon Lee's skills as an actor also bring an attraction to the film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good Supernatural Thing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    manishnagi
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    what a great movie i watched today . The Crow . I had read the novel i like that so much Now i saw this movie its brilliant , it is awesome Like i said novel it is great work done by John O'Barr . Now movie is is very good adopted The acting of Brandon Lee is awesome , all the fight scenes , martial arts , everything is awesome . i feel sad for Brandon Lee that he died . R.I.P i also like the little girl Rochelle Davis who played Sarah , Her acting is good This film is very good directed an screen played . i like the way story is moving along and all this supernatural thing , It inspires me a lot I had fun watching this movie
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The is my fav movie ever!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ssj-nightwing
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A lot of people that know me know how much I love comic book movies and characters and this is true I do. Bearing in mind comic book movies are getting better and better I just can't shake how totally ninja The Crow is. I love everything about, the simple revenge plot, the dark Gothic feel, the cast, everything. I have also read the graphic novel which this movie was based on! James O' Barr is a genius! If your after a true original before Marvel and DC this is great. Forgot to mention the soundtrack is pretty good too! Burn by the Cure, Nine Inch Nails - Dead Soul and Jane Siberry's It Can't Rain all the time are spot on. Very intrigued to see what they do with the reboot!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    deveraux009-650-383191
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The film portrays a young rock guitarist who comes back from the dead to avenge the murders of himself and his fianc&eacute;e. Even as a kid I always enjoyed watching it, as I found Lee's Crow to be easily watchable and I couldn't help but sympathize with the character, thanks to Lee's performance. He truly shined as the character, and captured what James O' Barr worked hard to create in his graphic novels. The atmosphere of the film was damn perfect, and even though some of the dialogue was a bit hit-and-miss(Mainly Rochelle Davis as Sarah), the cast worked and went great together. Michael Wincott as 'Top Dollar' was easily one of the best villains interpreted on-screen, and had some of the best dialogue and scenes besides Lee. To touch up a bit about Brandon Lee as The Crow, the way Lee portrayed the title character was what made the film so great, with his powerful yet gentle charismatic presence, he made one of the best superheroes to ever hit the screen. The action in the film was alright, but without the film's good performances, it might not have carried as well. The direction of the film was practically flawless, and everything clicked just fine. Alex Proyas as director of the film was a fine choice.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sadness is the Main Character
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tjross-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is a tacit theme of sadness that is so ubiquitous throughout the entire movie that it should have been billed as the main character. It's raised to the next level when you remember that this was Brandon Lee's breakout movie and he died making it. I never read the comic so I do not know if it was true to it, but I do know that this movie had a tone that I've never felt before. Brandon Lee is simply amazing! The set design, writing, and directing are top notch--they truly transport you to the goth underbelly of a place you don't want to be. It will clearly be too violent and dark for many viewers, but if you can get over it, you will experience a brilliant film. i've seen this movie a few times and it gets better every time I see it. My only complaint is that I did not have the luxury of seeing it in a theater.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Genius
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Treyroo
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If the question were put to you, would you "go gently into that good night"? What if you weren't given the choice and, instead, were left with the more grisly task of balancing the scales? Would you take it? It's Mischief Night, or Devil's Night as it's referred to in this film, in Detroit and the night before musician Eric Draven (played by Brandon Lee) and Shelley Webster (played by Sofia Shinas) are to be married. Then, thanks to their efforts to fight eviction for themselves and their fellow tenants, their home is broken into. The invaders toss Draven (Lee) through a window and send him plummeting to the ground three stories below and savage his bride-to-be. The first officer on the scene is Sgt. Albrecht (played by Ernie Hudson) and when Shelley asks about her fianc&eacute;e, he spares her the truth and tells her he's fine. Then, when the latchkey kid that Eric and Shelley have taken under their wing stumbles upon the scene, Albrecht relays the lie once again. The child, Sarah (played by Rochelle Davis who also acts as the film's narrator), sees through the sergeant's reassuring fiction and departs soon after. Flash-forward one year, Sarah is visiting the graveyard where Shelly and Eric have been laid to rest and encounters a crow. After she'd left, the crow begins tapping on Eric's headstone with his beak. Then, that night, Eric emerges from his grave, shaking and traumatized. He returns to the apartment that he and Shelley once shared and finds that it is a ruin of the home he knew. While there, he begins experiencing flashbacks of the night one year before when he lost everything. Seeing the men responsible, who call themselves T-Bird (played by David Patrick Kelly), Tin-Tin (played by Laurence Mason), Funboy (played by Michael Massee), and Skank (played by Angel David). Still reeling from those memories, Eric grabs onto the frame that once held the apartment's only window and swings out and back in. He notices that he's cut himself on remnants on the window but, to his surprise, he heals almost immediately. With this new gift, he dons all black clothes, decorates his face in the style of a harlequin mask that was on the floor of his home, and sets out to seek revenge with the crow as his guide. I cannot adequately express how much I love this movie. The tone, the cinematography, the soundtrack, the antagonists. Everything about this movie is top-drawer. Fans of the graphic novel of the same name that inspired the film say that the master criminal in the film, known as Top Dollar in the novel and not actually given a name in the film, was far more ordinary than the evil genius Michael Wincott portrayed. Other critics say that the death of Brandon Lee gave this film a legacy it didn't earn, much the same way that critics claim Heath Ledger's death before the release of The Dark Knight added anticipation it wouldn't have gotten otherwise. As I was only ten when the film was first released, I was not aware of the film itself or Lee's death until much later. What I will say is that I cannot watch this film enough. Even so, if you haven't seen The Crow, shame on you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I don't know why this movie rated so high. Wast of time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    hdgunners
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I wasted 97 minutes of my life on this crap because of this IMDb rating. But I will advise who hasn't still seen this movie don't waste your time on this crap movie. I really wanted to see and like that movie but honestly speaking while watching the movie i dozed off a few times. Apart from the atmosphere, set design and photography everything is so dull and boring. Acting, screenplay, direction and every other thing about the movie are so poor and mediocre I cant help but to dislike the movie. Editing at some places seems rushed. and From Bruce Lee son you expect at least good action and martial arts skills but well what you get lifeless action and no martial arts. i amaze that i seen the same movie as the other. Awful movie not recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Crow  Revenge from beyond the grave on a human level and emotional
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Avid Climber
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Crow is by now a cult movie. Although it's getting a bit old for some of its special effects, it's still excellent. The soundtrack, especially the music, is exceptional. It's edgy, dark, and the emotions it stirs get you in the guts. It's a mirror image of the story. The revenge theme, certainly isn't new, not even one from beyond the grave, but the angle chosen here, is quite different. It's touching. You get a great mix of action, emotional drama, ghostly romance, and human relations, often dark and twisted, other times simple or basic. The sets are very dark and strongly Gothic. The acting is not perfect, but still strong and just. There are a few mistakes, not big, but at times noticeable, like some bad sound pickups. However, they seem to make the film into some sort of archaic rendition, which really works to its advantage. I recommend it if you don't mind its age.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I'm not sure why this movie is rated so high
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    elemari-365-648550
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Simply put, this movie is very mediocre. The storyline is weak. A rock star and his fianc&eacute; are murdered on Halloween night by a gang of thugs. The rock star then returns from the dead to seek revenge on the murder and rape of his fianc&eacute;. Honestly, this plot screams clich&eacute;. The whole rock star idea is extremely cheesy and just reminds me of the rock band KISS and their dreadful costumes. The acting is decent. I feel that Brandon Lee gives off too much of a "good guy" vibe for his role. Despite being dressed up as a menacing, undead badass seeking revenge, he somehow still gives off the impression that he's a nice guy. The gang thugs seem a bit like they're trying too hard. They seem to act how they think thugs would act instead of acting like thugs. I just didn't buy it. The highlight of this film is the special effects, which were well done for 1994. Even so, they fail to outshine a cheesy plot and mediocre acting. Don't get me wrong, the movie wasn't all bad, but it just wasn't good. The Crow lies out there in the vast gray area of mediocre action films.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The best of the them all
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lagudafuad
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Crow has reached an iconic high in the movie realm, mostly because it was the last movie that Brandon Lee stared him, as he Brandon died on set during the production of the film; his death was due to a gunshot. The gun was supposed to be loaded with blanks, but one life ammunition bullet was lodged in the gun that was then loaded with blanks. His death on set made the movie gross more than the producers could ever imagine and turned this movie to a cult classic. The movie is an adaptation of a comic book series of the same name, that was created by James O'Barr and it tells the tale of the life of Eric (Brandon Lee). Eric and his fianc&eacute;e were attacked at their home, Eric got shot and he was paralyzed, and could only watch as Shelly his fianc&eacute;e is savagely beaten and raped. The attackers finally kill Eric. But a year later Eric is resurrected by a crow, now he hunts the men that killed him and his fianc&eacute;e, Eric is now an undead, unable to be killed or hurt (as long as he stays on course, which is revenge on those who killed him and his fianc&eacute;e). The movie boasts of fast paced action, the movie adaption of the comic is seen by many to be near accurate. The movie's cinematography is engaging as we mostly are moving around with Eric in the night, the camera angles or light feed never make you wish that there were gotten from another shot or you needing more light. Then there is the score, the dark rocky score that brings you into the melancholy mood of Eric as you watch, the movie doesn't at any time take you to a high of good things happening then brings you back to the main dark theme Alex Proyas (the director, and also director of Dark City (1998) and I, Robot) made sure that from the get go of this movie you are introduced to a sad theme, a sad scene, a sad story and it the movie keeps to that till the end. The Crow goes places other hero movies don't want to go, no breather just darkness. The movies special effects were most rewarding and the story is very engaging a fit none of the other sequels after it has been able to accomplish, as more sequels were being released the worse the ratings they were getting, making this movie stand out the more. A remake of this said "untouchable classic" is being done, the argument is will this remake be as good as the original or is it just going to follow the way all the other sequels went. My take on this is, Hollywood filmmakers are now at the end of their rope, going back to remake movies or dragging them into trilogies just to make more money, the remake falls into this suit if you ask me (suit of not having an idea of what movie to do), because such movies like this should never be remade. That said, I will be watching the remake with high hopes, reason being times have changed, 1994 and now that is more than 18 years, enough technological advancement that could not be employed in 1994 will be used in this remake, I just hope it won't suck. www.lagsreviews.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Crow
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rachelle Stern
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Crows Revenge This movie begins on a dark night in Detroit. The Crow , Shelly Webster (Sofia Shenas) and Eric Draven (Brandon Lee) are engaged to be married the next day on Devils Night, Halloween, the night of fires, vandalism, and crime. Unfortunately that day never came for them. Shelly was raped and murdered for trying to get a petition to help rid the neighborhood of people that weren't contributing to society and that were making it worse. Eric was also killed. One year after their deaths, Eric came back to life as the crow to seek revenge for Shelly's death. The crow makes Eric somewhat invincible to getting hurt or killed while getting the justice that is deserved. The theme of this film seems to be revenge and justice. I feel the directors of this film, Daniel J. Schow and Alex Proyas, are trying to show that even in the darkest of times and bleakness of the night justice can prevail. One must fight to make it happen though. Although Draven was turned into the crow, he still had limitations to his invincibility. The crow followed Eric around the city and was there at the times that Tin-Tin, Fun Boy and T-Bird were brought to their final doom. If the crow was hurt Eric was inevitably hurt also. Justice doesn't always come easy and it's something we have to be willing to fight for. I'm personally attracted to this film for several reasons. One being the way justice is served, another being the love between Shelly and Eric. Eric loved her so much that he was willing to die for her and bring her death to justice; their love as to die for. This film also has a certain attraction to it because it is somewhat of a thriller. It keeps us on edge and captivated. The darkness and costumes bring a certain mysterious quality to it also. Brandon Lee's skills as an actor also bring an attraction to the film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good Supernatural Thing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    manishnagi
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    what a great movie i watched today . The Crow . I had read the novel i like that so much Now i saw this movie its brilliant , it is awesome Like i said novel it is great work done by John O'Barr . Now movie is is very good adopted The acting of Brandon Lee is awesome , all the fight scenes , martial arts , everything is awesome . i feel sad for Brandon Lee that he died . R.I.P i also like the little girl Rochelle Davis who played Sarah , Her acting is good This film is very good directed an screen played . i like the way story is moving along and all this supernatural thing , It inspires me a lot I had fun watching this movie
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The is my fav movie ever!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ssj-nightwing
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A lot of people that know me know how much I love comic book movies and characters and this is true I do. Bearing in mind comic book movies are getting better and better I just can't shake how totally ninja The Crow is. I love everything about, the simple revenge plot, the dark Gothic feel, the cast, everything. I have also read the graphic novel which this movie was based on! James O' Barr is a genius! If your after a true original before Marvel and DC this is great. Forgot to mention the soundtrack is pretty good too! Burn by the Cure, Nine Inch Nails - Dead Soul and Jane Siberry's It Can't Rain all the time are spot on. Very intrigued to see what they do with the reboot!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    deveraux009-650-383191
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The film portrays a young rock guitarist who comes back from the dead to avenge the murders of himself and his fianc&eacute;e. Even as a kid I always enjoyed watching it, as I found Lee's Crow to be easily watchable and I couldn't help but sympathize with the character, thanks to Lee's performance. He truly shined as the character, and captured what James O' Barr worked hard to create in his graphic novels. The atmosphere of the film was damn perfect, and even though some of the dialogue was a bit hit-and-miss(Mainly Rochelle Davis as Sarah), the cast worked and went great together. Michael Wincott as 'Top Dollar' was easily one of the best villains interpreted on-screen, and had some of the best dialogue and scenes besides Lee. To touch up a bit about Brandon Lee as The Crow, the way Lee portrayed the title character was what made the film so great, with his powerful yet gentle charismatic presence, he made one of the best superheroes to ever hit the screen. The action in the film was alright, but without the film's good performances, it might not have carried as well. The direction of the film was practically flawless, and everything clicked just fine. Alex Proyas as director of the film was a fine choice.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sadness is the Main Character
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tjross-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is a tacit theme of sadness that is so ubiquitous throughout the entire movie that it should have been billed as the main character. It's raised to the next level when you remember that this was Brandon Lee's breakout movie and he died making it. I never read the comic so I do not know if it was true to it, but I do know that this movie had a tone that I've never felt before. Brandon Lee is simply amazing! The set design, writing, and directing are top notch--they truly transport you to the goth underbelly of a place you don't want to be. It will clearly be too violent and dark for many viewers, but if you can get over it, you will experience a brilliant film. i've seen this movie a few times and it gets better every time I see it. My only complaint is that I did not have the luxury of seeing it in a theater.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Genius
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Treyroo
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If the question were put to you, would you "go gently into that good night"? What if you weren't given the choice and, instead, were left with the more grisly task of balancing the scales? Would you take it? It's Mischief Night, or Devil's Night as it's referred to in this film, in Detroit and the night before musician Eric Draven (played by Brandon Lee) and Shelley Webster (played by Sofia Shinas) are to be married. Then, thanks to their efforts to fight eviction for themselves and their fellow tenants, their home is broken into. The invaders toss Draven (Lee) through a window and send him plummeting to the ground three stories below and savage his bride-to-be. The first officer on the scene is Sgt. Albrecht (played by Ernie Hudson) and when Shelley asks about her fianc&eacute;e, he spares her the truth and tells her he's fine. Then, when the latchkey kid that Eric and Shelley have taken under their wing stumbles upon the scene, Albrecht relays the lie once again. The child, Sarah (played by Rochelle Davis who also acts as the film's narrator), sees through the sergeant's reassuring fiction and departs soon after. Flash-forward one year, Sarah is visiting the graveyard where Shelly and Eric have been laid to rest and encounters a crow. After she'd left, the crow begins tapping on Eric's headstone with his beak. Then, that night, Eric emerges from his grave, shaking and traumatized. He returns to the apartment that he and Shelley once shared and finds that it is a ruin of the home he knew. While there, he begins experiencing flashbacks of the night one year before when he lost everything. Seeing the men responsible, who call themselves T-Bird (played by David Patrick Kelly), Tin-Tin (played by Laurence Mason), Funboy (played by Michael Massee), and Skank (played by Angel David). Still reeling from those memories, Eric grabs onto the frame that once held the apartment's only window and swings out and back in. He notices that he's cut himself on remnants on the window but, to his surprise, he heals almost immediately. With this new gift, he dons all black clothes, decorates his face in the style of a harlequin mask that was on the floor of his home, and sets out to seek revenge with the crow as his guide. I cannot adequately express how much I love this movie. The tone, the cinematography, the soundtrack, the antagonists. Everything about this movie is top-drawer. Fans of the graphic novel of the same name that inspired the film say that the master criminal in the film, known as Top Dollar in the novel and not actually given a name in the film, was far more ordinary than the evil genius Michael Wincott portrayed. Other critics say that the death of Brandon Lee gave this film a legacy it didn't earn, much the same way that critics claim Heath Ledger's death before the release of The Dark Knight added anticipation it wouldn't have gotten otherwise. As I was only ten when the film was first released, I was not aware of the film itself or Lee's death until much later. What I will say is that I cannot watch this film enough. Even so, if you haven't seen The Crow, shame on you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I don't know why this movie rated so high. Wast of time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    hdgunners
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I wasted 97 minutes of my life on this crap because of this IMDb rating. But I will advise who hasn't still seen this movie don't waste your time on this crap movie. I really wanted to see and like that movie but honestly speaking while watching the movie i dozed off a few times. Apart from the atmosphere, set design and photography everything is so dull and boring. Acting, screenplay, direction and every other thing about the movie are so poor and mediocre I cant help but to dislike the movie. Editing at some places seems rushed. and From Bruce Lee son you expect at least good action and martial arts skills but well what you get lifeless action and no martial arts. i amaze that i seen the same movie as the other. Awful movie not recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Crow  Revenge from beyond the grave on a human level and emotional
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Avid Climber
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Crow is by now a cult movie. Although it's getting a bit old for some of its special effects, it's still excellent. The soundtrack, especially the music, is exceptional. It's edgy, dark, and the emotions it stirs get you in the guts. It's a mirror image of the story. The revenge theme, certainly isn't new, not even one from beyond the grave, but the angle chosen here, is quite different. It's touching. You get a great mix of action, emotional drama, ghostly romance, and human relations, often dark and twisted, other times simple or basic. The sets are very dark and strongly Gothic. The acting is not perfect, but still strong and just. There are a few mistakes, not big, but at times noticeable, like some bad sound pickups. However, they seem to make the film into some sort of archaic rendition, which really works to its advantage. I recommend it if you don't mind its age.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I'm not sure why this movie is rated so high
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    elemari-365-648550
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Simply put, this movie is very mediocre. The storyline is weak. A rock star and his fianc&eacute; are murdered on Halloween night by a gang of thugs. The rock star then returns from the dead to seek revenge on the murder and rape of his fianc&eacute;. Honestly, this plot screams clich&eacute;. The whole rock star idea is extremely cheesy and just reminds me of the rock band KISS and their dreadful costumes. The acting is decent. I feel that Brandon Lee gives off too much of a "good guy" vibe for his role. Despite being dressed up as a menacing, undead badass seeking revenge, he somehow still gives off the impression that he's a nice guy. The gang thugs seem a bit like they're trying too hard. They seem to act how they think thugs would act instead of acting like thugs. I just didn't buy it. The highlight of this film is the special effects, which were well done for 1994. Even so, they fail to outshine a cheesy plot and mediocre acting. Don't get me wrong, the movie wasn't all bad, but it just wasn't good. The Crow lies out there in the vast gray area of mediocre action films.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The best of the them all
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lagudafuad
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Crow has reached an iconic high in the movie realm, mostly because it was the last movie that Brandon Lee stared him, as he Brandon died on set during the production of the film; his death was due to a gunshot. The gun was supposed to be loaded with blanks, but one life ammunition bullet was lodged in the gun that was then loaded with blanks. His death on set made the movie gross more than the producers could ever imagine and turned this movie to a cult classic. The movie is an adaptation of a comic book series of the same name, that was created by James O'Barr and it tells the tale of the life of Eric (Brandon Lee). Eric and his fianc&eacute;e were attacked at their home, Eric got shot and he was paralyzed, and could only watch as Shelly his fianc&eacute;e is savagely beaten and raped. The attackers finally kill Eric. But a year later Eric is resurrected by a crow, now he hunts the men that killed him and his fianc&eacute;e, Eric is now an undead, unable to be killed or hurt (as long as he stays on course, which is revenge on those who killed him and his fianc&eacute;e). The movie boasts of fast paced action, the movie adaption of the comic is seen by many to be near accurate. The movie's cinematography is engaging as we mostly are moving around with Eric in the night, the camera angles or light feed never make you wish that there were gotten from another shot or you needing more light. Then there is the score, the dark rocky score that brings you into the melancholy mood of Eric as you watch, the movie doesn't at any time take you to a high of good things happening then brings you back to the main dark theme Alex Proyas (the director, and also director of Dark City (1998) and I, Robot) made sure that from the get go of this movie you are introduced to a sad theme, a sad scene, a sad story and it the movie keeps to that till the end. The Crow goes places other hero movies don't want to go, no breather just darkness. The movies special effects were most rewarding and the story is very engaging a fit none of the other sequels after it has been able to accomplish, as more sequels were being released the worse the ratings they were getting, making this movie stand out the more. A remake of this said "untouchable classic" is being done, the argument is will this remake be as good as the original or is it just going to follow the way all the other sequels went. My take on this is, Hollywood filmmakers are now at the end of their rope, going back to remake movies or dragging them into trilogies just to make more money, the remake falls into this suit if you ask me (suit of not having an idea of what movie to do), because such movies like this should never be remade. That said, I will be watching the remake with high hopes, reason being times have changed, 1994 and now that is more than 18 years, enough technological advancement that could not be employed in 1994 will be used in this remake, I just hope it won't suck. www.lagsreviews.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Crow
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rachelle Stern
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Crows Revenge This movie begins on a dark night in Detroit. The Crow , Shelly Webster (Sofia Shenas) and Eric Draven (Brandon Lee) are engaged to be married the next day on Devils Night, Halloween, the night of fires, vandalism, and crime. Unfortunately that day never came for them. Shelly was raped and murdered for trying to get a petition to help rid the neighborhood of people that weren't contributing to society and that were making it worse. Eric was also killed. One year after their deaths, Eric came back to life as the crow to seek revenge for Shelly's death. The crow makes Eric somewhat invincible to getting hurt or killed while getting the justice that is deserved. The theme of this film seems to be revenge and justice. I feel the directors of this film, Daniel J. Schow and Alex Proyas, are trying to show that even in the darkest of times and bleakness of the night justice can prevail. One must fight to make it happen though. Although Draven was turned into the crow, he still had limitations to his invincibility. The crow followed Eric around the city and was there at the times that Tin-Tin, Fun Boy and T-Bird were brought to their final doom. If the crow was hurt Eric was inevitably hurt also. Justice doesn't always come easy and it's something we have to be willing to fight for. I'm personally attracted to this film for several reasons. One being the way justice is served, another being the love between Shelly and Eric. Eric loved her so much that he was willing to die for her and bring her death to justice; their love as to die for. This film also has a certain attraction to it because it is somewhat of a thriller. It keeps us on edge and captivated. The darkness and costumes bring a certain mysterious quality to it also. Brandon Lee's skills as an actor also bring an attraction to the film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good Supernatural Thing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    manishnagi
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    what a great movie i watched today . The Crow . I had read the novel i like that so much Now i saw this movie its brilliant , it is awesome Like i said novel it is great work done by John O'Barr . Now movie is is very good adopted The acting of Brandon Lee is awesome , all the fight scenes , martial arts , everything is awesome . i feel sad for Brandon Lee that he died . R.I.P i also like the little girl Rochelle Davis who played Sarah , Her acting is good This film is very good directed an screen played . i like the way story is moving along and all this supernatural thing , It inspires me a lot I had fun watching this movie
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The is my fav movie ever!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ssj-nightwing
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A lot of people that know me know how much I love comic book movies and characters and this is true I do. Bearing in mind comic book movies are getting better and better I just can't shake how totally ninja The Crow is. I love everything about, the simple revenge plot, the dark Gothic feel, the cast, everything. I have also read the graphic novel which this movie was based on! James O' Barr is a genius! If your after a true original before Marvel and DC this is great. Forgot to mention the soundtrack is pretty good too! Burn by the Cure, Nine Inch Nails - Dead Soul and Jane Siberry's It Can't Rain all the time are spot on. Very intrigued to see what they do with the reboot!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    deveraux009-650-383191
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The film portrays a young rock guitarist who comes back from the dead to avenge the murders of himself and his fianc&eacute;e. Even as a kid I always enjoyed watching it, as I found Lee's Crow to be easily watchable and I couldn't help but sympathize with the character, thanks to Lee's performance. He truly shined as the character, and captured what James O' Barr worked hard to create in his graphic novels. The atmosphere of the film was damn perfect, and even though some of the dialogue was a bit hit-and-miss(Mainly Rochelle Davis as Sarah), the cast worked and went great together. Michael Wincott as 'Top Dollar' was easily one of the best villains interpreted on-screen, and had some of the best dialogue and scenes besides Lee. To touch up a bit about Brandon Lee as The Crow, the way Lee portrayed the title character was what made the film so great, with his powerful yet gentle charismatic presence, he made one of the best superheroes to ever hit the screen. The action in the film was alright, but without the film's good performances, it might not have carried as well. The direction of the film was practically flawless, and everything clicked just fine. Alex Proyas as director of the film was a fine choice.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sadness is the Main Character
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tjross-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is a tacit theme of sadness that is so ubiquitous throughout the entire movie that it should have been billed as the main character. It's raised to the next level when you remember that this was Brandon Lee's breakout movie and he died making it. I never read the comic so I do not know if it was true to it, but I do know that this movie had a tone that I've never felt before. Brandon Lee is simply amazing! The set design, writing, and directing are top notch--they truly transport you to the goth underbelly of a place you don't want to be. It will clearly be too violent and dark for many viewers, but if you can get over it, you will experience a brilliant film. i've seen this movie a few times and it gets better every time I see it. My only complaint is that I did not have the luxury of seeing it in a theater.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Genius
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Treyroo
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If the question were put to you, would you "go gently into that good night"? What if you weren't given the choice and, instead, were left with the more grisly task of balancing the scales? Would you take it? It's Mischief Night, or Devil's Night as it's referred to in this film, in Detroit and the night before musician Eric Draven (played by Brandon Lee) and Shelley Webster (played by Sofia Shinas) are to be married. Then, thanks to their efforts to fight eviction for themselves and their fellow tenants, their home is broken into. The invaders toss Draven (Lee) through a window and send him plummeting to the ground three stories below and savage his bride-to-be. The first officer on the scene is Sgt. Albrecht (played by Ernie Hudson) and when Shelley asks about her fianc&eacute;e, he spares her the truth and tells her he's fine. Then, when the latchkey kid that Eric and Shelley have taken under their wing stumbles upon the scene, Albrecht relays the lie once again. The child, Sarah (played by Rochelle Davis who also acts as the film's narrator), sees through the sergeant's reassuring fiction and departs soon after. Flash-forward one year, Sarah is visiting the graveyard where Shelly and Eric have been laid to rest and encounters a crow. After she'd left, the crow begins tapping on Eric's headstone with his beak. Then, that night, Eric emerges from his grave, shaking and traumatized. He returns to the apartment that he and Shelley once shared and finds that it is a ruin of the home he knew. While there, he begins experiencing flashbacks of the night one year before when he lost everything. Seeing the men responsible, who call themselves T-Bird (played by David Patrick Kelly), Tin-Tin (played by Laurence Mason), Funboy (played by Michael Massee), and Skank (played by Angel David). Still reeling from those memories, Eric grabs onto the frame that once held the apartment's only window and swings out and back in. He notices that he's cut himself on remnants on the window but, to his surprise, he heals almost immediately. With this new gift, he dons all black clothes, decorates his face in the style of a harlequin mask that was on the floor of his home, and sets out to seek revenge with the crow as his guide. I cannot adequately express how much I love this movie. The tone, the cinematography, the soundtrack, the antagonists. Everything about this movie is top-drawer. Fans of the graphic novel of the same name that inspired the film say that the master criminal in the film, known as Top Dollar in the novel and not actually given a name in the film, was far more ordinary than the evil genius Michael Wincott portrayed. Other critics say that the death of Brandon Lee gave this film a legacy it didn't earn, much the same way that critics claim Heath Ledger's death before the release of The Dark Knight added anticipation it wouldn't have gotten otherwise. As I was only ten when the film was first released, I was not aware of the film itself or Lee's death until much later. What I will say is that I cannot watch this film enough. Even so, if you haven't seen The Crow, shame on you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I don't know why this movie rated so high. Wast of time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    hdgunners
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I wasted 97 minutes of my life on this crap because of this IMDb rating. But I will advise who hasn't still seen this movie don't waste your time on this crap movie. I really wanted to see and like that movie but honestly speaking while watching the movie i dozed off a few times. Apart from the atmosphere, set design and photography everything is so dull and boring. Acting, screenplay, direction and every other thing about the movie are so poor and mediocre I cant help but to dislike the movie. Editing at some places seems rushed. and From Bruce Lee son you expect at least good action and martial arts skills but well what you get lifeless action and no martial arts. i amaze that i seen the same movie as the other. Awful movie not recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Crow  Revenge from beyond the grave on a human level and emotional
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Avid Climber
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Crow is by now a cult movie. Although it's getting a bit old for some of its special effects, it's still excellent. The soundtrack, especially the music, is exceptional. It's edgy, dark, and the emotions it stirs get you in the guts. It's a mirror image of the story. The revenge theme, certainly isn't new, not even one from beyond the grave, but the angle chosen here, is quite different. It's touching. You get a great mix of action, emotional drama, ghostly romance, and human relations, often dark and twisted, other times simple or basic. The sets are very dark and strongly Gothic. The acting is not perfect, but still strong and just. There are a few mistakes, not big, but at times noticeable, like some bad sound pickups. However, they seem to make the film into some sort of archaic rendition, which really works to its advantage. I recommend it if you don't mind its age.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I'm not sure why this movie is rated so high
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    elemari-365-648550
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Simply put, this movie is very mediocre. The storyline is weak. A rock star and his fianc&eacute; are murdered on Halloween night by a gang of thugs. The rock star then returns from the dead to seek revenge on the murder and rape of his fianc&eacute;. Honestly, this plot screams clich&eacute;. The whole rock star idea is extremely cheesy and just reminds me of the rock band KISS and their dreadful costumes. The acting is decent. I feel that Brandon Lee gives off too much of a "good guy" vibe for his role. Despite being dressed up as a menacing, undead badass seeking revenge, he somehow still gives off the impression that he's a nice guy. The gang thugs seem a bit like they're trying too hard. They seem to act how they think thugs would act instead of acting like thugs. I just didn't buy it. The highlight of this film is the special effects, which were well done for 1994. Even so, they fail to outshine a cheesy plot and mediocre acting. Don't get me wrong, the movie wasn't all bad, but it just wasn't good. The Crow lies out there in the vast gray area of mediocre action films.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The best of the them all
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lagudafuad
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Crow has reached an iconic high in the movie realm, mostly because it was the last movie that Brandon Lee stared him, as he Brandon died on set during the production of the film; his death was due to a gunshot. The gun was supposed to be loaded with blanks, but one life ammunition bullet was lodged in the gun that was then loaded with blanks. His death on set made the movie gross more than the producers could ever imagine and turned this movie to a cult classic. The movie is an adaptation of a comic book series of the same name, that was created by James O'Barr and it tells the tale of the life of Eric (Brandon Lee). Eric and his fianc&eacute;e were attacked at their home, Eric got shot and he was paralyzed, and could only watch as Shelly his fianc&eacute;e is savagely beaten and raped. The attackers finally kill Eric. But a year later Eric is resurrected by a crow, now he hunts the men that killed him and his fianc&eacute;e, Eric is now an undead, unable to be killed or hurt (as long as he stays on course, which is revenge on those who killed him and his fianc&eacute;e). The movie boasts of fast paced action, the movie adaption of the comic is seen by many to be near accurate. The movie's cinematography is engaging as we mostly are moving around with Eric in the night, the camera angles or light feed never make you wish that there were gotten from another shot or you needing more light. Then there is the score, the dark rocky score that brings you into the melancholy mood of Eric as you watch, the movie doesn't at any time take you to a high of good things happening then brings you back to the main dark theme Alex Proyas (the director, and also director of Dark City (1998) and I, Robot) made sure that from the get go of this movie you are introduced to a sad theme, a sad scene, a sad story and it the movie keeps to that till the end. The Crow goes places other hero movies don't want to go, no breather just darkness. The movies special effects were most rewarding and the story is very engaging a fit none of the other sequels after it has been able to accomplish, as more sequels were being released the worse the ratings they were getting, making this movie stand out the more. A remake of this said "untouchable classic" is being done, the argument is will this remake be as good as the original or is it just going to follow the way all the other sequels went. My take on this is, Hollywood filmmakers are now at the end of their rope, going back to remake movies or dragging them into trilogies just to make more money, the remake falls into this suit if you ask me (suit of not having an idea of what movie to do), because such movies like this should never be remade. That said, I will be watching the remake with high hopes, reason being times have changed, 1994 and now that is more than 18 years, enough technological advancement that could not be employed in 1994 will be used in this remake, I just hope it won't suck. www.lagsreviews.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Crow
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rachelle Stern
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Crows Revenge This movie begins on a dark night in Detroit. The Crow , Shelly Webster (Sofia Shenas) and Eric Draven (Brandon Lee) are engaged to be married the next day on Devils Night, Halloween, the night of fires, vandalism, and crime. Unfortunately that day never came for them. Shelly was raped and murdered for trying to get a petition to help rid the neighborhood of people that weren't contributing to society and that were making it worse. Eric was also killed. One year after their deaths, Eric came back to life as the crow to seek revenge for Shelly's death. The crow makes Eric somewhat invincible to getting hurt or killed while getting the justice that is deserved. The theme of this film seems to be revenge and justice. I feel the directors of this film, Daniel J. Schow and Alex Proyas, are trying to show that even in the darkest of times and bleakness of the night justice can prevail. One must fight to make it happen though. Although Draven was turned into the crow, he still had limitations to his invincibility. The crow followed Eric around the city and was there at the times that Tin-Tin, Fun Boy and T-Bird were brought to their final doom. If the crow was hurt Eric was inevitably hurt also. Justice doesn't always come easy and it's something we have to be willing to fight for. I'm personally attracted to this film for several reasons. One being the way justice is served, another being the love between Shelly and Eric. Eric loved her so much that he was willing to die for her and bring her death to justice; their love as to die for. This film also has a certain attraction to it because it is somewhat of a thriller. It keeps us on edge and captivated. The darkness and costumes bring a certain mysterious quality to it also. Brandon Lee's skills as an actor also bring an attraction to the film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good Supernatural Thing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    manishnagi
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    what a great movie i watched today . The Crow . I had read the novel i like that so much Now i saw this movie its brilliant , it is awesome Like i said novel it is great work done by John O'Barr . Now movie is is very good adopted The acting of Brandon Lee is awesome , all the fight scenes , martial arts , everything is awesome . i feel sad for Brandon Lee that he died . R.I.P i also like the little girl Rochelle Davis who played Sarah , Her acting is good This film is very good directed an screen played . i like the way story is moving along and all this supernatural thing , It inspires me a lot I had fun watching this movie
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The is my fav movie ever!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ssj-nightwing
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A lot of people that know me know how much I love comic book movies and characters and this is true I do. Bearing in mind comic book movies are getting better and better I just can't shake how totally ninja The Crow is. I love everything about, the simple revenge plot, the dark Gothic feel, the cast, everything. I have also read the graphic novel which this movie was based on! James O' Barr is a genius! If your after a true original before Marvel and DC this is great. Forgot to mention the soundtrack is pretty good too! Burn by the Cure, Nine Inch Nails - Dead Soul and Jane Siberry's It Can't Rain all the time are spot on. Very intrigued to see what they do with the reboot!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    deveraux009-650-383191
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The film portrays a young rock guitarist who comes back from the dead to avenge the murders of himself and his fianc&eacute;e. Even as a kid I always enjoyed watching it, as I found Lee's Crow to be easily watchable and I couldn't help but sympathize with the character, thanks to Lee's performance. He truly shined as the character, and captured what James O' Barr worked hard to create in his graphic novels. The atmosphere of the film was damn perfect, and even though some of the dialogue was a bit hit-and-miss(Mainly Rochelle Davis as Sarah), the cast worked and went great together. Michael Wincott as 'Top Dollar' was easily one of the best villains interpreted on-screen, and had some of the best dialogue and scenes besides Lee. To touch up a bit about Brandon Lee as The Crow, the way Lee portrayed the title character was what made the film so great, with his powerful yet gentle charismatic presence, he made one of the best superheroes to ever hit the screen. The action in the film was alright, but without the film's good performances, it might not have carried as well. The direction of the film was practically flawless, and everything clicked just fine. Alex Proyas as director of the film was a fine choice.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sadness is the Main Character
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tjross-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is a tacit theme of sadness that is so ubiquitous throughout the entire movie that it should have been billed as the main character. It's raised to the next level when you remember that this was Brandon Lee's breakout movie and he died making it. I never read the comic so I do not know if it was true to it, but I do know that this movie had a tone that I've never felt before. Brandon Lee is simply amazing! The set design, writing, and directing are top notch--they truly transport you to the goth underbelly of a place you don't want to be. It will clearly be too violent and dark for many viewers, but if you can get over it, you will experience a brilliant film. i've seen this movie a few times and it gets better every time I see it. My only complaint is that I did not have the luxury of seeing it in a theater.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Genius
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Treyroo
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If the question were put to you, would you "go gently into that good night"? What if you weren't given the choice and, instead, were left with the more grisly task of balancing the scales? Would you take it? It's Mischief Night, or Devil's Night as it's referred to in this film, in Detroit and the night before musician Eric Draven (played by Brandon Lee) and Shelley Webster (played by Sofia Shinas) are to be married. Then, thanks to their efforts to fight eviction for themselves and their fellow tenants, their home is broken into. The invaders toss Draven (Lee) through a window and send him plummeting to the ground three stories below and savage his bride-to-be. The first officer on the scene is Sgt. Albrecht (played by Ernie Hudson) and when Shelley asks about her fianc&eacute;e, he spares her the truth and tells her he's fine. Then, when the latchkey kid that Eric and Shelley have taken under their wing stumbles upon the scene, Albrecht relays the lie once again. The child, Sarah (played by Rochelle Davis who also acts as the film's narrator), sees through the sergeant's reassuring fiction and departs soon after. Flash-forward one year, Sarah is visiting the graveyard where Shelly and Eric have been laid to rest and encounters a crow. After she'd left, the crow begins tapping on Eric's headstone with his beak. Then, that night, Eric emerges from his grave, shaking and traumatized. He returns to the apartment that he and Shelley once shared and finds that it is a ruin of the home he knew. While there, he begins experiencing flashbacks of the night one year before when he lost everything. Seeing the men responsible, who call themselves T-Bird (played by David Patrick Kelly), Tin-Tin (played by Laurence Mason), Funboy (played by Michael Massee), and Skank (played by Angel David). Still reeling from those memories, Eric grabs onto the frame that once held the apartment's only window and swings out and back in. He notices that he's cut himself on remnants on the window but, to his surprise, he heals almost immediately. With this new gift, he dons all black clothes, decorates his face in the style of a harlequin mask that was on the floor of his home, and sets out to seek revenge with the crow as his guide. I cannot adequately express how much I love this movie. The tone, the cinematography, the soundtrack, the antagonists. Everything about this movie is top-drawer. Fans of the graphic novel of the same name that inspired the film say that the master criminal in the film, known as Top Dollar in the novel and not actually given a name in the film, was far more ordinary than the evil genius Michael Wincott portrayed. Other critics say that the death of Brandon Lee gave this film a legacy it didn't earn, much the same way that critics claim Heath Ledger's death before the release of The Dark Knight added anticipation it wouldn't have gotten otherwise. As I was only ten when the film was first released, I was not aware of the film itself or Lee's death until much later. What I will say is that I cannot watch this film enough. Even so, if you haven't seen The Crow, shame on you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I don't know why this movie rated so high. Wast of time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    hdgunners
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I wasted 97 minutes of my life on this crap because of this IMDb rating. But I will advise who hasn't still seen this movie don't waste your time on this crap movie. I really wanted to see and like that movie but honestly speaking while watching the movie i dozed off a few times. Apart from the atmosphere, set design and photography everything is so dull and boring. Acting, screenplay, direction and every other thing about the movie are so poor and mediocre I cant help but to dislike the movie. Editing at some places seems rushed. and From Bruce Lee son you expect at least good action and martial arts skills but well what you get lifeless action and no martial arts. i amaze that i seen the same movie as the other. Awful movie not recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Crow  Revenge from beyond the grave on a human level and emotional
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Avid Climber
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Crow is by now a cult movie. Although it's getting a bit old for some of its special effects, it's still excellent. The soundtrack, especially the music, is exceptional. It's edgy, dark, and the emotions it stirs get you in the guts. It's a mirror image of the story. The revenge theme, certainly isn't new, not even one from beyond the grave, but the angle chosen here, is quite different. It's touching. You get a great mix of action, emotional drama, ghostly romance, and human relations, often dark and twisted, other times simple or basic. The sets are very dark and strongly Gothic. The acting is not perfect, but still strong and just. There are a few mistakes, not big, but at times noticeable, like some bad sound pickups. However, they seem to make the film into some sort of archaic rendition, which really works to its advantage. I recommend it if you don't mind its age.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I'm not sure why this movie is rated so high
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    elemari-365-648550
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Simply put, this movie is very mediocre. The storyline is weak. A rock star and his fianc&eacute; are murdered on Halloween night by a gang of thugs. The rock star then returns from the dead to seek revenge on the murder and rape of his fianc&eacute;. Honestly, this plot screams clich&eacute;. The whole rock star idea is extremely cheesy and just reminds me of the rock band KISS and their dreadful costumes. The acting is decent. I feel that Brandon Lee gives off too much of a "good guy" vibe for his role. Despite being dressed up as a menacing, undead badass seeking revenge, he somehow still gives off the impression that he's a nice guy. The gang thugs seem a bit like they're trying too hard. They seem to act how they think thugs would act instead of acting like thugs. I just didn't buy it. The highlight of this film is the special effects, which were well done for 1994. Even so, they fail to outshine a cheesy plot and mediocre acting. Don't get me wrong, the movie wasn't all bad, but it just wasn't good. The Crow lies out there in the vast gray area of mediocre action films.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The best of the them all
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lagudafuad
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Crow has reached an iconic high in the movie realm, mostly because it was the last movie that Brandon Lee stared him, as he Brandon died on set during the production of the film; his death was due to a gunshot. The gun was supposed to be loaded with blanks, but one life ammunition bullet was lodged in the gun that was then loaded with blanks. His death on set made the movie gross more than the producers could ever imagine and turned this movie to a cult classic. The movie is an adaptation of a comic book series of the same name, that was created by James O'Barr and it tells the tale of the life of Eric (Brandon Lee). Eric and his fianc&eacute;e were attacked at their home, Eric got shot and he was paralyzed, and could only watch as Shelly his fianc&eacute;e is savagely beaten and raped. The attackers finally kill Eric. But a year later Eric is resurrected by a crow, now he hunts the men that killed him and his fianc&eacute;e, Eric is now an undead, unable to be killed or hurt (as long as he stays on course, which is revenge on those who killed him and his fianc&eacute;e). The movie boasts of fast paced action, the movie adaption of the comic is seen by many to be near accurate. The movie's cinematography is engaging as we mostly are moving around with Eric in the night, the camera angles or light feed never make you wish that there were gotten from another shot or you needing more light. Then there is the score, the dark rocky score that brings you into the melancholy mood of Eric as you watch, the movie doesn't at any time take you to a high of good things happening then brings you back to the main dark theme Alex Proyas (the director, and also director of Dark City (1998) and I, Robot) made sure that from the get go of this movie you are introduced to a sad theme, a sad scene, a sad story and it the movie keeps to that till the end. The Crow goes places other hero movies don't want to go, no breather just darkness. The movies special effects were most rewarding and the story is very engaging a fit none of the other sequels after it has been able to accomplish, as more sequels were being released the worse the ratings they were getting, making this movie stand out the more. A remake of this said "untouchable classic" is being done, the argument is will this remake be as good as the original or is it just going to follow the way all the other sequels went. My take on this is, Hollywood filmmakers are now at the end of their rope, going back to remake movies or dragging them into trilogies just to make more money, the remake falls into this suit if you ask me (suit of not having an idea of what movie to do), because such movies like this should never be remade. That said, I will be watching the remake with high hopes, reason being times have changed, 1994 and now that is more than 18 years, enough technological advancement that could not be employed in 1994 will be used in this remake, I just hope it won't suck. www.lagsreviews.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Crow
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rachelle Stern
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Crows Revenge This movie begins on a dark night in Detroit. The Crow , Shelly Webster (Sofia Shenas) and Eric Draven (Brandon Lee) are engaged to be married the next day on Devils Night, Halloween, the night of fires, vandalism, and crime. Unfortunately that day never came for them. Shelly was raped and murdered for trying to get a petition to help rid the neighborhood of people that weren't contributing to society and that were making it worse. Eric was also killed. One year after their deaths, Eric came back to life as the crow to seek revenge for Shelly's death. The crow makes Eric somewhat invincible to getting hurt or killed while getting the justice that is deserved. The theme of this film seems to be revenge and justice. I feel the directors of this film, Daniel J. Schow and Alex Proyas, are trying to show that even in the darkest of times and bleakness of the night justice can prevail. One must fight to make it happen though. Although Draven was turned into the crow, he still had limitations to his invincibility. The crow followed Eric around the city and was there at the times that Tin-Tin, Fun Boy and T-Bird were brought to their final doom. If the crow was hurt Eric was inevitably hurt also. Justice doesn't always come easy and it's something we have to be willing to fight for. I'm personally attracted to this film for several reasons. One being the way justice is served, another being the love between Shelly and Eric. Eric loved her so much that he was willing to die for her and bring her death to justice; their love as to die for. This film also has a certain attraction to it because it is somewhat of a thriller. It keeps us on edge and captivated. The darkness and costumes bring a certain mysterious quality to it also. Brandon Lee's skills as an actor also bring an attraction to the film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good Supernatural Thing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    manishnagi
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    what a great movie i watched today . The Crow . I had read the novel i like that so much Now i saw this movie its brilliant , it is awesome Like i said novel it is great work done by John O'Barr . Now movie is is very good adopted The acting of Brandon Lee is awesome , all the fight scenes , martial arts , everything is awesome . i feel sad for Brandon Lee that he died . R.I.P i also like the little girl Rochelle Davis who played Sarah , Her acting is good This film is very good directed an screen played . i like the way story is moving along and all this supernatural thing , It inspires me a lot I had fun watching this movie
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The is my fav movie ever!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ssj-nightwing
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A lot of people that know me know how much I love comic book movies and characters and this is true I do. Bearing in mind comic book movies are getting better and better I just can't shake how totally ninja The Crow is. I love everything about, the simple revenge plot, the dark Gothic feel, the cast, everything. I have also read the graphic novel which this movie was based on! James O' Barr is a genius! If your after a true original before Marvel and DC this is great. Forgot to mention the soundtrack is pretty good too! Burn by the Cure, Nine Inch Nails - Dead Soul and Jane Siberry's It Can't Rain all the time are spot on. Very intrigued to see what they do with the reboot!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    deveraux009-650-383191
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The film portrays a young rock guitarist who comes back from the dead to avenge the murders of himself and his fianc&eacute;e. Even as a kid I always enjoyed watching it, as I found Lee's Crow to be easily watchable and I couldn't help but sympathize with the character, thanks to Lee's performance. He truly shined as the character, and captured what James O' Barr worked hard to create in his graphic novels. The atmosphere of the film was damn perfect, and even though some of the dialogue was a bit hit-and-miss(Mainly Rochelle Davis as Sarah), the cast worked and went great together. Michael Wincott as 'Top Dollar' was easily one of the best villains interpreted on-screen, and had some of the best dialogue and scenes besides Lee. To touch up a bit about Brandon Lee as The Crow, the way Lee portrayed the title character was what made the film so great, with his powerful yet gentle charismatic presence, he made one of the best superheroes to ever hit the screen. The action in the film was alright, but without the film's good performances, it might not have carried as well. The direction of the film was practically flawless, and everything clicked just fine. Alex Proyas as director of the film was a fine choice.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sadness is the Main Character
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tjross-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is a tacit theme of sadness that is so ubiquitous throughout the entire movie that it should have been billed as the main character. It's raised to the next level when you remember that this was Brandon Lee's breakout movie and he died making it. I never read the comic so I do not know if it was true to it, but I do know that this movie had a tone that I've never felt before. Brandon Lee is simply amazing! The set design, writing, and directing are top notch--they truly transport you to the goth underbelly of a place you don't want to be. It will clearly be too violent and dark for many viewers, but if you can get over it, you will experience a brilliant film. i've seen this movie a few times and it gets better every time I see it. My only complaint is that I did not have the luxury of seeing it in a theater.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Genius
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Treyroo
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If the question were put to you, would you "go gently into that good night"? What if you weren't given the choice and, instead, were left with the more grisly task of balancing the scales? Would you take it? It's Mischief Night, or Devil's Night as it's referred to in this film, in Detroit and the night before musician Eric Draven (played by Brandon Lee) and Shelley Webster (played by Sofia Shinas) are to be married. Then, thanks to their efforts to fight eviction for themselves and their fellow tenants, their home is broken into. The invaders toss Draven (Lee) through a window and send him plummeting to the ground three stories below and savage his bride-to-be. The first officer on the scene is Sgt. Albrecht (played by Ernie Hudson) and when Shelley asks about her fianc&eacute;e, he spares her the truth and tells her he's fine. Then, when the latchkey kid that Eric and Shelley have taken under their wing stumbles upon the scene, Albrecht relays the lie once again. The child, Sarah (played by Rochelle Davis who also acts as the film's narrator), sees through the sergeant's reassuring fiction and departs soon after. Flash-forward one year, Sarah is visiting the graveyard where Shelly and Eric have been laid to rest and encounters a crow. After she'd left, the crow begins tapping on Eric's headstone with his beak. Then, that night, Eric emerges from his grave, shaking and traumatized. He returns to the apartment that he and Shelley once shared and finds that it is a ruin of the home he knew. While there, he begins experiencing flashbacks of the night one year before when he lost everything. Seeing the men responsible, who call themselves T-Bird (played by David Patrick Kelly), Tin-Tin (played by Laurence Mason), Funboy (played by Michael Massee), and Skank (played by Angel David). Still reeling from those memories, Eric grabs onto the frame that once held the apartment's only window and swings out and back in. He notices that he's cut himself on remnants on the window but, to his surprise, he heals almost immediately. With this new gift, he dons all black clothes, decorates his face in the style of a harlequin mask that was on the floor of his home, and sets out to seek revenge with the crow as his guide. I cannot adequately express how much I love this movie. The tone, the cinematography, the soundtrack, the antagonists. Everything about this movie is top-drawer. Fans of the graphic novel of the same name that inspired the film say that the master criminal in the film, known as Top Dollar in the novel and not actually given a name in the film, was far more ordinary than the evil genius Michael Wincott portrayed. Other critics say that the death of Brandon Lee gave this film a legacy it didn't earn, much the same way that critics claim Heath Ledger's death before the release of The Dark Knight added anticipation it wouldn't have gotten otherwise. As I was only ten when the film was first released, I was not aware of the film itself or Lee's death until much later. What I will say is that I cannot watch this film enough. Even so, if you haven't seen The Crow, shame on you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I don't know why this movie rated so high. Wast of time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    hdgunners
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I wasted 97 minutes of my life on this crap because of this IMDb rating. But I will advise who hasn't still seen this movie don't waste your time on this crap movie. I really wanted to see and like that movie but honestly speaking while watching the movie i dozed off a few times. Apart from the atmosphere, set design and photography everything is so dull and boring. Acting, screenplay, direction and every other thing about the movie are so poor and mediocre I cant help but to dislike the movie. Editing at some places seems rushed. and From Bruce Lee son you expect at least good action and martial arts skills but well what you get lifeless action and no martial arts. i amaze that i seen the same movie as the other. Awful movie not recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Crow  Revenge from beyond the grave on a human level and emotional
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Avid Climber
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Crow is by now a cult movie. Although it's getting a bit old for some of its special effects, it's still excellent. The soundtrack, especially the music, is exceptional. It's edgy, dark, and the emotions it stirs get you in the guts. It's a mirror image of the story. The revenge theme, certainly isn't new, not even one from beyond the grave, but the angle chosen here, is quite different. It's touching. You get a great mix of action, emotional drama, ghostly romance, and human relations, often dark and twisted, other times simple or basic. The sets are very dark and strongly Gothic. The acting is not perfect, but still strong and just. There are a few mistakes, not big, but at times noticeable, like some bad sound pickups. However, they seem to make the film into some sort of archaic rendition, which really works to its advantage. I recommend it if you don't mind its age.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I'm not sure why this movie is rated so high
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    elemari-365-648550
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Simply put, this movie is very mediocre. The storyline is weak. A rock star and his fianc&eacute; are murdered on Halloween night by a gang of thugs. The rock star then returns from the dead to seek revenge on the murder and rape of his fianc&eacute;. Honestly, this plot screams clich&eacute;. The whole rock star idea is extremely cheesy and just reminds me of the rock band KISS and their dreadful costumes. The acting is decent. I feel that Brandon Lee gives off too much of a "good guy" vibe for his role. Despite being dressed up as a menacing, undead badass seeking revenge, he somehow still gives off the impression that he's a nice guy. The gang thugs seem a bit like they're trying too hard. They seem to act how they think thugs would act instead of acting like thugs. I just didn't buy it. The highlight of this film is the special effects, which were well done for 1994. Even so, they fail to outshine a cheesy plot and mediocre acting. Don't get me wrong, the movie wasn't all bad, but it just wasn't good. The Crow lies out there in the vast gray area of mediocre action films.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The best of the them all
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lagudafuad
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Crow has reached an iconic high in the movie realm, mostly because it was the last movie that Brandon Lee stared him, as he Brandon died on set during the production of the film; his death was due to a gunshot. The gun was supposed to be loaded with blanks, but one life ammunition bullet was lodged in the gun that was then loaded with blanks. His death on set made the movie gross more than the producers could ever imagine and turned this movie to a cult classic. The movie is an adaptation of a comic book series of the same name, that was created by James O'Barr and it tells the tale of the life of Eric (Brandon Lee). Eric and his fianc&eacute;e were attacked at their home, Eric got shot and he was paralyzed, and could only watch as Shelly his fianc&eacute;e is savagely beaten and raped. The attackers finally kill Eric. But a year later Eric is resurrected by a crow, now he hunts the men that killed him and his fianc&eacute;e, Eric is now an undead, unable to be killed or hurt (as long as he stays on course, which is revenge on those who killed him and his fianc&eacute;e). The movie boasts of fast paced action, the movie adaption of the comic is seen by many to be near accurate. The movie's cinematography is engaging as we mostly are moving around with Eric in the night, the camera angles or light feed never make you wish that there were gotten from another shot or you needing more light. Then there is the score, the dark rocky score that brings you into the melancholy mood of Eric as you watch, the movie doesn't at any time take you to a high of good things happening then brings you back to the main dark theme Alex Proyas (the director, and also director of Dark City (1998) and I, Robot) made sure that from the get go of this movie you are introduced to a sad theme, a sad scene, a sad story and it the movie keeps to that till the end. The Crow goes places other hero movies don't want to go, no breather just darkness. The movies special effects were most rewarding and the story is very engaging a fit none of the other sequels after it has been able to accomplish, as more sequels were being released the worse the ratings they were getting, making this movie stand out the more. A remake of this said "untouchable classic" is being done, the argument is will this remake be as good as the original or is it just going to follow the way all the other sequels went. My take on this is, Hollywood filmmakers are now at the end of their rope, going back to remake movies or dragging them into trilogies just to make more money, the remake falls into this suit if you ask me (suit of not having an idea of what movie to do), because such movies like this should never be remade. That said, I will be watching the remake with high hopes, reason being times have changed, 1994 and now that is more than 18 years, enough technological advancement that could not be employed in 1994 will be used in this remake, I just hope it won't suck. www.lagsreviews.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Crow
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rachelle Stern
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Crows Revenge This movie begins on a dark night in Detroit. The Crow , Shelly Webster (Sofia Shenas) and Eric Draven (Brandon Lee) are engaged to be married the next day on Devils Night, Halloween, the night of fires, vandalism, and crime. Unfortunately that day never came for them. Shelly was raped and murdered for trying to get a petition to help rid the neighborhood of people that weren't contributing to society and that were making it worse. Eric was also killed. One year after their deaths, Eric came back to life as the crow to seek revenge for Shelly's death. The crow makes Eric somewhat invincible to getting hurt or killed while getting the justice that is deserved. The theme of this film seems to be revenge and justice. I feel the directors of this film, Daniel J. Schow and Alex Proyas, are trying to show that even in the darkest of times and bleakness of the night justice can prevail. One must fight to make it happen though. Although Draven was turned into the crow, he still had limitations to his invincibility. The crow followed Eric around the city and was there at the times that Tin-Tin, Fun Boy and T-Bird were brought to their final doom. If the crow was hurt Eric was inevitably hurt also. Justice doesn't always come easy and it's something we have to be willing to fight for. I'm personally attracted to this film for several reasons. One being the way justice is served, another being the love between Shelly and Eric. Eric loved her so much that he was willing to die for her and bring her death to justice; their love as to die for. This film also has a certain attraction to it because it is somewhat of a thriller. It keeps us on edge and captivated. The darkness and costumes bring a certain mysterious quality to it also. Brandon Lee's skills as an actor also bring an attraction to the film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good Supernatural Thing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    manishnagi
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    what a great movie i watched today . The Crow . I had read the novel i like that so much Now i saw this movie its brilliant , it is awesome Like i said novel it is great work done by John O'Barr . Now movie is is very good adopted The acting of Brandon Lee is awesome , all the fight scenes , martial arts , everything is awesome . i feel sad for Brandon Lee that he died . R.I.P i also like the little girl Rochelle Davis who played Sarah , Her acting is good This film is very good directed an screen played . i like the way story is moving along and all this supernatural thing , It inspires me a lot I had fun watching this movie
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The is my fav movie ever!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ssj-nightwing
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A lot of people that know me know how much I love comic book movies and characters and this is true I do. Bearing in mind comic book movies are getting better and better I just can't shake how totally ninja The Crow is. I love everything about, the simple revenge plot, the dark Gothic feel, the cast, everything. I have also read the graphic novel which this movie was based on! James O' Barr is a genius! If your after a true original before Marvel and DC this is great. Forgot to mention the soundtrack is pretty good too! Burn by the Cure, Nine Inch Nails - Dead Soul and Jane Siberry's It Can't Rain all the time are spot on. Very intrigued to see what they do with the reboot!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    deveraux009-650-383191
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The film portrays a young rock guitarist who comes back from the dead to avenge the murders of himself and his fianc&eacute;e. Even as a kid I always enjoyed watching it, as I found Lee's Crow to be easily watchable and I couldn't help but sympathize with the character, thanks to Lee's performance. He truly shined as the character, and captured what James O' Barr worked hard to create in his graphic novels. The atmosphere of the film was damn perfect, and even though some of the dialogue was a bit hit-and-miss(Mainly Rochelle Davis as Sarah), the cast worked and went great together. Michael Wincott as 'Top Dollar' was easily one of the best villains interpreted on-screen, and had some of the best dialogue and scenes besides Lee. To touch up a bit about Brandon Lee as The Crow, the way Lee portrayed the title character was what made the film so great, with his powerful yet gentle charismatic presence, he made one of the best superheroes to ever hit the screen. The action in the film was alright, but without the film's good performances, it might not have carried as well. The direction of the film was practically flawless, and everything clicked just fine. Alex Proyas as director of the film was a fine choice.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sadness is the Main Character
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tjross-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is a tacit theme of sadness that is so ubiquitous throughout the entire movie that it should have been billed as the main character. It's raised to the next level when you remember that this was Brandon Lee's breakout movie and he died making it. I never read the comic so I do not know if it was true to it, but I do know that this movie had a tone that I've never felt before. Brandon Lee is simply amazing! The set design, writing, and directing are top notch--they truly transport you to the goth underbelly of a place you don't want to be. It will clearly be too violent and dark for many viewers, but if you can get over it, you will experience a brilliant film. i've seen this movie a few times and it gets better every time I see it. My only complaint is that I did not have the luxury of seeing it in a theater.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Genius
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Treyroo
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If the question were put to you, would you "go gently into that good night"? What if you weren't given the choice and, instead, were left with the more grisly task of balancing the scales? Would you take it? It's Mischief Night, or Devil's Night as it's referred to in this film, in Detroit and the night before musician Eric Draven (played by Brandon Lee) and Shelley Webster (played by Sofia Shinas) are to be married. Then, thanks to their efforts to fight eviction for themselves and their fellow tenants, their home is broken into. The invaders toss Draven (Lee) through a window and send him plummeting to the ground three stories below and savage his bride-to-be. The first officer on the scene is Sgt. Albrecht (played by Ernie Hudson) and when Shelley asks about her fianc&eacute;e, he spares her the truth and tells her he's fine. Then, when the latchkey kid that Eric and Shelley have taken under their wing stumbles upon the scene, Albrecht relays the lie once again. The child, Sarah (played by Rochelle Davis who also acts as the film's narrator), sees through the sergeant's reassuring fiction and departs soon after. Flash-forward one year, Sarah is visiting the graveyard where Shelly and Eric have been laid to rest and encounters a crow. After she'd left, the crow begins tapping on Eric's headstone with his beak. Then, that night, Eric emerges from his grave, shaking and traumatized. He returns to the apartment that he and Shelley once shared and finds that it is a ruin of the home he knew. While there, he begins experiencing flashbacks of the night one year before when he lost everything. Seeing the men responsible, who call themselves T-Bird (played by David Patrick Kelly), Tin-Tin (played by Laurence Mason), Funboy (played by Michael Massee), and Skank (played by Angel David). Still reeling from those memories, Eric grabs onto the frame that once held the apartment's only window and swings out and back in. He notices that he's cut himself on remnants on the window but, to his surprise, he heals almost immediately. With this new gift, he dons all black clothes, decorates his face in the style of a harlequin mask that was on the floor of his home, and sets out to seek revenge with the crow as his guide. I cannot adequately express how much I love this movie. The tone, the cinematography, the soundtrack, the antagonists. Everything about this movie is top-drawer. Fans of the graphic novel of the same name that inspired the film say that the master criminal in the film, known as Top Dollar in the novel and not actually given a name in the film, was far more ordinary than the evil genius Michael Wincott portrayed. Other critics say that the death of Brandon Lee gave this film a legacy it didn't earn, much the same way that critics claim Heath Ledger's death before the release of The Dark Knight added anticipation it wouldn't have gotten otherwise. As I was only ten when the film was first released, I was not aware of the film itself or Lee's death until much later. What I will say is that I cannot watch this film enough. Even so, if you haven't seen The Crow, shame on you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I don't know why this movie rated so high. Wast of time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    hdgunners
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I wasted 97 minutes of my life on this crap because of this IMDb rating. But I will advise who hasn't still seen this movie don't waste your time on this crap movie. I really wanted to see and like that movie but honestly speaking while watching the movie i dozed off a few times. Apart from the atmosphere, set design and photography everything is so dull and boring. Acting, screenplay, direction and every other thing about the movie are so poor and mediocre I cant help but to dislike the movie. Editing at some places seems rushed. and From Bruce Lee son you expect at least good action and martial arts skills but well what you get lifeless action and no martial arts. i amaze that i seen the same movie as the other. Awful movie not recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Crow  Revenge from beyond the grave on a human level and emotional
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Avid Climber
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Crow is by now a cult movie. Although it's getting a bit old for some of its special effects, it's still excellent. The soundtrack, especially the music, is exceptional. It's edgy, dark, and the emotions it stirs get you in the guts. It's a mirror image of the story. The revenge theme, certainly isn't new, not even one from beyond the grave, but the angle chosen here, is quite different. It's touching. You get a great mix of action, emotional drama, ghostly romance, and human relations, often dark and twisted, other times simple or basic. The sets are very dark and strongly Gothic. The acting is not perfect, but still strong and just. There are a few mistakes, not big, but at times noticeable, like some bad sound pickups. However, they seem to make the film into some sort of archaic rendition, which really works to its advantage. I recommend it if you don't mind its age.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I'm not sure why this movie is rated so high
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    elemari-365-648550
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Simply put, this movie is very mediocre. The storyline is weak. A rock star and his fianc&eacute; are murdered on Halloween night by a gang of thugs. The rock star then returns from the dead to seek revenge on the murder and rape of his fianc&eacute;. Honestly, this plot screams clich&eacute;. The whole rock star idea is extremely cheesy and just reminds me of the rock band KISS and their dreadful costumes. The acting is decent. I feel that Brandon Lee gives off too much of a "good guy" vibe for his role. Despite being dressed up as a menacing, undead badass seeking revenge, he somehow still gives off the impression that he's a nice guy. The gang thugs seem a bit like they're trying too hard. They seem to act how they think thugs would act instead of acting like thugs. I just didn't buy it. The highlight of this film is the special effects, which were well done for 1994. Even so, they fail to outshine a cheesy plot and mediocre acting. Don't get me wrong, the movie wasn't all bad, but it just wasn't good. The Crow lies out there in the vast gray area of mediocre action films.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The best of the them all
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lagudafuad
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Crow has reached an iconic high in the movie realm, mostly because it was the last movie that Brandon Lee stared him, as he Brandon died on set during the production of the film; his death was due to a gunshot. The gun was supposed to be loaded with blanks, but one life ammunition bullet was lodged in the gun that was then loaded with blanks. His death on set made the movie gross more than the producers could ever imagine and turned this movie to a cult classic. The movie is an adaptation of a comic book series of the same name, that was created by James O'Barr and it tells the tale of the life of Eric (Brandon Lee). Eric and his fianc&eacute;e were attacked at their home, Eric got shot and he was paralyzed, and could only watch as Shelly his fianc&eacute;e is savagely beaten and raped. The attackers finally kill Eric. But a year later Eric is resurrected by a crow, now he hunts the men that killed him and his fianc&eacute;e, Eric is now an undead, unable to be killed or hurt (as long as he stays on course, which is revenge on those who killed him and his fianc&eacute;e). The movie boasts of fast paced action, the movie adaption of the comic is seen by many to be near accurate. The movie's cinematography is engaging as we mostly are moving around with Eric in the night, the camera angles or light feed never make you wish that there were gotten from another shot or you needing more light. Then there is the score, the dark rocky score that brings you into the melancholy mood of Eric as you watch, the movie doesn't at any time take you to a high of good things happening then brings you back to the main dark theme Alex Proyas (the director, and also director of Dark City (1998) and I, Robot) made sure that from the get go of this movie you are introduced to a sad theme, a sad scene, a sad story and it the movie keeps to that till the end. The Crow goes places other hero movies don't want to go, no breather just darkness. The movies special effects were most rewarding and the story is very engaging a fit none of the other sequels after it has been able to accomplish, as more sequels were being released the worse the ratings they were getting, making this movie stand out the more. A remake of this said "untouchable classic" is being done, the argument is will this remake be as good as the original or is it just going to follow the way all the other sequels went. My take on this is, Hollywood filmmakers are now at the end of their rope, going back to remake movies or dragging them into trilogies just to make more money, the remake falls into this suit if you ask me (suit of not having an idea of what movie to do), because such movies like this should never be remade. That said, I will be watching the remake with high hopes, reason being times have changed, 1994 and now that is more than 18 years, enough technological advancement that could not be employed in 1994 will be used in this remake, I just hope it won't suck. www.lagsreviews.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Crow
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rachelle Stern
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Crows Revenge This movie begins on a dark night in Detroit. The Crow , Shelly Webster (Sofia Shenas) and Eric Draven (Brandon Lee) are engaged to be married the next day on Devils Night, Halloween, the night of fires, vandalism, and crime. Unfortunately that day never came for them. Shelly was raped and murdered for trying to get a petition to help rid the neighborhood of people that weren't contributing to society and that were making it worse. Eric was also killed. One year after their deaths, Eric came back to life as the crow to seek revenge for Shelly's death. The crow makes Eric somewhat invincible to getting hurt or killed while getting the justice that is deserved. The theme of this film seems to be revenge and justice. I feel the directors of this film, Daniel J. Schow and Alex Proyas, are trying to show that even in the darkest of times and bleakness of the night justice can prevail. One must fight to make it happen though. Although Draven was turned into the crow, he still had limitations to his invincibility. The crow followed Eric around the city and was there at the times that Tin-Tin, Fun Boy and T-Bird were brought to their final doom. If the crow was hurt Eric was inevitably hurt also. Justice doesn't always come easy and it's something we have to be willing to fight for. I'm personally attracted to this film for several reasons. One being the way justice is served, another being the love between Shelly and Eric. Eric loved her so much that he was willing to die for her and bring her death to justice; their love as to die for. This film also has a certain attraction to it because it is somewhat of a thriller. It keeps us on edge and captivated. The darkness and costumes bring a certain mysterious quality to it also. Brandon Lee's skills as an actor also bring an attraction to the film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good Supernatural Thing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    manishnagi
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    what a great movie i watched today . The Crow . I had read the novel i like that so much Now i saw this movie its brilliant , it is awesome Like i said novel it is great work done by John O'Barr . Now movie is is very good adopted The acting of Brandon Lee is awesome , all the fight scenes , martial arts , everything is awesome . i feel sad for Brandon Lee that he died . R.I.P i also like the little girl Rochelle Davis who played Sarah , Her acting is good This film is very good directed an screen played . i like the way story is moving along and all this supernatural thing , It inspires me a lot I had fun watching this movie
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The is my fav movie ever!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ssj-nightwing
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A lot of people that know me know how much I love comic book movies and characters and this is true I do. Bearing in mind comic book movies are getting better and better I just can't shake how totally ninja The Crow is. I love everything about, the simple revenge plot, the dark Gothic feel, the cast, everything. I have also read the graphic novel which this movie was based on! James O' Barr is a genius! If your after a true original before Marvel and DC this is great. Forgot to mention the soundtrack is pretty good too! Burn by the Cure, Nine Inch Nails - Dead Soul and Jane Siberry's It Can't Rain all the time are spot on. Very intrigued to see what they do with the reboot!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    deveraux009-650-383191
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The film portrays a young rock guitarist who comes back from the dead to avenge the murders of himself and his fianc&eacute;e. Even as a kid I always enjoyed watching it, as I found Lee's Crow to be easily watchable and I couldn't help but sympathize with the character, thanks to Lee's performance. He truly shined as the character, and captured what James O' Barr worked hard to create in his graphic novels. The atmosphere of the film was damn perfect, and even though some of the dialogue was a bit hit-and-miss(Mainly Rochelle Davis as Sarah), the cast worked and went great together. Michael Wincott as 'Top Dollar' was easily one of the best villains interpreted on-screen, and had some of the best dialogue and scenes besides Lee. To touch up a bit about Brandon Lee as The Crow, the way Lee portrayed the title character was what made the film so great, with his powerful yet gentle charismatic presence, he made one of the best superheroes to ever hit the screen. The action in the film was alright, but without the film's good performances, it might not have carried as well. The direction of the film was practically flawless, and everything clicked just fine. Alex Proyas as director of the film was a fine choice.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sadness is the Main Character
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tjross-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is a tacit theme of sadness that is so ubiquitous throughout the entire movie that it should have been billed as the main character. It's raised to the next level when you remember that this was Brandon Lee's breakout movie and he died making it. I never read the comic so I do not know if it was true to it, but I do know that this movie had a tone that I've never felt before. Brandon Lee is simply amazing! The set design, writing, and directing are top notch--they truly transport you to the goth underbelly of a place you don't want to be. It will clearly be too violent and dark for many viewers, but if you can get over it, you will experience a brilliant film. i've seen this movie a few times and it gets better every time I see it. My only complaint is that I did not have the luxury of seeing it in a theater.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Genius
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Treyroo
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If the question were put to you, would you "go gently into that good night"? What if you weren't given the choice and, instead, were left with the more grisly task of balancing the scales? Would you take it? It's Mischief Night, or Devil's Night as it's referred to in this film, in Detroit and the night before musician Eric Draven (played by Brandon Lee) and Shelley Webster (played by Sofia Shinas) are to be married. Then, thanks to their efforts to fight eviction for themselves and their fellow tenants, their home is broken into. The invaders toss Draven (Lee) through a window and send him plummeting to the ground three stories below and savage his bride-to-be. The first officer on the scene is Sgt. Albrecht (played by Ernie Hudson) and when Shelley asks about her fianc&eacute;e, he spares her the truth and tells her he's fine. Then, when the latchkey kid that Eric and Shelley have taken under their wing stumbles upon the scene, Albrecht relays the lie once again. The child, Sarah (played by Rochelle Davis who also acts as the film's narrator), sees through the sergeant's reassuring fiction and departs soon after. Flash-forward one year, Sarah is visiting the graveyard where Shelly and Eric have been laid to rest and encounters a crow. After she'd left, the crow begins tapping on Eric's headstone with his beak. Then, that night, Eric emerges from his grave, shaking and traumatized. He returns to the apartment that he and Shelley once shared and finds that it is a ruin of the home he knew. While there, he begins experiencing flashbacks of the night one year before when he lost everything. Seeing the men responsible, who call themselves T-Bird (played by David Patrick Kelly), Tin-Tin (played by Laurence Mason), Funboy (played by Michael Massee), and Skank (played by Angel David). Still reeling from those memories, Eric grabs onto the frame that once held the apartment's only window and swings out and back in. He notices that he's cut himself on remnants on the window but, to his surprise, he heals almost immediately. With this new gift, he dons all black clothes, decorates his face in the style of a harlequin mask that was on the floor of his home, and sets out to seek revenge with the crow as his guide. I cannot adequately express how much I love this movie. The tone, the cinematography, the soundtrack, the antagonists. Everything about this movie is top-drawer. Fans of the graphic novel of the same name that inspired the film say that the master criminal in the film, known as Top Dollar in the novel and not actually given a name in the film, was far more ordinary than the evil genius Michael Wincott portrayed. Other critics say that the death of Brandon Lee gave this film a legacy it didn't earn, much the same way that critics claim Heath Ledger's death before the release of The Dark Knight added anticipation it wouldn't have gotten otherwise. As I was only ten when the film was first released, I was not aware of the film itself or Lee's death until much later. What I will say is that I cannot watch this film enough. Even so, if you haven't seen The Crow, shame on you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I don't know why this movie rated so high. Wast of time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    hdgunners
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I wasted 97 minutes of my life on this crap because of this IMDb rating. But I will advise who hasn't still seen this movie don't waste your time on this crap movie. I really wanted to see and like that movie but honestly speaking while watching the movie i dozed off a few times. Apart from the atmosphere, set design and photography everything is so dull and boring. Acting, screenplay, direction and every other thing about the movie are so poor and mediocre I cant help but to dislike the movie. Editing at some places seems rushed. and From Bruce Lee son you expect at least good action and martial arts skills but well what you get lifeless action and no martial arts. i amaze that i seen the same movie as the other. Awful movie not recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Crow  Revenge from beyond the grave on a human level and emotional
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Avid Climber
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Crow is by now a cult movie. Although it's getting a bit old for some of its special effects, it's still excellent. The soundtrack, especially the music, is exceptional. It's edgy, dark, and the emotions it stirs get you in the guts. It's a mirror image of the story. The revenge theme, certainly isn't new, not even one from beyond the grave, but the angle chosen here, is quite different. It's touching. You get a great mix of action, emotional drama, ghostly romance, and human relations, often dark and twisted, other times simple or basic. The sets are very dark and strongly Gothic. The acting is not perfect, but still strong and just. There are a few mistakes, not big, but at times noticeable, like some bad sound pickups. However, they seem to make the film into some sort of archaic rendition, which really works to its advantage. I recommend it if you don't mind its age.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I'm not sure why this movie is rated so high
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    elemari-365-648550
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Simply put, this movie is very mediocre. The storyline is weak. A rock star and his fianc&eacute; are murdered on Halloween night by a gang of thugs. The rock star then returns from the dead to seek revenge on the murder and rape of his fianc&eacute;. Honestly, this plot screams clich&eacute;. The whole rock star idea is extremely cheesy and just reminds me of the rock band KISS and their dreadful costumes. The acting is decent. I feel that Brandon Lee gives off too much of a "good guy" vibe for his role. Despite being dressed up as a menacing, undead badass seeking revenge, he somehow still gives off the impression that he's a nice guy. The gang thugs seem a bit like they're trying too hard. They seem to act how they think thugs would act instead of acting like thugs. I just didn't buy it. The highlight of this film is the special effects, which were well done for 1994. Even so, they fail to outshine a cheesy plot and mediocre acting. Don't get me wrong, the movie wasn't all bad, but it just wasn't good. The Crow lies out there in the vast gray area of mediocre action films.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The best of the them all
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lagudafuad
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Crow has reached an iconic high in the movie realm, mostly because it was the last movie that Brandon Lee stared him, as he Brandon died on set during the production of the film; his death was due to a gunshot. The gun was supposed to be loaded with blanks, but one life ammunition bullet was lodged in the gun that was then loaded with blanks. His death on set made the movie gross more than the producers could ever imagine and turned this movie to a cult classic. The movie is an adaptation of a comic book series of the same name, that was created by James O'Barr and it tells the tale of the life of Eric (Brandon Lee). Eric and his fianc&eacute;e were attacked at their home, Eric got shot and he was paralyzed, and could only watch as Shelly his fianc&eacute;e is savagely beaten and raped. The attackers finally kill Eric. But a year later Eric is resurrected by a crow, now he hunts the men that killed him and his fianc&eacute;e, Eric is now an undead, unable to be killed or hurt (as long as he stays on course, which is revenge on those who killed him and his fianc&eacute;e). The movie boasts of fast paced action, the movie adaption of the comic is seen by many to be near accurate. The movie's cinematography is engaging as we mostly are moving around with Eric in the night, the camera angles or light feed never make you wish that there were gotten from another shot or you needing more light. Then there is the score, the dark rocky score that brings you into the melancholy mood of Eric as you watch, the movie doesn't at any time take you to a high of good things happening then brings you back to the main dark theme Alex Proyas (the director, and also director of Dark City (1998) and I, Robot) made sure that from the get go of this movie you are introduced to a sad theme, a sad scene, a sad story and it the movie keeps to that till the end. The Crow goes places other hero movies don't want to go, no breather just darkness. The movies special effects were most rewarding and the story is very engaging a fit none of the other sequels after it has been able to accomplish, as more sequels were being released the worse the ratings they were getting, making this movie stand out the more. A remake of this said "untouchable classic" is being done, the argument is will this remake be as good as the original or is it just going to follow the way all the other sequels went. My take on this is, Hollywood filmmakers are now at the end of their rope, going back to remake movies or dragging them into trilogies just to make more money, the remake falls into this suit if you ask me (suit of not having an idea of what movie to do), because such movies like this should never be remade. That said, I will be watching the remake with high hopes, reason being times have changed, 1994 and now that is more than 18 years, enough technological advancement that could not be employed in 1994 will be used in this remake, I just hope it won't suck. www.lagsreviews.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
