<filme>
 <id>
  689
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0119395
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1997
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  O Chacal
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.2
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  An imprisoned IRA sniper is freed to help stop a brutal, seemingly "faceless" assassin from completing his next job.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Russian mobster Terek Murad has declared open season on the Russian militia and the United States FBI over the shooting of his brother in a Moscow nightclub. He hires "The Jackal" -- an elusive, nasty assassin -- to kill FBI Director Donald Brown. Present at the shooting of Murad's brother were FBI Deputy Director Carter Preston and Major Valentina Koslova of the Russian militia. Nearly no one has ever seen The Jackal, save for Declan Mulqueen, an imprisoned IRA sniper. Upon learning that the Director Brown is a target, Preston and Koslova enlist the services of the reluctant Mulqueen to track down the Jackal before he can assassinate Brown.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Action
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Adventure
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Crime
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   fbi
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   jackal
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   russian
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   ira
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   assassin
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Michael Caton-Jones
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Kenneth Ross
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Chuck Pfarrer
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Bruce Willis
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Richard Gere
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Sidney Poitier
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jackal-Split Among the Soviets? ***1/2
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Apparently, in this terse thriller, there was a split between various Soviet groups. Soviets have sent the Jackal out for his next killing,but yet there are Soviets who are working against him. That being said, we have a tense thriller where Bruce Willis sheds his usual crime stopping prevention to assume the role of the cold and calculating killer. He is wonderfully matched by Richard Gere's IRA terrorist, with a great Irish accent who has a score to settle with Willis. Willis is cunning, sly and remains unknown to all with the exception of Gere who had worked with him at one time. What the Willis character does to the Jack Black character is horrifying and yet we're able to watch it on screen. Sidney Poitier gives excellent support as a CIA agent. He comes to trust the Gere character fully as seen by the film's ending.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great Performance, Standard Action Thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tabuno
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The standout performance and characterization offered up by Bruce Willis as the Jackal somehow can't lift up this action thriller to the level of greatest which is odd because the script, the story are all classic Tom Clancy movie thriller standards. Nevertheless, this movie is well worth watching just for Willis's superior cold and calculating performance that most evil assassins just become another stereotypical, sub-intelligence by the numbers performances. There is just enough rough edges in this movie to make this movie well above average because it avoids being too cute, too polished, too super-ordinary implausible and that's this movie's nuanced directed distinction.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Decent Remake of the 1970's Film--Good Acting But Somewhat Predictable Script
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    classicalsteve
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Bruce Willis and Richard Gere have to be given a lot of credit for saving this film. If not for their excellent acting, the script does lapse into somewhat predictable political-espionage thriller clich&eacute;. It's not like we don't have a lot of similar fair piled into the film archives of the studios. Willis makes a great assassin nicknamed "Jackal". He' been hired out for 70 million no less to take out somewhat in the US, but we don't know who. He's the ultimate man of mystery, taking on different disguises in different part of the country. The FBI and CIA can't get a handle on him. Figures. So the only guy who might have a chance to keep the Jackal from blowing up the whole country is a US prisoner formerly with the IRA. Although not all the details are clear, he was involved in some kind of operation with the Jackall who shot his bride-to-be, wounding her and killing their unborn child in the process. The CIA and FBI, headed by Sidney Poitier, convince Gere to sign onto the operation to stop the Jackal from whatever heinous crime he is going to enact, which we assume is of a higher import than taking out the local janitor. He already does that with ease. In exchange, he might be released. The best parts of the film consist of the many disguises Willis dons as the Jackal. In one, he appears like a former hippie out of the Haight-Ashbury with long blond hair and plaid shirt untucked. In another, he's an international businessman. He even plays a homosexual. In one of his more contrived efforts, he's an overweight laborer with hideous taste in clothes. But he not only disguises himself. He constantly changes the color and plates of his van. And those who gets in his way pay the usual price. A superb cast infiltrates this movie. Besides Willis, Poitier, and Gere, even Jack Black makes a surprise appearance as a sleazy underground arms manufacturer. He receives an order from Willis to supply him with some kind of weapons device. Half now, half on delivery, Willis' typical terms. Of course, the schmuck doesn't understand who he's dealing with. You don't up the price on a hired assassin. Pretty good through about 2/3rd's to 3/4th's. When the actual crime is finally revealed, I found it somewhat of a let down. The very end seemed typical of many films of this type, leading to a final confrontation with Willis and Gere. I was hoping the film would take a detour and lead in an unexpected direction, but about 30 minutes toward the end, I kind of knew where it was going. That said, Willis' portrayal is still worth the price of admission.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not that good!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    spaz47
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a remake of an earlier film: "The day of the Jackal," which was far more believable and intense. The weapon used in the 1st film was very small and deadly, yet could be hidden very easily. In the 2nd film, the weapon in question looks like it belongs on a Bradley Fighting Vehicle! Also in the 1st film the detective solves the case; here we have An imprisoned Irish terrorist teaching a highly experienced FBI agent his job! A really "badly written" scene was where the 3 FBI agents have moved a family out of their house and the FBI folks are "cleaning up.(?) You actually have an FBI agent taking out the garbage! Trust me, agents don't have the time for this. Also, as soon as they noticed the 1st agent was missing and probably dead, they would have vacated the house and called for back-up! They should have also cut the speaker wires on the sound system that the Jackal was using to distract them! Yes, entertaining, but no where as good as the original...and remember that "lethal spray" that Willis used on his van to kill a "hijacker?" Nobody knows what it was. Well I'll tell you: it was "Anti-credibility spray" that destroys all credibility in any film that it's in...hooray for Hollywood!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bruce Willis is the whole show
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    msroz
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The original movie "Day of the Jackal" has nothing to worry about from this remake. I'd like to know why the Jackal intentionally gives important clues throughout. I'd like to know how Isabella knew where Declan (Richard Gere) was in the subway and where she got another gun. I'd like to know why the Jackal kills 3 agents in Isabella's hiding place, and then she shows up. I'd like to know how Willis got the weapon off the boat and to another location. That's enough loose ends for now. The second half was not as good as the first half, but the whole movie was surprisingly lacking in tension. It had too many hackneyed lines. It seemed tired. Sidney Poitier seemed tired. Willis was very good. His expressions and facial contortions and impassiveness at times made the movie. Gere's part was just too Hollywoodized. I knew that Diane Venora would bite the dust. She underplayed admirably. A flabby thriller flabbily directed. Apart from Willis, it had a neat monster weapon and method of assassination.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Solid, But Generic Thriller!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    g-bodyl
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Jackal is based of the 1973 film, The Day of the Jackal. This 1997 version is a different story than the 1973 version. It is more of a generic story with the feeling "been there, done that." However, it is still a good movie with action, great acting, and some unexpected moments. This is about how FBI deputy director gets a terrorist, Mulqueen out of prison to help him track down a shady assassin, known as the Jackal, before he assassinates his political targets. The acting is great. Bruce Willis and Richard Gere had great chemistry. Willis was the reason why I saw this movie. I was surprised to see Sidney Poitier here but he did a great job as usual. Overall, this is a solid film that is there for enjoyment, not for awards or major critical success. Even though I seen many of these kind of films, I liked it. I rate this film 8/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An underrated thriller undeserving of all the hate.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Shawn Watson (gator_macready@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've never understood why The Jackal has been cursed with poor reviews from pretty much everybody. From the day I saw it as a 17-year-old in January 1998 I always found it entertaining and exciting. This might be down to the fact that I have never seen the 1973 original. Brucie plays a nameless assassin, cool as ice and utterly emotionless. Richard Gere is the only man to have seen him. He's let out of prison to assist the FBI in catching the Jackal before he takes out an uncertain high-ranking official. Willis and Gere are, for the most part, leading their own movies as they never meet until the climax. It's very interesting watching them both go about their business, Willis hatching a master plan and Gere methodically picking apart his trail and hunting him down. There is great support from Sidney Poitier and cutie-pie Diane Venora as a scarred Russian cop. With a wide variety of brilliantly photographed locations across the US and Canada, and plot with a medium-level of complexity it's not entirely brainless viewing but not too taxing as to alienate lazy viewers. I honestly do not get why so many people hate it. Willis has done far worse films (even seen Mercury Rising?) that get off scot-free somehow, but The Jackal doesn't get off so lightly. Aside from Gere's slightly dodgy Oirish accent I have no complaints about this film. Give it a chance and you might just be entertained.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This film deserves a more honest look
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rene2030
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Yeah, I know, it is so easy to bash this film as so many of you have done. It's a thriller that doesn't stand out in it's genre, pretty easy to watch but not more than that. It has a high profile cast including Bruce Willis, Richard Gere and a couple of very very decent actors slash actresses like J.K. Simmons, Diane Venora and so on, so nothing wrong with that. A more than decent director in Michael Caton-Jones, who does his best with the material he's got and doing a good job at it. Sadly he has to work with a script that has potholes the size of Hummers H3 in it, so it's easy to see why this film doesn't work the way it's supposed to. but!!!! If you have read some of the novels written by Robert Ludlum (may God rest his soul) you will have picked up some of the vibe he has put in most of his novels, putting the Jason Bourne Trilogy upfront. And just to be clear about it, I'm not talking about the miniseries starring Richard Chamberlain and also not even mentioning the Matt Damon movies (although those were really cool) but the original novels as Mr. Ludlum intended them to be. If you have these novels in the back of your head and are a fan of them you will find this movie pretty enjoyable to watch although the execution of this movie has some problems in staying believable. It is in general a pretty normal thriller with (&Iacute;'m sorry to say) some mayor flaws. But I can't escape the feeling that the script (allthough adapted from an apparent classic of which I haven't yet had the pleasure of watching) was written in the mindset of an all-out genius Robert Ludlum-vibe, which I picked up on immediately and enjoyed very much.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This is not a remake
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    boatista24
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I think people here expect to see a remake of The Day of the Jackal. This movie has nothing to do with The Day of the Jackal. This is an independent fictitious tale based upon Carlos the Jackal. It is one of my favorite Bruce Willis flicks, and has one of the greatest movie scores of all time. As far as entertainment by Bruce Willis goes, this is an 8 out of 10, hands down. Get over this being a lousy remake of an entirely different movie, and appreciate it for what it is. An outstanding effort - $60 million worth. In my opinion, Bruce Willis is as good as a bad guy as he was in any of his good guy roles. I would not dismiss this movie until you see how great he was in it. A terrific cast and great story line make this a must see.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Slow and too traditionally scripted
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rightwingisevil
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie needs some patience to watch along. The screenplay was not quite well written, it's too loose and too slow and too traditionally directed, edited with bad casting job. The Special Agent on this case was too old and not quite necessary with a role in this movie. The cooperation between the Russian and the American were a bit ridiculous and unconvincing, the sound track, the music came along with the whole movie was so bad and so out of place. The so-called "Jackal" played by Bruce Willis was too pretentious and too clich&eacute;. Casting a scar-faced Russian Military Intelligence officer was also unnecessary. But the major problem was the lame role of the FBI Special Agent in Charge, Sydney Pottier was too old not to be forced into retirement maybe 10 years late. The whole movie spent a lot of money on locations, but the lame dialog simply failed to comply with the lame screenplay. The most ridiculous thing was the never stop changing hair style and the colors as though the only thing the Jackal good at was changing his hair colors and style. Arranged a IRA terrorist imprisoned in the U.S. territory was also a very lame scenario, Richard Gere in this movie was just like a lame office boy who's so smart that every time he could just cut in during FBI meetings to point out something nobody thought about, the smartest kid in the classroom. This is a very stupid and lame movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jackal-Split Among the Soviets? ***1/2
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Apparently, in this terse thriller, there was a split between various Soviet groups. Soviets have sent the Jackal out for his next killing,but yet there are Soviets who are working against him. That being said, we have a tense thriller where Bruce Willis sheds his usual crime stopping prevention to assume the role of the cold and calculating killer. He is wonderfully matched by Richard Gere's IRA terrorist, with a great Irish accent who has a score to settle with Willis. Willis is cunning, sly and remains unknown to all with the exception of Gere who had worked with him at one time. What the Willis character does to the Jack Black character is horrifying and yet we're able to watch it on screen. Sidney Poitier gives excellent support as a CIA agent. He comes to trust the Gere character fully as seen by the film's ending.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great Performance, Standard Action Thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tabuno
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The standout performance and characterization offered up by Bruce Willis as the Jackal somehow can't lift up this action thriller to the level of greatest which is odd because the script, the story are all classic Tom Clancy movie thriller standards. Nevertheless, this movie is well worth watching just for Willis's superior cold and calculating performance that most evil assassins just become another stereotypical, sub-intelligence by the numbers performances. There is just enough rough edges in this movie to make this movie well above average because it avoids being too cute, too polished, too super-ordinary implausible and that's this movie's nuanced directed distinction.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Decent Remake of the 1970's Film--Good Acting But Somewhat Predictable Script
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    classicalsteve
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Bruce Willis and Richard Gere have to be given a lot of credit for saving this film. If not for their excellent acting, the script does lapse into somewhat predictable political-espionage thriller clich&eacute;. It's not like we don't have a lot of similar fair piled into the film archives of the studios. Willis makes a great assassin nicknamed "Jackal". He' been hired out for 70 million no less to take out somewhat in the US, but we don't know who. He's the ultimate man of mystery, taking on different disguises in different part of the country. The FBI and CIA can't get a handle on him. Figures. So the only guy who might have a chance to keep the Jackal from blowing up the whole country is a US prisoner formerly with the IRA. Although not all the details are clear, he was involved in some kind of operation with the Jackall who shot his bride-to-be, wounding her and killing their unborn child in the process. The CIA and FBI, headed by Sidney Poitier, convince Gere to sign onto the operation to stop the Jackal from whatever heinous crime he is going to enact, which we assume is of a higher import than taking out the local janitor. He already does that with ease. In exchange, he might be released. The best parts of the film consist of the many disguises Willis dons as the Jackal. In one, he appears like a former hippie out of the Haight-Ashbury with long blond hair and plaid shirt untucked. In another, he's an international businessman. He even plays a homosexual. In one of his more contrived efforts, he's an overweight laborer with hideous taste in clothes. But he not only disguises himself. He constantly changes the color and plates of his van. And those who gets in his way pay the usual price. A superb cast infiltrates this movie. Besides Willis, Poitier, and Gere, even Jack Black makes a surprise appearance as a sleazy underground arms manufacturer. He receives an order from Willis to supply him with some kind of weapons device. Half now, half on delivery, Willis' typical terms. Of course, the schmuck doesn't understand who he's dealing with. You don't up the price on a hired assassin. Pretty good through about 2/3rd's to 3/4th's. When the actual crime is finally revealed, I found it somewhat of a let down. The very end seemed typical of many films of this type, leading to a final confrontation with Willis and Gere. I was hoping the film would take a detour and lead in an unexpected direction, but about 30 minutes toward the end, I kind of knew where it was going. That said, Willis' portrayal is still worth the price of admission.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not that good!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    spaz47
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a remake of an earlier film: "The day of the Jackal," which was far more believable and intense. The weapon used in the 1st film was very small and deadly, yet could be hidden very easily. In the 2nd film, the weapon in question looks like it belongs on a Bradley Fighting Vehicle! Also in the 1st film the detective solves the case; here we have An imprisoned Irish terrorist teaching a highly experienced FBI agent his job! A really "badly written" scene was where the 3 FBI agents have moved a family out of their house and the FBI folks are "cleaning up.(?) You actually have an FBI agent taking out the garbage! Trust me, agents don't have the time for this. Also, as soon as they noticed the 1st agent was missing and probably dead, they would have vacated the house and called for back-up! They should have also cut the speaker wires on the sound system that the Jackal was using to distract them! Yes, entertaining, but no where as good as the original...and remember that "lethal spray" that Willis used on his van to kill a "hijacker?" Nobody knows what it was. Well I'll tell you: it was "Anti-credibility spray" that destroys all credibility in any film that it's in...hooray for Hollywood!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bruce Willis is the whole show
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    msroz
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The original movie "Day of the Jackal" has nothing to worry about from this remake. I'd like to know why the Jackal intentionally gives important clues throughout. I'd like to know how Isabella knew where Declan (Richard Gere) was in the subway and where she got another gun. I'd like to know why the Jackal kills 3 agents in Isabella's hiding place, and then she shows up. I'd like to know how Willis got the weapon off the boat and to another location. That's enough loose ends for now. The second half was not as good as the first half, but the whole movie was surprisingly lacking in tension. It had too many hackneyed lines. It seemed tired. Sidney Poitier seemed tired. Willis was very good. His expressions and facial contortions and impassiveness at times made the movie. Gere's part was just too Hollywoodized. I knew that Diane Venora would bite the dust. She underplayed admirably. A flabby thriller flabbily directed. Apart from Willis, it had a neat monster weapon and method of assassination.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Solid, But Generic Thriller!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    g-bodyl
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Jackal is based of the 1973 film, The Day of the Jackal. This 1997 version is a different story than the 1973 version. It is more of a generic story with the feeling "been there, done that." However, it is still a good movie with action, great acting, and some unexpected moments. This is about how FBI deputy director gets a terrorist, Mulqueen out of prison to help him track down a shady assassin, known as the Jackal, before he assassinates his political targets. The acting is great. Bruce Willis and Richard Gere had great chemistry. Willis was the reason why I saw this movie. I was surprised to see Sidney Poitier here but he did a great job as usual. Overall, this is a solid film that is there for enjoyment, not for awards or major critical success. Even though I seen many of these kind of films, I liked it. I rate this film 8/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An underrated thriller undeserving of all the hate.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Shawn Watson (gator_macready@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've never understood why The Jackal has been cursed with poor reviews from pretty much everybody. From the day I saw it as a 17-year-old in January 1998 I always found it entertaining and exciting. This might be down to the fact that I have never seen the 1973 original. Brucie plays a nameless assassin, cool as ice and utterly emotionless. Richard Gere is the only man to have seen him. He's let out of prison to assist the FBI in catching the Jackal before he takes out an uncertain high-ranking official. Willis and Gere are, for the most part, leading their own movies as they never meet until the climax. It's very interesting watching them both go about their business, Willis hatching a master plan and Gere methodically picking apart his trail and hunting him down. There is great support from Sidney Poitier and cutie-pie Diane Venora as a scarred Russian cop. With a wide variety of brilliantly photographed locations across the US and Canada, and plot with a medium-level of complexity it's not entirely brainless viewing but not too taxing as to alienate lazy viewers. I honestly do not get why so many people hate it. Willis has done far worse films (even seen Mercury Rising?) that get off scot-free somehow, but The Jackal doesn't get off so lightly. Aside from Gere's slightly dodgy Oirish accent I have no complaints about this film. Give it a chance and you might just be entertained.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This film deserves a more honest look
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rene2030
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Yeah, I know, it is so easy to bash this film as so many of you have done. It's a thriller that doesn't stand out in it's genre, pretty easy to watch but not more than that. It has a high profile cast including Bruce Willis, Richard Gere and a couple of very very decent actors slash actresses like J.K. Simmons, Diane Venora and so on, so nothing wrong with that. A more than decent director in Michael Caton-Jones, who does his best with the material he's got and doing a good job at it. Sadly he has to work with a script that has potholes the size of Hummers H3 in it, so it's easy to see why this film doesn't work the way it's supposed to. but!!!! If you have read some of the novels written by Robert Ludlum (may God rest his soul) you will have picked up some of the vibe he has put in most of his novels, putting the Jason Bourne Trilogy upfront. And just to be clear about it, I'm not talking about the miniseries starring Richard Chamberlain and also not even mentioning the Matt Damon movies (although those were really cool) but the original novels as Mr. Ludlum intended them to be. If you have these novels in the back of your head and are a fan of them you will find this movie pretty enjoyable to watch although the execution of this movie has some problems in staying believable. It is in general a pretty normal thriller with (&Iacute;'m sorry to say) some mayor flaws. But I can't escape the feeling that the script (allthough adapted from an apparent classic of which I haven't yet had the pleasure of watching) was written in the mindset of an all-out genius Robert Ludlum-vibe, which I picked up on immediately and enjoyed very much.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This is not a remake
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    boatista24
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I think people here expect to see a remake of The Day of the Jackal. This movie has nothing to do with The Day of the Jackal. This is an independent fictitious tale based upon Carlos the Jackal. It is one of my favorite Bruce Willis flicks, and has one of the greatest movie scores of all time. As far as entertainment by Bruce Willis goes, this is an 8 out of 10, hands down. Get over this being a lousy remake of an entirely different movie, and appreciate it for what it is. An outstanding effort - $60 million worth. In my opinion, Bruce Willis is as good as a bad guy as he was in any of his good guy roles. I would not dismiss this movie until you see how great he was in it. A terrific cast and great story line make this a must see.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Slow and too traditionally scripted
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rightwingisevil
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie needs some patience to watch along. The screenplay was not quite well written, it's too loose and too slow and too traditionally directed, edited with bad casting job. The Special Agent on this case was too old and not quite necessary with a role in this movie. The cooperation between the Russian and the American were a bit ridiculous and unconvincing, the sound track, the music came along with the whole movie was so bad and so out of place. The so-called "Jackal" played by Bruce Willis was too pretentious and too clich&eacute;. Casting a scar-faced Russian Military Intelligence officer was also unnecessary. But the major problem was the lame role of the FBI Special Agent in Charge, Sydney Pottier was too old not to be forced into retirement maybe 10 years late. The whole movie spent a lot of money on locations, but the lame dialog simply failed to comply with the lame screenplay. The most ridiculous thing was the never stop changing hair style and the colors as though the only thing the Jackal good at was changing his hair colors and style. Arranged a IRA terrorist imprisoned in the U.S. territory was also a very lame scenario, Richard Gere in this movie was just like a lame office boy who's so smart that every time he could just cut in during FBI meetings to point out something nobody thought about, the smartest kid in the classroom. This is a very stupid and lame movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jackal-Split Among the Soviets? ***1/2
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Apparently, in this terse thriller, there was a split between various Soviet groups. Soviets have sent the Jackal out for his next killing,but yet there are Soviets who are working against him. That being said, we have a tense thriller where Bruce Willis sheds his usual crime stopping prevention to assume the role of the cold and calculating killer. He is wonderfully matched by Richard Gere's IRA terrorist, with a great Irish accent who has a score to settle with Willis. Willis is cunning, sly and remains unknown to all with the exception of Gere who had worked with him at one time. What the Willis character does to the Jack Black character is horrifying and yet we're able to watch it on screen. Sidney Poitier gives excellent support as a CIA agent. He comes to trust the Gere character fully as seen by the film's ending.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great Performance, Standard Action Thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tabuno
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The standout performance and characterization offered up by Bruce Willis as the Jackal somehow can't lift up this action thriller to the level of greatest which is odd because the script, the story are all classic Tom Clancy movie thriller standards. Nevertheless, this movie is well worth watching just for Willis's superior cold and calculating performance that most evil assassins just become another stereotypical, sub-intelligence by the numbers performances. There is just enough rough edges in this movie to make this movie well above average because it avoids being too cute, too polished, too super-ordinary implausible and that's this movie's nuanced directed distinction.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Decent Remake of the 1970's Film--Good Acting But Somewhat Predictable Script
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    classicalsteve
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Bruce Willis and Richard Gere have to be given a lot of credit for saving this film. If not for their excellent acting, the script does lapse into somewhat predictable political-espionage thriller clich&eacute;. It's not like we don't have a lot of similar fair piled into the film archives of the studios. Willis makes a great assassin nicknamed "Jackal". He' been hired out for 70 million no less to take out somewhat in the US, but we don't know who. He's the ultimate man of mystery, taking on different disguises in different part of the country. The FBI and CIA can't get a handle on him. Figures. So the only guy who might have a chance to keep the Jackal from blowing up the whole country is a US prisoner formerly with the IRA. Although not all the details are clear, he was involved in some kind of operation with the Jackall who shot his bride-to-be, wounding her and killing their unborn child in the process. The CIA and FBI, headed by Sidney Poitier, convince Gere to sign onto the operation to stop the Jackal from whatever heinous crime he is going to enact, which we assume is of a higher import than taking out the local janitor. He already does that with ease. In exchange, he might be released. The best parts of the film consist of the many disguises Willis dons as the Jackal. In one, he appears like a former hippie out of the Haight-Ashbury with long blond hair and plaid shirt untucked. In another, he's an international businessman. He even plays a homosexual. In one of his more contrived efforts, he's an overweight laborer with hideous taste in clothes. But he not only disguises himself. He constantly changes the color and plates of his van. And those who gets in his way pay the usual price. A superb cast infiltrates this movie. Besides Willis, Poitier, and Gere, even Jack Black makes a surprise appearance as a sleazy underground arms manufacturer. He receives an order from Willis to supply him with some kind of weapons device. Half now, half on delivery, Willis' typical terms. Of course, the schmuck doesn't understand who he's dealing with. You don't up the price on a hired assassin. Pretty good through about 2/3rd's to 3/4th's. When the actual crime is finally revealed, I found it somewhat of a let down. The very end seemed typical of many films of this type, leading to a final confrontation with Willis and Gere. I was hoping the film would take a detour and lead in an unexpected direction, but about 30 minutes toward the end, I kind of knew where it was going. That said, Willis' portrayal is still worth the price of admission.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not that good!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    spaz47
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a remake of an earlier film: "The day of the Jackal," which was far more believable and intense. The weapon used in the 1st film was very small and deadly, yet could be hidden very easily. In the 2nd film, the weapon in question looks like it belongs on a Bradley Fighting Vehicle! Also in the 1st film the detective solves the case; here we have An imprisoned Irish terrorist teaching a highly experienced FBI agent his job! A really "badly written" scene was where the 3 FBI agents have moved a family out of their house and the FBI folks are "cleaning up.(?) You actually have an FBI agent taking out the garbage! Trust me, agents don't have the time for this. Also, as soon as they noticed the 1st agent was missing and probably dead, they would have vacated the house and called for back-up! They should have also cut the speaker wires on the sound system that the Jackal was using to distract them! Yes, entertaining, but no where as good as the original...and remember that "lethal spray" that Willis used on his van to kill a "hijacker?" Nobody knows what it was. Well I'll tell you: it was "Anti-credibility spray" that destroys all credibility in any film that it's in...hooray for Hollywood!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bruce Willis is the whole show
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    msroz
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The original movie "Day of the Jackal" has nothing to worry about from this remake. I'd like to know why the Jackal intentionally gives important clues throughout. I'd like to know how Isabella knew where Declan (Richard Gere) was in the subway and where she got another gun. I'd like to know why the Jackal kills 3 agents in Isabella's hiding place, and then she shows up. I'd like to know how Willis got the weapon off the boat and to another location. That's enough loose ends for now. The second half was not as good as the first half, but the whole movie was surprisingly lacking in tension. It had too many hackneyed lines. It seemed tired. Sidney Poitier seemed tired. Willis was very good. His expressions and facial contortions and impassiveness at times made the movie. Gere's part was just too Hollywoodized. I knew that Diane Venora would bite the dust. She underplayed admirably. A flabby thriller flabbily directed. Apart from Willis, it had a neat monster weapon and method of assassination.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Solid, But Generic Thriller!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    g-bodyl
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Jackal is based of the 1973 film, The Day of the Jackal. This 1997 version is a different story than the 1973 version. It is more of a generic story with the feeling "been there, done that." However, it is still a good movie with action, great acting, and some unexpected moments. This is about how FBI deputy director gets a terrorist, Mulqueen out of prison to help him track down a shady assassin, known as the Jackal, before he assassinates his political targets. The acting is great. Bruce Willis and Richard Gere had great chemistry. Willis was the reason why I saw this movie. I was surprised to see Sidney Poitier here but he did a great job as usual. Overall, this is a solid film that is there for enjoyment, not for awards or major critical success. Even though I seen many of these kind of films, I liked it. I rate this film 8/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An underrated thriller undeserving of all the hate.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Shawn Watson (gator_macready@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've never understood why The Jackal has been cursed with poor reviews from pretty much everybody. From the day I saw it as a 17-year-old in January 1998 I always found it entertaining and exciting. This might be down to the fact that I have never seen the 1973 original. Brucie plays a nameless assassin, cool as ice and utterly emotionless. Richard Gere is the only man to have seen him. He's let out of prison to assist the FBI in catching the Jackal before he takes out an uncertain high-ranking official. Willis and Gere are, for the most part, leading their own movies as they never meet until the climax. It's very interesting watching them both go about their business, Willis hatching a master plan and Gere methodically picking apart his trail and hunting him down. There is great support from Sidney Poitier and cutie-pie Diane Venora as a scarred Russian cop. With a wide variety of brilliantly photographed locations across the US and Canada, and plot with a medium-level of complexity it's not entirely brainless viewing but not too taxing as to alienate lazy viewers. I honestly do not get why so many people hate it. Willis has done far worse films (even seen Mercury Rising?) that get off scot-free somehow, but The Jackal doesn't get off so lightly. Aside from Gere's slightly dodgy Oirish accent I have no complaints about this film. Give it a chance and you might just be entertained.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This film deserves a more honest look
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rene2030
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Yeah, I know, it is so easy to bash this film as so many of you have done. It's a thriller that doesn't stand out in it's genre, pretty easy to watch but not more than that. It has a high profile cast including Bruce Willis, Richard Gere and a couple of very very decent actors slash actresses like J.K. Simmons, Diane Venora and so on, so nothing wrong with that. A more than decent director in Michael Caton-Jones, who does his best with the material he's got and doing a good job at it. Sadly he has to work with a script that has potholes the size of Hummers H3 in it, so it's easy to see why this film doesn't work the way it's supposed to. but!!!! If you have read some of the novels written by Robert Ludlum (may God rest his soul) you will have picked up some of the vibe he has put in most of his novels, putting the Jason Bourne Trilogy upfront. And just to be clear about it, I'm not talking about the miniseries starring Richard Chamberlain and also not even mentioning the Matt Damon movies (although those were really cool) but the original novels as Mr. Ludlum intended them to be. If you have these novels in the back of your head and are a fan of them you will find this movie pretty enjoyable to watch although the execution of this movie has some problems in staying believable. It is in general a pretty normal thriller with (&Iacute;'m sorry to say) some mayor flaws. But I can't escape the feeling that the script (allthough adapted from an apparent classic of which I haven't yet had the pleasure of watching) was written in the mindset of an all-out genius Robert Ludlum-vibe, which I picked up on immediately and enjoyed very much.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This is not a remake
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    boatista24
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I think people here expect to see a remake of The Day of the Jackal. This movie has nothing to do with The Day of the Jackal. This is an independent fictitious tale based upon Carlos the Jackal. It is one of my favorite Bruce Willis flicks, and has one of the greatest movie scores of all time. As far as entertainment by Bruce Willis goes, this is an 8 out of 10, hands down. Get over this being a lousy remake of an entirely different movie, and appreciate it for what it is. An outstanding effort - $60 million worth. In my opinion, Bruce Willis is as good as a bad guy as he was in any of his good guy roles. I would not dismiss this movie until you see how great he was in it. A terrific cast and great story line make this a must see.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Slow and too traditionally scripted
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rightwingisevil
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie needs some patience to watch along. The screenplay was not quite well written, it's too loose and too slow and too traditionally directed, edited with bad casting job. The Special Agent on this case was too old and not quite necessary with a role in this movie. The cooperation between the Russian and the American were a bit ridiculous and unconvincing, the sound track, the music came along with the whole movie was so bad and so out of place. The so-called "Jackal" played by Bruce Willis was too pretentious and too clich&eacute;. Casting a scar-faced Russian Military Intelligence officer was also unnecessary. But the major problem was the lame role of the FBI Special Agent in Charge, Sydney Pottier was too old not to be forced into retirement maybe 10 years late. The whole movie spent a lot of money on locations, but the lame dialog simply failed to comply with the lame screenplay. The most ridiculous thing was the never stop changing hair style and the colors as though the only thing the Jackal good at was changing his hair colors and style. Arranged a IRA terrorist imprisoned in the U.S. territory was also a very lame scenario, Richard Gere in this movie was just like a lame office boy who's so smart that every time he could just cut in during FBI meetings to point out something nobody thought about, the smartest kid in the classroom. This is a very stupid and lame movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jackal-Split Among the Soviets? ***1/2
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Apparently, in this terse thriller, there was a split between various Soviet groups. Soviets have sent the Jackal out for his next killing,but yet there are Soviets who are working against him. That being said, we have a tense thriller where Bruce Willis sheds his usual crime stopping prevention to assume the role of the cold and calculating killer. He is wonderfully matched by Richard Gere's IRA terrorist, with a great Irish accent who has a score to settle with Willis. Willis is cunning, sly and remains unknown to all with the exception of Gere who had worked with him at one time. What the Willis character does to the Jack Black character is horrifying and yet we're able to watch it on screen. Sidney Poitier gives excellent support as a CIA agent. He comes to trust the Gere character fully as seen by the film's ending.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great Performance, Standard Action Thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tabuno
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The standout performance and characterization offered up by Bruce Willis as the Jackal somehow can't lift up this action thriller to the level of greatest which is odd because the script, the story are all classic Tom Clancy movie thriller standards. Nevertheless, this movie is well worth watching just for Willis's superior cold and calculating performance that most evil assassins just become another stereotypical, sub-intelligence by the numbers performances. There is just enough rough edges in this movie to make this movie well above average because it avoids being too cute, too polished, too super-ordinary implausible and that's this movie's nuanced directed distinction.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Decent Remake of the 1970's Film--Good Acting But Somewhat Predictable Script
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    classicalsteve
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Bruce Willis and Richard Gere have to be given a lot of credit for saving this film. If not for their excellent acting, the script does lapse into somewhat predictable political-espionage thriller clich&eacute;. It's not like we don't have a lot of similar fair piled into the film archives of the studios. Willis makes a great assassin nicknamed "Jackal". He' been hired out for 70 million no less to take out somewhat in the US, but we don't know who. He's the ultimate man of mystery, taking on different disguises in different part of the country. The FBI and CIA can't get a handle on him. Figures. So the only guy who might have a chance to keep the Jackal from blowing up the whole country is a US prisoner formerly with the IRA. Although not all the details are clear, he was involved in some kind of operation with the Jackall who shot his bride-to-be, wounding her and killing their unborn child in the process. The CIA and FBI, headed by Sidney Poitier, convince Gere to sign onto the operation to stop the Jackal from whatever heinous crime he is going to enact, which we assume is of a higher import than taking out the local janitor. He already does that with ease. In exchange, he might be released. The best parts of the film consist of the many disguises Willis dons as the Jackal. In one, he appears like a former hippie out of the Haight-Ashbury with long blond hair and plaid shirt untucked. In another, he's an international businessman. He even plays a homosexual. In one of his more contrived efforts, he's an overweight laborer with hideous taste in clothes. But he not only disguises himself. He constantly changes the color and plates of his van. And those who gets in his way pay the usual price. A superb cast infiltrates this movie. Besides Willis, Poitier, and Gere, even Jack Black makes a surprise appearance as a sleazy underground arms manufacturer. He receives an order from Willis to supply him with some kind of weapons device. Half now, half on delivery, Willis' typical terms. Of course, the schmuck doesn't understand who he's dealing with. You don't up the price on a hired assassin. Pretty good through about 2/3rd's to 3/4th's. When the actual crime is finally revealed, I found it somewhat of a let down. The very end seemed typical of many films of this type, leading to a final confrontation with Willis and Gere. I was hoping the film would take a detour and lead in an unexpected direction, but about 30 minutes toward the end, I kind of knew where it was going. That said, Willis' portrayal is still worth the price of admission.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not that good!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    spaz47
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a remake of an earlier film: "The day of the Jackal," which was far more believable and intense. The weapon used in the 1st film was very small and deadly, yet could be hidden very easily. In the 2nd film, the weapon in question looks like it belongs on a Bradley Fighting Vehicle! Also in the 1st film the detective solves the case; here we have An imprisoned Irish terrorist teaching a highly experienced FBI agent his job! A really "badly written" scene was where the 3 FBI agents have moved a family out of their house and the FBI folks are "cleaning up.(?) You actually have an FBI agent taking out the garbage! Trust me, agents don't have the time for this. Also, as soon as they noticed the 1st agent was missing and probably dead, they would have vacated the house and called for back-up! They should have also cut the speaker wires on the sound system that the Jackal was using to distract them! Yes, entertaining, but no where as good as the original...and remember that "lethal spray" that Willis used on his van to kill a "hijacker?" Nobody knows what it was. Well I'll tell you: it was "Anti-credibility spray" that destroys all credibility in any film that it's in...hooray for Hollywood!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bruce Willis is the whole show
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    msroz
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The original movie "Day of the Jackal" has nothing to worry about from this remake. I'd like to know why the Jackal intentionally gives important clues throughout. I'd like to know how Isabella knew where Declan (Richard Gere) was in the subway and where she got another gun. I'd like to know why the Jackal kills 3 agents in Isabella's hiding place, and then she shows up. I'd like to know how Willis got the weapon off the boat and to another location. That's enough loose ends for now. The second half was not as good as the first half, but the whole movie was surprisingly lacking in tension. It had too many hackneyed lines. It seemed tired. Sidney Poitier seemed tired. Willis was very good. His expressions and facial contortions and impassiveness at times made the movie. Gere's part was just too Hollywoodized. I knew that Diane Venora would bite the dust. She underplayed admirably. A flabby thriller flabbily directed. Apart from Willis, it had a neat monster weapon and method of assassination.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Solid, But Generic Thriller!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    g-bodyl
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Jackal is based of the 1973 film, The Day of the Jackal. This 1997 version is a different story than the 1973 version. It is more of a generic story with the feeling "been there, done that." However, it is still a good movie with action, great acting, and some unexpected moments. This is about how FBI deputy director gets a terrorist, Mulqueen out of prison to help him track down a shady assassin, known as the Jackal, before he assassinates his political targets. The acting is great. Bruce Willis and Richard Gere had great chemistry. Willis was the reason why I saw this movie. I was surprised to see Sidney Poitier here but he did a great job as usual. Overall, this is a solid film that is there for enjoyment, not for awards or major critical success. Even though I seen many of these kind of films, I liked it. I rate this film 8/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An underrated thriller undeserving of all the hate.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Shawn Watson (gator_macready@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've never understood why The Jackal has been cursed with poor reviews from pretty much everybody. From the day I saw it as a 17-year-old in January 1998 I always found it entertaining and exciting. This might be down to the fact that I have never seen the 1973 original. Brucie plays a nameless assassin, cool as ice and utterly emotionless. Richard Gere is the only man to have seen him. He's let out of prison to assist the FBI in catching the Jackal before he takes out an uncertain high-ranking official. Willis and Gere are, for the most part, leading their own movies as they never meet until the climax. It's very interesting watching them both go about their business, Willis hatching a master plan and Gere methodically picking apart his trail and hunting him down. There is great support from Sidney Poitier and cutie-pie Diane Venora as a scarred Russian cop. With a wide variety of brilliantly photographed locations across the US and Canada, and plot with a medium-level of complexity it's not entirely brainless viewing but not too taxing as to alienate lazy viewers. I honestly do not get why so many people hate it. Willis has done far worse films (even seen Mercury Rising?) that get off scot-free somehow, but The Jackal doesn't get off so lightly. Aside from Gere's slightly dodgy Oirish accent I have no complaints about this film. Give it a chance and you might just be entertained.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This film deserves a more honest look
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rene2030
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Yeah, I know, it is so easy to bash this film as so many of you have done. It's a thriller that doesn't stand out in it's genre, pretty easy to watch but not more than that. It has a high profile cast including Bruce Willis, Richard Gere and a couple of very very decent actors slash actresses like J.K. Simmons, Diane Venora and so on, so nothing wrong with that. A more than decent director in Michael Caton-Jones, who does his best with the material he's got and doing a good job at it. Sadly he has to work with a script that has potholes the size of Hummers H3 in it, so it's easy to see why this film doesn't work the way it's supposed to. but!!!! If you have read some of the novels written by Robert Ludlum (may God rest his soul) you will have picked up some of the vibe he has put in most of his novels, putting the Jason Bourne Trilogy upfront. And just to be clear about it, I'm not talking about the miniseries starring Richard Chamberlain and also not even mentioning the Matt Damon movies (although those were really cool) but the original novels as Mr. Ludlum intended them to be. If you have these novels in the back of your head and are a fan of them you will find this movie pretty enjoyable to watch although the execution of this movie has some problems in staying believable. It is in general a pretty normal thriller with (&Iacute;'m sorry to say) some mayor flaws. But I can't escape the feeling that the script (allthough adapted from an apparent classic of which I haven't yet had the pleasure of watching) was written in the mindset of an all-out genius Robert Ludlum-vibe, which I picked up on immediately and enjoyed very much.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This is not a remake
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    boatista24
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I think people here expect to see a remake of The Day of the Jackal. This movie has nothing to do with The Day of the Jackal. This is an independent fictitious tale based upon Carlos the Jackal. It is one of my favorite Bruce Willis flicks, and has one of the greatest movie scores of all time. As far as entertainment by Bruce Willis goes, this is an 8 out of 10, hands down. Get over this being a lousy remake of an entirely different movie, and appreciate it for what it is. An outstanding effort - $60 million worth. In my opinion, Bruce Willis is as good as a bad guy as he was in any of his good guy roles. I would not dismiss this movie until you see how great he was in it. A terrific cast and great story line make this a must see.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Slow and too traditionally scripted
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rightwingisevil
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie needs some patience to watch along. The screenplay was not quite well written, it's too loose and too slow and too traditionally directed, edited with bad casting job. The Special Agent on this case was too old and not quite necessary with a role in this movie. The cooperation between the Russian and the American were a bit ridiculous and unconvincing, the sound track, the music came along with the whole movie was so bad and so out of place. The so-called "Jackal" played by Bruce Willis was too pretentious and too clich&eacute;. Casting a scar-faced Russian Military Intelligence officer was also unnecessary. But the major problem was the lame role of the FBI Special Agent in Charge, Sydney Pottier was too old not to be forced into retirement maybe 10 years late. The whole movie spent a lot of money on locations, but the lame dialog simply failed to comply with the lame screenplay. The most ridiculous thing was the never stop changing hair style and the colors as though the only thing the Jackal good at was changing his hair colors and style. Arranged a IRA terrorist imprisoned in the U.S. territory was also a very lame scenario, Richard Gere in this movie was just like a lame office boy who's so smart that every time he could just cut in during FBI meetings to point out something nobody thought about, the smartest kid in the classroom. This is a very stupid and lame movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jackal-Split Among the Soviets? ***1/2
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Apparently, in this terse thriller, there was a split between various Soviet groups. Soviets have sent the Jackal out for his next killing,but yet there are Soviets who are working against him. That being said, we have a tense thriller where Bruce Willis sheds his usual crime stopping prevention to assume the role of the cold and calculating killer. He is wonderfully matched by Richard Gere's IRA terrorist, with a great Irish accent who has a score to settle with Willis. Willis is cunning, sly and remains unknown to all with the exception of Gere who had worked with him at one time. What the Willis character does to the Jack Black character is horrifying and yet we're able to watch it on screen. Sidney Poitier gives excellent support as a CIA agent. He comes to trust the Gere character fully as seen by the film's ending.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great Performance, Standard Action Thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tabuno
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The standout performance and characterization offered up by Bruce Willis as the Jackal somehow can't lift up this action thriller to the level of greatest which is odd because the script, the story are all classic Tom Clancy movie thriller standards. Nevertheless, this movie is well worth watching just for Willis's superior cold and calculating performance that most evil assassins just become another stereotypical, sub-intelligence by the numbers performances. There is just enough rough edges in this movie to make this movie well above average because it avoids being too cute, too polished, too super-ordinary implausible and that's this movie's nuanced directed distinction.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Decent Remake of the 1970's Film--Good Acting But Somewhat Predictable Script
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    classicalsteve
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Bruce Willis and Richard Gere have to be given a lot of credit for saving this film. If not for their excellent acting, the script does lapse into somewhat predictable political-espionage thriller clich&eacute;. It's not like we don't have a lot of similar fair piled into the film archives of the studios. Willis makes a great assassin nicknamed "Jackal". He' been hired out for 70 million no less to take out somewhat in the US, but we don't know who. He's the ultimate man of mystery, taking on different disguises in different part of the country. The FBI and CIA can't get a handle on him. Figures. So the only guy who might have a chance to keep the Jackal from blowing up the whole country is a US prisoner formerly with the IRA. Although not all the details are clear, he was involved in some kind of operation with the Jackall who shot his bride-to-be, wounding her and killing their unborn child in the process. The CIA and FBI, headed by Sidney Poitier, convince Gere to sign onto the operation to stop the Jackal from whatever heinous crime he is going to enact, which we assume is of a higher import than taking out the local janitor. He already does that with ease. In exchange, he might be released. The best parts of the film consist of the many disguises Willis dons as the Jackal. In one, he appears like a former hippie out of the Haight-Ashbury with long blond hair and plaid shirt untucked. In another, he's an international businessman. He even plays a homosexual. In one of his more contrived efforts, he's an overweight laborer with hideous taste in clothes. But he not only disguises himself. He constantly changes the color and plates of his van. And those who gets in his way pay the usual price. A superb cast infiltrates this movie. Besides Willis, Poitier, and Gere, even Jack Black makes a surprise appearance as a sleazy underground arms manufacturer. He receives an order from Willis to supply him with some kind of weapons device. Half now, half on delivery, Willis' typical terms. Of course, the schmuck doesn't understand who he's dealing with. You don't up the price on a hired assassin. Pretty good through about 2/3rd's to 3/4th's. When the actual crime is finally revealed, I found it somewhat of a let down. The very end seemed typical of many films of this type, leading to a final confrontation with Willis and Gere. I was hoping the film would take a detour and lead in an unexpected direction, but about 30 minutes toward the end, I kind of knew where it was going. That said, Willis' portrayal is still worth the price of admission.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not that good!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    spaz47
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a remake of an earlier film: "The day of the Jackal," which was far more believable and intense. The weapon used in the 1st film was very small and deadly, yet could be hidden very easily. In the 2nd film, the weapon in question looks like it belongs on a Bradley Fighting Vehicle! Also in the 1st film the detective solves the case; here we have An imprisoned Irish terrorist teaching a highly experienced FBI agent his job! A really "badly written" scene was where the 3 FBI agents have moved a family out of their house and the FBI folks are "cleaning up.(?) You actually have an FBI agent taking out the garbage! Trust me, agents don't have the time for this. Also, as soon as they noticed the 1st agent was missing and probably dead, they would have vacated the house and called for back-up! They should have also cut the speaker wires on the sound system that the Jackal was using to distract them! Yes, entertaining, but no where as good as the original...and remember that "lethal spray" that Willis used on his van to kill a "hijacker?" Nobody knows what it was. Well I'll tell you: it was "Anti-credibility spray" that destroys all credibility in any film that it's in...hooray for Hollywood!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bruce Willis is the whole show
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    msroz
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The original movie "Day of the Jackal" has nothing to worry about from this remake. I'd like to know why the Jackal intentionally gives important clues throughout. I'd like to know how Isabella knew where Declan (Richard Gere) was in the subway and where she got another gun. I'd like to know why the Jackal kills 3 agents in Isabella's hiding place, and then she shows up. I'd like to know how Willis got the weapon off the boat and to another location. That's enough loose ends for now. The second half was not as good as the first half, but the whole movie was surprisingly lacking in tension. It had too many hackneyed lines. It seemed tired. Sidney Poitier seemed tired. Willis was very good. His expressions and facial contortions and impassiveness at times made the movie. Gere's part was just too Hollywoodized. I knew that Diane Venora would bite the dust. She underplayed admirably. A flabby thriller flabbily directed. Apart from Willis, it had a neat monster weapon and method of assassination.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Solid, But Generic Thriller!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    g-bodyl
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Jackal is based of the 1973 film, The Day of the Jackal. This 1997 version is a different story than the 1973 version. It is more of a generic story with the feeling "been there, done that." However, it is still a good movie with action, great acting, and some unexpected moments. This is about how FBI deputy director gets a terrorist, Mulqueen out of prison to help him track down a shady assassin, known as the Jackal, before he assassinates his political targets. The acting is great. Bruce Willis and Richard Gere had great chemistry. Willis was the reason why I saw this movie. I was surprised to see Sidney Poitier here but he did a great job as usual. Overall, this is a solid film that is there for enjoyment, not for awards or major critical success. Even though I seen many of these kind of films, I liked it. I rate this film 8/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An underrated thriller undeserving of all the hate.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Shawn Watson (gator_macready@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've never understood why The Jackal has been cursed with poor reviews from pretty much everybody. From the day I saw it as a 17-year-old in January 1998 I always found it entertaining and exciting. This might be down to the fact that I have never seen the 1973 original. Brucie plays a nameless assassin, cool as ice and utterly emotionless. Richard Gere is the only man to have seen him. He's let out of prison to assist the FBI in catching the Jackal before he takes out an uncertain high-ranking official. Willis and Gere are, for the most part, leading their own movies as they never meet until the climax. It's very interesting watching them both go about their business, Willis hatching a master plan and Gere methodically picking apart his trail and hunting him down. There is great support from Sidney Poitier and cutie-pie Diane Venora as a scarred Russian cop. With a wide variety of brilliantly photographed locations across the US and Canada, and plot with a medium-level of complexity it's not entirely brainless viewing but not too taxing as to alienate lazy viewers. I honestly do not get why so many people hate it. Willis has done far worse films (even seen Mercury Rising?) that get off scot-free somehow, but The Jackal doesn't get off so lightly. Aside from Gere's slightly dodgy Oirish accent I have no complaints about this film. Give it a chance and you might just be entertained.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This film deserves a more honest look
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rene2030
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Yeah, I know, it is so easy to bash this film as so many of you have done. It's a thriller that doesn't stand out in it's genre, pretty easy to watch but not more than that. It has a high profile cast including Bruce Willis, Richard Gere and a couple of very very decent actors slash actresses like J.K. Simmons, Diane Venora and so on, so nothing wrong with that. A more than decent director in Michael Caton-Jones, who does his best with the material he's got and doing a good job at it. Sadly he has to work with a script that has potholes the size of Hummers H3 in it, so it's easy to see why this film doesn't work the way it's supposed to. but!!!! If you have read some of the novels written by Robert Ludlum (may God rest his soul) you will have picked up some of the vibe he has put in most of his novels, putting the Jason Bourne Trilogy upfront. And just to be clear about it, I'm not talking about the miniseries starring Richard Chamberlain and also not even mentioning the Matt Damon movies (although those were really cool) but the original novels as Mr. Ludlum intended them to be. If you have these novels in the back of your head and are a fan of them you will find this movie pretty enjoyable to watch although the execution of this movie has some problems in staying believable. It is in general a pretty normal thriller with (&Iacute;'m sorry to say) some mayor flaws. But I can't escape the feeling that the script (allthough adapted from an apparent classic of which I haven't yet had the pleasure of watching) was written in the mindset of an all-out genius Robert Ludlum-vibe, which I picked up on immediately and enjoyed very much.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This is not a remake
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    boatista24
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I think people here expect to see a remake of The Day of the Jackal. This movie has nothing to do with The Day of the Jackal. This is an independent fictitious tale based upon Carlos the Jackal. It is one of my favorite Bruce Willis flicks, and has one of the greatest movie scores of all time. As far as entertainment by Bruce Willis goes, this is an 8 out of 10, hands down. Get over this being a lousy remake of an entirely different movie, and appreciate it for what it is. An outstanding effort - $60 million worth. In my opinion, Bruce Willis is as good as a bad guy as he was in any of his good guy roles. I would not dismiss this movie until you see how great he was in it. A terrific cast and great story line make this a must see.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Slow and too traditionally scripted
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rightwingisevil
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie needs some patience to watch along. The screenplay was not quite well written, it's too loose and too slow and too traditionally directed, edited with bad casting job. The Special Agent on this case was too old and not quite necessary with a role in this movie. The cooperation between the Russian and the American were a bit ridiculous and unconvincing, the sound track, the music came along with the whole movie was so bad and so out of place. The so-called "Jackal" played by Bruce Willis was too pretentious and too clich&eacute;. Casting a scar-faced Russian Military Intelligence officer was also unnecessary. But the major problem was the lame role of the FBI Special Agent in Charge, Sydney Pottier was too old not to be forced into retirement maybe 10 years late. The whole movie spent a lot of money on locations, but the lame dialog simply failed to comply with the lame screenplay. The most ridiculous thing was the never stop changing hair style and the colors as though the only thing the Jackal good at was changing his hair colors and style. Arranged a IRA terrorist imprisoned in the U.S. territory was also a very lame scenario, Richard Gere in this movie was just like a lame office boy who's so smart that every time he could just cut in during FBI meetings to point out something nobody thought about, the smartest kid in the classroom. This is a very stupid and lame movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jackal-Split Among the Soviets? ***1/2
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Apparently, in this terse thriller, there was a split between various Soviet groups. Soviets have sent the Jackal out for his next killing,but yet there are Soviets who are working against him. That being said, we have a tense thriller where Bruce Willis sheds his usual crime stopping prevention to assume the role of the cold and calculating killer. He is wonderfully matched by Richard Gere's IRA terrorist, with a great Irish accent who has a score to settle with Willis. Willis is cunning, sly and remains unknown to all with the exception of Gere who had worked with him at one time. What the Willis character does to the Jack Black character is horrifying and yet we're able to watch it on screen. Sidney Poitier gives excellent support as a CIA agent. He comes to trust the Gere character fully as seen by the film's ending.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great Performance, Standard Action Thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tabuno
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The standout performance and characterization offered up by Bruce Willis as the Jackal somehow can't lift up this action thriller to the level of greatest which is odd because the script, the story are all classic Tom Clancy movie thriller standards. Nevertheless, this movie is well worth watching just for Willis's superior cold and calculating performance that most evil assassins just become another stereotypical, sub-intelligence by the numbers performances. There is just enough rough edges in this movie to make this movie well above average because it avoids being too cute, too polished, too super-ordinary implausible and that's this movie's nuanced directed distinction.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Decent Remake of the 1970's Film--Good Acting But Somewhat Predictable Script
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    classicalsteve
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Bruce Willis and Richard Gere have to be given a lot of credit for saving this film. If not for their excellent acting, the script does lapse into somewhat predictable political-espionage thriller clich&eacute;. It's not like we don't have a lot of similar fair piled into the film archives of the studios. Willis makes a great assassin nicknamed "Jackal". He' been hired out for 70 million no less to take out somewhat in the US, but we don't know who. He's the ultimate man of mystery, taking on different disguises in different part of the country. The FBI and CIA can't get a handle on him. Figures. So the only guy who might have a chance to keep the Jackal from blowing up the whole country is a US prisoner formerly with the IRA. Although not all the details are clear, he was involved in some kind of operation with the Jackall who shot his bride-to-be, wounding her and killing their unborn child in the process. The CIA and FBI, headed by Sidney Poitier, convince Gere to sign onto the operation to stop the Jackal from whatever heinous crime he is going to enact, which we assume is of a higher import than taking out the local janitor. He already does that with ease. In exchange, he might be released. The best parts of the film consist of the many disguises Willis dons as the Jackal. In one, he appears like a former hippie out of the Haight-Ashbury with long blond hair and plaid shirt untucked. In another, he's an international businessman. He even plays a homosexual. In one of his more contrived efforts, he's an overweight laborer with hideous taste in clothes. But he not only disguises himself. He constantly changes the color and plates of his van. And those who gets in his way pay the usual price. A superb cast infiltrates this movie. Besides Willis, Poitier, and Gere, even Jack Black makes a surprise appearance as a sleazy underground arms manufacturer. He receives an order from Willis to supply him with some kind of weapons device. Half now, half on delivery, Willis' typical terms. Of course, the schmuck doesn't understand who he's dealing with. You don't up the price on a hired assassin. Pretty good through about 2/3rd's to 3/4th's. When the actual crime is finally revealed, I found it somewhat of a let down. The very end seemed typical of many films of this type, leading to a final confrontation with Willis and Gere. I was hoping the film would take a detour and lead in an unexpected direction, but about 30 minutes toward the end, I kind of knew where it was going. That said, Willis' portrayal is still worth the price of admission.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not that good!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    spaz47
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a remake of an earlier film: "The day of the Jackal," which was far more believable and intense. The weapon used in the 1st film was very small and deadly, yet could be hidden very easily. In the 2nd film, the weapon in question looks like it belongs on a Bradley Fighting Vehicle! Also in the 1st film the detective solves the case; here we have An imprisoned Irish terrorist teaching a highly experienced FBI agent his job! A really "badly written" scene was where the 3 FBI agents have moved a family out of their house and the FBI folks are "cleaning up.(?) You actually have an FBI agent taking out the garbage! Trust me, agents don't have the time for this. Also, as soon as they noticed the 1st agent was missing and probably dead, they would have vacated the house and called for back-up! They should have also cut the speaker wires on the sound system that the Jackal was using to distract them! Yes, entertaining, but no where as good as the original...and remember that "lethal spray" that Willis used on his van to kill a "hijacker?" Nobody knows what it was. Well I'll tell you: it was "Anti-credibility spray" that destroys all credibility in any film that it's in...hooray for Hollywood!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bruce Willis is the whole show
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    msroz
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The original movie "Day of the Jackal" has nothing to worry about from this remake. I'd like to know why the Jackal intentionally gives important clues throughout. I'd like to know how Isabella knew where Declan (Richard Gere) was in the subway and where she got another gun. I'd like to know why the Jackal kills 3 agents in Isabella's hiding place, and then she shows up. I'd like to know how Willis got the weapon off the boat and to another location. That's enough loose ends for now. The second half was not as good as the first half, but the whole movie was surprisingly lacking in tension. It had too many hackneyed lines. It seemed tired. Sidney Poitier seemed tired. Willis was very good. His expressions and facial contortions and impassiveness at times made the movie. Gere's part was just too Hollywoodized. I knew that Diane Venora would bite the dust. She underplayed admirably. A flabby thriller flabbily directed. Apart from Willis, it had a neat monster weapon and method of assassination.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Solid, But Generic Thriller!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    g-bodyl
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Jackal is based of the 1973 film, The Day of the Jackal. This 1997 version is a different story than the 1973 version. It is more of a generic story with the feeling "been there, done that." However, it is still a good movie with action, great acting, and some unexpected moments. This is about how FBI deputy director gets a terrorist, Mulqueen out of prison to help him track down a shady assassin, known as the Jackal, before he assassinates his political targets. The acting is great. Bruce Willis and Richard Gere had great chemistry. Willis was the reason why I saw this movie. I was surprised to see Sidney Poitier here but he did a great job as usual. Overall, this is a solid film that is there for enjoyment, not for awards or major critical success. Even though I seen many of these kind of films, I liked it. I rate this film 8/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An underrated thriller undeserving of all the hate.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Shawn Watson (gator_macready@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've never understood why The Jackal has been cursed with poor reviews from pretty much everybody. From the day I saw it as a 17-year-old in January 1998 I always found it entertaining and exciting. This might be down to the fact that I have never seen the 1973 original. Brucie plays a nameless assassin, cool as ice and utterly emotionless. Richard Gere is the only man to have seen him. He's let out of prison to assist the FBI in catching the Jackal before he takes out an uncertain high-ranking official. Willis and Gere are, for the most part, leading their own movies as they never meet until the climax. It's very interesting watching them both go about their business, Willis hatching a master plan and Gere methodically picking apart his trail and hunting him down. There is great support from Sidney Poitier and cutie-pie Diane Venora as a scarred Russian cop. With a wide variety of brilliantly photographed locations across the US and Canada, and plot with a medium-level of complexity it's not entirely brainless viewing but not too taxing as to alienate lazy viewers. I honestly do not get why so many people hate it. Willis has done far worse films (even seen Mercury Rising?) that get off scot-free somehow, but The Jackal doesn't get off so lightly. Aside from Gere's slightly dodgy Oirish accent I have no complaints about this film. Give it a chance and you might just be entertained.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This film deserves a more honest look
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rene2030
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Yeah, I know, it is so easy to bash this film as so many of you have done. It's a thriller that doesn't stand out in it's genre, pretty easy to watch but not more than that. It has a high profile cast including Bruce Willis, Richard Gere and a couple of very very decent actors slash actresses like J.K. Simmons, Diane Venora and so on, so nothing wrong with that. A more than decent director in Michael Caton-Jones, who does his best with the material he's got and doing a good job at it. Sadly he has to work with a script that has potholes the size of Hummers H3 in it, so it's easy to see why this film doesn't work the way it's supposed to. but!!!! If you have read some of the novels written by Robert Ludlum (may God rest his soul) you will have picked up some of the vibe he has put in most of his novels, putting the Jason Bourne Trilogy upfront. And just to be clear about it, I'm not talking about the miniseries starring Richard Chamberlain and also not even mentioning the Matt Damon movies (although those were really cool) but the original novels as Mr. Ludlum intended them to be. If you have these novels in the back of your head and are a fan of them you will find this movie pretty enjoyable to watch although the execution of this movie has some problems in staying believable. It is in general a pretty normal thriller with (&Iacute;'m sorry to say) some mayor flaws. But I can't escape the feeling that the script (allthough adapted from an apparent classic of which I haven't yet had the pleasure of watching) was written in the mindset of an all-out genius Robert Ludlum-vibe, which I picked up on immediately and enjoyed very much.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This is not a remake
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    boatista24
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I think people here expect to see a remake of The Day of the Jackal. This movie has nothing to do with The Day of the Jackal. This is an independent fictitious tale based upon Carlos the Jackal. It is one of my favorite Bruce Willis flicks, and has one of the greatest movie scores of all time. As far as entertainment by Bruce Willis goes, this is an 8 out of 10, hands down. Get over this being a lousy remake of an entirely different movie, and appreciate it for what it is. An outstanding effort - $60 million worth. In my opinion, Bruce Willis is as good as a bad guy as he was in any of his good guy roles. I would not dismiss this movie until you see how great he was in it. A terrific cast and great story line make this a must see.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Slow and too traditionally scripted
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rightwingisevil
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie needs some patience to watch along. The screenplay was not quite well written, it's too loose and too slow and too traditionally directed, edited with bad casting job. The Special Agent on this case was too old and not quite necessary with a role in this movie. The cooperation between the Russian and the American were a bit ridiculous and unconvincing, the sound track, the music came along with the whole movie was so bad and so out of place. The so-called "Jackal" played by Bruce Willis was too pretentious and too clich&eacute;. Casting a scar-faced Russian Military Intelligence officer was also unnecessary. But the major problem was the lame role of the FBI Special Agent in Charge, Sydney Pottier was too old not to be forced into retirement maybe 10 years late. The whole movie spent a lot of money on locations, but the lame dialog simply failed to comply with the lame screenplay. The most ridiculous thing was the never stop changing hair style and the colors as though the only thing the Jackal good at was changing his hair colors and style. Arranged a IRA terrorist imprisoned in the U.S. territory was also a very lame scenario, Richard Gere in this movie was just like a lame office boy who's so smart that every time he could just cut in during FBI meetings to point out something nobody thought about, the smartest kid in the classroom. This is a very stupid and lame movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jackal-Split Among the Soviets? ***1/2
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Apparently, in this terse thriller, there was a split between various Soviet groups. Soviets have sent the Jackal out for his next killing,but yet there are Soviets who are working against him. That being said, we have a tense thriller where Bruce Willis sheds his usual crime stopping prevention to assume the role of the cold and calculating killer. He is wonderfully matched by Richard Gere's IRA terrorist, with a great Irish accent who has a score to settle with Willis. Willis is cunning, sly and remains unknown to all with the exception of Gere who had worked with him at one time. What the Willis character does to the Jack Black character is horrifying and yet we're able to watch it on screen. Sidney Poitier gives excellent support as a CIA agent. He comes to trust the Gere character fully as seen by the film's ending.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great Performance, Standard Action Thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tabuno
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The standout performance and characterization offered up by Bruce Willis as the Jackal somehow can't lift up this action thriller to the level of greatest which is odd because the script, the story are all classic Tom Clancy movie thriller standards. Nevertheless, this movie is well worth watching just for Willis's superior cold and calculating performance that most evil assassins just become another stereotypical, sub-intelligence by the numbers performances. There is just enough rough edges in this movie to make this movie well above average because it avoids being too cute, too polished, too super-ordinary implausible and that's this movie's nuanced directed distinction.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Decent Remake of the 1970's Film--Good Acting But Somewhat Predictable Script
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    classicalsteve
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Bruce Willis and Richard Gere have to be given a lot of credit for saving this film. If not for their excellent acting, the script does lapse into somewhat predictable political-espionage thriller clich&eacute;. It's not like we don't have a lot of similar fair piled into the film archives of the studios. Willis makes a great assassin nicknamed "Jackal". He' been hired out for 70 million no less to take out somewhat in the US, but we don't know who. He's the ultimate man of mystery, taking on different disguises in different part of the country. The FBI and CIA can't get a handle on him. Figures. So the only guy who might have a chance to keep the Jackal from blowing up the whole country is a US prisoner formerly with the IRA. Although not all the details are clear, he was involved in some kind of operation with the Jackall who shot his bride-to-be, wounding her and killing their unborn child in the process. The CIA and FBI, headed by Sidney Poitier, convince Gere to sign onto the operation to stop the Jackal from whatever heinous crime he is going to enact, which we assume is of a higher import than taking out the local janitor. He already does that with ease. In exchange, he might be released. The best parts of the film consist of the many disguises Willis dons as the Jackal. In one, he appears like a former hippie out of the Haight-Ashbury with long blond hair and plaid shirt untucked. In another, he's an international businessman. He even plays a homosexual. In one of his more contrived efforts, he's an overweight laborer with hideous taste in clothes. But he not only disguises himself. He constantly changes the color and plates of his van. And those who gets in his way pay the usual price. A superb cast infiltrates this movie. Besides Willis, Poitier, and Gere, even Jack Black makes a surprise appearance as a sleazy underground arms manufacturer. He receives an order from Willis to supply him with some kind of weapons device. Half now, half on delivery, Willis' typical terms. Of course, the schmuck doesn't understand who he's dealing with. You don't up the price on a hired assassin. Pretty good through about 2/3rd's to 3/4th's. When the actual crime is finally revealed, I found it somewhat of a let down. The very end seemed typical of many films of this type, leading to a final confrontation with Willis and Gere. I was hoping the film would take a detour and lead in an unexpected direction, but about 30 minutes toward the end, I kind of knew where it was going. That said, Willis' portrayal is still worth the price of admission.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not that good!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    spaz47
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a remake of an earlier film: "The day of the Jackal," which was far more believable and intense. The weapon used in the 1st film was very small and deadly, yet could be hidden very easily. In the 2nd film, the weapon in question looks like it belongs on a Bradley Fighting Vehicle! Also in the 1st film the detective solves the case; here we have An imprisoned Irish terrorist teaching a highly experienced FBI agent his job! A really "badly written" scene was where the 3 FBI agents have moved a family out of their house and the FBI folks are "cleaning up.(?) You actually have an FBI agent taking out the garbage! Trust me, agents don't have the time for this. Also, as soon as they noticed the 1st agent was missing and probably dead, they would have vacated the house and called for back-up! They should have also cut the speaker wires on the sound system that the Jackal was using to distract them! Yes, entertaining, but no where as good as the original...and remember that "lethal spray" that Willis used on his van to kill a "hijacker?" Nobody knows what it was. Well I'll tell you: it was "Anti-credibility spray" that destroys all credibility in any film that it's in...hooray for Hollywood!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bruce Willis is the whole show
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    msroz
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The original movie "Day of the Jackal" has nothing to worry about from this remake. I'd like to know why the Jackal intentionally gives important clues throughout. I'd like to know how Isabella knew where Declan (Richard Gere) was in the subway and where she got another gun. I'd like to know why the Jackal kills 3 agents in Isabella's hiding place, and then she shows up. I'd like to know how Willis got the weapon off the boat and to another location. That's enough loose ends for now. The second half was not as good as the first half, but the whole movie was surprisingly lacking in tension. It had too many hackneyed lines. It seemed tired. Sidney Poitier seemed tired. Willis was very good. His expressions and facial contortions and impassiveness at times made the movie. Gere's part was just too Hollywoodized. I knew that Diane Venora would bite the dust. She underplayed admirably. A flabby thriller flabbily directed. Apart from Willis, it had a neat monster weapon and method of assassination.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Solid, But Generic Thriller!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    g-bodyl
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Jackal is based of the 1973 film, The Day of the Jackal. This 1997 version is a different story than the 1973 version. It is more of a generic story with the feeling "been there, done that." However, it is still a good movie with action, great acting, and some unexpected moments. This is about how FBI deputy director gets a terrorist, Mulqueen out of prison to help him track down a shady assassin, known as the Jackal, before he assassinates his political targets. The acting is great. Bruce Willis and Richard Gere had great chemistry. Willis was the reason why I saw this movie. I was surprised to see Sidney Poitier here but he did a great job as usual. Overall, this is a solid film that is there for enjoyment, not for awards or major critical success. Even though I seen many of these kind of films, I liked it. I rate this film 8/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An underrated thriller undeserving of all the hate.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Shawn Watson (gator_macready@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've never understood why The Jackal has been cursed with poor reviews from pretty much everybody. From the day I saw it as a 17-year-old in January 1998 I always found it entertaining and exciting. This might be down to the fact that I have never seen the 1973 original. Brucie plays a nameless assassin, cool as ice and utterly emotionless. Richard Gere is the only man to have seen him. He's let out of prison to assist the FBI in catching the Jackal before he takes out an uncertain high-ranking official. Willis and Gere are, for the most part, leading their own movies as they never meet until the climax. It's very interesting watching them both go about their business, Willis hatching a master plan and Gere methodically picking apart his trail and hunting him down. There is great support from Sidney Poitier and cutie-pie Diane Venora as a scarred Russian cop. With a wide variety of brilliantly photographed locations across the US and Canada, and plot with a medium-level of complexity it's not entirely brainless viewing but not too taxing as to alienate lazy viewers. I honestly do not get why so many people hate it. Willis has done far worse films (even seen Mercury Rising?) that get off scot-free somehow, but The Jackal doesn't get off so lightly. Aside from Gere's slightly dodgy Oirish accent I have no complaints about this film. Give it a chance and you might just be entertained.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This film deserves a more honest look
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rene2030
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Yeah, I know, it is so easy to bash this film as so many of you have done. It's a thriller that doesn't stand out in it's genre, pretty easy to watch but not more than that. It has a high profile cast including Bruce Willis, Richard Gere and a couple of very very decent actors slash actresses like J.K. Simmons, Diane Venora and so on, so nothing wrong with that. A more than decent director in Michael Caton-Jones, who does his best with the material he's got and doing a good job at it. Sadly he has to work with a script that has potholes the size of Hummers H3 in it, so it's easy to see why this film doesn't work the way it's supposed to. but!!!! If you have read some of the novels written by Robert Ludlum (may God rest his soul) you will have picked up some of the vibe he has put in most of his novels, putting the Jason Bourne Trilogy upfront. And just to be clear about it, I'm not talking about the miniseries starring Richard Chamberlain and also not even mentioning the Matt Damon movies (although those were really cool) but the original novels as Mr. Ludlum intended them to be. If you have these novels in the back of your head and are a fan of them you will find this movie pretty enjoyable to watch although the execution of this movie has some problems in staying believable. It is in general a pretty normal thriller with (&Iacute;'m sorry to say) some mayor flaws. But I can't escape the feeling that the script (allthough adapted from an apparent classic of which I haven't yet had the pleasure of watching) was written in the mindset of an all-out genius Robert Ludlum-vibe, which I picked up on immediately and enjoyed very much.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This is not a remake
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    boatista24
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I think people here expect to see a remake of The Day of the Jackal. This movie has nothing to do with The Day of the Jackal. This is an independent fictitious tale based upon Carlos the Jackal. It is one of my favorite Bruce Willis flicks, and has one of the greatest movie scores of all time. As far as entertainment by Bruce Willis goes, this is an 8 out of 10, hands down. Get over this being a lousy remake of an entirely different movie, and appreciate it for what it is. An outstanding effort - $60 million worth. In my opinion, Bruce Willis is as good as a bad guy as he was in any of his good guy roles. I would not dismiss this movie until you see how great he was in it. A terrific cast and great story line make this a must see.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Slow and too traditionally scripted
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rightwingisevil
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie needs some patience to watch along. The screenplay was not quite well written, it's too loose and too slow and too traditionally directed, edited with bad casting job. The Special Agent on this case was too old and not quite necessary with a role in this movie. The cooperation between the Russian and the American were a bit ridiculous and unconvincing, the sound track, the music came along with the whole movie was so bad and so out of place. The so-called "Jackal" played by Bruce Willis was too pretentious and too clich&eacute;. Casting a scar-faced Russian Military Intelligence officer was also unnecessary. But the major problem was the lame role of the FBI Special Agent in Charge, Sydney Pottier was too old not to be forced into retirement maybe 10 years late. The whole movie spent a lot of money on locations, but the lame dialog simply failed to comply with the lame screenplay. The most ridiculous thing was the never stop changing hair style and the colors as though the only thing the Jackal good at was changing his hair colors and style. Arranged a IRA terrorist imprisoned in the U.S. territory was also a very lame scenario, Richard Gere in this movie was just like a lame office boy who's so smart that every time he could just cut in during FBI meetings to point out something nobody thought about, the smartest kid in the classroom. This is a very stupid and lame movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jackal-Split Among the Soviets? ***1/2
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Apparently, in this terse thriller, there was a split between various Soviet groups. Soviets have sent the Jackal out for his next killing,but yet there are Soviets who are working against him. That being said, we have a tense thriller where Bruce Willis sheds his usual crime stopping prevention to assume the role of the cold and calculating killer. He is wonderfully matched by Richard Gere's IRA terrorist, with a great Irish accent who has a score to settle with Willis. Willis is cunning, sly and remains unknown to all with the exception of Gere who had worked with him at one time. What the Willis character does to the Jack Black character is horrifying and yet we're able to watch it on screen. Sidney Poitier gives excellent support as a CIA agent. He comes to trust the Gere character fully as seen by the film's ending.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great Performance, Standard Action Thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tabuno
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The standout performance and characterization offered up by Bruce Willis as the Jackal somehow can't lift up this action thriller to the level of greatest which is odd because the script, the story are all classic Tom Clancy movie thriller standards. Nevertheless, this movie is well worth watching just for Willis's superior cold and calculating performance that most evil assassins just become another stereotypical, sub-intelligence by the numbers performances. There is just enough rough edges in this movie to make this movie well above average because it avoids being too cute, too polished, too super-ordinary implausible and that's this movie's nuanced directed distinction.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Decent Remake of the 1970's Film--Good Acting But Somewhat Predictable Script
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    classicalsteve
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Bruce Willis and Richard Gere have to be given a lot of credit for saving this film. If not for their excellent acting, the script does lapse into somewhat predictable political-espionage thriller clich&eacute;. It's not like we don't have a lot of similar fair piled into the film archives of the studios. Willis makes a great assassin nicknamed "Jackal". He' been hired out for 70 million no less to take out somewhat in the US, but we don't know who. He's the ultimate man of mystery, taking on different disguises in different part of the country. The FBI and CIA can't get a handle on him. Figures. So the only guy who might have a chance to keep the Jackal from blowing up the whole country is a US prisoner formerly with the IRA. Although not all the details are clear, he was involved in some kind of operation with the Jackall who shot his bride-to-be, wounding her and killing their unborn child in the process. The CIA and FBI, headed by Sidney Poitier, convince Gere to sign onto the operation to stop the Jackal from whatever heinous crime he is going to enact, which we assume is of a higher import than taking out the local janitor. He already does that with ease. In exchange, he might be released. The best parts of the film consist of the many disguises Willis dons as the Jackal. In one, he appears like a former hippie out of the Haight-Ashbury with long blond hair and plaid shirt untucked. In another, he's an international businessman. He even plays a homosexual. In one of his more contrived efforts, he's an overweight laborer with hideous taste in clothes. But he not only disguises himself. He constantly changes the color and plates of his van. And those who gets in his way pay the usual price. A superb cast infiltrates this movie. Besides Willis, Poitier, and Gere, even Jack Black makes a surprise appearance as a sleazy underground arms manufacturer. He receives an order from Willis to supply him with some kind of weapons device. Half now, half on delivery, Willis' typical terms. Of course, the schmuck doesn't understand who he's dealing with. You don't up the price on a hired assassin. Pretty good through about 2/3rd's to 3/4th's. When the actual crime is finally revealed, I found it somewhat of a let down. The very end seemed typical of many films of this type, leading to a final confrontation with Willis and Gere. I was hoping the film would take a detour and lead in an unexpected direction, but about 30 minutes toward the end, I kind of knew where it was going. That said, Willis' portrayal is still worth the price of admission.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not that good!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    spaz47
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a remake of an earlier film: "The day of the Jackal," which was far more believable and intense. The weapon used in the 1st film was very small and deadly, yet could be hidden very easily. In the 2nd film, the weapon in question looks like it belongs on a Bradley Fighting Vehicle! Also in the 1st film the detective solves the case; here we have An imprisoned Irish terrorist teaching a highly experienced FBI agent his job! A really "badly written" scene was where the 3 FBI agents have moved a family out of their house and the FBI folks are "cleaning up.(?) You actually have an FBI agent taking out the garbage! Trust me, agents don't have the time for this. Also, as soon as they noticed the 1st agent was missing and probably dead, they would have vacated the house and called for back-up! They should have also cut the speaker wires on the sound system that the Jackal was using to distract them! Yes, entertaining, but no where as good as the original...and remember that "lethal spray" that Willis used on his van to kill a "hijacker?" Nobody knows what it was. Well I'll tell you: it was "Anti-credibility spray" that destroys all credibility in any film that it's in...hooray for Hollywood!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bruce Willis is the whole show
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    msroz
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The original movie "Day of the Jackal" has nothing to worry about from this remake. I'd like to know why the Jackal intentionally gives important clues throughout. I'd like to know how Isabella knew where Declan (Richard Gere) was in the subway and where she got another gun. I'd like to know why the Jackal kills 3 agents in Isabella's hiding place, and then she shows up. I'd like to know how Willis got the weapon off the boat and to another location. That's enough loose ends for now. The second half was not as good as the first half, but the whole movie was surprisingly lacking in tension. It had too many hackneyed lines. It seemed tired. Sidney Poitier seemed tired. Willis was very good. His expressions and facial contortions and impassiveness at times made the movie. Gere's part was just too Hollywoodized. I knew that Diane Venora would bite the dust. She underplayed admirably. A flabby thriller flabbily directed. Apart from Willis, it had a neat monster weapon and method of assassination.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Solid, But Generic Thriller!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    g-bodyl
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Jackal is based of the 1973 film, The Day of the Jackal. This 1997 version is a different story than the 1973 version. It is more of a generic story with the feeling "been there, done that." However, it is still a good movie with action, great acting, and some unexpected moments. This is about how FBI deputy director gets a terrorist, Mulqueen out of prison to help him track down a shady assassin, known as the Jackal, before he assassinates his political targets. The acting is great. Bruce Willis and Richard Gere had great chemistry. Willis was the reason why I saw this movie. I was surprised to see Sidney Poitier here but he did a great job as usual. Overall, this is a solid film that is there for enjoyment, not for awards or major critical success. Even though I seen many of these kind of films, I liked it. I rate this film 8/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An underrated thriller undeserving of all the hate.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Shawn Watson (gator_macready@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've never understood why The Jackal has been cursed with poor reviews from pretty much everybody. From the day I saw it as a 17-year-old in January 1998 I always found it entertaining and exciting. This might be down to the fact that I have never seen the 1973 original. Brucie plays a nameless assassin, cool as ice and utterly emotionless. Richard Gere is the only man to have seen him. He's let out of prison to assist the FBI in catching the Jackal before he takes out an uncertain high-ranking official. Willis and Gere are, for the most part, leading their own movies as they never meet until the climax. It's very interesting watching them both go about their business, Willis hatching a master plan and Gere methodically picking apart his trail and hunting him down. There is great support from Sidney Poitier and cutie-pie Diane Venora as a scarred Russian cop. With a wide variety of brilliantly photographed locations across the US and Canada, and plot with a medium-level of complexity it's not entirely brainless viewing but not too taxing as to alienate lazy viewers. I honestly do not get why so many people hate it. Willis has done far worse films (even seen Mercury Rising?) that get off scot-free somehow, but The Jackal doesn't get off so lightly. Aside from Gere's slightly dodgy Oirish accent I have no complaints about this film. Give it a chance and you might just be entertained.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This film deserves a more honest look
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rene2030
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Yeah, I know, it is so easy to bash this film as so many of you have done. It's a thriller that doesn't stand out in it's genre, pretty easy to watch but not more than that. It has a high profile cast including Bruce Willis, Richard Gere and a couple of very very decent actors slash actresses like J.K. Simmons, Diane Venora and so on, so nothing wrong with that. A more than decent director in Michael Caton-Jones, who does his best with the material he's got and doing a good job at it. Sadly he has to work with a script that has potholes the size of Hummers H3 in it, so it's easy to see why this film doesn't work the way it's supposed to. but!!!! If you have read some of the novels written by Robert Ludlum (may God rest his soul) you will have picked up some of the vibe he has put in most of his novels, putting the Jason Bourne Trilogy upfront. And just to be clear about it, I'm not talking about the miniseries starring Richard Chamberlain and also not even mentioning the Matt Damon movies (although those were really cool) but the original novels as Mr. Ludlum intended them to be. If you have these novels in the back of your head and are a fan of them you will find this movie pretty enjoyable to watch although the execution of this movie has some problems in staying believable. It is in general a pretty normal thriller with (&Iacute;'m sorry to say) some mayor flaws. But I can't escape the feeling that the script (allthough adapted from an apparent classic of which I haven't yet had the pleasure of watching) was written in the mindset of an all-out genius Robert Ludlum-vibe, which I picked up on immediately and enjoyed very much.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This is not a remake
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    boatista24
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I think people here expect to see a remake of The Day of the Jackal. This movie has nothing to do with The Day of the Jackal. This is an independent fictitious tale based upon Carlos the Jackal. It is one of my favorite Bruce Willis flicks, and has one of the greatest movie scores of all time. As far as entertainment by Bruce Willis goes, this is an 8 out of 10, hands down. Get over this being a lousy remake of an entirely different movie, and appreciate it for what it is. An outstanding effort - $60 million worth. In my opinion, Bruce Willis is as good as a bad guy as he was in any of his good guy roles. I would not dismiss this movie until you see how great he was in it. A terrific cast and great story line make this a must see.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Slow and too traditionally scripted
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rightwingisevil
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie needs some patience to watch along. The screenplay was not quite well written, it's too loose and too slow and too traditionally directed, edited with bad casting job. The Special Agent on this case was too old and not quite necessary with a role in this movie. The cooperation between the Russian and the American were a bit ridiculous and unconvincing, the sound track, the music came along with the whole movie was so bad and so out of place. The so-called "Jackal" played by Bruce Willis was too pretentious and too clich&eacute;. Casting a scar-faced Russian Military Intelligence officer was also unnecessary. But the major problem was the lame role of the FBI Special Agent in Charge, Sydney Pottier was too old not to be forced into retirement maybe 10 years late. The whole movie spent a lot of money on locations, but the lame dialog simply failed to comply with the lame screenplay. The most ridiculous thing was the never stop changing hair style and the colors as though the only thing the Jackal good at was changing his hair colors and style. Arranged a IRA terrorist imprisoned in the U.S. territory was also a very lame scenario, Richard Gere in this movie was just like a lame office boy who's so smart that every time he could just cut in during FBI meetings to point out something nobody thought about, the smartest kid in the classroom. This is a very stupid and lame movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jackal-Split Among the Soviets? ***1/2
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Apparently, in this terse thriller, there was a split between various Soviet groups. Soviets have sent the Jackal out for his next killing,but yet there are Soviets who are working against him. That being said, we have a tense thriller where Bruce Willis sheds his usual crime stopping prevention to assume the role of the cold and calculating killer. He is wonderfully matched by Richard Gere's IRA terrorist, with a great Irish accent who has a score to settle with Willis. Willis is cunning, sly and remains unknown to all with the exception of Gere who had worked with him at one time. What the Willis character does to the Jack Black character is horrifying and yet we're able to watch it on screen. Sidney Poitier gives excellent support as a CIA agent. He comes to trust the Gere character fully as seen by the film's ending.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great Performance, Standard Action Thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tabuno
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The standout performance and characterization offered up by Bruce Willis as the Jackal somehow can't lift up this action thriller to the level of greatest which is odd because the script, the story are all classic Tom Clancy movie thriller standards. Nevertheless, this movie is well worth watching just for Willis's superior cold and calculating performance that most evil assassins just become another stereotypical, sub-intelligence by the numbers performances. There is just enough rough edges in this movie to make this movie well above average because it avoids being too cute, too polished, too super-ordinary implausible and that's this movie's nuanced directed distinction.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Decent Remake of the 1970's Film--Good Acting But Somewhat Predictable Script
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    classicalsteve
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Bruce Willis and Richard Gere have to be given a lot of credit for saving this film. If not for their excellent acting, the script does lapse into somewhat predictable political-espionage thriller clich&eacute;. It's not like we don't have a lot of similar fair piled into the film archives of the studios. Willis makes a great assassin nicknamed "Jackal". He' been hired out for 70 million no less to take out somewhat in the US, but we don't know who. He's the ultimate man of mystery, taking on different disguises in different part of the country. The FBI and CIA can't get a handle on him. Figures. So the only guy who might have a chance to keep the Jackal from blowing up the whole country is a US prisoner formerly with the IRA. Although not all the details are clear, he was involved in some kind of operation with the Jackall who shot his bride-to-be, wounding her and killing their unborn child in the process. The CIA and FBI, headed by Sidney Poitier, convince Gere to sign onto the operation to stop the Jackal from whatever heinous crime he is going to enact, which we assume is of a higher import than taking out the local janitor. He already does that with ease. In exchange, he might be released. The best parts of the film consist of the many disguises Willis dons as the Jackal. In one, he appears like a former hippie out of the Haight-Ashbury with long blond hair and plaid shirt untucked. In another, he's an international businessman. He even plays a homosexual. In one of his more contrived efforts, he's an overweight laborer with hideous taste in clothes. But he not only disguises himself. He constantly changes the color and plates of his van. And those who gets in his way pay the usual price. A superb cast infiltrates this movie. Besides Willis, Poitier, and Gere, even Jack Black makes a surprise appearance as a sleazy underground arms manufacturer. He receives an order from Willis to supply him with some kind of weapons device. Half now, half on delivery, Willis' typical terms. Of course, the schmuck doesn't understand who he's dealing with. You don't up the price on a hired assassin. Pretty good through about 2/3rd's to 3/4th's. When the actual crime is finally revealed, I found it somewhat of a let down. The very end seemed typical of many films of this type, leading to a final confrontation with Willis and Gere. I was hoping the film would take a detour and lead in an unexpected direction, but about 30 minutes toward the end, I kind of knew where it was going. That said, Willis' portrayal is still worth the price of admission.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not that good!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    spaz47
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a remake of an earlier film: "The day of the Jackal," which was far more believable and intense. The weapon used in the 1st film was very small and deadly, yet could be hidden very easily. In the 2nd film, the weapon in question looks like it belongs on a Bradley Fighting Vehicle! Also in the 1st film the detective solves the case; here we have An imprisoned Irish terrorist teaching a highly experienced FBI agent his job! A really "badly written" scene was where the 3 FBI agents have moved a family out of their house and the FBI folks are "cleaning up.(?) You actually have an FBI agent taking out the garbage! Trust me, agents don't have the time for this. Also, as soon as they noticed the 1st agent was missing and probably dead, they would have vacated the house and called for back-up! They should have also cut the speaker wires on the sound system that the Jackal was using to distract them! Yes, entertaining, but no where as good as the original...and remember that "lethal spray" that Willis used on his van to kill a "hijacker?" Nobody knows what it was. Well I'll tell you: it was "Anti-credibility spray" that destroys all credibility in any film that it's in...hooray for Hollywood!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bruce Willis is the whole show
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    msroz
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The original movie "Day of the Jackal" has nothing to worry about from this remake. I'd like to know why the Jackal intentionally gives important clues throughout. I'd like to know how Isabella knew where Declan (Richard Gere) was in the subway and where she got another gun. I'd like to know why the Jackal kills 3 agents in Isabella's hiding place, and then she shows up. I'd like to know how Willis got the weapon off the boat and to another location. That's enough loose ends for now. The second half was not as good as the first half, but the whole movie was surprisingly lacking in tension. It had too many hackneyed lines. It seemed tired. Sidney Poitier seemed tired. Willis was very good. His expressions and facial contortions and impassiveness at times made the movie. Gere's part was just too Hollywoodized. I knew that Diane Venora would bite the dust. She underplayed admirably. A flabby thriller flabbily directed. Apart from Willis, it had a neat monster weapon and method of assassination.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Solid, But Generic Thriller!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    g-bodyl
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Jackal is based of the 1973 film, The Day of the Jackal. This 1997 version is a different story than the 1973 version. It is more of a generic story with the feeling "been there, done that." However, it is still a good movie with action, great acting, and some unexpected moments. This is about how FBI deputy director gets a terrorist, Mulqueen out of prison to help him track down a shady assassin, known as the Jackal, before he assassinates his political targets. The acting is great. Bruce Willis and Richard Gere had great chemistry. Willis was the reason why I saw this movie. I was surprised to see Sidney Poitier here but he did a great job as usual. Overall, this is a solid film that is there for enjoyment, not for awards or major critical success. Even though I seen many of these kind of films, I liked it. I rate this film 8/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An underrated thriller undeserving of all the hate.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Shawn Watson (gator_macready@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've never understood why The Jackal has been cursed with poor reviews from pretty much everybody. From the day I saw it as a 17-year-old in January 1998 I always found it entertaining and exciting. This might be down to the fact that I have never seen the 1973 original. Brucie plays a nameless assassin, cool as ice and utterly emotionless. Richard Gere is the only man to have seen him. He's let out of prison to assist the FBI in catching the Jackal before he takes out an uncertain high-ranking official. Willis and Gere are, for the most part, leading their own movies as they never meet until the climax. It's very interesting watching them both go about their business, Willis hatching a master plan and Gere methodically picking apart his trail and hunting him down. There is great support from Sidney Poitier and cutie-pie Diane Venora as a scarred Russian cop. With a wide variety of brilliantly photographed locations across the US and Canada, and plot with a medium-level of complexity it's not entirely brainless viewing but not too taxing as to alienate lazy viewers. I honestly do not get why so many people hate it. Willis has done far worse films (even seen Mercury Rising?) that get off scot-free somehow, but The Jackal doesn't get off so lightly. Aside from Gere's slightly dodgy Oirish accent I have no complaints about this film. Give it a chance and you might just be entertained.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This film deserves a more honest look
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rene2030
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Yeah, I know, it is so easy to bash this film as so many of you have done. It's a thriller that doesn't stand out in it's genre, pretty easy to watch but not more than that. It has a high profile cast including Bruce Willis, Richard Gere and a couple of very very decent actors slash actresses like J.K. Simmons, Diane Venora and so on, so nothing wrong with that. A more than decent director in Michael Caton-Jones, who does his best with the material he's got and doing a good job at it. Sadly he has to work with a script that has potholes the size of Hummers H3 in it, so it's easy to see why this film doesn't work the way it's supposed to. but!!!! If you have read some of the novels written by Robert Ludlum (may God rest his soul) you will have picked up some of the vibe he has put in most of his novels, putting the Jason Bourne Trilogy upfront. And just to be clear about it, I'm not talking about the miniseries starring Richard Chamberlain and also not even mentioning the Matt Damon movies (although those were really cool) but the original novels as Mr. Ludlum intended them to be. If you have these novels in the back of your head and are a fan of them you will find this movie pretty enjoyable to watch although the execution of this movie has some problems in staying believable. It is in general a pretty normal thriller with (&Iacute;'m sorry to say) some mayor flaws. But I can't escape the feeling that the script (allthough adapted from an apparent classic of which I haven't yet had the pleasure of watching) was written in the mindset of an all-out genius Robert Ludlum-vibe, which I picked up on immediately and enjoyed very much.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This is not a remake
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    boatista24
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I think people here expect to see a remake of The Day of the Jackal. This movie has nothing to do with The Day of the Jackal. This is an independent fictitious tale based upon Carlos the Jackal. It is one of my favorite Bruce Willis flicks, and has one of the greatest movie scores of all time. As far as entertainment by Bruce Willis goes, this is an 8 out of 10, hands down. Get over this being a lousy remake of an entirely different movie, and appreciate it for what it is. An outstanding effort - $60 million worth. In my opinion, Bruce Willis is as good as a bad guy as he was in any of his good guy roles. I would not dismiss this movie until you see how great he was in it. A terrific cast and great story line make this a must see.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Slow and too traditionally scripted
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rightwingisevil
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie needs some patience to watch along. The screenplay was not quite well written, it's too loose and too slow and too traditionally directed, edited with bad casting job. The Special Agent on this case was too old and not quite necessary with a role in this movie. The cooperation between the Russian and the American were a bit ridiculous and unconvincing, the sound track, the music came along with the whole movie was so bad and so out of place. The so-called "Jackal" played by Bruce Willis was too pretentious and too clich&eacute;. Casting a scar-faced Russian Military Intelligence officer was also unnecessary. But the major problem was the lame role of the FBI Special Agent in Charge, Sydney Pottier was too old not to be forced into retirement maybe 10 years late. The whole movie spent a lot of money on locations, but the lame dialog simply failed to comply with the lame screenplay. The most ridiculous thing was the never stop changing hair style and the colors as though the only thing the Jackal good at was changing his hair colors and style. Arranged a IRA terrorist imprisoned in the U.S. territory was also a very lame scenario, Richard Gere in this movie was just like a lame office boy who's so smart that every time he could just cut in during FBI meetings to point out something nobody thought about, the smartest kid in the classroom. This is a very stupid and lame movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jackal-Split Among the Soviets? ***1/2
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Apparently, in this terse thriller, there was a split between various Soviet groups. Soviets have sent the Jackal out for his next killing,but yet there are Soviets who are working against him. That being said, we have a tense thriller where Bruce Willis sheds his usual crime stopping prevention to assume the role of the cold and calculating killer. He is wonderfully matched by Richard Gere's IRA terrorist, with a great Irish accent who has a score to settle with Willis. Willis is cunning, sly and remains unknown to all with the exception of Gere who had worked with him at one time. What the Willis character does to the Jack Black character is horrifying and yet we're able to watch it on screen. Sidney Poitier gives excellent support as a CIA agent. He comes to trust the Gere character fully as seen by the film's ending.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great Performance, Standard Action Thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tabuno
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The standout performance and characterization offered up by Bruce Willis as the Jackal somehow can't lift up this action thriller to the level of greatest which is odd because the script, the story are all classic Tom Clancy movie thriller standards. Nevertheless, this movie is well worth watching just for Willis's superior cold and calculating performance that most evil assassins just become another stereotypical, sub-intelligence by the numbers performances. There is just enough rough edges in this movie to make this movie well above average because it avoids being too cute, too polished, too super-ordinary implausible and that's this movie's nuanced directed distinction.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Decent Remake of the 1970's Film--Good Acting But Somewhat Predictable Script
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    classicalsteve
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Bruce Willis and Richard Gere have to be given a lot of credit for saving this film. If not for their excellent acting, the script does lapse into somewhat predictable political-espionage thriller clich&eacute;. It's not like we don't have a lot of similar fair piled into the film archives of the studios. Willis makes a great assassin nicknamed "Jackal". He' been hired out for 70 million no less to take out somewhat in the US, but we don't know who. He's the ultimate man of mystery, taking on different disguises in different part of the country. The FBI and CIA can't get a handle on him. Figures. So the only guy who might have a chance to keep the Jackal from blowing up the whole country is a US prisoner formerly with the IRA. Although not all the details are clear, he was involved in some kind of operation with the Jackall who shot his bride-to-be, wounding her and killing their unborn child in the process. The CIA and FBI, headed by Sidney Poitier, convince Gere to sign onto the operation to stop the Jackal from whatever heinous crime he is going to enact, which we assume is of a higher import than taking out the local janitor. He already does that with ease. In exchange, he might be released. The best parts of the film consist of the many disguises Willis dons as the Jackal. In one, he appears like a former hippie out of the Haight-Ashbury with long blond hair and plaid shirt untucked. In another, he's an international businessman. He even plays a homosexual. In one of his more contrived efforts, he's an overweight laborer with hideous taste in clothes. But he not only disguises himself. He constantly changes the color and plates of his van. And those who gets in his way pay the usual price. A superb cast infiltrates this movie. Besides Willis, Poitier, and Gere, even Jack Black makes a surprise appearance as a sleazy underground arms manufacturer. He receives an order from Willis to supply him with some kind of weapons device. Half now, half on delivery, Willis' typical terms. Of course, the schmuck doesn't understand who he's dealing with. You don't up the price on a hired assassin. Pretty good through about 2/3rd's to 3/4th's. When the actual crime is finally revealed, I found it somewhat of a let down. The very end seemed typical of many films of this type, leading to a final confrontation with Willis and Gere. I was hoping the film would take a detour and lead in an unexpected direction, but about 30 minutes toward the end, I kind of knew where it was going. That said, Willis' portrayal is still worth the price of admission.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not that good!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    spaz47
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a remake of an earlier film: "The day of the Jackal," which was far more believable and intense. The weapon used in the 1st film was very small and deadly, yet could be hidden very easily. In the 2nd film, the weapon in question looks like it belongs on a Bradley Fighting Vehicle! Also in the 1st film the detective solves the case; here we have An imprisoned Irish terrorist teaching a highly experienced FBI agent his job! A really "badly written" scene was where the 3 FBI agents have moved a family out of their house and the FBI folks are "cleaning up.(?) You actually have an FBI agent taking out the garbage! Trust me, agents don't have the time for this. Also, as soon as they noticed the 1st agent was missing and probably dead, they would have vacated the house and called for back-up! They should have also cut the speaker wires on the sound system that the Jackal was using to distract them! Yes, entertaining, but no where as good as the original...and remember that "lethal spray" that Willis used on his van to kill a "hijacker?" Nobody knows what it was. Well I'll tell you: it was "Anti-credibility spray" that destroys all credibility in any film that it's in...hooray for Hollywood!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bruce Willis is the whole show
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    msroz
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The original movie "Day of the Jackal" has nothing to worry about from this remake. I'd like to know why the Jackal intentionally gives important clues throughout. I'd like to know how Isabella knew where Declan (Richard Gere) was in the subway and where she got another gun. I'd like to know why the Jackal kills 3 agents in Isabella's hiding place, and then she shows up. I'd like to know how Willis got the weapon off the boat and to another location. That's enough loose ends for now. The second half was not as good as the first half, but the whole movie was surprisingly lacking in tension. It had too many hackneyed lines. It seemed tired. Sidney Poitier seemed tired. Willis was very good. His expressions and facial contortions and impassiveness at times made the movie. Gere's part was just too Hollywoodized. I knew that Diane Venora would bite the dust. She underplayed admirably. A flabby thriller flabbily directed. Apart from Willis, it had a neat monster weapon and method of assassination.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Solid, But Generic Thriller!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    g-bodyl
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/5/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Jackal is based of the 1973 film, The Day of the Jackal. This 1997 version is a different story than the 1973 version. It is more of a generic story with the feeling "been there, done that." However, it is still a good movie with action, great acting, and some unexpected moments. This is about how FBI deputy director gets a terrorist, Mulqueen out of prison to help him track down a shady assassin, known as the Jackal, before he assassinates his political targets. The acting is great. Bruce Willis and Richard Gere had great chemistry. Willis was the reason why I saw this movie. I was surprised to see Sidney Poitier here but he did a great job as usual. Overall, this is a solid film that is there for enjoyment, not for awards or major critical success. Even though I seen many of these kind of films, I liked it. I rate this film 8/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An underrated thriller undeserving of all the hate.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Shawn Watson (gator_macready@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've never understood why The Jackal has been cursed with poor reviews from pretty much everybody. From the day I saw it as a 17-year-old in January 1998 I always found it entertaining and exciting. This might be down to the fact that I have never seen the 1973 original. Brucie plays a nameless assassin, cool as ice and utterly emotionless. Richard Gere is the only man to have seen him. He's let out of prison to assist the FBI in catching the Jackal before he takes out an uncertain high-ranking official. Willis and Gere are, for the most part, leading their own movies as they never meet until the climax. It's very interesting watching them both go about their business, Willis hatching a master plan and Gere methodically picking apart his trail and hunting him down. There is great support from Sidney Poitier and cutie-pie Diane Venora as a scarred Russian cop. With a wide variety of brilliantly photographed locations across the US and Canada, and plot with a medium-level of complexity it's not entirely brainless viewing but not too taxing as to alienate lazy viewers. I honestly do not get why so many people hate it. Willis has done far worse films (even seen Mercury Rising?) that get off scot-free somehow, but The Jackal doesn't get off so lightly. Aside from Gere's slightly dodgy Oirish accent I have no complaints about this film. Give it a chance and you might just be entertained.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This film deserves a more honest look
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rene2030
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Yeah, I know, it is so easy to bash this film as so many of you have done. It's a thriller that doesn't stand out in it's genre, pretty easy to watch but not more than that. It has a high profile cast including Bruce Willis, Richard Gere and a couple of very very decent actors slash actresses like J.K. Simmons, Diane Venora and so on, so nothing wrong with that. A more than decent director in Michael Caton-Jones, who does his best with the material he's got and doing a good job at it. Sadly he has to work with a script that has potholes the size of Hummers H3 in it, so it's easy to see why this film doesn't work the way it's supposed to. but!!!! If you have read some of the novels written by Robert Ludlum (may God rest his soul) you will have picked up some of the vibe he has put in most of his novels, putting the Jason Bourne Trilogy upfront. And just to be clear about it, I'm not talking about the miniseries starring Richard Chamberlain and also not even mentioning the Matt Damon movies (although those were really cool) but the original novels as Mr. Ludlum intended them to be. If you have these novels in the back of your head and are a fan of them you will find this movie pretty enjoyable to watch although the execution of this movie has some problems in staying believable. It is in general a pretty normal thriller with (&Iacute;'m sorry to say) some mayor flaws. But I can't escape the feeling that the script (allthough adapted from an apparent classic of which I haven't yet had the pleasure of watching) was written in the mindset of an all-out genius Robert Ludlum-vibe, which I picked up on immediately and enjoyed very much.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This is not a remake
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    boatista24
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I think people here expect to see a remake of The Day of the Jackal. This movie has nothing to do with The Day of the Jackal. This is an independent fictitious tale based upon Carlos the Jackal. It is one of my favorite Bruce Willis flicks, and has one of the greatest movie scores of all time. As far as entertainment by Bruce Willis goes, this is an 8 out of 10, hands down. Get over this being a lousy remake of an entirely different movie, and appreciate it for what it is. An outstanding effort - $60 million worth. In my opinion, Bruce Willis is as good as a bad guy as he was in any of his good guy roles. I would not dismiss this movie until you see how great he was in it. A terrific cast and great story line make this a must see.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Slow and too traditionally scripted
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rightwingisevil
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie needs some patience to watch along. The screenplay was not quite well written, it's too loose and too slow and too traditionally directed, edited with bad casting job. The Special Agent on this case was too old and not quite necessary with a role in this movie. The cooperation between the Russian and the American were a bit ridiculous and unconvincing, the sound track, the music came along with the whole movie was so bad and so out of place. The so-called "Jackal" played by Bruce Willis was too pretentious and too clich&eacute;. Casting a scar-faced Russian Military Intelligence officer was also unnecessary. But the major problem was the lame role of the FBI Special Agent in Charge, Sydney Pottier was too old not to be forced into retirement maybe 10 years late. The whole movie spent a lot of money on locations, but the lame dialog simply failed to comply with the lame screenplay. The most ridiculous thing was the never stop changing hair style and the colors as though the only thing the Jackal good at was changing his hair colors and style. Arranged a IRA terrorist imprisoned in the U.S. territory was also a very lame scenario, Richard Gere in this movie was just like a lame office boy who's so smart that every time he could just cut in during FBI meetings to point out something nobody thought about, the smartest kid in the classroom. This is a very stupid and lame movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
