<filme>
 <id>
  69
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0109830
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1994
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Forrest Gump, o Contador de Hist&oacute;rias
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  8.7
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Forrest Gump, while not intelligent, has accidentally been present at many historic moments, but his true love, Jenny Curran, eludes him.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Forrest Gump is a simple man with a low I.Q. but good intentions. He is running through childhood with his best and only friend Jenny. His 'mama' teaches him the ways of life and leaves him to choose his destiny. Forrest joins the army for service in Vietnam, finding new friends called Dan and Bubba, he wins medals, creates a famous shrimp fishing fleet, inspires people to jog, starts a ping-pong craze, create the smiley, write bumper stickers and songs, donating to people and meeting the president several times. However, this is all irrelevant to Forrest who can only think of his childhood sweetheart Jenny Curran. Who has messed up her life. Although in the end all he wants to prove is that anyone can love anyone.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Romance
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   love
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   bus stop
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   running
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   bus
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   simple man
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Robert Zemeckis
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Winston Groom
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Eric Roth
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Tom Hanks
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Robin Wright
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Gary Sinise
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Amazing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    monicaalettarollins94
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Quite simple, the greatest film ever made. This movie is simply one of the greatest movie ever made. Its a mixture of love, danger, drugs, and lot and lots of running. This movie is still going strong and it 2013. That is amazing not even any of the movies made this year is still going this strong. That is amazing that just tells you that this movie is great very bit as worthy for the Oscar. And anything else that it might get. I can't say it enough watch this movie and I bet it will make you cry. I cannot say it enough: This is THE top film of all time. Watch it you'll see.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Unforgettable Classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    coltinlillico
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Forrest Gump sums up American pop culture from the 60s to the 90s. The impossible to dislike protagonist Forrest Gump takes the film on an unforgettable journey through some of America's most famous moments. One of Tom Hanks' best performances and with a top notch director like Robert Zemeckis, it is hard to go wrong. Every single aspect of the film falls together perfectly, the supporting cast, cinematography, and especially the soundtrack give this movie everything it needs. At times, it may seem clich&eacute; and unrealistic, but its really the heart of this movie that makes you fall in love with it. Forrest Gump is a must see for everyone.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Touches One's Heart
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Angel Metayer
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I LOVED this movie. It was so cutely written. The fortune's of a man who decided to take all the steps he needed to not only run, but to run for the one he loves. Forest Gump isn't just a POV of the 'simple minded' on heir views of love, but it's also the triumph you feel for him. Despite everything, home really was were the heart is. This movie will cause you to open your heart and your mind, following Gump on his journey of determination to prove he could be a real man for Jenny. He didn't stay down when he was bullied and he didn't, as most humans selfishly do, think of only himself. I would definitely recommend this movie for families to watch, it will always be a family classic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Momma said they was my magic shoes...momma said they'd take me anywhere"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    daftpunknightvision
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    , Forrest Gump is the kind of guy that would take off his coat for a stranger if they were cold. The kind of person who forgives over and over and doesn't really want much in return besides friendship. He's not the smartest tool in the shed, but his love and compassion for the ones in his life go beyond what most normal people are capable of. Everyone knows he's basically the nerdy (but witty) underdog, and he is always teased or asked if he's stupid, to which he normally replies "stupid is as stupid does". He joins the army after he graduates college and meets his best good friend Bubba on the bus (a black man who is very similar in character to Forrest, and who immediately clicks with him). Bubba tells Forrest about the shrimping business, which has run in his family for at least 2 generations. They make a deal to form a "shrimping" team after they return home and split all the money 50-50. *SPOILER ALERT* *DO NOT KEEP SCROLLING IF YOU HAVEN'T SEEN THIS MOVIE Not very long after Bubba and Gump make their pact, Bubba gets wounded in battle, as does their Lieutenant, Dan...and a couple other characters. Dan wants Forrest to leave him to get killed in battle (by bombs) because he lost his legs and he wanted to die with honor, but Forrest picked him up despite Dan's orders, and tries to save both him and Bubba, but after Bubba is carried by Forrest (also against Dan's orders), he is gasping for air and dies in Forrest's arms. I think this is one of the most important parts of the movie, because it shows not only how humble Mr. Gump is towards his friends, but his sheer backbone and determination to do the right thing. Thank you for reading
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Forrest Gump is awesome
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Abdullah Mohammed
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For as long as i remember my brother and friend have been convincing me to watch this movie but i said i will one day. Few days ago i finally did and WOW it blew me away O_O it was such an awesome experience. I recommend this movie to everyone if you are like me waiting for almost 20 years lol :D the story of the movie is told by Forrest Gump in the famous bus stop then movie goes into flash backs as he is explaining. this is a great adventure that shouldn't be missed and you should watch the Blu-ray version because its cheap and really great. This has to be my Favorite Tom Hanks movie and i think its the movie that made him so famous. i give this movie 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Support makes the Difference
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bo Thurston
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is excellent because of its supporting characters. The movie takes place during the 1950's to 1970's, and follows the journey of a simple man living in Alabama, named Forrest Gump. The movie starts off with him describing his childhood to a complete stranger, while waiting for a bus at the bus stop, and continues to tell his story to several different strangers. When he is telling his story he reveals that he fought in Vietnam, met a few presidents, and even won the Medal of Honor. Throughout his story, Forrest has a huge impact on the people in his life, which also have the same effect on him. I like the movie Forrest Gump because the plot hooks you right from the beginning, with supporting characters that make their own unique contribution to Forrest's life. In Forrest Gump there are four supporting characters named Mama, Lieutenant Dan, Jenny, and Bubba. Each of these four supporting characters has an effect on Forrest's overall story. Mama is Forrest's mother, and is the foundation for his life. Mama is the character who raised him, taught him right from wrong, and was always able to help him by explaining the aspects of life in a unique way. For example, when Forrest asks what happened to his father, his mother says "he is on vacation" and uses this to explain that the father left them. Lieutenant Dan is the Lieutenant in charge of Forrest while he is serving in Vietnam. Lieutenant Dan is the man that inspires Forrest to be a better person, and to never leave a man behind. After Vietnam, the two of them go into the shrimping business together and make a lot of money. Initially when Forrest first meets Lieutenant Dan, Dan is very hostile. Once they go into the shrimping business together, Forrest mentions that Dan has "coming to Jesus" moment, which I think was influenced by Forrest. Jenny Curran is in my opinion the most important supporting character in the entire movie, because she is constantly Forrest's object of affection. In the beginning of the movie, they first meet on the school bus, where Forrest compares Jenny to an angel. From that point on, they become best friends and is mentioned that they are "like peas and carrots". In every significant event in Forrest's life, Forrest always mentions something about Jenny or that he misses her. They have several encounters throughout the entire movie, with one of them resulting to parenthood for Jenny and Forrest. Towards the end of the movie, Jenny reveals that she has some kind of virus but the doctors do not know what it is, and ends up asking Forrest to marry her. Forrest and Jenny get married, but unfortunately Jenny dies shortly after. This leaves Forrest to raise their son on his own. Bubba is the last supporting character, and is Forrest's other best friend, besides Jenny. Forrest meets Bubba in Vietnam, and persuades Forrest to go into the shrimping business. Overall this is a must-see movie because of its use of supporting characters to heavily influence the main character's thought process and way of life. It is more interesting to watch a movie or TV show when you care not only about the main character, but the supporting characters as well. You're more intrigued to watch the entire movie because you want to know what the resolution is for everyone, because it is fairly easy to predict the outcome for the main character a majority of the time. In conclusion, I like the movie Forrest Gump because the plot hooks you right from the beginning, with supporting characters that make their own unique contribution to Forrest's life.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Why the Hate?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sam_frank95
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Forrest Gump is a feat in cinematic history. It has set a new (high) standard for movies. So, why the hate? This movie I have seen on both most overrated and worst Best Picture Winners list. It is my favorite movie. However, on the other hand, it is also on Top Best Picture Winners lists. Forrest Gump has virtually anything you could want in a movie (besides crime). It has action (war violence), comedy, drama, romance... This list could go on and on. I'm simply saying this: this movie is fantastic, I love it, and it is a MUST-SEE for film fans (and anyone else). By the way, I cried, and I have never cried in a movie before. This movie is golden, it won six Oscars (and should have won more) and ignore the negative reviews. You don't know Forrest Gump until you've seen it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Please don't watch...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tarun Singh Surya
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Please don't watch this.... i have rated this movie a 10 but still i hate it... only because this is so damn beautiful... sometimes too much beauty creates ache in the heart... it makes you sad for once and the next moment motivated... 1994 was one of the best year for movies, Pulp fiction, The shawshank redemption and Forrest Gump... Everything about this movie is perfect... no surprise that it was awarded so heavily... sometimes i wonder why they stopped making those great movies... all we get is some sequel or prequel of action dramas... i hope to see some good movie soon in near future... Tom hanks please please, now move over to the Dan brown stuff. one of the best watch ever..
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Uplifting & Wondrous Fable.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tom Hanks plays Forrest Gump in Robert Zemekis's Academy Award winning(Best picture, director, & actor) fable about a simple and honest man who finds himself floating through life like(the ever-present) feather in the wind. He is often bullied growing up, but finds solace in his best friend Jenny, whom he comes to love dearly as they get older. She tells him to "run Forrest, run" and he does, and one day runs into a football game, inspiring the coach to put him on the team, which makes him more popular, though at graduation he joins the military, where he fits right in, much to the bewilderment of his superior officer, Lt. Dan(played by Gary Sinise) whose life he saves, giving him a medal and inspiring him to be a Ping-Pong champion, where he meets three different U.S. Presidents, and later becomes a multi-millionaire by investing in "a fruit company" that takes off in a big way. He loves his mother(played by Sally Field) and takes her departure quite hard, running a marathon across the country for years, until he meets up with the elusive Jenny once again... Epic-scale character study is supremely well crafted and acted, remaining a funny, moving, and inspired drama about how one good man can affect the world around him, and still not know it, and remain uncorrupted by it. A truly marvelous achievement by all.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    best movie ever
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ozan HATIL
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I just recently saw this film and I gotta say, it had to be one of the best movies I've ever seen! This film has everything you could want in a film, humor, sadness, drama, action, etc. The actors were fantastic, especially Tom Hanks, who's performance is one of the best ever. Once you love this movie you can never ever forget it. it's so unique and wonderful. just a brilliant masterpiece. i'm really lucky that i watched this movie. Maybe thats why it took 6 academy awards. I re-watch it every year.:) I can just recommend it for everybody who wants to see a perfect movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Amazing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    monicaalettarollins94
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Quite simple, the greatest film ever made. This movie is simply one of the greatest movie ever made. Its a mixture of love, danger, drugs, and lot and lots of running. This movie is still going strong and it 2013. That is amazing not even any of the movies made this year is still going this strong. That is amazing that just tells you that this movie is great very bit as worthy for the Oscar. And anything else that it might get. I can't say it enough watch this movie and I bet it will make you cry. I cannot say it enough: This is THE top film of all time. Watch it you'll see.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Unforgettable Classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    coltinlillico
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Forrest Gump sums up American pop culture from the 60s to the 90s. The impossible to dislike protagonist Forrest Gump takes the film on an unforgettable journey through some of America's most famous moments. One of Tom Hanks' best performances and with a top notch director like Robert Zemeckis, it is hard to go wrong. Every single aspect of the film falls together perfectly, the supporting cast, cinematography, and especially the soundtrack give this movie everything it needs. At times, it may seem clich&eacute; and unrealistic, but its really the heart of this movie that makes you fall in love with it. Forrest Gump is a must see for everyone.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Touches One's Heart
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Angel Metayer
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I LOVED this movie. It was so cutely written. The fortune's of a man who decided to take all the steps he needed to not only run, but to run for the one he loves. Forest Gump isn't just a POV of the 'simple minded' on heir views of love, but it's also the triumph you feel for him. Despite everything, home really was were the heart is. This movie will cause you to open your heart and your mind, following Gump on his journey of determination to prove he could be a real man for Jenny. He didn't stay down when he was bullied and he didn't, as most humans selfishly do, think of only himself. I would definitely recommend this movie for families to watch, it will always be a family classic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Momma said they was my magic shoes...momma said they'd take me anywhere"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    daftpunknightvision
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    , Forrest Gump is the kind of guy that would take off his coat for a stranger if they were cold. The kind of person who forgives over and over and doesn't really want much in return besides friendship. He's not the smartest tool in the shed, but his love and compassion for the ones in his life go beyond what most normal people are capable of. Everyone knows he's basically the nerdy (but witty) underdog, and he is always teased or asked if he's stupid, to which he normally replies "stupid is as stupid does". He joins the army after he graduates college and meets his best good friend Bubba on the bus (a black man who is very similar in character to Forrest, and who immediately clicks with him). Bubba tells Forrest about the shrimping business, which has run in his family for at least 2 generations. They make a deal to form a "shrimping" team after they return home and split all the money 50-50. *SPOILER ALERT* *DO NOT KEEP SCROLLING IF YOU HAVEN'T SEEN THIS MOVIE Not very long after Bubba and Gump make their pact, Bubba gets wounded in battle, as does their Lieutenant, Dan...and a couple other characters. Dan wants Forrest to leave him to get killed in battle (by bombs) because he lost his legs and he wanted to die with honor, but Forrest picked him up despite Dan's orders, and tries to save both him and Bubba, but after Bubba is carried by Forrest (also against Dan's orders), he is gasping for air and dies in Forrest's arms. I think this is one of the most important parts of the movie, because it shows not only how humble Mr. Gump is towards his friends, but his sheer backbone and determination to do the right thing. Thank you for reading
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Forrest Gump is awesome
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Abdullah Mohammed
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For as long as i remember my brother and friend have been convincing me to watch this movie but i said i will one day. Few days ago i finally did and WOW it blew me away O_O it was such an awesome experience. I recommend this movie to everyone if you are like me waiting for almost 20 years lol :D the story of the movie is told by Forrest Gump in the famous bus stop then movie goes into flash backs as he is explaining. this is a great adventure that shouldn't be missed and you should watch the Blu-ray version because its cheap and really great. This has to be my Favorite Tom Hanks movie and i think its the movie that made him so famous. i give this movie 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Support makes the Difference
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bo Thurston
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is excellent because of its supporting characters. The movie takes place during the 1950's to 1970's, and follows the journey of a simple man living in Alabama, named Forrest Gump. The movie starts off with him describing his childhood to a complete stranger, while waiting for a bus at the bus stop, and continues to tell his story to several different strangers. When he is telling his story he reveals that he fought in Vietnam, met a few presidents, and even won the Medal of Honor. Throughout his story, Forrest has a huge impact on the people in his life, which also have the same effect on him. I like the movie Forrest Gump because the plot hooks you right from the beginning, with supporting characters that make their own unique contribution to Forrest's life. In Forrest Gump there are four supporting characters named Mama, Lieutenant Dan, Jenny, and Bubba. Each of these four supporting characters has an effect on Forrest's overall story. Mama is Forrest's mother, and is the foundation for his life. Mama is the character who raised him, taught him right from wrong, and was always able to help him by explaining the aspects of life in a unique way. For example, when Forrest asks what happened to his father, his mother says "he is on vacation" and uses this to explain that the father left them. Lieutenant Dan is the Lieutenant in charge of Forrest while he is serving in Vietnam. Lieutenant Dan is the man that inspires Forrest to be a better person, and to never leave a man behind. After Vietnam, the two of them go into the shrimping business together and make a lot of money. Initially when Forrest first meets Lieutenant Dan, Dan is very hostile. Once they go into the shrimping business together, Forrest mentions that Dan has "coming to Jesus" moment, which I think was influenced by Forrest. Jenny Curran is in my opinion the most important supporting character in the entire movie, because she is constantly Forrest's object of affection. In the beginning of the movie, they first meet on the school bus, where Forrest compares Jenny to an angel. From that point on, they become best friends and is mentioned that they are "like peas and carrots". In every significant event in Forrest's life, Forrest always mentions something about Jenny or that he misses her. They have several encounters throughout the entire movie, with one of them resulting to parenthood for Jenny and Forrest. Towards the end of the movie, Jenny reveals that she has some kind of virus but the doctors do not know what it is, and ends up asking Forrest to marry her. Forrest and Jenny get married, but unfortunately Jenny dies shortly after. This leaves Forrest to raise their son on his own. Bubba is the last supporting character, and is Forrest's other best friend, besides Jenny. Forrest meets Bubba in Vietnam, and persuades Forrest to go into the shrimping business. Overall this is a must-see movie because of its use of supporting characters to heavily influence the main character's thought process and way of life. It is more interesting to watch a movie or TV show when you care not only about the main character, but the supporting characters as well. You're more intrigued to watch the entire movie because you want to know what the resolution is for everyone, because it is fairly easy to predict the outcome for the main character a majority of the time. In conclusion, I like the movie Forrest Gump because the plot hooks you right from the beginning, with supporting characters that make their own unique contribution to Forrest's life.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Why the Hate?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sam_frank95
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Forrest Gump is a feat in cinematic history. It has set a new (high) standard for movies. So, why the hate? This movie I have seen on both most overrated and worst Best Picture Winners list. It is my favorite movie. However, on the other hand, it is also on Top Best Picture Winners lists. Forrest Gump has virtually anything you could want in a movie (besides crime). It has action (war violence), comedy, drama, romance... This list could go on and on. I'm simply saying this: this movie is fantastic, I love it, and it is a MUST-SEE for film fans (and anyone else). By the way, I cried, and I have never cried in a movie before. This movie is golden, it won six Oscars (and should have won more) and ignore the negative reviews. You don't know Forrest Gump until you've seen it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Please don't watch...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tarun Singh Surya
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Please don't watch this.... i have rated this movie a 10 but still i hate it... only because this is so damn beautiful... sometimes too much beauty creates ache in the heart... it makes you sad for once and the next moment motivated... 1994 was one of the best year for movies, Pulp fiction, The shawshank redemption and Forrest Gump... Everything about this movie is perfect... no surprise that it was awarded so heavily... sometimes i wonder why they stopped making those great movies... all we get is some sequel or prequel of action dramas... i hope to see some good movie soon in near future... Tom hanks please please, now move over to the Dan brown stuff. one of the best watch ever..
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Uplifting & Wondrous Fable.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tom Hanks plays Forrest Gump in Robert Zemekis's Academy Award winning(Best picture, director, & actor) fable about a simple and honest man who finds himself floating through life like(the ever-present) feather in the wind. He is often bullied growing up, but finds solace in his best friend Jenny, whom he comes to love dearly as they get older. She tells him to "run Forrest, run" and he does, and one day runs into a football game, inspiring the coach to put him on the team, which makes him more popular, though at graduation he joins the military, where he fits right in, much to the bewilderment of his superior officer, Lt. Dan(played by Gary Sinise) whose life he saves, giving him a medal and inspiring him to be a Ping-Pong champion, where he meets three different U.S. Presidents, and later becomes a multi-millionaire by investing in "a fruit company" that takes off in a big way. He loves his mother(played by Sally Field) and takes her departure quite hard, running a marathon across the country for years, until he meets up with the elusive Jenny once again... Epic-scale character study is supremely well crafted and acted, remaining a funny, moving, and inspired drama about how one good man can affect the world around him, and still not know it, and remain uncorrupted by it. A truly marvelous achievement by all.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    best movie ever
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ozan HATIL
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I just recently saw this film and I gotta say, it had to be one of the best movies I've ever seen! This film has everything you could want in a film, humor, sadness, drama, action, etc. The actors were fantastic, especially Tom Hanks, who's performance is one of the best ever. Once you love this movie you can never ever forget it. it's so unique and wonderful. just a brilliant masterpiece. i'm really lucky that i watched this movie. Maybe thats why it took 6 academy awards. I re-watch it every year.:) I can just recommend it for everybody who wants to see a perfect movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Amazing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    monicaalettarollins94
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Quite simple, the greatest film ever made. This movie is simply one of the greatest movie ever made. Its a mixture of love, danger, drugs, and lot and lots of running. This movie is still going strong and it 2013. That is amazing not even any of the movies made this year is still going this strong. That is amazing that just tells you that this movie is great very bit as worthy for the Oscar. And anything else that it might get. I can't say it enough watch this movie and I bet it will make you cry. I cannot say it enough: This is THE top film of all time. Watch it you'll see.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Unforgettable Classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    coltinlillico
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Forrest Gump sums up American pop culture from the 60s to the 90s. The impossible to dislike protagonist Forrest Gump takes the film on an unforgettable journey through some of America's most famous moments. One of Tom Hanks' best performances and with a top notch director like Robert Zemeckis, it is hard to go wrong. Every single aspect of the film falls together perfectly, the supporting cast, cinematography, and especially the soundtrack give this movie everything it needs. At times, it may seem clich&eacute; and unrealistic, but its really the heart of this movie that makes you fall in love with it. Forrest Gump is a must see for everyone.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Touches One's Heart
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Angel Metayer
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I LOVED this movie. It was so cutely written. The fortune's of a man who decided to take all the steps he needed to not only run, but to run for the one he loves. Forest Gump isn't just a POV of the 'simple minded' on heir views of love, but it's also the triumph you feel for him. Despite everything, home really was were the heart is. This movie will cause you to open your heart and your mind, following Gump on his journey of determination to prove he could be a real man for Jenny. He didn't stay down when he was bullied and he didn't, as most humans selfishly do, think of only himself. I would definitely recommend this movie for families to watch, it will always be a family classic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Momma said they was my magic shoes...momma said they'd take me anywhere"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    daftpunknightvision
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    , Forrest Gump is the kind of guy that would take off his coat for a stranger if they were cold. The kind of person who forgives over and over and doesn't really want much in return besides friendship. He's not the smartest tool in the shed, but his love and compassion for the ones in his life go beyond what most normal people are capable of. Everyone knows he's basically the nerdy (but witty) underdog, and he is always teased or asked if he's stupid, to which he normally replies "stupid is as stupid does". He joins the army after he graduates college and meets his best good friend Bubba on the bus (a black man who is very similar in character to Forrest, and who immediately clicks with him). Bubba tells Forrest about the shrimping business, which has run in his family for at least 2 generations. They make a deal to form a "shrimping" team after they return home and split all the money 50-50. *SPOILER ALERT* *DO NOT KEEP SCROLLING IF YOU HAVEN'T SEEN THIS MOVIE Not very long after Bubba and Gump make their pact, Bubba gets wounded in battle, as does their Lieutenant, Dan...and a couple other characters. Dan wants Forrest to leave him to get killed in battle (by bombs) because he lost his legs and he wanted to die with honor, but Forrest picked him up despite Dan's orders, and tries to save both him and Bubba, but after Bubba is carried by Forrest (also against Dan's orders), he is gasping for air and dies in Forrest's arms. I think this is one of the most important parts of the movie, because it shows not only how humble Mr. Gump is towards his friends, but his sheer backbone and determination to do the right thing. Thank you for reading
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Forrest Gump is awesome
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Abdullah Mohammed
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For as long as i remember my brother and friend have been convincing me to watch this movie but i said i will one day. Few days ago i finally did and WOW it blew me away O_O it was such an awesome experience. I recommend this movie to everyone if you are like me waiting for almost 20 years lol :D the story of the movie is told by Forrest Gump in the famous bus stop then movie goes into flash backs as he is explaining. this is a great adventure that shouldn't be missed and you should watch the Blu-ray version because its cheap and really great. This has to be my Favorite Tom Hanks movie and i think its the movie that made him so famous. i give this movie 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Support makes the Difference
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bo Thurston
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is excellent because of its supporting characters. The movie takes place during the 1950's to 1970's, and follows the journey of a simple man living in Alabama, named Forrest Gump. The movie starts off with him describing his childhood to a complete stranger, while waiting for a bus at the bus stop, and continues to tell his story to several different strangers. When he is telling his story he reveals that he fought in Vietnam, met a few presidents, and even won the Medal of Honor. Throughout his story, Forrest has a huge impact on the people in his life, which also have the same effect on him. I like the movie Forrest Gump because the plot hooks you right from the beginning, with supporting characters that make their own unique contribution to Forrest's life. In Forrest Gump there are four supporting characters named Mama, Lieutenant Dan, Jenny, and Bubba. Each of these four supporting characters has an effect on Forrest's overall story. Mama is Forrest's mother, and is the foundation for his life. Mama is the character who raised him, taught him right from wrong, and was always able to help him by explaining the aspects of life in a unique way. For example, when Forrest asks what happened to his father, his mother says "he is on vacation" and uses this to explain that the father left them. Lieutenant Dan is the Lieutenant in charge of Forrest while he is serving in Vietnam. Lieutenant Dan is the man that inspires Forrest to be a better person, and to never leave a man behind. After Vietnam, the two of them go into the shrimping business together and make a lot of money. Initially when Forrest first meets Lieutenant Dan, Dan is very hostile. Once they go into the shrimping business together, Forrest mentions that Dan has "coming to Jesus" moment, which I think was influenced by Forrest. Jenny Curran is in my opinion the most important supporting character in the entire movie, because she is constantly Forrest's object of affection. In the beginning of the movie, they first meet on the school bus, where Forrest compares Jenny to an angel. From that point on, they become best friends and is mentioned that they are "like peas and carrots". In every significant event in Forrest's life, Forrest always mentions something about Jenny or that he misses her. They have several encounters throughout the entire movie, with one of them resulting to parenthood for Jenny and Forrest. Towards the end of the movie, Jenny reveals that she has some kind of virus but the doctors do not know what it is, and ends up asking Forrest to marry her. Forrest and Jenny get married, but unfortunately Jenny dies shortly after. This leaves Forrest to raise their son on his own. Bubba is the last supporting character, and is Forrest's other best friend, besides Jenny. Forrest meets Bubba in Vietnam, and persuades Forrest to go into the shrimping business. Overall this is a must-see movie because of its use of supporting characters to heavily influence the main character's thought process and way of life. It is more interesting to watch a movie or TV show when you care not only about the main character, but the supporting characters as well. You're more intrigued to watch the entire movie because you want to know what the resolution is for everyone, because it is fairly easy to predict the outcome for the main character a majority of the time. In conclusion, I like the movie Forrest Gump because the plot hooks you right from the beginning, with supporting characters that make their own unique contribution to Forrest's life.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Why the Hate?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sam_frank95
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Forrest Gump is a feat in cinematic history. It has set a new (high) standard for movies. So, why the hate? This movie I have seen on both most overrated and worst Best Picture Winners list. It is my favorite movie. However, on the other hand, it is also on Top Best Picture Winners lists. Forrest Gump has virtually anything you could want in a movie (besides crime). It has action (war violence), comedy, drama, romance... This list could go on and on. I'm simply saying this: this movie is fantastic, I love it, and it is a MUST-SEE for film fans (and anyone else). By the way, I cried, and I have never cried in a movie before. This movie is golden, it won six Oscars (and should have won more) and ignore the negative reviews. You don't know Forrest Gump until you've seen it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Please don't watch...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tarun Singh Surya
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Please don't watch this.... i have rated this movie a 10 but still i hate it... only because this is so damn beautiful... sometimes too much beauty creates ache in the heart... it makes you sad for once and the next moment motivated... 1994 was one of the best year for movies, Pulp fiction, The shawshank redemption and Forrest Gump... Everything about this movie is perfect... no surprise that it was awarded so heavily... sometimes i wonder why they stopped making those great movies... all we get is some sequel or prequel of action dramas... i hope to see some good movie soon in near future... Tom hanks please please, now move over to the Dan brown stuff. one of the best watch ever..
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Uplifting & Wondrous Fable.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tom Hanks plays Forrest Gump in Robert Zemekis's Academy Award winning(Best picture, director, & actor) fable about a simple and honest man who finds himself floating through life like(the ever-present) feather in the wind. He is often bullied growing up, but finds solace in his best friend Jenny, whom he comes to love dearly as they get older. She tells him to "run Forrest, run" and he does, and one day runs into a football game, inspiring the coach to put him on the team, which makes him more popular, though at graduation he joins the military, where he fits right in, much to the bewilderment of his superior officer, Lt. Dan(played by Gary Sinise) whose life he saves, giving him a medal and inspiring him to be a Ping-Pong champion, where he meets three different U.S. Presidents, and later becomes a multi-millionaire by investing in "a fruit company" that takes off in a big way. He loves his mother(played by Sally Field) and takes her departure quite hard, running a marathon across the country for years, until he meets up with the elusive Jenny once again... Epic-scale character study is supremely well crafted and acted, remaining a funny, moving, and inspired drama about how one good man can affect the world around him, and still not know it, and remain uncorrupted by it. A truly marvelous achievement by all.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    best movie ever
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ozan HATIL
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I just recently saw this film and I gotta say, it had to be one of the best movies I've ever seen! This film has everything you could want in a film, humor, sadness, drama, action, etc. The actors were fantastic, especially Tom Hanks, who's performance is one of the best ever. Once you love this movie you can never ever forget it. it's so unique and wonderful. just a brilliant masterpiece. i'm really lucky that i watched this movie. Maybe thats why it took 6 academy awards. I re-watch it every year.:) I can just recommend it for everybody who wants to see a perfect movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Amazing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    monicaalettarollins94
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Quite simple, the greatest film ever made. This movie is simply one of the greatest movie ever made. Its a mixture of love, danger, drugs, and lot and lots of running. This movie is still going strong and it 2013. That is amazing not even any of the movies made this year is still going this strong. That is amazing that just tells you that this movie is great very bit as worthy for the Oscar. And anything else that it might get. I can't say it enough watch this movie and I bet it will make you cry. I cannot say it enough: This is THE top film of all time. Watch it you'll see.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Unforgettable Classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    coltinlillico
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Forrest Gump sums up American pop culture from the 60s to the 90s. The impossible to dislike protagonist Forrest Gump takes the film on an unforgettable journey through some of America's most famous moments. One of Tom Hanks' best performances and with a top notch director like Robert Zemeckis, it is hard to go wrong. Every single aspect of the film falls together perfectly, the supporting cast, cinematography, and especially the soundtrack give this movie everything it needs. At times, it may seem clich&eacute; and unrealistic, but its really the heart of this movie that makes you fall in love with it. Forrest Gump is a must see for everyone.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Touches One's Heart
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Angel Metayer
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I LOVED this movie. It was so cutely written. The fortune's of a man who decided to take all the steps he needed to not only run, but to run for the one he loves. Forest Gump isn't just a POV of the 'simple minded' on heir views of love, but it's also the triumph you feel for him. Despite everything, home really was were the heart is. This movie will cause you to open your heart and your mind, following Gump on his journey of determination to prove he could be a real man for Jenny. He didn't stay down when he was bullied and he didn't, as most humans selfishly do, think of only himself. I would definitely recommend this movie for families to watch, it will always be a family classic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Momma said they was my magic shoes...momma said they'd take me anywhere"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    daftpunknightvision
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    , Forrest Gump is the kind of guy that would take off his coat for a stranger if they were cold. The kind of person who forgives over and over and doesn't really want much in return besides friendship. He's not the smartest tool in the shed, but his love and compassion for the ones in his life go beyond what most normal people are capable of. Everyone knows he's basically the nerdy (but witty) underdog, and he is always teased or asked if he's stupid, to which he normally replies "stupid is as stupid does". He joins the army after he graduates college and meets his best good friend Bubba on the bus (a black man who is very similar in character to Forrest, and who immediately clicks with him). Bubba tells Forrest about the shrimping business, which has run in his family for at least 2 generations. They make a deal to form a "shrimping" team after they return home and split all the money 50-50. *SPOILER ALERT* *DO NOT KEEP SCROLLING IF YOU HAVEN'T SEEN THIS MOVIE Not very long after Bubba and Gump make their pact, Bubba gets wounded in battle, as does their Lieutenant, Dan...and a couple other characters. Dan wants Forrest to leave him to get killed in battle (by bombs) because he lost his legs and he wanted to die with honor, but Forrest picked him up despite Dan's orders, and tries to save both him and Bubba, but after Bubba is carried by Forrest (also against Dan's orders), he is gasping for air and dies in Forrest's arms. I think this is one of the most important parts of the movie, because it shows not only how humble Mr. Gump is towards his friends, but his sheer backbone and determination to do the right thing. Thank you for reading
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Forrest Gump is awesome
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Abdullah Mohammed
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For as long as i remember my brother and friend have been convincing me to watch this movie but i said i will one day. Few days ago i finally did and WOW it blew me away O_O it was such an awesome experience. I recommend this movie to everyone if you are like me waiting for almost 20 years lol :D the story of the movie is told by Forrest Gump in the famous bus stop then movie goes into flash backs as he is explaining. this is a great adventure that shouldn't be missed and you should watch the Blu-ray version because its cheap and really great. This has to be my Favorite Tom Hanks movie and i think its the movie that made him so famous. i give this movie 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Support makes the Difference
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bo Thurston
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is excellent because of its supporting characters. The movie takes place during the 1950's to 1970's, and follows the journey of a simple man living in Alabama, named Forrest Gump. The movie starts off with him describing his childhood to a complete stranger, while waiting for a bus at the bus stop, and continues to tell his story to several different strangers. When he is telling his story he reveals that he fought in Vietnam, met a few presidents, and even won the Medal of Honor. Throughout his story, Forrest has a huge impact on the people in his life, which also have the same effect on him. I like the movie Forrest Gump because the plot hooks you right from the beginning, with supporting characters that make their own unique contribution to Forrest's life. In Forrest Gump there are four supporting characters named Mama, Lieutenant Dan, Jenny, and Bubba. Each of these four supporting characters has an effect on Forrest's overall story. Mama is Forrest's mother, and is the foundation for his life. Mama is the character who raised him, taught him right from wrong, and was always able to help him by explaining the aspects of life in a unique way. For example, when Forrest asks what happened to his father, his mother says "he is on vacation" and uses this to explain that the father left them. Lieutenant Dan is the Lieutenant in charge of Forrest while he is serving in Vietnam. Lieutenant Dan is the man that inspires Forrest to be a better person, and to never leave a man behind. After Vietnam, the two of them go into the shrimping business together and make a lot of money. Initially when Forrest first meets Lieutenant Dan, Dan is very hostile. Once they go into the shrimping business together, Forrest mentions that Dan has "coming to Jesus" moment, which I think was influenced by Forrest. Jenny Curran is in my opinion the most important supporting character in the entire movie, because she is constantly Forrest's object of affection. In the beginning of the movie, they first meet on the school bus, where Forrest compares Jenny to an angel. From that point on, they become best friends and is mentioned that they are "like peas and carrots". In every significant event in Forrest's life, Forrest always mentions something about Jenny or that he misses her. They have several encounters throughout the entire movie, with one of them resulting to parenthood for Jenny and Forrest. Towards the end of the movie, Jenny reveals that she has some kind of virus but the doctors do not know what it is, and ends up asking Forrest to marry her. Forrest and Jenny get married, but unfortunately Jenny dies shortly after. This leaves Forrest to raise their son on his own. Bubba is the last supporting character, and is Forrest's other best friend, besides Jenny. Forrest meets Bubba in Vietnam, and persuades Forrest to go into the shrimping business. Overall this is a must-see movie because of its use of supporting characters to heavily influence the main character's thought process and way of life. It is more interesting to watch a movie or TV show when you care not only about the main character, but the supporting characters as well. You're more intrigued to watch the entire movie because you want to know what the resolution is for everyone, because it is fairly easy to predict the outcome for the main character a majority of the time. In conclusion, I like the movie Forrest Gump because the plot hooks you right from the beginning, with supporting characters that make their own unique contribution to Forrest's life.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Why the Hate?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sam_frank95
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Forrest Gump is a feat in cinematic history. It has set a new (high) standard for movies. So, why the hate? This movie I have seen on both most overrated and worst Best Picture Winners list. It is my favorite movie. However, on the other hand, it is also on Top Best Picture Winners lists. Forrest Gump has virtually anything you could want in a movie (besides crime). It has action (war violence), comedy, drama, romance... This list could go on and on. I'm simply saying this: this movie is fantastic, I love it, and it is a MUST-SEE for film fans (and anyone else). By the way, I cried, and I have never cried in a movie before. This movie is golden, it won six Oscars (and should have won more) and ignore the negative reviews. You don't know Forrest Gump until you've seen it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Please don't watch...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tarun Singh Surya
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Please don't watch this.... i have rated this movie a 10 but still i hate it... only because this is so damn beautiful... sometimes too much beauty creates ache in the heart... it makes you sad for once and the next moment motivated... 1994 was one of the best year for movies, Pulp fiction, The shawshank redemption and Forrest Gump... Everything about this movie is perfect... no surprise that it was awarded so heavily... sometimes i wonder why they stopped making those great movies... all we get is some sequel or prequel of action dramas... i hope to see some good movie soon in near future... Tom hanks please please, now move over to the Dan brown stuff. one of the best watch ever..
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Uplifting & Wondrous Fable.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tom Hanks plays Forrest Gump in Robert Zemekis's Academy Award winning(Best picture, director, & actor) fable about a simple and honest man who finds himself floating through life like(the ever-present) feather in the wind. He is often bullied growing up, but finds solace in his best friend Jenny, whom he comes to love dearly as they get older. She tells him to "run Forrest, run" and he does, and one day runs into a football game, inspiring the coach to put him on the team, which makes him more popular, though at graduation he joins the military, where he fits right in, much to the bewilderment of his superior officer, Lt. Dan(played by Gary Sinise) whose life he saves, giving him a medal and inspiring him to be a Ping-Pong champion, where he meets three different U.S. Presidents, and later becomes a multi-millionaire by investing in "a fruit company" that takes off in a big way. He loves his mother(played by Sally Field) and takes her departure quite hard, running a marathon across the country for years, until he meets up with the elusive Jenny once again... Epic-scale character study is supremely well crafted and acted, remaining a funny, moving, and inspired drama about how one good man can affect the world around him, and still not know it, and remain uncorrupted by it. A truly marvelous achievement by all.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    best movie ever
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ozan HATIL
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I just recently saw this film and I gotta say, it had to be one of the best movies I've ever seen! This film has everything you could want in a film, humor, sadness, drama, action, etc. The actors were fantastic, especially Tom Hanks, who's performance is one of the best ever. Once you love this movie you can never ever forget it. it's so unique and wonderful. just a brilliant masterpiece. i'm really lucky that i watched this movie. Maybe thats why it took 6 academy awards. I re-watch it every year.:) I can just recommend it for everybody who wants to see a perfect movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Amazing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    monicaalettarollins94
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Quite simple, the greatest film ever made. This movie is simply one of the greatest movie ever made. Its a mixture of love, danger, drugs, and lot and lots of running. This movie is still going strong and it 2013. That is amazing not even any of the movies made this year is still going this strong. That is amazing that just tells you that this movie is great very bit as worthy for the Oscar. And anything else that it might get. I can't say it enough watch this movie and I bet it will make you cry. I cannot say it enough: This is THE top film of all time. Watch it you'll see.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Unforgettable Classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    coltinlillico
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Forrest Gump sums up American pop culture from the 60s to the 90s. The impossible to dislike protagonist Forrest Gump takes the film on an unforgettable journey through some of America's most famous moments. One of Tom Hanks' best performances and with a top notch director like Robert Zemeckis, it is hard to go wrong. Every single aspect of the film falls together perfectly, the supporting cast, cinematography, and especially the soundtrack give this movie everything it needs. At times, it may seem clich&eacute; and unrealistic, but its really the heart of this movie that makes you fall in love with it. Forrest Gump is a must see for everyone.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Touches One's Heart
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Angel Metayer
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I LOVED this movie. It was so cutely written. The fortune's of a man who decided to take all the steps he needed to not only run, but to run for the one he loves. Forest Gump isn't just a POV of the 'simple minded' on heir views of love, but it's also the triumph you feel for him. Despite everything, home really was were the heart is. This movie will cause you to open your heart and your mind, following Gump on his journey of determination to prove he could be a real man for Jenny. He didn't stay down when he was bullied and he didn't, as most humans selfishly do, think of only himself. I would definitely recommend this movie for families to watch, it will always be a family classic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Momma said they was my magic shoes...momma said they'd take me anywhere"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    daftpunknightvision
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    , Forrest Gump is the kind of guy that would take off his coat for a stranger if they were cold. The kind of person who forgives over and over and doesn't really want much in return besides friendship. He's not the smartest tool in the shed, but his love and compassion for the ones in his life go beyond what most normal people are capable of. Everyone knows he's basically the nerdy (but witty) underdog, and he is always teased or asked if he's stupid, to which he normally replies "stupid is as stupid does". He joins the army after he graduates college and meets his best good friend Bubba on the bus (a black man who is very similar in character to Forrest, and who immediately clicks with him). Bubba tells Forrest about the shrimping business, which has run in his family for at least 2 generations. They make a deal to form a "shrimping" team after they return home and split all the money 50-50. *SPOILER ALERT* *DO NOT KEEP SCROLLING IF YOU HAVEN'T SEEN THIS MOVIE Not very long after Bubba and Gump make their pact, Bubba gets wounded in battle, as does their Lieutenant, Dan...and a couple other characters. Dan wants Forrest to leave him to get killed in battle (by bombs) because he lost his legs and he wanted to die with honor, but Forrest picked him up despite Dan's orders, and tries to save both him and Bubba, but after Bubba is carried by Forrest (also against Dan's orders), he is gasping for air and dies in Forrest's arms. I think this is one of the most important parts of the movie, because it shows not only how humble Mr. Gump is towards his friends, but his sheer backbone and determination to do the right thing. Thank you for reading
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Forrest Gump is awesome
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Abdullah Mohammed
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For as long as i remember my brother and friend have been convincing me to watch this movie but i said i will one day. Few days ago i finally did and WOW it blew me away O_O it was such an awesome experience. I recommend this movie to everyone if you are like me waiting for almost 20 years lol :D the story of the movie is told by Forrest Gump in the famous bus stop then movie goes into flash backs as he is explaining. this is a great adventure that shouldn't be missed and you should watch the Blu-ray version because its cheap and really great. This has to be my Favorite Tom Hanks movie and i think its the movie that made him so famous. i give this movie 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Support makes the Difference
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bo Thurston
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is excellent because of its supporting characters. The movie takes place during the 1950's to 1970's, and follows the journey of a simple man living in Alabama, named Forrest Gump. The movie starts off with him describing his childhood to a complete stranger, while waiting for a bus at the bus stop, and continues to tell his story to several different strangers. When he is telling his story he reveals that he fought in Vietnam, met a few presidents, and even won the Medal of Honor. Throughout his story, Forrest has a huge impact on the people in his life, which also have the same effect on him. I like the movie Forrest Gump because the plot hooks you right from the beginning, with supporting characters that make their own unique contribution to Forrest's life. In Forrest Gump there are four supporting characters named Mama, Lieutenant Dan, Jenny, and Bubba. Each of these four supporting characters has an effect on Forrest's overall story. Mama is Forrest's mother, and is the foundation for his life. Mama is the character who raised him, taught him right from wrong, and was always able to help him by explaining the aspects of life in a unique way. For example, when Forrest asks what happened to his father, his mother says "he is on vacation" and uses this to explain that the father left them. Lieutenant Dan is the Lieutenant in charge of Forrest while he is serving in Vietnam. Lieutenant Dan is the man that inspires Forrest to be a better person, and to never leave a man behind. After Vietnam, the two of them go into the shrimping business together and make a lot of money. Initially when Forrest first meets Lieutenant Dan, Dan is very hostile. Once they go into the shrimping business together, Forrest mentions that Dan has "coming to Jesus" moment, which I think was influenced by Forrest. Jenny Curran is in my opinion the most important supporting character in the entire movie, because she is constantly Forrest's object of affection. In the beginning of the movie, they first meet on the school bus, where Forrest compares Jenny to an angel. From that point on, they become best friends and is mentioned that they are "like peas and carrots". In every significant event in Forrest's life, Forrest always mentions something about Jenny or that he misses her. They have several encounters throughout the entire movie, with one of them resulting to parenthood for Jenny and Forrest. Towards the end of the movie, Jenny reveals that she has some kind of virus but the doctors do not know what it is, and ends up asking Forrest to marry her. Forrest and Jenny get married, but unfortunately Jenny dies shortly after. This leaves Forrest to raise their son on his own. Bubba is the last supporting character, and is Forrest's other best friend, besides Jenny. Forrest meets Bubba in Vietnam, and persuades Forrest to go into the shrimping business. Overall this is a must-see movie because of its use of supporting characters to heavily influence the main character's thought process and way of life. It is more interesting to watch a movie or TV show when you care not only about the main character, but the supporting characters as well. You're more intrigued to watch the entire movie because you want to know what the resolution is for everyone, because it is fairly easy to predict the outcome for the main character a majority of the time. In conclusion, I like the movie Forrest Gump because the plot hooks you right from the beginning, with supporting characters that make their own unique contribution to Forrest's life.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Why the Hate?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sam_frank95
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Forrest Gump is a feat in cinematic history. It has set a new (high) standard for movies. So, why the hate? This movie I have seen on both most overrated and worst Best Picture Winners list. It is my favorite movie. However, on the other hand, it is also on Top Best Picture Winners lists. Forrest Gump has virtually anything you could want in a movie (besides crime). It has action (war violence), comedy, drama, romance... This list could go on and on. I'm simply saying this: this movie is fantastic, I love it, and it is a MUST-SEE for film fans (and anyone else). By the way, I cried, and I have never cried in a movie before. This movie is golden, it won six Oscars (and should have won more) and ignore the negative reviews. You don't know Forrest Gump until you've seen it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Please don't watch...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tarun Singh Surya
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Please don't watch this.... i have rated this movie a 10 but still i hate it... only because this is so damn beautiful... sometimes too much beauty creates ache in the heart... it makes you sad for once and the next moment motivated... 1994 was one of the best year for movies, Pulp fiction, The shawshank redemption and Forrest Gump... Everything about this movie is perfect... no surprise that it was awarded so heavily... sometimes i wonder why they stopped making those great movies... all we get is some sequel or prequel of action dramas... i hope to see some good movie soon in near future... Tom hanks please please, now move over to the Dan brown stuff. one of the best watch ever..
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Uplifting & Wondrous Fable.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tom Hanks plays Forrest Gump in Robert Zemekis's Academy Award winning(Best picture, director, & actor) fable about a simple and honest man who finds himself floating through life like(the ever-present) feather in the wind. He is often bullied growing up, but finds solace in his best friend Jenny, whom he comes to love dearly as they get older. She tells him to "run Forrest, run" and he does, and one day runs into a football game, inspiring the coach to put him on the team, which makes him more popular, though at graduation he joins the military, where he fits right in, much to the bewilderment of his superior officer, Lt. Dan(played by Gary Sinise) whose life he saves, giving him a medal and inspiring him to be a Ping-Pong champion, where he meets three different U.S. Presidents, and later becomes a multi-millionaire by investing in "a fruit company" that takes off in a big way. He loves his mother(played by Sally Field) and takes her departure quite hard, running a marathon across the country for years, until he meets up with the elusive Jenny once again... Epic-scale character study is supremely well crafted and acted, remaining a funny, moving, and inspired drama about how one good man can affect the world around him, and still not know it, and remain uncorrupted by it. A truly marvelous achievement by all.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    best movie ever
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ozan HATIL
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I just recently saw this film and I gotta say, it had to be one of the best movies I've ever seen! This film has everything you could want in a film, humor, sadness, drama, action, etc. The actors were fantastic, especially Tom Hanks, who's performance is one of the best ever. Once you love this movie you can never ever forget it. it's so unique and wonderful. just a brilliant masterpiece. i'm really lucky that i watched this movie. Maybe thats why it took 6 academy awards. I re-watch it every year.:) I can just recommend it for everybody who wants to see a perfect movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Amazing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    monicaalettarollins94
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Quite simple, the greatest film ever made. This movie is simply one of the greatest movie ever made. Its a mixture of love, danger, drugs, and lot and lots of running. This movie is still going strong and it 2013. That is amazing not even any of the movies made this year is still going this strong. That is amazing that just tells you that this movie is great very bit as worthy for the Oscar. And anything else that it might get. I can't say it enough watch this movie and I bet it will make you cry. I cannot say it enough: This is THE top film of all time. Watch it you'll see.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Unforgettable Classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    coltinlillico
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Forrest Gump sums up American pop culture from the 60s to the 90s. The impossible to dislike protagonist Forrest Gump takes the film on an unforgettable journey through some of America's most famous moments. One of Tom Hanks' best performances and with a top notch director like Robert Zemeckis, it is hard to go wrong. Every single aspect of the film falls together perfectly, the supporting cast, cinematography, and especially the soundtrack give this movie everything it needs. At times, it may seem clich&eacute; and unrealistic, but its really the heart of this movie that makes you fall in love with it. Forrest Gump is a must see for everyone.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Touches One's Heart
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Angel Metayer
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I LOVED this movie. It was so cutely written. The fortune's of a man who decided to take all the steps he needed to not only run, but to run for the one he loves. Forest Gump isn't just a POV of the 'simple minded' on heir views of love, but it's also the triumph you feel for him. Despite everything, home really was were the heart is. This movie will cause you to open your heart and your mind, following Gump on his journey of determination to prove he could be a real man for Jenny. He didn't stay down when he was bullied and he didn't, as most humans selfishly do, think of only himself. I would definitely recommend this movie for families to watch, it will always be a family classic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Momma said they was my magic shoes...momma said they'd take me anywhere"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    daftpunknightvision
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    , Forrest Gump is the kind of guy that would take off his coat for a stranger if they were cold. The kind of person who forgives over and over and doesn't really want much in return besides friendship. He's not the smartest tool in the shed, but his love and compassion for the ones in his life go beyond what most normal people are capable of. Everyone knows he's basically the nerdy (but witty) underdog, and he is always teased or asked if he's stupid, to which he normally replies "stupid is as stupid does". He joins the army after he graduates college and meets his best good friend Bubba on the bus (a black man who is very similar in character to Forrest, and who immediately clicks with him). Bubba tells Forrest about the shrimping business, which has run in his family for at least 2 generations. They make a deal to form a "shrimping" team after they return home and split all the money 50-50. *SPOILER ALERT* *DO NOT KEEP SCROLLING IF YOU HAVEN'T SEEN THIS MOVIE Not very long after Bubba and Gump make their pact, Bubba gets wounded in battle, as does their Lieutenant, Dan...and a couple other characters. Dan wants Forrest to leave him to get killed in battle (by bombs) because he lost his legs and he wanted to die with honor, but Forrest picked him up despite Dan's orders, and tries to save both him and Bubba, but after Bubba is carried by Forrest (also against Dan's orders), he is gasping for air and dies in Forrest's arms. I think this is one of the most important parts of the movie, because it shows not only how humble Mr. Gump is towards his friends, but his sheer backbone and determination to do the right thing. Thank you for reading
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Forrest Gump is awesome
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Abdullah Mohammed
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For as long as i remember my brother and friend have been convincing me to watch this movie but i said i will one day. Few days ago i finally did and WOW it blew me away O_O it was such an awesome experience. I recommend this movie to everyone if you are like me waiting for almost 20 years lol :D the story of the movie is told by Forrest Gump in the famous bus stop then movie goes into flash backs as he is explaining. this is a great adventure that shouldn't be missed and you should watch the Blu-ray version because its cheap and really great. This has to be my Favorite Tom Hanks movie and i think its the movie that made him so famous. i give this movie 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Support makes the Difference
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bo Thurston
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is excellent because of its supporting characters. The movie takes place during the 1950's to 1970's, and follows the journey of a simple man living in Alabama, named Forrest Gump. The movie starts off with him describing his childhood to a complete stranger, while waiting for a bus at the bus stop, and continues to tell his story to several different strangers. When he is telling his story he reveals that he fought in Vietnam, met a few presidents, and even won the Medal of Honor. Throughout his story, Forrest has a huge impact on the people in his life, which also have the same effect on him. I like the movie Forrest Gump because the plot hooks you right from the beginning, with supporting characters that make their own unique contribution to Forrest's life. In Forrest Gump there are four supporting characters named Mama, Lieutenant Dan, Jenny, and Bubba. Each of these four supporting characters has an effect on Forrest's overall story. Mama is Forrest's mother, and is the foundation for his life. Mama is the character who raised him, taught him right from wrong, and was always able to help him by explaining the aspects of life in a unique way. For example, when Forrest asks what happened to his father, his mother says "he is on vacation" and uses this to explain that the father left them. Lieutenant Dan is the Lieutenant in charge of Forrest while he is serving in Vietnam. Lieutenant Dan is the man that inspires Forrest to be a better person, and to never leave a man behind. After Vietnam, the two of them go into the shrimping business together and make a lot of money. Initially when Forrest first meets Lieutenant Dan, Dan is very hostile. Once they go into the shrimping business together, Forrest mentions that Dan has "coming to Jesus" moment, which I think was influenced by Forrest. Jenny Curran is in my opinion the most important supporting character in the entire movie, because she is constantly Forrest's object of affection. In the beginning of the movie, they first meet on the school bus, where Forrest compares Jenny to an angel. From that point on, they become best friends and is mentioned that they are "like peas and carrots". In every significant event in Forrest's life, Forrest always mentions something about Jenny or that he misses her. They have several encounters throughout the entire movie, with one of them resulting to parenthood for Jenny and Forrest. Towards the end of the movie, Jenny reveals that she has some kind of virus but the doctors do not know what it is, and ends up asking Forrest to marry her. Forrest and Jenny get married, but unfortunately Jenny dies shortly after. This leaves Forrest to raise their son on his own. Bubba is the last supporting character, and is Forrest's other best friend, besides Jenny. Forrest meets Bubba in Vietnam, and persuades Forrest to go into the shrimping business. Overall this is a must-see movie because of its use of supporting characters to heavily influence the main character's thought process and way of life. It is more interesting to watch a movie or TV show when you care not only about the main character, but the supporting characters as well. You're more intrigued to watch the entire movie because you want to know what the resolution is for everyone, because it is fairly easy to predict the outcome for the main character a majority of the time. In conclusion, I like the movie Forrest Gump because the plot hooks you right from the beginning, with supporting characters that make their own unique contribution to Forrest's life.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Why the Hate?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sam_frank95
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Forrest Gump is a feat in cinematic history. It has set a new (high) standard for movies. So, why the hate? This movie I have seen on both most overrated and worst Best Picture Winners list. It is my favorite movie. However, on the other hand, it is also on Top Best Picture Winners lists. Forrest Gump has virtually anything you could want in a movie (besides crime). It has action (war violence), comedy, drama, romance... This list could go on and on. I'm simply saying this: this movie is fantastic, I love it, and it is a MUST-SEE for film fans (and anyone else). By the way, I cried, and I have never cried in a movie before. This movie is golden, it won six Oscars (and should have won more) and ignore the negative reviews. You don't know Forrest Gump until you've seen it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Please don't watch...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tarun Singh Surya
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Please don't watch this.... i have rated this movie a 10 but still i hate it... only because this is so damn beautiful... sometimes too much beauty creates ache in the heart... it makes you sad for once and the next moment motivated... 1994 was one of the best year for movies, Pulp fiction, The shawshank redemption and Forrest Gump... Everything about this movie is perfect... no surprise that it was awarded so heavily... sometimes i wonder why they stopped making those great movies... all we get is some sequel or prequel of action dramas... i hope to see some good movie soon in near future... Tom hanks please please, now move over to the Dan brown stuff. one of the best watch ever..
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Uplifting & Wondrous Fable.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tom Hanks plays Forrest Gump in Robert Zemekis's Academy Award winning(Best picture, director, & actor) fable about a simple and honest man who finds himself floating through life like(the ever-present) feather in the wind. He is often bullied growing up, but finds solace in his best friend Jenny, whom he comes to love dearly as they get older. She tells him to "run Forrest, run" and he does, and one day runs into a football game, inspiring the coach to put him on the team, which makes him more popular, though at graduation he joins the military, where he fits right in, much to the bewilderment of his superior officer, Lt. Dan(played by Gary Sinise) whose life he saves, giving him a medal and inspiring him to be a Ping-Pong champion, where he meets three different U.S. Presidents, and later becomes a multi-millionaire by investing in "a fruit company" that takes off in a big way. He loves his mother(played by Sally Field) and takes her departure quite hard, running a marathon across the country for years, until he meets up with the elusive Jenny once again... Epic-scale character study is supremely well crafted and acted, remaining a funny, moving, and inspired drama about how one good man can affect the world around him, and still not know it, and remain uncorrupted by it. A truly marvelous achievement by all.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    best movie ever
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ozan HATIL
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I just recently saw this film and I gotta say, it had to be one of the best movies I've ever seen! This film has everything you could want in a film, humor, sadness, drama, action, etc. The actors were fantastic, especially Tom Hanks, who's performance is one of the best ever. Once you love this movie you can never ever forget it. it's so unique and wonderful. just a brilliant masterpiece. i'm really lucky that i watched this movie. Maybe thats why it took 6 academy awards. I re-watch it every year.:) I can just recommend it for everybody who wants to see a perfect movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Amazing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    monicaalettarollins94
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Quite simple, the greatest film ever made. This movie is simply one of the greatest movie ever made. Its a mixture of love, danger, drugs, and lot and lots of running. This movie is still going strong and it 2013. That is amazing not even any of the movies made this year is still going this strong. That is amazing that just tells you that this movie is great very bit as worthy for the Oscar. And anything else that it might get. I can't say it enough watch this movie and I bet it will make you cry. I cannot say it enough: This is THE top film of all time. Watch it you'll see.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Unforgettable Classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    coltinlillico
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Forrest Gump sums up American pop culture from the 60s to the 90s. The impossible to dislike protagonist Forrest Gump takes the film on an unforgettable journey through some of America's most famous moments. One of Tom Hanks' best performances and with a top notch director like Robert Zemeckis, it is hard to go wrong. Every single aspect of the film falls together perfectly, the supporting cast, cinematography, and especially the soundtrack give this movie everything it needs. At times, it may seem clich&eacute; and unrealistic, but its really the heart of this movie that makes you fall in love with it. Forrest Gump is a must see for everyone.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Touches One's Heart
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Angel Metayer
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I LOVED this movie. It was so cutely written. The fortune's of a man who decided to take all the steps he needed to not only run, but to run for the one he loves. Forest Gump isn't just a POV of the 'simple minded' on heir views of love, but it's also the triumph you feel for him. Despite everything, home really was were the heart is. This movie will cause you to open your heart and your mind, following Gump on his journey of determination to prove he could be a real man for Jenny. He didn't stay down when he was bullied and he didn't, as most humans selfishly do, think of only himself. I would definitely recommend this movie for families to watch, it will always be a family classic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Momma said they was my magic shoes...momma said they'd take me anywhere"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    daftpunknightvision
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    , Forrest Gump is the kind of guy that would take off his coat for a stranger if they were cold. The kind of person who forgives over and over and doesn't really want much in return besides friendship. He's not the smartest tool in the shed, but his love and compassion for the ones in his life go beyond what most normal people are capable of. Everyone knows he's basically the nerdy (but witty) underdog, and he is always teased or asked if he's stupid, to which he normally replies "stupid is as stupid does". He joins the army after he graduates college and meets his best good friend Bubba on the bus (a black man who is very similar in character to Forrest, and who immediately clicks with him). Bubba tells Forrest about the shrimping business, which has run in his family for at least 2 generations. They make a deal to form a "shrimping" team after they return home and split all the money 50-50. *SPOILER ALERT* *DO NOT KEEP SCROLLING IF YOU HAVEN'T SEEN THIS MOVIE Not very long after Bubba and Gump make their pact, Bubba gets wounded in battle, as does their Lieutenant, Dan...and a couple other characters. Dan wants Forrest to leave him to get killed in battle (by bombs) because he lost his legs and he wanted to die with honor, but Forrest picked him up despite Dan's orders, and tries to save both him and Bubba, but after Bubba is carried by Forrest (also against Dan's orders), he is gasping for air and dies in Forrest's arms. I think this is one of the most important parts of the movie, because it shows not only how humble Mr. Gump is towards his friends, but his sheer backbone and determination to do the right thing. Thank you for reading
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Forrest Gump is awesome
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Abdullah Mohammed
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For as long as i remember my brother and friend have been convincing me to watch this movie but i said i will one day. Few days ago i finally did and WOW it blew me away O_O it was such an awesome experience. I recommend this movie to everyone if you are like me waiting for almost 20 years lol :D the story of the movie is told by Forrest Gump in the famous bus stop then movie goes into flash backs as he is explaining. this is a great adventure that shouldn't be missed and you should watch the Blu-ray version because its cheap and really great. This has to be my Favorite Tom Hanks movie and i think its the movie that made him so famous. i give this movie 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Support makes the Difference
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bo Thurston
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is excellent because of its supporting characters. The movie takes place during the 1950's to 1970's, and follows the journey of a simple man living in Alabama, named Forrest Gump. The movie starts off with him describing his childhood to a complete stranger, while waiting for a bus at the bus stop, and continues to tell his story to several different strangers. When he is telling his story he reveals that he fought in Vietnam, met a few presidents, and even won the Medal of Honor. Throughout his story, Forrest has a huge impact on the people in his life, which also have the same effect on him. I like the movie Forrest Gump because the plot hooks you right from the beginning, with supporting characters that make their own unique contribution to Forrest's life. In Forrest Gump there are four supporting characters named Mama, Lieutenant Dan, Jenny, and Bubba. Each of these four supporting characters has an effect on Forrest's overall story. Mama is Forrest's mother, and is the foundation for his life. Mama is the character who raised him, taught him right from wrong, and was always able to help him by explaining the aspects of life in a unique way. For example, when Forrest asks what happened to his father, his mother says "he is on vacation" and uses this to explain that the father left them. Lieutenant Dan is the Lieutenant in charge of Forrest while he is serving in Vietnam. Lieutenant Dan is the man that inspires Forrest to be a better person, and to never leave a man behind. After Vietnam, the two of them go into the shrimping business together and make a lot of money. Initially when Forrest first meets Lieutenant Dan, Dan is very hostile. Once they go into the shrimping business together, Forrest mentions that Dan has "coming to Jesus" moment, which I think was influenced by Forrest. Jenny Curran is in my opinion the most important supporting character in the entire movie, because she is constantly Forrest's object of affection. In the beginning of the movie, they first meet on the school bus, where Forrest compares Jenny to an angel. From that point on, they become best friends and is mentioned that they are "like peas and carrots". In every significant event in Forrest's life, Forrest always mentions something about Jenny or that he misses her. They have several encounters throughout the entire movie, with one of them resulting to parenthood for Jenny and Forrest. Towards the end of the movie, Jenny reveals that she has some kind of virus but the doctors do not know what it is, and ends up asking Forrest to marry her. Forrest and Jenny get married, but unfortunately Jenny dies shortly after. This leaves Forrest to raise their son on his own. Bubba is the last supporting character, and is Forrest's other best friend, besides Jenny. Forrest meets Bubba in Vietnam, and persuades Forrest to go into the shrimping business. Overall this is a must-see movie because of its use of supporting characters to heavily influence the main character's thought process and way of life. It is more interesting to watch a movie or TV show when you care not only about the main character, but the supporting characters as well. You're more intrigued to watch the entire movie because you want to know what the resolution is for everyone, because it is fairly easy to predict the outcome for the main character a majority of the time. In conclusion, I like the movie Forrest Gump because the plot hooks you right from the beginning, with supporting characters that make their own unique contribution to Forrest's life.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Why the Hate?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sam_frank95
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Forrest Gump is a feat in cinematic history. It has set a new (high) standard for movies. So, why the hate? This movie I have seen on both most overrated and worst Best Picture Winners list. It is my favorite movie. However, on the other hand, it is also on Top Best Picture Winners lists. Forrest Gump has virtually anything you could want in a movie (besides crime). It has action (war violence), comedy, drama, romance... This list could go on and on. I'm simply saying this: this movie is fantastic, I love it, and it is a MUST-SEE for film fans (and anyone else). By the way, I cried, and I have never cried in a movie before. This movie is golden, it won six Oscars (and should have won more) and ignore the negative reviews. You don't know Forrest Gump until you've seen it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Please don't watch...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tarun Singh Surya
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Please don't watch this.... i have rated this movie a 10 but still i hate it... only because this is so damn beautiful... sometimes too much beauty creates ache in the heart... it makes you sad for once and the next moment motivated... 1994 was one of the best year for movies, Pulp fiction, The shawshank redemption and Forrest Gump... Everything about this movie is perfect... no surprise that it was awarded so heavily... sometimes i wonder why they stopped making those great movies... all we get is some sequel or prequel of action dramas... i hope to see some good movie soon in near future... Tom hanks please please, now move over to the Dan brown stuff. one of the best watch ever..
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Uplifting & Wondrous Fable.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tom Hanks plays Forrest Gump in Robert Zemekis's Academy Award winning(Best picture, director, & actor) fable about a simple and honest man who finds himself floating through life like(the ever-present) feather in the wind. He is often bullied growing up, but finds solace in his best friend Jenny, whom he comes to love dearly as they get older. She tells him to "run Forrest, run" and he does, and one day runs into a football game, inspiring the coach to put him on the team, which makes him more popular, though at graduation he joins the military, where he fits right in, much to the bewilderment of his superior officer, Lt. Dan(played by Gary Sinise) whose life he saves, giving him a medal and inspiring him to be a Ping-Pong champion, where he meets three different U.S. Presidents, and later becomes a multi-millionaire by investing in "a fruit company" that takes off in a big way. He loves his mother(played by Sally Field) and takes her departure quite hard, running a marathon across the country for years, until he meets up with the elusive Jenny once again... Epic-scale character study is supremely well crafted and acted, remaining a funny, moving, and inspired drama about how one good man can affect the world around him, and still not know it, and remain uncorrupted by it. A truly marvelous achievement by all.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    best movie ever
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ozan HATIL
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I just recently saw this film and I gotta say, it had to be one of the best movies I've ever seen! This film has everything you could want in a film, humor, sadness, drama, action, etc. The actors were fantastic, especially Tom Hanks, who's performance is one of the best ever. Once you love this movie you can never ever forget it. it's so unique and wonderful. just a brilliant masterpiece. i'm really lucky that i watched this movie. Maybe thats why it took 6 academy awards. I re-watch it every year.:) I can just recommend it for everybody who wants to see a perfect movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Amazing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    monicaalettarollins94
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Quite simple, the greatest film ever made. This movie is simply one of the greatest movie ever made. Its a mixture of love, danger, drugs, and lot and lots of running. This movie is still going strong and it 2013. That is amazing not even any of the movies made this year is still going this strong. That is amazing that just tells you that this movie is great very bit as worthy for the Oscar. And anything else that it might get. I can't say it enough watch this movie and I bet it will make you cry. I cannot say it enough: This is THE top film of all time. Watch it you'll see.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Unforgettable Classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    coltinlillico
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Forrest Gump sums up American pop culture from the 60s to the 90s. The impossible to dislike protagonist Forrest Gump takes the film on an unforgettable journey through some of America's most famous moments. One of Tom Hanks' best performances and with a top notch director like Robert Zemeckis, it is hard to go wrong. Every single aspect of the film falls together perfectly, the supporting cast, cinematography, and especially the soundtrack give this movie everything it needs. At times, it may seem clich&eacute; and unrealistic, but its really the heart of this movie that makes you fall in love with it. Forrest Gump is a must see for everyone.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Touches One's Heart
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Angel Metayer
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I LOVED this movie. It was so cutely written. The fortune's of a man who decided to take all the steps he needed to not only run, but to run for the one he loves. Forest Gump isn't just a POV of the 'simple minded' on heir views of love, but it's also the triumph you feel for him. Despite everything, home really was were the heart is. This movie will cause you to open your heart and your mind, following Gump on his journey of determination to prove he could be a real man for Jenny. He didn't stay down when he was bullied and he didn't, as most humans selfishly do, think of only himself. I would definitely recommend this movie for families to watch, it will always be a family classic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Momma said they was my magic shoes...momma said they'd take me anywhere"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    daftpunknightvision
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    , Forrest Gump is the kind of guy that would take off his coat for a stranger if they were cold. The kind of person who forgives over and over and doesn't really want much in return besides friendship. He's not the smartest tool in the shed, but his love and compassion for the ones in his life go beyond what most normal people are capable of. Everyone knows he's basically the nerdy (but witty) underdog, and he is always teased or asked if he's stupid, to which he normally replies "stupid is as stupid does". He joins the army after he graduates college and meets his best good friend Bubba on the bus (a black man who is very similar in character to Forrest, and who immediately clicks with him). Bubba tells Forrest about the shrimping business, which has run in his family for at least 2 generations. They make a deal to form a "shrimping" team after they return home and split all the money 50-50. *SPOILER ALERT* *DO NOT KEEP SCROLLING IF YOU HAVEN'T SEEN THIS MOVIE Not very long after Bubba and Gump make their pact, Bubba gets wounded in battle, as does their Lieutenant, Dan...and a couple other characters. Dan wants Forrest to leave him to get killed in battle (by bombs) because he lost his legs and he wanted to die with honor, but Forrest picked him up despite Dan's orders, and tries to save both him and Bubba, but after Bubba is carried by Forrest (also against Dan's orders), he is gasping for air and dies in Forrest's arms. I think this is one of the most important parts of the movie, because it shows not only how humble Mr. Gump is towards his friends, but his sheer backbone and determination to do the right thing. Thank you for reading
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Forrest Gump is awesome
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Abdullah Mohammed
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For as long as i remember my brother and friend have been convincing me to watch this movie but i said i will one day. Few days ago i finally did and WOW it blew me away O_O it was such an awesome experience. I recommend this movie to everyone if you are like me waiting for almost 20 years lol :D the story of the movie is told by Forrest Gump in the famous bus stop then movie goes into flash backs as he is explaining. this is a great adventure that shouldn't be missed and you should watch the Blu-ray version because its cheap and really great. This has to be my Favorite Tom Hanks movie and i think its the movie that made him so famous. i give this movie 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Support makes the Difference
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bo Thurston
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is excellent because of its supporting characters. The movie takes place during the 1950's to 1970's, and follows the journey of a simple man living in Alabama, named Forrest Gump. The movie starts off with him describing his childhood to a complete stranger, while waiting for a bus at the bus stop, and continues to tell his story to several different strangers. When he is telling his story he reveals that he fought in Vietnam, met a few presidents, and even won the Medal of Honor. Throughout his story, Forrest has a huge impact on the people in his life, which also have the same effect on him. I like the movie Forrest Gump because the plot hooks you right from the beginning, with supporting characters that make their own unique contribution to Forrest's life. In Forrest Gump there are four supporting characters named Mama, Lieutenant Dan, Jenny, and Bubba. Each of these four supporting characters has an effect on Forrest's overall story. Mama is Forrest's mother, and is the foundation for his life. Mama is the character who raised him, taught him right from wrong, and was always able to help him by explaining the aspects of life in a unique way. For example, when Forrest asks what happened to his father, his mother says "he is on vacation" and uses this to explain that the father left them. Lieutenant Dan is the Lieutenant in charge of Forrest while he is serving in Vietnam. Lieutenant Dan is the man that inspires Forrest to be a better person, and to never leave a man behind. After Vietnam, the two of them go into the shrimping business together and make a lot of money. Initially when Forrest first meets Lieutenant Dan, Dan is very hostile. Once they go into the shrimping business together, Forrest mentions that Dan has "coming to Jesus" moment, which I think was influenced by Forrest. Jenny Curran is in my opinion the most important supporting character in the entire movie, because she is constantly Forrest's object of affection. In the beginning of the movie, they first meet on the school bus, where Forrest compares Jenny to an angel. From that point on, they become best friends and is mentioned that they are "like peas and carrots". In every significant event in Forrest's life, Forrest always mentions something about Jenny or that he misses her. They have several encounters throughout the entire movie, with one of them resulting to parenthood for Jenny and Forrest. Towards the end of the movie, Jenny reveals that she has some kind of virus but the doctors do not know what it is, and ends up asking Forrest to marry her. Forrest and Jenny get married, but unfortunately Jenny dies shortly after. This leaves Forrest to raise their son on his own. Bubba is the last supporting character, and is Forrest's other best friend, besides Jenny. Forrest meets Bubba in Vietnam, and persuades Forrest to go into the shrimping business. Overall this is a must-see movie because of its use of supporting characters to heavily influence the main character's thought process and way of life. It is more interesting to watch a movie or TV show when you care not only about the main character, but the supporting characters as well. You're more intrigued to watch the entire movie because you want to know what the resolution is for everyone, because it is fairly easy to predict the outcome for the main character a majority of the time. In conclusion, I like the movie Forrest Gump because the plot hooks you right from the beginning, with supporting characters that make their own unique contribution to Forrest's life.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Why the Hate?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sam_frank95
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Forrest Gump is a feat in cinematic history. It has set a new (high) standard for movies. So, why the hate? This movie I have seen on both most overrated and worst Best Picture Winners list. It is my favorite movie. However, on the other hand, it is also on Top Best Picture Winners lists. Forrest Gump has virtually anything you could want in a movie (besides crime). It has action (war violence), comedy, drama, romance... This list could go on and on. I'm simply saying this: this movie is fantastic, I love it, and it is a MUST-SEE for film fans (and anyone else). By the way, I cried, and I have never cried in a movie before. This movie is golden, it won six Oscars (and should have won more) and ignore the negative reviews. You don't know Forrest Gump until you've seen it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Please don't watch...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tarun Singh Surya
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Please don't watch this.... i have rated this movie a 10 but still i hate it... only because this is so damn beautiful... sometimes too much beauty creates ache in the heart... it makes you sad for once and the next moment motivated... 1994 was one of the best year for movies, Pulp fiction, The shawshank redemption and Forrest Gump... Everything about this movie is perfect... no surprise that it was awarded so heavily... sometimes i wonder why they stopped making those great movies... all we get is some sequel or prequel of action dramas... i hope to see some good movie soon in near future... Tom hanks please please, now move over to the Dan brown stuff. one of the best watch ever..
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Uplifting & Wondrous Fable.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tom Hanks plays Forrest Gump in Robert Zemekis's Academy Award winning(Best picture, director, & actor) fable about a simple and honest man who finds himself floating through life like(the ever-present) feather in the wind. He is often bullied growing up, but finds solace in his best friend Jenny, whom he comes to love dearly as they get older. She tells him to "run Forrest, run" and he does, and one day runs into a football game, inspiring the coach to put him on the team, which makes him more popular, though at graduation he joins the military, where he fits right in, much to the bewilderment of his superior officer, Lt. Dan(played by Gary Sinise) whose life he saves, giving him a medal and inspiring him to be a Ping-Pong champion, where he meets three different U.S. Presidents, and later becomes a multi-millionaire by investing in "a fruit company" that takes off in a big way. He loves his mother(played by Sally Field) and takes her departure quite hard, running a marathon across the country for years, until he meets up with the elusive Jenny once again... Epic-scale character study is supremely well crafted and acted, remaining a funny, moving, and inspired drama about how one good man can affect the world around him, and still not know it, and remain uncorrupted by it. A truly marvelous achievement by all.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    best movie ever
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ozan HATIL
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I just recently saw this film and I gotta say, it had to be one of the best movies I've ever seen! This film has everything you could want in a film, humor, sadness, drama, action, etc. The actors were fantastic, especially Tom Hanks, who's performance is one of the best ever. Once you love this movie you can never ever forget it. it's so unique and wonderful. just a brilliant masterpiece. i'm really lucky that i watched this movie. Maybe thats why it took 6 academy awards. I re-watch it every year.:) I can just recommend it for everybody who wants to see a perfect movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Amazing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    monicaalettarollins94
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Quite simple, the greatest film ever made. This movie is simply one of the greatest movie ever made. Its a mixture of love, danger, drugs, and lot and lots of running. This movie is still going strong and it 2013. That is amazing not even any of the movies made this year is still going this strong. That is amazing that just tells you that this movie is great very bit as worthy for the Oscar. And anything else that it might get. I can't say it enough watch this movie and I bet it will make you cry. I cannot say it enough: This is THE top film of all time. Watch it you'll see.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Unforgettable Classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    coltinlillico
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Forrest Gump sums up American pop culture from the 60s to the 90s. The impossible to dislike protagonist Forrest Gump takes the film on an unforgettable journey through some of America's most famous moments. One of Tom Hanks' best performances and with a top notch director like Robert Zemeckis, it is hard to go wrong. Every single aspect of the film falls together perfectly, the supporting cast, cinematography, and especially the soundtrack give this movie everything it needs. At times, it may seem clich&eacute; and unrealistic, but its really the heart of this movie that makes you fall in love with it. Forrest Gump is a must see for everyone.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Touches One's Heart
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Angel Metayer
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I LOVED this movie. It was so cutely written. The fortune's of a man who decided to take all the steps he needed to not only run, but to run for the one he loves. Forest Gump isn't just a POV of the 'simple minded' on heir views of love, but it's also the triumph you feel for him. Despite everything, home really was were the heart is. This movie will cause you to open your heart and your mind, following Gump on his journey of determination to prove he could be a real man for Jenny. He didn't stay down when he was bullied and he didn't, as most humans selfishly do, think of only himself. I would definitely recommend this movie for families to watch, it will always be a family classic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Momma said they was my magic shoes...momma said they'd take me anywhere"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    daftpunknightvision
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    , Forrest Gump is the kind of guy that would take off his coat for a stranger if they were cold. The kind of person who forgives over and over and doesn't really want much in return besides friendship. He's not the smartest tool in the shed, but his love and compassion for the ones in his life go beyond what most normal people are capable of. Everyone knows he's basically the nerdy (but witty) underdog, and he is always teased or asked if he's stupid, to which he normally replies "stupid is as stupid does". He joins the army after he graduates college and meets his best good friend Bubba on the bus (a black man who is very similar in character to Forrest, and who immediately clicks with him). Bubba tells Forrest about the shrimping business, which has run in his family for at least 2 generations. They make a deal to form a "shrimping" team after they return home and split all the money 50-50. *SPOILER ALERT* *DO NOT KEEP SCROLLING IF YOU HAVEN'T SEEN THIS MOVIE Not very long after Bubba and Gump make their pact, Bubba gets wounded in battle, as does their Lieutenant, Dan...and a couple other characters. Dan wants Forrest to leave him to get killed in battle (by bombs) because he lost his legs and he wanted to die with honor, but Forrest picked him up despite Dan's orders, and tries to save both him and Bubba, but after Bubba is carried by Forrest (also against Dan's orders), he is gasping for air and dies in Forrest's arms. I think this is one of the most important parts of the movie, because it shows not only how humble Mr. Gump is towards his friends, but his sheer backbone and determination to do the right thing. Thank you for reading
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Forrest Gump is awesome
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Abdullah Mohammed
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For as long as i remember my brother and friend have been convincing me to watch this movie but i said i will one day. Few days ago i finally did and WOW it blew me away O_O it was such an awesome experience. I recommend this movie to everyone if you are like me waiting for almost 20 years lol :D the story of the movie is told by Forrest Gump in the famous bus stop then movie goes into flash backs as he is explaining. this is a great adventure that shouldn't be missed and you should watch the Blu-ray version because its cheap and really great. This has to be my Favorite Tom Hanks movie and i think its the movie that made him so famous. i give this movie 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Support makes the Difference
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bo Thurston
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is excellent because of its supporting characters. The movie takes place during the 1950's to 1970's, and follows the journey of a simple man living in Alabama, named Forrest Gump. The movie starts off with him describing his childhood to a complete stranger, while waiting for a bus at the bus stop, and continues to tell his story to several different strangers. When he is telling his story he reveals that he fought in Vietnam, met a few presidents, and even won the Medal of Honor. Throughout his story, Forrest has a huge impact on the people in his life, which also have the same effect on him. I like the movie Forrest Gump because the plot hooks you right from the beginning, with supporting characters that make their own unique contribution to Forrest's life. In Forrest Gump there are four supporting characters named Mama, Lieutenant Dan, Jenny, and Bubba. Each of these four supporting characters has an effect on Forrest's overall story. Mama is Forrest's mother, and is the foundation for his life. Mama is the character who raised him, taught him right from wrong, and was always able to help him by explaining the aspects of life in a unique way. For example, when Forrest asks what happened to his father, his mother says "he is on vacation" and uses this to explain that the father left them. Lieutenant Dan is the Lieutenant in charge of Forrest while he is serving in Vietnam. Lieutenant Dan is the man that inspires Forrest to be a better person, and to never leave a man behind. After Vietnam, the two of them go into the shrimping business together and make a lot of money. Initially when Forrest first meets Lieutenant Dan, Dan is very hostile. Once they go into the shrimping business together, Forrest mentions that Dan has "coming to Jesus" moment, which I think was influenced by Forrest. Jenny Curran is in my opinion the most important supporting character in the entire movie, because she is constantly Forrest's object of affection. In the beginning of the movie, they first meet on the school bus, where Forrest compares Jenny to an angel. From that point on, they become best friends and is mentioned that they are "like peas and carrots". In every significant event in Forrest's life, Forrest always mentions something about Jenny or that he misses her. They have several encounters throughout the entire movie, with one of them resulting to parenthood for Jenny and Forrest. Towards the end of the movie, Jenny reveals that she has some kind of virus but the doctors do not know what it is, and ends up asking Forrest to marry her. Forrest and Jenny get married, but unfortunately Jenny dies shortly after. This leaves Forrest to raise their son on his own. Bubba is the last supporting character, and is Forrest's other best friend, besides Jenny. Forrest meets Bubba in Vietnam, and persuades Forrest to go into the shrimping business. Overall this is a must-see movie because of its use of supporting characters to heavily influence the main character's thought process and way of life. It is more interesting to watch a movie or TV show when you care not only about the main character, but the supporting characters as well. You're more intrigued to watch the entire movie because you want to know what the resolution is for everyone, because it is fairly easy to predict the outcome for the main character a majority of the time. In conclusion, I like the movie Forrest Gump because the plot hooks you right from the beginning, with supporting characters that make their own unique contribution to Forrest's life.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Why the Hate?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sam_frank95
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Forrest Gump is a feat in cinematic history. It has set a new (high) standard for movies. So, why the hate? This movie I have seen on both most overrated and worst Best Picture Winners list. It is my favorite movie. However, on the other hand, it is also on Top Best Picture Winners lists. Forrest Gump has virtually anything you could want in a movie (besides crime). It has action (war violence), comedy, drama, romance... This list could go on and on. I'm simply saying this: this movie is fantastic, I love it, and it is a MUST-SEE for film fans (and anyone else). By the way, I cried, and I have never cried in a movie before. This movie is golden, it won six Oscars (and should have won more) and ignore the negative reviews. You don't know Forrest Gump until you've seen it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Please don't watch...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tarun Singh Surya
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Please don't watch this.... i have rated this movie a 10 but still i hate it... only because this is so damn beautiful... sometimes too much beauty creates ache in the heart... it makes you sad for once and the next moment motivated... 1994 was one of the best year for movies, Pulp fiction, The shawshank redemption and Forrest Gump... Everything about this movie is perfect... no surprise that it was awarded so heavily... sometimes i wonder why they stopped making those great movies... all we get is some sequel or prequel of action dramas... i hope to see some good movie soon in near future... Tom hanks please please, now move over to the Dan brown stuff. one of the best watch ever..
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Uplifting & Wondrous Fable.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tom Hanks plays Forrest Gump in Robert Zemekis's Academy Award winning(Best picture, director, & actor) fable about a simple and honest man who finds himself floating through life like(the ever-present) feather in the wind. He is often bullied growing up, but finds solace in his best friend Jenny, whom he comes to love dearly as they get older. She tells him to "run Forrest, run" and he does, and one day runs into a football game, inspiring the coach to put him on the team, which makes him more popular, though at graduation he joins the military, where he fits right in, much to the bewilderment of his superior officer, Lt. Dan(played by Gary Sinise) whose life he saves, giving him a medal and inspiring him to be a Ping-Pong champion, where he meets three different U.S. Presidents, and later becomes a multi-millionaire by investing in "a fruit company" that takes off in a big way. He loves his mother(played by Sally Field) and takes her departure quite hard, running a marathon across the country for years, until he meets up with the elusive Jenny once again... Epic-scale character study is supremely well crafted and acted, remaining a funny, moving, and inspired drama about how one good man can affect the world around him, and still not know it, and remain uncorrupted by it. A truly marvelous achievement by all.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    best movie ever
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ozan HATIL
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I just recently saw this film and I gotta say, it had to be one of the best movies I've ever seen! This film has everything you could want in a film, humor, sadness, drama, action, etc. The actors were fantastic, especially Tom Hanks, who's performance is one of the best ever. Once you love this movie you can never ever forget it. it's so unique and wonderful. just a brilliant masterpiece. i'm really lucky that i watched this movie. Maybe thats why it took 6 academy awards. I re-watch it every year.:) I can just recommend it for everybody who wants to see a perfect movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Amazing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    monicaalettarollins94
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Quite simple, the greatest film ever made. This movie is simply one of the greatest movie ever made. Its a mixture of love, danger, drugs, and lot and lots of running. This movie is still going strong and it 2013. That is amazing not even any of the movies made this year is still going this strong. That is amazing that just tells you that this movie is great very bit as worthy for the Oscar. And anything else that it might get. I can't say it enough watch this movie and I bet it will make you cry. I cannot say it enough: This is THE top film of all time. Watch it you'll see.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Unforgettable Classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    coltinlillico
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Forrest Gump sums up American pop culture from the 60s to the 90s. The impossible to dislike protagonist Forrest Gump takes the film on an unforgettable journey through some of America's most famous moments. One of Tom Hanks' best performances and with a top notch director like Robert Zemeckis, it is hard to go wrong. Every single aspect of the film falls together perfectly, the supporting cast, cinematography, and especially the soundtrack give this movie everything it needs. At times, it may seem clich&eacute; and unrealistic, but its really the heart of this movie that makes you fall in love with it. Forrest Gump is a must see for everyone.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Touches One's Heart
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Angel Metayer
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I LOVED this movie. It was so cutely written. The fortune's of a man who decided to take all the steps he needed to not only run, but to run for the one he loves. Forest Gump isn't just a POV of the 'simple minded' on heir views of love, but it's also the triumph you feel for him. Despite everything, home really was were the heart is. This movie will cause you to open your heart and your mind, following Gump on his journey of determination to prove he could be a real man for Jenny. He didn't stay down when he was bullied and he didn't, as most humans selfishly do, think of only himself. I would definitely recommend this movie for families to watch, it will always be a family classic.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Momma said they was my magic shoes...momma said they'd take me anywhere"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    daftpunknightvision
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    , Forrest Gump is the kind of guy that would take off his coat for a stranger if they were cold. The kind of person who forgives over and over and doesn't really want much in return besides friendship. He's not the smartest tool in the shed, but his love and compassion for the ones in his life go beyond what most normal people are capable of. Everyone knows he's basically the nerdy (but witty) underdog, and he is always teased or asked if he's stupid, to which he normally replies "stupid is as stupid does". He joins the army after he graduates college and meets his best good friend Bubba on the bus (a black man who is very similar in character to Forrest, and who immediately clicks with him). Bubba tells Forrest about the shrimping business, which has run in his family for at least 2 generations. They make a deal to form a "shrimping" team after they return home and split all the money 50-50. *SPOILER ALERT* *DO NOT KEEP SCROLLING IF YOU HAVEN'T SEEN THIS MOVIE Not very long after Bubba and Gump make their pact, Bubba gets wounded in battle, as does their Lieutenant, Dan...and a couple other characters. Dan wants Forrest to leave him to get killed in battle (by bombs) because he lost his legs and he wanted to die with honor, but Forrest picked him up despite Dan's orders, and tries to save both him and Bubba, but after Bubba is carried by Forrest (also against Dan's orders), he is gasping for air and dies in Forrest's arms. I think this is one of the most important parts of the movie, because it shows not only how humble Mr. Gump is towards his friends, but his sheer backbone and determination to do the right thing. Thank you for reading
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Forrest Gump is awesome
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Abdullah Mohammed
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For as long as i remember my brother and friend have been convincing me to watch this movie but i said i will one day. Few days ago i finally did and WOW it blew me away O_O it was such an awesome experience. I recommend this movie to everyone if you are like me waiting for almost 20 years lol :D the story of the movie is told by Forrest Gump in the famous bus stop then movie goes into flash backs as he is explaining. this is a great adventure that shouldn't be missed and you should watch the Blu-ray version because its cheap and really great. This has to be my Favorite Tom Hanks movie and i think its the movie that made him so famous. i give this movie 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Support makes the Difference
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bo Thurston
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is excellent because of its supporting characters. The movie takes place during the 1950's to 1970's, and follows the journey of a simple man living in Alabama, named Forrest Gump. The movie starts off with him describing his childhood to a complete stranger, while waiting for a bus at the bus stop, and continues to tell his story to several different strangers. When he is telling his story he reveals that he fought in Vietnam, met a few presidents, and even won the Medal of Honor. Throughout his story, Forrest has a huge impact on the people in his life, which also have the same effect on him. I like the movie Forrest Gump because the plot hooks you right from the beginning, with supporting characters that make their own unique contribution to Forrest's life. In Forrest Gump there are four supporting characters named Mama, Lieutenant Dan, Jenny, and Bubba. Each of these four supporting characters has an effect on Forrest's overall story. Mama is Forrest's mother, and is the foundation for his life. Mama is the character who raised him, taught him right from wrong, and was always able to help him by explaining the aspects of life in a unique way. For example, when Forrest asks what happened to his father, his mother says "he is on vacation" and uses this to explain that the father left them. Lieutenant Dan is the Lieutenant in charge of Forrest while he is serving in Vietnam. Lieutenant Dan is the man that inspires Forrest to be a better person, and to never leave a man behind. After Vietnam, the two of them go into the shrimping business together and make a lot of money. Initially when Forrest first meets Lieutenant Dan, Dan is very hostile. Once they go into the shrimping business together, Forrest mentions that Dan has "coming to Jesus" moment, which I think was influenced by Forrest. Jenny Curran is in my opinion the most important supporting character in the entire movie, because she is constantly Forrest's object of affection. In the beginning of the movie, they first meet on the school bus, where Forrest compares Jenny to an angel. From that point on, they become best friends and is mentioned that they are "like peas and carrots". In every significant event in Forrest's life, Forrest always mentions something about Jenny or that he misses her. They have several encounters throughout the entire movie, with one of them resulting to parenthood for Jenny and Forrest. Towards the end of the movie, Jenny reveals that she has some kind of virus but the doctors do not know what it is, and ends up asking Forrest to marry her. Forrest and Jenny get married, but unfortunately Jenny dies shortly after. This leaves Forrest to raise their son on his own. Bubba is the last supporting character, and is Forrest's other best friend, besides Jenny. Forrest meets Bubba in Vietnam, and persuades Forrest to go into the shrimping business. Overall this is a must-see movie because of its use of supporting characters to heavily influence the main character's thought process and way of life. It is more interesting to watch a movie or TV show when you care not only about the main character, but the supporting characters as well. You're more intrigued to watch the entire movie because you want to know what the resolution is for everyone, because it is fairly easy to predict the outcome for the main character a majority of the time. In conclusion, I like the movie Forrest Gump because the plot hooks you right from the beginning, with supporting characters that make their own unique contribution to Forrest's life.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Why the Hate?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sam_frank95
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Forrest Gump is a feat in cinematic history. It has set a new (high) standard for movies. So, why the hate? This movie I have seen on both most overrated and worst Best Picture Winners list. It is my favorite movie. However, on the other hand, it is also on Top Best Picture Winners lists. Forrest Gump has virtually anything you could want in a movie (besides crime). It has action (war violence), comedy, drama, romance... This list could go on and on. I'm simply saying this: this movie is fantastic, I love it, and it is a MUST-SEE for film fans (and anyone else). By the way, I cried, and I have never cried in a movie before. This movie is golden, it won six Oscars (and should have won more) and ignore the negative reviews. You don't know Forrest Gump until you've seen it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Please don't watch...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Tarun Singh Surya
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Please don't watch this.... i have rated this movie a 10 but still i hate it... only because this is so damn beautiful... sometimes too much beauty creates ache in the heart... it makes you sad for once and the next moment motivated... 1994 was one of the best year for movies, Pulp fiction, The shawshank redemption and Forrest Gump... Everything about this movie is perfect... no surprise that it was awarded so heavily... sometimes i wonder why they stopped making those great movies... all we get is some sequel or prequel of action dramas... i hope to see some good movie soon in near future... Tom hanks please please, now move over to the Dan brown stuff. one of the best watch ever..
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Uplifting & Wondrous Fable.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tom Hanks plays Forrest Gump in Robert Zemekis's Academy Award winning(Best picture, director, & actor) fable about a simple and honest man who finds himself floating through life like(the ever-present) feather in the wind. He is often bullied growing up, but finds solace in his best friend Jenny, whom he comes to love dearly as they get older. She tells him to "run Forrest, run" and he does, and one day runs into a football game, inspiring the coach to put him on the team, which makes him more popular, though at graduation he joins the military, where he fits right in, much to the bewilderment of his superior officer, Lt. Dan(played by Gary Sinise) whose life he saves, giving him a medal and inspiring him to be a Ping-Pong champion, where he meets three different U.S. Presidents, and later becomes a multi-millionaire by investing in "a fruit company" that takes off in a big way. He loves his mother(played by Sally Field) and takes her departure quite hard, running a marathon across the country for years, until he meets up with the elusive Jenny once again... Epic-scale character study is supremely well crafted and acted, remaining a funny, moving, and inspired drama about how one good man can affect the world around him, and still not know it, and remain uncorrupted by it. A truly marvelous achievement by all.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    best movie ever
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ozan HATIL
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I just recently saw this film and I gotta say, it had to be one of the best movies I've ever seen! This film has everything you could want in a film, humor, sadness, drama, action, etc. The actors were fantastic, especially Tom Hanks, who's performance is one of the best ever. Once you love this movie you can never ever forget it. it's so unique and wonderful. just a brilliant masterpiece. i'm really lucky that i watched this movie. Maybe thats why it took 6 academy awards. I re-watch it every year.:) I can just recommend it for everybody who wants to see a perfect movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
