<filme>
 <id>
  691
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0118929
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1998
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Cidade das Sombras
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  7.7
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  A man struggles with memories of his past, including a wife he cannot remember, in a nightmarish world with no sun and run by beings with telekinetic powers who seek the souls of humans.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  John Murdoch awakens alone in a strange hotel to find that he has lost his memory and is wanted for a series of brutal and bizarre murders. While trying to piece together his past, he stumbles upon a fiendish underworld controlled by a group of beings known as The Strangers who possess the ability to put people to sleep and alter the city and its inhabitants. Now Murdoch must find a way to stop them before they take control of his mind and destroy him.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Mystery
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Sci-Fi
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   memory
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   murder
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   hotel
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   soul
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   sleep
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Alex Proyas
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Alex Proyas
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Lem Dobbs
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Rufus Sewell
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Kiefer Sutherland
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Jennifer Connelly
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I am missing something here
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    shankh-sarkar
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Whenever in doubt, I have always treated IMDb's rating as a benchmark before deciding if it was worth my while watching a particular movie . If it's above 7.5 , its on. So despite my initial doubts while skimming through the movie on vlc, I decided to watch it solely because it was rated 7.7. And here's what I realized; that I wanted the last couple of hours of my life back. The plot of the movie failed to account for the crucial element of suspension of disbelief. At no point could I convince myself that what was playing on the screen was even remotely feasible. The old philosophical adage, "Nothing comes from nothing" kept repeating itself in my head as the characters played out their superhuman capabilities. Comparisons with "The Matrix" are inevitable because of the similar theme of their being a chosen one but The Matrix beats The Dark City hands down because of its superior graphics, tight knit plot and superb storytelling. I ain't gonna bother raising my doubts because there are far too many of them and none of them can be answered satisfactorily even after accounting for cinematic liberty. So for those of you that dig the movie, I really am missing something here and glad for it too.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Finding our humanity
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    hall895
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dark City begins with an opening voice-over narration which basically gives the whole plot away. Fans of the film hated this and in a later cut of the film the narration was removed. It does seem logical that a movie which has so many mysterious elements shouldn't reveal all its secrets in the first thirty seconds. But in this case the narration probably served the film well. Because what is going on in this film is very weird, exceedingly bizarre and not particularly easy to comprehend unless you have some solid base of initial knowledge to fall back on. And there are still enough twists, turns and impactful surprises to make the film very compelling. Giving the audience a little help at the beginning paid off. Otherwise by the time the film finally fully revealed itself many people may have been too lost, too confused, too frustrated to appreciate what they had seen. And there is so much to appreciate. It also must be said that having the story laid out in such detail early on allows the audience to accept that story much easier. It is a story which requires tremendous leaps of faith. Without sufficient grounding the story may ultimately have proved to be just too strange for many people to take. Even with so many of its secrets given away right at the start the story still manages to grab you. A man wakes up in a bathtub. He can't seem to remember anything. His forehead is bleeding. There's a dead woman on the floor. And then the phone rings, someone tells him he needs to run away now because they are coming to get him. Who are "they"? Who knows? Anyway, the man flees and the movie kicks into high gear very quickly. The man is John Murdoch. Or is he? It becomes clear very quickly that nothing in this city is exactly what it seems. John Murdoch is not the only person here with vanished memories. He doesn't really know who he is. Nobody does. But nobody besides John realizes anything is amiss. It is up to him to unravel the mystery. What he discovers will shock both him and us. The film packs quite a dramatic punch and raises serious questions about humanity. What makes us human? This film's mysterious Strangers need to know the answer to that question. It is the Strangers who drive the plot. They can manipulate the physical environment of the city, creating new buildings and changing the form of existing ones in mere moments with just the power of their minds. And yet none of the humans ever notice anything has changed. And it is not just the buildings the Strangers change, they have a rather insidious, invasive way of changing the people themselves. Then the Strangers sit back and see what happens. The humans, unknowingly, are their lab rats. John however is resistant to the efforts of the Strangers. Not only that he apparently shares their powers. With the help of a police detective he sets out to find the truth and to give the citizens of the city back their humanity, give them back a sense of who they really are. Rufus Sewell does very well with the challenging role of John Murdoch, a man who does not know who he is. Sewell captures the original bewilderment well and then grows with the character as John finds the strength and determination to put an end to whatever is going on here. William Hurt plays the detective who ends up assisting John, Jennifer Connelly plays John's wife. They both end up very confused and Hurt and Connelly give very good performances as their characters try to figure out what the heck is going on here. Richard O'Brien is appropriately creepy playing the film's most prominent Stranger. Perhaps the only misstep comes from Kiefer Sutherland playing a doctor mixed up in the activities of the Strangers. Sutherland plays the role with a stammer which becomes distracting and annoying very quickly. It's a little bit of weirdness the film didn't need, it adds nothing to the character and the film's plenty weird enough already. But that quibble aside the film generally works very well. It is a fascinating, intriguing, thought-provoking story. Visually the film looks spectacular with wonderful set design and brilliantly executed effects. Perhaps the film goes a little overboard with the effects near the end. The story gets somewhat left behind as things wrap up with a big visual effects blowout. You can't help but think this very smart film deserved a little bit smarter of an ending. But the film ultimately is more than satisfying enough. It entertains you and it also makes you think which is always a good combination. Dark City's story is a very complex web to weave your way through, having had a little guidance at the start surely couldn't have hurt. And when you get to the end you'll look back and be grateful for the long, strange, fascinating trip the film took you on.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I don't get the fuss
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Fluke_Skywalker
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For most of its running time it sort of plays like an extended 'Twilight Zone' episode, and It hooked me well enough. I wanted to know what was happening and why... for a while, at least. Then I just got bored. When the pieces of the puzzle finally do come together, it's quite a let down. And then, after 90 minutes of dull neo-noir mystery, it turned on a dime with a tonally incongruous smack-down finale that did little to re-ignite my interest. There's some nifty stuff in there, and I can see its influence on more recentand much betterwork, but I just can't see what all the hubbub is about with 'Dark City'.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Welcome To Shell Beach.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dark City D/C Dark City is directed by Alex Proyas who also co-writes the screenplay with Leon Dobbs and David S. Goyer. It stars Rufus Sewell, William Hurt, Jennifer Connelly, Kiefer Sutherland, Richard O'Brien and Ian Richardson. Music is by Trevor Jones and cinematography by Dariusz Wolski. A man wakes up in a grotty hotel bathroom and upon finding a dead girl in another room he realises he has no recollection of who he is or how he got there... There's a lot of Blade Runner fans still out there waiting for that film's sexual partner to happen along. What many of them don't realise is that Alex Proyas has already made that movie. More than a cult film yet still criminally ignored in certain circles, Dark City, by way of poor box office and studio interference, never got off to the best of starts. The problems were compounded with the release of The Matrix the following year, where that film's popularity, and its sci-fi linkage to Dark City, led many to think that Proyas' movie was a Matrix rip-off; pushing it further (unjustly) back in the sci-fi noir pantheon. Fact is is that Dark City homages much great cinema from previous years, but it has influenced much that followed, with Inception fans asked to note that Nolan himself was taking notes... Stolen Memories. Dark City is a feverish film noir dressed up in stunning sci-fi clothes. The amazing visuals have led many to state that it's a film with much style and little substance, something which Proyas has fiercely argued against; and he's right to do so, especially once his own preferred director's cut became available to view. The story is a complex one, pulsing with human characters living in a world where there is no daylight, with their respective memories scratchy to say the least, it quickly becomes evident that a creepy alien race are overseeing things. The aliens, wonderfully attired in black trench-coats and hats to match, and aided by Kiefer Sutherland's shifty - stammer affected - doctor, have special powers and their reasons for being here unfold in deftly constructed stages. One man stands in their way, John Murdoch (Sewell), but he is an olde noir amnesia sufferer supreme and his battle to unravel what is going on is our task as well. Do you think about the past much Mrs. Murdoch? The search for identity and the truth is what propels the picture forward. Murdoch in his confused state is not only at the center of an existential dilemma, he's also the focal point for a serial killer murder investigation. This also as he tries to come to terms with matters of the heart, it seems he has a beautiful wife (Connelly), and that she may have cheated on him? And why is he drawn to the place known as Shell Beach? A simple narrative hidden by visual splendours? Don't make me laugh! But hell you have to say the visual look and atmosphere of the design is very much attention grabbing. I have become the monster you were intended to be. With the film noir characters in place; Hurt's dour sleuth, Sewell's amnesiac and Connelly's sultry torch singer, Proyas brings German expressionism in abundance whilst overseeing an eye splintering neo-noir colour palette. Greens and reds often ping from the screen, while the murky browns and golds down on the angular city streets pave the way for changed perceptions and revelations of plotting. There are reoccurring motifs throughout, with swirls and circles integral to mood and meanings, while at the mid-point we then get to see Proyas' tricks of the trade, where the city shifts and moves to create a meeting of Metropolis and Gotham, all as the humans slumber away. Watch those clocks folks... You know how I was supposed to feel. That person isn't me... never was. You wanted to know what it was about us that made us human. Well, you're not going to find it... Acting performances are hardly top of the line (Sutherland especially irritates more than he impresses), but they actually don't need to be, and they all look terrific in their respective dressage. The story is of course bonkers and one which I myself found was much better whilst consuming mucho alcohol! (I watched it three times in 48 hours!) While Proyas himself is on record as saying it's a far from flawless picture. Again he is right, but he also knows that his film is still under valued and in need of more to seek out his director's cut. The late Roger Ebert championed Dark City with much gusto, and he provides very good input on the DVD, much like Roger I have to say, this is a unique and fabulous sci-fi noir experience. A film in fact fit to watch alongside Blade Runner; And I do not say that lightly. 9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Directors Cut is a must
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    hello610
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Fantastic visuals that still looks good even compared to todays standards. I must reiterate, directors cut is a must! The theatrical version has a narration in the start which ruins the mystery. The mystery is what makes us closely follow the main character, John Murdoch, as he tries to piece parts to unveil the past. The Story is very intriguing and keeps the viewer interested through series of events that unveil the truth about the city and the viewer is confronted with questions about the very essence of humanity, and whether our world is really as real as we think. The characters played by Connelley and Sewell are very realistic and convince you that the situation in the movie is very much at hand; their acting is superb and captivating. This movie is spectacular.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A bewildering situation full of questions without answers
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Avid Climber
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dark City is one of those movies that is very difficult to categorized. It makes us experience something truly unique. The good. Extremely imaginative setup. Very dark. Strong intrigue with multiple parts that keeps us guessing for most of the movie. The actors. Rufus Sewell gives us a solid performance as the main confused protagonist, and we feel just like him. On the other hand, as a watcher, it is William Hurt playing the detective who leads our inquiries, trying to understand the mystery as we would. The ever beautiful Jennifer Connelly is adorable in her gentle role. Kiefer Sutherland gives strange ticks to the persona he is playing, making him seem slightly fake. The bad. The green screen shot are poor, and fortunately somewhat rare. The rest of the special effect imperfections can be viewed as "stylish" and more easily absorbed. The final fight is a bit too simple. The ugly. That dying critter near the end that looks almost pixelated. The result. Quite a stupefying ride. Recommended to anyone, especially lovers of strange intrigues.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Underrated Sci Fi Classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    user-35583
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of the great movies of the 90's. It was under-seen on release and has been over- looked ever since. I think it belongs with Blade Runner and 12 Monkees to name a couple of others in a similar vein. I can only guess it was the casting of Rufus Sewell - a then unknown Aussie actor - in the lead role. On the contrary, he is rock solid and owns the role of the confused yet curious protagonist who looks to recovery his memory while trying to solve the murders of which he has been accused. All the while being tracked by the Strangers - a collective of strange "men" that are able to transform the physical world they inhabit. The supporting cast is amazing. WIlliam Hurt, Jennifer Connelly, Kiefer Sutherland and Melissa George among them and all own their roles with aplomb. The set decoration is incredible and still looks stunning on viewing 15 years later. If you haven't seen this, I highly recommend it - especially stunning on Blue Ray.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Phew! My Brain Just Wouldn't Stop Farting!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dalbert Pringle
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For me, the grim and grimy bleakness of Dark City's story was delivered in such a chaotic muddle that it gave me the worst case of brain farts ever experienced from watching any movie since seeing the likes of the ultra-boring Blade Runner. And, after only a short while, just the mere mention of Shell Beach seriously began to grate on my nerves like you wouldn't believe. Dark City certainly didn't even come anywhere near to living up to its potential or its apparent reputation as being a perfect example of a brilliant Sci-Fi/Fantasy story dealing intelligently with such subject matter as "humans-as-guinea-pigs". This film was just silly, comic-book shenanigans that left the viewer less than satisfied with its inevitable outcome. It was very much like being shipwrecked on the shores of Shell Beach. This story's major downfall was that "The Strangers" kept the city with no-name in a state of continual darkness. If they had even the least bit of understanding about humans, they would've realized that we essentially need sunlight for our very survival. (The humans in this story seem to have not realized this, as well) Living in perpetual darkness would mean only severe sickness and surely a quick death for the human race. We, literally, cannot continue to live without relying on the sun as our #1 source of energy. Two things that I found really puzzling about "The Strangers" was that there was only one child amongst the whole lot and that there were absolutely no women, at all. I don't know if this was some sort of an oversight by the screenwriters, or what, but I found it only added even more damaging weight to the overall weakness of Dark City's already seriously floundering story. Of the 4 principal actors who starred in Dark City (Kiefer Sutherland, William Hurt, Rufus Sewell, Jennifer Connelly), I thought that each and every one of their performances to be unacceptably poor and downright mundane. It was the annoying, pig-faced Sutherland, in particular, who was so atrociously despicable as Dr. Schreber that I immediately began to dread every single scene that he happened to appear in. It was he, alone, who brought this movie down a couple of significant notches. Well, about all that I have left to say is - Thank goodness that my brain farts were odorless, otherwise, if they hadn't been, I would have ended up stinking everyone else watching Dark City with me right out of the room.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Still enjoyable, but I can't believe I glossed over the acting & dialogue
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gotmayle
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When this came out it never made much of a splash here, but I loved it as a cult sci-fi movie. Noir and off-beat, some interesting effects and a concept that, whilst not exactly new, was about to be re-done for the Matrix a few short years later. I watched it and re-watched it a numberof times in the early 2000s, but it's been about a decade and I decided to sit down and enjoy it again. How did I ever get past the stodgy acting, corny dialogue and clunky exposition? These are things that I usually don't even become aware of unless someone else points them out? If you haven't seen it, give it a try - it's got lots of merit, but for the most part it seems like the actors are being asked to do long division in their heads while their delivering their lines - that vacant look and lack of emotion just brings the pithy dialogue into focus all the more.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great Sci fi....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pk-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Still one of my all time favorite science fiction movies. Great plot. Great special affects. Acting is top notch... You rarely see such classic sci fi nowadays. Lately, It's all stupid comic book crap like Iron Man, Transformers and Spiderman. Which explains the clueless bad reviews from younger reviewers who have no patience for a good developing plot. Glad to finally see it played on cable. Until recently, I have never found it available on any premium channels till lately. But I noticed it has shown up on Comcast these past few weeks. Plot is totally original. Humans are taken to this experimental Ship to help save a dying Alien race. Only to find out they are too different from us to help save themselves from their fate...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I am missing something here
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    shankh-sarkar
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Whenever in doubt, I have always treated IMDb's rating as a benchmark before deciding if it was worth my while watching a particular movie . If it's above 7.5 , its on. So despite my initial doubts while skimming through the movie on vlc, I decided to watch it solely because it was rated 7.7. And here's what I realized; that I wanted the last couple of hours of my life back. The plot of the movie failed to account for the crucial element of suspension of disbelief. At no point could I convince myself that what was playing on the screen was even remotely feasible. The old philosophical adage, "Nothing comes from nothing" kept repeating itself in my head as the characters played out their superhuman capabilities. Comparisons with "The Matrix" are inevitable because of the similar theme of their being a chosen one but The Matrix beats The Dark City hands down because of its superior graphics, tight knit plot and superb storytelling. I ain't gonna bother raising my doubts because there are far too many of them and none of them can be answered satisfactorily even after accounting for cinematic liberty. So for those of you that dig the movie, I really am missing something here and glad for it too.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Finding our humanity
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    hall895
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dark City begins with an opening voice-over narration which basically gives the whole plot away. Fans of the film hated this and in a later cut of the film the narration was removed. It does seem logical that a movie which has so many mysterious elements shouldn't reveal all its secrets in the first thirty seconds. But in this case the narration probably served the film well. Because what is going on in this film is very weird, exceedingly bizarre and not particularly easy to comprehend unless you have some solid base of initial knowledge to fall back on. And there are still enough twists, turns and impactful surprises to make the film very compelling. Giving the audience a little help at the beginning paid off. Otherwise by the time the film finally fully revealed itself many people may have been too lost, too confused, too frustrated to appreciate what they had seen. And there is so much to appreciate. It also must be said that having the story laid out in such detail early on allows the audience to accept that story much easier. It is a story which requires tremendous leaps of faith. Without sufficient grounding the story may ultimately have proved to be just too strange for many people to take. Even with so many of its secrets given away right at the start the story still manages to grab you. A man wakes up in a bathtub. He can't seem to remember anything. His forehead is bleeding. There's a dead woman on the floor. And then the phone rings, someone tells him he needs to run away now because they are coming to get him. Who are "they"? Who knows? Anyway, the man flees and the movie kicks into high gear very quickly. The man is John Murdoch. Or is he? It becomes clear very quickly that nothing in this city is exactly what it seems. John Murdoch is not the only person here with vanished memories. He doesn't really know who he is. Nobody does. But nobody besides John realizes anything is amiss. It is up to him to unravel the mystery. What he discovers will shock both him and us. The film packs quite a dramatic punch and raises serious questions about humanity. What makes us human? This film's mysterious Strangers need to know the answer to that question. It is the Strangers who drive the plot. They can manipulate the physical environment of the city, creating new buildings and changing the form of existing ones in mere moments with just the power of their minds. And yet none of the humans ever notice anything has changed. And it is not just the buildings the Strangers change, they have a rather insidious, invasive way of changing the people themselves. Then the Strangers sit back and see what happens. The humans, unknowingly, are their lab rats. John however is resistant to the efforts of the Strangers. Not only that he apparently shares their powers. With the help of a police detective he sets out to find the truth and to give the citizens of the city back their humanity, give them back a sense of who they really are. Rufus Sewell does very well with the challenging role of John Murdoch, a man who does not know who he is. Sewell captures the original bewilderment well and then grows with the character as John finds the strength and determination to put an end to whatever is going on here. William Hurt plays the detective who ends up assisting John, Jennifer Connelly plays John's wife. They both end up very confused and Hurt and Connelly give very good performances as their characters try to figure out what the heck is going on here. Richard O'Brien is appropriately creepy playing the film's most prominent Stranger. Perhaps the only misstep comes from Kiefer Sutherland playing a doctor mixed up in the activities of the Strangers. Sutherland plays the role with a stammer which becomes distracting and annoying very quickly. It's a little bit of weirdness the film didn't need, it adds nothing to the character and the film's plenty weird enough already. But that quibble aside the film generally works very well. It is a fascinating, intriguing, thought-provoking story. Visually the film looks spectacular with wonderful set design and brilliantly executed effects. Perhaps the film goes a little overboard with the effects near the end. The story gets somewhat left behind as things wrap up with a big visual effects blowout. You can't help but think this very smart film deserved a little bit smarter of an ending. But the film ultimately is more than satisfying enough. It entertains you and it also makes you think which is always a good combination. Dark City's story is a very complex web to weave your way through, having had a little guidance at the start surely couldn't have hurt. And when you get to the end you'll look back and be grateful for the long, strange, fascinating trip the film took you on.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I don't get the fuss
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Fluke_Skywalker
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For most of its running time it sort of plays like an extended 'Twilight Zone' episode, and It hooked me well enough. I wanted to know what was happening and why... for a while, at least. Then I just got bored. When the pieces of the puzzle finally do come together, it's quite a let down. And then, after 90 minutes of dull neo-noir mystery, it turned on a dime with a tonally incongruous smack-down finale that did little to re-ignite my interest. There's some nifty stuff in there, and I can see its influence on more recentand much betterwork, but I just can't see what all the hubbub is about with 'Dark City'.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Welcome To Shell Beach.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dark City D/C Dark City is directed by Alex Proyas who also co-writes the screenplay with Leon Dobbs and David S. Goyer. It stars Rufus Sewell, William Hurt, Jennifer Connelly, Kiefer Sutherland, Richard O'Brien and Ian Richardson. Music is by Trevor Jones and cinematography by Dariusz Wolski. A man wakes up in a grotty hotel bathroom and upon finding a dead girl in another room he realises he has no recollection of who he is or how he got there... There's a lot of Blade Runner fans still out there waiting for that film's sexual partner to happen along. What many of them don't realise is that Alex Proyas has already made that movie. More than a cult film yet still criminally ignored in certain circles, Dark City, by way of poor box office and studio interference, never got off to the best of starts. The problems were compounded with the release of The Matrix the following year, where that film's popularity, and its sci-fi linkage to Dark City, led many to think that Proyas' movie was a Matrix rip-off; pushing it further (unjustly) back in the sci-fi noir pantheon. Fact is is that Dark City homages much great cinema from previous years, but it has influenced much that followed, with Inception fans asked to note that Nolan himself was taking notes... Stolen Memories. Dark City is a feverish film noir dressed up in stunning sci-fi clothes. The amazing visuals have led many to state that it's a film with much style and little substance, something which Proyas has fiercely argued against; and he's right to do so, especially once his own preferred director's cut became available to view. The story is a complex one, pulsing with human characters living in a world where there is no daylight, with their respective memories scratchy to say the least, it quickly becomes evident that a creepy alien race are overseeing things. The aliens, wonderfully attired in black trench-coats and hats to match, and aided by Kiefer Sutherland's shifty - stammer affected - doctor, have special powers and their reasons for being here unfold in deftly constructed stages. One man stands in their way, John Murdoch (Sewell), but he is an olde noir amnesia sufferer supreme and his battle to unravel what is going on is our task as well. Do you think about the past much Mrs. Murdoch? The search for identity and the truth is what propels the picture forward. Murdoch in his confused state is not only at the center of an existential dilemma, he's also the focal point for a serial killer murder investigation. This also as he tries to come to terms with matters of the heart, it seems he has a beautiful wife (Connelly), and that she may have cheated on him? And why is he drawn to the place known as Shell Beach? A simple narrative hidden by visual splendours? Don't make me laugh! But hell you have to say the visual look and atmosphere of the design is very much attention grabbing. I have become the monster you were intended to be. With the film noir characters in place; Hurt's dour sleuth, Sewell's amnesiac and Connelly's sultry torch singer, Proyas brings German expressionism in abundance whilst overseeing an eye splintering neo-noir colour palette. Greens and reds often ping from the screen, while the murky browns and golds down on the angular city streets pave the way for changed perceptions and revelations of plotting. There are reoccurring motifs throughout, with swirls and circles integral to mood and meanings, while at the mid-point we then get to see Proyas' tricks of the trade, where the city shifts and moves to create a meeting of Metropolis and Gotham, all as the humans slumber away. Watch those clocks folks... You know how I was supposed to feel. That person isn't me... never was. You wanted to know what it was about us that made us human. Well, you're not going to find it... Acting performances are hardly top of the line (Sutherland especially irritates more than he impresses), but they actually don't need to be, and they all look terrific in their respective dressage. The story is of course bonkers and one which I myself found was much better whilst consuming mucho alcohol! (I watched it three times in 48 hours!) While Proyas himself is on record as saying it's a far from flawless picture. Again he is right, but he also knows that his film is still under valued and in need of more to seek out his director's cut. The late Roger Ebert championed Dark City with much gusto, and he provides very good input on the DVD, much like Roger I have to say, this is a unique and fabulous sci-fi noir experience. A film in fact fit to watch alongside Blade Runner; And I do not say that lightly. 9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Directors Cut is a must
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    hello610
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Fantastic visuals that still looks good even compared to todays standards. I must reiterate, directors cut is a must! The theatrical version has a narration in the start which ruins the mystery. The mystery is what makes us closely follow the main character, John Murdoch, as he tries to piece parts to unveil the past. The Story is very intriguing and keeps the viewer interested through series of events that unveil the truth about the city and the viewer is confronted with questions about the very essence of humanity, and whether our world is really as real as we think. The characters played by Connelley and Sewell are very realistic and convince you that the situation in the movie is very much at hand; their acting is superb and captivating. This movie is spectacular.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A bewildering situation full of questions without answers
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Avid Climber
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dark City is one of those movies that is very difficult to categorized. It makes us experience something truly unique. The good. Extremely imaginative setup. Very dark. Strong intrigue with multiple parts that keeps us guessing for most of the movie. The actors. Rufus Sewell gives us a solid performance as the main confused protagonist, and we feel just like him. On the other hand, as a watcher, it is William Hurt playing the detective who leads our inquiries, trying to understand the mystery as we would. The ever beautiful Jennifer Connelly is adorable in her gentle role. Kiefer Sutherland gives strange ticks to the persona he is playing, making him seem slightly fake. The bad. The green screen shot are poor, and fortunately somewhat rare. The rest of the special effect imperfections can be viewed as "stylish" and more easily absorbed. The final fight is a bit too simple. The ugly. That dying critter near the end that looks almost pixelated. The result. Quite a stupefying ride. Recommended to anyone, especially lovers of strange intrigues.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Underrated Sci Fi Classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    user-35583
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of the great movies of the 90's. It was under-seen on release and has been over- looked ever since. I think it belongs with Blade Runner and 12 Monkees to name a couple of others in a similar vein. I can only guess it was the casting of Rufus Sewell - a then unknown Aussie actor - in the lead role. On the contrary, he is rock solid and owns the role of the confused yet curious protagonist who looks to recovery his memory while trying to solve the murders of which he has been accused. All the while being tracked by the Strangers - a collective of strange "men" that are able to transform the physical world they inhabit. The supporting cast is amazing. WIlliam Hurt, Jennifer Connelly, Kiefer Sutherland and Melissa George among them and all own their roles with aplomb. The set decoration is incredible and still looks stunning on viewing 15 years later. If you haven't seen this, I highly recommend it - especially stunning on Blue Ray.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Phew! My Brain Just Wouldn't Stop Farting!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dalbert Pringle
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For me, the grim and grimy bleakness of Dark City's story was delivered in such a chaotic muddle that it gave me the worst case of brain farts ever experienced from watching any movie since seeing the likes of the ultra-boring Blade Runner. And, after only a short while, just the mere mention of Shell Beach seriously began to grate on my nerves like you wouldn't believe. Dark City certainly didn't even come anywhere near to living up to its potential or its apparent reputation as being a perfect example of a brilliant Sci-Fi/Fantasy story dealing intelligently with such subject matter as "humans-as-guinea-pigs". This film was just silly, comic-book shenanigans that left the viewer less than satisfied with its inevitable outcome. It was very much like being shipwrecked on the shores of Shell Beach. This story's major downfall was that "The Strangers" kept the city with no-name in a state of continual darkness. If they had even the least bit of understanding about humans, they would've realized that we essentially need sunlight for our very survival. (The humans in this story seem to have not realized this, as well) Living in perpetual darkness would mean only severe sickness and surely a quick death for the human race. We, literally, cannot continue to live without relying on the sun as our #1 source of energy. Two things that I found really puzzling about "The Strangers" was that there was only one child amongst the whole lot and that there were absolutely no women, at all. I don't know if this was some sort of an oversight by the screenwriters, or what, but I found it only added even more damaging weight to the overall weakness of Dark City's already seriously floundering story. Of the 4 principal actors who starred in Dark City (Kiefer Sutherland, William Hurt, Rufus Sewell, Jennifer Connelly), I thought that each and every one of their performances to be unacceptably poor and downright mundane. It was the annoying, pig-faced Sutherland, in particular, who was so atrociously despicable as Dr. Schreber that I immediately began to dread every single scene that he happened to appear in. It was he, alone, who brought this movie down a couple of significant notches. Well, about all that I have left to say is - Thank goodness that my brain farts were odorless, otherwise, if they hadn't been, I would have ended up stinking everyone else watching Dark City with me right out of the room.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Still enjoyable, but I can't believe I glossed over the acting & dialogue
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gotmayle
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When this came out it never made much of a splash here, but I loved it as a cult sci-fi movie. Noir and off-beat, some interesting effects and a concept that, whilst not exactly new, was about to be re-done for the Matrix a few short years later. I watched it and re-watched it a numberof times in the early 2000s, but it's been about a decade and I decided to sit down and enjoy it again. How did I ever get past the stodgy acting, corny dialogue and clunky exposition? These are things that I usually don't even become aware of unless someone else points them out? If you haven't seen it, give it a try - it's got lots of merit, but for the most part it seems like the actors are being asked to do long division in their heads while their delivering their lines - that vacant look and lack of emotion just brings the pithy dialogue into focus all the more.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great Sci fi....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pk-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Still one of my all time favorite science fiction movies. Great plot. Great special affects. Acting is top notch... You rarely see such classic sci fi nowadays. Lately, It's all stupid comic book crap like Iron Man, Transformers and Spiderman. Which explains the clueless bad reviews from younger reviewers who have no patience for a good developing plot. Glad to finally see it played on cable. Until recently, I have never found it available on any premium channels till lately. But I noticed it has shown up on Comcast these past few weeks. Plot is totally original. Humans are taken to this experimental Ship to help save a dying Alien race. Only to find out they are too different from us to help save themselves from their fate...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I am missing something here
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    shankh-sarkar
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Whenever in doubt, I have always treated IMDb's rating as a benchmark before deciding if it was worth my while watching a particular movie . If it's above 7.5 , its on. So despite my initial doubts while skimming through the movie on vlc, I decided to watch it solely because it was rated 7.7. And here's what I realized; that I wanted the last couple of hours of my life back. The plot of the movie failed to account for the crucial element of suspension of disbelief. At no point could I convince myself that what was playing on the screen was even remotely feasible. The old philosophical adage, "Nothing comes from nothing" kept repeating itself in my head as the characters played out their superhuman capabilities. Comparisons with "The Matrix" are inevitable because of the similar theme of their being a chosen one but The Matrix beats The Dark City hands down because of its superior graphics, tight knit plot and superb storytelling. I ain't gonna bother raising my doubts because there are far too many of them and none of them can be answered satisfactorily even after accounting for cinematic liberty. So for those of you that dig the movie, I really am missing something here and glad for it too.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Finding our humanity
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    hall895
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dark City begins with an opening voice-over narration which basically gives the whole plot away. Fans of the film hated this and in a later cut of the film the narration was removed. It does seem logical that a movie which has so many mysterious elements shouldn't reveal all its secrets in the first thirty seconds. But in this case the narration probably served the film well. Because what is going on in this film is very weird, exceedingly bizarre and not particularly easy to comprehend unless you have some solid base of initial knowledge to fall back on. And there are still enough twists, turns and impactful surprises to make the film very compelling. Giving the audience a little help at the beginning paid off. Otherwise by the time the film finally fully revealed itself many people may have been too lost, too confused, too frustrated to appreciate what they had seen. And there is so much to appreciate. It also must be said that having the story laid out in such detail early on allows the audience to accept that story much easier. It is a story which requires tremendous leaps of faith. Without sufficient grounding the story may ultimately have proved to be just too strange for many people to take. Even with so many of its secrets given away right at the start the story still manages to grab you. A man wakes up in a bathtub. He can't seem to remember anything. His forehead is bleeding. There's a dead woman on the floor. And then the phone rings, someone tells him he needs to run away now because they are coming to get him. Who are "they"? Who knows? Anyway, the man flees and the movie kicks into high gear very quickly. The man is John Murdoch. Or is he? It becomes clear very quickly that nothing in this city is exactly what it seems. John Murdoch is not the only person here with vanished memories. He doesn't really know who he is. Nobody does. But nobody besides John realizes anything is amiss. It is up to him to unravel the mystery. What he discovers will shock both him and us. The film packs quite a dramatic punch and raises serious questions about humanity. What makes us human? This film's mysterious Strangers need to know the answer to that question. It is the Strangers who drive the plot. They can manipulate the physical environment of the city, creating new buildings and changing the form of existing ones in mere moments with just the power of their minds. And yet none of the humans ever notice anything has changed. And it is not just the buildings the Strangers change, they have a rather insidious, invasive way of changing the people themselves. Then the Strangers sit back and see what happens. The humans, unknowingly, are their lab rats. John however is resistant to the efforts of the Strangers. Not only that he apparently shares their powers. With the help of a police detective he sets out to find the truth and to give the citizens of the city back their humanity, give them back a sense of who they really are. Rufus Sewell does very well with the challenging role of John Murdoch, a man who does not know who he is. Sewell captures the original bewilderment well and then grows with the character as John finds the strength and determination to put an end to whatever is going on here. William Hurt plays the detective who ends up assisting John, Jennifer Connelly plays John's wife. They both end up very confused and Hurt and Connelly give very good performances as their characters try to figure out what the heck is going on here. Richard O'Brien is appropriately creepy playing the film's most prominent Stranger. Perhaps the only misstep comes from Kiefer Sutherland playing a doctor mixed up in the activities of the Strangers. Sutherland plays the role with a stammer which becomes distracting and annoying very quickly. It's a little bit of weirdness the film didn't need, it adds nothing to the character and the film's plenty weird enough already. But that quibble aside the film generally works very well. It is a fascinating, intriguing, thought-provoking story. Visually the film looks spectacular with wonderful set design and brilliantly executed effects. Perhaps the film goes a little overboard with the effects near the end. The story gets somewhat left behind as things wrap up with a big visual effects blowout. You can't help but think this very smart film deserved a little bit smarter of an ending. But the film ultimately is more than satisfying enough. It entertains you and it also makes you think which is always a good combination. Dark City's story is a very complex web to weave your way through, having had a little guidance at the start surely couldn't have hurt. And when you get to the end you'll look back and be grateful for the long, strange, fascinating trip the film took you on.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I don't get the fuss
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Fluke_Skywalker
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For most of its running time it sort of plays like an extended 'Twilight Zone' episode, and It hooked me well enough. I wanted to know what was happening and why... for a while, at least. Then I just got bored. When the pieces of the puzzle finally do come together, it's quite a let down. And then, after 90 minutes of dull neo-noir mystery, it turned on a dime with a tonally incongruous smack-down finale that did little to re-ignite my interest. There's some nifty stuff in there, and I can see its influence on more recentand much betterwork, but I just can't see what all the hubbub is about with 'Dark City'.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Welcome To Shell Beach.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dark City D/C Dark City is directed by Alex Proyas who also co-writes the screenplay with Leon Dobbs and David S. Goyer. It stars Rufus Sewell, William Hurt, Jennifer Connelly, Kiefer Sutherland, Richard O'Brien and Ian Richardson. Music is by Trevor Jones and cinematography by Dariusz Wolski. A man wakes up in a grotty hotel bathroom and upon finding a dead girl in another room he realises he has no recollection of who he is or how he got there... There's a lot of Blade Runner fans still out there waiting for that film's sexual partner to happen along. What many of them don't realise is that Alex Proyas has already made that movie. More than a cult film yet still criminally ignored in certain circles, Dark City, by way of poor box office and studio interference, never got off to the best of starts. The problems were compounded with the release of The Matrix the following year, where that film's popularity, and its sci-fi linkage to Dark City, led many to think that Proyas' movie was a Matrix rip-off; pushing it further (unjustly) back in the sci-fi noir pantheon. Fact is is that Dark City homages much great cinema from previous years, but it has influenced much that followed, with Inception fans asked to note that Nolan himself was taking notes... Stolen Memories. Dark City is a feverish film noir dressed up in stunning sci-fi clothes. The amazing visuals have led many to state that it's a film with much style and little substance, something which Proyas has fiercely argued against; and he's right to do so, especially once his own preferred director's cut became available to view. The story is a complex one, pulsing with human characters living in a world where there is no daylight, with their respective memories scratchy to say the least, it quickly becomes evident that a creepy alien race are overseeing things. The aliens, wonderfully attired in black trench-coats and hats to match, and aided by Kiefer Sutherland's shifty - stammer affected - doctor, have special powers and their reasons for being here unfold in deftly constructed stages. One man stands in their way, John Murdoch (Sewell), but he is an olde noir amnesia sufferer supreme and his battle to unravel what is going on is our task as well. Do you think about the past much Mrs. Murdoch? The search for identity and the truth is what propels the picture forward. Murdoch in his confused state is not only at the center of an existential dilemma, he's also the focal point for a serial killer murder investigation. This also as he tries to come to terms with matters of the heart, it seems he has a beautiful wife (Connelly), and that she may have cheated on him? And why is he drawn to the place known as Shell Beach? A simple narrative hidden by visual splendours? Don't make me laugh! But hell you have to say the visual look and atmosphere of the design is very much attention grabbing. I have become the monster you were intended to be. With the film noir characters in place; Hurt's dour sleuth, Sewell's amnesiac and Connelly's sultry torch singer, Proyas brings German expressionism in abundance whilst overseeing an eye splintering neo-noir colour palette. Greens and reds often ping from the screen, while the murky browns and golds down on the angular city streets pave the way for changed perceptions and revelations of plotting. There are reoccurring motifs throughout, with swirls and circles integral to mood and meanings, while at the mid-point we then get to see Proyas' tricks of the trade, where the city shifts and moves to create a meeting of Metropolis and Gotham, all as the humans slumber away. Watch those clocks folks... You know how I was supposed to feel. That person isn't me... never was. You wanted to know what it was about us that made us human. Well, you're not going to find it... Acting performances are hardly top of the line (Sutherland especially irritates more than he impresses), but they actually don't need to be, and they all look terrific in their respective dressage. The story is of course bonkers and one which I myself found was much better whilst consuming mucho alcohol! (I watched it three times in 48 hours!) While Proyas himself is on record as saying it's a far from flawless picture. Again he is right, but he also knows that his film is still under valued and in need of more to seek out his director's cut. The late Roger Ebert championed Dark City with much gusto, and he provides very good input on the DVD, much like Roger I have to say, this is a unique and fabulous sci-fi noir experience. A film in fact fit to watch alongside Blade Runner; And I do not say that lightly. 9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Directors Cut is a must
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    hello610
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Fantastic visuals that still looks good even compared to todays standards. I must reiterate, directors cut is a must! The theatrical version has a narration in the start which ruins the mystery. The mystery is what makes us closely follow the main character, John Murdoch, as he tries to piece parts to unveil the past. The Story is very intriguing and keeps the viewer interested through series of events that unveil the truth about the city and the viewer is confronted with questions about the very essence of humanity, and whether our world is really as real as we think. The characters played by Connelley and Sewell are very realistic and convince you that the situation in the movie is very much at hand; their acting is superb and captivating. This movie is spectacular.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A bewildering situation full of questions without answers
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Avid Climber
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dark City is one of those movies that is very difficult to categorized. It makes us experience something truly unique. The good. Extremely imaginative setup. Very dark. Strong intrigue with multiple parts that keeps us guessing for most of the movie. The actors. Rufus Sewell gives us a solid performance as the main confused protagonist, and we feel just like him. On the other hand, as a watcher, it is William Hurt playing the detective who leads our inquiries, trying to understand the mystery as we would. The ever beautiful Jennifer Connelly is adorable in her gentle role. Kiefer Sutherland gives strange ticks to the persona he is playing, making him seem slightly fake. The bad. The green screen shot are poor, and fortunately somewhat rare. The rest of the special effect imperfections can be viewed as "stylish" and more easily absorbed. The final fight is a bit too simple. The ugly. That dying critter near the end that looks almost pixelated. The result. Quite a stupefying ride. Recommended to anyone, especially lovers of strange intrigues.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Underrated Sci Fi Classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    user-35583
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of the great movies of the 90's. It was under-seen on release and has been over- looked ever since. I think it belongs with Blade Runner and 12 Monkees to name a couple of others in a similar vein. I can only guess it was the casting of Rufus Sewell - a then unknown Aussie actor - in the lead role. On the contrary, he is rock solid and owns the role of the confused yet curious protagonist who looks to recovery his memory while trying to solve the murders of which he has been accused. All the while being tracked by the Strangers - a collective of strange "men" that are able to transform the physical world they inhabit. The supporting cast is amazing. WIlliam Hurt, Jennifer Connelly, Kiefer Sutherland and Melissa George among them and all own their roles with aplomb. The set decoration is incredible and still looks stunning on viewing 15 years later. If you haven't seen this, I highly recommend it - especially stunning on Blue Ray.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Phew! My Brain Just Wouldn't Stop Farting!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dalbert Pringle
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For me, the grim and grimy bleakness of Dark City's story was delivered in such a chaotic muddle that it gave me the worst case of brain farts ever experienced from watching any movie since seeing the likes of the ultra-boring Blade Runner. And, after only a short while, just the mere mention of Shell Beach seriously began to grate on my nerves like you wouldn't believe. Dark City certainly didn't even come anywhere near to living up to its potential or its apparent reputation as being a perfect example of a brilliant Sci-Fi/Fantasy story dealing intelligently with such subject matter as "humans-as-guinea-pigs". This film was just silly, comic-book shenanigans that left the viewer less than satisfied with its inevitable outcome. It was very much like being shipwrecked on the shores of Shell Beach. This story's major downfall was that "The Strangers" kept the city with no-name in a state of continual darkness. If they had even the least bit of understanding about humans, they would've realized that we essentially need sunlight for our very survival. (The humans in this story seem to have not realized this, as well) Living in perpetual darkness would mean only severe sickness and surely a quick death for the human race. We, literally, cannot continue to live without relying on the sun as our #1 source of energy. Two things that I found really puzzling about "The Strangers" was that there was only one child amongst the whole lot and that there were absolutely no women, at all. I don't know if this was some sort of an oversight by the screenwriters, or what, but I found it only added even more damaging weight to the overall weakness of Dark City's already seriously floundering story. Of the 4 principal actors who starred in Dark City (Kiefer Sutherland, William Hurt, Rufus Sewell, Jennifer Connelly), I thought that each and every one of their performances to be unacceptably poor and downright mundane. It was the annoying, pig-faced Sutherland, in particular, who was so atrociously despicable as Dr. Schreber that I immediately began to dread every single scene that he happened to appear in. It was he, alone, who brought this movie down a couple of significant notches. Well, about all that I have left to say is - Thank goodness that my brain farts were odorless, otherwise, if they hadn't been, I would have ended up stinking everyone else watching Dark City with me right out of the room.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Still enjoyable, but I can't believe I glossed over the acting & dialogue
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gotmayle
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When this came out it never made much of a splash here, but I loved it as a cult sci-fi movie. Noir and off-beat, some interesting effects and a concept that, whilst not exactly new, was about to be re-done for the Matrix a few short years later. I watched it and re-watched it a numberof times in the early 2000s, but it's been about a decade and I decided to sit down and enjoy it again. How did I ever get past the stodgy acting, corny dialogue and clunky exposition? These are things that I usually don't even become aware of unless someone else points them out? If you haven't seen it, give it a try - it's got lots of merit, but for the most part it seems like the actors are being asked to do long division in their heads while their delivering their lines - that vacant look and lack of emotion just brings the pithy dialogue into focus all the more.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great Sci fi....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pk-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Still one of my all time favorite science fiction movies. Great plot. Great special affects. Acting is top notch... You rarely see such classic sci fi nowadays. Lately, It's all stupid comic book crap like Iron Man, Transformers and Spiderman. Which explains the clueless bad reviews from younger reviewers who have no patience for a good developing plot. Glad to finally see it played on cable. Until recently, I have never found it available on any premium channels till lately. But I noticed it has shown up on Comcast these past few weeks. Plot is totally original. Humans are taken to this experimental Ship to help save a dying Alien race. Only to find out they are too different from us to help save themselves from their fate...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I am missing something here
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    shankh-sarkar
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Whenever in doubt, I have always treated IMDb's rating as a benchmark before deciding if it was worth my while watching a particular movie . If it's above 7.5 , its on. So despite my initial doubts while skimming through the movie on vlc, I decided to watch it solely because it was rated 7.7. And here's what I realized; that I wanted the last couple of hours of my life back. The plot of the movie failed to account for the crucial element of suspension of disbelief. At no point could I convince myself that what was playing on the screen was even remotely feasible. The old philosophical adage, "Nothing comes from nothing" kept repeating itself in my head as the characters played out their superhuman capabilities. Comparisons with "The Matrix" are inevitable because of the similar theme of their being a chosen one but The Matrix beats The Dark City hands down because of its superior graphics, tight knit plot and superb storytelling. I ain't gonna bother raising my doubts because there are far too many of them and none of them can be answered satisfactorily even after accounting for cinematic liberty. So for those of you that dig the movie, I really am missing something here and glad for it too.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Finding our humanity
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    hall895
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dark City begins with an opening voice-over narration which basically gives the whole plot away. Fans of the film hated this and in a later cut of the film the narration was removed. It does seem logical that a movie which has so many mysterious elements shouldn't reveal all its secrets in the first thirty seconds. But in this case the narration probably served the film well. Because what is going on in this film is very weird, exceedingly bizarre and not particularly easy to comprehend unless you have some solid base of initial knowledge to fall back on. And there are still enough twists, turns and impactful surprises to make the film very compelling. Giving the audience a little help at the beginning paid off. Otherwise by the time the film finally fully revealed itself many people may have been too lost, too confused, too frustrated to appreciate what they had seen. And there is so much to appreciate. It also must be said that having the story laid out in such detail early on allows the audience to accept that story much easier. It is a story which requires tremendous leaps of faith. Without sufficient grounding the story may ultimately have proved to be just too strange for many people to take. Even with so many of its secrets given away right at the start the story still manages to grab you. A man wakes up in a bathtub. He can't seem to remember anything. His forehead is bleeding. There's a dead woman on the floor. And then the phone rings, someone tells him he needs to run away now because they are coming to get him. Who are "they"? Who knows? Anyway, the man flees and the movie kicks into high gear very quickly. The man is John Murdoch. Or is he? It becomes clear very quickly that nothing in this city is exactly what it seems. John Murdoch is not the only person here with vanished memories. He doesn't really know who he is. Nobody does. But nobody besides John realizes anything is amiss. It is up to him to unravel the mystery. What he discovers will shock both him and us. The film packs quite a dramatic punch and raises serious questions about humanity. What makes us human? This film's mysterious Strangers need to know the answer to that question. It is the Strangers who drive the plot. They can manipulate the physical environment of the city, creating new buildings and changing the form of existing ones in mere moments with just the power of their minds. And yet none of the humans ever notice anything has changed. And it is not just the buildings the Strangers change, they have a rather insidious, invasive way of changing the people themselves. Then the Strangers sit back and see what happens. The humans, unknowingly, are their lab rats. John however is resistant to the efforts of the Strangers. Not only that he apparently shares their powers. With the help of a police detective he sets out to find the truth and to give the citizens of the city back their humanity, give them back a sense of who they really are. Rufus Sewell does very well with the challenging role of John Murdoch, a man who does not know who he is. Sewell captures the original bewilderment well and then grows with the character as John finds the strength and determination to put an end to whatever is going on here. William Hurt plays the detective who ends up assisting John, Jennifer Connelly plays John's wife. They both end up very confused and Hurt and Connelly give very good performances as their characters try to figure out what the heck is going on here. Richard O'Brien is appropriately creepy playing the film's most prominent Stranger. Perhaps the only misstep comes from Kiefer Sutherland playing a doctor mixed up in the activities of the Strangers. Sutherland plays the role with a stammer which becomes distracting and annoying very quickly. It's a little bit of weirdness the film didn't need, it adds nothing to the character and the film's plenty weird enough already. But that quibble aside the film generally works very well. It is a fascinating, intriguing, thought-provoking story. Visually the film looks spectacular with wonderful set design and brilliantly executed effects. Perhaps the film goes a little overboard with the effects near the end. The story gets somewhat left behind as things wrap up with a big visual effects blowout. You can't help but think this very smart film deserved a little bit smarter of an ending. But the film ultimately is more than satisfying enough. It entertains you and it also makes you think which is always a good combination. Dark City's story is a very complex web to weave your way through, having had a little guidance at the start surely couldn't have hurt. And when you get to the end you'll look back and be grateful for the long, strange, fascinating trip the film took you on.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I don't get the fuss
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Fluke_Skywalker
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For most of its running time it sort of plays like an extended 'Twilight Zone' episode, and It hooked me well enough. I wanted to know what was happening and why... for a while, at least. Then I just got bored. When the pieces of the puzzle finally do come together, it's quite a let down. And then, after 90 minutes of dull neo-noir mystery, it turned on a dime with a tonally incongruous smack-down finale that did little to re-ignite my interest. There's some nifty stuff in there, and I can see its influence on more recentand much betterwork, but I just can't see what all the hubbub is about with 'Dark City'.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Welcome To Shell Beach.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dark City D/C Dark City is directed by Alex Proyas who also co-writes the screenplay with Leon Dobbs and David S. Goyer. It stars Rufus Sewell, William Hurt, Jennifer Connelly, Kiefer Sutherland, Richard O'Brien and Ian Richardson. Music is by Trevor Jones and cinematography by Dariusz Wolski. A man wakes up in a grotty hotel bathroom and upon finding a dead girl in another room he realises he has no recollection of who he is or how he got there... There's a lot of Blade Runner fans still out there waiting for that film's sexual partner to happen along. What many of them don't realise is that Alex Proyas has already made that movie. More than a cult film yet still criminally ignored in certain circles, Dark City, by way of poor box office and studio interference, never got off to the best of starts. The problems were compounded with the release of The Matrix the following year, where that film's popularity, and its sci-fi linkage to Dark City, led many to think that Proyas' movie was a Matrix rip-off; pushing it further (unjustly) back in the sci-fi noir pantheon. Fact is is that Dark City homages much great cinema from previous years, but it has influenced much that followed, with Inception fans asked to note that Nolan himself was taking notes... Stolen Memories. Dark City is a feverish film noir dressed up in stunning sci-fi clothes. The amazing visuals have led many to state that it's a film with much style and little substance, something which Proyas has fiercely argued against; and he's right to do so, especially once his own preferred director's cut became available to view. The story is a complex one, pulsing with human characters living in a world where there is no daylight, with their respective memories scratchy to say the least, it quickly becomes evident that a creepy alien race are overseeing things. The aliens, wonderfully attired in black trench-coats and hats to match, and aided by Kiefer Sutherland's shifty - stammer affected - doctor, have special powers and their reasons for being here unfold in deftly constructed stages. One man stands in their way, John Murdoch (Sewell), but he is an olde noir amnesia sufferer supreme and his battle to unravel what is going on is our task as well. Do you think about the past much Mrs. Murdoch? The search for identity and the truth is what propels the picture forward. Murdoch in his confused state is not only at the center of an existential dilemma, he's also the focal point for a serial killer murder investigation. This also as he tries to come to terms with matters of the heart, it seems he has a beautiful wife (Connelly), and that she may have cheated on him? And why is he drawn to the place known as Shell Beach? A simple narrative hidden by visual splendours? Don't make me laugh! But hell you have to say the visual look and atmosphere of the design is very much attention grabbing. I have become the monster you were intended to be. With the film noir characters in place; Hurt's dour sleuth, Sewell's amnesiac and Connelly's sultry torch singer, Proyas brings German expressionism in abundance whilst overseeing an eye splintering neo-noir colour palette. Greens and reds often ping from the screen, while the murky browns and golds down on the angular city streets pave the way for changed perceptions and revelations of plotting. There are reoccurring motifs throughout, with swirls and circles integral to mood and meanings, while at the mid-point we then get to see Proyas' tricks of the trade, where the city shifts and moves to create a meeting of Metropolis and Gotham, all as the humans slumber away. Watch those clocks folks... You know how I was supposed to feel. That person isn't me... never was. You wanted to know what it was about us that made us human. Well, you're not going to find it... Acting performances are hardly top of the line (Sutherland especially irritates more than he impresses), but they actually don't need to be, and they all look terrific in their respective dressage. The story is of course bonkers and one which I myself found was much better whilst consuming mucho alcohol! (I watched it three times in 48 hours!) While Proyas himself is on record as saying it's a far from flawless picture. Again he is right, but he also knows that his film is still under valued and in need of more to seek out his director's cut. The late Roger Ebert championed Dark City with much gusto, and he provides very good input on the DVD, much like Roger I have to say, this is a unique and fabulous sci-fi noir experience. A film in fact fit to watch alongside Blade Runner; And I do not say that lightly. 9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Directors Cut is a must
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    hello610
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Fantastic visuals that still looks good even compared to todays standards. I must reiterate, directors cut is a must! The theatrical version has a narration in the start which ruins the mystery. The mystery is what makes us closely follow the main character, John Murdoch, as he tries to piece parts to unveil the past. The Story is very intriguing and keeps the viewer interested through series of events that unveil the truth about the city and the viewer is confronted with questions about the very essence of humanity, and whether our world is really as real as we think. The characters played by Connelley and Sewell are very realistic and convince you that the situation in the movie is very much at hand; their acting is superb and captivating. This movie is spectacular.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A bewildering situation full of questions without answers
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Avid Climber
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dark City is one of those movies that is very difficult to categorized. It makes us experience something truly unique. The good. Extremely imaginative setup. Very dark. Strong intrigue with multiple parts that keeps us guessing for most of the movie. The actors. Rufus Sewell gives us a solid performance as the main confused protagonist, and we feel just like him. On the other hand, as a watcher, it is William Hurt playing the detective who leads our inquiries, trying to understand the mystery as we would. The ever beautiful Jennifer Connelly is adorable in her gentle role. Kiefer Sutherland gives strange ticks to the persona he is playing, making him seem slightly fake. The bad. The green screen shot are poor, and fortunately somewhat rare. The rest of the special effect imperfections can be viewed as "stylish" and more easily absorbed. The final fight is a bit too simple. The ugly. That dying critter near the end that looks almost pixelated. The result. Quite a stupefying ride. Recommended to anyone, especially lovers of strange intrigues.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Underrated Sci Fi Classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    user-35583
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of the great movies of the 90's. It was under-seen on release and has been over- looked ever since. I think it belongs with Blade Runner and 12 Monkees to name a couple of others in a similar vein. I can only guess it was the casting of Rufus Sewell - a then unknown Aussie actor - in the lead role. On the contrary, he is rock solid and owns the role of the confused yet curious protagonist who looks to recovery his memory while trying to solve the murders of which he has been accused. All the while being tracked by the Strangers - a collective of strange "men" that are able to transform the physical world they inhabit. The supporting cast is amazing. WIlliam Hurt, Jennifer Connelly, Kiefer Sutherland and Melissa George among them and all own their roles with aplomb. The set decoration is incredible and still looks stunning on viewing 15 years later. If you haven't seen this, I highly recommend it - especially stunning on Blue Ray.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Phew! My Brain Just Wouldn't Stop Farting!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dalbert Pringle
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For me, the grim and grimy bleakness of Dark City's story was delivered in such a chaotic muddle that it gave me the worst case of brain farts ever experienced from watching any movie since seeing the likes of the ultra-boring Blade Runner. And, after only a short while, just the mere mention of Shell Beach seriously began to grate on my nerves like you wouldn't believe. Dark City certainly didn't even come anywhere near to living up to its potential or its apparent reputation as being a perfect example of a brilliant Sci-Fi/Fantasy story dealing intelligently with such subject matter as "humans-as-guinea-pigs". This film was just silly, comic-book shenanigans that left the viewer less than satisfied with its inevitable outcome. It was very much like being shipwrecked on the shores of Shell Beach. This story's major downfall was that "The Strangers" kept the city with no-name in a state of continual darkness. If they had even the least bit of understanding about humans, they would've realized that we essentially need sunlight for our very survival. (The humans in this story seem to have not realized this, as well) Living in perpetual darkness would mean only severe sickness and surely a quick death for the human race. We, literally, cannot continue to live without relying on the sun as our #1 source of energy. Two things that I found really puzzling about "The Strangers" was that there was only one child amongst the whole lot and that there were absolutely no women, at all. I don't know if this was some sort of an oversight by the screenwriters, or what, but I found it only added even more damaging weight to the overall weakness of Dark City's already seriously floundering story. Of the 4 principal actors who starred in Dark City (Kiefer Sutherland, William Hurt, Rufus Sewell, Jennifer Connelly), I thought that each and every one of their performances to be unacceptably poor and downright mundane. It was the annoying, pig-faced Sutherland, in particular, who was so atrociously despicable as Dr. Schreber that I immediately began to dread every single scene that he happened to appear in. It was he, alone, who brought this movie down a couple of significant notches. Well, about all that I have left to say is - Thank goodness that my brain farts were odorless, otherwise, if they hadn't been, I would have ended up stinking everyone else watching Dark City with me right out of the room.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Still enjoyable, but I can't believe I glossed over the acting & dialogue
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gotmayle
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When this came out it never made much of a splash here, but I loved it as a cult sci-fi movie. Noir and off-beat, some interesting effects and a concept that, whilst not exactly new, was about to be re-done for the Matrix a few short years later. I watched it and re-watched it a numberof times in the early 2000s, but it's been about a decade and I decided to sit down and enjoy it again. How did I ever get past the stodgy acting, corny dialogue and clunky exposition? These are things that I usually don't even become aware of unless someone else points them out? If you haven't seen it, give it a try - it's got lots of merit, but for the most part it seems like the actors are being asked to do long division in their heads while their delivering their lines - that vacant look and lack of emotion just brings the pithy dialogue into focus all the more.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great Sci fi....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pk-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Still one of my all time favorite science fiction movies. Great plot. Great special affects. Acting is top notch... You rarely see such classic sci fi nowadays. Lately, It's all stupid comic book crap like Iron Man, Transformers and Spiderman. Which explains the clueless bad reviews from younger reviewers who have no patience for a good developing plot. Glad to finally see it played on cable. Until recently, I have never found it available on any premium channels till lately. But I noticed it has shown up on Comcast these past few weeks. Plot is totally original. Humans are taken to this experimental Ship to help save a dying Alien race. Only to find out they are too different from us to help save themselves from their fate...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I am missing something here
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    shankh-sarkar
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Whenever in doubt, I have always treated IMDb's rating as a benchmark before deciding if it was worth my while watching a particular movie . If it's above 7.5 , its on. So despite my initial doubts while skimming through the movie on vlc, I decided to watch it solely because it was rated 7.7. And here's what I realized; that I wanted the last couple of hours of my life back. The plot of the movie failed to account for the crucial element of suspension of disbelief. At no point could I convince myself that what was playing on the screen was even remotely feasible. The old philosophical adage, "Nothing comes from nothing" kept repeating itself in my head as the characters played out their superhuman capabilities. Comparisons with "The Matrix" are inevitable because of the similar theme of their being a chosen one but The Matrix beats The Dark City hands down because of its superior graphics, tight knit plot and superb storytelling. I ain't gonna bother raising my doubts because there are far too many of them and none of them can be answered satisfactorily even after accounting for cinematic liberty. So for those of you that dig the movie, I really am missing something here and glad for it too.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Finding our humanity
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    hall895
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dark City begins with an opening voice-over narration which basically gives the whole plot away. Fans of the film hated this and in a later cut of the film the narration was removed. It does seem logical that a movie which has so many mysterious elements shouldn't reveal all its secrets in the first thirty seconds. But in this case the narration probably served the film well. Because what is going on in this film is very weird, exceedingly bizarre and not particularly easy to comprehend unless you have some solid base of initial knowledge to fall back on. And there are still enough twists, turns and impactful surprises to make the film very compelling. Giving the audience a little help at the beginning paid off. Otherwise by the time the film finally fully revealed itself many people may have been too lost, too confused, too frustrated to appreciate what they had seen. And there is so much to appreciate. It also must be said that having the story laid out in such detail early on allows the audience to accept that story much easier. It is a story which requires tremendous leaps of faith. Without sufficient grounding the story may ultimately have proved to be just too strange for many people to take. Even with so many of its secrets given away right at the start the story still manages to grab you. A man wakes up in a bathtub. He can't seem to remember anything. His forehead is bleeding. There's a dead woman on the floor. And then the phone rings, someone tells him he needs to run away now because they are coming to get him. Who are "they"? Who knows? Anyway, the man flees and the movie kicks into high gear very quickly. The man is John Murdoch. Or is he? It becomes clear very quickly that nothing in this city is exactly what it seems. John Murdoch is not the only person here with vanished memories. He doesn't really know who he is. Nobody does. But nobody besides John realizes anything is amiss. It is up to him to unravel the mystery. What he discovers will shock both him and us. The film packs quite a dramatic punch and raises serious questions about humanity. What makes us human? This film's mysterious Strangers need to know the answer to that question. It is the Strangers who drive the plot. They can manipulate the physical environment of the city, creating new buildings and changing the form of existing ones in mere moments with just the power of their minds. And yet none of the humans ever notice anything has changed. And it is not just the buildings the Strangers change, they have a rather insidious, invasive way of changing the people themselves. Then the Strangers sit back and see what happens. The humans, unknowingly, are their lab rats. John however is resistant to the efforts of the Strangers. Not only that he apparently shares their powers. With the help of a police detective he sets out to find the truth and to give the citizens of the city back their humanity, give them back a sense of who they really are. Rufus Sewell does very well with the challenging role of John Murdoch, a man who does not know who he is. Sewell captures the original bewilderment well and then grows with the character as John finds the strength and determination to put an end to whatever is going on here. William Hurt plays the detective who ends up assisting John, Jennifer Connelly plays John's wife. They both end up very confused and Hurt and Connelly give very good performances as their characters try to figure out what the heck is going on here. Richard O'Brien is appropriately creepy playing the film's most prominent Stranger. Perhaps the only misstep comes from Kiefer Sutherland playing a doctor mixed up in the activities of the Strangers. Sutherland plays the role with a stammer which becomes distracting and annoying very quickly. It's a little bit of weirdness the film didn't need, it adds nothing to the character and the film's plenty weird enough already. But that quibble aside the film generally works very well. It is a fascinating, intriguing, thought-provoking story. Visually the film looks spectacular with wonderful set design and brilliantly executed effects. Perhaps the film goes a little overboard with the effects near the end. The story gets somewhat left behind as things wrap up with a big visual effects blowout. You can't help but think this very smart film deserved a little bit smarter of an ending. But the film ultimately is more than satisfying enough. It entertains you and it also makes you think which is always a good combination. Dark City's story is a very complex web to weave your way through, having had a little guidance at the start surely couldn't have hurt. And when you get to the end you'll look back and be grateful for the long, strange, fascinating trip the film took you on.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I don't get the fuss
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Fluke_Skywalker
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For most of its running time it sort of plays like an extended 'Twilight Zone' episode, and It hooked me well enough. I wanted to know what was happening and why... for a while, at least. Then I just got bored. When the pieces of the puzzle finally do come together, it's quite a let down. And then, after 90 minutes of dull neo-noir mystery, it turned on a dime with a tonally incongruous smack-down finale that did little to re-ignite my interest. There's some nifty stuff in there, and I can see its influence on more recentand much betterwork, but I just can't see what all the hubbub is about with 'Dark City'.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Welcome To Shell Beach.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dark City D/C Dark City is directed by Alex Proyas who also co-writes the screenplay with Leon Dobbs and David S. Goyer. It stars Rufus Sewell, William Hurt, Jennifer Connelly, Kiefer Sutherland, Richard O'Brien and Ian Richardson. Music is by Trevor Jones and cinematography by Dariusz Wolski. A man wakes up in a grotty hotel bathroom and upon finding a dead girl in another room he realises he has no recollection of who he is or how he got there... There's a lot of Blade Runner fans still out there waiting for that film's sexual partner to happen along. What many of them don't realise is that Alex Proyas has already made that movie. More than a cult film yet still criminally ignored in certain circles, Dark City, by way of poor box office and studio interference, never got off to the best of starts. The problems were compounded with the release of The Matrix the following year, where that film's popularity, and its sci-fi linkage to Dark City, led many to think that Proyas' movie was a Matrix rip-off; pushing it further (unjustly) back in the sci-fi noir pantheon. Fact is is that Dark City homages much great cinema from previous years, but it has influenced much that followed, with Inception fans asked to note that Nolan himself was taking notes... Stolen Memories. Dark City is a feverish film noir dressed up in stunning sci-fi clothes. The amazing visuals have led many to state that it's a film with much style and little substance, something which Proyas has fiercely argued against; and he's right to do so, especially once his own preferred director's cut became available to view. The story is a complex one, pulsing with human characters living in a world where there is no daylight, with their respective memories scratchy to say the least, it quickly becomes evident that a creepy alien race are overseeing things. The aliens, wonderfully attired in black trench-coats and hats to match, and aided by Kiefer Sutherland's shifty - stammer affected - doctor, have special powers and their reasons for being here unfold in deftly constructed stages. One man stands in their way, John Murdoch (Sewell), but he is an olde noir amnesia sufferer supreme and his battle to unravel what is going on is our task as well. Do you think about the past much Mrs. Murdoch? The search for identity and the truth is what propels the picture forward. Murdoch in his confused state is not only at the center of an existential dilemma, he's also the focal point for a serial killer murder investigation. This also as he tries to come to terms with matters of the heart, it seems he has a beautiful wife (Connelly), and that she may have cheated on him? And why is he drawn to the place known as Shell Beach? A simple narrative hidden by visual splendours? Don't make me laugh! But hell you have to say the visual look and atmosphere of the design is very much attention grabbing. I have become the monster you were intended to be. With the film noir characters in place; Hurt's dour sleuth, Sewell's amnesiac and Connelly's sultry torch singer, Proyas brings German expressionism in abundance whilst overseeing an eye splintering neo-noir colour palette. Greens and reds often ping from the screen, while the murky browns and golds down on the angular city streets pave the way for changed perceptions and revelations of plotting. There are reoccurring motifs throughout, with swirls and circles integral to mood and meanings, while at the mid-point we then get to see Proyas' tricks of the trade, where the city shifts and moves to create a meeting of Metropolis and Gotham, all as the humans slumber away. Watch those clocks folks... You know how I was supposed to feel. That person isn't me... never was. You wanted to know what it was about us that made us human. Well, you're not going to find it... Acting performances are hardly top of the line (Sutherland especially irritates more than he impresses), but they actually don't need to be, and they all look terrific in their respective dressage. The story is of course bonkers and one which I myself found was much better whilst consuming mucho alcohol! (I watched it three times in 48 hours!) While Proyas himself is on record as saying it's a far from flawless picture. Again he is right, but he also knows that his film is still under valued and in need of more to seek out his director's cut. The late Roger Ebert championed Dark City with much gusto, and he provides very good input on the DVD, much like Roger I have to say, this is a unique and fabulous sci-fi noir experience. A film in fact fit to watch alongside Blade Runner; And I do not say that lightly. 9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Directors Cut is a must
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    hello610
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Fantastic visuals that still looks good even compared to todays standards. I must reiterate, directors cut is a must! The theatrical version has a narration in the start which ruins the mystery. The mystery is what makes us closely follow the main character, John Murdoch, as he tries to piece parts to unveil the past. The Story is very intriguing and keeps the viewer interested through series of events that unveil the truth about the city and the viewer is confronted with questions about the very essence of humanity, and whether our world is really as real as we think. The characters played by Connelley and Sewell are very realistic and convince you that the situation in the movie is very much at hand; their acting is superb and captivating. This movie is spectacular.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A bewildering situation full of questions without answers
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Avid Climber
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dark City is one of those movies that is very difficult to categorized. It makes us experience something truly unique. The good. Extremely imaginative setup. Very dark. Strong intrigue with multiple parts that keeps us guessing for most of the movie. The actors. Rufus Sewell gives us a solid performance as the main confused protagonist, and we feel just like him. On the other hand, as a watcher, it is William Hurt playing the detective who leads our inquiries, trying to understand the mystery as we would. The ever beautiful Jennifer Connelly is adorable in her gentle role. Kiefer Sutherland gives strange ticks to the persona he is playing, making him seem slightly fake. The bad. The green screen shot are poor, and fortunately somewhat rare. The rest of the special effect imperfections can be viewed as "stylish" and more easily absorbed. The final fight is a bit too simple. The ugly. That dying critter near the end that looks almost pixelated. The result. Quite a stupefying ride. Recommended to anyone, especially lovers of strange intrigues.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Underrated Sci Fi Classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    user-35583
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of the great movies of the 90's. It was under-seen on release and has been over- looked ever since. I think it belongs with Blade Runner and 12 Monkees to name a couple of others in a similar vein. I can only guess it was the casting of Rufus Sewell - a then unknown Aussie actor - in the lead role. On the contrary, he is rock solid and owns the role of the confused yet curious protagonist who looks to recovery his memory while trying to solve the murders of which he has been accused. All the while being tracked by the Strangers - a collective of strange "men" that are able to transform the physical world they inhabit. The supporting cast is amazing. WIlliam Hurt, Jennifer Connelly, Kiefer Sutherland and Melissa George among them and all own their roles with aplomb. The set decoration is incredible and still looks stunning on viewing 15 years later. If you haven't seen this, I highly recommend it - especially stunning on Blue Ray.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Phew! My Brain Just Wouldn't Stop Farting!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dalbert Pringle
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For me, the grim and grimy bleakness of Dark City's story was delivered in such a chaotic muddle that it gave me the worst case of brain farts ever experienced from watching any movie since seeing the likes of the ultra-boring Blade Runner. And, after only a short while, just the mere mention of Shell Beach seriously began to grate on my nerves like you wouldn't believe. Dark City certainly didn't even come anywhere near to living up to its potential or its apparent reputation as being a perfect example of a brilliant Sci-Fi/Fantasy story dealing intelligently with such subject matter as "humans-as-guinea-pigs". This film was just silly, comic-book shenanigans that left the viewer less than satisfied with its inevitable outcome. It was very much like being shipwrecked on the shores of Shell Beach. This story's major downfall was that "The Strangers" kept the city with no-name in a state of continual darkness. If they had even the least bit of understanding about humans, they would've realized that we essentially need sunlight for our very survival. (The humans in this story seem to have not realized this, as well) Living in perpetual darkness would mean only severe sickness and surely a quick death for the human race. We, literally, cannot continue to live without relying on the sun as our #1 source of energy. Two things that I found really puzzling about "The Strangers" was that there was only one child amongst the whole lot and that there were absolutely no women, at all. I don't know if this was some sort of an oversight by the screenwriters, or what, but I found it only added even more damaging weight to the overall weakness of Dark City's already seriously floundering story. Of the 4 principal actors who starred in Dark City (Kiefer Sutherland, William Hurt, Rufus Sewell, Jennifer Connelly), I thought that each and every one of their performances to be unacceptably poor and downright mundane. It was the annoying, pig-faced Sutherland, in particular, who was so atrociously despicable as Dr. Schreber that I immediately began to dread every single scene that he happened to appear in. It was he, alone, who brought this movie down a couple of significant notches. Well, about all that I have left to say is - Thank goodness that my brain farts were odorless, otherwise, if they hadn't been, I would have ended up stinking everyone else watching Dark City with me right out of the room.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Still enjoyable, but I can't believe I glossed over the acting & dialogue
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gotmayle
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When this came out it never made much of a splash here, but I loved it as a cult sci-fi movie. Noir and off-beat, some interesting effects and a concept that, whilst not exactly new, was about to be re-done for the Matrix a few short years later. I watched it and re-watched it a numberof times in the early 2000s, but it's been about a decade and I decided to sit down and enjoy it again. How did I ever get past the stodgy acting, corny dialogue and clunky exposition? These are things that I usually don't even become aware of unless someone else points them out? If you haven't seen it, give it a try - it's got lots of merit, but for the most part it seems like the actors are being asked to do long division in their heads while their delivering their lines - that vacant look and lack of emotion just brings the pithy dialogue into focus all the more.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great Sci fi....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pk-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Still one of my all time favorite science fiction movies. Great plot. Great special affects. Acting is top notch... You rarely see such classic sci fi nowadays. Lately, It's all stupid comic book crap like Iron Man, Transformers and Spiderman. Which explains the clueless bad reviews from younger reviewers who have no patience for a good developing plot. Glad to finally see it played on cable. Until recently, I have never found it available on any premium channels till lately. But I noticed it has shown up on Comcast these past few weeks. Plot is totally original. Humans are taken to this experimental Ship to help save a dying Alien race. Only to find out they are too different from us to help save themselves from their fate...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I am missing something here
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    shankh-sarkar
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Whenever in doubt, I have always treated IMDb's rating as a benchmark before deciding if it was worth my while watching a particular movie . If it's above 7.5 , its on. So despite my initial doubts while skimming through the movie on vlc, I decided to watch it solely because it was rated 7.7. And here's what I realized; that I wanted the last couple of hours of my life back. The plot of the movie failed to account for the crucial element of suspension of disbelief. At no point could I convince myself that what was playing on the screen was even remotely feasible. The old philosophical adage, "Nothing comes from nothing" kept repeating itself in my head as the characters played out their superhuman capabilities. Comparisons with "The Matrix" are inevitable because of the similar theme of their being a chosen one but The Matrix beats The Dark City hands down because of its superior graphics, tight knit plot and superb storytelling. I ain't gonna bother raising my doubts because there are far too many of them and none of them can be answered satisfactorily even after accounting for cinematic liberty. So for those of you that dig the movie, I really am missing something here and glad for it too.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Finding our humanity
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    hall895
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dark City begins with an opening voice-over narration which basically gives the whole plot away. Fans of the film hated this and in a later cut of the film the narration was removed. It does seem logical that a movie which has so many mysterious elements shouldn't reveal all its secrets in the first thirty seconds. But in this case the narration probably served the film well. Because what is going on in this film is very weird, exceedingly bizarre and not particularly easy to comprehend unless you have some solid base of initial knowledge to fall back on. And there are still enough twists, turns and impactful surprises to make the film very compelling. Giving the audience a little help at the beginning paid off. Otherwise by the time the film finally fully revealed itself many people may have been too lost, too confused, too frustrated to appreciate what they had seen. And there is so much to appreciate. It also must be said that having the story laid out in such detail early on allows the audience to accept that story much easier. It is a story which requires tremendous leaps of faith. Without sufficient grounding the story may ultimately have proved to be just too strange for many people to take. Even with so many of its secrets given away right at the start the story still manages to grab you. A man wakes up in a bathtub. He can't seem to remember anything. His forehead is bleeding. There's a dead woman on the floor. And then the phone rings, someone tells him he needs to run away now because they are coming to get him. Who are "they"? Who knows? Anyway, the man flees and the movie kicks into high gear very quickly. The man is John Murdoch. Or is he? It becomes clear very quickly that nothing in this city is exactly what it seems. John Murdoch is not the only person here with vanished memories. He doesn't really know who he is. Nobody does. But nobody besides John realizes anything is amiss. It is up to him to unravel the mystery. What he discovers will shock both him and us. The film packs quite a dramatic punch and raises serious questions about humanity. What makes us human? This film's mysterious Strangers need to know the answer to that question. It is the Strangers who drive the plot. They can manipulate the physical environment of the city, creating new buildings and changing the form of existing ones in mere moments with just the power of their minds. And yet none of the humans ever notice anything has changed. And it is not just the buildings the Strangers change, they have a rather insidious, invasive way of changing the people themselves. Then the Strangers sit back and see what happens. The humans, unknowingly, are their lab rats. John however is resistant to the efforts of the Strangers. Not only that he apparently shares their powers. With the help of a police detective he sets out to find the truth and to give the citizens of the city back their humanity, give them back a sense of who they really are. Rufus Sewell does very well with the challenging role of John Murdoch, a man who does not know who he is. Sewell captures the original bewilderment well and then grows with the character as John finds the strength and determination to put an end to whatever is going on here. William Hurt plays the detective who ends up assisting John, Jennifer Connelly plays John's wife. They both end up very confused and Hurt and Connelly give very good performances as their characters try to figure out what the heck is going on here. Richard O'Brien is appropriately creepy playing the film's most prominent Stranger. Perhaps the only misstep comes from Kiefer Sutherland playing a doctor mixed up in the activities of the Strangers. Sutherland plays the role with a stammer which becomes distracting and annoying very quickly. It's a little bit of weirdness the film didn't need, it adds nothing to the character and the film's plenty weird enough already. But that quibble aside the film generally works very well. It is a fascinating, intriguing, thought-provoking story. Visually the film looks spectacular with wonderful set design and brilliantly executed effects. Perhaps the film goes a little overboard with the effects near the end. The story gets somewhat left behind as things wrap up with a big visual effects blowout. You can't help but think this very smart film deserved a little bit smarter of an ending. But the film ultimately is more than satisfying enough. It entertains you and it also makes you think which is always a good combination. Dark City's story is a very complex web to weave your way through, having had a little guidance at the start surely couldn't have hurt. And when you get to the end you'll look back and be grateful for the long, strange, fascinating trip the film took you on.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I don't get the fuss
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Fluke_Skywalker
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For most of its running time it sort of plays like an extended 'Twilight Zone' episode, and It hooked me well enough. I wanted to know what was happening and why... for a while, at least. Then I just got bored. When the pieces of the puzzle finally do come together, it's quite a let down. And then, after 90 minutes of dull neo-noir mystery, it turned on a dime with a tonally incongruous smack-down finale that did little to re-ignite my interest. There's some nifty stuff in there, and I can see its influence on more recentand much betterwork, but I just can't see what all the hubbub is about with 'Dark City'.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Welcome To Shell Beach.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dark City D/C Dark City is directed by Alex Proyas who also co-writes the screenplay with Leon Dobbs and David S. Goyer. It stars Rufus Sewell, William Hurt, Jennifer Connelly, Kiefer Sutherland, Richard O'Brien and Ian Richardson. Music is by Trevor Jones and cinematography by Dariusz Wolski. A man wakes up in a grotty hotel bathroom and upon finding a dead girl in another room he realises he has no recollection of who he is or how he got there... There's a lot of Blade Runner fans still out there waiting for that film's sexual partner to happen along. What many of them don't realise is that Alex Proyas has already made that movie. More than a cult film yet still criminally ignored in certain circles, Dark City, by way of poor box office and studio interference, never got off to the best of starts. The problems were compounded with the release of The Matrix the following year, where that film's popularity, and its sci-fi linkage to Dark City, led many to think that Proyas' movie was a Matrix rip-off; pushing it further (unjustly) back in the sci-fi noir pantheon. Fact is is that Dark City homages much great cinema from previous years, but it has influenced much that followed, with Inception fans asked to note that Nolan himself was taking notes... Stolen Memories. Dark City is a feverish film noir dressed up in stunning sci-fi clothes. The amazing visuals have led many to state that it's a film with much style and little substance, something which Proyas has fiercely argued against; and he's right to do so, especially once his own preferred director's cut became available to view. The story is a complex one, pulsing with human characters living in a world where there is no daylight, with their respective memories scratchy to say the least, it quickly becomes evident that a creepy alien race are overseeing things. The aliens, wonderfully attired in black trench-coats and hats to match, and aided by Kiefer Sutherland's shifty - stammer affected - doctor, have special powers and their reasons for being here unfold in deftly constructed stages. One man stands in their way, John Murdoch (Sewell), but he is an olde noir amnesia sufferer supreme and his battle to unravel what is going on is our task as well. Do you think about the past much Mrs. Murdoch? The search for identity and the truth is what propels the picture forward. Murdoch in his confused state is not only at the center of an existential dilemma, he's also the focal point for a serial killer murder investigation. This also as he tries to come to terms with matters of the heart, it seems he has a beautiful wife (Connelly), and that she may have cheated on him? And why is he drawn to the place known as Shell Beach? A simple narrative hidden by visual splendours? Don't make me laugh! But hell you have to say the visual look and atmosphere of the design is very much attention grabbing. I have become the monster you were intended to be. With the film noir characters in place; Hurt's dour sleuth, Sewell's amnesiac and Connelly's sultry torch singer, Proyas brings German expressionism in abundance whilst overseeing an eye splintering neo-noir colour palette. Greens and reds often ping from the screen, while the murky browns and golds down on the angular city streets pave the way for changed perceptions and revelations of plotting. There are reoccurring motifs throughout, with swirls and circles integral to mood and meanings, while at the mid-point we then get to see Proyas' tricks of the trade, where the city shifts and moves to create a meeting of Metropolis and Gotham, all as the humans slumber away. Watch those clocks folks... You know how I was supposed to feel. That person isn't me... never was. You wanted to know what it was about us that made us human. Well, you're not going to find it... Acting performances are hardly top of the line (Sutherland especially irritates more than he impresses), but they actually don't need to be, and they all look terrific in their respective dressage. The story is of course bonkers and one which I myself found was much better whilst consuming mucho alcohol! (I watched it three times in 48 hours!) While Proyas himself is on record as saying it's a far from flawless picture. Again he is right, but he also knows that his film is still under valued and in need of more to seek out his director's cut. The late Roger Ebert championed Dark City with much gusto, and he provides very good input on the DVD, much like Roger I have to say, this is a unique and fabulous sci-fi noir experience. A film in fact fit to watch alongside Blade Runner; And I do not say that lightly. 9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Directors Cut is a must
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    hello610
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Fantastic visuals that still looks good even compared to todays standards. I must reiterate, directors cut is a must! The theatrical version has a narration in the start which ruins the mystery. The mystery is what makes us closely follow the main character, John Murdoch, as he tries to piece parts to unveil the past. The Story is very intriguing and keeps the viewer interested through series of events that unveil the truth about the city and the viewer is confronted with questions about the very essence of humanity, and whether our world is really as real as we think. The characters played by Connelley and Sewell are very realistic and convince you that the situation in the movie is very much at hand; their acting is superb and captivating. This movie is spectacular.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A bewildering situation full of questions without answers
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Avid Climber
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dark City is one of those movies that is very difficult to categorized. It makes us experience something truly unique. The good. Extremely imaginative setup. Very dark. Strong intrigue with multiple parts that keeps us guessing for most of the movie. The actors. Rufus Sewell gives us a solid performance as the main confused protagonist, and we feel just like him. On the other hand, as a watcher, it is William Hurt playing the detective who leads our inquiries, trying to understand the mystery as we would. The ever beautiful Jennifer Connelly is adorable in her gentle role. Kiefer Sutherland gives strange ticks to the persona he is playing, making him seem slightly fake. The bad. The green screen shot are poor, and fortunately somewhat rare. The rest of the special effect imperfections can be viewed as "stylish" and more easily absorbed. The final fight is a bit too simple. The ugly. That dying critter near the end that looks almost pixelated. The result. Quite a stupefying ride. Recommended to anyone, especially lovers of strange intrigues.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Underrated Sci Fi Classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    user-35583
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of the great movies of the 90's. It was under-seen on release and has been over- looked ever since. I think it belongs with Blade Runner and 12 Monkees to name a couple of others in a similar vein. I can only guess it was the casting of Rufus Sewell - a then unknown Aussie actor - in the lead role. On the contrary, he is rock solid and owns the role of the confused yet curious protagonist who looks to recovery his memory while trying to solve the murders of which he has been accused. All the while being tracked by the Strangers - a collective of strange "men" that are able to transform the physical world they inhabit. The supporting cast is amazing. WIlliam Hurt, Jennifer Connelly, Kiefer Sutherland and Melissa George among them and all own their roles with aplomb. The set decoration is incredible and still looks stunning on viewing 15 years later. If you haven't seen this, I highly recommend it - especially stunning on Blue Ray.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Phew! My Brain Just Wouldn't Stop Farting!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dalbert Pringle
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For me, the grim and grimy bleakness of Dark City's story was delivered in such a chaotic muddle that it gave me the worst case of brain farts ever experienced from watching any movie since seeing the likes of the ultra-boring Blade Runner. And, after only a short while, just the mere mention of Shell Beach seriously began to grate on my nerves like you wouldn't believe. Dark City certainly didn't even come anywhere near to living up to its potential or its apparent reputation as being a perfect example of a brilliant Sci-Fi/Fantasy story dealing intelligently with such subject matter as "humans-as-guinea-pigs". This film was just silly, comic-book shenanigans that left the viewer less than satisfied with its inevitable outcome. It was very much like being shipwrecked on the shores of Shell Beach. This story's major downfall was that "The Strangers" kept the city with no-name in a state of continual darkness. If they had even the least bit of understanding about humans, they would've realized that we essentially need sunlight for our very survival. (The humans in this story seem to have not realized this, as well) Living in perpetual darkness would mean only severe sickness and surely a quick death for the human race. We, literally, cannot continue to live without relying on the sun as our #1 source of energy. Two things that I found really puzzling about "The Strangers" was that there was only one child amongst the whole lot and that there were absolutely no women, at all. I don't know if this was some sort of an oversight by the screenwriters, or what, but I found it only added even more damaging weight to the overall weakness of Dark City's already seriously floundering story. Of the 4 principal actors who starred in Dark City (Kiefer Sutherland, William Hurt, Rufus Sewell, Jennifer Connelly), I thought that each and every one of their performances to be unacceptably poor and downright mundane. It was the annoying, pig-faced Sutherland, in particular, who was so atrociously despicable as Dr. Schreber that I immediately began to dread every single scene that he happened to appear in. It was he, alone, who brought this movie down a couple of significant notches. Well, about all that I have left to say is - Thank goodness that my brain farts were odorless, otherwise, if they hadn't been, I would have ended up stinking everyone else watching Dark City with me right out of the room.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Still enjoyable, but I can't believe I glossed over the acting & dialogue
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gotmayle
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When this came out it never made much of a splash here, but I loved it as a cult sci-fi movie. Noir and off-beat, some interesting effects and a concept that, whilst not exactly new, was about to be re-done for the Matrix a few short years later. I watched it and re-watched it a numberof times in the early 2000s, but it's been about a decade and I decided to sit down and enjoy it again. How did I ever get past the stodgy acting, corny dialogue and clunky exposition? These are things that I usually don't even become aware of unless someone else points them out? If you haven't seen it, give it a try - it's got lots of merit, but for the most part it seems like the actors are being asked to do long division in their heads while their delivering their lines - that vacant look and lack of emotion just brings the pithy dialogue into focus all the more.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great Sci fi....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pk-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Still one of my all time favorite science fiction movies. Great plot. Great special affects. Acting is top notch... You rarely see such classic sci fi nowadays. Lately, It's all stupid comic book crap like Iron Man, Transformers and Spiderman. Which explains the clueless bad reviews from younger reviewers who have no patience for a good developing plot. Glad to finally see it played on cable. Until recently, I have never found it available on any premium channels till lately. But I noticed it has shown up on Comcast these past few weeks. Plot is totally original. Humans are taken to this experimental Ship to help save a dying Alien race. Only to find out they are too different from us to help save themselves from their fate...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I am missing something here
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    shankh-sarkar
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Whenever in doubt, I have always treated IMDb's rating as a benchmark before deciding if it was worth my while watching a particular movie . If it's above 7.5 , its on. So despite my initial doubts while skimming through the movie on vlc, I decided to watch it solely because it was rated 7.7. And here's what I realized; that I wanted the last couple of hours of my life back. The plot of the movie failed to account for the crucial element of suspension of disbelief. At no point could I convince myself that what was playing on the screen was even remotely feasible. The old philosophical adage, "Nothing comes from nothing" kept repeating itself in my head as the characters played out their superhuman capabilities. Comparisons with "The Matrix" are inevitable because of the similar theme of their being a chosen one but The Matrix beats The Dark City hands down because of its superior graphics, tight knit plot and superb storytelling. I ain't gonna bother raising my doubts because there are far too many of them and none of them can be answered satisfactorily even after accounting for cinematic liberty. So for those of you that dig the movie, I really am missing something here and glad for it too.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Finding our humanity
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    hall895
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dark City begins with an opening voice-over narration which basically gives the whole plot away. Fans of the film hated this and in a later cut of the film the narration was removed. It does seem logical that a movie which has so many mysterious elements shouldn't reveal all its secrets in the first thirty seconds. But in this case the narration probably served the film well. Because what is going on in this film is very weird, exceedingly bizarre and not particularly easy to comprehend unless you have some solid base of initial knowledge to fall back on. And there are still enough twists, turns and impactful surprises to make the film very compelling. Giving the audience a little help at the beginning paid off. Otherwise by the time the film finally fully revealed itself many people may have been too lost, too confused, too frustrated to appreciate what they had seen. And there is so much to appreciate. It also must be said that having the story laid out in such detail early on allows the audience to accept that story much easier. It is a story which requires tremendous leaps of faith. Without sufficient grounding the story may ultimately have proved to be just too strange for many people to take. Even with so many of its secrets given away right at the start the story still manages to grab you. A man wakes up in a bathtub. He can't seem to remember anything. His forehead is bleeding. There's a dead woman on the floor. And then the phone rings, someone tells him he needs to run away now because they are coming to get him. Who are "they"? Who knows? Anyway, the man flees and the movie kicks into high gear very quickly. The man is John Murdoch. Or is he? It becomes clear very quickly that nothing in this city is exactly what it seems. John Murdoch is not the only person here with vanished memories. He doesn't really know who he is. Nobody does. But nobody besides John realizes anything is amiss. It is up to him to unravel the mystery. What he discovers will shock both him and us. The film packs quite a dramatic punch and raises serious questions about humanity. What makes us human? This film's mysterious Strangers need to know the answer to that question. It is the Strangers who drive the plot. They can manipulate the physical environment of the city, creating new buildings and changing the form of existing ones in mere moments with just the power of their minds. And yet none of the humans ever notice anything has changed. And it is not just the buildings the Strangers change, they have a rather insidious, invasive way of changing the people themselves. Then the Strangers sit back and see what happens. The humans, unknowingly, are their lab rats. John however is resistant to the efforts of the Strangers. Not only that he apparently shares their powers. With the help of a police detective he sets out to find the truth and to give the citizens of the city back their humanity, give them back a sense of who they really are. Rufus Sewell does very well with the challenging role of John Murdoch, a man who does not know who he is. Sewell captures the original bewilderment well and then grows with the character as John finds the strength and determination to put an end to whatever is going on here. William Hurt plays the detective who ends up assisting John, Jennifer Connelly plays John's wife. They both end up very confused and Hurt and Connelly give very good performances as their characters try to figure out what the heck is going on here. Richard O'Brien is appropriately creepy playing the film's most prominent Stranger. Perhaps the only misstep comes from Kiefer Sutherland playing a doctor mixed up in the activities of the Strangers. Sutherland plays the role with a stammer which becomes distracting and annoying very quickly. It's a little bit of weirdness the film didn't need, it adds nothing to the character and the film's plenty weird enough already. But that quibble aside the film generally works very well. It is a fascinating, intriguing, thought-provoking story. Visually the film looks spectacular with wonderful set design and brilliantly executed effects. Perhaps the film goes a little overboard with the effects near the end. The story gets somewhat left behind as things wrap up with a big visual effects blowout. You can't help but think this very smart film deserved a little bit smarter of an ending. But the film ultimately is more than satisfying enough. It entertains you and it also makes you think which is always a good combination. Dark City's story is a very complex web to weave your way through, having had a little guidance at the start surely couldn't have hurt. And when you get to the end you'll look back and be grateful for the long, strange, fascinating trip the film took you on.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I don't get the fuss
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Fluke_Skywalker
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For most of its running time it sort of plays like an extended 'Twilight Zone' episode, and It hooked me well enough. I wanted to know what was happening and why... for a while, at least. Then I just got bored. When the pieces of the puzzle finally do come together, it's quite a let down. And then, after 90 minutes of dull neo-noir mystery, it turned on a dime with a tonally incongruous smack-down finale that did little to re-ignite my interest. There's some nifty stuff in there, and I can see its influence on more recentand much betterwork, but I just can't see what all the hubbub is about with 'Dark City'.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Welcome To Shell Beach.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dark City D/C Dark City is directed by Alex Proyas who also co-writes the screenplay with Leon Dobbs and David S. Goyer. It stars Rufus Sewell, William Hurt, Jennifer Connelly, Kiefer Sutherland, Richard O'Brien and Ian Richardson. Music is by Trevor Jones and cinematography by Dariusz Wolski. A man wakes up in a grotty hotel bathroom and upon finding a dead girl in another room he realises he has no recollection of who he is or how he got there... There's a lot of Blade Runner fans still out there waiting for that film's sexual partner to happen along. What many of them don't realise is that Alex Proyas has already made that movie. More than a cult film yet still criminally ignored in certain circles, Dark City, by way of poor box office and studio interference, never got off to the best of starts. The problems were compounded with the release of The Matrix the following year, where that film's popularity, and its sci-fi linkage to Dark City, led many to think that Proyas' movie was a Matrix rip-off; pushing it further (unjustly) back in the sci-fi noir pantheon. Fact is is that Dark City homages much great cinema from previous years, but it has influenced much that followed, with Inception fans asked to note that Nolan himself was taking notes... Stolen Memories. Dark City is a feverish film noir dressed up in stunning sci-fi clothes. The amazing visuals have led many to state that it's a film with much style and little substance, something which Proyas has fiercely argued against; and he's right to do so, especially once his own preferred director's cut became available to view. The story is a complex one, pulsing with human characters living in a world where there is no daylight, with their respective memories scratchy to say the least, it quickly becomes evident that a creepy alien race are overseeing things. The aliens, wonderfully attired in black trench-coats and hats to match, and aided by Kiefer Sutherland's shifty - stammer affected - doctor, have special powers and their reasons for being here unfold in deftly constructed stages. One man stands in their way, John Murdoch (Sewell), but he is an olde noir amnesia sufferer supreme and his battle to unravel what is going on is our task as well. Do you think about the past much Mrs. Murdoch? The search for identity and the truth is what propels the picture forward. Murdoch in his confused state is not only at the center of an existential dilemma, he's also the focal point for a serial killer murder investigation. This also as he tries to come to terms with matters of the heart, it seems he has a beautiful wife (Connelly), and that she may have cheated on him? And why is he drawn to the place known as Shell Beach? A simple narrative hidden by visual splendours? Don't make me laugh! But hell you have to say the visual look and atmosphere of the design is very much attention grabbing. I have become the monster you were intended to be. With the film noir characters in place; Hurt's dour sleuth, Sewell's amnesiac and Connelly's sultry torch singer, Proyas brings German expressionism in abundance whilst overseeing an eye splintering neo-noir colour palette. Greens and reds often ping from the screen, while the murky browns and golds down on the angular city streets pave the way for changed perceptions and revelations of plotting. There are reoccurring motifs throughout, with swirls and circles integral to mood and meanings, while at the mid-point we then get to see Proyas' tricks of the trade, where the city shifts and moves to create a meeting of Metropolis and Gotham, all as the humans slumber away. Watch those clocks folks... You know how I was supposed to feel. That person isn't me... never was. You wanted to know what it was about us that made us human. Well, you're not going to find it... Acting performances are hardly top of the line (Sutherland especially irritates more than he impresses), but they actually don't need to be, and they all look terrific in their respective dressage. The story is of course bonkers and one which I myself found was much better whilst consuming mucho alcohol! (I watched it three times in 48 hours!) While Proyas himself is on record as saying it's a far from flawless picture. Again he is right, but he also knows that his film is still under valued and in need of more to seek out his director's cut. The late Roger Ebert championed Dark City with much gusto, and he provides very good input on the DVD, much like Roger I have to say, this is a unique and fabulous sci-fi noir experience. A film in fact fit to watch alongside Blade Runner; And I do not say that lightly. 9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Directors Cut is a must
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    hello610
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Fantastic visuals that still looks good even compared to todays standards. I must reiterate, directors cut is a must! The theatrical version has a narration in the start which ruins the mystery. The mystery is what makes us closely follow the main character, John Murdoch, as he tries to piece parts to unveil the past. The Story is very intriguing and keeps the viewer interested through series of events that unveil the truth about the city and the viewer is confronted with questions about the very essence of humanity, and whether our world is really as real as we think. The characters played by Connelley and Sewell are very realistic and convince you that the situation in the movie is very much at hand; their acting is superb and captivating. This movie is spectacular.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A bewildering situation full of questions without answers
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Avid Climber
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dark City is one of those movies that is very difficult to categorized. It makes us experience something truly unique. The good. Extremely imaginative setup. Very dark. Strong intrigue with multiple parts that keeps us guessing for most of the movie. The actors. Rufus Sewell gives us a solid performance as the main confused protagonist, and we feel just like him. On the other hand, as a watcher, it is William Hurt playing the detective who leads our inquiries, trying to understand the mystery as we would. The ever beautiful Jennifer Connelly is adorable in her gentle role. Kiefer Sutherland gives strange ticks to the persona he is playing, making him seem slightly fake. The bad. The green screen shot are poor, and fortunately somewhat rare. The rest of the special effect imperfections can be viewed as "stylish" and more easily absorbed. The final fight is a bit too simple. The ugly. That dying critter near the end that looks almost pixelated. The result. Quite a stupefying ride. Recommended to anyone, especially lovers of strange intrigues.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Underrated Sci Fi Classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    user-35583
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of the great movies of the 90's. It was under-seen on release and has been over- looked ever since. I think it belongs with Blade Runner and 12 Monkees to name a couple of others in a similar vein. I can only guess it was the casting of Rufus Sewell - a then unknown Aussie actor - in the lead role. On the contrary, he is rock solid and owns the role of the confused yet curious protagonist who looks to recovery his memory while trying to solve the murders of which he has been accused. All the while being tracked by the Strangers - a collective of strange "men" that are able to transform the physical world they inhabit. The supporting cast is amazing. WIlliam Hurt, Jennifer Connelly, Kiefer Sutherland and Melissa George among them and all own their roles with aplomb. The set decoration is incredible and still looks stunning on viewing 15 years later. If you haven't seen this, I highly recommend it - especially stunning on Blue Ray.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Phew! My Brain Just Wouldn't Stop Farting!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dalbert Pringle
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For me, the grim and grimy bleakness of Dark City's story was delivered in such a chaotic muddle that it gave me the worst case of brain farts ever experienced from watching any movie since seeing the likes of the ultra-boring Blade Runner. And, after only a short while, just the mere mention of Shell Beach seriously began to grate on my nerves like you wouldn't believe. Dark City certainly didn't even come anywhere near to living up to its potential or its apparent reputation as being a perfect example of a brilliant Sci-Fi/Fantasy story dealing intelligently with such subject matter as "humans-as-guinea-pigs". This film was just silly, comic-book shenanigans that left the viewer less than satisfied with its inevitable outcome. It was very much like being shipwrecked on the shores of Shell Beach. This story's major downfall was that "The Strangers" kept the city with no-name in a state of continual darkness. If they had even the least bit of understanding about humans, they would've realized that we essentially need sunlight for our very survival. (The humans in this story seem to have not realized this, as well) Living in perpetual darkness would mean only severe sickness and surely a quick death for the human race. We, literally, cannot continue to live without relying on the sun as our #1 source of energy. Two things that I found really puzzling about "The Strangers" was that there was only one child amongst the whole lot and that there were absolutely no women, at all. I don't know if this was some sort of an oversight by the screenwriters, or what, but I found it only added even more damaging weight to the overall weakness of Dark City's already seriously floundering story. Of the 4 principal actors who starred in Dark City (Kiefer Sutherland, William Hurt, Rufus Sewell, Jennifer Connelly), I thought that each and every one of their performances to be unacceptably poor and downright mundane. It was the annoying, pig-faced Sutherland, in particular, who was so atrociously despicable as Dr. Schreber that I immediately began to dread every single scene that he happened to appear in. It was he, alone, who brought this movie down a couple of significant notches. Well, about all that I have left to say is - Thank goodness that my brain farts were odorless, otherwise, if they hadn't been, I would have ended up stinking everyone else watching Dark City with me right out of the room.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Still enjoyable, but I can't believe I glossed over the acting & dialogue
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gotmayle
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When this came out it never made much of a splash here, but I loved it as a cult sci-fi movie. Noir and off-beat, some interesting effects and a concept that, whilst not exactly new, was about to be re-done for the Matrix a few short years later. I watched it and re-watched it a numberof times in the early 2000s, but it's been about a decade and I decided to sit down and enjoy it again. How did I ever get past the stodgy acting, corny dialogue and clunky exposition? These are things that I usually don't even become aware of unless someone else points them out? If you haven't seen it, give it a try - it's got lots of merit, but for the most part it seems like the actors are being asked to do long division in their heads while their delivering their lines - that vacant look and lack of emotion just brings the pithy dialogue into focus all the more.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great Sci fi....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pk-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Still one of my all time favorite science fiction movies. Great plot. Great special affects. Acting is top notch... You rarely see such classic sci fi nowadays. Lately, It's all stupid comic book crap like Iron Man, Transformers and Spiderman. Which explains the clueless bad reviews from younger reviewers who have no patience for a good developing plot. Glad to finally see it played on cable. Until recently, I have never found it available on any premium channels till lately. But I noticed it has shown up on Comcast these past few weeks. Plot is totally original. Humans are taken to this experimental Ship to help save a dying Alien race. Only to find out they are too different from us to help save themselves from their fate...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I am missing something here
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    shankh-sarkar
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Whenever in doubt, I have always treated IMDb's rating as a benchmark before deciding if it was worth my while watching a particular movie . If it's above 7.5 , its on. So despite my initial doubts while skimming through the movie on vlc, I decided to watch it solely because it was rated 7.7. And here's what I realized; that I wanted the last couple of hours of my life back. The plot of the movie failed to account for the crucial element of suspension of disbelief. At no point could I convince myself that what was playing on the screen was even remotely feasible. The old philosophical adage, "Nothing comes from nothing" kept repeating itself in my head as the characters played out their superhuman capabilities. Comparisons with "The Matrix" are inevitable because of the similar theme of their being a chosen one but The Matrix beats The Dark City hands down because of its superior graphics, tight knit plot and superb storytelling. I ain't gonna bother raising my doubts because there are far too many of them and none of them can be answered satisfactorily even after accounting for cinematic liberty. So for those of you that dig the movie, I really am missing something here and glad for it too.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Finding our humanity
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    hall895
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dark City begins with an opening voice-over narration which basically gives the whole plot away. Fans of the film hated this and in a later cut of the film the narration was removed. It does seem logical that a movie which has so many mysterious elements shouldn't reveal all its secrets in the first thirty seconds. But in this case the narration probably served the film well. Because what is going on in this film is very weird, exceedingly bizarre and not particularly easy to comprehend unless you have some solid base of initial knowledge to fall back on. And there are still enough twists, turns and impactful surprises to make the film very compelling. Giving the audience a little help at the beginning paid off. Otherwise by the time the film finally fully revealed itself many people may have been too lost, too confused, too frustrated to appreciate what they had seen. And there is so much to appreciate. It also must be said that having the story laid out in such detail early on allows the audience to accept that story much easier. It is a story which requires tremendous leaps of faith. Without sufficient grounding the story may ultimately have proved to be just too strange for many people to take. Even with so many of its secrets given away right at the start the story still manages to grab you. A man wakes up in a bathtub. He can't seem to remember anything. His forehead is bleeding. There's a dead woman on the floor. And then the phone rings, someone tells him he needs to run away now because they are coming to get him. Who are "they"? Who knows? Anyway, the man flees and the movie kicks into high gear very quickly. The man is John Murdoch. Or is he? It becomes clear very quickly that nothing in this city is exactly what it seems. John Murdoch is not the only person here with vanished memories. He doesn't really know who he is. Nobody does. But nobody besides John realizes anything is amiss. It is up to him to unravel the mystery. What he discovers will shock both him and us. The film packs quite a dramatic punch and raises serious questions about humanity. What makes us human? This film's mysterious Strangers need to know the answer to that question. It is the Strangers who drive the plot. They can manipulate the physical environment of the city, creating new buildings and changing the form of existing ones in mere moments with just the power of their minds. And yet none of the humans ever notice anything has changed. And it is not just the buildings the Strangers change, they have a rather insidious, invasive way of changing the people themselves. Then the Strangers sit back and see what happens. The humans, unknowingly, are their lab rats. John however is resistant to the efforts of the Strangers. Not only that he apparently shares their powers. With the help of a police detective he sets out to find the truth and to give the citizens of the city back their humanity, give them back a sense of who they really are. Rufus Sewell does very well with the challenging role of John Murdoch, a man who does not know who he is. Sewell captures the original bewilderment well and then grows with the character as John finds the strength and determination to put an end to whatever is going on here. William Hurt plays the detective who ends up assisting John, Jennifer Connelly plays John's wife. They both end up very confused and Hurt and Connelly give very good performances as their characters try to figure out what the heck is going on here. Richard O'Brien is appropriately creepy playing the film's most prominent Stranger. Perhaps the only misstep comes from Kiefer Sutherland playing a doctor mixed up in the activities of the Strangers. Sutherland plays the role with a stammer which becomes distracting and annoying very quickly. It's a little bit of weirdness the film didn't need, it adds nothing to the character and the film's plenty weird enough already. But that quibble aside the film generally works very well. It is a fascinating, intriguing, thought-provoking story. Visually the film looks spectacular with wonderful set design and brilliantly executed effects. Perhaps the film goes a little overboard with the effects near the end. The story gets somewhat left behind as things wrap up with a big visual effects blowout. You can't help but think this very smart film deserved a little bit smarter of an ending. But the film ultimately is more than satisfying enough. It entertains you and it also makes you think which is always a good combination. Dark City's story is a very complex web to weave your way through, having had a little guidance at the start surely couldn't have hurt. And when you get to the end you'll look back and be grateful for the long, strange, fascinating trip the film took you on.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I don't get the fuss
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Fluke_Skywalker
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For most of its running time it sort of plays like an extended 'Twilight Zone' episode, and It hooked me well enough. I wanted to know what was happening and why... for a while, at least. Then I just got bored. When the pieces of the puzzle finally do come together, it's quite a let down. And then, after 90 minutes of dull neo-noir mystery, it turned on a dime with a tonally incongruous smack-down finale that did little to re-ignite my interest. There's some nifty stuff in there, and I can see its influence on more recentand much betterwork, but I just can't see what all the hubbub is about with 'Dark City'.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Welcome To Shell Beach.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dark City D/C Dark City is directed by Alex Proyas who also co-writes the screenplay with Leon Dobbs and David S. Goyer. It stars Rufus Sewell, William Hurt, Jennifer Connelly, Kiefer Sutherland, Richard O'Brien and Ian Richardson. Music is by Trevor Jones and cinematography by Dariusz Wolski. A man wakes up in a grotty hotel bathroom and upon finding a dead girl in another room he realises he has no recollection of who he is or how he got there... There's a lot of Blade Runner fans still out there waiting for that film's sexual partner to happen along. What many of them don't realise is that Alex Proyas has already made that movie. More than a cult film yet still criminally ignored in certain circles, Dark City, by way of poor box office and studio interference, never got off to the best of starts. The problems were compounded with the release of The Matrix the following year, where that film's popularity, and its sci-fi linkage to Dark City, led many to think that Proyas' movie was a Matrix rip-off; pushing it further (unjustly) back in the sci-fi noir pantheon. Fact is is that Dark City homages much great cinema from previous years, but it has influenced much that followed, with Inception fans asked to note that Nolan himself was taking notes... Stolen Memories. Dark City is a feverish film noir dressed up in stunning sci-fi clothes. The amazing visuals have led many to state that it's a film with much style and little substance, something which Proyas has fiercely argued against; and he's right to do so, especially once his own preferred director's cut became available to view. The story is a complex one, pulsing with human characters living in a world where there is no daylight, with their respective memories scratchy to say the least, it quickly becomes evident that a creepy alien race are overseeing things. The aliens, wonderfully attired in black trench-coats and hats to match, and aided by Kiefer Sutherland's shifty - stammer affected - doctor, have special powers and their reasons for being here unfold in deftly constructed stages. One man stands in their way, John Murdoch (Sewell), but he is an olde noir amnesia sufferer supreme and his battle to unravel what is going on is our task as well. Do you think about the past much Mrs. Murdoch? The search for identity and the truth is what propels the picture forward. Murdoch in his confused state is not only at the center of an existential dilemma, he's also the focal point for a serial killer murder investigation. This also as he tries to come to terms with matters of the heart, it seems he has a beautiful wife (Connelly), and that she may have cheated on him? And why is he drawn to the place known as Shell Beach? A simple narrative hidden by visual splendours? Don't make me laugh! But hell you have to say the visual look and atmosphere of the design is very much attention grabbing. I have become the monster you were intended to be. With the film noir characters in place; Hurt's dour sleuth, Sewell's amnesiac and Connelly's sultry torch singer, Proyas brings German expressionism in abundance whilst overseeing an eye splintering neo-noir colour palette. Greens and reds often ping from the screen, while the murky browns and golds down on the angular city streets pave the way for changed perceptions and revelations of plotting. There are reoccurring motifs throughout, with swirls and circles integral to mood and meanings, while at the mid-point we then get to see Proyas' tricks of the trade, where the city shifts and moves to create a meeting of Metropolis and Gotham, all as the humans slumber away. Watch those clocks folks... You know how I was supposed to feel. That person isn't me... never was. You wanted to know what it was about us that made us human. Well, you're not going to find it... Acting performances are hardly top of the line (Sutherland especially irritates more than he impresses), but they actually don't need to be, and they all look terrific in their respective dressage. The story is of course bonkers and one which I myself found was much better whilst consuming mucho alcohol! (I watched it three times in 48 hours!) While Proyas himself is on record as saying it's a far from flawless picture. Again he is right, but he also knows that his film is still under valued and in need of more to seek out his director's cut. The late Roger Ebert championed Dark City with much gusto, and he provides very good input on the DVD, much like Roger I have to say, this is a unique and fabulous sci-fi noir experience. A film in fact fit to watch alongside Blade Runner; And I do not say that lightly. 9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Directors Cut is a must
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    hello610
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Fantastic visuals that still looks good even compared to todays standards. I must reiterate, directors cut is a must! The theatrical version has a narration in the start which ruins the mystery. The mystery is what makes us closely follow the main character, John Murdoch, as he tries to piece parts to unveil the past. The Story is very intriguing and keeps the viewer interested through series of events that unveil the truth about the city and the viewer is confronted with questions about the very essence of humanity, and whether our world is really as real as we think. The characters played by Connelley and Sewell are very realistic and convince you that the situation in the movie is very much at hand; their acting is superb and captivating. This movie is spectacular.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A bewildering situation full of questions without answers
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Avid Climber
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dark City is one of those movies that is very difficult to categorized. It makes us experience something truly unique. The good. Extremely imaginative setup. Very dark. Strong intrigue with multiple parts that keeps us guessing for most of the movie. The actors. Rufus Sewell gives us a solid performance as the main confused protagonist, and we feel just like him. On the other hand, as a watcher, it is William Hurt playing the detective who leads our inquiries, trying to understand the mystery as we would. The ever beautiful Jennifer Connelly is adorable in her gentle role. Kiefer Sutherland gives strange ticks to the persona he is playing, making him seem slightly fake. The bad. The green screen shot are poor, and fortunately somewhat rare. The rest of the special effect imperfections can be viewed as "stylish" and more easily absorbed. The final fight is a bit too simple. The ugly. That dying critter near the end that looks almost pixelated. The result. Quite a stupefying ride. Recommended to anyone, especially lovers of strange intrigues.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Underrated Sci Fi Classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    user-35583
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of the great movies of the 90's. It was under-seen on release and has been over- looked ever since. I think it belongs with Blade Runner and 12 Monkees to name a couple of others in a similar vein. I can only guess it was the casting of Rufus Sewell - a then unknown Aussie actor - in the lead role. On the contrary, he is rock solid and owns the role of the confused yet curious protagonist who looks to recovery his memory while trying to solve the murders of which he has been accused. All the while being tracked by the Strangers - a collective of strange "men" that are able to transform the physical world they inhabit. The supporting cast is amazing. WIlliam Hurt, Jennifer Connelly, Kiefer Sutherland and Melissa George among them and all own their roles with aplomb. The set decoration is incredible and still looks stunning on viewing 15 years later. If you haven't seen this, I highly recommend it - especially stunning on Blue Ray.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Phew! My Brain Just Wouldn't Stop Farting!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dalbert Pringle
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For me, the grim and grimy bleakness of Dark City's story was delivered in such a chaotic muddle that it gave me the worst case of brain farts ever experienced from watching any movie since seeing the likes of the ultra-boring Blade Runner. And, after only a short while, just the mere mention of Shell Beach seriously began to grate on my nerves like you wouldn't believe. Dark City certainly didn't even come anywhere near to living up to its potential or its apparent reputation as being a perfect example of a brilliant Sci-Fi/Fantasy story dealing intelligently with such subject matter as "humans-as-guinea-pigs". This film was just silly, comic-book shenanigans that left the viewer less than satisfied with its inevitable outcome. It was very much like being shipwrecked on the shores of Shell Beach. This story's major downfall was that "The Strangers" kept the city with no-name in a state of continual darkness. If they had even the least bit of understanding about humans, they would've realized that we essentially need sunlight for our very survival. (The humans in this story seem to have not realized this, as well) Living in perpetual darkness would mean only severe sickness and surely a quick death for the human race. We, literally, cannot continue to live without relying on the sun as our #1 source of energy. Two things that I found really puzzling about "The Strangers" was that there was only one child amongst the whole lot and that there were absolutely no women, at all. I don't know if this was some sort of an oversight by the screenwriters, or what, but I found it only added even more damaging weight to the overall weakness of Dark City's already seriously floundering story. Of the 4 principal actors who starred in Dark City (Kiefer Sutherland, William Hurt, Rufus Sewell, Jennifer Connelly), I thought that each and every one of their performances to be unacceptably poor and downright mundane. It was the annoying, pig-faced Sutherland, in particular, who was so atrociously despicable as Dr. Schreber that I immediately began to dread every single scene that he happened to appear in. It was he, alone, who brought this movie down a couple of significant notches. Well, about all that I have left to say is - Thank goodness that my brain farts were odorless, otherwise, if they hadn't been, I would have ended up stinking everyone else watching Dark City with me right out of the room.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Still enjoyable, but I can't believe I glossed over the acting & dialogue
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gotmayle
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When this came out it never made much of a splash here, but I loved it as a cult sci-fi movie. Noir and off-beat, some interesting effects and a concept that, whilst not exactly new, was about to be re-done for the Matrix a few short years later. I watched it and re-watched it a numberof times in the early 2000s, but it's been about a decade and I decided to sit down and enjoy it again. How did I ever get past the stodgy acting, corny dialogue and clunky exposition? These are things that I usually don't even become aware of unless someone else points them out? If you haven't seen it, give it a try - it's got lots of merit, but for the most part it seems like the actors are being asked to do long division in their heads while their delivering their lines - that vacant look and lack of emotion just brings the pithy dialogue into focus all the more.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great Sci fi....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pk-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Still one of my all time favorite science fiction movies. Great plot. Great special affects. Acting is top notch... You rarely see such classic sci fi nowadays. Lately, It's all stupid comic book crap like Iron Man, Transformers and Spiderman. Which explains the clueless bad reviews from younger reviewers who have no patience for a good developing plot. Glad to finally see it played on cable. Until recently, I have never found it available on any premium channels till lately. But I noticed it has shown up on Comcast these past few weeks. Plot is totally original. Humans are taken to this experimental Ship to help save a dying Alien race. Only to find out they are too different from us to help save themselves from their fate...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I am missing something here
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    shankh-sarkar
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Whenever in doubt, I have always treated IMDb's rating as a benchmark before deciding if it was worth my while watching a particular movie . If it's above 7.5 , its on. So despite my initial doubts while skimming through the movie on vlc, I decided to watch it solely because it was rated 7.7. And here's what I realized; that I wanted the last couple of hours of my life back. The plot of the movie failed to account for the crucial element of suspension of disbelief. At no point could I convince myself that what was playing on the screen was even remotely feasible. The old philosophical adage, "Nothing comes from nothing" kept repeating itself in my head as the characters played out their superhuman capabilities. Comparisons with "The Matrix" are inevitable because of the similar theme of their being a chosen one but The Matrix beats The Dark City hands down because of its superior graphics, tight knit plot and superb storytelling. I ain't gonna bother raising my doubts because there are far too many of them and none of them can be answered satisfactorily even after accounting for cinematic liberty. So for those of you that dig the movie, I really am missing something here and glad for it too.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Finding our humanity
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    hall895
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dark City begins with an opening voice-over narration which basically gives the whole plot away. Fans of the film hated this and in a later cut of the film the narration was removed. It does seem logical that a movie which has so many mysterious elements shouldn't reveal all its secrets in the first thirty seconds. But in this case the narration probably served the film well. Because what is going on in this film is very weird, exceedingly bizarre and not particularly easy to comprehend unless you have some solid base of initial knowledge to fall back on. And there are still enough twists, turns and impactful surprises to make the film very compelling. Giving the audience a little help at the beginning paid off. Otherwise by the time the film finally fully revealed itself many people may have been too lost, too confused, too frustrated to appreciate what they had seen. And there is so much to appreciate. It also must be said that having the story laid out in such detail early on allows the audience to accept that story much easier. It is a story which requires tremendous leaps of faith. Without sufficient grounding the story may ultimately have proved to be just too strange for many people to take. Even with so many of its secrets given away right at the start the story still manages to grab you. A man wakes up in a bathtub. He can't seem to remember anything. His forehead is bleeding. There's a dead woman on the floor. And then the phone rings, someone tells him he needs to run away now because they are coming to get him. Who are "they"? Who knows? Anyway, the man flees and the movie kicks into high gear very quickly. The man is John Murdoch. Or is he? It becomes clear very quickly that nothing in this city is exactly what it seems. John Murdoch is not the only person here with vanished memories. He doesn't really know who he is. Nobody does. But nobody besides John realizes anything is amiss. It is up to him to unravel the mystery. What he discovers will shock both him and us. The film packs quite a dramatic punch and raises serious questions about humanity. What makes us human? This film's mysterious Strangers need to know the answer to that question. It is the Strangers who drive the plot. They can manipulate the physical environment of the city, creating new buildings and changing the form of existing ones in mere moments with just the power of their minds. And yet none of the humans ever notice anything has changed. And it is not just the buildings the Strangers change, they have a rather insidious, invasive way of changing the people themselves. Then the Strangers sit back and see what happens. The humans, unknowingly, are their lab rats. John however is resistant to the efforts of the Strangers. Not only that he apparently shares their powers. With the help of a police detective he sets out to find the truth and to give the citizens of the city back their humanity, give them back a sense of who they really are. Rufus Sewell does very well with the challenging role of John Murdoch, a man who does not know who he is. Sewell captures the original bewilderment well and then grows with the character as John finds the strength and determination to put an end to whatever is going on here. William Hurt plays the detective who ends up assisting John, Jennifer Connelly plays John's wife. They both end up very confused and Hurt and Connelly give very good performances as their characters try to figure out what the heck is going on here. Richard O'Brien is appropriately creepy playing the film's most prominent Stranger. Perhaps the only misstep comes from Kiefer Sutherland playing a doctor mixed up in the activities of the Strangers. Sutherland plays the role with a stammer which becomes distracting and annoying very quickly. It's a little bit of weirdness the film didn't need, it adds nothing to the character and the film's plenty weird enough already. But that quibble aside the film generally works very well. It is a fascinating, intriguing, thought-provoking story. Visually the film looks spectacular with wonderful set design and brilliantly executed effects. Perhaps the film goes a little overboard with the effects near the end. The story gets somewhat left behind as things wrap up with a big visual effects blowout. You can't help but think this very smart film deserved a little bit smarter of an ending. But the film ultimately is more than satisfying enough. It entertains you and it also makes you think which is always a good combination. Dark City's story is a very complex web to weave your way through, having had a little guidance at the start surely couldn't have hurt. And when you get to the end you'll look back and be grateful for the long, strange, fascinating trip the film took you on.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I don't get the fuss
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Fluke_Skywalker
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For most of its running time it sort of plays like an extended 'Twilight Zone' episode, and It hooked me well enough. I wanted to know what was happening and why... for a while, at least. Then I just got bored. When the pieces of the puzzle finally do come together, it's quite a let down. And then, after 90 minutes of dull neo-noir mystery, it turned on a dime with a tonally incongruous smack-down finale that did little to re-ignite my interest. There's some nifty stuff in there, and I can see its influence on more recentand much betterwork, but I just can't see what all the hubbub is about with 'Dark City'.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Welcome To Shell Beach.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dark City D/C Dark City is directed by Alex Proyas who also co-writes the screenplay with Leon Dobbs and David S. Goyer. It stars Rufus Sewell, William Hurt, Jennifer Connelly, Kiefer Sutherland, Richard O'Brien and Ian Richardson. Music is by Trevor Jones and cinematography by Dariusz Wolski. A man wakes up in a grotty hotel bathroom and upon finding a dead girl in another room he realises he has no recollection of who he is or how he got there... There's a lot of Blade Runner fans still out there waiting for that film's sexual partner to happen along. What many of them don't realise is that Alex Proyas has already made that movie. More than a cult film yet still criminally ignored in certain circles, Dark City, by way of poor box office and studio interference, never got off to the best of starts. The problems were compounded with the release of The Matrix the following year, where that film's popularity, and its sci-fi linkage to Dark City, led many to think that Proyas' movie was a Matrix rip-off; pushing it further (unjustly) back in the sci-fi noir pantheon. Fact is is that Dark City homages much great cinema from previous years, but it has influenced much that followed, with Inception fans asked to note that Nolan himself was taking notes... Stolen Memories. Dark City is a feverish film noir dressed up in stunning sci-fi clothes. The amazing visuals have led many to state that it's a film with much style and little substance, something which Proyas has fiercely argued against; and he's right to do so, especially once his own preferred director's cut became available to view. The story is a complex one, pulsing with human characters living in a world where there is no daylight, with their respective memories scratchy to say the least, it quickly becomes evident that a creepy alien race are overseeing things. The aliens, wonderfully attired in black trench-coats and hats to match, and aided by Kiefer Sutherland's shifty - stammer affected - doctor, have special powers and their reasons for being here unfold in deftly constructed stages. One man stands in their way, John Murdoch (Sewell), but he is an olde noir amnesia sufferer supreme and his battle to unravel what is going on is our task as well. Do you think about the past much Mrs. Murdoch? The search for identity and the truth is what propels the picture forward. Murdoch in his confused state is not only at the center of an existential dilemma, he's also the focal point for a serial killer murder investigation. This also as he tries to come to terms with matters of the heart, it seems he has a beautiful wife (Connelly), and that she may have cheated on him? And why is he drawn to the place known as Shell Beach? A simple narrative hidden by visual splendours? Don't make me laugh! But hell you have to say the visual look and atmosphere of the design is very much attention grabbing. I have become the monster you were intended to be. With the film noir characters in place; Hurt's dour sleuth, Sewell's amnesiac and Connelly's sultry torch singer, Proyas brings German expressionism in abundance whilst overseeing an eye splintering neo-noir colour palette. Greens and reds often ping from the screen, while the murky browns and golds down on the angular city streets pave the way for changed perceptions and revelations of plotting. There are reoccurring motifs throughout, with swirls and circles integral to mood and meanings, while at the mid-point we then get to see Proyas' tricks of the trade, where the city shifts and moves to create a meeting of Metropolis and Gotham, all as the humans slumber away. Watch those clocks folks... You know how I was supposed to feel. That person isn't me... never was. You wanted to know what it was about us that made us human. Well, you're not going to find it... Acting performances are hardly top of the line (Sutherland especially irritates more than he impresses), but they actually don't need to be, and they all look terrific in their respective dressage. The story is of course bonkers and one which I myself found was much better whilst consuming mucho alcohol! (I watched it three times in 48 hours!) While Proyas himself is on record as saying it's a far from flawless picture. Again he is right, but he also knows that his film is still under valued and in need of more to seek out his director's cut. The late Roger Ebert championed Dark City with much gusto, and he provides very good input on the DVD, much like Roger I have to say, this is a unique and fabulous sci-fi noir experience. A film in fact fit to watch alongside Blade Runner; And I do not say that lightly. 9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Directors Cut is a must
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    hello610
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Fantastic visuals that still looks good even compared to todays standards. I must reiterate, directors cut is a must! The theatrical version has a narration in the start which ruins the mystery. The mystery is what makes us closely follow the main character, John Murdoch, as he tries to piece parts to unveil the past. The Story is very intriguing and keeps the viewer interested through series of events that unveil the truth about the city and the viewer is confronted with questions about the very essence of humanity, and whether our world is really as real as we think. The characters played by Connelley and Sewell are very realistic and convince you that the situation in the movie is very much at hand; their acting is superb and captivating. This movie is spectacular.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A bewildering situation full of questions without answers
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Avid Climber
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dark City is one of those movies that is very difficult to categorized. It makes us experience something truly unique. The good. Extremely imaginative setup. Very dark. Strong intrigue with multiple parts that keeps us guessing for most of the movie. The actors. Rufus Sewell gives us a solid performance as the main confused protagonist, and we feel just like him. On the other hand, as a watcher, it is William Hurt playing the detective who leads our inquiries, trying to understand the mystery as we would. The ever beautiful Jennifer Connelly is adorable in her gentle role. Kiefer Sutherland gives strange ticks to the persona he is playing, making him seem slightly fake. The bad. The green screen shot are poor, and fortunately somewhat rare. The rest of the special effect imperfections can be viewed as "stylish" and more easily absorbed. The final fight is a bit too simple. The ugly. That dying critter near the end that looks almost pixelated. The result. Quite a stupefying ride. Recommended to anyone, especially lovers of strange intrigues.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Underrated Sci Fi Classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    user-35583
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of the great movies of the 90's. It was under-seen on release and has been over- looked ever since. I think it belongs with Blade Runner and 12 Monkees to name a couple of others in a similar vein. I can only guess it was the casting of Rufus Sewell - a then unknown Aussie actor - in the lead role. On the contrary, he is rock solid and owns the role of the confused yet curious protagonist who looks to recovery his memory while trying to solve the murders of which he has been accused. All the while being tracked by the Strangers - a collective of strange "men" that are able to transform the physical world they inhabit. The supporting cast is amazing. WIlliam Hurt, Jennifer Connelly, Kiefer Sutherland and Melissa George among them and all own their roles with aplomb. The set decoration is incredible and still looks stunning on viewing 15 years later. If you haven't seen this, I highly recommend it - especially stunning on Blue Ray.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Phew! My Brain Just Wouldn't Stop Farting!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dalbert Pringle
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For me, the grim and grimy bleakness of Dark City's story was delivered in such a chaotic muddle that it gave me the worst case of brain farts ever experienced from watching any movie since seeing the likes of the ultra-boring Blade Runner. And, after only a short while, just the mere mention of Shell Beach seriously began to grate on my nerves like you wouldn't believe. Dark City certainly didn't even come anywhere near to living up to its potential or its apparent reputation as being a perfect example of a brilliant Sci-Fi/Fantasy story dealing intelligently with such subject matter as "humans-as-guinea-pigs". This film was just silly, comic-book shenanigans that left the viewer less than satisfied with its inevitable outcome. It was very much like being shipwrecked on the shores of Shell Beach. This story's major downfall was that "The Strangers" kept the city with no-name in a state of continual darkness. If they had even the least bit of understanding about humans, they would've realized that we essentially need sunlight for our very survival. (The humans in this story seem to have not realized this, as well) Living in perpetual darkness would mean only severe sickness and surely a quick death for the human race. We, literally, cannot continue to live without relying on the sun as our #1 source of energy. Two things that I found really puzzling about "The Strangers" was that there was only one child amongst the whole lot and that there were absolutely no women, at all. I don't know if this was some sort of an oversight by the screenwriters, or what, but I found it only added even more damaging weight to the overall weakness of Dark City's already seriously floundering story. Of the 4 principal actors who starred in Dark City (Kiefer Sutherland, William Hurt, Rufus Sewell, Jennifer Connelly), I thought that each and every one of their performances to be unacceptably poor and downright mundane. It was the annoying, pig-faced Sutherland, in particular, who was so atrociously despicable as Dr. Schreber that I immediately began to dread every single scene that he happened to appear in. It was he, alone, who brought this movie down a couple of significant notches. Well, about all that I have left to say is - Thank goodness that my brain farts were odorless, otherwise, if they hadn't been, I would have ended up stinking everyone else watching Dark City with me right out of the room.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Still enjoyable, but I can't believe I glossed over the acting & dialogue
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gotmayle
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When this came out it never made much of a splash here, but I loved it as a cult sci-fi movie. Noir and off-beat, some interesting effects and a concept that, whilst not exactly new, was about to be re-done for the Matrix a few short years later. I watched it and re-watched it a numberof times in the early 2000s, but it's been about a decade and I decided to sit down and enjoy it again. How did I ever get past the stodgy acting, corny dialogue and clunky exposition? These are things that I usually don't even become aware of unless someone else points them out? If you haven't seen it, give it a try - it's got lots of merit, but for the most part it seems like the actors are being asked to do long division in their heads while their delivering their lines - that vacant look and lack of emotion just brings the pithy dialogue into focus all the more.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great Sci fi....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pk-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Still one of my all time favorite science fiction movies. Great plot. Great special affects. Acting is top notch... You rarely see such classic sci fi nowadays. Lately, It's all stupid comic book crap like Iron Man, Transformers and Spiderman. Which explains the clueless bad reviews from younger reviewers who have no patience for a good developing plot. Glad to finally see it played on cable. Until recently, I have never found it available on any premium channels till lately. But I noticed it has shown up on Comcast these past few weeks. Plot is totally original. Humans are taken to this experimental Ship to help save a dying Alien race. Only to find out they are too different from us to help save themselves from their fate...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I am missing something here
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    shankh-sarkar
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Whenever in doubt, I have always treated IMDb's rating as a benchmark before deciding if it was worth my while watching a particular movie . If it's above 7.5 , its on. So despite my initial doubts while skimming through the movie on vlc, I decided to watch it solely because it was rated 7.7. And here's what I realized; that I wanted the last couple of hours of my life back. The plot of the movie failed to account for the crucial element of suspension of disbelief. At no point could I convince myself that what was playing on the screen was even remotely feasible. The old philosophical adage, "Nothing comes from nothing" kept repeating itself in my head as the characters played out their superhuman capabilities. Comparisons with "The Matrix" are inevitable because of the similar theme of their being a chosen one but The Matrix beats The Dark City hands down because of its superior graphics, tight knit plot and superb storytelling. I ain't gonna bother raising my doubts because there are far too many of them and none of them can be answered satisfactorily even after accounting for cinematic liberty. So for those of you that dig the movie, I really am missing something here and glad for it too.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Finding our humanity
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    hall895
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dark City begins with an opening voice-over narration which basically gives the whole plot away. Fans of the film hated this and in a later cut of the film the narration was removed. It does seem logical that a movie which has so many mysterious elements shouldn't reveal all its secrets in the first thirty seconds. But in this case the narration probably served the film well. Because what is going on in this film is very weird, exceedingly bizarre and not particularly easy to comprehend unless you have some solid base of initial knowledge to fall back on. And there are still enough twists, turns and impactful surprises to make the film very compelling. Giving the audience a little help at the beginning paid off. Otherwise by the time the film finally fully revealed itself many people may have been too lost, too confused, too frustrated to appreciate what they had seen. And there is so much to appreciate. It also must be said that having the story laid out in such detail early on allows the audience to accept that story much easier. It is a story which requires tremendous leaps of faith. Without sufficient grounding the story may ultimately have proved to be just too strange for many people to take. Even with so many of its secrets given away right at the start the story still manages to grab you. A man wakes up in a bathtub. He can't seem to remember anything. His forehead is bleeding. There's a dead woman on the floor. And then the phone rings, someone tells him he needs to run away now because they are coming to get him. Who are "they"? Who knows? Anyway, the man flees and the movie kicks into high gear very quickly. The man is John Murdoch. Or is he? It becomes clear very quickly that nothing in this city is exactly what it seems. John Murdoch is not the only person here with vanished memories. He doesn't really know who he is. Nobody does. But nobody besides John realizes anything is amiss. It is up to him to unravel the mystery. What he discovers will shock both him and us. The film packs quite a dramatic punch and raises serious questions about humanity. What makes us human? This film's mysterious Strangers need to know the answer to that question. It is the Strangers who drive the plot. They can manipulate the physical environment of the city, creating new buildings and changing the form of existing ones in mere moments with just the power of their minds. And yet none of the humans ever notice anything has changed. And it is not just the buildings the Strangers change, they have a rather insidious, invasive way of changing the people themselves. Then the Strangers sit back and see what happens. The humans, unknowingly, are their lab rats. John however is resistant to the efforts of the Strangers. Not only that he apparently shares their powers. With the help of a police detective he sets out to find the truth and to give the citizens of the city back their humanity, give them back a sense of who they really are. Rufus Sewell does very well with the challenging role of John Murdoch, a man who does not know who he is. Sewell captures the original bewilderment well and then grows with the character as John finds the strength and determination to put an end to whatever is going on here. William Hurt plays the detective who ends up assisting John, Jennifer Connelly plays John's wife. They both end up very confused and Hurt and Connelly give very good performances as their characters try to figure out what the heck is going on here. Richard O'Brien is appropriately creepy playing the film's most prominent Stranger. Perhaps the only misstep comes from Kiefer Sutherland playing a doctor mixed up in the activities of the Strangers. Sutherland plays the role with a stammer which becomes distracting and annoying very quickly. It's a little bit of weirdness the film didn't need, it adds nothing to the character and the film's plenty weird enough already. But that quibble aside the film generally works very well. It is a fascinating, intriguing, thought-provoking story. Visually the film looks spectacular with wonderful set design and brilliantly executed effects. Perhaps the film goes a little overboard with the effects near the end. The story gets somewhat left behind as things wrap up with a big visual effects blowout. You can't help but think this very smart film deserved a little bit smarter of an ending. But the film ultimately is more than satisfying enough. It entertains you and it also makes you think which is always a good combination. Dark City's story is a very complex web to weave your way through, having had a little guidance at the start surely couldn't have hurt. And when you get to the end you'll look back and be grateful for the long, strange, fascinating trip the film took you on.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I don't get the fuss
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Fluke_Skywalker
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For most of its running time it sort of plays like an extended 'Twilight Zone' episode, and It hooked me well enough. I wanted to know what was happening and why... for a while, at least. Then I just got bored. When the pieces of the puzzle finally do come together, it's quite a let down. And then, after 90 minutes of dull neo-noir mystery, it turned on a dime with a tonally incongruous smack-down finale that did little to re-ignite my interest. There's some nifty stuff in there, and I can see its influence on more recentand much betterwork, but I just can't see what all the hubbub is about with 'Dark City'.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Welcome To Shell Beach.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JohnRouseMerriottChard
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dark City D/C Dark City is directed by Alex Proyas who also co-writes the screenplay with Leon Dobbs and David S. Goyer. It stars Rufus Sewell, William Hurt, Jennifer Connelly, Kiefer Sutherland, Richard O'Brien and Ian Richardson. Music is by Trevor Jones and cinematography by Dariusz Wolski. A man wakes up in a grotty hotel bathroom and upon finding a dead girl in another room he realises he has no recollection of who he is or how he got there... There's a lot of Blade Runner fans still out there waiting for that film's sexual partner to happen along. What many of them don't realise is that Alex Proyas has already made that movie. More than a cult film yet still criminally ignored in certain circles, Dark City, by way of poor box office and studio interference, never got off to the best of starts. The problems were compounded with the release of The Matrix the following year, where that film's popularity, and its sci-fi linkage to Dark City, led many to think that Proyas' movie was a Matrix rip-off; pushing it further (unjustly) back in the sci-fi noir pantheon. Fact is is that Dark City homages much great cinema from previous years, but it has influenced much that followed, with Inception fans asked to note that Nolan himself was taking notes... Stolen Memories. Dark City is a feverish film noir dressed up in stunning sci-fi clothes. The amazing visuals have led many to state that it's a film with much style and little substance, something which Proyas has fiercely argued against; and he's right to do so, especially once his own preferred director's cut became available to view. The story is a complex one, pulsing with human characters living in a world where there is no daylight, with their respective memories scratchy to say the least, it quickly becomes evident that a creepy alien race are overseeing things. The aliens, wonderfully attired in black trench-coats and hats to match, and aided by Kiefer Sutherland's shifty - stammer affected - doctor, have special powers and their reasons for being here unfold in deftly constructed stages. One man stands in their way, John Murdoch (Sewell), but he is an olde noir amnesia sufferer supreme and his battle to unravel what is going on is our task as well. Do you think about the past much Mrs. Murdoch? The search for identity and the truth is what propels the picture forward. Murdoch in his confused state is not only at the center of an existential dilemma, he's also the focal point for a serial killer murder investigation. This also as he tries to come to terms with matters of the heart, it seems he has a beautiful wife (Connelly), and that she may have cheated on him? And why is he drawn to the place known as Shell Beach? A simple narrative hidden by visual splendours? Don't make me laugh! But hell you have to say the visual look and atmosphere of the design is very much attention grabbing. I have become the monster you were intended to be. With the film noir characters in place; Hurt's dour sleuth, Sewell's amnesiac and Connelly's sultry torch singer, Proyas brings German expressionism in abundance whilst overseeing an eye splintering neo-noir colour palette. Greens and reds often ping from the screen, while the murky browns and golds down on the angular city streets pave the way for changed perceptions and revelations of plotting. There are reoccurring motifs throughout, with swirls and circles integral to mood and meanings, while at the mid-point we then get to see Proyas' tricks of the trade, where the city shifts and moves to create a meeting of Metropolis and Gotham, all as the humans slumber away. Watch those clocks folks... You know how I was supposed to feel. That person isn't me... never was. You wanted to know what it was about us that made us human. Well, you're not going to find it... Acting performances are hardly top of the line (Sutherland especially irritates more than he impresses), but they actually don't need to be, and they all look terrific in their respective dressage. The story is of course bonkers and one which I myself found was much better whilst consuming mucho alcohol! (I watched it three times in 48 hours!) While Proyas himself is on record as saying it's a far from flawless picture. Again he is right, but he also knows that his film is still under valued and in need of more to seek out his director's cut. The late Roger Ebert championed Dark City with much gusto, and he provides very good input on the DVD, much like Roger I have to say, this is a unique and fabulous sci-fi noir experience. A film in fact fit to watch alongside Blade Runner; And I do not say that lightly. 9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Directors Cut is a must
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    hello610
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Fantastic visuals that still looks good even compared to todays standards. I must reiterate, directors cut is a must! The theatrical version has a narration in the start which ruins the mystery. The mystery is what makes us closely follow the main character, John Murdoch, as he tries to piece parts to unveil the past. The Story is very intriguing and keeps the viewer interested through series of events that unveil the truth about the city and the viewer is confronted with questions about the very essence of humanity, and whether our world is really as real as we think. The characters played by Connelley and Sewell are very realistic and convince you that the situation in the movie is very much at hand; their acting is superb and captivating. This movie is spectacular.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A bewildering situation full of questions without answers
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Avid Climber
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dark City is one of those movies that is very difficult to categorized. It makes us experience something truly unique. The good. Extremely imaginative setup. Very dark. Strong intrigue with multiple parts that keeps us guessing for most of the movie. The actors. Rufus Sewell gives us a solid performance as the main confused protagonist, and we feel just like him. On the other hand, as a watcher, it is William Hurt playing the detective who leads our inquiries, trying to understand the mystery as we would. The ever beautiful Jennifer Connelly is adorable in her gentle role. Kiefer Sutherland gives strange ticks to the persona he is playing, making him seem slightly fake. The bad. The green screen shot are poor, and fortunately somewhat rare. The rest of the special effect imperfections can be viewed as "stylish" and more easily absorbed. The final fight is a bit too simple. The ugly. That dying critter near the end that looks almost pixelated. The result. Quite a stupefying ride. Recommended to anyone, especially lovers of strange intrigues.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Underrated Sci Fi Classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    user-35583
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of the great movies of the 90's. It was under-seen on release and has been over- looked ever since. I think it belongs with Blade Runner and 12 Monkees to name a couple of others in a similar vein. I can only guess it was the casting of Rufus Sewell - a then unknown Aussie actor - in the lead role. On the contrary, he is rock solid and owns the role of the confused yet curious protagonist who looks to recovery his memory while trying to solve the murders of which he has been accused. All the while being tracked by the Strangers - a collective of strange "men" that are able to transform the physical world they inhabit. The supporting cast is amazing. WIlliam Hurt, Jennifer Connelly, Kiefer Sutherland and Melissa George among them and all own their roles with aplomb. The set decoration is incredible and still looks stunning on viewing 15 years later. If you haven't seen this, I highly recommend it - especially stunning on Blue Ray.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Phew! My Brain Just Wouldn't Stop Farting!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dalbert Pringle
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For me, the grim and grimy bleakness of Dark City's story was delivered in such a chaotic muddle that it gave me the worst case of brain farts ever experienced from watching any movie since seeing the likes of the ultra-boring Blade Runner. And, after only a short while, just the mere mention of Shell Beach seriously began to grate on my nerves like you wouldn't believe. Dark City certainly didn't even come anywhere near to living up to its potential or its apparent reputation as being a perfect example of a brilliant Sci-Fi/Fantasy story dealing intelligently with such subject matter as "humans-as-guinea-pigs". This film was just silly, comic-book shenanigans that left the viewer less than satisfied with its inevitable outcome. It was very much like being shipwrecked on the shores of Shell Beach. This story's major downfall was that "The Strangers" kept the city with no-name in a state of continual darkness. If they had even the least bit of understanding about humans, they would've realized that we essentially need sunlight for our very survival. (The humans in this story seem to have not realized this, as well) Living in perpetual darkness would mean only severe sickness and surely a quick death for the human race. We, literally, cannot continue to live without relying on the sun as our #1 source of energy. Two things that I found really puzzling about "The Strangers" was that there was only one child amongst the whole lot and that there were absolutely no women, at all. I don't know if this was some sort of an oversight by the screenwriters, or what, but I found it only added even more damaging weight to the overall weakness of Dark City's already seriously floundering story. Of the 4 principal actors who starred in Dark City (Kiefer Sutherland, William Hurt, Rufus Sewell, Jennifer Connelly), I thought that each and every one of their performances to be unacceptably poor and downright mundane. It was the annoying, pig-faced Sutherland, in particular, who was so atrociously despicable as Dr. Schreber that I immediately began to dread every single scene that he happened to appear in. It was he, alone, who brought this movie down a couple of significant notches. Well, about all that I have left to say is - Thank goodness that my brain farts were odorless, otherwise, if they hadn't been, I would have ended up stinking everyone else watching Dark City with me right out of the room.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Still enjoyable, but I can't believe I glossed over the acting & dialogue
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gotmayle
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When this came out it never made much of a splash here, but I loved it as a cult sci-fi movie. Noir and off-beat, some interesting effects and a concept that, whilst not exactly new, was about to be re-done for the Matrix a few short years later. I watched it and re-watched it a numberof times in the early 2000s, but it's been about a decade and I decided to sit down and enjoy it again. How did I ever get past the stodgy acting, corny dialogue and clunky exposition? These are things that I usually don't even become aware of unless someone else points them out? If you haven't seen it, give it a try - it's got lots of merit, but for the most part it seems like the actors are being asked to do long division in their heads while their delivering their lines - that vacant look and lack of emotion just brings the pithy dialogue into focus all the more.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great Sci fi....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pk-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Still one of my all time favorite science fiction movies. Great plot. Great special affects. Acting is top notch... You rarely see such classic sci fi nowadays. Lately, It's all stupid comic book crap like Iron Man, Transformers and Spiderman. Which explains the clueless bad reviews from younger reviewers who have no patience for a good developing plot. Glad to finally see it played on cable. Until recently, I have never found it available on any premium channels till lately. But I noticed it has shown up on Comcast these past few weeks. Plot is totally original. Humans are taken to this experimental Ship to help save a dying Alien race. Only to find out they are too different from us to help save themselves from their fate...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
