<filme>
 <id>
  693
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0112641
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1995
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Cassino
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  8.2
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Greed, deception, money, power, and murder occur between two mobster best friends and a trophy wife over a gambling empire.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  This Martin Scorsese film depicts the Janus-like quality of Las Vegas--it has a glittering, glamorous face, as well as a brutal, cruel one. Ace Rothstein and Nicky Santoro, mobsters who move to Las Vegas to make their mark, live and work in this paradoxical world. Seen through their eyes, each as a foil to the other, the details of mob involvement in the casinos of the 1970's and '80's are revealed. Ace is the smooth operator of the Tangiers casino, while Nicky is his boyhood friend and tough strongman, robbing and shaking down the locals. However, they each have a tragic flaw--Ace falls in love with a hustler, Ginger, and Nicky falls into an ever-deepening spiral of drugs and violence.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Biography
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Crime
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   casino
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   boyhood friend
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   mafia
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   gambling
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   greed
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Martin Scorsese
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Nicholas Pileggi
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Martin Scorsese
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Robert De Niro
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Sharon Stone
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Joe Pesci
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Though "Casino" is not Scorsese's strongest hour, its vision of what mob-run casinos would be like is creative
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris Mizerak
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After bringing us the outstanding 1990 crime drama GoodFellas, critically acclaimed director Martin Scorsese, author/screenwriter Nicholas Pileggi, and stars Robert DeNiro and Joe Pesci team up again for another crime drama five years later called Casino. What's interesting about Casino is that it's basically GoodFellas all over again only set in Las Vegas. It's a good thing no one came up with the idea of naming this film GoodFellas in Las Vegas, since it would make it all the more obvious to us that they're trying to recreate the same movie. That being said, does the fact that Casino bares countless similarities to GoodFellas make it bad? Not at all, it's simply a way of summarizing the movie in a nutshell. Regardless, let's take a deeper look at what we've got. Casino tells the story of a Mafia member named Sam Rothstein (Robert DeNiro) who is sent to Las Vegas to run a casino funded by the Mafia on behalf of mob families living in the Midwest. His friend Nicky Santoro (Joe Pesci) is also eventually sent to Las Vegas to watch his back. The main reason they are both there is to oversee the casino operations which largely centers on illegal activity. Basically, the Mafia has rigged the casino so that none of the customers win anything, and they make millions of dollars off of their money without the customers knowing a thing about it. Essentially, Sam and Nicky are there to make sure that their "skim" goes according to plan. But all of that changes however when a fellow hustler named Ginger (Sharon Stone) enters their lives and eventually interferes with their business to the point where there's no way they could possibly fix whatever costly mistakes erupt. The first couple minutes of Casino, when we're being introduced to the process of how these Mafia-ruled casinos work, are arguably where the most fascinating part of the entire picture resides. We not only learn that the scamming this casino gets away with on a regular basis is supposedly normal, but we are also given the scary conclusion that wasting money on gambling is the main reason people go to Las Vegas in the first place. It definitely makes people who haven't been to Las Vegas before question whether or not they want to go out of their way to a city in the middle of a desert just to lose vast sums of money. I know that it wouldn't be a town I'd want to go to yet based on what I've seen here. So I thought Casino had a fairly strong introduction based on the kind of world it was introducing us to. The rest of the film was pretty decent with Robert DeNiro and Joe Pesci turning in strong acting just like they did with GoodFellas. However, I felt that most of the main narrative was not as compelling or focused as I wanted it to be. The storytelling simply felt a little fragmented for my taste, and the love story between DeNiro and Stone doesn't help with that either. For the record, I respect that the love story does contribute to the events that take place in the second half of the film. Also, Roger Ebert's comments on how different this love story is compared with the love stories in Martin Scorsese's previous works are justified to a certain degree. Regardless, the love story still didn't do much for me at all and I think a crucial reason for that is Sharon Stone. I don't think I've seen much of her work and the ones that I do recall seeing aside from this film are Total Recall, Basic Instinct, and Antz. In my opinion, from what I've seen, she looks physically great, but her acting is too over-the-top for my liking. I'm having trouble placing my finger on it, but something about her acting just seems inappropriate for the movies she stars in. While I acknowledge that some of her roles including this one require her to be very dramatic, she has the distinction of being too childishly over dramatic that she ends up feeling way out of place in her films, this one included. While I still think Joe Pesci acts out his role reasonably well here, his role is maybe a little too identical to his work in GoodFellas. And although I do feel that the story does lose focus around the halfway point, for some reason, I still find Casino watchable enough for me to recommend it overall. And again, this is mainly because of the theories this film shows us regarding how a mob-run casino would operate. There's a well-directed scene involving the casino managers asking a customer to leave because he is placing his feet on the casino tables. Without revealing too much, the payoff of this scene isn't quite what you'd expect at first. The same thing could be said for another scene involving the casino managers dealing with someone who is maybe having too good a day at their casino. If that scene doesn't scare you off from playing and winning too much at a casino, I don't know what will. If you're looking for a story and characters that will impact you the same way Scorsese's earlier films like GoodFellas did, you might be disappointed by what Casino offers. However, if you're looking for a picture with a fascinating premise that introduces creative theories along the way and will settle for something that is at least watchable, then I think you'll like this film fine enough. As for me, though I don't think Casino ranks among Scorsese's best by a good bit and I probably don't have that much interest in looking at it again, I was satisfied enough with seeing it once. Like Las Vegas itself, approach at your own financial risk.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Casino (1995)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ashish sood (ashistrong@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Casino" is another modern classic from Martin Scorsese. Drawing parallels with his earlier "Goodfellas" , "Casino" again teams Scorsese up with writer Nicholas Pileggi having De Niro & Joe Pesci in lead traditional favourite of Scorsese. The result is a truly engaging tale of mobsters setting up a new gambling empire in Las Vegas and the subsequent ripple effects that involve the local authorities and the police. A joy from beginning to end, "Casino" is an example of a perfect movie. There's nothing you'd want to change about this film. It's full of memorable scenes that are rich with outstanding performances and dialogue and it simply demands a repeat viewing. Casino spans three decades and chronicles the true story of a faction of the mob who ran Las Vegas casinos. Robert De Niro plays Sam Ace Rothstein, a fantastic bookie who is chosen to run the Tangiers hotel and Casino. Along the way, he marries a drug-addicted con-artist trophy wife (Sharon Stone) and struggles with his friendship with loose-cannon Nicky Santoro (Joe Pesci). Rothstein is a complicated figure in that he is not a heavy, yet he wields a lot of power due to the respect he has gained from his mob bosses back home. Robert De Niro and Joe Pesci are both fantastic in their roles, and Sharon Stone actually turned out a non-irritating performance. As the viewer, you can't stand her, but that is the point. Scorsese seems to have several different directing styles, and Casino follows in the tradition of Goodfellas as a pseudo-documentary. A lot of the exposition is revealed by the characters themselves in the form of voice-overs, and several scenes are filmed in documentarian fashion. The entire production however, is sleek and very quick. The use of music bears mentioning as well: Most Martin Scorsese films have an amazing soundtrack that adds to and enhances the scene. Scorsese doesn't just utilize the soundtrack, he makes it part of the storytelling - by the music, we chronologically know what time period we are witnessing, since one cannot rely on other factors, such as fashion alone. One of my favorite scenes in film which effectively involves music is actually from Casino - the very intense scene when the relationship between DeNiro, Stone and Pesci come to a head in the climax of the film. The pounding music cut throughout this scene is a cover of "Satisfaction" by Devo and the result is absolutely brilliant. Being a complete movie buff, I generally don't watch films that feature certain stars, I go to films by certain directors and Scorsese is definitely one of them. The man is a complete genius, and a gift to any movie buff - my suggestion is to watch some of his films, then check out his unbelievable series, "A Personal Journey with Martin Scorsese Through American Movies" which was done the same year as Casino. The series is essentially a primer on the history of film, sectioned off by film genres. You not only will experience his amazing intellect and massive knowledge of film history, but his incredible humility as well. Casino has to be one of the most underrated films that Martin Scorsese directed in the nineties. The acting by the leads is good and the script is excellent. Robert De Niro gave an Oscar worthy performance and Joe Pesci is chilling yet funny again. Even Sharon Stone is good in this brilliant film. My Rating  9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pure entertainment! Pure Scorsese!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MrGadgetman
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you haven't seen this masterpiece yet..., let's just say that you need to re-prioritize your life. It's that good. It has something for everyone. Action, suspense, drama (lots of drama!) gunshots and fist fights, comedy and yes... a love story. It is beautifully shot and captures all the magic and flare of the gambling lifestyle and fast paced environment. It will easily suck you in to the movie and you never once look at your watch to notice that it's nearly 3 hours long. All the characters have substance and a purpose in the film which always gives you something (or someone) to think about while you watch the story unfold. I've seen it several times, own it on disc and still catch myself watching it when it comes on Starz...it's that good.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My Favorite Film of All Time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Film Watchin Fool
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well it doesn't get any better than Casino. The cast, acting, directing, cinematography, music, and story are top notch and it makes for a memorable watch. In my opinion this is Scorsese's best film and could watch it over and over again. It is a great mobster film that follows Ace Rothstein (Deniro) and has many trials and tribulations that comes with trying to run Tangiers Casino for the mob. Don't miss this movie and it is one you should see before you die. Put it on your list of must see movies. If you are interested in more details... Again, it is my favorite film of all time so I am a bit biased. That said, Scorsese entrenches you in Las Vegas and Ace Rothstein's reign of the Tangiers casino. Nicholas Pileggi doesn't put out anything but quality material and him and Scorsese together are like peanut butter and jelly. You can't say enough about Scorsese directing and vision in this film. I can't think of a movie that was better put together and has such a great and natural flow to it. On to the acting and casting, which is nothing short of superb. Robert Deniro is Ace Rothstein and does a fantastic job. It isn't his best work, but you couldn't have found a better actor to play the part. Joe Pesci is outstanding as Nicky Santoro and plays one of the most memorable characters in my recent memory. Sharon Stone is great as Ginger and it is arguably her best work to date. You take all that into account with the supporting cast and you have something special. The movie is lengthy, but everything about it doesn't make it seem so long. I am telling you it will go much faster than the two and half hours that it runs and be impressive the entire way. The directing and cinematography are something to marvel and I don't think it gets any better than this film. I highly recommend this to anyone looking for a outstanding gangster film. This ranks as my favorite film of all time and you won't be disappointed. Email me at filmwatchinfool@gmail.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Long But Dosen't Stop Being Interesting,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dillon Harris
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Casino is a fantastic movie with a very long and detailed storyline that stretches out to nearly three hours but it never stops being interesting and enjoyable.The cast of this movie is all brilliant and inspired,Robert De Niro,Sharon Stone and of course Joe Pesci all deliver very impressive performance,James Woods is also very good in this movie as usual but I was disappointed that he wasn't really in it that much,I thought he would have a much more important role in the movie because i've always found his acting very impressive.My only problem with the movie really is that it could have been less detailed and also,my same problem with Goodfellas,is the fact that they get different characters narrating,it should all revolve around one characters point of view so we can hear their story instead of different peoples point of views.It should have all been Robert De Niro's point of view and not changing it to Joe Pesci at times and some other characters as well.A must see for fans of Martin Scorsese and Robert De Niro movies. Story of Sam Rothstein (Robert De Niro) and Nicky Santoro (Joe Pesci) as they begin running a casino business and let their greed get the best of them.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Greed foils crime
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    StoryCharts
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Casino is tough to analyze with Story Charts. The casino racket plot (along with all the other subplots) all start at their highs and tumble down to failures. The only Controlling Idea I can think of is that crime will always fail because of greed. The Story Chart for Casino is not very interesting, basically everything crumbles because of the characters are up to no good. My main beef with the movie is two fold. One is specific about this movie: why make a movie about crime that fails when no one in the movie does any good at all and there is no moral center to the film? Since everyone is up to no good, the only rational way to keep our attention is to up the ante on how bad the characters become and how cool they when they are being bad.So a film whose central idea is about the inevitable downfall of crime betrays its central idea by making the characters "cool" and full of "attitude" and glorifying them. Seriously why do we need a movie like this? It seems to just perpetuate all the negative stereotypes about movies glorifying violence and bad characters. My second beef is in general about Martin Scorsese. I feel films like Casino and many of his other works are mostly show-and-tells rather than true storytelling by characters, conflict and consequence. This shows through most obviously through the abundant voice overs that tell us how "cool" the characters are and tells us the changes that are happening as opposed to showing us through action and consequence. I think voice overs are the nemesis of absorbing movie making and Casino spends about half its time with its characters voicing over stuff that happens on screen: its like a holiday slide-show from "cool" gangsters. I think Casino tries to objectively document a period of Vegas excess driven by a few characters and their criminal ways. It's voice overs certainly make it documentary-like. But its glorification of how cool these guys subjectively tells us to sympathize with these criminals on their inevitable demise. I don't get it, why make a movie that suggests crime doesn't pay but suggest it's cool to be a criminal? How does this make the world a better place? If it doesn't, why make movies at all? My Story Chart of the movie is at storycharts.ca
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Scorsese at his Top...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Janis Livens
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Casino is a great Scorsese film from the mid 90's and it's in my opinion one his better films up there with Goodfellas and Taxi Driver. It showcases excellent performances, great story and his exceptional eye for visuals. While it run for almost three hours, I was never bored, it never dragged for me and I was completely immersed in the story being told. I agree that Casino should have been shorter and they could have toned the violence slightly down, but end result just doesn't really bother me. It's very engaging, the actors pretty much own the film. giving very strong performances. The reason why Casino doesn't get as much of acclaim as it should, is because of Goodfellas. Tonally and if you look at the story itself, they are rather similar. Some details are different but the overall feel of the story and the way it's told is surprisingly similar. Even at 3 hour run time they miss out on some details and leave some treads hanging. But as a whole the film worked really well and I completely engrossed in the world Scorsese had created. I would say that this film is a must see for anyone who likes a good story surrounding Las Vegas, the mob or just experience excellent actors giving all they got. A definite must see.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    In one word: overrated
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Fuzius
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After telling a friend I enjoyed The Godfather trilogy, he recommended I watch this film. And I'm sorry to say I totally regret doing so. This film is the opposite of The Godfather. It has zero emotional content. The characters are intentionally one dimensional, idiotic and therefor impossible to identify with. Most of the movie feature narration, which at first feels welcome and classic, but soon grows tiring because instead of the movie just "happening", the narration disrupts the acting all throughout the 3 hours. Now I know many might consider this one a classic, but I will bet you right here and now, that non of the actors playing in "Casino" would willingly sit through this 3 hour torture.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not to be missed mob movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    donpauliano
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was one of the first Movies I can recall watching that gives a little insight into how the Mafia make a living out of legitimate Business. along with titles such as Donnie Brasco, Goodfellas and the Godfather, which I enjoyed each immensely, Casino doesn't only show the dark side of organized crime but the ups and downs of their personal lives too. I watched Casino for the first time with my crew at the Cinema, we loved the outfits that De niro wears and his head for perfection as Casino Manager it really made us chuckle, one of the funniest bits was the bit about everyone being watched by someone: The dealer watches the player, the box man watches the dealer, the pit boss watches the box men, the floor manager watches the pit bosses, the casino manager watches the floor manager, I am watching the casino manager. and in the roof are about a dozen cheats watching everything because they know every trick in the book, and the eye in the sky is watching us all. This would make you think there is more chance in play in a Casino than skill or good luck.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great, but Great to Scorsese is Mediocre to The Everyday Director
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RyanCShowers
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Trust. The fascinating theme and moral reassurance for Martin Scorsese's attempt to hit critics and audiences as hard as he hit them with his classic, Goodfellas. Unfortunately, his arm isn't strong enough to smack the audience on that level. However, he does leave a great impression thanks to his style, control, of course the two components that make his films the best of the best: his film editor and Robert DeNiro. In Spanish, "money" is translated to "diniro". Hiring Robert DeNiro to star as the leading role in a film centered around gambling. The irony is fascinating. Thrown into a role that is more simplistic than past roles Scorsese has put DeNiro front and center for, DeNiro delivers the goods and is the MVP in Casino, when his two co-stars are given much more to raise a circus with. Speaking of, Joe Pesci. While one may question the actor's range with his role choices, no one can deny him the praise he deserves at knocking these types of characters through the wall and then some. Talk about more irony. Sharon Stone was the only cast member (or crew member for that fact) to receive an Oscar nomination for her work in Casino. She gets to cry, she gets to yell, she gets to do drugs, but hardly is she ever to scratch below the surface and bring something real out in her character. Ginger is resorted to Stone's awkwardness on the screen, struggling through scenes other actresses could've killed by throwing a hissy fit. She doesn't work in the role. Not that the role isn't rooted in clich&eacute;, unoriginality, and lacks the development needed to make this trite stereotype a quality character. Much of the film is montage with narration guiding the viewer through the quick action. Scorsese films have tightly strung editing, but nothing ever like this has been produced before. The film barely gives us full length scenes until the last third, but those are drown in Stone's distracting acting efforts. It's a complete mystery to me how Casino was shot and edited; there are so many scenes to get caught up in that last 20 seconds at most some of them. Major props to the editing and Scorsese. I'm aware giving Scorsese praise in that fashion is redundant and expected with each film he directs, but here it's earned considering this is one of his weaker efforts. The film's running time is a monstrous one, and coming from a person who checks their watch incessantly in a film that's over two hours, I didn't feel the length once. It kept me interested and invested in the happenings of the story. The viewer almost rides it like a raft down a river. But, just because it's watchable doesn't always mean it's worth watching. In this case, it is worth the flaws. Flaws, in which the film erupts with as does the opening scene's car bombing. The story is fun, minutely intriguing, and entertains us with the back dealings of Vegas and then seem. But somehow the story and the characters sometimes feel like they are struggling to stay above water. Casino is very reminiscent of The Godfather and The Godfather Part II, homaging the plot arc, specific scenes, themes, subject matters, and the iconic endings. When I was growing up, my mother demanded respect at all times. Even when we were giving her respect beyond any of our peer's efforts for their parents, she still never felt it was enough. She was never going to be satisfied For DeNiro's character, Trust is his version of my mother's trust. He falls in love with Stone's character, knowing her tarnished reputation and her art of conning, but still he chooses to marry her and forces her to be loyal to him. Deep down he knows that he shouldn't trust her, but he lives reality as if she was worthy of his trust. Just as the average joe wants to believe Vegas is an honest place and in gambling you risk it all, but as the saying goes The House Always Wins. Perhaps DeNiro strives for personal strivings for trust result from his view of the unlawful acts of the city. Even though he tries to maintain legitimacy in his end of business dealings, maybe real trust cannot be found in Las Vegas. RATING: 7.5/10 GRADE: B+
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Though "Casino" is not Scorsese's strongest hour, its vision of what mob-run casinos would be like is creative
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris Mizerak
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After bringing us the outstanding 1990 crime drama GoodFellas, critically acclaimed director Martin Scorsese, author/screenwriter Nicholas Pileggi, and stars Robert DeNiro and Joe Pesci team up again for another crime drama five years later called Casino. What's interesting about Casino is that it's basically GoodFellas all over again only set in Las Vegas. It's a good thing no one came up with the idea of naming this film GoodFellas in Las Vegas, since it would make it all the more obvious to us that they're trying to recreate the same movie. That being said, does the fact that Casino bares countless similarities to GoodFellas make it bad? Not at all, it's simply a way of summarizing the movie in a nutshell. Regardless, let's take a deeper look at what we've got. Casino tells the story of a Mafia member named Sam Rothstein (Robert DeNiro) who is sent to Las Vegas to run a casino funded by the Mafia on behalf of mob families living in the Midwest. His friend Nicky Santoro (Joe Pesci) is also eventually sent to Las Vegas to watch his back. The main reason they are both there is to oversee the casino operations which largely centers on illegal activity. Basically, the Mafia has rigged the casino so that none of the customers win anything, and they make millions of dollars off of their money without the customers knowing a thing about it. Essentially, Sam and Nicky are there to make sure that their "skim" goes according to plan. But all of that changes however when a fellow hustler named Ginger (Sharon Stone) enters their lives and eventually interferes with their business to the point where there's no way they could possibly fix whatever costly mistakes erupt. The first couple minutes of Casino, when we're being introduced to the process of how these Mafia-ruled casinos work, are arguably where the most fascinating part of the entire picture resides. We not only learn that the scamming this casino gets away with on a regular basis is supposedly normal, but we are also given the scary conclusion that wasting money on gambling is the main reason people go to Las Vegas in the first place. It definitely makes people who haven't been to Las Vegas before question whether or not they want to go out of their way to a city in the middle of a desert just to lose vast sums of money. I know that it wouldn't be a town I'd want to go to yet based on what I've seen here. So I thought Casino had a fairly strong introduction based on the kind of world it was introducing us to. The rest of the film was pretty decent with Robert DeNiro and Joe Pesci turning in strong acting just like they did with GoodFellas. However, I felt that most of the main narrative was not as compelling or focused as I wanted it to be. The storytelling simply felt a little fragmented for my taste, and the love story between DeNiro and Stone doesn't help with that either. For the record, I respect that the love story does contribute to the events that take place in the second half of the film. Also, Roger Ebert's comments on how different this love story is compared with the love stories in Martin Scorsese's previous works are justified to a certain degree. Regardless, the love story still didn't do much for me at all and I think a crucial reason for that is Sharon Stone. I don't think I've seen much of her work and the ones that I do recall seeing aside from this film are Total Recall, Basic Instinct, and Antz. In my opinion, from what I've seen, she looks physically great, but her acting is too over-the-top for my liking. I'm having trouble placing my finger on it, but something about her acting just seems inappropriate for the movies she stars in. While I acknowledge that some of her roles including this one require her to be very dramatic, she has the distinction of being too childishly over dramatic that she ends up feeling way out of place in her films, this one included. While I still think Joe Pesci acts out his role reasonably well here, his role is maybe a little too identical to his work in GoodFellas. And although I do feel that the story does lose focus around the halfway point, for some reason, I still find Casino watchable enough for me to recommend it overall. And again, this is mainly because of the theories this film shows us regarding how a mob-run casino would operate. There's a well-directed scene involving the casino managers asking a customer to leave because he is placing his feet on the casino tables. Without revealing too much, the payoff of this scene isn't quite what you'd expect at first. The same thing could be said for another scene involving the casino managers dealing with someone who is maybe having too good a day at their casino. If that scene doesn't scare you off from playing and winning too much at a casino, I don't know what will. If you're looking for a story and characters that will impact you the same way Scorsese's earlier films like GoodFellas did, you might be disappointed by what Casino offers. However, if you're looking for a picture with a fascinating premise that introduces creative theories along the way and will settle for something that is at least watchable, then I think you'll like this film fine enough. As for me, though I don't think Casino ranks among Scorsese's best by a good bit and I probably don't have that much interest in looking at it again, I was satisfied enough with seeing it once. Like Las Vegas itself, approach at your own financial risk.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Casino (1995)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ashish sood (ashistrong@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Casino" is another modern classic from Martin Scorsese. Drawing parallels with his earlier "Goodfellas" , "Casino" again teams Scorsese up with writer Nicholas Pileggi having De Niro & Joe Pesci in lead traditional favourite of Scorsese. The result is a truly engaging tale of mobsters setting up a new gambling empire in Las Vegas and the subsequent ripple effects that involve the local authorities and the police. A joy from beginning to end, "Casino" is an example of a perfect movie. There's nothing you'd want to change about this film. It's full of memorable scenes that are rich with outstanding performances and dialogue and it simply demands a repeat viewing. Casino spans three decades and chronicles the true story of a faction of the mob who ran Las Vegas casinos. Robert De Niro plays Sam Ace Rothstein, a fantastic bookie who is chosen to run the Tangiers hotel and Casino. Along the way, he marries a drug-addicted con-artist trophy wife (Sharon Stone) and struggles with his friendship with loose-cannon Nicky Santoro (Joe Pesci). Rothstein is a complicated figure in that he is not a heavy, yet he wields a lot of power due to the respect he has gained from his mob bosses back home. Robert De Niro and Joe Pesci are both fantastic in their roles, and Sharon Stone actually turned out a non-irritating performance. As the viewer, you can't stand her, but that is the point. Scorsese seems to have several different directing styles, and Casino follows in the tradition of Goodfellas as a pseudo-documentary. A lot of the exposition is revealed by the characters themselves in the form of voice-overs, and several scenes are filmed in documentarian fashion. The entire production however, is sleek and very quick. The use of music bears mentioning as well: Most Martin Scorsese films have an amazing soundtrack that adds to and enhances the scene. Scorsese doesn't just utilize the soundtrack, he makes it part of the storytelling - by the music, we chronologically know what time period we are witnessing, since one cannot rely on other factors, such as fashion alone. One of my favorite scenes in film which effectively involves music is actually from Casino - the very intense scene when the relationship between DeNiro, Stone and Pesci come to a head in the climax of the film. The pounding music cut throughout this scene is a cover of "Satisfaction" by Devo and the result is absolutely brilliant. Being a complete movie buff, I generally don't watch films that feature certain stars, I go to films by certain directors and Scorsese is definitely one of them. The man is a complete genius, and a gift to any movie buff - my suggestion is to watch some of his films, then check out his unbelievable series, "A Personal Journey with Martin Scorsese Through American Movies" which was done the same year as Casino. The series is essentially a primer on the history of film, sectioned off by film genres. You not only will experience his amazing intellect and massive knowledge of film history, but his incredible humility as well. Casino has to be one of the most underrated films that Martin Scorsese directed in the nineties. The acting by the leads is good and the script is excellent. Robert De Niro gave an Oscar worthy performance and Joe Pesci is chilling yet funny again. Even Sharon Stone is good in this brilliant film. My Rating  9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pure entertainment! Pure Scorsese!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MrGadgetman
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you haven't seen this masterpiece yet..., let's just say that you need to re-prioritize your life. It's that good. It has something for everyone. Action, suspense, drama (lots of drama!) gunshots and fist fights, comedy and yes... a love story. It is beautifully shot and captures all the magic and flare of the gambling lifestyle and fast paced environment. It will easily suck you in to the movie and you never once look at your watch to notice that it's nearly 3 hours long. All the characters have substance and a purpose in the film which always gives you something (or someone) to think about while you watch the story unfold. I've seen it several times, own it on disc and still catch myself watching it when it comes on Starz...it's that good.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My Favorite Film of All Time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Film Watchin Fool
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well it doesn't get any better than Casino. The cast, acting, directing, cinematography, music, and story are top notch and it makes for a memorable watch. In my opinion this is Scorsese's best film and could watch it over and over again. It is a great mobster film that follows Ace Rothstein (Deniro) and has many trials and tribulations that comes with trying to run Tangiers Casino for the mob. Don't miss this movie and it is one you should see before you die. Put it on your list of must see movies. If you are interested in more details... Again, it is my favorite film of all time so I am a bit biased. That said, Scorsese entrenches you in Las Vegas and Ace Rothstein's reign of the Tangiers casino. Nicholas Pileggi doesn't put out anything but quality material and him and Scorsese together are like peanut butter and jelly. You can't say enough about Scorsese directing and vision in this film. I can't think of a movie that was better put together and has such a great and natural flow to it. On to the acting and casting, which is nothing short of superb. Robert Deniro is Ace Rothstein and does a fantastic job. It isn't his best work, but you couldn't have found a better actor to play the part. Joe Pesci is outstanding as Nicky Santoro and plays one of the most memorable characters in my recent memory. Sharon Stone is great as Ginger and it is arguably her best work to date. You take all that into account with the supporting cast and you have something special. The movie is lengthy, but everything about it doesn't make it seem so long. I am telling you it will go much faster than the two and half hours that it runs and be impressive the entire way. The directing and cinematography are something to marvel and I don't think it gets any better than this film. I highly recommend this to anyone looking for a outstanding gangster film. This ranks as my favorite film of all time and you won't be disappointed. Email me at filmwatchinfool@gmail.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Long But Dosen't Stop Being Interesting,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dillon Harris
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Casino is a fantastic movie with a very long and detailed storyline that stretches out to nearly three hours but it never stops being interesting and enjoyable.The cast of this movie is all brilliant and inspired,Robert De Niro,Sharon Stone and of course Joe Pesci all deliver very impressive performance,James Woods is also very good in this movie as usual but I was disappointed that he wasn't really in it that much,I thought he would have a much more important role in the movie because i've always found his acting very impressive.My only problem with the movie really is that it could have been less detailed and also,my same problem with Goodfellas,is the fact that they get different characters narrating,it should all revolve around one characters point of view so we can hear their story instead of different peoples point of views.It should have all been Robert De Niro's point of view and not changing it to Joe Pesci at times and some other characters as well.A must see for fans of Martin Scorsese and Robert De Niro movies. Story of Sam Rothstein (Robert De Niro) and Nicky Santoro (Joe Pesci) as they begin running a casino business and let their greed get the best of them.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Greed foils crime
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    StoryCharts
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Casino is tough to analyze with Story Charts. The casino racket plot (along with all the other subplots) all start at their highs and tumble down to failures. The only Controlling Idea I can think of is that crime will always fail because of greed. The Story Chart for Casino is not very interesting, basically everything crumbles because of the characters are up to no good. My main beef with the movie is two fold. One is specific about this movie: why make a movie about crime that fails when no one in the movie does any good at all and there is no moral center to the film? Since everyone is up to no good, the only rational way to keep our attention is to up the ante on how bad the characters become and how cool they when they are being bad.So a film whose central idea is about the inevitable downfall of crime betrays its central idea by making the characters "cool" and full of "attitude" and glorifying them. Seriously why do we need a movie like this? It seems to just perpetuate all the negative stereotypes about movies glorifying violence and bad characters. My second beef is in general about Martin Scorsese. I feel films like Casino and many of his other works are mostly show-and-tells rather than true storytelling by characters, conflict and consequence. This shows through most obviously through the abundant voice overs that tell us how "cool" the characters are and tells us the changes that are happening as opposed to showing us through action and consequence. I think voice overs are the nemesis of absorbing movie making and Casino spends about half its time with its characters voicing over stuff that happens on screen: its like a holiday slide-show from "cool" gangsters. I think Casino tries to objectively document a period of Vegas excess driven by a few characters and their criminal ways. It's voice overs certainly make it documentary-like. But its glorification of how cool these guys subjectively tells us to sympathize with these criminals on their inevitable demise. I don't get it, why make a movie that suggests crime doesn't pay but suggest it's cool to be a criminal? How does this make the world a better place? If it doesn't, why make movies at all? My Story Chart of the movie is at storycharts.ca
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Scorsese at his Top...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Janis Livens
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Casino is a great Scorsese film from the mid 90's and it's in my opinion one his better films up there with Goodfellas and Taxi Driver. It showcases excellent performances, great story and his exceptional eye for visuals. While it run for almost three hours, I was never bored, it never dragged for me and I was completely immersed in the story being told. I agree that Casino should have been shorter and they could have toned the violence slightly down, but end result just doesn't really bother me. It's very engaging, the actors pretty much own the film. giving very strong performances. The reason why Casino doesn't get as much of acclaim as it should, is because of Goodfellas. Tonally and if you look at the story itself, they are rather similar. Some details are different but the overall feel of the story and the way it's told is surprisingly similar. Even at 3 hour run time they miss out on some details and leave some treads hanging. But as a whole the film worked really well and I completely engrossed in the world Scorsese had created. I would say that this film is a must see for anyone who likes a good story surrounding Las Vegas, the mob or just experience excellent actors giving all they got. A definite must see.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    In one word: overrated
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Fuzius
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After telling a friend I enjoyed The Godfather trilogy, he recommended I watch this film. And I'm sorry to say I totally regret doing so. This film is the opposite of The Godfather. It has zero emotional content. The characters are intentionally one dimensional, idiotic and therefor impossible to identify with. Most of the movie feature narration, which at first feels welcome and classic, but soon grows tiring because instead of the movie just "happening", the narration disrupts the acting all throughout the 3 hours. Now I know many might consider this one a classic, but I will bet you right here and now, that non of the actors playing in "Casino" would willingly sit through this 3 hour torture.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not to be missed mob movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    donpauliano
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was one of the first Movies I can recall watching that gives a little insight into how the Mafia make a living out of legitimate Business. along with titles such as Donnie Brasco, Goodfellas and the Godfather, which I enjoyed each immensely, Casino doesn't only show the dark side of organized crime but the ups and downs of their personal lives too. I watched Casino for the first time with my crew at the Cinema, we loved the outfits that De niro wears and his head for perfection as Casino Manager it really made us chuckle, one of the funniest bits was the bit about everyone being watched by someone: The dealer watches the player, the box man watches the dealer, the pit boss watches the box men, the floor manager watches the pit bosses, the casino manager watches the floor manager, I am watching the casino manager. and in the roof are about a dozen cheats watching everything because they know every trick in the book, and the eye in the sky is watching us all. This would make you think there is more chance in play in a Casino than skill or good luck.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great, but Great to Scorsese is Mediocre to The Everyday Director
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RyanCShowers
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Trust. The fascinating theme and moral reassurance for Martin Scorsese's attempt to hit critics and audiences as hard as he hit them with his classic, Goodfellas. Unfortunately, his arm isn't strong enough to smack the audience on that level. However, he does leave a great impression thanks to his style, control, of course the two components that make his films the best of the best: his film editor and Robert DeNiro. In Spanish, "money" is translated to "diniro". Hiring Robert DeNiro to star as the leading role in a film centered around gambling. The irony is fascinating. Thrown into a role that is more simplistic than past roles Scorsese has put DeNiro front and center for, DeNiro delivers the goods and is the MVP in Casino, when his two co-stars are given much more to raise a circus with. Speaking of, Joe Pesci. While one may question the actor's range with his role choices, no one can deny him the praise he deserves at knocking these types of characters through the wall and then some. Talk about more irony. Sharon Stone was the only cast member (or crew member for that fact) to receive an Oscar nomination for her work in Casino. She gets to cry, she gets to yell, she gets to do drugs, but hardly is she ever to scratch below the surface and bring something real out in her character. Ginger is resorted to Stone's awkwardness on the screen, struggling through scenes other actresses could've killed by throwing a hissy fit. She doesn't work in the role. Not that the role isn't rooted in clich&eacute;, unoriginality, and lacks the development needed to make this trite stereotype a quality character. Much of the film is montage with narration guiding the viewer through the quick action. Scorsese films have tightly strung editing, but nothing ever like this has been produced before. The film barely gives us full length scenes until the last third, but those are drown in Stone's distracting acting efforts. It's a complete mystery to me how Casino was shot and edited; there are so many scenes to get caught up in that last 20 seconds at most some of them. Major props to the editing and Scorsese. I'm aware giving Scorsese praise in that fashion is redundant and expected with each film he directs, but here it's earned considering this is one of his weaker efforts. The film's running time is a monstrous one, and coming from a person who checks their watch incessantly in a film that's over two hours, I didn't feel the length once. It kept me interested and invested in the happenings of the story. The viewer almost rides it like a raft down a river. But, just because it's watchable doesn't always mean it's worth watching. In this case, it is worth the flaws. Flaws, in which the film erupts with as does the opening scene's car bombing. The story is fun, minutely intriguing, and entertains us with the back dealings of Vegas and then seem. But somehow the story and the characters sometimes feel like they are struggling to stay above water. Casino is very reminiscent of The Godfather and The Godfather Part II, homaging the plot arc, specific scenes, themes, subject matters, and the iconic endings. When I was growing up, my mother demanded respect at all times. Even when we were giving her respect beyond any of our peer's efforts for their parents, she still never felt it was enough. She was never going to be satisfied For DeNiro's character, Trust is his version of my mother's trust. He falls in love with Stone's character, knowing her tarnished reputation and her art of conning, but still he chooses to marry her and forces her to be loyal to him. Deep down he knows that he shouldn't trust her, but he lives reality as if she was worthy of his trust. Just as the average joe wants to believe Vegas is an honest place and in gambling you risk it all, but as the saying goes The House Always Wins. Perhaps DeNiro strives for personal strivings for trust result from his view of the unlawful acts of the city. Even though he tries to maintain legitimacy in his end of business dealings, maybe real trust cannot be found in Las Vegas. RATING: 7.5/10 GRADE: B+
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Though "Casino" is not Scorsese's strongest hour, its vision of what mob-run casinos would be like is creative
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris Mizerak
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After bringing us the outstanding 1990 crime drama GoodFellas, critically acclaimed director Martin Scorsese, author/screenwriter Nicholas Pileggi, and stars Robert DeNiro and Joe Pesci team up again for another crime drama five years later called Casino. What's interesting about Casino is that it's basically GoodFellas all over again only set in Las Vegas. It's a good thing no one came up with the idea of naming this film GoodFellas in Las Vegas, since it would make it all the more obvious to us that they're trying to recreate the same movie. That being said, does the fact that Casino bares countless similarities to GoodFellas make it bad? Not at all, it's simply a way of summarizing the movie in a nutshell. Regardless, let's take a deeper look at what we've got. Casino tells the story of a Mafia member named Sam Rothstein (Robert DeNiro) who is sent to Las Vegas to run a casino funded by the Mafia on behalf of mob families living in the Midwest. His friend Nicky Santoro (Joe Pesci) is also eventually sent to Las Vegas to watch his back. The main reason they are both there is to oversee the casino operations which largely centers on illegal activity. Basically, the Mafia has rigged the casino so that none of the customers win anything, and they make millions of dollars off of their money without the customers knowing a thing about it. Essentially, Sam and Nicky are there to make sure that their "skim" goes according to plan. But all of that changes however when a fellow hustler named Ginger (Sharon Stone) enters their lives and eventually interferes with their business to the point where there's no way they could possibly fix whatever costly mistakes erupt. The first couple minutes of Casino, when we're being introduced to the process of how these Mafia-ruled casinos work, are arguably where the most fascinating part of the entire picture resides. We not only learn that the scamming this casino gets away with on a regular basis is supposedly normal, but we are also given the scary conclusion that wasting money on gambling is the main reason people go to Las Vegas in the first place. It definitely makes people who haven't been to Las Vegas before question whether or not they want to go out of their way to a city in the middle of a desert just to lose vast sums of money. I know that it wouldn't be a town I'd want to go to yet based on what I've seen here. So I thought Casino had a fairly strong introduction based on the kind of world it was introducing us to. The rest of the film was pretty decent with Robert DeNiro and Joe Pesci turning in strong acting just like they did with GoodFellas. However, I felt that most of the main narrative was not as compelling or focused as I wanted it to be. The storytelling simply felt a little fragmented for my taste, and the love story between DeNiro and Stone doesn't help with that either. For the record, I respect that the love story does contribute to the events that take place in the second half of the film. Also, Roger Ebert's comments on how different this love story is compared with the love stories in Martin Scorsese's previous works are justified to a certain degree. Regardless, the love story still didn't do much for me at all and I think a crucial reason for that is Sharon Stone. I don't think I've seen much of her work and the ones that I do recall seeing aside from this film are Total Recall, Basic Instinct, and Antz. In my opinion, from what I've seen, she looks physically great, but her acting is too over-the-top for my liking. I'm having trouble placing my finger on it, but something about her acting just seems inappropriate for the movies she stars in. While I acknowledge that some of her roles including this one require her to be very dramatic, she has the distinction of being too childishly over dramatic that she ends up feeling way out of place in her films, this one included. While I still think Joe Pesci acts out his role reasonably well here, his role is maybe a little too identical to his work in GoodFellas. And although I do feel that the story does lose focus around the halfway point, for some reason, I still find Casino watchable enough for me to recommend it overall. And again, this is mainly because of the theories this film shows us regarding how a mob-run casino would operate. There's a well-directed scene involving the casino managers asking a customer to leave because he is placing his feet on the casino tables. Without revealing too much, the payoff of this scene isn't quite what you'd expect at first. The same thing could be said for another scene involving the casino managers dealing with someone who is maybe having too good a day at their casino. If that scene doesn't scare you off from playing and winning too much at a casino, I don't know what will. If you're looking for a story and characters that will impact you the same way Scorsese's earlier films like GoodFellas did, you might be disappointed by what Casino offers. However, if you're looking for a picture with a fascinating premise that introduces creative theories along the way and will settle for something that is at least watchable, then I think you'll like this film fine enough. As for me, though I don't think Casino ranks among Scorsese's best by a good bit and I probably don't have that much interest in looking at it again, I was satisfied enough with seeing it once. Like Las Vegas itself, approach at your own financial risk.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Casino (1995)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ashish sood (ashistrong@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Casino" is another modern classic from Martin Scorsese. Drawing parallels with his earlier "Goodfellas" , "Casino" again teams Scorsese up with writer Nicholas Pileggi having De Niro & Joe Pesci in lead traditional favourite of Scorsese. The result is a truly engaging tale of mobsters setting up a new gambling empire in Las Vegas and the subsequent ripple effects that involve the local authorities and the police. A joy from beginning to end, "Casino" is an example of a perfect movie. There's nothing you'd want to change about this film. It's full of memorable scenes that are rich with outstanding performances and dialogue and it simply demands a repeat viewing. Casino spans three decades and chronicles the true story of a faction of the mob who ran Las Vegas casinos. Robert De Niro plays Sam Ace Rothstein, a fantastic bookie who is chosen to run the Tangiers hotel and Casino. Along the way, he marries a drug-addicted con-artist trophy wife (Sharon Stone) and struggles with his friendship with loose-cannon Nicky Santoro (Joe Pesci). Rothstein is a complicated figure in that he is not a heavy, yet he wields a lot of power due to the respect he has gained from his mob bosses back home. Robert De Niro and Joe Pesci are both fantastic in their roles, and Sharon Stone actually turned out a non-irritating performance. As the viewer, you can't stand her, but that is the point. Scorsese seems to have several different directing styles, and Casino follows in the tradition of Goodfellas as a pseudo-documentary. A lot of the exposition is revealed by the characters themselves in the form of voice-overs, and several scenes are filmed in documentarian fashion. The entire production however, is sleek and very quick. The use of music bears mentioning as well: Most Martin Scorsese films have an amazing soundtrack that adds to and enhances the scene. Scorsese doesn't just utilize the soundtrack, he makes it part of the storytelling - by the music, we chronologically know what time period we are witnessing, since one cannot rely on other factors, such as fashion alone. One of my favorite scenes in film which effectively involves music is actually from Casino - the very intense scene when the relationship between DeNiro, Stone and Pesci come to a head in the climax of the film. The pounding music cut throughout this scene is a cover of "Satisfaction" by Devo and the result is absolutely brilliant. Being a complete movie buff, I generally don't watch films that feature certain stars, I go to films by certain directors and Scorsese is definitely one of them. The man is a complete genius, and a gift to any movie buff - my suggestion is to watch some of his films, then check out his unbelievable series, "A Personal Journey with Martin Scorsese Through American Movies" which was done the same year as Casino. The series is essentially a primer on the history of film, sectioned off by film genres. You not only will experience his amazing intellect and massive knowledge of film history, but his incredible humility as well. Casino has to be one of the most underrated films that Martin Scorsese directed in the nineties. The acting by the leads is good and the script is excellent. Robert De Niro gave an Oscar worthy performance and Joe Pesci is chilling yet funny again. Even Sharon Stone is good in this brilliant film. My Rating  9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pure entertainment! Pure Scorsese!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MrGadgetman
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you haven't seen this masterpiece yet..., let's just say that you need to re-prioritize your life. It's that good. It has something for everyone. Action, suspense, drama (lots of drama!) gunshots and fist fights, comedy and yes... a love story. It is beautifully shot and captures all the magic and flare of the gambling lifestyle and fast paced environment. It will easily suck you in to the movie and you never once look at your watch to notice that it's nearly 3 hours long. All the characters have substance and a purpose in the film which always gives you something (or someone) to think about while you watch the story unfold. I've seen it several times, own it on disc and still catch myself watching it when it comes on Starz...it's that good.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My Favorite Film of All Time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Film Watchin Fool
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well it doesn't get any better than Casino. The cast, acting, directing, cinematography, music, and story are top notch and it makes for a memorable watch. In my opinion this is Scorsese's best film and could watch it over and over again. It is a great mobster film that follows Ace Rothstein (Deniro) and has many trials and tribulations that comes with trying to run Tangiers Casino for the mob. Don't miss this movie and it is one you should see before you die. Put it on your list of must see movies. If you are interested in more details... Again, it is my favorite film of all time so I am a bit biased. That said, Scorsese entrenches you in Las Vegas and Ace Rothstein's reign of the Tangiers casino. Nicholas Pileggi doesn't put out anything but quality material and him and Scorsese together are like peanut butter and jelly. You can't say enough about Scorsese directing and vision in this film. I can't think of a movie that was better put together and has such a great and natural flow to it. On to the acting and casting, which is nothing short of superb. Robert Deniro is Ace Rothstein and does a fantastic job. It isn't his best work, but you couldn't have found a better actor to play the part. Joe Pesci is outstanding as Nicky Santoro and plays one of the most memorable characters in my recent memory. Sharon Stone is great as Ginger and it is arguably her best work to date. You take all that into account with the supporting cast and you have something special. The movie is lengthy, but everything about it doesn't make it seem so long. I am telling you it will go much faster than the two and half hours that it runs and be impressive the entire way. The directing and cinematography are something to marvel and I don't think it gets any better than this film. I highly recommend this to anyone looking for a outstanding gangster film. This ranks as my favorite film of all time and you won't be disappointed. Email me at filmwatchinfool@gmail.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Long But Dosen't Stop Being Interesting,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dillon Harris
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Casino is a fantastic movie with a very long and detailed storyline that stretches out to nearly three hours but it never stops being interesting and enjoyable.The cast of this movie is all brilliant and inspired,Robert De Niro,Sharon Stone and of course Joe Pesci all deliver very impressive performance,James Woods is also very good in this movie as usual but I was disappointed that he wasn't really in it that much,I thought he would have a much more important role in the movie because i've always found his acting very impressive.My only problem with the movie really is that it could have been less detailed and also,my same problem with Goodfellas,is the fact that they get different characters narrating,it should all revolve around one characters point of view so we can hear their story instead of different peoples point of views.It should have all been Robert De Niro's point of view and not changing it to Joe Pesci at times and some other characters as well.A must see for fans of Martin Scorsese and Robert De Niro movies. Story of Sam Rothstein (Robert De Niro) and Nicky Santoro (Joe Pesci) as they begin running a casino business and let their greed get the best of them.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Greed foils crime
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    StoryCharts
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Casino is tough to analyze with Story Charts. The casino racket plot (along with all the other subplots) all start at their highs and tumble down to failures. The only Controlling Idea I can think of is that crime will always fail because of greed. The Story Chart for Casino is not very interesting, basically everything crumbles because of the characters are up to no good. My main beef with the movie is two fold. One is specific about this movie: why make a movie about crime that fails when no one in the movie does any good at all and there is no moral center to the film? Since everyone is up to no good, the only rational way to keep our attention is to up the ante on how bad the characters become and how cool they when they are being bad.So a film whose central idea is about the inevitable downfall of crime betrays its central idea by making the characters "cool" and full of "attitude" and glorifying them. Seriously why do we need a movie like this? It seems to just perpetuate all the negative stereotypes about movies glorifying violence and bad characters. My second beef is in general about Martin Scorsese. I feel films like Casino and many of his other works are mostly show-and-tells rather than true storytelling by characters, conflict and consequence. This shows through most obviously through the abundant voice overs that tell us how "cool" the characters are and tells us the changes that are happening as opposed to showing us through action and consequence. I think voice overs are the nemesis of absorbing movie making and Casino spends about half its time with its characters voicing over stuff that happens on screen: its like a holiday slide-show from "cool" gangsters. I think Casino tries to objectively document a period of Vegas excess driven by a few characters and their criminal ways. It's voice overs certainly make it documentary-like. But its glorification of how cool these guys subjectively tells us to sympathize with these criminals on their inevitable demise. I don't get it, why make a movie that suggests crime doesn't pay but suggest it's cool to be a criminal? How does this make the world a better place? If it doesn't, why make movies at all? My Story Chart of the movie is at storycharts.ca
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Scorsese at his Top...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Janis Livens
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Casino is a great Scorsese film from the mid 90's and it's in my opinion one his better films up there with Goodfellas and Taxi Driver. It showcases excellent performances, great story and his exceptional eye for visuals. While it run for almost three hours, I was never bored, it never dragged for me and I was completely immersed in the story being told. I agree that Casino should have been shorter and they could have toned the violence slightly down, but end result just doesn't really bother me. It's very engaging, the actors pretty much own the film. giving very strong performances. The reason why Casino doesn't get as much of acclaim as it should, is because of Goodfellas. Tonally and if you look at the story itself, they are rather similar. Some details are different but the overall feel of the story and the way it's told is surprisingly similar. Even at 3 hour run time they miss out on some details and leave some treads hanging. But as a whole the film worked really well and I completely engrossed in the world Scorsese had created. I would say that this film is a must see for anyone who likes a good story surrounding Las Vegas, the mob or just experience excellent actors giving all they got. A definite must see.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    In one word: overrated
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Fuzius
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After telling a friend I enjoyed The Godfather trilogy, he recommended I watch this film. And I'm sorry to say I totally regret doing so. This film is the opposite of The Godfather. It has zero emotional content. The characters are intentionally one dimensional, idiotic and therefor impossible to identify with. Most of the movie feature narration, which at first feels welcome and classic, but soon grows tiring because instead of the movie just "happening", the narration disrupts the acting all throughout the 3 hours. Now I know many might consider this one a classic, but I will bet you right here and now, that non of the actors playing in "Casino" would willingly sit through this 3 hour torture.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not to be missed mob movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    donpauliano
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was one of the first Movies I can recall watching that gives a little insight into how the Mafia make a living out of legitimate Business. along with titles such as Donnie Brasco, Goodfellas and the Godfather, which I enjoyed each immensely, Casino doesn't only show the dark side of organized crime but the ups and downs of their personal lives too. I watched Casino for the first time with my crew at the Cinema, we loved the outfits that De niro wears and his head for perfection as Casino Manager it really made us chuckle, one of the funniest bits was the bit about everyone being watched by someone: The dealer watches the player, the box man watches the dealer, the pit boss watches the box men, the floor manager watches the pit bosses, the casino manager watches the floor manager, I am watching the casino manager. and in the roof are about a dozen cheats watching everything because they know every trick in the book, and the eye in the sky is watching us all. This would make you think there is more chance in play in a Casino than skill or good luck.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great, but Great to Scorsese is Mediocre to The Everyday Director
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RyanCShowers
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Trust. The fascinating theme and moral reassurance for Martin Scorsese's attempt to hit critics and audiences as hard as he hit them with his classic, Goodfellas. Unfortunately, his arm isn't strong enough to smack the audience on that level. However, he does leave a great impression thanks to his style, control, of course the two components that make his films the best of the best: his film editor and Robert DeNiro. In Spanish, "money" is translated to "diniro". Hiring Robert DeNiro to star as the leading role in a film centered around gambling. The irony is fascinating. Thrown into a role that is more simplistic than past roles Scorsese has put DeNiro front and center for, DeNiro delivers the goods and is the MVP in Casino, when his two co-stars are given much more to raise a circus with. Speaking of, Joe Pesci. While one may question the actor's range with his role choices, no one can deny him the praise he deserves at knocking these types of characters through the wall and then some. Talk about more irony. Sharon Stone was the only cast member (or crew member for that fact) to receive an Oscar nomination for her work in Casino. She gets to cry, she gets to yell, she gets to do drugs, but hardly is she ever to scratch below the surface and bring something real out in her character. Ginger is resorted to Stone's awkwardness on the screen, struggling through scenes other actresses could've killed by throwing a hissy fit. She doesn't work in the role. Not that the role isn't rooted in clich&eacute;, unoriginality, and lacks the development needed to make this trite stereotype a quality character. Much of the film is montage with narration guiding the viewer through the quick action. Scorsese films have tightly strung editing, but nothing ever like this has been produced before. The film barely gives us full length scenes until the last third, but those are drown in Stone's distracting acting efforts. It's a complete mystery to me how Casino was shot and edited; there are so many scenes to get caught up in that last 20 seconds at most some of them. Major props to the editing and Scorsese. I'm aware giving Scorsese praise in that fashion is redundant and expected with each film he directs, but here it's earned considering this is one of his weaker efforts. The film's running time is a monstrous one, and coming from a person who checks their watch incessantly in a film that's over two hours, I didn't feel the length once. It kept me interested and invested in the happenings of the story. The viewer almost rides it like a raft down a river. But, just because it's watchable doesn't always mean it's worth watching. In this case, it is worth the flaws. Flaws, in which the film erupts with as does the opening scene's car bombing. The story is fun, minutely intriguing, and entertains us with the back dealings of Vegas and then seem. But somehow the story and the characters sometimes feel like they are struggling to stay above water. Casino is very reminiscent of The Godfather and The Godfather Part II, homaging the plot arc, specific scenes, themes, subject matters, and the iconic endings. When I was growing up, my mother demanded respect at all times. Even when we were giving her respect beyond any of our peer's efforts for their parents, she still never felt it was enough. She was never going to be satisfied For DeNiro's character, Trust is his version of my mother's trust. He falls in love with Stone's character, knowing her tarnished reputation and her art of conning, but still he chooses to marry her and forces her to be loyal to him. Deep down he knows that he shouldn't trust her, but he lives reality as if she was worthy of his trust. Just as the average joe wants to believe Vegas is an honest place and in gambling you risk it all, but as the saying goes The House Always Wins. Perhaps DeNiro strives for personal strivings for trust result from his view of the unlawful acts of the city. Even though he tries to maintain legitimacy in his end of business dealings, maybe real trust cannot be found in Las Vegas. RATING: 7.5/10 GRADE: B+
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Though "Casino" is not Scorsese's strongest hour, its vision of what mob-run casinos would be like is creative
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris Mizerak
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After bringing us the outstanding 1990 crime drama GoodFellas, critically acclaimed director Martin Scorsese, author/screenwriter Nicholas Pileggi, and stars Robert DeNiro and Joe Pesci team up again for another crime drama five years later called Casino. What's interesting about Casino is that it's basically GoodFellas all over again only set in Las Vegas. It's a good thing no one came up with the idea of naming this film GoodFellas in Las Vegas, since it would make it all the more obvious to us that they're trying to recreate the same movie. That being said, does the fact that Casino bares countless similarities to GoodFellas make it bad? Not at all, it's simply a way of summarizing the movie in a nutshell. Regardless, let's take a deeper look at what we've got. Casino tells the story of a Mafia member named Sam Rothstein (Robert DeNiro) who is sent to Las Vegas to run a casino funded by the Mafia on behalf of mob families living in the Midwest. His friend Nicky Santoro (Joe Pesci) is also eventually sent to Las Vegas to watch his back. The main reason they are both there is to oversee the casino operations which largely centers on illegal activity. Basically, the Mafia has rigged the casino so that none of the customers win anything, and they make millions of dollars off of their money without the customers knowing a thing about it. Essentially, Sam and Nicky are there to make sure that their "skim" goes according to plan. But all of that changes however when a fellow hustler named Ginger (Sharon Stone) enters their lives and eventually interferes with their business to the point where there's no way they could possibly fix whatever costly mistakes erupt. The first couple minutes of Casino, when we're being introduced to the process of how these Mafia-ruled casinos work, are arguably where the most fascinating part of the entire picture resides. We not only learn that the scamming this casino gets away with on a regular basis is supposedly normal, but we are also given the scary conclusion that wasting money on gambling is the main reason people go to Las Vegas in the first place. It definitely makes people who haven't been to Las Vegas before question whether or not they want to go out of their way to a city in the middle of a desert just to lose vast sums of money. I know that it wouldn't be a town I'd want to go to yet based on what I've seen here. So I thought Casino had a fairly strong introduction based on the kind of world it was introducing us to. The rest of the film was pretty decent with Robert DeNiro and Joe Pesci turning in strong acting just like they did with GoodFellas. However, I felt that most of the main narrative was not as compelling or focused as I wanted it to be. The storytelling simply felt a little fragmented for my taste, and the love story between DeNiro and Stone doesn't help with that either. For the record, I respect that the love story does contribute to the events that take place in the second half of the film. Also, Roger Ebert's comments on how different this love story is compared with the love stories in Martin Scorsese's previous works are justified to a certain degree. Regardless, the love story still didn't do much for me at all and I think a crucial reason for that is Sharon Stone. I don't think I've seen much of her work and the ones that I do recall seeing aside from this film are Total Recall, Basic Instinct, and Antz. In my opinion, from what I've seen, she looks physically great, but her acting is too over-the-top for my liking. I'm having trouble placing my finger on it, but something about her acting just seems inappropriate for the movies she stars in. While I acknowledge that some of her roles including this one require her to be very dramatic, she has the distinction of being too childishly over dramatic that she ends up feeling way out of place in her films, this one included. While I still think Joe Pesci acts out his role reasonably well here, his role is maybe a little too identical to his work in GoodFellas. And although I do feel that the story does lose focus around the halfway point, for some reason, I still find Casino watchable enough for me to recommend it overall. And again, this is mainly because of the theories this film shows us regarding how a mob-run casino would operate. There's a well-directed scene involving the casino managers asking a customer to leave because he is placing his feet on the casino tables. Without revealing too much, the payoff of this scene isn't quite what you'd expect at first. The same thing could be said for another scene involving the casino managers dealing with someone who is maybe having too good a day at their casino. If that scene doesn't scare you off from playing and winning too much at a casino, I don't know what will. If you're looking for a story and characters that will impact you the same way Scorsese's earlier films like GoodFellas did, you might be disappointed by what Casino offers. However, if you're looking for a picture with a fascinating premise that introduces creative theories along the way and will settle for something that is at least watchable, then I think you'll like this film fine enough. As for me, though I don't think Casino ranks among Scorsese's best by a good bit and I probably don't have that much interest in looking at it again, I was satisfied enough with seeing it once. Like Las Vegas itself, approach at your own financial risk.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Casino (1995)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ashish sood (ashistrong@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Casino" is another modern classic from Martin Scorsese. Drawing parallels with his earlier "Goodfellas" , "Casino" again teams Scorsese up with writer Nicholas Pileggi having De Niro & Joe Pesci in lead traditional favourite of Scorsese. The result is a truly engaging tale of mobsters setting up a new gambling empire in Las Vegas and the subsequent ripple effects that involve the local authorities and the police. A joy from beginning to end, "Casino" is an example of a perfect movie. There's nothing you'd want to change about this film. It's full of memorable scenes that are rich with outstanding performances and dialogue and it simply demands a repeat viewing. Casino spans three decades and chronicles the true story of a faction of the mob who ran Las Vegas casinos. Robert De Niro plays Sam Ace Rothstein, a fantastic bookie who is chosen to run the Tangiers hotel and Casino. Along the way, he marries a drug-addicted con-artist trophy wife (Sharon Stone) and struggles with his friendship with loose-cannon Nicky Santoro (Joe Pesci). Rothstein is a complicated figure in that he is not a heavy, yet he wields a lot of power due to the respect he has gained from his mob bosses back home. Robert De Niro and Joe Pesci are both fantastic in their roles, and Sharon Stone actually turned out a non-irritating performance. As the viewer, you can't stand her, but that is the point. Scorsese seems to have several different directing styles, and Casino follows in the tradition of Goodfellas as a pseudo-documentary. A lot of the exposition is revealed by the characters themselves in the form of voice-overs, and several scenes are filmed in documentarian fashion. The entire production however, is sleek and very quick. The use of music bears mentioning as well: Most Martin Scorsese films have an amazing soundtrack that adds to and enhances the scene. Scorsese doesn't just utilize the soundtrack, he makes it part of the storytelling - by the music, we chronologically know what time period we are witnessing, since one cannot rely on other factors, such as fashion alone. One of my favorite scenes in film which effectively involves music is actually from Casino - the very intense scene when the relationship between DeNiro, Stone and Pesci come to a head in the climax of the film. The pounding music cut throughout this scene is a cover of "Satisfaction" by Devo and the result is absolutely brilliant. Being a complete movie buff, I generally don't watch films that feature certain stars, I go to films by certain directors and Scorsese is definitely one of them. The man is a complete genius, and a gift to any movie buff - my suggestion is to watch some of his films, then check out his unbelievable series, "A Personal Journey with Martin Scorsese Through American Movies" which was done the same year as Casino. The series is essentially a primer on the history of film, sectioned off by film genres. You not only will experience his amazing intellect and massive knowledge of film history, but his incredible humility as well. Casino has to be one of the most underrated films that Martin Scorsese directed in the nineties. The acting by the leads is good and the script is excellent. Robert De Niro gave an Oscar worthy performance and Joe Pesci is chilling yet funny again. Even Sharon Stone is good in this brilliant film. My Rating  9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pure entertainment! Pure Scorsese!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MrGadgetman
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you haven't seen this masterpiece yet..., let's just say that you need to re-prioritize your life. It's that good. It has something for everyone. Action, suspense, drama (lots of drama!) gunshots and fist fights, comedy and yes... a love story. It is beautifully shot and captures all the magic and flare of the gambling lifestyle and fast paced environment. It will easily suck you in to the movie and you never once look at your watch to notice that it's nearly 3 hours long. All the characters have substance and a purpose in the film which always gives you something (or someone) to think about while you watch the story unfold. I've seen it several times, own it on disc and still catch myself watching it when it comes on Starz...it's that good.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My Favorite Film of All Time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Film Watchin Fool
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well it doesn't get any better than Casino. The cast, acting, directing, cinematography, music, and story are top notch and it makes for a memorable watch. In my opinion this is Scorsese's best film and could watch it over and over again. It is a great mobster film that follows Ace Rothstein (Deniro) and has many trials and tribulations that comes with trying to run Tangiers Casino for the mob. Don't miss this movie and it is one you should see before you die. Put it on your list of must see movies. If you are interested in more details... Again, it is my favorite film of all time so I am a bit biased. That said, Scorsese entrenches you in Las Vegas and Ace Rothstein's reign of the Tangiers casino. Nicholas Pileggi doesn't put out anything but quality material and him and Scorsese together are like peanut butter and jelly. You can't say enough about Scorsese directing and vision in this film. I can't think of a movie that was better put together and has such a great and natural flow to it. On to the acting and casting, which is nothing short of superb. Robert Deniro is Ace Rothstein and does a fantastic job. It isn't his best work, but you couldn't have found a better actor to play the part. Joe Pesci is outstanding as Nicky Santoro and plays one of the most memorable characters in my recent memory. Sharon Stone is great as Ginger and it is arguably her best work to date. You take all that into account with the supporting cast and you have something special. The movie is lengthy, but everything about it doesn't make it seem so long. I am telling you it will go much faster than the two and half hours that it runs and be impressive the entire way. The directing and cinematography are something to marvel and I don't think it gets any better than this film. I highly recommend this to anyone looking for a outstanding gangster film. This ranks as my favorite film of all time and you won't be disappointed. Email me at filmwatchinfool@gmail.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Long But Dosen't Stop Being Interesting,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dillon Harris
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Casino is a fantastic movie with a very long and detailed storyline that stretches out to nearly three hours but it never stops being interesting and enjoyable.The cast of this movie is all brilliant and inspired,Robert De Niro,Sharon Stone and of course Joe Pesci all deliver very impressive performance,James Woods is also very good in this movie as usual but I was disappointed that he wasn't really in it that much,I thought he would have a much more important role in the movie because i've always found his acting very impressive.My only problem with the movie really is that it could have been less detailed and also,my same problem with Goodfellas,is the fact that they get different characters narrating,it should all revolve around one characters point of view so we can hear their story instead of different peoples point of views.It should have all been Robert De Niro's point of view and not changing it to Joe Pesci at times and some other characters as well.A must see for fans of Martin Scorsese and Robert De Niro movies. Story of Sam Rothstein (Robert De Niro) and Nicky Santoro (Joe Pesci) as they begin running a casino business and let their greed get the best of them.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Greed foils crime
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    StoryCharts
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Casino is tough to analyze with Story Charts. The casino racket plot (along with all the other subplots) all start at their highs and tumble down to failures. The only Controlling Idea I can think of is that crime will always fail because of greed. The Story Chart for Casino is not very interesting, basically everything crumbles because of the characters are up to no good. My main beef with the movie is two fold. One is specific about this movie: why make a movie about crime that fails when no one in the movie does any good at all and there is no moral center to the film? Since everyone is up to no good, the only rational way to keep our attention is to up the ante on how bad the characters become and how cool they when they are being bad.So a film whose central idea is about the inevitable downfall of crime betrays its central idea by making the characters "cool" and full of "attitude" and glorifying them. Seriously why do we need a movie like this? It seems to just perpetuate all the negative stereotypes about movies glorifying violence and bad characters. My second beef is in general about Martin Scorsese. I feel films like Casino and many of his other works are mostly show-and-tells rather than true storytelling by characters, conflict and consequence. This shows through most obviously through the abundant voice overs that tell us how "cool" the characters are and tells us the changes that are happening as opposed to showing us through action and consequence. I think voice overs are the nemesis of absorbing movie making and Casino spends about half its time with its characters voicing over stuff that happens on screen: its like a holiday slide-show from "cool" gangsters. I think Casino tries to objectively document a period of Vegas excess driven by a few characters and their criminal ways. It's voice overs certainly make it documentary-like. But its glorification of how cool these guys subjectively tells us to sympathize with these criminals on their inevitable demise. I don't get it, why make a movie that suggests crime doesn't pay but suggest it's cool to be a criminal? How does this make the world a better place? If it doesn't, why make movies at all? My Story Chart of the movie is at storycharts.ca
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Scorsese at his Top...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Janis Livens
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Casino is a great Scorsese film from the mid 90's and it's in my opinion one his better films up there with Goodfellas and Taxi Driver. It showcases excellent performances, great story and his exceptional eye for visuals. While it run for almost three hours, I was never bored, it never dragged for me and I was completely immersed in the story being told. I agree that Casino should have been shorter and they could have toned the violence slightly down, but end result just doesn't really bother me. It's very engaging, the actors pretty much own the film. giving very strong performances. The reason why Casino doesn't get as much of acclaim as it should, is because of Goodfellas. Tonally and if you look at the story itself, they are rather similar. Some details are different but the overall feel of the story and the way it's told is surprisingly similar. Even at 3 hour run time they miss out on some details and leave some treads hanging. But as a whole the film worked really well and I completely engrossed in the world Scorsese had created. I would say that this film is a must see for anyone who likes a good story surrounding Las Vegas, the mob or just experience excellent actors giving all they got. A definite must see.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    In one word: overrated
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Fuzius
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After telling a friend I enjoyed The Godfather trilogy, he recommended I watch this film. And I'm sorry to say I totally regret doing so. This film is the opposite of The Godfather. It has zero emotional content. The characters are intentionally one dimensional, idiotic and therefor impossible to identify with. Most of the movie feature narration, which at first feels welcome and classic, but soon grows tiring because instead of the movie just "happening", the narration disrupts the acting all throughout the 3 hours. Now I know many might consider this one a classic, but I will bet you right here and now, that non of the actors playing in "Casino" would willingly sit through this 3 hour torture.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not to be missed mob movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    donpauliano
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was one of the first Movies I can recall watching that gives a little insight into how the Mafia make a living out of legitimate Business. along with titles such as Donnie Brasco, Goodfellas and the Godfather, which I enjoyed each immensely, Casino doesn't only show the dark side of organized crime but the ups and downs of their personal lives too. I watched Casino for the first time with my crew at the Cinema, we loved the outfits that De niro wears and his head for perfection as Casino Manager it really made us chuckle, one of the funniest bits was the bit about everyone being watched by someone: The dealer watches the player, the box man watches the dealer, the pit boss watches the box men, the floor manager watches the pit bosses, the casino manager watches the floor manager, I am watching the casino manager. and in the roof are about a dozen cheats watching everything because they know every trick in the book, and the eye in the sky is watching us all. This would make you think there is more chance in play in a Casino than skill or good luck.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great, but Great to Scorsese is Mediocre to The Everyday Director
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RyanCShowers
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Trust. The fascinating theme and moral reassurance for Martin Scorsese's attempt to hit critics and audiences as hard as he hit them with his classic, Goodfellas. Unfortunately, his arm isn't strong enough to smack the audience on that level. However, he does leave a great impression thanks to his style, control, of course the two components that make his films the best of the best: his film editor and Robert DeNiro. In Spanish, "money" is translated to "diniro". Hiring Robert DeNiro to star as the leading role in a film centered around gambling. The irony is fascinating. Thrown into a role that is more simplistic than past roles Scorsese has put DeNiro front and center for, DeNiro delivers the goods and is the MVP in Casino, when his two co-stars are given much more to raise a circus with. Speaking of, Joe Pesci. While one may question the actor's range with his role choices, no one can deny him the praise he deserves at knocking these types of characters through the wall and then some. Talk about more irony. Sharon Stone was the only cast member (or crew member for that fact) to receive an Oscar nomination for her work in Casino. She gets to cry, she gets to yell, she gets to do drugs, but hardly is she ever to scratch below the surface and bring something real out in her character. Ginger is resorted to Stone's awkwardness on the screen, struggling through scenes other actresses could've killed by throwing a hissy fit. She doesn't work in the role. Not that the role isn't rooted in clich&eacute;, unoriginality, and lacks the development needed to make this trite stereotype a quality character. Much of the film is montage with narration guiding the viewer through the quick action. Scorsese films have tightly strung editing, but nothing ever like this has been produced before. The film barely gives us full length scenes until the last third, but those are drown in Stone's distracting acting efforts. It's a complete mystery to me how Casino was shot and edited; there are so many scenes to get caught up in that last 20 seconds at most some of them. Major props to the editing and Scorsese. I'm aware giving Scorsese praise in that fashion is redundant and expected with each film he directs, but here it's earned considering this is one of his weaker efforts. The film's running time is a monstrous one, and coming from a person who checks their watch incessantly in a film that's over two hours, I didn't feel the length once. It kept me interested and invested in the happenings of the story. The viewer almost rides it like a raft down a river. But, just because it's watchable doesn't always mean it's worth watching. In this case, it is worth the flaws. Flaws, in which the film erupts with as does the opening scene's car bombing. The story is fun, minutely intriguing, and entertains us with the back dealings of Vegas and then seem. But somehow the story and the characters sometimes feel like they are struggling to stay above water. Casino is very reminiscent of The Godfather and The Godfather Part II, homaging the plot arc, specific scenes, themes, subject matters, and the iconic endings. When I was growing up, my mother demanded respect at all times. Even when we were giving her respect beyond any of our peer's efforts for their parents, she still never felt it was enough. She was never going to be satisfied For DeNiro's character, Trust is his version of my mother's trust. He falls in love with Stone's character, knowing her tarnished reputation and her art of conning, but still he chooses to marry her and forces her to be loyal to him. Deep down he knows that he shouldn't trust her, but he lives reality as if she was worthy of his trust. Just as the average joe wants to believe Vegas is an honest place and in gambling you risk it all, but as the saying goes The House Always Wins. Perhaps DeNiro strives for personal strivings for trust result from his view of the unlawful acts of the city. Even though he tries to maintain legitimacy in his end of business dealings, maybe real trust cannot be found in Las Vegas. RATING: 7.5/10 GRADE: B+
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Though "Casino" is not Scorsese's strongest hour, its vision of what mob-run casinos would be like is creative
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris Mizerak
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After bringing us the outstanding 1990 crime drama GoodFellas, critically acclaimed director Martin Scorsese, author/screenwriter Nicholas Pileggi, and stars Robert DeNiro and Joe Pesci team up again for another crime drama five years later called Casino. What's interesting about Casino is that it's basically GoodFellas all over again only set in Las Vegas. It's a good thing no one came up with the idea of naming this film GoodFellas in Las Vegas, since it would make it all the more obvious to us that they're trying to recreate the same movie. That being said, does the fact that Casino bares countless similarities to GoodFellas make it bad? Not at all, it's simply a way of summarizing the movie in a nutshell. Regardless, let's take a deeper look at what we've got. Casino tells the story of a Mafia member named Sam Rothstein (Robert DeNiro) who is sent to Las Vegas to run a casino funded by the Mafia on behalf of mob families living in the Midwest. His friend Nicky Santoro (Joe Pesci) is also eventually sent to Las Vegas to watch his back. The main reason they are both there is to oversee the casino operations which largely centers on illegal activity. Basically, the Mafia has rigged the casino so that none of the customers win anything, and they make millions of dollars off of their money without the customers knowing a thing about it. Essentially, Sam and Nicky are there to make sure that their "skim" goes according to plan. But all of that changes however when a fellow hustler named Ginger (Sharon Stone) enters their lives and eventually interferes with their business to the point where there's no way they could possibly fix whatever costly mistakes erupt. The first couple minutes of Casino, when we're being introduced to the process of how these Mafia-ruled casinos work, are arguably where the most fascinating part of the entire picture resides. We not only learn that the scamming this casino gets away with on a regular basis is supposedly normal, but we are also given the scary conclusion that wasting money on gambling is the main reason people go to Las Vegas in the first place. It definitely makes people who haven't been to Las Vegas before question whether or not they want to go out of their way to a city in the middle of a desert just to lose vast sums of money. I know that it wouldn't be a town I'd want to go to yet based on what I've seen here. So I thought Casino had a fairly strong introduction based on the kind of world it was introducing us to. The rest of the film was pretty decent with Robert DeNiro and Joe Pesci turning in strong acting just like they did with GoodFellas. However, I felt that most of the main narrative was not as compelling or focused as I wanted it to be. The storytelling simply felt a little fragmented for my taste, and the love story between DeNiro and Stone doesn't help with that either. For the record, I respect that the love story does contribute to the events that take place in the second half of the film. Also, Roger Ebert's comments on how different this love story is compared with the love stories in Martin Scorsese's previous works are justified to a certain degree. Regardless, the love story still didn't do much for me at all and I think a crucial reason for that is Sharon Stone. I don't think I've seen much of her work and the ones that I do recall seeing aside from this film are Total Recall, Basic Instinct, and Antz. In my opinion, from what I've seen, she looks physically great, but her acting is too over-the-top for my liking. I'm having trouble placing my finger on it, but something about her acting just seems inappropriate for the movies she stars in. While I acknowledge that some of her roles including this one require her to be very dramatic, she has the distinction of being too childishly over dramatic that she ends up feeling way out of place in her films, this one included. While I still think Joe Pesci acts out his role reasonably well here, his role is maybe a little too identical to his work in GoodFellas. And although I do feel that the story does lose focus around the halfway point, for some reason, I still find Casino watchable enough for me to recommend it overall. And again, this is mainly because of the theories this film shows us regarding how a mob-run casino would operate. There's a well-directed scene involving the casino managers asking a customer to leave because he is placing his feet on the casino tables. Without revealing too much, the payoff of this scene isn't quite what you'd expect at first. The same thing could be said for another scene involving the casino managers dealing with someone who is maybe having too good a day at their casino. If that scene doesn't scare you off from playing and winning too much at a casino, I don't know what will. If you're looking for a story and characters that will impact you the same way Scorsese's earlier films like GoodFellas did, you might be disappointed by what Casino offers. However, if you're looking for a picture with a fascinating premise that introduces creative theories along the way and will settle for something that is at least watchable, then I think you'll like this film fine enough. As for me, though I don't think Casino ranks among Scorsese's best by a good bit and I probably don't have that much interest in looking at it again, I was satisfied enough with seeing it once. Like Las Vegas itself, approach at your own financial risk.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Casino (1995)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ashish sood (ashistrong@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Casino" is another modern classic from Martin Scorsese. Drawing parallels with his earlier "Goodfellas" , "Casino" again teams Scorsese up with writer Nicholas Pileggi having De Niro & Joe Pesci in lead traditional favourite of Scorsese. The result is a truly engaging tale of mobsters setting up a new gambling empire in Las Vegas and the subsequent ripple effects that involve the local authorities and the police. A joy from beginning to end, "Casino" is an example of a perfect movie. There's nothing you'd want to change about this film. It's full of memorable scenes that are rich with outstanding performances and dialogue and it simply demands a repeat viewing. Casino spans three decades and chronicles the true story of a faction of the mob who ran Las Vegas casinos. Robert De Niro plays Sam Ace Rothstein, a fantastic bookie who is chosen to run the Tangiers hotel and Casino. Along the way, he marries a drug-addicted con-artist trophy wife (Sharon Stone) and struggles with his friendship with loose-cannon Nicky Santoro (Joe Pesci). Rothstein is a complicated figure in that he is not a heavy, yet he wields a lot of power due to the respect he has gained from his mob bosses back home. Robert De Niro and Joe Pesci are both fantastic in their roles, and Sharon Stone actually turned out a non-irritating performance. As the viewer, you can't stand her, but that is the point. Scorsese seems to have several different directing styles, and Casino follows in the tradition of Goodfellas as a pseudo-documentary. A lot of the exposition is revealed by the characters themselves in the form of voice-overs, and several scenes are filmed in documentarian fashion. The entire production however, is sleek and very quick. The use of music bears mentioning as well: Most Martin Scorsese films have an amazing soundtrack that adds to and enhances the scene. Scorsese doesn't just utilize the soundtrack, he makes it part of the storytelling - by the music, we chronologically know what time period we are witnessing, since one cannot rely on other factors, such as fashion alone. One of my favorite scenes in film which effectively involves music is actually from Casino - the very intense scene when the relationship between DeNiro, Stone and Pesci come to a head in the climax of the film. The pounding music cut throughout this scene is a cover of "Satisfaction" by Devo and the result is absolutely brilliant. Being a complete movie buff, I generally don't watch films that feature certain stars, I go to films by certain directors and Scorsese is definitely one of them. The man is a complete genius, and a gift to any movie buff - my suggestion is to watch some of his films, then check out his unbelievable series, "A Personal Journey with Martin Scorsese Through American Movies" which was done the same year as Casino. The series is essentially a primer on the history of film, sectioned off by film genres. You not only will experience his amazing intellect and massive knowledge of film history, but his incredible humility as well. Casino has to be one of the most underrated films that Martin Scorsese directed in the nineties. The acting by the leads is good and the script is excellent. Robert De Niro gave an Oscar worthy performance and Joe Pesci is chilling yet funny again. Even Sharon Stone is good in this brilliant film. My Rating  9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pure entertainment! Pure Scorsese!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MrGadgetman
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you haven't seen this masterpiece yet..., let's just say that you need to re-prioritize your life. It's that good. It has something for everyone. Action, suspense, drama (lots of drama!) gunshots and fist fights, comedy and yes... a love story. It is beautifully shot and captures all the magic and flare of the gambling lifestyle and fast paced environment. It will easily suck you in to the movie and you never once look at your watch to notice that it's nearly 3 hours long. All the characters have substance and a purpose in the film which always gives you something (or someone) to think about while you watch the story unfold. I've seen it several times, own it on disc and still catch myself watching it when it comes on Starz...it's that good.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My Favorite Film of All Time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Film Watchin Fool
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well it doesn't get any better than Casino. The cast, acting, directing, cinematography, music, and story are top notch and it makes for a memorable watch. In my opinion this is Scorsese's best film and could watch it over and over again. It is a great mobster film that follows Ace Rothstein (Deniro) and has many trials and tribulations that comes with trying to run Tangiers Casino for the mob. Don't miss this movie and it is one you should see before you die. Put it on your list of must see movies. If you are interested in more details... Again, it is my favorite film of all time so I am a bit biased. That said, Scorsese entrenches you in Las Vegas and Ace Rothstein's reign of the Tangiers casino. Nicholas Pileggi doesn't put out anything but quality material and him and Scorsese together are like peanut butter and jelly. You can't say enough about Scorsese directing and vision in this film. I can't think of a movie that was better put together and has such a great and natural flow to it. On to the acting and casting, which is nothing short of superb. Robert Deniro is Ace Rothstein and does a fantastic job. It isn't his best work, but you couldn't have found a better actor to play the part. Joe Pesci is outstanding as Nicky Santoro and plays one of the most memorable characters in my recent memory. Sharon Stone is great as Ginger and it is arguably her best work to date. You take all that into account with the supporting cast and you have something special. The movie is lengthy, but everything about it doesn't make it seem so long. I am telling you it will go much faster than the two and half hours that it runs and be impressive the entire way. The directing and cinematography are something to marvel and I don't think it gets any better than this film. I highly recommend this to anyone looking for a outstanding gangster film. This ranks as my favorite film of all time and you won't be disappointed. Email me at filmwatchinfool@gmail.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Long But Dosen't Stop Being Interesting,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dillon Harris
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Casino is a fantastic movie with a very long and detailed storyline that stretches out to nearly three hours but it never stops being interesting and enjoyable.The cast of this movie is all brilliant and inspired,Robert De Niro,Sharon Stone and of course Joe Pesci all deliver very impressive performance,James Woods is also very good in this movie as usual but I was disappointed that he wasn't really in it that much,I thought he would have a much more important role in the movie because i've always found his acting very impressive.My only problem with the movie really is that it could have been less detailed and also,my same problem with Goodfellas,is the fact that they get different characters narrating,it should all revolve around one characters point of view so we can hear their story instead of different peoples point of views.It should have all been Robert De Niro's point of view and not changing it to Joe Pesci at times and some other characters as well.A must see for fans of Martin Scorsese and Robert De Niro movies. Story of Sam Rothstein (Robert De Niro) and Nicky Santoro (Joe Pesci) as they begin running a casino business and let their greed get the best of them.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Greed foils crime
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    StoryCharts
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Casino is tough to analyze with Story Charts. The casino racket plot (along with all the other subplots) all start at their highs and tumble down to failures. The only Controlling Idea I can think of is that crime will always fail because of greed. The Story Chart for Casino is not very interesting, basically everything crumbles because of the characters are up to no good. My main beef with the movie is two fold. One is specific about this movie: why make a movie about crime that fails when no one in the movie does any good at all and there is no moral center to the film? Since everyone is up to no good, the only rational way to keep our attention is to up the ante on how bad the characters become and how cool they when they are being bad.So a film whose central idea is about the inevitable downfall of crime betrays its central idea by making the characters "cool" and full of "attitude" and glorifying them. Seriously why do we need a movie like this? It seems to just perpetuate all the negative stereotypes about movies glorifying violence and bad characters. My second beef is in general about Martin Scorsese. I feel films like Casino and many of his other works are mostly show-and-tells rather than true storytelling by characters, conflict and consequence. This shows through most obviously through the abundant voice overs that tell us how "cool" the characters are and tells us the changes that are happening as opposed to showing us through action and consequence. I think voice overs are the nemesis of absorbing movie making and Casino spends about half its time with its characters voicing over stuff that happens on screen: its like a holiday slide-show from "cool" gangsters. I think Casino tries to objectively document a period of Vegas excess driven by a few characters and their criminal ways. It's voice overs certainly make it documentary-like. But its glorification of how cool these guys subjectively tells us to sympathize with these criminals on their inevitable demise. I don't get it, why make a movie that suggests crime doesn't pay but suggest it's cool to be a criminal? How does this make the world a better place? If it doesn't, why make movies at all? My Story Chart of the movie is at storycharts.ca
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Scorsese at his Top...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Janis Livens
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Casino is a great Scorsese film from the mid 90's and it's in my opinion one his better films up there with Goodfellas and Taxi Driver. It showcases excellent performances, great story and his exceptional eye for visuals. While it run for almost three hours, I was never bored, it never dragged for me and I was completely immersed in the story being told. I agree that Casino should have been shorter and they could have toned the violence slightly down, but end result just doesn't really bother me. It's very engaging, the actors pretty much own the film. giving very strong performances. The reason why Casino doesn't get as much of acclaim as it should, is because of Goodfellas. Tonally and if you look at the story itself, they are rather similar. Some details are different but the overall feel of the story and the way it's told is surprisingly similar. Even at 3 hour run time they miss out on some details and leave some treads hanging. But as a whole the film worked really well and I completely engrossed in the world Scorsese had created. I would say that this film is a must see for anyone who likes a good story surrounding Las Vegas, the mob or just experience excellent actors giving all they got. A definite must see.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    In one word: overrated
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Fuzius
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After telling a friend I enjoyed The Godfather trilogy, he recommended I watch this film. And I'm sorry to say I totally regret doing so. This film is the opposite of The Godfather. It has zero emotional content. The characters are intentionally one dimensional, idiotic and therefor impossible to identify with. Most of the movie feature narration, which at first feels welcome and classic, but soon grows tiring because instead of the movie just "happening", the narration disrupts the acting all throughout the 3 hours. Now I know many might consider this one a classic, but I will bet you right here and now, that non of the actors playing in "Casino" would willingly sit through this 3 hour torture.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not to be missed mob movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    donpauliano
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was one of the first Movies I can recall watching that gives a little insight into how the Mafia make a living out of legitimate Business. along with titles such as Donnie Brasco, Goodfellas and the Godfather, which I enjoyed each immensely, Casino doesn't only show the dark side of organized crime but the ups and downs of their personal lives too. I watched Casino for the first time with my crew at the Cinema, we loved the outfits that De niro wears and his head for perfection as Casino Manager it really made us chuckle, one of the funniest bits was the bit about everyone being watched by someone: The dealer watches the player, the box man watches the dealer, the pit boss watches the box men, the floor manager watches the pit bosses, the casino manager watches the floor manager, I am watching the casino manager. and in the roof are about a dozen cheats watching everything because they know every trick in the book, and the eye in the sky is watching us all. This would make you think there is more chance in play in a Casino than skill or good luck.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great, but Great to Scorsese is Mediocre to The Everyday Director
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RyanCShowers
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Trust. The fascinating theme and moral reassurance for Martin Scorsese's attempt to hit critics and audiences as hard as he hit them with his classic, Goodfellas. Unfortunately, his arm isn't strong enough to smack the audience on that level. However, he does leave a great impression thanks to his style, control, of course the two components that make his films the best of the best: his film editor and Robert DeNiro. In Spanish, "money" is translated to "diniro". Hiring Robert DeNiro to star as the leading role in a film centered around gambling. The irony is fascinating. Thrown into a role that is more simplistic than past roles Scorsese has put DeNiro front and center for, DeNiro delivers the goods and is the MVP in Casino, when his two co-stars are given much more to raise a circus with. Speaking of, Joe Pesci. While one may question the actor's range with his role choices, no one can deny him the praise he deserves at knocking these types of characters through the wall and then some. Talk about more irony. Sharon Stone was the only cast member (or crew member for that fact) to receive an Oscar nomination for her work in Casino. She gets to cry, she gets to yell, she gets to do drugs, but hardly is she ever to scratch below the surface and bring something real out in her character. Ginger is resorted to Stone's awkwardness on the screen, struggling through scenes other actresses could've killed by throwing a hissy fit. She doesn't work in the role. Not that the role isn't rooted in clich&eacute;, unoriginality, and lacks the development needed to make this trite stereotype a quality character. Much of the film is montage with narration guiding the viewer through the quick action. Scorsese films have tightly strung editing, but nothing ever like this has been produced before. The film barely gives us full length scenes until the last third, but those are drown in Stone's distracting acting efforts. It's a complete mystery to me how Casino was shot and edited; there are so many scenes to get caught up in that last 20 seconds at most some of them. Major props to the editing and Scorsese. I'm aware giving Scorsese praise in that fashion is redundant and expected with each film he directs, but here it's earned considering this is one of his weaker efforts. The film's running time is a monstrous one, and coming from a person who checks their watch incessantly in a film that's over two hours, I didn't feel the length once. It kept me interested and invested in the happenings of the story. The viewer almost rides it like a raft down a river. But, just because it's watchable doesn't always mean it's worth watching. In this case, it is worth the flaws. Flaws, in which the film erupts with as does the opening scene's car bombing. The story is fun, minutely intriguing, and entertains us with the back dealings of Vegas and then seem. But somehow the story and the characters sometimes feel like they are struggling to stay above water. Casino is very reminiscent of The Godfather and The Godfather Part II, homaging the plot arc, specific scenes, themes, subject matters, and the iconic endings. When I was growing up, my mother demanded respect at all times. Even when we were giving her respect beyond any of our peer's efforts for their parents, she still never felt it was enough. She was never going to be satisfied For DeNiro's character, Trust is his version of my mother's trust. He falls in love with Stone's character, knowing her tarnished reputation and her art of conning, but still he chooses to marry her and forces her to be loyal to him. Deep down he knows that he shouldn't trust her, but he lives reality as if she was worthy of his trust. Just as the average joe wants to believe Vegas is an honest place and in gambling you risk it all, but as the saying goes The House Always Wins. Perhaps DeNiro strives for personal strivings for trust result from his view of the unlawful acts of the city. Even though he tries to maintain legitimacy in his end of business dealings, maybe real trust cannot be found in Las Vegas. RATING: 7.5/10 GRADE: B+
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Though "Casino" is not Scorsese's strongest hour, its vision of what mob-run casinos would be like is creative
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris Mizerak
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After bringing us the outstanding 1990 crime drama GoodFellas, critically acclaimed director Martin Scorsese, author/screenwriter Nicholas Pileggi, and stars Robert DeNiro and Joe Pesci team up again for another crime drama five years later called Casino. What's interesting about Casino is that it's basically GoodFellas all over again only set in Las Vegas. It's a good thing no one came up with the idea of naming this film GoodFellas in Las Vegas, since it would make it all the more obvious to us that they're trying to recreate the same movie. That being said, does the fact that Casino bares countless similarities to GoodFellas make it bad? Not at all, it's simply a way of summarizing the movie in a nutshell. Regardless, let's take a deeper look at what we've got. Casino tells the story of a Mafia member named Sam Rothstein (Robert DeNiro) who is sent to Las Vegas to run a casino funded by the Mafia on behalf of mob families living in the Midwest. His friend Nicky Santoro (Joe Pesci) is also eventually sent to Las Vegas to watch his back. The main reason they are both there is to oversee the casino operations which largely centers on illegal activity. Basically, the Mafia has rigged the casino so that none of the customers win anything, and they make millions of dollars off of their money without the customers knowing a thing about it. Essentially, Sam and Nicky are there to make sure that their "skim" goes according to plan. But all of that changes however when a fellow hustler named Ginger (Sharon Stone) enters their lives and eventually interferes with their business to the point where there's no way they could possibly fix whatever costly mistakes erupt. The first couple minutes of Casino, when we're being introduced to the process of how these Mafia-ruled casinos work, are arguably where the most fascinating part of the entire picture resides. We not only learn that the scamming this casino gets away with on a regular basis is supposedly normal, but we are also given the scary conclusion that wasting money on gambling is the main reason people go to Las Vegas in the first place. It definitely makes people who haven't been to Las Vegas before question whether or not they want to go out of their way to a city in the middle of a desert just to lose vast sums of money. I know that it wouldn't be a town I'd want to go to yet based on what I've seen here. So I thought Casino had a fairly strong introduction based on the kind of world it was introducing us to. The rest of the film was pretty decent with Robert DeNiro and Joe Pesci turning in strong acting just like they did with GoodFellas. However, I felt that most of the main narrative was not as compelling or focused as I wanted it to be. The storytelling simply felt a little fragmented for my taste, and the love story between DeNiro and Stone doesn't help with that either. For the record, I respect that the love story does contribute to the events that take place in the second half of the film. Also, Roger Ebert's comments on how different this love story is compared with the love stories in Martin Scorsese's previous works are justified to a certain degree. Regardless, the love story still didn't do much for me at all and I think a crucial reason for that is Sharon Stone. I don't think I've seen much of her work and the ones that I do recall seeing aside from this film are Total Recall, Basic Instinct, and Antz. In my opinion, from what I've seen, she looks physically great, but her acting is too over-the-top for my liking. I'm having trouble placing my finger on it, but something about her acting just seems inappropriate for the movies she stars in. While I acknowledge that some of her roles including this one require her to be very dramatic, she has the distinction of being too childishly over dramatic that she ends up feeling way out of place in her films, this one included. While I still think Joe Pesci acts out his role reasonably well here, his role is maybe a little too identical to his work in GoodFellas. And although I do feel that the story does lose focus around the halfway point, for some reason, I still find Casino watchable enough for me to recommend it overall. And again, this is mainly because of the theories this film shows us regarding how a mob-run casino would operate. There's a well-directed scene involving the casino managers asking a customer to leave because he is placing his feet on the casino tables. Without revealing too much, the payoff of this scene isn't quite what you'd expect at first. The same thing could be said for another scene involving the casino managers dealing with someone who is maybe having too good a day at their casino. If that scene doesn't scare you off from playing and winning too much at a casino, I don't know what will. If you're looking for a story and characters that will impact you the same way Scorsese's earlier films like GoodFellas did, you might be disappointed by what Casino offers. However, if you're looking for a picture with a fascinating premise that introduces creative theories along the way and will settle for something that is at least watchable, then I think you'll like this film fine enough. As for me, though I don't think Casino ranks among Scorsese's best by a good bit and I probably don't have that much interest in looking at it again, I was satisfied enough with seeing it once. Like Las Vegas itself, approach at your own financial risk.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Casino (1995)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ashish sood (ashistrong@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Casino" is another modern classic from Martin Scorsese. Drawing parallels with his earlier "Goodfellas" , "Casino" again teams Scorsese up with writer Nicholas Pileggi having De Niro & Joe Pesci in lead traditional favourite of Scorsese. The result is a truly engaging tale of mobsters setting up a new gambling empire in Las Vegas and the subsequent ripple effects that involve the local authorities and the police. A joy from beginning to end, "Casino" is an example of a perfect movie. There's nothing you'd want to change about this film. It's full of memorable scenes that are rich with outstanding performances and dialogue and it simply demands a repeat viewing. Casino spans three decades and chronicles the true story of a faction of the mob who ran Las Vegas casinos. Robert De Niro plays Sam Ace Rothstein, a fantastic bookie who is chosen to run the Tangiers hotel and Casino. Along the way, he marries a drug-addicted con-artist trophy wife (Sharon Stone) and struggles with his friendship with loose-cannon Nicky Santoro (Joe Pesci). Rothstein is a complicated figure in that he is not a heavy, yet he wields a lot of power due to the respect he has gained from his mob bosses back home. Robert De Niro and Joe Pesci are both fantastic in their roles, and Sharon Stone actually turned out a non-irritating performance. As the viewer, you can't stand her, but that is the point. Scorsese seems to have several different directing styles, and Casino follows in the tradition of Goodfellas as a pseudo-documentary. A lot of the exposition is revealed by the characters themselves in the form of voice-overs, and several scenes are filmed in documentarian fashion. The entire production however, is sleek and very quick. The use of music bears mentioning as well: Most Martin Scorsese films have an amazing soundtrack that adds to and enhances the scene. Scorsese doesn't just utilize the soundtrack, he makes it part of the storytelling - by the music, we chronologically know what time period we are witnessing, since one cannot rely on other factors, such as fashion alone. One of my favorite scenes in film which effectively involves music is actually from Casino - the very intense scene when the relationship between DeNiro, Stone and Pesci come to a head in the climax of the film. The pounding music cut throughout this scene is a cover of "Satisfaction" by Devo and the result is absolutely brilliant. Being a complete movie buff, I generally don't watch films that feature certain stars, I go to films by certain directors and Scorsese is definitely one of them. The man is a complete genius, and a gift to any movie buff - my suggestion is to watch some of his films, then check out his unbelievable series, "A Personal Journey with Martin Scorsese Through American Movies" which was done the same year as Casino. The series is essentially a primer on the history of film, sectioned off by film genres. You not only will experience his amazing intellect and massive knowledge of film history, but his incredible humility as well. Casino has to be one of the most underrated films that Martin Scorsese directed in the nineties. The acting by the leads is good and the script is excellent. Robert De Niro gave an Oscar worthy performance and Joe Pesci is chilling yet funny again. Even Sharon Stone is good in this brilliant film. My Rating  9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pure entertainment! Pure Scorsese!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MrGadgetman
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you haven't seen this masterpiece yet..., let's just say that you need to re-prioritize your life. It's that good. It has something for everyone. Action, suspense, drama (lots of drama!) gunshots and fist fights, comedy and yes... a love story. It is beautifully shot and captures all the magic and flare of the gambling lifestyle and fast paced environment. It will easily suck you in to the movie and you never once look at your watch to notice that it's nearly 3 hours long. All the characters have substance and a purpose in the film which always gives you something (or someone) to think about while you watch the story unfold. I've seen it several times, own it on disc and still catch myself watching it when it comes on Starz...it's that good.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My Favorite Film of All Time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Film Watchin Fool
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well it doesn't get any better than Casino. The cast, acting, directing, cinematography, music, and story are top notch and it makes for a memorable watch. In my opinion this is Scorsese's best film and could watch it over and over again. It is a great mobster film that follows Ace Rothstein (Deniro) and has many trials and tribulations that comes with trying to run Tangiers Casino for the mob. Don't miss this movie and it is one you should see before you die. Put it on your list of must see movies. If you are interested in more details... Again, it is my favorite film of all time so I am a bit biased. That said, Scorsese entrenches you in Las Vegas and Ace Rothstein's reign of the Tangiers casino. Nicholas Pileggi doesn't put out anything but quality material and him and Scorsese together are like peanut butter and jelly. You can't say enough about Scorsese directing and vision in this film. I can't think of a movie that was better put together and has such a great and natural flow to it. On to the acting and casting, which is nothing short of superb. Robert Deniro is Ace Rothstein and does a fantastic job. It isn't his best work, but you couldn't have found a better actor to play the part. Joe Pesci is outstanding as Nicky Santoro and plays one of the most memorable characters in my recent memory. Sharon Stone is great as Ginger and it is arguably her best work to date. You take all that into account with the supporting cast and you have something special. The movie is lengthy, but everything about it doesn't make it seem so long. I am telling you it will go much faster than the two and half hours that it runs and be impressive the entire way. The directing and cinematography are something to marvel and I don't think it gets any better than this film. I highly recommend this to anyone looking for a outstanding gangster film. This ranks as my favorite film of all time and you won't be disappointed. Email me at filmwatchinfool@gmail.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Long But Dosen't Stop Being Interesting,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dillon Harris
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Casino is a fantastic movie with a very long and detailed storyline that stretches out to nearly three hours but it never stops being interesting and enjoyable.The cast of this movie is all brilliant and inspired,Robert De Niro,Sharon Stone and of course Joe Pesci all deliver very impressive performance,James Woods is also very good in this movie as usual but I was disappointed that he wasn't really in it that much,I thought he would have a much more important role in the movie because i've always found his acting very impressive.My only problem with the movie really is that it could have been less detailed and also,my same problem with Goodfellas,is the fact that they get different characters narrating,it should all revolve around one characters point of view so we can hear their story instead of different peoples point of views.It should have all been Robert De Niro's point of view and not changing it to Joe Pesci at times and some other characters as well.A must see for fans of Martin Scorsese and Robert De Niro movies. Story of Sam Rothstein (Robert De Niro) and Nicky Santoro (Joe Pesci) as they begin running a casino business and let their greed get the best of them.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Greed foils crime
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    StoryCharts
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Casino is tough to analyze with Story Charts. The casino racket plot (along with all the other subplots) all start at their highs and tumble down to failures. The only Controlling Idea I can think of is that crime will always fail because of greed. The Story Chart for Casino is not very interesting, basically everything crumbles because of the characters are up to no good. My main beef with the movie is two fold. One is specific about this movie: why make a movie about crime that fails when no one in the movie does any good at all and there is no moral center to the film? Since everyone is up to no good, the only rational way to keep our attention is to up the ante on how bad the characters become and how cool they when they are being bad.So a film whose central idea is about the inevitable downfall of crime betrays its central idea by making the characters "cool" and full of "attitude" and glorifying them. Seriously why do we need a movie like this? It seems to just perpetuate all the negative stereotypes about movies glorifying violence and bad characters. My second beef is in general about Martin Scorsese. I feel films like Casino and many of his other works are mostly show-and-tells rather than true storytelling by characters, conflict and consequence. This shows through most obviously through the abundant voice overs that tell us how "cool" the characters are and tells us the changes that are happening as opposed to showing us through action and consequence. I think voice overs are the nemesis of absorbing movie making and Casino spends about half its time with its characters voicing over stuff that happens on screen: its like a holiday slide-show from "cool" gangsters. I think Casino tries to objectively document a period of Vegas excess driven by a few characters and their criminal ways. It's voice overs certainly make it documentary-like. But its glorification of how cool these guys subjectively tells us to sympathize with these criminals on their inevitable demise. I don't get it, why make a movie that suggests crime doesn't pay but suggest it's cool to be a criminal? How does this make the world a better place? If it doesn't, why make movies at all? My Story Chart of the movie is at storycharts.ca
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Scorsese at his Top...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Janis Livens
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Casino is a great Scorsese film from the mid 90's and it's in my opinion one his better films up there with Goodfellas and Taxi Driver. It showcases excellent performances, great story and his exceptional eye for visuals. While it run for almost three hours, I was never bored, it never dragged for me and I was completely immersed in the story being told. I agree that Casino should have been shorter and they could have toned the violence slightly down, but end result just doesn't really bother me. It's very engaging, the actors pretty much own the film. giving very strong performances. The reason why Casino doesn't get as much of acclaim as it should, is because of Goodfellas. Tonally and if you look at the story itself, they are rather similar. Some details are different but the overall feel of the story and the way it's told is surprisingly similar. Even at 3 hour run time they miss out on some details and leave some treads hanging. But as a whole the film worked really well and I completely engrossed in the world Scorsese had created. I would say that this film is a must see for anyone who likes a good story surrounding Las Vegas, the mob or just experience excellent actors giving all they got. A definite must see.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    In one word: overrated
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Fuzius
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After telling a friend I enjoyed The Godfather trilogy, he recommended I watch this film. And I'm sorry to say I totally regret doing so. This film is the opposite of The Godfather. It has zero emotional content. The characters are intentionally one dimensional, idiotic and therefor impossible to identify with. Most of the movie feature narration, which at first feels welcome and classic, but soon grows tiring because instead of the movie just "happening", the narration disrupts the acting all throughout the 3 hours. Now I know many might consider this one a classic, but I will bet you right here and now, that non of the actors playing in "Casino" would willingly sit through this 3 hour torture.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not to be missed mob movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    donpauliano
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was one of the first Movies I can recall watching that gives a little insight into how the Mafia make a living out of legitimate Business. along with titles such as Donnie Brasco, Goodfellas and the Godfather, which I enjoyed each immensely, Casino doesn't only show the dark side of organized crime but the ups and downs of their personal lives too. I watched Casino for the first time with my crew at the Cinema, we loved the outfits that De niro wears and his head for perfection as Casino Manager it really made us chuckle, one of the funniest bits was the bit about everyone being watched by someone: The dealer watches the player, the box man watches the dealer, the pit boss watches the box men, the floor manager watches the pit bosses, the casino manager watches the floor manager, I am watching the casino manager. and in the roof are about a dozen cheats watching everything because they know every trick in the book, and the eye in the sky is watching us all. This would make you think there is more chance in play in a Casino than skill or good luck.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great, but Great to Scorsese is Mediocre to The Everyday Director
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RyanCShowers
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Trust. The fascinating theme and moral reassurance for Martin Scorsese's attempt to hit critics and audiences as hard as he hit them with his classic, Goodfellas. Unfortunately, his arm isn't strong enough to smack the audience on that level. However, he does leave a great impression thanks to his style, control, of course the two components that make his films the best of the best: his film editor and Robert DeNiro. In Spanish, "money" is translated to "diniro". Hiring Robert DeNiro to star as the leading role in a film centered around gambling. The irony is fascinating. Thrown into a role that is more simplistic than past roles Scorsese has put DeNiro front and center for, DeNiro delivers the goods and is the MVP in Casino, when his two co-stars are given much more to raise a circus with. Speaking of, Joe Pesci. While one may question the actor's range with his role choices, no one can deny him the praise he deserves at knocking these types of characters through the wall and then some. Talk about more irony. Sharon Stone was the only cast member (or crew member for that fact) to receive an Oscar nomination for her work in Casino. She gets to cry, she gets to yell, she gets to do drugs, but hardly is she ever to scratch below the surface and bring something real out in her character. Ginger is resorted to Stone's awkwardness on the screen, struggling through scenes other actresses could've killed by throwing a hissy fit. She doesn't work in the role. Not that the role isn't rooted in clich&eacute;, unoriginality, and lacks the development needed to make this trite stereotype a quality character. Much of the film is montage with narration guiding the viewer through the quick action. Scorsese films have tightly strung editing, but nothing ever like this has been produced before. The film barely gives us full length scenes until the last third, but those are drown in Stone's distracting acting efforts. It's a complete mystery to me how Casino was shot and edited; there are so many scenes to get caught up in that last 20 seconds at most some of them. Major props to the editing and Scorsese. I'm aware giving Scorsese praise in that fashion is redundant and expected with each film he directs, but here it's earned considering this is one of his weaker efforts. The film's running time is a monstrous one, and coming from a person who checks their watch incessantly in a film that's over two hours, I didn't feel the length once. It kept me interested and invested in the happenings of the story. The viewer almost rides it like a raft down a river. But, just because it's watchable doesn't always mean it's worth watching. In this case, it is worth the flaws. Flaws, in which the film erupts with as does the opening scene's car bombing. The story is fun, minutely intriguing, and entertains us with the back dealings of Vegas and then seem. But somehow the story and the characters sometimes feel like they are struggling to stay above water. Casino is very reminiscent of The Godfather and The Godfather Part II, homaging the plot arc, specific scenes, themes, subject matters, and the iconic endings. When I was growing up, my mother demanded respect at all times. Even when we were giving her respect beyond any of our peer's efforts for their parents, she still never felt it was enough. She was never going to be satisfied For DeNiro's character, Trust is his version of my mother's trust. He falls in love with Stone's character, knowing her tarnished reputation and her art of conning, but still he chooses to marry her and forces her to be loyal to him. Deep down he knows that he shouldn't trust her, but he lives reality as if she was worthy of his trust. Just as the average joe wants to believe Vegas is an honest place and in gambling you risk it all, but as the saying goes The House Always Wins. Perhaps DeNiro strives for personal strivings for trust result from his view of the unlawful acts of the city. Even though he tries to maintain legitimacy in his end of business dealings, maybe real trust cannot be found in Las Vegas. RATING: 7.5/10 GRADE: B+
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Though "Casino" is not Scorsese's strongest hour, its vision of what mob-run casinos would be like is creative
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris Mizerak
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After bringing us the outstanding 1990 crime drama GoodFellas, critically acclaimed director Martin Scorsese, author/screenwriter Nicholas Pileggi, and stars Robert DeNiro and Joe Pesci team up again for another crime drama five years later called Casino. What's interesting about Casino is that it's basically GoodFellas all over again only set in Las Vegas. It's a good thing no one came up with the idea of naming this film GoodFellas in Las Vegas, since it would make it all the more obvious to us that they're trying to recreate the same movie. That being said, does the fact that Casino bares countless similarities to GoodFellas make it bad? Not at all, it's simply a way of summarizing the movie in a nutshell. Regardless, let's take a deeper look at what we've got. Casino tells the story of a Mafia member named Sam Rothstein (Robert DeNiro) who is sent to Las Vegas to run a casino funded by the Mafia on behalf of mob families living in the Midwest. His friend Nicky Santoro (Joe Pesci) is also eventually sent to Las Vegas to watch his back. The main reason they are both there is to oversee the casino operations which largely centers on illegal activity. Basically, the Mafia has rigged the casino so that none of the customers win anything, and they make millions of dollars off of their money without the customers knowing a thing about it. Essentially, Sam and Nicky are there to make sure that their "skim" goes according to plan. But all of that changes however when a fellow hustler named Ginger (Sharon Stone) enters their lives and eventually interferes with their business to the point where there's no way they could possibly fix whatever costly mistakes erupt. The first couple minutes of Casino, when we're being introduced to the process of how these Mafia-ruled casinos work, are arguably where the most fascinating part of the entire picture resides. We not only learn that the scamming this casino gets away with on a regular basis is supposedly normal, but we are also given the scary conclusion that wasting money on gambling is the main reason people go to Las Vegas in the first place. It definitely makes people who haven't been to Las Vegas before question whether or not they want to go out of their way to a city in the middle of a desert just to lose vast sums of money. I know that it wouldn't be a town I'd want to go to yet based on what I've seen here. So I thought Casino had a fairly strong introduction based on the kind of world it was introducing us to. The rest of the film was pretty decent with Robert DeNiro and Joe Pesci turning in strong acting just like they did with GoodFellas. However, I felt that most of the main narrative was not as compelling or focused as I wanted it to be. The storytelling simply felt a little fragmented for my taste, and the love story between DeNiro and Stone doesn't help with that either. For the record, I respect that the love story does contribute to the events that take place in the second half of the film. Also, Roger Ebert's comments on how different this love story is compared with the love stories in Martin Scorsese's previous works are justified to a certain degree. Regardless, the love story still didn't do much for me at all and I think a crucial reason for that is Sharon Stone. I don't think I've seen much of her work and the ones that I do recall seeing aside from this film are Total Recall, Basic Instinct, and Antz. In my opinion, from what I've seen, she looks physically great, but her acting is too over-the-top for my liking. I'm having trouble placing my finger on it, but something about her acting just seems inappropriate for the movies she stars in. While I acknowledge that some of her roles including this one require her to be very dramatic, she has the distinction of being too childishly over dramatic that she ends up feeling way out of place in her films, this one included. While I still think Joe Pesci acts out his role reasonably well here, his role is maybe a little too identical to his work in GoodFellas. And although I do feel that the story does lose focus around the halfway point, for some reason, I still find Casino watchable enough for me to recommend it overall. And again, this is mainly because of the theories this film shows us regarding how a mob-run casino would operate. There's a well-directed scene involving the casino managers asking a customer to leave because he is placing his feet on the casino tables. Without revealing too much, the payoff of this scene isn't quite what you'd expect at first. The same thing could be said for another scene involving the casino managers dealing with someone who is maybe having too good a day at their casino. If that scene doesn't scare you off from playing and winning too much at a casino, I don't know what will. If you're looking for a story and characters that will impact you the same way Scorsese's earlier films like GoodFellas did, you might be disappointed by what Casino offers. However, if you're looking for a picture with a fascinating premise that introduces creative theories along the way and will settle for something that is at least watchable, then I think you'll like this film fine enough. As for me, though I don't think Casino ranks among Scorsese's best by a good bit and I probably don't have that much interest in looking at it again, I was satisfied enough with seeing it once. Like Las Vegas itself, approach at your own financial risk.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Casino (1995)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ashish sood (ashistrong@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Casino" is another modern classic from Martin Scorsese. Drawing parallels with his earlier "Goodfellas" , "Casino" again teams Scorsese up with writer Nicholas Pileggi having De Niro & Joe Pesci in lead traditional favourite of Scorsese. The result is a truly engaging tale of mobsters setting up a new gambling empire in Las Vegas and the subsequent ripple effects that involve the local authorities and the police. A joy from beginning to end, "Casino" is an example of a perfect movie. There's nothing you'd want to change about this film. It's full of memorable scenes that are rich with outstanding performances and dialogue and it simply demands a repeat viewing. Casino spans three decades and chronicles the true story of a faction of the mob who ran Las Vegas casinos. Robert De Niro plays Sam Ace Rothstein, a fantastic bookie who is chosen to run the Tangiers hotel and Casino. Along the way, he marries a drug-addicted con-artist trophy wife (Sharon Stone) and struggles with his friendship with loose-cannon Nicky Santoro (Joe Pesci). Rothstein is a complicated figure in that he is not a heavy, yet he wields a lot of power due to the respect he has gained from his mob bosses back home. Robert De Niro and Joe Pesci are both fantastic in their roles, and Sharon Stone actually turned out a non-irritating performance. As the viewer, you can't stand her, but that is the point. Scorsese seems to have several different directing styles, and Casino follows in the tradition of Goodfellas as a pseudo-documentary. A lot of the exposition is revealed by the characters themselves in the form of voice-overs, and several scenes are filmed in documentarian fashion. The entire production however, is sleek and very quick. The use of music bears mentioning as well: Most Martin Scorsese films have an amazing soundtrack that adds to and enhances the scene. Scorsese doesn't just utilize the soundtrack, he makes it part of the storytelling - by the music, we chronologically know what time period we are witnessing, since one cannot rely on other factors, such as fashion alone. One of my favorite scenes in film which effectively involves music is actually from Casino - the very intense scene when the relationship between DeNiro, Stone and Pesci come to a head in the climax of the film. The pounding music cut throughout this scene is a cover of "Satisfaction" by Devo and the result is absolutely brilliant. Being a complete movie buff, I generally don't watch films that feature certain stars, I go to films by certain directors and Scorsese is definitely one of them. The man is a complete genius, and a gift to any movie buff - my suggestion is to watch some of his films, then check out his unbelievable series, "A Personal Journey with Martin Scorsese Through American Movies" which was done the same year as Casino. The series is essentially a primer on the history of film, sectioned off by film genres. You not only will experience his amazing intellect and massive knowledge of film history, but his incredible humility as well. Casino has to be one of the most underrated films that Martin Scorsese directed in the nineties. The acting by the leads is good and the script is excellent. Robert De Niro gave an Oscar worthy performance and Joe Pesci is chilling yet funny again. Even Sharon Stone is good in this brilliant film. My Rating  9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pure entertainment! Pure Scorsese!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MrGadgetman
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you haven't seen this masterpiece yet..., let's just say that you need to re-prioritize your life. It's that good. It has something for everyone. Action, suspense, drama (lots of drama!) gunshots and fist fights, comedy and yes... a love story. It is beautifully shot and captures all the magic and flare of the gambling lifestyle and fast paced environment. It will easily suck you in to the movie and you never once look at your watch to notice that it's nearly 3 hours long. All the characters have substance and a purpose in the film which always gives you something (or someone) to think about while you watch the story unfold. I've seen it several times, own it on disc and still catch myself watching it when it comes on Starz...it's that good.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My Favorite Film of All Time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Film Watchin Fool
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well it doesn't get any better than Casino. The cast, acting, directing, cinematography, music, and story are top notch and it makes for a memorable watch. In my opinion this is Scorsese's best film and could watch it over and over again. It is a great mobster film that follows Ace Rothstein (Deniro) and has many trials and tribulations that comes with trying to run Tangiers Casino for the mob. Don't miss this movie and it is one you should see before you die. Put it on your list of must see movies. If you are interested in more details... Again, it is my favorite film of all time so I am a bit biased. That said, Scorsese entrenches you in Las Vegas and Ace Rothstein's reign of the Tangiers casino. Nicholas Pileggi doesn't put out anything but quality material and him and Scorsese together are like peanut butter and jelly. You can't say enough about Scorsese directing and vision in this film. I can't think of a movie that was better put together and has such a great and natural flow to it. On to the acting and casting, which is nothing short of superb. Robert Deniro is Ace Rothstein and does a fantastic job. It isn't his best work, but you couldn't have found a better actor to play the part. Joe Pesci is outstanding as Nicky Santoro and plays one of the most memorable characters in my recent memory. Sharon Stone is great as Ginger and it is arguably her best work to date. You take all that into account with the supporting cast and you have something special. The movie is lengthy, but everything about it doesn't make it seem so long. I am telling you it will go much faster than the two and half hours that it runs and be impressive the entire way. The directing and cinematography are something to marvel and I don't think it gets any better than this film. I highly recommend this to anyone looking for a outstanding gangster film. This ranks as my favorite film of all time and you won't be disappointed. Email me at filmwatchinfool@gmail.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Long But Dosen't Stop Being Interesting,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dillon Harris
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Casino is a fantastic movie with a very long and detailed storyline that stretches out to nearly three hours but it never stops being interesting and enjoyable.The cast of this movie is all brilliant and inspired,Robert De Niro,Sharon Stone and of course Joe Pesci all deliver very impressive performance,James Woods is also very good in this movie as usual but I was disappointed that he wasn't really in it that much,I thought he would have a much more important role in the movie because i've always found his acting very impressive.My only problem with the movie really is that it could have been less detailed and also,my same problem with Goodfellas,is the fact that they get different characters narrating,it should all revolve around one characters point of view so we can hear their story instead of different peoples point of views.It should have all been Robert De Niro's point of view and not changing it to Joe Pesci at times and some other characters as well.A must see for fans of Martin Scorsese and Robert De Niro movies. Story of Sam Rothstein (Robert De Niro) and Nicky Santoro (Joe Pesci) as they begin running a casino business and let their greed get the best of them.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Greed foils crime
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    StoryCharts
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Casino is tough to analyze with Story Charts. The casino racket plot (along with all the other subplots) all start at their highs and tumble down to failures. The only Controlling Idea I can think of is that crime will always fail because of greed. The Story Chart for Casino is not very interesting, basically everything crumbles because of the characters are up to no good. My main beef with the movie is two fold. One is specific about this movie: why make a movie about crime that fails when no one in the movie does any good at all and there is no moral center to the film? Since everyone is up to no good, the only rational way to keep our attention is to up the ante on how bad the characters become and how cool they when they are being bad.So a film whose central idea is about the inevitable downfall of crime betrays its central idea by making the characters "cool" and full of "attitude" and glorifying them. Seriously why do we need a movie like this? It seems to just perpetuate all the negative stereotypes about movies glorifying violence and bad characters. My second beef is in general about Martin Scorsese. I feel films like Casino and many of his other works are mostly show-and-tells rather than true storytelling by characters, conflict and consequence. This shows through most obviously through the abundant voice overs that tell us how "cool" the characters are and tells us the changes that are happening as opposed to showing us through action and consequence. I think voice overs are the nemesis of absorbing movie making and Casino spends about half its time with its characters voicing over stuff that happens on screen: its like a holiday slide-show from "cool" gangsters. I think Casino tries to objectively document a period of Vegas excess driven by a few characters and their criminal ways. It's voice overs certainly make it documentary-like. But its glorification of how cool these guys subjectively tells us to sympathize with these criminals on their inevitable demise. I don't get it, why make a movie that suggests crime doesn't pay but suggest it's cool to be a criminal? How does this make the world a better place? If it doesn't, why make movies at all? My Story Chart of the movie is at storycharts.ca
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Scorsese at his Top...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Janis Livens
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Casino is a great Scorsese film from the mid 90's and it's in my opinion one his better films up there with Goodfellas and Taxi Driver. It showcases excellent performances, great story and his exceptional eye for visuals. While it run for almost three hours, I was never bored, it never dragged for me and I was completely immersed in the story being told. I agree that Casino should have been shorter and they could have toned the violence slightly down, but end result just doesn't really bother me. It's very engaging, the actors pretty much own the film. giving very strong performances. The reason why Casino doesn't get as much of acclaim as it should, is because of Goodfellas. Tonally and if you look at the story itself, they are rather similar. Some details are different but the overall feel of the story and the way it's told is surprisingly similar. Even at 3 hour run time they miss out on some details and leave some treads hanging. But as a whole the film worked really well and I completely engrossed in the world Scorsese had created. I would say that this film is a must see for anyone who likes a good story surrounding Las Vegas, the mob or just experience excellent actors giving all they got. A definite must see.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    In one word: overrated
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Fuzius
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After telling a friend I enjoyed The Godfather trilogy, he recommended I watch this film. And I'm sorry to say I totally regret doing so. This film is the opposite of The Godfather. It has zero emotional content. The characters are intentionally one dimensional, idiotic and therefor impossible to identify with. Most of the movie feature narration, which at first feels welcome and classic, but soon grows tiring because instead of the movie just "happening", the narration disrupts the acting all throughout the 3 hours. Now I know many might consider this one a classic, but I will bet you right here and now, that non of the actors playing in "Casino" would willingly sit through this 3 hour torture.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not to be missed mob movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    donpauliano
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was one of the first Movies I can recall watching that gives a little insight into how the Mafia make a living out of legitimate Business. along with titles such as Donnie Brasco, Goodfellas and the Godfather, which I enjoyed each immensely, Casino doesn't only show the dark side of organized crime but the ups and downs of their personal lives too. I watched Casino for the first time with my crew at the Cinema, we loved the outfits that De niro wears and his head for perfection as Casino Manager it really made us chuckle, one of the funniest bits was the bit about everyone being watched by someone: The dealer watches the player, the box man watches the dealer, the pit boss watches the box men, the floor manager watches the pit bosses, the casino manager watches the floor manager, I am watching the casino manager. and in the roof are about a dozen cheats watching everything because they know every trick in the book, and the eye in the sky is watching us all. This would make you think there is more chance in play in a Casino than skill or good luck.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great, but Great to Scorsese is Mediocre to The Everyday Director
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RyanCShowers
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Trust. The fascinating theme and moral reassurance for Martin Scorsese's attempt to hit critics and audiences as hard as he hit them with his classic, Goodfellas. Unfortunately, his arm isn't strong enough to smack the audience on that level. However, he does leave a great impression thanks to his style, control, of course the two components that make his films the best of the best: his film editor and Robert DeNiro. In Spanish, "money" is translated to "diniro". Hiring Robert DeNiro to star as the leading role in a film centered around gambling. The irony is fascinating. Thrown into a role that is more simplistic than past roles Scorsese has put DeNiro front and center for, DeNiro delivers the goods and is the MVP in Casino, when his two co-stars are given much more to raise a circus with. Speaking of, Joe Pesci. While one may question the actor's range with his role choices, no one can deny him the praise he deserves at knocking these types of characters through the wall and then some. Talk about more irony. Sharon Stone was the only cast member (or crew member for that fact) to receive an Oscar nomination for her work in Casino. She gets to cry, she gets to yell, she gets to do drugs, but hardly is she ever to scratch below the surface and bring something real out in her character. Ginger is resorted to Stone's awkwardness on the screen, struggling through scenes other actresses could've killed by throwing a hissy fit. She doesn't work in the role. Not that the role isn't rooted in clich&eacute;, unoriginality, and lacks the development needed to make this trite stereotype a quality character. Much of the film is montage with narration guiding the viewer through the quick action. Scorsese films have tightly strung editing, but nothing ever like this has been produced before. The film barely gives us full length scenes until the last third, but those are drown in Stone's distracting acting efforts. It's a complete mystery to me how Casino was shot and edited; there are so many scenes to get caught up in that last 20 seconds at most some of them. Major props to the editing and Scorsese. I'm aware giving Scorsese praise in that fashion is redundant and expected with each film he directs, but here it's earned considering this is one of his weaker efforts. The film's running time is a monstrous one, and coming from a person who checks their watch incessantly in a film that's over two hours, I didn't feel the length once. It kept me interested and invested in the happenings of the story. The viewer almost rides it like a raft down a river. But, just because it's watchable doesn't always mean it's worth watching. In this case, it is worth the flaws. Flaws, in which the film erupts with as does the opening scene's car bombing. The story is fun, minutely intriguing, and entertains us with the back dealings of Vegas and then seem. But somehow the story and the characters sometimes feel like they are struggling to stay above water. Casino is very reminiscent of The Godfather and The Godfather Part II, homaging the plot arc, specific scenes, themes, subject matters, and the iconic endings. When I was growing up, my mother demanded respect at all times. Even when we were giving her respect beyond any of our peer's efforts for their parents, she still never felt it was enough. She was never going to be satisfied For DeNiro's character, Trust is his version of my mother's trust. He falls in love with Stone's character, knowing her tarnished reputation and her art of conning, but still he chooses to marry her and forces her to be loyal to him. Deep down he knows that he shouldn't trust her, but he lives reality as if she was worthy of his trust. Just as the average joe wants to believe Vegas is an honest place and in gambling you risk it all, but as the saying goes The House Always Wins. Perhaps DeNiro strives for personal strivings for trust result from his view of the unlawful acts of the city. Even though he tries to maintain legitimacy in his end of business dealings, maybe real trust cannot be found in Las Vegas. RATING: 7.5/10 GRADE: B+
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Though "Casino" is not Scorsese's strongest hour, its vision of what mob-run casinos would be like is creative
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris Mizerak
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After bringing us the outstanding 1990 crime drama GoodFellas, critically acclaimed director Martin Scorsese, author/screenwriter Nicholas Pileggi, and stars Robert DeNiro and Joe Pesci team up again for another crime drama five years later called Casino. What's interesting about Casino is that it's basically GoodFellas all over again only set in Las Vegas. It's a good thing no one came up with the idea of naming this film GoodFellas in Las Vegas, since it would make it all the more obvious to us that they're trying to recreate the same movie. That being said, does the fact that Casino bares countless similarities to GoodFellas make it bad? Not at all, it's simply a way of summarizing the movie in a nutshell. Regardless, let's take a deeper look at what we've got. Casino tells the story of a Mafia member named Sam Rothstein (Robert DeNiro) who is sent to Las Vegas to run a casino funded by the Mafia on behalf of mob families living in the Midwest. His friend Nicky Santoro (Joe Pesci) is also eventually sent to Las Vegas to watch his back. The main reason they are both there is to oversee the casino operations which largely centers on illegal activity. Basically, the Mafia has rigged the casino so that none of the customers win anything, and they make millions of dollars off of their money without the customers knowing a thing about it. Essentially, Sam and Nicky are there to make sure that their "skim" goes according to plan. But all of that changes however when a fellow hustler named Ginger (Sharon Stone) enters their lives and eventually interferes with their business to the point where there's no way they could possibly fix whatever costly mistakes erupt. The first couple minutes of Casino, when we're being introduced to the process of how these Mafia-ruled casinos work, are arguably where the most fascinating part of the entire picture resides. We not only learn that the scamming this casino gets away with on a regular basis is supposedly normal, but we are also given the scary conclusion that wasting money on gambling is the main reason people go to Las Vegas in the first place. It definitely makes people who haven't been to Las Vegas before question whether or not they want to go out of their way to a city in the middle of a desert just to lose vast sums of money. I know that it wouldn't be a town I'd want to go to yet based on what I've seen here. So I thought Casino had a fairly strong introduction based on the kind of world it was introducing us to. The rest of the film was pretty decent with Robert DeNiro and Joe Pesci turning in strong acting just like they did with GoodFellas. However, I felt that most of the main narrative was not as compelling or focused as I wanted it to be. The storytelling simply felt a little fragmented for my taste, and the love story between DeNiro and Stone doesn't help with that either. For the record, I respect that the love story does contribute to the events that take place in the second half of the film. Also, Roger Ebert's comments on how different this love story is compared with the love stories in Martin Scorsese's previous works are justified to a certain degree. Regardless, the love story still didn't do much for me at all and I think a crucial reason for that is Sharon Stone. I don't think I've seen much of her work and the ones that I do recall seeing aside from this film are Total Recall, Basic Instinct, and Antz. In my opinion, from what I've seen, she looks physically great, but her acting is too over-the-top for my liking. I'm having trouble placing my finger on it, but something about her acting just seems inappropriate for the movies she stars in. While I acknowledge that some of her roles including this one require her to be very dramatic, she has the distinction of being too childishly over dramatic that she ends up feeling way out of place in her films, this one included. While I still think Joe Pesci acts out his role reasonably well here, his role is maybe a little too identical to his work in GoodFellas. And although I do feel that the story does lose focus around the halfway point, for some reason, I still find Casino watchable enough for me to recommend it overall. And again, this is mainly because of the theories this film shows us regarding how a mob-run casino would operate. There's a well-directed scene involving the casino managers asking a customer to leave because he is placing his feet on the casino tables. Without revealing too much, the payoff of this scene isn't quite what you'd expect at first. The same thing could be said for another scene involving the casino managers dealing with someone who is maybe having too good a day at their casino. If that scene doesn't scare you off from playing and winning too much at a casino, I don't know what will. If you're looking for a story and characters that will impact you the same way Scorsese's earlier films like GoodFellas did, you might be disappointed by what Casino offers. However, if you're looking for a picture with a fascinating premise that introduces creative theories along the way and will settle for something that is at least watchable, then I think you'll like this film fine enough. As for me, though I don't think Casino ranks among Scorsese's best by a good bit and I probably don't have that much interest in looking at it again, I was satisfied enough with seeing it once. Like Las Vegas itself, approach at your own financial risk.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Casino (1995)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ashish sood (ashistrong@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Casino" is another modern classic from Martin Scorsese. Drawing parallels with his earlier "Goodfellas" , "Casino" again teams Scorsese up with writer Nicholas Pileggi having De Niro & Joe Pesci in lead traditional favourite of Scorsese. The result is a truly engaging tale of mobsters setting up a new gambling empire in Las Vegas and the subsequent ripple effects that involve the local authorities and the police. A joy from beginning to end, "Casino" is an example of a perfect movie. There's nothing you'd want to change about this film. It's full of memorable scenes that are rich with outstanding performances and dialogue and it simply demands a repeat viewing. Casino spans three decades and chronicles the true story of a faction of the mob who ran Las Vegas casinos. Robert De Niro plays Sam Ace Rothstein, a fantastic bookie who is chosen to run the Tangiers hotel and Casino. Along the way, he marries a drug-addicted con-artist trophy wife (Sharon Stone) and struggles with his friendship with loose-cannon Nicky Santoro (Joe Pesci). Rothstein is a complicated figure in that he is not a heavy, yet he wields a lot of power due to the respect he has gained from his mob bosses back home. Robert De Niro and Joe Pesci are both fantastic in their roles, and Sharon Stone actually turned out a non-irritating performance. As the viewer, you can't stand her, but that is the point. Scorsese seems to have several different directing styles, and Casino follows in the tradition of Goodfellas as a pseudo-documentary. A lot of the exposition is revealed by the characters themselves in the form of voice-overs, and several scenes are filmed in documentarian fashion. The entire production however, is sleek and very quick. The use of music bears mentioning as well: Most Martin Scorsese films have an amazing soundtrack that adds to and enhances the scene. Scorsese doesn't just utilize the soundtrack, he makes it part of the storytelling - by the music, we chronologically know what time period we are witnessing, since one cannot rely on other factors, such as fashion alone. One of my favorite scenes in film which effectively involves music is actually from Casino - the very intense scene when the relationship between DeNiro, Stone and Pesci come to a head in the climax of the film. The pounding music cut throughout this scene is a cover of "Satisfaction" by Devo and the result is absolutely brilliant. Being a complete movie buff, I generally don't watch films that feature certain stars, I go to films by certain directors and Scorsese is definitely one of them. The man is a complete genius, and a gift to any movie buff - my suggestion is to watch some of his films, then check out his unbelievable series, "A Personal Journey with Martin Scorsese Through American Movies" which was done the same year as Casino. The series is essentially a primer on the history of film, sectioned off by film genres. You not only will experience his amazing intellect and massive knowledge of film history, but his incredible humility as well. Casino has to be one of the most underrated films that Martin Scorsese directed in the nineties. The acting by the leads is good and the script is excellent. Robert De Niro gave an Oscar worthy performance and Joe Pesci is chilling yet funny again. Even Sharon Stone is good in this brilliant film. My Rating  9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pure entertainment! Pure Scorsese!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MrGadgetman
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you haven't seen this masterpiece yet..., let's just say that you need to re-prioritize your life. It's that good. It has something for everyone. Action, suspense, drama (lots of drama!) gunshots and fist fights, comedy and yes... a love story. It is beautifully shot and captures all the magic and flare of the gambling lifestyle and fast paced environment. It will easily suck you in to the movie and you never once look at your watch to notice that it's nearly 3 hours long. All the characters have substance and a purpose in the film which always gives you something (or someone) to think about while you watch the story unfold. I've seen it several times, own it on disc and still catch myself watching it when it comes on Starz...it's that good.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My Favorite Film of All Time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Film Watchin Fool
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well it doesn't get any better than Casino. The cast, acting, directing, cinematography, music, and story are top notch and it makes for a memorable watch. In my opinion this is Scorsese's best film and could watch it over and over again. It is a great mobster film that follows Ace Rothstein (Deniro) and has many trials and tribulations that comes with trying to run Tangiers Casino for the mob. Don't miss this movie and it is one you should see before you die. Put it on your list of must see movies. If you are interested in more details... Again, it is my favorite film of all time so I am a bit biased. That said, Scorsese entrenches you in Las Vegas and Ace Rothstein's reign of the Tangiers casino. Nicholas Pileggi doesn't put out anything but quality material and him and Scorsese together are like peanut butter and jelly. You can't say enough about Scorsese directing and vision in this film. I can't think of a movie that was better put together and has such a great and natural flow to it. On to the acting and casting, which is nothing short of superb. Robert Deniro is Ace Rothstein and does a fantastic job. It isn't his best work, but you couldn't have found a better actor to play the part. Joe Pesci is outstanding as Nicky Santoro and plays one of the most memorable characters in my recent memory. Sharon Stone is great as Ginger and it is arguably her best work to date. You take all that into account with the supporting cast and you have something special. The movie is lengthy, but everything about it doesn't make it seem so long. I am telling you it will go much faster than the two and half hours that it runs and be impressive the entire way. The directing and cinematography are something to marvel and I don't think it gets any better than this film. I highly recommend this to anyone looking for a outstanding gangster film. This ranks as my favorite film of all time and you won't be disappointed. Email me at filmwatchinfool@gmail.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Long But Dosen't Stop Being Interesting,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dillon Harris
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Casino is a fantastic movie with a very long and detailed storyline that stretches out to nearly three hours but it never stops being interesting and enjoyable.The cast of this movie is all brilliant and inspired,Robert De Niro,Sharon Stone and of course Joe Pesci all deliver very impressive performance,James Woods is also very good in this movie as usual but I was disappointed that he wasn't really in it that much,I thought he would have a much more important role in the movie because i've always found his acting very impressive.My only problem with the movie really is that it could have been less detailed and also,my same problem with Goodfellas,is the fact that they get different characters narrating,it should all revolve around one characters point of view so we can hear their story instead of different peoples point of views.It should have all been Robert De Niro's point of view and not changing it to Joe Pesci at times and some other characters as well.A must see for fans of Martin Scorsese and Robert De Niro movies. Story of Sam Rothstein (Robert De Niro) and Nicky Santoro (Joe Pesci) as they begin running a casino business and let their greed get the best of them.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Greed foils crime
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    StoryCharts
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Casino is tough to analyze with Story Charts. The casino racket plot (along with all the other subplots) all start at their highs and tumble down to failures. The only Controlling Idea I can think of is that crime will always fail because of greed. The Story Chart for Casino is not very interesting, basically everything crumbles because of the characters are up to no good. My main beef with the movie is two fold. One is specific about this movie: why make a movie about crime that fails when no one in the movie does any good at all and there is no moral center to the film? Since everyone is up to no good, the only rational way to keep our attention is to up the ante on how bad the characters become and how cool they when they are being bad.So a film whose central idea is about the inevitable downfall of crime betrays its central idea by making the characters "cool" and full of "attitude" and glorifying them. Seriously why do we need a movie like this? It seems to just perpetuate all the negative stereotypes about movies glorifying violence and bad characters. My second beef is in general about Martin Scorsese. I feel films like Casino and many of his other works are mostly show-and-tells rather than true storytelling by characters, conflict and consequence. This shows through most obviously through the abundant voice overs that tell us how "cool" the characters are and tells us the changes that are happening as opposed to showing us through action and consequence. I think voice overs are the nemesis of absorbing movie making and Casino spends about half its time with its characters voicing over stuff that happens on screen: its like a holiday slide-show from "cool" gangsters. I think Casino tries to objectively document a period of Vegas excess driven by a few characters and their criminal ways. It's voice overs certainly make it documentary-like. But its glorification of how cool these guys subjectively tells us to sympathize with these criminals on their inevitable demise. I don't get it, why make a movie that suggests crime doesn't pay but suggest it's cool to be a criminal? How does this make the world a better place? If it doesn't, why make movies at all? My Story Chart of the movie is at storycharts.ca
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Scorsese at his Top...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Janis Livens
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Casino is a great Scorsese film from the mid 90's and it's in my opinion one his better films up there with Goodfellas and Taxi Driver. It showcases excellent performances, great story and his exceptional eye for visuals. While it run for almost three hours, I was never bored, it never dragged for me and I was completely immersed in the story being told. I agree that Casino should have been shorter and they could have toned the violence slightly down, but end result just doesn't really bother me. It's very engaging, the actors pretty much own the film. giving very strong performances. The reason why Casino doesn't get as much of acclaim as it should, is because of Goodfellas. Tonally and if you look at the story itself, they are rather similar. Some details are different but the overall feel of the story and the way it's told is surprisingly similar. Even at 3 hour run time they miss out on some details and leave some treads hanging. But as a whole the film worked really well and I completely engrossed in the world Scorsese had created. I would say that this film is a must see for anyone who likes a good story surrounding Las Vegas, the mob or just experience excellent actors giving all they got. A definite must see.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    In one word: overrated
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Fuzius
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After telling a friend I enjoyed The Godfather trilogy, he recommended I watch this film. And I'm sorry to say I totally regret doing so. This film is the opposite of The Godfather. It has zero emotional content. The characters are intentionally one dimensional, idiotic and therefor impossible to identify with. Most of the movie feature narration, which at first feels welcome and classic, but soon grows tiring because instead of the movie just "happening", the narration disrupts the acting all throughout the 3 hours. Now I know many might consider this one a classic, but I will bet you right here and now, that non of the actors playing in "Casino" would willingly sit through this 3 hour torture.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not to be missed mob movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    donpauliano
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was one of the first Movies I can recall watching that gives a little insight into how the Mafia make a living out of legitimate Business. along with titles such as Donnie Brasco, Goodfellas and the Godfather, which I enjoyed each immensely, Casino doesn't only show the dark side of organized crime but the ups and downs of their personal lives too. I watched Casino for the first time with my crew at the Cinema, we loved the outfits that De niro wears and his head for perfection as Casino Manager it really made us chuckle, one of the funniest bits was the bit about everyone being watched by someone: The dealer watches the player, the box man watches the dealer, the pit boss watches the box men, the floor manager watches the pit bosses, the casino manager watches the floor manager, I am watching the casino manager. and in the roof are about a dozen cheats watching everything because they know every trick in the book, and the eye in the sky is watching us all. This would make you think there is more chance in play in a Casino than skill or good luck.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great, but Great to Scorsese is Mediocre to The Everyday Director
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RyanCShowers
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Trust. The fascinating theme and moral reassurance for Martin Scorsese's attempt to hit critics and audiences as hard as he hit them with his classic, Goodfellas. Unfortunately, his arm isn't strong enough to smack the audience on that level. However, he does leave a great impression thanks to his style, control, of course the two components that make his films the best of the best: his film editor and Robert DeNiro. In Spanish, "money" is translated to "diniro". Hiring Robert DeNiro to star as the leading role in a film centered around gambling. The irony is fascinating. Thrown into a role that is more simplistic than past roles Scorsese has put DeNiro front and center for, DeNiro delivers the goods and is the MVP in Casino, when his two co-stars are given much more to raise a circus with. Speaking of, Joe Pesci. While one may question the actor's range with his role choices, no one can deny him the praise he deserves at knocking these types of characters through the wall and then some. Talk about more irony. Sharon Stone was the only cast member (or crew member for that fact) to receive an Oscar nomination for her work in Casino. She gets to cry, she gets to yell, she gets to do drugs, but hardly is she ever to scratch below the surface and bring something real out in her character. Ginger is resorted to Stone's awkwardness on the screen, struggling through scenes other actresses could've killed by throwing a hissy fit. She doesn't work in the role. Not that the role isn't rooted in clich&eacute;, unoriginality, and lacks the development needed to make this trite stereotype a quality character. Much of the film is montage with narration guiding the viewer through the quick action. Scorsese films have tightly strung editing, but nothing ever like this has been produced before. The film barely gives us full length scenes until the last third, but those are drown in Stone's distracting acting efforts. It's a complete mystery to me how Casino was shot and edited; there are so many scenes to get caught up in that last 20 seconds at most some of them. Major props to the editing and Scorsese. I'm aware giving Scorsese praise in that fashion is redundant and expected with each film he directs, but here it's earned considering this is one of his weaker efforts. The film's running time is a monstrous one, and coming from a person who checks their watch incessantly in a film that's over two hours, I didn't feel the length once. It kept me interested and invested in the happenings of the story. The viewer almost rides it like a raft down a river. But, just because it's watchable doesn't always mean it's worth watching. In this case, it is worth the flaws. Flaws, in which the film erupts with as does the opening scene's car bombing. The story is fun, minutely intriguing, and entertains us with the back dealings of Vegas and then seem. But somehow the story and the characters sometimes feel like they are struggling to stay above water. Casino is very reminiscent of The Godfather and The Godfather Part II, homaging the plot arc, specific scenes, themes, subject matters, and the iconic endings. When I was growing up, my mother demanded respect at all times. Even when we were giving her respect beyond any of our peer's efforts for their parents, she still never felt it was enough. She was never going to be satisfied For DeNiro's character, Trust is his version of my mother's trust. He falls in love with Stone's character, knowing her tarnished reputation and her art of conning, but still he chooses to marry her and forces her to be loyal to him. Deep down he knows that he shouldn't trust her, but he lives reality as if she was worthy of his trust. Just as the average joe wants to believe Vegas is an honest place and in gambling you risk it all, but as the saying goes The House Always Wins. Perhaps DeNiro strives for personal strivings for trust result from his view of the unlawful acts of the city. Even though he tries to maintain legitimacy in his end of business dealings, maybe real trust cannot be found in Las Vegas. RATING: 7.5/10 GRADE: B+
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Though "Casino" is not Scorsese's strongest hour, its vision of what mob-run casinos would be like is creative
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris Mizerak
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After bringing us the outstanding 1990 crime drama GoodFellas, critically acclaimed director Martin Scorsese, author/screenwriter Nicholas Pileggi, and stars Robert DeNiro and Joe Pesci team up again for another crime drama five years later called Casino. What's interesting about Casino is that it's basically GoodFellas all over again only set in Las Vegas. It's a good thing no one came up with the idea of naming this film GoodFellas in Las Vegas, since it would make it all the more obvious to us that they're trying to recreate the same movie. That being said, does the fact that Casino bares countless similarities to GoodFellas make it bad? Not at all, it's simply a way of summarizing the movie in a nutshell. Regardless, let's take a deeper look at what we've got. Casino tells the story of a Mafia member named Sam Rothstein (Robert DeNiro) who is sent to Las Vegas to run a casino funded by the Mafia on behalf of mob families living in the Midwest. His friend Nicky Santoro (Joe Pesci) is also eventually sent to Las Vegas to watch his back. The main reason they are both there is to oversee the casino operations which largely centers on illegal activity. Basically, the Mafia has rigged the casino so that none of the customers win anything, and they make millions of dollars off of their money without the customers knowing a thing about it. Essentially, Sam and Nicky are there to make sure that their "skim" goes according to plan. But all of that changes however when a fellow hustler named Ginger (Sharon Stone) enters their lives and eventually interferes with their business to the point where there's no way they could possibly fix whatever costly mistakes erupt. The first couple minutes of Casino, when we're being introduced to the process of how these Mafia-ruled casinos work, are arguably where the most fascinating part of the entire picture resides. We not only learn that the scamming this casino gets away with on a regular basis is supposedly normal, but we are also given the scary conclusion that wasting money on gambling is the main reason people go to Las Vegas in the first place. It definitely makes people who haven't been to Las Vegas before question whether or not they want to go out of their way to a city in the middle of a desert just to lose vast sums of money. I know that it wouldn't be a town I'd want to go to yet based on what I've seen here. So I thought Casino had a fairly strong introduction based on the kind of world it was introducing us to. The rest of the film was pretty decent with Robert DeNiro and Joe Pesci turning in strong acting just like they did with GoodFellas. However, I felt that most of the main narrative was not as compelling or focused as I wanted it to be. The storytelling simply felt a little fragmented for my taste, and the love story between DeNiro and Stone doesn't help with that either. For the record, I respect that the love story does contribute to the events that take place in the second half of the film. Also, Roger Ebert's comments on how different this love story is compared with the love stories in Martin Scorsese's previous works are justified to a certain degree. Regardless, the love story still didn't do much for me at all and I think a crucial reason for that is Sharon Stone. I don't think I've seen much of her work and the ones that I do recall seeing aside from this film are Total Recall, Basic Instinct, and Antz. In my opinion, from what I've seen, she looks physically great, but her acting is too over-the-top for my liking. I'm having trouble placing my finger on it, but something about her acting just seems inappropriate for the movies she stars in. While I acknowledge that some of her roles including this one require her to be very dramatic, she has the distinction of being too childishly over dramatic that she ends up feeling way out of place in her films, this one included. While I still think Joe Pesci acts out his role reasonably well here, his role is maybe a little too identical to his work in GoodFellas. And although I do feel that the story does lose focus around the halfway point, for some reason, I still find Casino watchable enough for me to recommend it overall. And again, this is mainly because of the theories this film shows us regarding how a mob-run casino would operate. There's a well-directed scene involving the casino managers asking a customer to leave because he is placing his feet on the casino tables. Without revealing too much, the payoff of this scene isn't quite what you'd expect at first. The same thing could be said for another scene involving the casino managers dealing with someone who is maybe having too good a day at their casino. If that scene doesn't scare you off from playing and winning too much at a casino, I don't know what will. If you're looking for a story and characters that will impact you the same way Scorsese's earlier films like GoodFellas did, you might be disappointed by what Casino offers. However, if you're looking for a picture with a fascinating premise that introduces creative theories along the way and will settle for something that is at least watchable, then I think you'll like this film fine enough. As for me, though I don't think Casino ranks among Scorsese's best by a good bit and I probably don't have that much interest in looking at it again, I was satisfied enough with seeing it once. Like Las Vegas itself, approach at your own financial risk.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Casino (1995)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ashish sood (ashistrong@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Casino" is another modern classic from Martin Scorsese. Drawing parallels with his earlier "Goodfellas" , "Casino" again teams Scorsese up with writer Nicholas Pileggi having De Niro & Joe Pesci in lead traditional favourite of Scorsese. The result is a truly engaging tale of mobsters setting up a new gambling empire in Las Vegas and the subsequent ripple effects that involve the local authorities and the police. A joy from beginning to end, "Casino" is an example of a perfect movie. There's nothing you'd want to change about this film. It's full of memorable scenes that are rich with outstanding performances and dialogue and it simply demands a repeat viewing. Casino spans three decades and chronicles the true story of a faction of the mob who ran Las Vegas casinos. Robert De Niro plays Sam Ace Rothstein, a fantastic bookie who is chosen to run the Tangiers hotel and Casino. Along the way, he marries a drug-addicted con-artist trophy wife (Sharon Stone) and struggles with his friendship with loose-cannon Nicky Santoro (Joe Pesci). Rothstein is a complicated figure in that he is not a heavy, yet he wields a lot of power due to the respect he has gained from his mob bosses back home. Robert De Niro and Joe Pesci are both fantastic in their roles, and Sharon Stone actually turned out a non-irritating performance. As the viewer, you can't stand her, but that is the point. Scorsese seems to have several different directing styles, and Casino follows in the tradition of Goodfellas as a pseudo-documentary. A lot of the exposition is revealed by the characters themselves in the form of voice-overs, and several scenes are filmed in documentarian fashion. The entire production however, is sleek and very quick. The use of music bears mentioning as well: Most Martin Scorsese films have an amazing soundtrack that adds to and enhances the scene. Scorsese doesn't just utilize the soundtrack, he makes it part of the storytelling - by the music, we chronologically know what time period we are witnessing, since one cannot rely on other factors, such as fashion alone. One of my favorite scenes in film which effectively involves music is actually from Casino - the very intense scene when the relationship between DeNiro, Stone and Pesci come to a head in the climax of the film. The pounding music cut throughout this scene is a cover of "Satisfaction" by Devo and the result is absolutely brilliant. Being a complete movie buff, I generally don't watch films that feature certain stars, I go to films by certain directors and Scorsese is definitely one of them. The man is a complete genius, and a gift to any movie buff - my suggestion is to watch some of his films, then check out his unbelievable series, "A Personal Journey with Martin Scorsese Through American Movies" which was done the same year as Casino. The series is essentially a primer on the history of film, sectioned off by film genres. You not only will experience his amazing intellect and massive knowledge of film history, but his incredible humility as well. Casino has to be one of the most underrated films that Martin Scorsese directed in the nineties. The acting by the leads is good and the script is excellent. Robert De Niro gave an Oscar worthy performance and Joe Pesci is chilling yet funny again. Even Sharon Stone is good in this brilliant film. My Rating  9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pure entertainment! Pure Scorsese!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MrGadgetman
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you haven't seen this masterpiece yet..., let's just say that you need to re-prioritize your life. It's that good. It has something for everyone. Action, suspense, drama (lots of drama!) gunshots and fist fights, comedy and yes... a love story. It is beautifully shot and captures all the magic and flare of the gambling lifestyle and fast paced environment. It will easily suck you in to the movie and you never once look at your watch to notice that it's nearly 3 hours long. All the characters have substance and a purpose in the film which always gives you something (or someone) to think about while you watch the story unfold. I've seen it several times, own it on disc and still catch myself watching it when it comes on Starz...it's that good.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My Favorite Film of All Time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Film Watchin Fool
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well it doesn't get any better than Casino. The cast, acting, directing, cinematography, music, and story are top notch and it makes for a memorable watch. In my opinion this is Scorsese's best film and could watch it over and over again. It is a great mobster film that follows Ace Rothstein (Deniro) and has many trials and tribulations that comes with trying to run Tangiers Casino for the mob. Don't miss this movie and it is one you should see before you die. Put it on your list of must see movies. If you are interested in more details... Again, it is my favorite film of all time so I am a bit biased. That said, Scorsese entrenches you in Las Vegas and Ace Rothstein's reign of the Tangiers casino. Nicholas Pileggi doesn't put out anything but quality material and him and Scorsese together are like peanut butter and jelly. You can't say enough about Scorsese directing and vision in this film. I can't think of a movie that was better put together and has such a great and natural flow to it. On to the acting and casting, which is nothing short of superb. Robert Deniro is Ace Rothstein and does a fantastic job. It isn't his best work, but you couldn't have found a better actor to play the part. Joe Pesci is outstanding as Nicky Santoro and plays one of the most memorable characters in my recent memory. Sharon Stone is great as Ginger and it is arguably her best work to date. You take all that into account with the supporting cast and you have something special. The movie is lengthy, but everything about it doesn't make it seem so long. I am telling you it will go much faster than the two and half hours that it runs and be impressive the entire way. The directing and cinematography are something to marvel and I don't think it gets any better than this film. I highly recommend this to anyone looking for a outstanding gangster film. This ranks as my favorite film of all time and you won't be disappointed. Email me at filmwatchinfool@gmail.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Long But Dosen't Stop Being Interesting,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dillon Harris
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Casino is a fantastic movie with a very long and detailed storyline that stretches out to nearly three hours but it never stops being interesting and enjoyable.The cast of this movie is all brilliant and inspired,Robert De Niro,Sharon Stone and of course Joe Pesci all deliver very impressive performance,James Woods is also very good in this movie as usual but I was disappointed that he wasn't really in it that much,I thought he would have a much more important role in the movie because i've always found his acting very impressive.My only problem with the movie really is that it could have been less detailed and also,my same problem with Goodfellas,is the fact that they get different characters narrating,it should all revolve around one characters point of view so we can hear their story instead of different peoples point of views.It should have all been Robert De Niro's point of view and not changing it to Joe Pesci at times and some other characters as well.A must see for fans of Martin Scorsese and Robert De Niro movies. Story of Sam Rothstein (Robert De Niro) and Nicky Santoro (Joe Pesci) as they begin running a casino business and let their greed get the best of them.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Greed foils crime
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    StoryCharts
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Casino is tough to analyze with Story Charts. The casino racket plot (along with all the other subplots) all start at their highs and tumble down to failures. The only Controlling Idea I can think of is that crime will always fail because of greed. The Story Chart for Casino is not very interesting, basically everything crumbles because of the characters are up to no good. My main beef with the movie is two fold. One is specific about this movie: why make a movie about crime that fails when no one in the movie does any good at all and there is no moral center to the film? Since everyone is up to no good, the only rational way to keep our attention is to up the ante on how bad the characters become and how cool they when they are being bad.So a film whose central idea is about the inevitable downfall of crime betrays its central idea by making the characters "cool" and full of "attitude" and glorifying them. Seriously why do we need a movie like this? It seems to just perpetuate all the negative stereotypes about movies glorifying violence and bad characters. My second beef is in general about Martin Scorsese. I feel films like Casino and many of his other works are mostly show-and-tells rather than true storytelling by characters, conflict and consequence. This shows through most obviously through the abundant voice overs that tell us how "cool" the characters are and tells us the changes that are happening as opposed to showing us through action and consequence. I think voice overs are the nemesis of absorbing movie making and Casino spends about half its time with its characters voicing over stuff that happens on screen: its like a holiday slide-show from "cool" gangsters. I think Casino tries to objectively document a period of Vegas excess driven by a few characters and their criminal ways. It's voice overs certainly make it documentary-like. But its glorification of how cool these guys subjectively tells us to sympathize with these criminals on their inevitable demise. I don't get it, why make a movie that suggests crime doesn't pay but suggest it's cool to be a criminal? How does this make the world a better place? If it doesn't, why make movies at all? My Story Chart of the movie is at storycharts.ca
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Scorsese at his Top...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Janis Livens
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Casino is a great Scorsese film from the mid 90's and it's in my opinion one his better films up there with Goodfellas and Taxi Driver. It showcases excellent performances, great story and his exceptional eye for visuals. While it run for almost three hours, I was never bored, it never dragged for me and I was completely immersed in the story being told. I agree that Casino should have been shorter and they could have toned the violence slightly down, but end result just doesn't really bother me. It's very engaging, the actors pretty much own the film. giving very strong performances. The reason why Casino doesn't get as much of acclaim as it should, is because of Goodfellas. Tonally and if you look at the story itself, they are rather similar. Some details are different but the overall feel of the story and the way it's told is surprisingly similar. Even at 3 hour run time they miss out on some details and leave some treads hanging. But as a whole the film worked really well and I completely engrossed in the world Scorsese had created. I would say that this film is a must see for anyone who likes a good story surrounding Las Vegas, the mob or just experience excellent actors giving all they got. A definite must see.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    In one word: overrated
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Fuzius
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After telling a friend I enjoyed The Godfather trilogy, he recommended I watch this film. And I'm sorry to say I totally regret doing so. This film is the opposite of The Godfather. It has zero emotional content. The characters are intentionally one dimensional, idiotic and therefor impossible to identify with. Most of the movie feature narration, which at first feels welcome and classic, but soon grows tiring because instead of the movie just "happening", the narration disrupts the acting all throughout the 3 hours. Now I know many might consider this one a classic, but I will bet you right here and now, that non of the actors playing in "Casino" would willingly sit through this 3 hour torture.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not to be missed mob movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    donpauliano
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was one of the first Movies I can recall watching that gives a little insight into how the Mafia make a living out of legitimate Business. along with titles such as Donnie Brasco, Goodfellas and the Godfather, which I enjoyed each immensely, Casino doesn't only show the dark side of organized crime but the ups and downs of their personal lives too. I watched Casino for the first time with my crew at the Cinema, we loved the outfits that De niro wears and his head for perfection as Casino Manager it really made us chuckle, one of the funniest bits was the bit about everyone being watched by someone: The dealer watches the player, the box man watches the dealer, the pit boss watches the box men, the floor manager watches the pit bosses, the casino manager watches the floor manager, I am watching the casino manager. and in the roof are about a dozen cheats watching everything because they know every trick in the book, and the eye in the sky is watching us all. This would make you think there is more chance in play in a Casino than skill or good luck.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great, but Great to Scorsese is Mediocre to The Everyday Director
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RyanCShowers
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Trust. The fascinating theme and moral reassurance for Martin Scorsese's attempt to hit critics and audiences as hard as he hit them with his classic, Goodfellas. Unfortunately, his arm isn't strong enough to smack the audience on that level. However, he does leave a great impression thanks to his style, control, of course the two components that make his films the best of the best: his film editor and Robert DeNiro. In Spanish, "money" is translated to "diniro". Hiring Robert DeNiro to star as the leading role in a film centered around gambling. The irony is fascinating. Thrown into a role that is more simplistic than past roles Scorsese has put DeNiro front and center for, DeNiro delivers the goods and is the MVP in Casino, when his two co-stars are given much more to raise a circus with. Speaking of, Joe Pesci. While one may question the actor's range with his role choices, no one can deny him the praise he deserves at knocking these types of characters through the wall and then some. Talk about more irony. Sharon Stone was the only cast member (or crew member for that fact) to receive an Oscar nomination for her work in Casino. She gets to cry, she gets to yell, she gets to do drugs, but hardly is she ever to scratch below the surface and bring something real out in her character. Ginger is resorted to Stone's awkwardness on the screen, struggling through scenes other actresses could've killed by throwing a hissy fit. She doesn't work in the role. Not that the role isn't rooted in clich&eacute;, unoriginality, and lacks the development needed to make this trite stereotype a quality character. Much of the film is montage with narration guiding the viewer through the quick action. Scorsese films have tightly strung editing, but nothing ever like this has been produced before. The film barely gives us full length scenes until the last third, but those are drown in Stone's distracting acting efforts. It's a complete mystery to me how Casino was shot and edited; there are so many scenes to get caught up in that last 20 seconds at most some of them. Major props to the editing and Scorsese. I'm aware giving Scorsese praise in that fashion is redundant and expected with each film he directs, but here it's earned considering this is one of his weaker efforts. The film's running time is a monstrous one, and coming from a person who checks their watch incessantly in a film that's over two hours, I didn't feel the length once. It kept me interested and invested in the happenings of the story. The viewer almost rides it like a raft down a river. But, just because it's watchable doesn't always mean it's worth watching. In this case, it is worth the flaws. Flaws, in which the film erupts with as does the opening scene's car bombing. The story is fun, minutely intriguing, and entertains us with the back dealings of Vegas and then seem. But somehow the story and the characters sometimes feel like they are struggling to stay above water. Casino is very reminiscent of The Godfather and The Godfather Part II, homaging the plot arc, specific scenes, themes, subject matters, and the iconic endings. When I was growing up, my mother demanded respect at all times. Even when we were giving her respect beyond any of our peer's efforts for their parents, she still never felt it was enough. She was never going to be satisfied For DeNiro's character, Trust is his version of my mother's trust. He falls in love with Stone's character, knowing her tarnished reputation and her art of conning, but still he chooses to marry her and forces her to be loyal to him. Deep down he knows that he shouldn't trust her, but he lives reality as if she was worthy of his trust. Just as the average joe wants to believe Vegas is an honest place and in gambling you risk it all, but as the saying goes The House Always Wins. Perhaps DeNiro strives for personal strivings for trust result from his view of the unlawful acts of the city. Even though he tries to maintain legitimacy in his end of business dealings, maybe real trust cannot be found in Las Vegas. RATING: 7.5/10 GRADE: B+
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Though "Casino" is not Scorsese's strongest hour, its vision of what mob-run casinos would be like is creative
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris Mizerak
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After bringing us the outstanding 1990 crime drama GoodFellas, critically acclaimed director Martin Scorsese, author/screenwriter Nicholas Pileggi, and stars Robert DeNiro and Joe Pesci team up again for another crime drama five years later called Casino. What's interesting about Casino is that it's basically GoodFellas all over again only set in Las Vegas. It's a good thing no one came up with the idea of naming this film GoodFellas in Las Vegas, since it would make it all the more obvious to us that they're trying to recreate the same movie. That being said, does the fact that Casino bares countless similarities to GoodFellas make it bad? Not at all, it's simply a way of summarizing the movie in a nutshell. Regardless, let's take a deeper look at what we've got. Casino tells the story of a Mafia member named Sam Rothstein (Robert DeNiro) who is sent to Las Vegas to run a casino funded by the Mafia on behalf of mob families living in the Midwest. His friend Nicky Santoro (Joe Pesci) is also eventually sent to Las Vegas to watch his back. The main reason they are both there is to oversee the casino operations which largely centers on illegal activity. Basically, the Mafia has rigged the casino so that none of the customers win anything, and they make millions of dollars off of their money without the customers knowing a thing about it. Essentially, Sam and Nicky are there to make sure that their "skim" goes according to plan. But all of that changes however when a fellow hustler named Ginger (Sharon Stone) enters their lives and eventually interferes with their business to the point where there's no way they could possibly fix whatever costly mistakes erupt. The first couple minutes of Casino, when we're being introduced to the process of how these Mafia-ruled casinos work, are arguably where the most fascinating part of the entire picture resides. We not only learn that the scamming this casino gets away with on a regular basis is supposedly normal, but we are also given the scary conclusion that wasting money on gambling is the main reason people go to Las Vegas in the first place. It definitely makes people who haven't been to Las Vegas before question whether or not they want to go out of their way to a city in the middle of a desert just to lose vast sums of money. I know that it wouldn't be a town I'd want to go to yet based on what I've seen here. So I thought Casino had a fairly strong introduction based on the kind of world it was introducing us to. The rest of the film was pretty decent with Robert DeNiro and Joe Pesci turning in strong acting just like they did with GoodFellas. However, I felt that most of the main narrative was not as compelling or focused as I wanted it to be. The storytelling simply felt a little fragmented for my taste, and the love story between DeNiro and Stone doesn't help with that either. For the record, I respect that the love story does contribute to the events that take place in the second half of the film. Also, Roger Ebert's comments on how different this love story is compared with the love stories in Martin Scorsese's previous works are justified to a certain degree. Regardless, the love story still didn't do much for me at all and I think a crucial reason for that is Sharon Stone. I don't think I've seen much of her work and the ones that I do recall seeing aside from this film are Total Recall, Basic Instinct, and Antz. In my opinion, from what I've seen, she looks physically great, but her acting is too over-the-top for my liking. I'm having trouble placing my finger on it, but something about her acting just seems inappropriate for the movies she stars in. While I acknowledge that some of her roles including this one require her to be very dramatic, she has the distinction of being too childishly over dramatic that she ends up feeling way out of place in her films, this one included. While I still think Joe Pesci acts out his role reasonably well here, his role is maybe a little too identical to his work in GoodFellas. And although I do feel that the story does lose focus around the halfway point, for some reason, I still find Casino watchable enough for me to recommend it overall. And again, this is mainly because of the theories this film shows us regarding how a mob-run casino would operate. There's a well-directed scene involving the casino managers asking a customer to leave because he is placing his feet on the casino tables. Without revealing too much, the payoff of this scene isn't quite what you'd expect at first. The same thing could be said for another scene involving the casino managers dealing with someone who is maybe having too good a day at their casino. If that scene doesn't scare you off from playing and winning too much at a casino, I don't know what will. If you're looking for a story and characters that will impact you the same way Scorsese's earlier films like GoodFellas did, you might be disappointed by what Casino offers. However, if you're looking for a picture with a fascinating premise that introduces creative theories along the way and will settle for something that is at least watchable, then I think you'll like this film fine enough. As for me, though I don't think Casino ranks among Scorsese's best by a good bit and I probably don't have that much interest in looking at it again, I was satisfied enough with seeing it once. Like Las Vegas itself, approach at your own financial risk.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Casino (1995)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ashish sood (ashistrong@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Casino" is another modern classic from Martin Scorsese. Drawing parallels with his earlier "Goodfellas" , "Casino" again teams Scorsese up with writer Nicholas Pileggi having De Niro & Joe Pesci in lead traditional favourite of Scorsese. The result is a truly engaging tale of mobsters setting up a new gambling empire in Las Vegas and the subsequent ripple effects that involve the local authorities and the police. A joy from beginning to end, "Casino" is an example of a perfect movie. There's nothing you'd want to change about this film. It's full of memorable scenes that are rich with outstanding performances and dialogue and it simply demands a repeat viewing. Casino spans three decades and chronicles the true story of a faction of the mob who ran Las Vegas casinos. Robert De Niro plays Sam Ace Rothstein, a fantastic bookie who is chosen to run the Tangiers hotel and Casino. Along the way, he marries a drug-addicted con-artist trophy wife (Sharon Stone) and struggles with his friendship with loose-cannon Nicky Santoro (Joe Pesci). Rothstein is a complicated figure in that he is not a heavy, yet he wields a lot of power due to the respect he has gained from his mob bosses back home. Robert De Niro and Joe Pesci are both fantastic in their roles, and Sharon Stone actually turned out a non-irritating performance. As the viewer, you can't stand her, but that is the point. Scorsese seems to have several different directing styles, and Casino follows in the tradition of Goodfellas as a pseudo-documentary. A lot of the exposition is revealed by the characters themselves in the form of voice-overs, and several scenes are filmed in documentarian fashion. The entire production however, is sleek and very quick. The use of music bears mentioning as well: Most Martin Scorsese films have an amazing soundtrack that adds to and enhances the scene. Scorsese doesn't just utilize the soundtrack, he makes it part of the storytelling - by the music, we chronologically know what time period we are witnessing, since one cannot rely on other factors, such as fashion alone. One of my favorite scenes in film which effectively involves music is actually from Casino - the very intense scene when the relationship between DeNiro, Stone and Pesci come to a head in the climax of the film. The pounding music cut throughout this scene is a cover of "Satisfaction" by Devo and the result is absolutely brilliant. Being a complete movie buff, I generally don't watch films that feature certain stars, I go to films by certain directors and Scorsese is definitely one of them. The man is a complete genius, and a gift to any movie buff - my suggestion is to watch some of his films, then check out his unbelievable series, "A Personal Journey with Martin Scorsese Through American Movies" which was done the same year as Casino. The series is essentially a primer on the history of film, sectioned off by film genres. You not only will experience his amazing intellect and massive knowledge of film history, but his incredible humility as well. Casino has to be one of the most underrated films that Martin Scorsese directed in the nineties. The acting by the leads is good and the script is excellent. Robert De Niro gave an Oscar worthy performance and Joe Pesci is chilling yet funny again. Even Sharon Stone is good in this brilliant film. My Rating  9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pure entertainment! Pure Scorsese!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MrGadgetman
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you haven't seen this masterpiece yet..., let's just say that you need to re-prioritize your life. It's that good. It has something for everyone. Action, suspense, drama (lots of drama!) gunshots and fist fights, comedy and yes... a love story. It is beautifully shot and captures all the magic and flare of the gambling lifestyle and fast paced environment. It will easily suck you in to the movie and you never once look at your watch to notice that it's nearly 3 hours long. All the characters have substance and a purpose in the film which always gives you something (or someone) to think about while you watch the story unfold. I've seen it several times, own it on disc and still catch myself watching it when it comes on Starz...it's that good.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My Favorite Film of All Time
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Film Watchin Fool
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well it doesn't get any better than Casino. The cast, acting, directing, cinematography, music, and story are top notch and it makes for a memorable watch. In my opinion this is Scorsese's best film and could watch it over and over again. It is a great mobster film that follows Ace Rothstein (Deniro) and has many trials and tribulations that comes with trying to run Tangiers Casino for the mob. Don't miss this movie and it is one you should see before you die. Put it on your list of must see movies. If you are interested in more details... Again, it is my favorite film of all time so I am a bit biased. That said, Scorsese entrenches you in Las Vegas and Ace Rothstein's reign of the Tangiers casino. Nicholas Pileggi doesn't put out anything but quality material and him and Scorsese together are like peanut butter and jelly. You can't say enough about Scorsese directing and vision in this film. I can't think of a movie that was better put together and has such a great and natural flow to it. On to the acting and casting, which is nothing short of superb. Robert Deniro is Ace Rothstein and does a fantastic job. It isn't his best work, but you couldn't have found a better actor to play the part. Joe Pesci is outstanding as Nicky Santoro and plays one of the most memorable characters in my recent memory. Sharon Stone is great as Ginger and it is arguably her best work to date. You take all that into account with the supporting cast and you have something special. The movie is lengthy, but everything about it doesn't make it seem so long. I am telling you it will go much faster than the two and half hours that it runs and be impressive the entire way. The directing and cinematography are something to marvel and I don't think it gets any better than this film. I highly recommend this to anyone looking for a outstanding gangster film. This ranks as my favorite film of all time and you won't be disappointed. Email me at filmwatchinfool@gmail.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Long But Dosen't Stop Being Interesting,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dillon Harris
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Casino is a fantastic movie with a very long and detailed storyline that stretches out to nearly three hours but it never stops being interesting and enjoyable.The cast of this movie is all brilliant and inspired,Robert De Niro,Sharon Stone and of course Joe Pesci all deliver very impressive performance,James Woods is also very good in this movie as usual but I was disappointed that he wasn't really in it that much,I thought he would have a much more important role in the movie because i've always found his acting very impressive.My only problem with the movie really is that it could have been less detailed and also,my same problem with Goodfellas,is the fact that they get different characters narrating,it should all revolve around one characters point of view so we can hear their story instead of different peoples point of views.It should have all been Robert De Niro's point of view and not changing it to Joe Pesci at times and some other characters as well.A must see for fans of Martin Scorsese and Robert De Niro movies. Story of Sam Rothstein (Robert De Niro) and Nicky Santoro (Joe Pesci) as they begin running a casino business and let their greed get the best of them.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Greed foils crime
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    StoryCharts
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Casino is tough to analyze with Story Charts. The casino racket plot (along with all the other subplots) all start at their highs and tumble down to failures. The only Controlling Idea I can think of is that crime will always fail because of greed. The Story Chart for Casino is not very interesting, basically everything crumbles because of the characters are up to no good. My main beef with the movie is two fold. One is specific about this movie: why make a movie about crime that fails when no one in the movie does any good at all and there is no moral center to the film? Since everyone is up to no good, the only rational way to keep our attention is to up the ante on how bad the characters become and how cool they when they are being bad.So a film whose central idea is about the inevitable downfall of crime betrays its central idea by making the characters "cool" and full of "attitude" and glorifying them. Seriously why do we need a movie like this? It seems to just perpetuate all the negative stereotypes about movies glorifying violence and bad characters. My second beef is in general about Martin Scorsese. I feel films like Casino and many of his other works are mostly show-and-tells rather than true storytelling by characters, conflict and consequence. This shows through most obviously through the abundant voice overs that tell us how "cool" the characters are and tells us the changes that are happening as opposed to showing us through action and consequence. I think voice overs are the nemesis of absorbing movie making and Casino spends about half its time with its characters voicing over stuff that happens on screen: its like a holiday slide-show from "cool" gangsters. I think Casino tries to objectively document a period of Vegas excess driven by a few characters and their criminal ways. It's voice overs certainly make it documentary-like. But its glorification of how cool these guys subjectively tells us to sympathize with these criminals on their inevitable demise. I don't get it, why make a movie that suggests crime doesn't pay but suggest it's cool to be a criminal? How does this make the world a better place? If it doesn't, why make movies at all? My Story Chart of the movie is at storycharts.ca
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Scorsese at his Top...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Janis Livens
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Casino is a great Scorsese film from the mid 90's and it's in my opinion one his better films up there with Goodfellas and Taxi Driver. It showcases excellent performances, great story and his exceptional eye for visuals. While it run for almost three hours, I was never bored, it never dragged for me and I was completely immersed in the story being told. I agree that Casino should have been shorter and they could have toned the violence slightly down, but end result just doesn't really bother me. It's very engaging, the actors pretty much own the film. giving very strong performances. The reason why Casino doesn't get as much of acclaim as it should, is because of Goodfellas. Tonally and if you look at the story itself, they are rather similar. Some details are different but the overall feel of the story and the way it's told is surprisingly similar. Even at 3 hour run time they miss out on some details and leave some treads hanging. But as a whole the film worked really well and I completely engrossed in the world Scorsese had created. I would say that this film is a must see for anyone who likes a good story surrounding Las Vegas, the mob or just experience excellent actors giving all they got. A definite must see.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    In one word: overrated
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Fuzius
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After telling a friend I enjoyed The Godfather trilogy, he recommended I watch this film. And I'm sorry to say I totally regret doing so. This film is the opposite of The Godfather. It has zero emotional content. The characters are intentionally one dimensional, idiotic and therefor impossible to identify with. Most of the movie feature narration, which at first feels welcome and classic, but soon grows tiring because instead of the movie just "happening", the narration disrupts the acting all throughout the 3 hours. Now I know many might consider this one a classic, but I will bet you right here and now, that non of the actors playing in "Casino" would willingly sit through this 3 hour torture.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not to be missed mob movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    donpauliano
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This was one of the first Movies I can recall watching that gives a little insight into how the Mafia make a living out of legitimate Business. along with titles such as Donnie Brasco, Goodfellas and the Godfather, which I enjoyed each immensely, Casino doesn't only show the dark side of organized crime but the ups and downs of their personal lives too. I watched Casino for the first time with my crew at the Cinema, we loved the outfits that De niro wears and his head for perfection as Casino Manager it really made us chuckle, one of the funniest bits was the bit about everyone being watched by someone: The dealer watches the player, the box man watches the dealer, the pit boss watches the box men, the floor manager watches the pit bosses, the casino manager watches the floor manager, I am watching the casino manager. and in the roof are about a dozen cheats watching everything because they know every trick in the book, and the eye in the sky is watching us all. This would make you think there is more chance in play in a Casino than skill or good luck.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great, but Great to Scorsese is Mediocre to The Everyday Director
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RyanCShowers
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Trust. The fascinating theme and moral reassurance for Martin Scorsese's attempt to hit critics and audiences as hard as he hit them with his classic, Goodfellas. Unfortunately, his arm isn't strong enough to smack the audience on that level. However, he does leave a great impression thanks to his style, control, of course the two components that make his films the best of the best: his film editor and Robert DeNiro. In Spanish, "money" is translated to "diniro". Hiring Robert DeNiro to star as the leading role in a film centered around gambling. The irony is fascinating. Thrown into a role that is more simplistic than past roles Scorsese has put DeNiro front and center for, DeNiro delivers the goods and is the MVP in Casino, when his two co-stars are given much more to raise a circus with. Speaking of, Joe Pesci. While one may question the actor's range with his role choices, no one can deny him the praise he deserves at knocking these types of characters through the wall and then some. Talk about more irony. Sharon Stone was the only cast member (or crew member for that fact) to receive an Oscar nomination for her work in Casino. She gets to cry, she gets to yell, she gets to do drugs, but hardly is she ever to scratch below the surface and bring something real out in her character. Ginger is resorted to Stone's awkwardness on the screen, struggling through scenes other actresses could've killed by throwing a hissy fit. She doesn't work in the role. Not that the role isn't rooted in clich&eacute;, unoriginality, and lacks the development needed to make this trite stereotype a quality character. Much of the film is montage with narration guiding the viewer through the quick action. Scorsese films have tightly strung editing, but nothing ever like this has been produced before. The film barely gives us full length scenes until the last third, but those are drown in Stone's distracting acting efforts. It's a complete mystery to me how Casino was shot and edited; there are so many scenes to get caught up in that last 20 seconds at most some of them. Major props to the editing and Scorsese. I'm aware giving Scorsese praise in that fashion is redundant and expected with each film he directs, but here it's earned considering this is one of his weaker efforts. The film's running time is a monstrous one, and coming from a person who checks their watch incessantly in a film that's over two hours, I didn't feel the length once. It kept me interested and invested in the happenings of the story. The viewer almost rides it like a raft down a river. But, just because it's watchable doesn't always mean it's worth watching. In this case, it is worth the flaws. Flaws, in which the film erupts with as does the opening scene's car bombing. The story is fun, minutely intriguing, and entertains us with the back dealings of Vegas and then seem. But somehow the story and the characters sometimes feel like they are struggling to stay above water. Casino is very reminiscent of The Godfather and The Godfather Part II, homaging the plot arc, specific scenes, themes, subject matters, and the iconic endings. When I was growing up, my mother demanded respect at all times. Even when we were giving her respect beyond any of our peer's efforts for their parents, she still never felt it was enough. She was never going to be satisfied For DeNiro's character, Trust is his version of my mother's trust. He falls in love with Stone's character, knowing her tarnished reputation and her art of conning, but still he chooses to marry her and forces her to be loyal to him. Deep down he knows that he shouldn't trust her, but he lives reality as if she was worthy of his trust. Just as the average joe wants to believe Vegas is an honest place and in gambling you risk it all, but as the saying goes The House Always Wins. Perhaps DeNiro strives for personal strivings for trust result from his view of the unlawful acts of the city. Even though he tries to maintain legitimacy in his end of business dealings, maybe real trust cannot be found in Las Vegas. RATING: 7.5/10 GRADE: B+
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
