<filme>
 <id>
  699
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0110367
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1994
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Ador&aacute;veis Mulheres
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  7.1
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  The March sisters live and grow in post-Civil War America.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  With their father away fighting in the Civil War, Jo, Meg, Beth and Amy grow up with their mother in somewhat reduced circumstances. They are a close family who inevitably have their squabbles and tragedies. But the bond holds even when, later, men friends start to become a part of the household.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Romance
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   writing
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   singing
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   horse and carriage
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   neighbor
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   piano
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Gillian Armstrong
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Louisa May Alcott
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Robin Swicord
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Susan Sarandon
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Winona Ryder
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Kirsten Dunst
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An adaptation that would make Alcott proud
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    fleurfairy
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Little Women remains one of my all-time favorite films. I first saw it as a child (after having loved the 1949 version) and this film completely opened up the world of the March sisters for me. Not to knock the previous two big screen adaptations, but they don't come close to conveying the happiness, heartbreak, and nostalgia that Little Women of 1994 does. What is so refreshing about this film is the truth and realism of the book. The actresses don't wear makeup, they don't speak in melodramatic tones; the men aren't playboys or Rhett Butlers. The writing and acting feels natural and true to Alcott's novel - which makes the sisters' victories and losses all the more authentic to the viewer. This is a wonderful movie to watch with your family to teach them values of love, friendship, and loyalty.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wonderful Classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    piedbeauty37
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I read "Little Women" many times growing up. It is a wonderful book with memorable characters and great writing. It has been made into a movie three times. The first time, Jo was played by Kathryn Hepburn, the second time she was played by June Allyson, and this third time, she is played by Wonona Ryder. This is the story of the four March sisters who are growing up in Concord, Massachusetts. Their father is away serving the North in the War of the States. The family has undergone the hardship of losing their former money and must now struggle to maintain their genteel lifestyle. Meg, Jo, Beth, and Amy become so real that they leap out at you from the book and on the screen. Their various mishaps and adventures are well done, touching and at times hilarious. Each sister has her distinctive personality, but it is Jo who is the real star. She is Louisa May Alcott's, the author, alter ego. Winona does a credible job playing her. A young Christian Bale plays Laurie, the boy next store. This is a beautiful movie which the entire family will enjoy especially at Christmas.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    heart-warming and drawing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (daviddaphneredding@att.net)
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie, which I watch every Christmas, is a wonderful movie in so many ways and for so many reasons. The aesthetic qualities are very appealing: the snow in Civil War-time Concord, Massachusetts was very beautiful, as is the grass in the spring time. As for the acting, the cast was superb. Susan Sarandon, who could act well the part of a rough southern girl, adapted herself well to this part of a proper New England lady who meets well the challenge of raising her four daughters (the "little women"). While you hated Christian Bale in "Shaft", he made a very positive impression in this movie as Teddy. Mary Wickes was convincingly crabby as Aunt March, and you felt for Claire Danes as the fragile Beth. Winona Ryder was excellent as the beautiful and high-spirited Jo. The story was a portmanteau: there were three different love affairs which were resolved at the end of the movie. The final scene was very touching. All in all, it was a superb production which was magnetic: again, I'm drawn to it every Christmas, though it is good entertainment for any time of the year. Definitely a favorite of mine.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Choppy and forced
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bluebwings
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As a movie I find it to be sub-par as compared to the 1949 version. I'm torn, I do not want to rate it purely as a comparison but having been so familiar with the second version I can't entirely help it. Being honest with myself, were this the first time I was watching "Little Women" and this was the first version to be introduced to it I'd have stopped watching or completely lost interest. It was choppy, the acting didn't carry through all too well and it just seemed to be trying too hard to stick to a novel. Because of this I suspect it may be closer in accuracy to the novel than the '49 version. For that reason I am now interested in reading the novel that much more. Ryder did not play as strong a Jo as I found June Allyson did. Claire Danes was not a very warm and loving Beth nor was she very memorable a character as the '49 carried. I now simply must see the '33 version to compare as it is considered even better than the '49 version.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    hmm...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Cameron-gagon
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well I don't know where to start with this movie. I don't like it. The problem with this movie is there are no little women. There is one played by the mediocre Kirsten Dunst. Next, who names their child Jo. Jo is a man's name. If you want a butch in the movie, just name her Jo. She crushes on like a 40 year old man anyway. That explains the marital situation in the early 1900's. I didn't understand the point of the movie. The title was named for Jo's book that she wrote? Apparently i need to read the book... NOT. I wouldn't dare read this book. This movie maybe a classic for past generations of women with heart warming fun about lovely girls' lives in the early 1900's and how they deal with relationships. That in my opinion is the WORST. STORY LINE. EVER. Even if I appear to be sexist. I laugh at this movie every time Christian Bale appears with such a gross Fu Man Chu. It's gross and no one wants to see that. I think i got a little gayer watching Christian(Laurie)prance around like a little boy off the Newzies.(hey oh!) I mean he took my breath away! And not in a good way. In conclusion, if you're a girl, enjoy watching.:) If you're a boy and like this movie, you have major issues and keep watching gay boys dance around...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Missed the Bar
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Stephan Quinland
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Many flaws and not enough true romance. First and biggest problem is the film spends well over half of entire 123 minutes in the Concord House Where nobody had grown, or changed or learned. Then suddenly before the end, main character Josephine left for New York and young Amy went to France to "paint"?. Much of the Concord house is old and full of dark wood and did reflect the reduced circumstance of the family, where upon their neighbors were healthy and worldly. How does that happened ? The oldest sister Meg is married off and basically had no lines for the rest of the film. That left high-spirited,tempestuous Jo to fill much of rest of the movie. Susan Sarandon, normally a high-powered actress, had nothing much to do except appeared matronly. The long-returned father was much older than everyone else and strangely had no war stories to tell, or any gifts for his daughters. Young suitor Christian Bale and Jo seemed a natural couple but inexplicably Jo rebuffed his proposal, only to meet up later with a generation-apart German professor in NYC. When Jo went to the boarding house, the book has her taking the duty of governess to the proprietress's children. There wasn't a moment's footage suggesting anything of the kind. Wynona Ryder did fine work here and some argues the 1940's version with Kate Hepburn as Jo was more spirited. It is easy to imagined that but Ryder is more attractive and therefore easier to accept, while the most memorable performance belongs really to Kirsten Dunst's young Amy, the little sis. She was perfectly puckish and adorable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My Favorite "Little Women".
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Melanie Campbell
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Little Women" has always been a favorite book of mine. I think I've seen every film adaptation at least once. I can't resist costume dramas. All that having been said, is it any surprise that I love this movie? I enjoyed this movie more than all the other adaptations. It has depth that the others lack. It does not play the novel out scene by scene or have the cast reciting big chunks of the book itself. You are drawn into the very lively world of young women as the grow up. You cheer for them, and cry with them. All the characters are very well played. Here, the biggest, and best surprise is how fully realized male characters are. Laurie gets his due as a fifth lead, and John Brook steps out of the background to become someone the audience really likes. This film works as well as a film as it does as a story. Everything looks beautiful, and the music is great.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Where is the love?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    melsishunney
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let me just say that i have never read the book nor seen another adaptation, so this is my first "Little Women" experience... I am a huge fan of period dramas and usually figure that they are going to be soppy and romantic and usually i am correct. Usually. I thought the acting in this movie was great, it was just some of the plot that made this film impossible to enjoy. I am sure in the book things flow a lot nicer than they do in this film.. Basically i thought that Laurie and Jo were meant to end up together, and for some reason when he proposes she says no! She says they would fight too much but they didn't fight at all in the movie.. I couldn't understand when they seemed to have such good chemistry. I've come to an understanding that in the book she considers him more as a brother but i only found this out AFTER watching the film and getting mad at her rejection of him. When Jo's love interest is introduced all I could do was shake my head and say "no no no no" There seemed to be no chemistry there compared to what Jo and Laurie had previously.So when they kiss at the end, It all feels wrong. Then finally, when Laurie sees the older Amy and suddenly likes her? how long has actually past since Jo's rejection of him? To me it seemed as though he was on the rebound. Their marriage wasn't romantic at all.. I just didn't feel the romance in this film they way other period films show it. It was disappointing. The rest of the story was fine.But if you're looking for romance watch something like Wives and Daughters or North and South (Gaskell) or something Austen. They are all better than this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Historical girlie fare
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Neil Welch
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I suspect that the average Brit isn't half as exposed to Little Women as the average Yank. It has existed on the outside edge of my awareness since I was a kid, and I have caught odd tasters of various versions over the year without ever encountering the full works. So this 1994 movie version is the first version I have ever experienced all the way through, and I am considering it on a stand alone basis. This is an historical piece, telling of four sisters growing up in fairly cushioned circumstances in Concord Massachusetts. Father is away in the Civil War and money is tight. Each of the sisters is strongly drawn, but the story belongs to Jo, strong-willed, independent, and rather progressive (and, I suspect, also author Louisa M Alcott's alter ego). It is also rather soapy, much of what happens being fairly ordinary - money problems, boyfriend problems, births, deaths, marriages and so on. It's all fairly comforting and mildly entertaining. It comes alive when it hits moments of high emotion, and also when it follows Jo into an adult life in which she chooses to quietly challenge convention. She is also the sister who has the least obvious love life, falling in love (though neither of them are minded to face it) with German Professor Baer. This film is beautiful to look at and presents attractive performances from all the principals. The story is, frankly, a bit drippy for your average ageing British bloke, but it passes the time reasonably well. I think women will enjoy this a lot: I enjoyed it well enough.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Lovely Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thrwmbsbgkdoepmcjrmrdw
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love rewatching things after not seeing them in a long time and just falling in love with it all over again. And that's what happened here with Little Women. I was a young girl myself when it came out in theaters and I enjoyed it then, though honestly I don't recall if I had ever read the book before then. I don't have any sisters so I don't know the true relationship between sisters but I imagine it's a lot like brothers and I have three of them so I could relate in many ways to the relationships between the four of them. I think that Jo and Laurie would have made a great couple, but Jo was right. Laurie needed someone more like Amy than herself. Jo and Laurie were too much alike. The combination of Laurie and Amy matched together similar to Jo and Fredrick.Amy was calm and Laurie outgoing and Fredrick was calm and Jo outgoing. I can't think of anyone I know who has seen this movie and not cried when Beth passes away. A scene that sticks in your mind even days after watching it. Cuddle up in a blanket with your popcorn and enjoy this wonderful film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An adaptation that would make Alcott proud
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    fleurfairy
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Little Women remains one of my all-time favorite films. I first saw it as a child (after having loved the 1949 version) and this film completely opened up the world of the March sisters for me. Not to knock the previous two big screen adaptations, but they don't come close to conveying the happiness, heartbreak, and nostalgia that Little Women of 1994 does. What is so refreshing about this film is the truth and realism of the book. The actresses don't wear makeup, they don't speak in melodramatic tones; the men aren't playboys or Rhett Butlers. The writing and acting feels natural and true to Alcott's novel - which makes the sisters' victories and losses all the more authentic to the viewer. This is a wonderful movie to watch with your family to teach them values of love, friendship, and loyalty.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wonderful Classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    piedbeauty37
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I read "Little Women" many times growing up. It is a wonderful book with memorable characters and great writing. It has been made into a movie three times. The first time, Jo was played by Kathryn Hepburn, the second time she was played by June Allyson, and this third time, she is played by Wonona Ryder. This is the story of the four March sisters who are growing up in Concord, Massachusetts. Their father is away serving the North in the War of the States. The family has undergone the hardship of losing their former money and must now struggle to maintain their genteel lifestyle. Meg, Jo, Beth, and Amy become so real that they leap out at you from the book and on the screen. Their various mishaps and adventures are well done, touching and at times hilarious. Each sister has her distinctive personality, but it is Jo who is the real star. She is Louisa May Alcott's, the author, alter ego. Winona does a credible job playing her. A young Christian Bale plays Laurie, the boy next store. This is a beautiful movie which the entire family will enjoy especially at Christmas.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    heart-warming and drawing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (daviddaphneredding@att.net)
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie, which I watch every Christmas, is a wonderful movie in so many ways and for so many reasons. The aesthetic qualities are very appealing: the snow in Civil War-time Concord, Massachusetts was very beautiful, as is the grass in the spring time. As for the acting, the cast was superb. Susan Sarandon, who could act well the part of a rough southern girl, adapted herself well to this part of a proper New England lady who meets well the challenge of raising her four daughters (the "little women"). While you hated Christian Bale in "Shaft", he made a very positive impression in this movie as Teddy. Mary Wickes was convincingly crabby as Aunt March, and you felt for Claire Danes as the fragile Beth. Winona Ryder was excellent as the beautiful and high-spirited Jo. The story was a portmanteau: there were three different love affairs which were resolved at the end of the movie. The final scene was very touching. All in all, it was a superb production which was magnetic: again, I'm drawn to it every Christmas, though it is good entertainment for any time of the year. Definitely a favorite of mine.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Choppy and forced
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bluebwings
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As a movie I find it to be sub-par as compared to the 1949 version. I'm torn, I do not want to rate it purely as a comparison but having been so familiar with the second version I can't entirely help it. Being honest with myself, were this the first time I was watching "Little Women" and this was the first version to be introduced to it I'd have stopped watching or completely lost interest. It was choppy, the acting didn't carry through all too well and it just seemed to be trying too hard to stick to a novel. Because of this I suspect it may be closer in accuracy to the novel than the '49 version. For that reason I am now interested in reading the novel that much more. Ryder did not play as strong a Jo as I found June Allyson did. Claire Danes was not a very warm and loving Beth nor was she very memorable a character as the '49 carried. I now simply must see the '33 version to compare as it is considered even better than the '49 version.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    hmm...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Cameron-gagon
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well I don't know where to start with this movie. I don't like it. The problem with this movie is there are no little women. There is one played by the mediocre Kirsten Dunst. Next, who names their child Jo. Jo is a man's name. If you want a butch in the movie, just name her Jo. She crushes on like a 40 year old man anyway. That explains the marital situation in the early 1900's. I didn't understand the point of the movie. The title was named for Jo's book that she wrote? Apparently i need to read the book... NOT. I wouldn't dare read this book. This movie maybe a classic for past generations of women with heart warming fun about lovely girls' lives in the early 1900's and how they deal with relationships. That in my opinion is the WORST. STORY LINE. EVER. Even if I appear to be sexist. I laugh at this movie every time Christian Bale appears with such a gross Fu Man Chu. It's gross and no one wants to see that. I think i got a little gayer watching Christian(Laurie)prance around like a little boy off the Newzies.(hey oh!) I mean he took my breath away! And not in a good way. In conclusion, if you're a girl, enjoy watching.:) If you're a boy and like this movie, you have major issues and keep watching gay boys dance around...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Missed the Bar
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Stephan Quinland
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Many flaws and not enough true romance. First and biggest problem is the film spends well over half of entire 123 minutes in the Concord House Where nobody had grown, or changed or learned. Then suddenly before the end, main character Josephine left for New York and young Amy went to France to "paint"?. Much of the Concord house is old and full of dark wood and did reflect the reduced circumstance of the family, where upon their neighbors were healthy and worldly. How does that happened ? The oldest sister Meg is married off and basically had no lines for the rest of the film. That left high-spirited,tempestuous Jo to fill much of rest of the movie. Susan Sarandon, normally a high-powered actress, had nothing much to do except appeared matronly. The long-returned father was much older than everyone else and strangely had no war stories to tell, or any gifts for his daughters. Young suitor Christian Bale and Jo seemed a natural couple but inexplicably Jo rebuffed his proposal, only to meet up later with a generation-apart German professor in NYC. When Jo went to the boarding house, the book has her taking the duty of governess to the proprietress's children. There wasn't a moment's footage suggesting anything of the kind. Wynona Ryder did fine work here and some argues the 1940's version with Kate Hepburn as Jo was more spirited. It is easy to imagined that but Ryder is more attractive and therefore easier to accept, while the most memorable performance belongs really to Kirsten Dunst's young Amy, the little sis. She was perfectly puckish and adorable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My Favorite "Little Women".
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Melanie Campbell
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Little Women" has always been a favorite book of mine. I think I've seen every film adaptation at least once. I can't resist costume dramas. All that having been said, is it any surprise that I love this movie? I enjoyed this movie more than all the other adaptations. It has depth that the others lack. It does not play the novel out scene by scene or have the cast reciting big chunks of the book itself. You are drawn into the very lively world of young women as the grow up. You cheer for them, and cry with them. All the characters are very well played. Here, the biggest, and best surprise is how fully realized male characters are. Laurie gets his due as a fifth lead, and John Brook steps out of the background to become someone the audience really likes. This film works as well as a film as it does as a story. Everything looks beautiful, and the music is great.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Where is the love?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    melsishunney
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let me just say that i have never read the book nor seen another adaptation, so this is my first "Little Women" experience... I am a huge fan of period dramas and usually figure that they are going to be soppy and romantic and usually i am correct. Usually. I thought the acting in this movie was great, it was just some of the plot that made this film impossible to enjoy. I am sure in the book things flow a lot nicer than they do in this film.. Basically i thought that Laurie and Jo were meant to end up together, and for some reason when he proposes she says no! She says they would fight too much but they didn't fight at all in the movie.. I couldn't understand when they seemed to have such good chemistry. I've come to an understanding that in the book she considers him more as a brother but i only found this out AFTER watching the film and getting mad at her rejection of him. When Jo's love interest is introduced all I could do was shake my head and say "no no no no" There seemed to be no chemistry there compared to what Jo and Laurie had previously.So when they kiss at the end, It all feels wrong. Then finally, when Laurie sees the older Amy and suddenly likes her? how long has actually past since Jo's rejection of him? To me it seemed as though he was on the rebound. Their marriage wasn't romantic at all.. I just didn't feel the romance in this film they way other period films show it. It was disappointing. The rest of the story was fine.But if you're looking for romance watch something like Wives and Daughters or North and South (Gaskell) or something Austen. They are all better than this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Historical girlie fare
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Neil Welch
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I suspect that the average Brit isn't half as exposed to Little Women as the average Yank. It has existed on the outside edge of my awareness since I was a kid, and I have caught odd tasters of various versions over the year without ever encountering the full works. So this 1994 movie version is the first version I have ever experienced all the way through, and I am considering it on a stand alone basis. This is an historical piece, telling of four sisters growing up in fairly cushioned circumstances in Concord Massachusetts. Father is away in the Civil War and money is tight. Each of the sisters is strongly drawn, but the story belongs to Jo, strong-willed, independent, and rather progressive (and, I suspect, also author Louisa M Alcott's alter ego). It is also rather soapy, much of what happens being fairly ordinary - money problems, boyfriend problems, births, deaths, marriages and so on. It's all fairly comforting and mildly entertaining. It comes alive when it hits moments of high emotion, and also when it follows Jo into an adult life in which she chooses to quietly challenge convention. She is also the sister who has the least obvious love life, falling in love (though neither of them are minded to face it) with German Professor Baer. This film is beautiful to look at and presents attractive performances from all the principals. The story is, frankly, a bit drippy for your average ageing British bloke, but it passes the time reasonably well. I think women will enjoy this a lot: I enjoyed it well enough.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Lovely Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thrwmbsbgkdoepmcjrmrdw
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love rewatching things after not seeing them in a long time and just falling in love with it all over again. And that's what happened here with Little Women. I was a young girl myself when it came out in theaters and I enjoyed it then, though honestly I don't recall if I had ever read the book before then. I don't have any sisters so I don't know the true relationship between sisters but I imagine it's a lot like brothers and I have three of them so I could relate in many ways to the relationships between the four of them. I think that Jo and Laurie would have made a great couple, but Jo was right. Laurie needed someone more like Amy than herself. Jo and Laurie were too much alike. The combination of Laurie and Amy matched together similar to Jo and Fredrick.Amy was calm and Laurie outgoing and Fredrick was calm and Jo outgoing. I can't think of anyone I know who has seen this movie and not cried when Beth passes away. A scene that sticks in your mind even days after watching it. Cuddle up in a blanket with your popcorn and enjoy this wonderful film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An adaptation that would make Alcott proud
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    fleurfairy
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Little Women remains one of my all-time favorite films. I first saw it as a child (after having loved the 1949 version) and this film completely opened up the world of the March sisters for me. Not to knock the previous two big screen adaptations, but they don't come close to conveying the happiness, heartbreak, and nostalgia that Little Women of 1994 does. What is so refreshing about this film is the truth and realism of the book. The actresses don't wear makeup, they don't speak in melodramatic tones; the men aren't playboys or Rhett Butlers. The writing and acting feels natural and true to Alcott's novel - which makes the sisters' victories and losses all the more authentic to the viewer. This is a wonderful movie to watch with your family to teach them values of love, friendship, and loyalty.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wonderful Classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    piedbeauty37
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I read "Little Women" many times growing up. It is a wonderful book with memorable characters and great writing. It has been made into a movie three times. The first time, Jo was played by Kathryn Hepburn, the second time she was played by June Allyson, and this third time, she is played by Wonona Ryder. This is the story of the four March sisters who are growing up in Concord, Massachusetts. Their father is away serving the North in the War of the States. The family has undergone the hardship of losing their former money and must now struggle to maintain their genteel lifestyle. Meg, Jo, Beth, and Amy become so real that they leap out at you from the book and on the screen. Their various mishaps and adventures are well done, touching and at times hilarious. Each sister has her distinctive personality, but it is Jo who is the real star. She is Louisa May Alcott's, the author, alter ego. Winona does a credible job playing her. A young Christian Bale plays Laurie, the boy next store. This is a beautiful movie which the entire family will enjoy especially at Christmas.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    heart-warming and drawing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (daviddaphneredding@att.net)
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie, which I watch every Christmas, is a wonderful movie in so many ways and for so many reasons. The aesthetic qualities are very appealing: the snow in Civil War-time Concord, Massachusetts was very beautiful, as is the grass in the spring time. As for the acting, the cast was superb. Susan Sarandon, who could act well the part of a rough southern girl, adapted herself well to this part of a proper New England lady who meets well the challenge of raising her four daughters (the "little women"). While you hated Christian Bale in "Shaft", he made a very positive impression in this movie as Teddy. Mary Wickes was convincingly crabby as Aunt March, and you felt for Claire Danes as the fragile Beth. Winona Ryder was excellent as the beautiful and high-spirited Jo. The story was a portmanteau: there were three different love affairs which were resolved at the end of the movie. The final scene was very touching. All in all, it was a superb production which was magnetic: again, I'm drawn to it every Christmas, though it is good entertainment for any time of the year. Definitely a favorite of mine.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Choppy and forced
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bluebwings
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As a movie I find it to be sub-par as compared to the 1949 version. I'm torn, I do not want to rate it purely as a comparison but having been so familiar with the second version I can't entirely help it. Being honest with myself, were this the first time I was watching "Little Women" and this was the first version to be introduced to it I'd have stopped watching or completely lost interest. It was choppy, the acting didn't carry through all too well and it just seemed to be trying too hard to stick to a novel. Because of this I suspect it may be closer in accuracy to the novel than the '49 version. For that reason I am now interested in reading the novel that much more. Ryder did not play as strong a Jo as I found June Allyson did. Claire Danes was not a very warm and loving Beth nor was she very memorable a character as the '49 carried. I now simply must see the '33 version to compare as it is considered even better than the '49 version.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    hmm...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Cameron-gagon
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well I don't know where to start with this movie. I don't like it. The problem with this movie is there are no little women. There is one played by the mediocre Kirsten Dunst. Next, who names their child Jo. Jo is a man's name. If you want a butch in the movie, just name her Jo. She crushes on like a 40 year old man anyway. That explains the marital situation in the early 1900's. I didn't understand the point of the movie. The title was named for Jo's book that she wrote? Apparently i need to read the book... NOT. I wouldn't dare read this book. This movie maybe a classic for past generations of women with heart warming fun about lovely girls' lives in the early 1900's and how they deal with relationships. That in my opinion is the WORST. STORY LINE. EVER. Even if I appear to be sexist. I laugh at this movie every time Christian Bale appears with such a gross Fu Man Chu. It's gross and no one wants to see that. I think i got a little gayer watching Christian(Laurie)prance around like a little boy off the Newzies.(hey oh!) I mean he took my breath away! And not in a good way. In conclusion, if you're a girl, enjoy watching.:) If you're a boy and like this movie, you have major issues and keep watching gay boys dance around...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Missed the Bar
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Stephan Quinland
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Many flaws and not enough true romance. First and biggest problem is the film spends well over half of entire 123 minutes in the Concord House Where nobody had grown, or changed or learned. Then suddenly before the end, main character Josephine left for New York and young Amy went to France to "paint"?. Much of the Concord house is old and full of dark wood and did reflect the reduced circumstance of the family, where upon their neighbors were healthy and worldly. How does that happened ? The oldest sister Meg is married off and basically had no lines for the rest of the film. That left high-spirited,tempestuous Jo to fill much of rest of the movie. Susan Sarandon, normally a high-powered actress, had nothing much to do except appeared matronly. The long-returned father was much older than everyone else and strangely had no war stories to tell, or any gifts for his daughters. Young suitor Christian Bale and Jo seemed a natural couple but inexplicably Jo rebuffed his proposal, only to meet up later with a generation-apart German professor in NYC. When Jo went to the boarding house, the book has her taking the duty of governess to the proprietress's children. There wasn't a moment's footage suggesting anything of the kind. Wynona Ryder did fine work here and some argues the 1940's version with Kate Hepburn as Jo was more spirited. It is easy to imagined that but Ryder is more attractive and therefore easier to accept, while the most memorable performance belongs really to Kirsten Dunst's young Amy, the little sis. She was perfectly puckish and adorable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My Favorite "Little Women".
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Melanie Campbell
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Little Women" has always been a favorite book of mine. I think I've seen every film adaptation at least once. I can't resist costume dramas. All that having been said, is it any surprise that I love this movie? I enjoyed this movie more than all the other adaptations. It has depth that the others lack. It does not play the novel out scene by scene or have the cast reciting big chunks of the book itself. You are drawn into the very lively world of young women as the grow up. You cheer for them, and cry with them. All the characters are very well played. Here, the biggest, and best surprise is how fully realized male characters are. Laurie gets his due as a fifth lead, and John Brook steps out of the background to become someone the audience really likes. This film works as well as a film as it does as a story. Everything looks beautiful, and the music is great.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Where is the love?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    melsishunney
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let me just say that i have never read the book nor seen another adaptation, so this is my first "Little Women" experience... I am a huge fan of period dramas and usually figure that they are going to be soppy and romantic and usually i am correct. Usually. I thought the acting in this movie was great, it was just some of the plot that made this film impossible to enjoy. I am sure in the book things flow a lot nicer than they do in this film.. Basically i thought that Laurie and Jo were meant to end up together, and for some reason when he proposes she says no! She says they would fight too much but they didn't fight at all in the movie.. I couldn't understand when they seemed to have such good chemistry. I've come to an understanding that in the book she considers him more as a brother but i only found this out AFTER watching the film and getting mad at her rejection of him. When Jo's love interest is introduced all I could do was shake my head and say "no no no no" There seemed to be no chemistry there compared to what Jo and Laurie had previously.So when they kiss at the end, It all feels wrong. Then finally, when Laurie sees the older Amy and suddenly likes her? how long has actually past since Jo's rejection of him? To me it seemed as though he was on the rebound. Their marriage wasn't romantic at all.. I just didn't feel the romance in this film they way other period films show it. It was disappointing. The rest of the story was fine.But if you're looking for romance watch something like Wives and Daughters or North and South (Gaskell) or something Austen. They are all better than this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Historical girlie fare
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Neil Welch
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I suspect that the average Brit isn't half as exposed to Little Women as the average Yank. It has existed on the outside edge of my awareness since I was a kid, and I have caught odd tasters of various versions over the year without ever encountering the full works. So this 1994 movie version is the first version I have ever experienced all the way through, and I am considering it on a stand alone basis. This is an historical piece, telling of four sisters growing up in fairly cushioned circumstances in Concord Massachusetts. Father is away in the Civil War and money is tight. Each of the sisters is strongly drawn, but the story belongs to Jo, strong-willed, independent, and rather progressive (and, I suspect, also author Louisa M Alcott's alter ego). It is also rather soapy, much of what happens being fairly ordinary - money problems, boyfriend problems, births, deaths, marriages and so on. It's all fairly comforting and mildly entertaining. It comes alive when it hits moments of high emotion, and also when it follows Jo into an adult life in which she chooses to quietly challenge convention. She is also the sister who has the least obvious love life, falling in love (though neither of them are minded to face it) with German Professor Baer. This film is beautiful to look at and presents attractive performances from all the principals. The story is, frankly, a bit drippy for your average ageing British bloke, but it passes the time reasonably well. I think women will enjoy this a lot: I enjoyed it well enough.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Lovely Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thrwmbsbgkdoepmcjrmrdw
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love rewatching things after not seeing them in a long time and just falling in love with it all over again. And that's what happened here with Little Women. I was a young girl myself when it came out in theaters and I enjoyed it then, though honestly I don't recall if I had ever read the book before then. I don't have any sisters so I don't know the true relationship between sisters but I imagine it's a lot like brothers and I have three of them so I could relate in many ways to the relationships between the four of them. I think that Jo and Laurie would have made a great couple, but Jo was right. Laurie needed someone more like Amy than herself. Jo and Laurie were too much alike. The combination of Laurie and Amy matched together similar to Jo and Fredrick.Amy was calm and Laurie outgoing and Fredrick was calm and Jo outgoing. I can't think of anyone I know who has seen this movie and not cried when Beth passes away. A scene that sticks in your mind even days after watching it. Cuddle up in a blanket with your popcorn and enjoy this wonderful film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An adaptation that would make Alcott proud
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    fleurfairy
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Little Women remains one of my all-time favorite films. I first saw it as a child (after having loved the 1949 version) and this film completely opened up the world of the March sisters for me. Not to knock the previous two big screen adaptations, but they don't come close to conveying the happiness, heartbreak, and nostalgia that Little Women of 1994 does. What is so refreshing about this film is the truth and realism of the book. The actresses don't wear makeup, they don't speak in melodramatic tones; the men aren't playboys or Rhett Butlers. The writing and acting feels natural and true to Alcott's novel - which makes the sisters' victories and losses all the more authentic to the viewer. This is a wonderful movie to watch with your family to teach them values of love, friendship, and loyalty.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wonderful Classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    piedbeauty37
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I read "Little Women" many times growing up. It is a wonderful book with memorable characters and great writing. It has been made into a movie three times. The first time, Jo was played by Kathryn Hepburn, the second time she was played by June Allyson, and this third time, she is played by Wonona Ryder. This is the story of the four March sisters who are growing up in Concord, Massachusetts. Their father is away serving the North in the War of the States. The family has undergone the hardship of losing their former money and must now struggle to maintain their genteel lifestyle. Meg, Jo, Beth, and Amy become so real that they leap out at you from the book and on the screen. Their various mishaps and adventures are well done, touching and at times hilarious. Each sister has her distinctive personality, but it is Jo who is the real star. She is Louisa May Alcott's, the author, alter ego. Winona does a credible job playing her. A young Christian Bale plays Laurie, the boy next store. This is a beautiful movie which the entire family will enjoy especially at Christmas.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    heart-warming and drawing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (daviddaphneredding@att.net)
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie, which I watch every Christmas, is a wonderful movie in so many ways and for so many reasons. The aesthetic qualities are very appealing: the snow in Civil War-time Concord, Massachusetts was very beautiful, as is the grass in the spring time. As for the acting, the cast was superb. Susan Sarandon, who could act well the part of a rough southern girl, adapted herself well to this part of a proper New England lady who meets well the challenge of raising her four daughters (the "little women"). While you hated Christian Bale in "Shaft", he made a very positive impression in this movie as Teddy. Mary Wickes was convincingly crabby as Aunt March, and you felt for Claire Danes as the fragile Beth. Winona Ryder was excellent as the beautiful and high-spirited Jo. The story was a portmanteau: there were three different love affairs which were resolved at the end of the movie. The final scene was very touching. All in all, it was a superb production which was magnetic: again, I'm drawn to it every Christmas, though it is good entertainment for any time of the year. Definitely a favorite of mine.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Choppy and forced
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bluebwings
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As a movie I find it to be sub-par as compared to the 1949 version. I'm torn, I do not want to rate it purely as a comparison but having been so familiar with the second version I can't entirely help it. Being honest with myself, were this the first time I was watching "Little Women" and this was the first version to be introduced to it I'd have stopped watching or completely lost interest. It was choppy, the acting didn't carry through all too well and it just seemed to be trying too hard to stick to a novel. Because of this I suspect it may be closer in accuracy to the novel than the '49 version. For that reason I am now interested in reading the novel that much more. Ryder did not play as strong a Jo as I found June Allyson did. Claire Danes was not a very warm and loving Beth nor was she very memorable a character as the '49 carried. I now simply must see the '33 version to compare as it is considered even better than the '49 version.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    hmm...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Cameron-gagon
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well I don't know where to start with this movie. I don't like it. The problem with this movie is there are no little women. There is one played by the mediocre Kirsten Dunst. Next, who names their child Jo. Jo is a man's name. If you want a butch in the movie, just name her Jo. She crushes on like a 40 year old man anyway. That explains the marital situation in the early 1900's. I didn't understand the point of the movie. The title was named for Jo's book that she wrote? Apparently i need to read the book... NOT. I wouldn't dare read this book. This movie maybe a classic for past generations of women with heart warming fun about lovely girls' lives in the early 1900's and how they deal with relationships. That in my opinion is the WORST. STORY LINE. EVER. Even if I appear to be sexist. I laugh at this movie every time Christian Bale appears with such a gross Fu Man Chu. It's gross and no one wants to see that. I think i got a little gayer watching Christian(Laurie)prance around like a little boy off the Newzies.(hey oh!) I mean he took my breath away! And not in a good way. In conclusion, if you're a girl, enjoy watching.:) If you're a boy and like this movie, you have major issues and keep watching gay boys dance around...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Missed the Bar
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Stephan Quinland
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Many flaws and not enough true romance. First and biggest problem is the film spends well over half of entire 123 minutes in the Concord House Where nobody had grown, or changed or learned. Then suddenly before the end, main character Josephine left for New York and young Amy went to France to "paint"?. Much of the Concord house is old and full of dark wood and did reflect the reduced circumstance of the family, where upon their neighbors were healthy and worldly. How does that happened ? The oldest sister Meg is married off and basically had no lines for the rest of the film. That left high-spirited,tempestuous Jo to fill much of rest of the movie. Susan Sarandon, normally a high-powered actress, had nothing much to do except appeared matronly. The long-returned father was much older than everyone else and strangely had no war stories to tell, or any gifts for his daughters. Young suitor Christian Bale and Jo seemed a natural couple but inexplicably Jo rebuffed his proposal, only to meet up later with a generation-apart German professor in NYC. When Jo went to the boarding house, the book has her taking the duty of governess to the proprietress's children. There wasn't a moment's footage suggesting anything of the kind. Wynona Ryder did fine work here and some argues the 1940's version with Kate Hepburn as Jo was more spirited. It is easy to imagined that but Ryder is more attractive and therefore easier to accept, while the most memorable performance belongs really to Kirsten Dunst's young Amy, the little sis. She was perfectly puckish and adorable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My Favorite "Little Women".
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Melanie Campbell
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Little Women" has always been a favorite book of mine. I think I've seen every film adaptation at least once. I can't resist costume dramas. All that having been said, is it any surprise that I love this movie? I enjoyed this movie more than all the other adaptations. It has depth that the others lack. It does not play the novel out scene by scene or have the cast reciting big chunks of the book itself. You are drawn into the very lively world of young women as the grow up. You cheer for them, and cry with them. All the characters are very well played. Here, the biggest, and best surprise is how fully realized male characters are. Laurie gets his due as a fifth lead, and John Brook steps out of the background to become someone the audience really likes. This film works as well as a film as it does as a story. Everything looks beautiful, and the music is great.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Where is the love?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    melsishunney
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let me just say that i have never read the book nor seen another adaptation, so this is my first "Little Women" experience... I am a huge fan of period dramas and usually figure that they are going to be soppy and romantic and usually i am correct. Usually. I thought the acting in this movie was great, it was just some of the plot that made this film impossible to enjoy. I am sure in the book things flow a lot nicer than they do in this film.. Basically i thought that Laurie and Jo were meant to end up together, and for some reason when he proposes she says no! She says they would fight too much but they didn't fight at all in the movie.. I couldn't understand when they seemed to have such good chemistry. I've come to an understanding that in the book she considers him more as a brother but i only found this out AFTER watching the film and getting mad at her rejection of him. When Jo's love interest is introduced all I could do was shake my head and say "no no no no" There seemed to be no chemistry there compared to what Jo and Laurie had previously.So when they kiss at the end, It all feels wrong. Then finally, when Laurie sees the older Amy and suddenly likes her? how long has actually past since Jo's rejection of him? To me it seemed as though he was on the rebound. Their marriage wasn't romantic at all.. I just didn't feel the romance in this film they way other period films show it. It was disappointing. The rest of the story was fine.But if you're looking for romance watch something like Wives and Daughters or North and South (Gaskell) or something Austen. They are all better than this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Historical girlie fare
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Neil Welch
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I suspect that the average Brit isn't half as exposed to Little Women as the average Yank. It has existed on the outside edge of my awareness since I was a kid, and I have caught odd tasters of various versions over the year without ever encountering the full works. So this 1994 movie version is the first version I have ever experienced all the way through, and I am considering it on a stand alone basis. This is an historical piece, telling of four sisters growing up in fairly cushioned circumstances in Concord Massachusetts. Father is away in the Civil War and money is tight. Each of the sisters is strongly drawn, but the story belongs to Jo, strong-willed, independent, and rather progressive (and, I suspect, also author Louisa M Alcott's alter ego). It is also rather soapy, much of what happens being fairly ordinary - money problems, boyfriend problems, births, deaths, marriages and so on. It's all fairly comforting and mildly entertaining. It comes alive when it hits moments of high emotion, and also when it follows Jo into an adult life in which she chooses to quietly challenge convention. She is also the sister who has the least obvious love life, falling in love (though neither of them are minded to face it) with German Professor Baer. This film is beautiful to look at and presents attractive performances from all the principals. The story is, frankly, a bit drippy for your average ageing British bloke, but it passes the time reasonably well. I think women will enjoy this a lot: I enjoyed it well enough.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Lovely Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thrwmbsbgkdoepmcjrmrdw
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love rewatching things after not seeing them in a long time and just falling in love with it all over again. And that's what happened here with Little Women. I was a young girl myself when it came out in theaters and I enjoyed it then, though honestly I don't recall if I had ever read the book before then. I don't have any sisters so I don't know the true relationship between sisters but I imagine it's a lot like brothers and I have three of them so I could relate in many ways to the relationships between the four of them. I think that Jo and Laurie would have made a great couple, but Jo was right. Laurie needed someone more like Amy than herself. Jo and Laurie were too much alike. The combination of Laurie and Amy matched together similar to Jo and Fredrick.Amy was calm and Laurie outgoing and Fredrick was calm and Jo outgoing. I can't think of anyone I know who has seen this movie and not cried when Beth passes away. A scene that sticks in your mind even days after watching it. Cuddle up in a blanket with your popcorn and enjoy this wonderful film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An adaptation that would make Alcott proud
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    fleurfairy
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Little Women remains one of my all-time favorite films. I first saw it as a child (after having loved the 1949 version) and this film completely opened up the world of the March sisters for me. Not to knock the previous two big screen adaptations, but they don't come close to conveying the happiness, heartbreak, and nostalgia that Little Women of 1994 does. What is so refreshing about this film is the truth and realism of the book. The actresses don't wear makeup, they don't speak in melodramatic tones; the men aren't playboys or Rhett Butlers. The writing and acting feels natural and true to Alcott's novel - which makes the sisters' victories and losses all the more authentic to the viewer. This is a wonderful movie to watch with your family to teach them values of love, friendship, and loyalty.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wonderful Classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    piedbeauty37
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I read "Little Women" many times growing up. It is a wonderful book with memorable characters and great writing. It has been made into a movie three times. The first time, Jo was played by Kathryn Hepburn, the second time she was played by June Allyson, and this third time, she is played by Wonona Ryder. This is the story of the four March sisters who are growing up in Concord, Massachusetts. Their father is away serving the North in the War of the States. The family has undergone the hardship of losing their former money and must now struggle to maintain their genteel lifestyle. Meg, Jo, Beth, and Amy become so real that they leap out at you from the book and on the screen. Their various mishaps and adventures are well done, touching and at times hilarious. Each sister has her distinctive personality, but it is Jo who is the real star. She is Louisa May Alcott's, the author, alter ego. Winona does a credible job playing her. A young Christian Bale plays Laurie, the boy next store. This is a beautiful movie which the entire family will enjoy especially at Christmas.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    heart-warming and drawing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (daviddaphneredding@att.net)
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie, which I watch every Christmas, is a wonderful movie in so many ways and for so many reasons. The aesthetic qualities are very appealing: the snow in Civil War-time Concord, Massachusetts was very beautiful, as is the grass in the spring time. As for the acting, the cast was superb. Susan Sarandon, who could act well the part of a rough southern girl, adapted herself well to this part of a proper New England lady who meets well the challenge of raising her four daughters (the "little women"). While you hated Christian Bale in "Shaft", he made a very positive impression in this movie as Teddy. Mary Wickes was convincingly crabby as Aunt March, and you felt for Claire Danes as the fragile Beth. Winona Ryder was excellent as the beautiful and high-spirited Jo. The story was a portmanteau: there were three different love affairs which were resolved at the end of the movie. The final scene was very touching. All in all, it was a superb production which was magnetic: again, I'm drawn to it every Christmas, though it is good entertainment for any time of the year. Definitely a favorite of mine.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Choppy and forced
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bluebwings
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As a movie I find it to be sub-par as compared to the 1949 version. I'm torn, I do not want to rate it purely as a comparison but having been so familiar with the second version I can't entirely help it. Being honest with myself, were this the first time I was watching "Little Women" and this was the first version to be introduced to it I'd have stopped watching or completely lost interest. It was choppy, the acting didn't carry through all too well and it just seemed to be trying too hard to stick to a novel. Because of this I suspect it may be closer in accuracy to the novel than the '49 version. For that reason I am now interested in reading the novel that much more. Ryder did not play as strong a Jo as I found June Allyson did. Claire Danes was not a very warm and loving Beth nor was she very memorable a character as the '49 carried. I now simply must see the '33 version to compare as it is considered even better than the '49 version.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    hmm...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Cameron-gagon
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well I don't know where to start with this movie. I don't like it. The problem with this movie is there are no little women. There is one played by the mediocre Kirsten Dunst. Next, who names their child Jo. Jo is a man's name. If you want a butch in the movie, just name her Jo. She crushes on like a 40 year old man anyway. That explains the marital situation in the early 1900's. I didn't understand the point of the movie. The title was named for Jo's book that she wrote? Apparently i need to read the book... NOT. I wouldn't dare read this book. This movie maybe a classic for past generations of women with heart warming fun about lovely girls' lives in the early 1900's and how they deal with relationships. That in my opinion is the WORST. STORY LINE. EVER. Even if I appear to be sexist. I laugh at this movie every time Christian Bale appears with such a gross Fu Man Chu. It's gross and no one wants to see that. I think i got a little gayer watching Christian(Laurie)prance around like a little boy off the Newzies.(hey oh!) I mean he took my breath away! And not in a good way. In conclusion, if you're a girl, enjoy watching.:) If you're a boy and like this movie, you have major issues and keep watching gay boys dance around...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Missed the Bar
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Stephan Quinland
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Many flaws and not enough true romance. First and biggest problem is the film spends well over half of entire 123 minutes in the Concord House Where nobody had grown, or changed or learned. Then suddenly before the end, main character Josephine left for New York and young Amy went to France to "paint"?. Much of the Concord house is old and full of dark wood and did reflect the reduced circumstance of the family, where upon their neighbors were healthy and worldly. How does that happened ? The oldest sister Meg is married off and basically had no lines for the rest of the film. That left high-spirited,tempestuous Jo to fill much of rest of the movie. Susan Sarandon, normally a high-powered actress, had nothing much to do except appeared matronly. The long-returned father was much older than everyone else and strangely had no war stories to tell, or any gifts for his daughters. Young suitor Christian Bale and Jo seemed a natural couple but inexplicably Jo rebuffed his proposal, only to meet up later with a generation-apart German professor in NYC. When Jo went to the boarding house, the book has her taking the duty of governess to the proprietress's children. There wasn't a moment's footage suggesting anything of the kind. Wynona Ryder did fine work here and some argues the 1940's version with Kate Hepburn as Jo was more spirited. It is easy to imagined that but Ryder is more attractive and therefore easier to accept, while the most memorable performance belongs really to Kirsten Dunst's young Amy, the little sis. She was perfectly puckish and adorable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My Favorite "Little Women".
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Melanie Campbell
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Little Women" has always been a favorite book of mine. I think I've seen every film adaptation at least once. I can't resist costume dramas. All that having been said, is it any surprise that I love this movie? I enjoyed this movie more than all the other adaptations. It has depth that the others lack. It does not play the novel out scene by scene or have the cast reciting big chunks of the book itself. You are drawn into the very lively world of young women as the grow up. You cheer for them, and cry with them. All the characters are very well played. Here, the biggest, and best surprise is how fully realized male characters are. Laurie gets his due as a fifth lead, and John Brook steps out of the background to become someone the audience really likes. This film works as well as a film as it does as a story. Everything looks beautiful, and the music is great.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Where is the love?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    melsishunney
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let me just say that i have never read the book nor seen another adaptation, so this is my first "Little Women" experience... I am a huge fan of period dramas and usually figure that they are going to be soppy and romantic and usually i am correct. Usually. I thought the acting in this movie was great, it was just some of the plot that made this film impossible to enjoy. I am sure in the book things flow a lot nicer than they do in this film.. Basically i thought that Laurie and Jo were meant to end up together, and for some reason when he proposes she says no! She says they would fight too much but they didn't fight at all in the movie.. I couldn't understand when they seemed to have such good chemistry. I've come to an understanding that in the book she considers him more as a brother but i only found this out AFTER watching the film and getting mad at her rejection of him. When Jo's love interest is introduced all I could do was shake my head and say "no no no no" There seemed to be no chemistry there compared to what Jo and Laurie had previously.So when they kiss at the end, It all feels wrong. Then finally, when Laurie sees the older Amy and suddenly likes her? how long has actually past since Jo's rejection of him? To me it seemed as though he was on the rebound. Their marriage wasn't romantic at all.. I just didn't feel the romance in this film they way other period films show it. It was disappointing. The rest of the story was fine.But if you're looking for romance watch something like Wives and Daughters or North and South (Gaskell) or something Austen. They are all better than this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Historical girlie fare
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Neil Welch
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I suspect that the average Brit isn't half as exposed to Little Women as the average Yank. It has existed on the outside edge of my awareness since I was a kid, and I have caught odd tasters of various versions over the year without ever encountering the full works. So this 1994 movie version is the first version I have ever experienced all the way through, and I am considering it on a stand alone basis. This is an historical piece, telling of four sisters growing up in fairly cushioned circumstances in Concord Massachusetts. Father is away in the Civil War and money is tight. Each of the sisters is strongly drawn, but the story belongs to Jo, strong-willed, independent, and rather progressive (and, I suspect, also author Louisa M Alcott's alter ego). It is also rather soapy, much of what happens being fairly ordinary - money problems, boyfriend problems, births, deaths, marriages and so on. It's all fairly comforting and mildly entertaining. It comes alive when it hits moments of high emotion, and also when it follows Jo into an adult life in which she chooses to quietly challenge convention. She is also the sister who has the least obvious love life, falling in love (though neither of them are minded to face it) with German Professor Baer. This film is beautiful to look at and presents attractive performances from all the principals. The story is, frankly, a bit drippy for your average ageing British bloke, but it passes the time reasonably well. I think women will enjoy this a lot: I enjoyed it well enough.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Lovely Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thrwmbsbgkdoepmcjrmrdw
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love rewatching things after not seeing them in a long time and just falling in love with it all over again. And that's what happened here with Little Women. I was a young girl myself when it came out in theaters and I enjoyed it then, though honestly I don't recall if I had ever read the book before then. I don't have any sisters so I don't know the true relationship between sisters but I imagine it's a lot like brothers and I have three of them so I could relate in many ways to the relationships between the four of them. I think that Jo and Laurie would have made a great couple, but Jo was right. Laurie needed someone more like Amy than herself. Jo and Laurie were too much alike. The combination of Laurie and Amy matched together similar to Jo and Fredrick.Amy was calm and Laurie outgoing and Fredrick was calm and Jo outgoing. I can't think of anyone I know who has seen this movie and not cried when Beth passes away. A scene that sticks in your mind even days after watching it. Cuddle up in a blanket with your popcorn and enjoy this wonderful film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An adaptation that would make Alcott proud
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    fleurfairy
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Little Women remains one of my all-time favorite films. I first saw it as a child (after having loved the 1949 version) and this film completely opened up the world of the March sisters for me. Not to knock the previous two big screen adaptations, but they don't come close to conveying the happiness, heartbreak, and nostalgia that Little Women of 1994 does. What is so refreshing about this film is the truth and realism of the book. The actresses don't wear makeup, they don't speak in melodramatic tones; the men aren't playboys or Rhett Butlers. The writing and acting feels natural and true to Alcott's novel - which makes the sisters' victories and losses all the more authentic to the viewer. This is a wonderful movie to watch with your family to teach them values of love, friendship, and loyalty.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wonderful Classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    piedbeauty37
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I read "Little Women" many times growing up. It is a wonderful book with memorable characters and great writing. It has been made into a movie three times. The first time, Jo was played by Kathryn Hepburn, the second time she was played by June Allyson, and this third time, she is played by Wonona Ryder. This is the story of the four March sisters who are growing up in Concord, Massachusetts. Their father is away serving the North in the War of the States. The family has undergone the hardship of losing their former money and must now struggle to maintain their genteel lifestyle. Meg, Jo, Beth, and Amy become so real that they leap out at you from the book and on the screen. Their various mishaps and adventures are well done, touching and at times hilarious. Each sister has her distinctive personality, but it is Jo who is the real star. She is Louisa May Alcott's, the author, alter ego. Winona does a credible job playing her. A young Christian Bale plays Laurie, the boy next store. This is a beautiful movie which the entire family will enjoy especially at Christmas.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    heart-warming and drawing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (daviddaphneredding@att.net)
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie, which I watch every Christmas, is a wonderful movie in so many ways and for so many reasons. The aesthetic qualities are very appealing: the snow in Civil War-time Concord, Massachusetts was very beautiful, as is the grass in the spring time. As for the acting, the cast was superb. Susan Sarandon, who could act well the part of a rough southern girl, adapted herself well to this part of a proper New England lady who meets well the challenge of raising her four daughters (the "little women"). While you hated Christian Bale in "Shaft", he made a very positive impression in this movie as Teddy. Mary Wickes was convincingly crabby as Aunt March, and you felt for Claire Danes as the fragile Beth. Winona Ryder was excellent as the beautiful and high-spirited Jo. The story was a portmanteau: there were three different love affairs which were resolved at the end of the movie. The final scene was very touching. All in all, it was a superb production which was magnetic: again, I'm drawn to it every Christmas, though it is good entertainment for any time of the year. Definitely a favorite of mine.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Choppy and forced
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bluebwings
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As a movie I find it to be sub-par as compared to the 1949 version. I'm torn, I do not want to rate it purely as a comparison but having been so familiar with the second version I can't entirely help it. Being honest with myself, were this the first time I was watching "Little Women" and this was the first version to be introduced to it I'd have stopped watching or completely lost interest. It was choppy, the acting didn't carry through all too well and it just seemed to be trying too hard to stick to a novel. Because of this I suspect it may be closer in accuracy to the novel than the '49 version. For that reason I am now interested in reading the novel that much more. Ryder did not play as strong a Jo as I found June Allyson did. Claire Danes was not a very warm and loving Beth nor was she very memorable a character as the '49 carried. I now simply must see the '33 version to compare as it is considered even better than the '49 version.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    hmm...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Cameron-gagon
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well I don't know where to start with this movie. I don't like it. The problem with this movie is there are no little women. There is one played by the mediocre Kirsten Dunst. Next, who names their child Jo. Jo is a man's name. If you want a butch in the movie, just name her Jo. She crushes on like a 40 year old man anyway. That explains the marital situation in the early 1900's. I didn't understand the point of the movie. The title was named for Jo's book that she wrote? Apparently i need to read the book... NOT. I wouldn't dare read this book. This movie maybe a classic for past generations of women with heart warming fun about lovely girls' lives in the early 1900's and how they deal with relationships. That in my opinion is the WORST. STORY LINE. EVER. Even if I appear to be sexist. I laugh at this movie every time Christian Bale appears with such a gross Fu Man Chu. It's gross and no one wants to see that. I think i got a little gayer watching Christian(Laurie)prance around like a little boy off the Newzies.(hey oh!) I mean he took my breath away! And not in a good way. In conclusion, if you're a girl, enjoy watching.:) If you're a boy and like this movie, you have major issues and keep watching gay boys dance around...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Missed the Bar
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Stephan Quinland
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Many flaws and not enough true romance. First and biggest problem is the film spends well over half of entire 123 minutes in the Concord House Where nobody had grown, or changed or learned. Then suddenly before the end, main character Josephine left for New York and young Amy went to France to "paint"?. Much of the Concord house is old and full of dark wood and did reflect the reduced circumstance of the family, where upon their neighbors were healthy and worldly. How does that happened ? The oldest sister Meg is married off and basically had no lines for the rest of the film. That left high-spirited,tempestuous Jo to fill much of rest of the movie. Susan Sarandon, normally a high-powered actress, had nothing much to do except appeared matronly. The long-returned father was much older than everyone else and strangely had no war stories to tell, or any gifts for his daughters. Young suitor Christian Bale and Jo seemed a natural couple but inexplicably Jo rebuffed his proposal, only to meet up later with a generation-apart German professor in NYC. When Jo went to the boarding house, the book has her taking the duty of governess to the proprietress's children. There wasn't a moment's footage suggesting anything of the kind. Wynona Ryder did fine work here and some argues the 1940's version with Kate Hepburn as Jo was more spirited. It is easy to imagined that but Ryder is more attractive and therefore easier to accept, while the most memorable performance belongs really to Kirsten Dunst's young Amy, the little sis. She was perfectly puckish and adorable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My Favorite "Little Women".
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Melanie Campbell
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Little Women" has always been a favorite book of mine. I think I've seen every film adaptation at least once. I can't resist costume dramas. All that having been said, is it any surprise that I love this movie? I enjoyed this movie more than all the other adaptations. It has depth that the others lack. It does not play the novel out scene by scene or have the cast reciting big chunks of the book itself. You are drawn into the very lively world of young women as the grow up. You cheer for them, and cry with them. All the characters are very well played. Here, the biggest, and best surprise is how fully realized male characters are. Laurie gets his due as a fifth lead, and John Brook steps out of the background to become someone the audience really likes. This film works as well as a film as it does as a story. Everything looks beautiful, and the music is great.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Where is the love?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    melsishunney
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let me just say that i have never read the book nor seen another adaptation, so this is my first "Little Women" experience... I am a huge fan of period dramas and usually figure that they are going to be soppy and romantic and usually i am correct. Usually. I thought the acting in this movie was great, it was just some of the plot that made this film impossible to enjoy. I am sure in the book things flow a lot nicer than they do in this film.. Basically i thought that Laurie and Jo were meant to end up together, and for some reason when he proposes she says no! She says they would fight too much but they didn't fight at all in the movie.. I couldn't understand when they seemed to have such good chemistry. I've come to an understanding that in the book she considers him more as a brother but i only found this out AFTER watching the film and getting mad at her rejection of him. When Jo's love interest is introduced all I could do was shake my head and say "no no no no" There seemed to be no chemistry there compared to what Jo and Laurie had previously.So when they kiss at the end, It all feels wrong. Then finally, when Laurie sees the older Amy and suddenly likes her? how long has actually past since Jo's rejection of him? To me it seemed as though he was on the rebound. Their marriage wasn't romantic at all.. I just didn't feel the romance in this film they way other period films show it. It was disappointing. The rest of the story was fine.But if you're looking for romance watch something like Wives and Daughters or North and South (Gaskell) or something Austen. They are all better than this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Historical girlie fare
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Neil Welch
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I suspect that the average Brit isn't half as exposed to Little Women as the average Yank. It has existed on the outside edge of my awareness since I was a kid, and I have caught odd tasters of various versions over the year without ever encountering the full works. So this 1994 movie version is the first version I have ever experienced all the way through, and I am considering it on a stand alone basis. This is an historical piece, telling of four sisters growing up in fairly cushioned circumstances in Concord Massachusetts. Father is away in the Civil War and money is tight. Each of the sisters is strongly drawn, but the story belongs to Jo, strong-willed, independent, and rather progressive (and, I suspect, also author Louisa M Alcott's alter ego). It is also rather soapy, much of what happens being fairly ordinary - money problems, boyfriend problems, births, deaths, marriages and so on. It's all fairly comforting and mildly entertaining. It comes alive when it hits moments of high emotion, and also when it follows Jo into an adult life in which she chooses to quietly challenge convention. She is also the sister who has the least obvious love life, falling in love (though neither of them are minded to face it) with German Professor Baer. This film is beautiful to look at and presents attractive performances from all the principals. The story is, frankly, a bit drippy for your average ageing British bloke, but it passes the time reasonably well. I think women will enjoy this a lot: I enjoyed it well enough.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Lovely Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thrwmbsbgkdoepmcjrmrdw
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love rewatching things after not seeing them in a long time and just falling in love with it all over again. And that's what happened here with Little Women. I was a young girl myself when it came out in theaters and I enjoyed it then, though honestly I don't recall if I had ever read the book before then. I don't have any sisters so I don't know the true relationship between sisters but I imagine it's a lot like brothers and I have three of them so I could relate in many ways to the relationships between the four of them. I think that Jo and Laurie would have made a great couple, but Jo was right. Laurie needed someone more like Amy than herself. Jo and Laurie were too much alike. The combination of Laurie and Amy matched together similar to Jo and Fredrick.Amy was calm and Laurie outgoing and Fredrick was calm and Jo outgoing. I can't think of anyone I know who has seen this movie and not cried when Beth passes away. A scene that sticks in your mind even days after watching it. Cuddle up in a blanket with your popcorn and enjoy this wonderful film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An adaptation that would make Alcott proud
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    fleurfairy
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Little Women remains one of my all-time favorite films. I first saw it as a child (after having loved the 1949 version) and this film completely opened up the world of the March sisters for me. Not to knock the previous two big screen adaptations, but they don't come close to conveying the happiness, heartbreak, and nostalgia that Little Women of 1994 does. What is so refreshing about this film is the truth and realism of the book. The actresses don't wear makeup, they don't speak in melodramatic tones; the men aren't playboys or Rhett Butlers. The writing and acting feels natural and true to Alcott's novel - which makes the sisters' victories and losses all the more authentic to the viewer. This is a wonderful movie to watch with your family to teach them values of love, friendship, and loyalty.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wonderful Classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    piedbeauty37
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I read "Little Women" many times growing up. It is a wonderful book with memorable characters and great writing. It has been made into a movie three times. The first time, Jo was played by Kathryn Hepburn, the second time she was played by June Allyson, and this third time, she is played by Wonona Ryder. This is the story of the four March sisters who are growing up in Concord, Massachusetts. Their father is away serving the North in the War of the States. The family has undergone the hardship of losing their former money and must now struggle to maintain their genteel lifestyle. Meg, Jo, Beth, and Amy become so real that they leap out at you from the book and on the screen. Their various mishaps and adventures are well done, touching and at times hilarious. Each sister has her distinctive personality, but it is Jo who is the real star. She is Louisa May Alcott's, the author, alter ego. Winona does a credible job playing her. A young Christian Bale plays Laurie, the boy next store. This is a beautiful movie which the entire family will enjoy especially at Christmas.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    heart-warming and drawing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (daviddaphneredding@att.net)
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie, which I watch every Christmas, is a wonderful movie in so many ways and for so many reasons. The aesthetic qualities are very appealing: the snow in Civil War-time Concord, Massachusetts was very beautiful, as is the grass in the spring time. As for the acting, the cast was superb. Susan Sarandon, who could act well the part of a rough southern girl, adapted herself well to this part of a proper New England lady who meets well the challenge of raising her four daughters (the "little women"). While you hated Christian Bale in "Shaft", he made a very positive impression in this movie as Teddy. Mary Wickes was convincingly crabby as Aunt March, and you felt for Claire Danes as the fragile Beth. Winona Ryder was excellent as the beautiful and high-spirited Jo. The story was a portmanteau: there were three different love affairs which were resolved at the end of the movie. The final scene was very touching. All in all, it was a superb production which was magnetic: again, I'm drawn to it every Christmas, though it is good entertainment for any time of the year. Definitely a favorite of mine.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Choppy and forced
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bluebwings
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As a movie I find it to be sub-par as compared to the 1949 version. I'm torn, I do not want to rate it purely as a comparison but having been so familiar with the second version I can't entirely help it. Being honest with myself, were this the first time I was watching "Little Women" and this was the first version to be introduced to it I'd have stopped watching or completely lost interest. It was choppy, the acting didn't carry through all too well and it just seemed to be trying too hard to stick to a novel. Because of this I suspect it may be closer in accuracy to the novel than the '49 version. For that reason I am now interested in reading the novel that much more. Ryder did not play as strong a Jo as I found June Allyson did. Claire Danes was not a very warm and loving Beth nor was she very memorable a character as the '49 carried. I now simply must see the '33 version to compare as it is considered even better than the '49 version.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    hmm...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Cameron-gagon
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well I don't know where to start with this movie. I don't like it. The problem with this movie is there are no little women. There is one played by the mediocre Kirsten Dunst. Next, who names their child Jo. Jo is a man's name. If you want a butch in the movie, just name her Jo. She crushes on like a 40 year old man anyway. That explains the marital situation in the early 1900's. I didn't understand the point of the movie. The title was named for Jo's book that she wrote? Apparently i need to read the book... NOT. I wouldn't dare read this book. This movie maybe a classic for past generations of women with heart warming fun about lovely girls' lives in the early 1900's and how they deal with relationships. That in my opinion is the WORST. STORY LINE. EVER. Even if I appear to be sexist. I laugh at this movie every time Christian Bale appears with such a gross Fu Man Chu. It's gross and no one wants to see that. I think i got a little gayer watching Christian(Laurie)prance around like a little boy off the Newzies.(hey oh!) I mean he took my breath away! And not in a good way. In conclusion, if you're a girl, enjoy watching.:) If you're a boy and like this movie, you have major issues and keep watching gay boys dance around...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Missed the Bar
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Stephan Quinland
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Many flaws and not enough true romance. First and biggest problem is the film spends well over half of entire 123 minutes in the Concord House Where nobody had grown, or changed or learned. Then suddenly before the end, main character Josephine left for New York and young Amy went to France to "paint"?. Much of the Concord house is old and full of dark wood and did reflect the reduced circumstance of the family, where upon their neighbors were healthy and worldly. How does that happened ? The oldest sister Meg is married off and basically had no lines for the rest of the film. That left high-spirited,tempestuous Jo to fill much of rest of the movie. Susan Sarandon, normally a high-powered actress, had nothing much to do except appeared matronly. The long-returned father was much older than everyone else and strangely had no war stories to tell, or any gifts for his daughters. Young suitor Christian Bale and Jo seemed a natural couple but inexplicably Jo rebuffed his proposal, only to meet up later with a generation-apart German professor in NYC. When Jo went to the boarding house, the book has her taking the duty of governess to the proprietress's children. There wasn't a moment's footage suggesting anything of the kind. Wynona Ryder did fine work here and some argues the 1940's version with Kate Hepburn as Jo was more spirited. It is easy to imagined that but Ryder is more attractive and therefore easier to accept, while the most memorable performance belongs really to Kirsten Dunst's young Amy, the little sis. She was perfectly puckish and adorable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My Favorite "Little Women".
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Melanie Campbell
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Little Women" has always been a favorite book of mine. I think I've seen every film adaptation at least once. I can't resist costume dramas. All that having been said, is it any surprise that I love this movie? I enjoyed this movie more than all the other adaptations. It has depth that the others lack. It does not play the novel out scene by scene or have the cast reciting big chunks of the book itself. You are drawn into the very lively world of young women as the grow up. You cheer for them, and cry with them. All the characters are very well played. Here, the biggest, and best surprise is how fully realized male characters are. Laurie gets his due as a fifth lead, and John Brook steps out of the background to become someone the audience really likes. This film works as well as a film as it does as a story. Everything looks beautiful, and the music is great.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Where is the love?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    melsishunney
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let me just say that i have never read the book nor seen another adaptation, so this is my first "Little Women" experience... I am a huge fan of period dramas and usually figure that they are going to be soppy and romantic and usually i am correct. Usually. I thought the acting in this movie was great, it was just some of the plot that made this film impossible to enjoy. I am sure in the book things flow a lot nicer than they do in this film.. Basically i thought that Laurie and Jo were meant to end up together, and for some reason when he proposes she says no! She says they would fight too much but they didn't fight at all in the movie.. I couldn't understand when they seemed to have such good chemistry. I've come to an understanding that in the book she considers him more as a brother but i only found this out AFTER watching the film and getting mad at her rejection of him. When Jo's love interest is introduced all I could do was shake my head and say "no no no no" There seemed to be no chemistry there compared to what Jo and Laurie had previously.So when they kiss at the end, It all feels wrong. Then finally, when Laurie sees the older Amy and suddenly likes her? how long has actually past since Jo's rejection of him? To me it seemed as though he was on the rebound. Their marriage wasn't romantic at all.. I just didn't feel the romance in this film they way other period films show it. It was disappointing. The rest of the story was fine.But if you're looking for romance watch something like Wives and Daughters or North and South (Gaskell) or something Austen. They are all better than this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Historical girlie fare
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Neil Welch
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I suspect that the average Brit isn't half as exposed to Little Women as the average Yank. It has existed on the outside edge of my awareness since I was a kid, and I have caught odd tasters of various versions over the year without ever encountering the full works. So this 1994 movie version is the first version I have ever experienced all the way through, and I am considering it on a stand alone basis. This is an historical piece, telling of four sisters growing up in fairly cushioned circumstances in Concord Massachusetts. Father is away in the Civil War and money is tight. Each of the sisters is strongly drawn, but the story belongs to Jo, strong-willed, independent, and rather progressive (and, I suspect, also author Louisa M Alcott's alter ego). It is also rather soapy, much of what happens being fairly ordinary - money problems, boyfriend problems, births, deaths, marriages and so on. It's all fairly comforting and mildly entertaining. It comes alive when it hits moments of high emotion, and also when it follows Jo into an adult life in which she chooses to quietly challenge convention. She is also the sister who has the least obvious love life, falling in love (though neither of them are minded to face it) with German Professor Baer. This film is beautiful to look at and presents attractive performances from all the principals. The story is, frankly, a bit drippy for your average ageing British bloke, but it passes the time reasonably well. I think women will enjoy this a lot: I enjoyed it well enough.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Lovely Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thrwmbsbgkdoepmcjrmrdw
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love rewatching things after not seeing them in a long time and just falling in love with it all over again. And that's what happened here with Little Women. I was a young girl myself when it came out in theaters and I enjoyed it then, though honestly I don't recall if I had ever read the book before then. I don't have any sisters so I don't know the true relationship between sisters but I imagine it's a lot like brothers and I have three of them so I could relate in many ways to the relationships between the four of them. I think that Jo and Laurie would have made a great couple, but Jo was right. Laurie needed someone more like Amy than herself. Jo and Laurie were too much alike. The combination of Laurie and Amy matched together similar to Jo and Fredrick.Amy was calm and Laurie outgoing and Fredrick was calm and Jo outgoing. I can't think of anyone I know who has seen this movie and not cried when Beth passes away. A scene that sticks in your mind even days after watching it. Cuddle up in a blanket with your popcorn and enjoy this wonderful film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An adaptation that would make Alcott proud
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    fleurfairy
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Little Women remains one of my all-time favorite films. I first saw it as a child (after having loved the 1949 version) and this film completely opened up the world of the March sisters for me. Not to knock the previous two big screen adaptations, but they don't come close to conveying the happiness, heartbreak, and nostalgia that Little Women of 1994 does. What is so refreshing about this film is the truth and realism of the book. The actresses don't wear makeup, they don't speak in melodramatic tones; the men aren't playboys or Rhett Butlers. The writing and acting feels natural and true to Alcott's novel - which makes the sisters' victories and losses all the more authentic to the viewer. This is a wonderful movie to watch with your family to teach them values of love, friendship, and loyalty.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wonderful Classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    piedbeauty37
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I read "Little Women" many times growing up. It is a wonderful book with memorable characters and great writing. It has been made into a movie three times. The first time, Jo was played by Kathryn Hepburn, the second time she was played by June Allyson, and this third time, she is played by Wonona Ryder. This is the story of the four March sisters who are growing up in Concord, Massachusetts. Their father is away serving the North in the War of the States. The family has undergone the hardship of losing their former money and must now struggle to maintain their genteel lifestyle. Meg, Jo, Beth, and Amy become so real that they leap out at you from the book and on the screen. Their various mishaps and adventures are well done, touching and at times hilarious. Each sister has her distinctive personality, but it is Jo who is the real star. She is Louisa May Alcott's, the author, alter ego. Winona does a credible job playing her. A young Christian Bale plays Laurie, the boy next store. This is a beautiful movie which the entire family will enjoy especially at Christmas.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    heart-warming and drawing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (daviddaphneredding@att.net)
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie, which I watch every Christmas, is a wonderful movie in so many ways and for so many reasons. The aesthetic qualities are very appealing: the snow in Civil War-time Concord, Massachusetts was very beautiful, as is the grass in the spring time. As for the acting, the cast was superb. Susan Sarandon, who could act well the part of a rough southern girl, adapted herself well to this part of a proper New England lady who meets well the challenge of raising her four daughters (the "little women"). While you hated Christian Bale in "Shaft", he made a very positive impression in this movie as Teddy. Mary Wickes was convincingly crabby as Aunt March, and you felt for Claire Danes as the fragile Beth. Winona Ryder was excellent as the beautiful and high-spirited Jo. The story was a portmanteau: there were three different love affairs which were resolved at the end of the movie. The final scene was very touching. All in all, it was a superb production which was magnetic: again, I'm drawn to it every Christmas, though it is good entertainment for any time of the year. Definitely a favorite of mine.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Choppy and forced
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bluebwings
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As a movie I find it to be sub-par as compared to the 1949 version. I'm torn, I do not want to rate it purely as a comparison but having been so familiar with the second version I can't entirely help it. Being honest with myself, were this the first time I was watching "Little Women" and this was the first version to be introduced to it I'd have stopped watching or completely lost interest. It was choppy, the acting didn't carry through all too well and it just seemed to be trying too hard to stick to a novel. Because of this I suspect it may be closer in accuracy to the novel than the '49 version. For that reason I am now interested in reading the novel that much more. Ryder did not play as strong a Jo as I found June Allyson did. Claire Danes was not a very warm and loving Beth nor was she very memorable a character as the '49 carried. I now simply must see the '33 version to compare as it is considered even better than the '49 version.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    hmm...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Cameron-gagon
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well I don't know where to start with this movie. I don't like it. The problem with this movie is there are no little women. There is one played by the mediocre Kirsten Dunst. Next, who names their child Jo. Jo is a man's name. If you want a butch in the movie, just name her Jo. She crushes on like a 40 year old man anyway. That explains the marital situation in the early 1900's. I didn't understand the point of the movie. The title was named for Jo's book that she wrote? Apparently i need to read the book... NOT. I wouldn't dare read this book. This movie maybe a classic for past generations of women with heart warming fun about lovely girls' lives in the early 1900's and how they deal with relationships. That in my opinion is the WORST. STORY LINE. EVER. Even if I appear to be sexist. I laugh at this movie every time Christian Bale appears with such a gross Fu Man Chu. It's gross and no one wants to see that. I think i got a little gayer watching Christian(Laurie)prance around like a little boy off the Newzies.(hey oh!) I mean he took my breath away! And not in a good way. In conclusion, if you're a girl, enjoy watching.:) If you're a boy and like this movie, you have major issues and keep watching gay boys dance around...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Missed the Bar
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Stephan Quinland
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Many flaws and not enough true romance. First and biggest problem is the film spends well over half of entire 123 minutes in the Concord House Where nobody had grown, or changed or learned. Then suddenly before the end, main character Josephine left for New York and young Amy went to France to "paint"?. Much of the Concord house is old and full of dark wood and did reflect the reduced circumstance of the family, where upon their neighbors were healthy and worldly. How does that happened ? The oldest sister Meg is married off and basically had no lines for the rest of the film. That left high-spirited,tempestuous Jo to fill much of rest of the movie. Susan Sarandon, normally a high-powered actress, had nothing much to do except appeared matronly. The long-returned father was much older than everyone else and strangely had no war stories to tell, or any gifts for his daughters. Young suitor Christian Bale and Jo seemed a natural couple but inexplicably Jo rebuffed his proposal, only to meet up later with a generation-apart German professor in NYC. When Jo went to the boarding house, the book has her taking the duty of governess to the proprietress's children. There wasn't a moment's footage suggesting anything of the kind. Wynona Ryder did fine work here and some argues the 1940's version with Kate Hepburn as Jo was more spirited. It is easy to imagined that but Ryder is more attractive and therefore easier to accept, while the most memorable performance belongs really to Kirsten Dunst's young Amy, the little sis. She was perfectly puckish and adorable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My Favorite "Little Women".
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Melanie Campbell
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Little Women" has always been a favorite book of mine. I think I've seen every film adaptation at least once. I can't resist costume dramas. All that having been said, is it any surprise that I love this movie? I enjoyed this movie more than all the other adaptations. It has depth that the others lack. It does not play the novel out scene by scene or have the cast reciting big chunks of the book itself. You are drawn into the very lively world of young women as the grow up. You cheer for them, and cry with them. All the characters are very well played. Here, the biggest, and best surprise is how fully realized male characters are. Laurie gets his due as a fifth lead, and John Brook steps out of the background to become someone the audience really likes. This film works as well as a film as it does as a story. Everything looks beautiful, and the music is great.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Where is the love?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    melsishunney
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let me just say that i have never read the book nor seen another adaptation, so this is my first "Little Women" experience... I am a huge fan of period dramas and usually figure that they are going to be soppy and romantic and usually i am correct. Usually. I thought the acting in this movie was great, it was just some of the plot that made this film impossible to enjoy. I am sure in the book things flow a lot nicer than they do in this film.. Basically i thought that Laurie and Jo were meant to end up together, and for some reason when he proposes she says no! She says they would fight too much but they didn't fight at all in the movie.. I couldn't understand when they seemed to have such good chemistry. I've come to an understanding that in the book she considers him more as a brother but i only found this out AFTER watching the film and getting mad at her rejection of him. When Jo's love interest is introduced all I could do was shake my head and say "no no no no" There seemed to be no chemistry there compared to what Jo and Laurie had previously.So when they kiss at the end, It all feels wrong. Then finally, when Laurie sees the older Amy and suddenly likes her? how long has actually past since Jo's rejection of him? To me it seemed as though he was on the rebound. Their marriage wasn't romantic at all.. I just didn't feel the romance in this film they way other period films show it. It was disappointing. The rest of the story was fine.But if you're looking for romance watch something like Wives and Daughters or North and South (Gaskell) or something Austen. They are all better than this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Historical girlie fare
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Neil Welch
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I suspect that the average Brit isn't half as exposed to Little Women as the average Yank. It has existed on the outside edge of my awareness since I was a kid, and I have caught odd tasters of various versions over the year without ever encountering the full works. So this 1994 movie version is the first version I have ever experienced all the way through, and I am considering it on a stand alone basis. This is an historical piece, telling of four sisters growing up in fairly cushioned circumstances in Concord Massachusetts. Father is away in the Civil War and money is tight. Each of the sisters is strongly drawn, but the story belongs to Jo, strong-willed, independent, and rather progressive (and, I suspect, also author Louisa M Alcott's alter ego). It is also rather soapy, much of what happens being fairly ordinary - money problems, boyfriend problems, births, deaths, marriages and so on. It's all fairly comforting and mildly entertaining. It comes alive when it hits moments of high emotion, and also when it follows Jo into an adult life in which she chooses to quietly challenge convention. She is also the sister who has the least obvious love life, falling in love (though neither of them are minded to face it) with German Professor Baer. This film is beautiful to look at and presents attractive performances from all the principals. The story is, frankly, a bit drippy for your average ageing British bloke, but it passes the time reasonably well. I think women will enjoy this a lot: I enjoyed it well enough.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Lovely Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thrwmbsbgkdoepmcjrmrdw
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love rewatching things after not seeing them in a long time and just falling in love with it all over again. And that's what happened here with Little Women. I was a young girl myself when it came out in theaters and I enjoyed it then, though honestly I don't recall if I had ever read the book before then. I don't have any sisters so I don't know the true relationship between sisters but I imagine it's a lot like brothers and I have three of them so I could relate in many ways to the relationships between the four of them. I think that Jo and Laurie would have made a great couple, but Jo was right. Laurie needed someone more like Amy than herself. Jo and Laurie were too much alike. The combination of Laurie and Amy matched together similar to Jo and Fredrick.Amy was calm and Laurie outgoing and Fredrick was calm and Jo outgoing. I can't think of anyone I know who has seen this movie and not cried when Beth passes away. A scene that sticks in your mind even days after watching it. Cuddle up in a blanket with your popcorn and enjoy this wonderful film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An adaptation that would make Alcott proud
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    fleurfairy
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Little Women remains one of my all-time favorite films. I first saw it as a child (after having loved the 1949 version) and this film completely opened up the world of the March sisters for me. Not to knock the previous two big screen adaptations, but they don't come close to conveying the happiness, heartbreak, and nostalgia that Little Women of 1994 does. What is so refreshing about this film is the truth and realism of the book. The actresses don't wear makeup, they don't speak in melodramatic tones; the men aren't playboys or Rhett Butlers. The writing and acting feels natural and true to Alcott's novel - which makes the sisters' victories and losses all the more authentic to the viewer. This is a wonderful movie to watch with your family to teach them values of love, friendship, and loyalty.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wonderful Classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    piedbeauty37
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I read "Little Women" many times growing up. It is a wonderful book with memorable characters and great writing. It has been made into a movie three times. The first time, Jo was played by Kathryn Hepburn, the second time she was played by June Allyson, and this third time, she is played by Wonona Ryder. This is the story of the four March sisters who are growing up in Concord, Massachusetts. Their father is away serving the North in the War of the States. The family has undergone the hardship of losing their former money and must now struggle to maintain their genteel lifestyle. Meg, Jo, Beth, and Amy become so real that they leap out at you from the book and on the screen. Their various mishaps and adventures are well done, touching and at times hilarious. Each sister has her distinctive personality, but it is Jo who is the real star. She is Louisa May Alcott's, the author, alter ego. Winona does a credible job playing her. A young Christian Bale plays Laurie, the boy next store. This is a beautiful movie which the entire family will enjoy especially at Christmas.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    heart-warming and drawing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (daviddaphneredding@att.net)
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie, which I watch every Christmas, is a wonderful movie in so many ways and for so many reasons. The aesthetic qualities are very appealing: the snow in Civil War-time Concord, Massachusetts was very beautiful, as is the grass in the spring time. As for the acting, the cast was superb. Susan Sarandon, who could act well the part of a rough southern girl, adapted herself well to this part of a proper New England lady who meets well the challenge of raising her four daughters (the "little women"). While you hated Christian Bale in "Shaft", he made a very positive impression in this movie as Teddy. Mary Wickes was convincingly crabby as Aunt March, and you felt for Claire Danes as the fragile Beth. Winona Ryder was excellent as the beautiful and high-spirited Jo. The story was a portmanteau: there were three different love affairs which were resolved at the end of the movie. The final scene was very touching. All in all, it was a superb production which was magnetic: again, I'm drawn to it every Christmas, though it is good entertainment for any time of the year. Definitely a favorite of mine.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Choppy and forced
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bluebwings
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As a movie I find it to be sub-par as compared to the 1949 version. I'm torn, I do not want to rate it purely as a comparison but having been so familiar with the second version I can't entirely help it. Being honest with myself, were this the first time I was watching "Little Women" and this was the first version to be introduced to it I'd have stopped watching or completely lost interest. It was choppy, the acting didn't carry through all too well and it just seemed to be trying too hard to stick to a novel. Because of this I suspect it may be closer in accuracy to the novel than the '49 version. For that reason I am now interested in reading the novel that much more. Ryder did not play as strong a Jo as I found June Allyson did. Claire Danes was not a very warm and loving Beth nor was she very memorable a character as the '49 carried. I now simply must see the '33 version to compare as it is considered even better than the '49 version.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    hmm...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Cameron-gagon
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well I don't know where to start with this movie. I don't like it. The problem with this movie is there are no little women. There is one played by the mediocre Kirsten Dunst. Next, who names their child Jo. Jo is a man's name. If you want a butch in the movie, just name her Jo. She crushes on like a 40 year old man anyway. That explains the marital situation in the early 1900's. I didn't understand the point of the movie. The title was named for Jo's book that she wrote? Apparently i need to read the book... NOT. I wouldn't dare read this book. This movie maybe a classic for past generations of women with heart warming fun about lovely girls' lives in the early 1900's and how they deal with relationships. That in my opinion is the WORST. STORY LINE. EVER. Even if I appear to be sexist. I laugh at this movie every time Christian Bale appears with such a gross Fu Man Chu. It's gross and no one wants to see that. I think i got a little gayer watching Christian(Laurie)prance around like a little boy off the Newzies.(hey oh!) I mean he took my breath away! And not in a good way. In conclusion, if you're a girl, enjoy watching.:) If you're a boy and like this movie, you have major issues and keep watching gay boys dance around...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Missed the Bar
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Stephan Quinland
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Many flaws and not enough true romance. First and biggest problem is the film spends well over half of entire 123 minutes in the Concord House Where nobody had grown, or changed or learned. Then suddenly before the end, main character Josephine left for New York and young Amy went to France to "paint"?. Much of the Concord house is old and full of dark wood and did reflect the reduced circumstance of the family, where upon their neighbors were healthy and worldly. How does that happened ? The oldest sister Meg is married off and basically had no lines for the rest of the film. That left high-spirited,tempestuous Jo to fill much of rest of the movie. Susan Sarandon, normally a high-powered actress, had nothing much to do except appeared matronly. The long-returned father was much older than everyone else and strangely had no war stories to tell, or any gifts for his daughters. Young suitor Christian Bale and Jo seemed a natural couple but inexplicably Jo rebuffed his proposal, only to meet up later with a generation-apart German professor in NYC. When Jo went to the boarding house, the book has her taking the duty of governess to the proprietress's children. There wasn't a moment's footage suggesting anything of the kind. Wynona Ryder did fine work here and some argues the 1940's version with Kate Hepburn as Jo was more spirited. It is easy to imagined that but Ryder is more attractive and therefore easier to accept, while the most memorable performance belongs really to Kirsten Dunst's young Amy, the little sis. She was perfectly puckish and adorable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My Favorite "Little Women".
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Melanie Campbell
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Little Women" has always been a favorite book of mine. I think I've seen every film adaptation at least once. I can't resist costume dramas. All that having been said, is it any surprise that I love this movie? I enjoyed this movie more than all the other adaptations. It has depth that the others lack. It does not play the novel out scene by scene or have the cast reciting big chunks of the book itself. You are drawn into the very lively world of young women as the grow up. You cheer for them, and cry with them. All the characters are very well played. Here, the biggest, and best surprise is how fully realized male characters are. Laurie gets his due as a fifth lead, and John Brook steps out of the background to become someone the audience really likes. This film works as well as a film as it does as a story. Everything looks beautiful, and the music is great.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Where is the love?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    melsishunney
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let me just say that i have never read the book nor seen another adaptation, so this is my first "Little Women" experience... I am a huge fan of period dramas and usually figure that they are going to be soppy and romantic and usually i am correct. Usually. I thought the acting in this movie was great, it was just some of the plot that made this film impossible to enjoy. I am sure in the book things flow a lot nicer than they do in this film.. Basically i thought that Laurie and Jo were meant to end up together, and for some reason when he proposes she says no! She says they would fight too much but they didn't fight at all in the movie.. I couldn't understand when they seemed to have such good chemistry. I've come to an understanding that in the book she considers him more as a brother but i only found this out AFTER watching the film and getting mad at her rejection of him. When Jo's love interest is introduced all I could do was shake my head and say "no no no no" There seemed to be no chemistry there compared to what Jo and Laurie had previously.So when they kiss at the end, It all feels wrong. Then finally, when Laurie sees the older Amy and suddenly likes her? how long has actually past since Jo's rejection of him? To me it seemed as though he was on the rebound. Their marriage wasn't romantic at all.. I just didn't feel the romance in this film they way other period films show it. It was disappointing. The rest of the story was fine.But if you're looking for romance watch something like Wives and Daughters or North and South (Gaskell) or something Austen. They are all better than this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Historical girlie fare
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Neil Welch
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I suspect that the average Brit isn't half as exposed to Little Women as the average Yank. It has existed on the outside edge of my awareness since I was a kid, and I have caught odd tasters of various versions over the year without ever encountering the full works. So this 1994 movie version is the first version I have ever experienced all the way through, and I am considering it on a stand alone basis. This is an historical piece, telling of four sisters growing up in fairly cushioned circumstances in Concord Massachusetts. Father is away in the Civil War and money is tight. Each of the sisters is strongly drawn, but the story belongs to Jo, strong-willed, independent, and rather progressive (and, I suspect, also author Louisa M Alcott's alter ego). It is also rather soapy, much of what happens being fairly ordinary - money problems, boyfriend problems, births, deaths, marriages and so on. It's all fairly comforting and mildly entertaining. It comes alive when it hits moments of high emotion, and also when it follows Jo into an adult life in which she chooses to quietly challenge convention. She is also the sister who has the least obvious love life, falling in love (though neither of them are minded to face it) with German Professor Baer. This film is beautiful to look at and presents attractive performances from all the principals. The story is, frankly, a bit drippy for your average ageing British bloke, but it passes the time reasonably well. I think women will enjoy this a lot: I enjoyed it well enough.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Lovely Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thrwmbsbgkdoepmcjrmrdw
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love rewatching things after not seeing them in a long time and just falling in love with it all over again. And that's what happened here with Little Women. I was a young girl myself when it came out in theaters and I enjoyed it then, though honestly I don't recall if I had ever read the book before then. I don't have any sisters so I don't know the true relationship between sisters but I imagine it's a lot like brothers and I have three of them so I could relate in many ways to the relationships between the four of them. I think that Jo and Laurie would have made a great couple, but Jo was right. Laurie needed someone more like Amy than herself. Jo and Laurie were too much alike. The combination of Laurie and Amy matched together similar to Jo and Fredrick.Amy was calm and Laurie outgoing and Fredrick was calm and Jo outgoing. I can't think of anyone I know who has seen this movie and not cried when Beth passes away. A scene that sticks in your mind even days after watching it. Cuddle up in a blanket with your popcorn and enjoy this wonderful film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An adaptation that would make Alcott proud
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    fleurfairy
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Little Women remains one of my all-time favorite films. I first saw it as a child (after having loved the 1949 version) and this film completely opened up the world of the March sisters for me. Not to knock the previous two big screen adaptations, but they don't come close to conveying the happiness, heartbreak, and nostalgia that Little Women of 1994 does. What is so refreshing about this film is the truth and realism of the book. The actresses don't wear makeup, they don't speak in melodramatic tones; the men aren't playboys or Rhett Butlers. The writing and acting feels natural and true to Alcott's novel - which makes the sisters' victories and losses all the more authentic to the viewer. This is a wonderful movie to watch with your family to teach them values of love, friendship, and loyalty.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wonderful Classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    piedbeauty37
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I read "Little Women" many times growing up. It is a wonderful book with memorable characters and great writing. It has been made into a movie three times. The first time, Jo was played by Kathryn Hepburn, the second time she was played by June Allyson, and this third time, she is played by Wonona Ryder. This is the story of the four March sisters who are growing up in Concord, Massachusetts. Their father is away serving the North in the War of the States. The family has undergone the hardship of losing their former money and must now struggle to maintain their genteel lifestyle. Meg, Jo, Beth, and Amy become so real that they leap out at you from the book and on the screen. Their various mishaps and adventures are well done, touching and at times hilarious. Each sister has her distinctive personality, but it is Jo who is the real star. She is Louisa May Alcott's, the author, alter ego. Winona does a credible job playing her. A young Christian Bale plays Laurie, the boy next store. This is a beautiful movie which the entire family will enjoy especially at Christmas.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    heart-warming and drawing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (daviddaphneredding@att.net)
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie, which I watch every Christmas, is a wonderful movie in so many ways and for so many reasons. The aesthetic qualities are very appealing: the snow in Civil War-time Concord, Massachusetts was very beautiful, as is the grass in the spring time. As for the acting, the cast was superb. Susan Sarandon, who could act well the part of a rough southern girl, adapted herself well to this part of a proper New England lady who meets well the challenge of raising her four daughters (the "little women"). While you hated Christian Bale in "Shaft", he made a very positive impression in this movie as Teddy. Mary Wickes was convincingly crabby as Aunt March, and you felt for Claire Danes as the fragile Beth. Winona Ryder was excellent as the beautiful and high-spirited Jo. The story was a portmanteau: there were three different love affairs which were resolved at the end of the movie. The final scene was very touching. All in all, it was a superb production which was magnetic: again, I'm drawn to it every Christmas, though it is good entertainment for any time of the year. Definitely a favorite of mine.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Choppy and forced
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bluebwings
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As a movie I find it to be sub-par as compared to the 1949 version. I'm torn, I do not want to rate it purely as a comparison but having been so familiar with the second version I can't entirely help it. Being honest with myself, were this the first time I was watching "Little Women" and this was the first version to be introduced to it I'd have stopped watching or completely lost interest. It was choppy, the acting didn't carry through all too well and it just seemed to be trying too hard to stick to a novel. Because of this I suspect it may be closer in accuracy to the novel than the '49 version. For that reason I am now interested in reading the novel that much more. Ryder did not play as strong a Jo as I found June Allyson did. Claire Danes was not a very warm and loving Beth nor was she very memorable a character as the '49 carried. I now simply must see the '33 version to compare as it is considered even better than the '49 version.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    hmm...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Cameron-gagon
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Well I don't know where to start with this movie. I don't like it. The problem with this movie is there are no little women. There is one played by the mediocre Kirsten Dunst. Next, who names their child Jo. Jo is a man's name. If you want a butch in the movie, just name her Jo. She crushes on like a 40 year old man anyway. That explains the marital situation in the early 1900's. I didn't understand the point of the movie. The title was named for Jo's book that she wrote? Apparently i need to read the book... NOT. I wouldn't dare read this book. This movie maybe a classic for past generations of women with heart warming fun about lovely girls' lives in the early 1900's and how they deal with relationships. That in my opinion is the WORST. STORY LINE. EVER. Even if I appear to be sexist. I laugh at this movie every time Christian Bale appears with such a gross Fu Man Chu. It's gross and no one wants to see that. I think i got a little gayer watching Christian(Laurie)prance around like a little boy off the Newzies.(hey oh!) I mean he took my breath away! And not in a good way. In conclusion, if you're a girl, enjoy watching.:) If you're a boy and like this movie, you have major issues and keep watching gay boys dance around...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Missed the Bar
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Stephan Quinland
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Many flaws and not enough true romance. First and biggest problem is the film spends well over half of entire 123 minutes in the Concord House Where nobody had grown, or changed or learned. Then suddenly before the end, main character Josephine left for New York and young Amy went to France to "paint"?. Much of the Concord house is old and full of dark wood and did reflect the reduced circumstance of the family, where upon their neighbors were healthy and worldly. How does that happened ? The oldest sister Meg is married off and basically had no lines for the rest of the film. That left high-spirited,tempestuous Jo to fill much of rest of the movie. Susan Sarandon, normally a high-powered actress, had nothing much to do except appeared matronly. The long-returned father was much older than everyone else and strangely had no war stories to tell, or any gifts for his daughters. Young suitor Christian Bale and Jo seemed a natural couple but inexplicably Jo rebuffed his proposal, only to meet up later with a generation-apart German professor in NYC. When Jo went to the boarding house, the book has her taking the duty of governess to the proprietress's children. There wasn't a moment's footage suggesting anything of the kind. Wynona Ryder did fine work here and some argues the 1940's version with Kate Hepburn as Jo was more spirited. It is easy to imagined that but Ryder is more attractive and therefore easier to accept, while the most memorable performance belongs really to Kirsten Dunst's young Amy, the little sis. She was perfectly puckish and adorable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    My Favorite "Little Women".
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Melanie Campbell
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/11/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Little Women" has always been a favorite book of mine. I think I've seen every film adaptation at least once. I can't resist costume dramas. All that having been said, is it any surprise that I love this movie? I enjoyed this movie more than all the other adaptations. It has depth that the others lack. It does not play the novel out scene by scene or have the cast reciting big chunks of the book itself. You are drawn into the very lively world of young women as the grow up. You cheer for them, and cry with them. All the characters are very well played. Here, the biggest, and best surprise is how fully realized male characters are. Laurie gets his due as a fifth lead, and John Brook steps out of the background to become someone the audience really likes. This film works as well as a film as it does as a story. Everything looks beautiful, and the music is great.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Where is the love?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    melsishunney
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let me just say that i have never read the book nor seen another adaptation, so this is my first "Little Women" experience... I am a huge fan of period dramas and usually figure that they are going to be soppy and romantic and usually i am correct. Usually. I thought the acting in this movie was great, it was just some of the plot that made this film impossible to enjoy. I am sure in the book things flow a lot nicer than they do in this film.. Basically i thought that Laurie and Jo were meant to end up together, and for some reason when he proposes she says no! She says they would fight too much but they didn't fight at all in the movie.. I couldn't understand when they seemed to have such good chemistry. I've come to an understanding that in the book she considers him more as a brother but i only found this out AFTER watching the film and getting mad at her rejection of him. When Jo's love interest is introduced all I could do was shake my head and say "no no no no" There seemed to be no chemistry there compared to what Jo and Laurie had previously.So when they kiss at the end, It all feels wrong. Then finally, when Laurie sees the older Amy and suddenly likes her? how long has actually past since Jo's rejection of him? To me it seemed as though he was on the rebound. Their marriage wasn't romantic at all.. I just didn't feel the romance in this film they way other period films show it. It was disappointing. The rest of the story was fine.But if you're looking for romance watch something like Wives and Daughters or North and South (Gaskell) or something Austen. They are all better than this.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Historical girlie fare
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Neil Welch
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I suspect that the average Brit isn't half as exposed to Little Women as the average Yank. It has existed on the outside edge of my awareness since I was a kid, and I have caught odd tasters of various versions over the year without ever encountering the full works. So this 1994 movie version is the first version I have ever experienced all the way through, and I am considering it on a stand alone basis. This is an historical piece, telling of four sisters growing up in fairly cushioned circumstances in Concord Massachusetts. Father is away in the Civil War and money is tight. Each of the sisters is strongly drawn, but the story belongs to Jo, strong-willed, independent, and rather progressive (and, I suspect, also author Louisa M Alcott's alter ego). It is also rather soapy, much of what happens being fairly ordinary - money problems, boyfriend problems, births, deaths, marriages and so on. It's all fairly comforting and mildly entertaining. It comes alive when it hits moments of high emotion, and also when it follows Jo into an adult life in which she chooses to quietly challenge convention. She is also the sister who has the least obvious love life, falling in love (though neither of them are minded to face it) with German Professor Baer. This film is beautiful to look at and presents attractive performances from all the principals. The story is, frankly, a bit drippy for your average ageing British bloke, but it passes the time reasonably well. I think women will enjoy this a lot: I enjoyed it well enough.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Lovely Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thrwmbsbgkdoepmcjrmrdw
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/4/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love rewatching things after not seeing them in a long time and just falling in love with it all over again. And that's what happened here with Little Women. I was a young girl myself when it came out in theaters and I enjoyed it then, though honestly I don't recall if I had ever read the book before then. I don't have any sisters so I don't know the true relationship between sisters but I imagine it's a lot like brothers and I have three of them so I could relate in many ways to the relationships between the four of them. I think that Jo and Laurie would have made a great couple, but Jo was right. Laurie needed someone more like Amy than herself. Jo and Laurie were too much alike. The combination of Laurie and Amy matched together similar to Jo and Fredrick.Amy was calm and Laurie outgoing and Fredrick was calm and Jo outgoing. I can't think of anyone I know who has seen this movie and not cried when Beth passes away. A scene that sticks in your mind even days after watching it. Cuddle up in a blanket with your popcorn and enjoy this wonderful film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
