<filme>
 <id>
  7
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0114746
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1995
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Os 12 Macacos
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  8.1
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  In a future world devastated by disease, a convict is sent back in time to gather information about the man-made virus that wiped out most of the human population on the planet.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  An unknown and lethal virus has wiped out five billion people in 1996. Only 1% of the population has survived by the year 2035, and is forced to live underground. A convict (James Cole) reluctantly volunteers to be sent back in time to 1996 to gather information about the origin of the epidemic (who he's told was spread by a mysterious "Army of the Twelve Monkeys") and locate the virus before it mutates so that scientists can study it. Unfortunately Cole is mistakenly sent to 1990, six years earlier than expected, and is arrested and locked up in a mental institution, where he meets Dr. Kathryn Railly, a psychiatrist, and Jeffrey Goines, the insane son of a famous scientist and virus expert.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Mystery
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Sci-Fi
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Thriller
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   virus
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   monkey
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   future
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   volunteer
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   animal
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Terry Gilliam
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Chris Marker
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   David Webb Peoples
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Bruce Willis
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Madeleine Stowe
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Brad Pitt
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gloomy atmosphere serves its purpose
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    soudkovahana
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You don't see very often movie that is as good as Twelve Monkeys. It's clever, it's unique, it doesn't have too much action but it's exciting and keeps your eyes wide awake for the whole time because you don't want to miss a second of this brilliant movie. This movie has one of the best performances from both stars, Pitt and Willis. When you try to act like a crazy person it's not actually that easy if you want it to look natural. Both actors played their parts with flair and made their characters just enough crazy to still believe them. The atmosphere of a gray, cold year of 1996 complete the story of a population that's gonna be destroyed perfectly. It's also interesting to see Terry Gilliam, who is mostly known for his rich imagination and wit, dealing with a movie, that in his very core is trying to be as dim as possible. Colors would only subvert the movie. The same goes for music which is so bland that you will not notice it most of the times. Nevertheless all this serves it's purpose because the movie, despite it's drowsy atmosphere or maybe because of it, is something that stays with you and makes it such a unique and unusual experience.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If You Think James Bond Is Escapism.....TRY THIS...!!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    werefox08
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Made in 1995, and Directed by the zany Terry Gilliam ...this a a superior sci. fi. flick. If you want escapism, and you want to rest your rational mind ...watch this 129 minute trip. The three main actors---Bruce Willis, Brad Pitt and Madeleine Stowe are great. The sets are astounding (without relying too much on C.G.I.) The movie purrs along at a good gallop ---so try not to miss a minute as the story goes back and forth in time...and the sub plots are deep. This was my first viewing and I will need to watch it again...(those pesky telephone calls !!!) I will be happy to have another look at this extremely well made film. I am sure it is one of those movies that one never forgets...because of its total originality ...Loved It....(You probably think it is 2013....are you sure ?)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bruce Willis goes on a mission to the past to seek a virus, and he meets Madeleine Stowe
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    msroz
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am quite taken by this very well done sci-fi movie in the time travel sub-genre. Sometimes Hollywood movies are dragged down by their female leads or else the kinds of characters that they are asked to portray. There is absolutely none of that here. Madeleine Stowe is a realistic woman and she brings the part to life, with just the right touches of compassion and doubt. Her emotional reaction to the difficult situation that Bruce Willis is in is surely one of the central features that hold this story together and make it rewarding. Willis is really good, as he has been in every movie I've ever seen him in, and that list is growing. He just gets right into his roles. The production design is more than enough to create both the future gizmos and the past that is under threat. The time travel anomaly of a person encountering himself when he goes back into the past is faced up to squarely by making it a key element of the story, and integrated by flashbacks. The director had "Twelve Monkeys" firmly under control. He had a very good script to work with and a capable cast. The result is a story that holds your attention, doesn't ever reveal too much at once, but enough to keep you in the ball game.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    MY REVIEW: The Time Travel Mystery
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sandeep Gupta
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Don't go by the title, it's not about animals. It's a pure science fiction based on the concept of time travel. The idea here is complex and even execution does not try to make it simpler for you. You need to provide your full attention to it in order to understand the sequence of events and correlate them to unsolve the mystery. The lead actors Bruce Willis, Madeleine Stowe play their part with perfection but it is Brad Pitt who steals the show with his portrayal of a maniac. The screenplay is water tight and background score is first-rate. There are lots of interesting conversations over understanding of human psyche. You would not like to miss it if time travel fantasies intrigue you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Army of the Twelve Monkeys
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    estebangonzalez10
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "I am mentally divergent, in that I am escaping certain unnamed realities that plague my life here. When I stop going there, I will be well. Are you also divergent, friend?" That is the question that the audience has to ask itself during this sci-fi mentally ill time traveling futuristic movie. Is the lead character mentally ill or is he really on a mission traveling through time in order to find a cure to a deadly virus that has wiped off nearly all the population and forced the few survivors to live underground? Director Terry Gilliam has created a memorable sci-fi flick that like all time traveling films has a few in-congruencies but still manages to hold the audience's attention. Gilliam is better known for his work in Monty Python, but he's also directed different types of genre films like The Fisher King (dramedy), Fear and Loathing in Las Vegas (adventure), and The Imaginarium of Doctor Parnassus (Fantasy). He has a pretty respectable filmography as a director, although I still think he did his best work in the 90's. This film has a strong screenplay, but it will be remembered for the strong performances from Bruce Willis and Brad Pitt. Twelve Monkeys is a dark futuristic film similar in some ways to Blade Runner although it kind of diverges all over the place with so many ideas. This is an inventive film but I don't know how many ideas were taken from Chris Marker's 1962 short film, La jetee, which inspired this movie. The screenplay was adapted by David Webb Peoples (Blade Runner, Unforgiven) and Janet Peoples. His influence from Blade Runner seems to be mixed in the screenplay here as well. This is a very fun sci-fi film although full of really weird moments. The film takes place sometime in the future after a deadly virus wiped out over 5 billion people and the few survivors were forced to live underground. James Cole (Bruce Willis) is a convict who is sent by a group of scientists to the past in order to gather information about the virus. The scientists want to study the virus so they can create a cure and live in the outside world once again. Cole is mistakenly sent to 1990 instead of 1996 which was the year in which the virus began spreading, and he ends up in a mental hospital after attacking several police officers. At the mental hospital he is treated by Dr. Railly (Madeleine Stowe) and he also meets another patient named Jeffrey Goines (Brad Pitt) who happens to be the son of a famous scientist (Christopher Plummer). Cole at first begins to search desperately for the "Army of the Twelve Monkeys" because they are believed to be the group responsible for spreading the virus, but later he begins to question himself and believe that he might actually be insane himself. This is a puzzle that he will have to piece together with the help of Railly. This is the puzzle that Gilliam invites the audience to solve along the way and keeps us guessing as the plot unfolds before our eyes. I'm not a huge fan of futuristic films, but Gilliam's vision here is pretty hypnotic and poetic. Most of the film actually takes place in the past, but there are several elements introduced that keep us guessing what will happen next. There were a few stand out scenes like the one in which Cole and Railly are at a movie theater and begin commenting on how despite having seen the movie before the perception of it changes every time, similar to what is happening with Cole through his time traveling. Does his presence in the past change things in the future? Can he find the virus on time in order to save the people in the future? These are a few questions that the film raises. The more you think about things the more flaws you will find, but that doesn't take away anything from this sci-fi film. I really liked Brad Pitt's performance here for which he received an Academy nomination, although he lost to Kevin Spacey (The Usual Suspects). The film runs a bit long, but it never ceases to entertain. Rating: 7,1/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Is he mad or are we? - Director Terry Gilliam
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Thommie Wallin
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film continues an ongoing thread of discussion in film history, about the subjective nature of memories and how they effect the perception of reality. It wears its specific references on its sleeves (and rightfully so): in the opening credits it says inspired by "La Jet&egrave;e" (1962) and later on the main characters literally watches "Vertigo" (1958) in a movie theater. The scene in "Vertigo" where they count the rings on the redwood tree align these films closest touching points, and reveal the overall story structure because they all exist in each of the three films. This is one of the most relevant use of a reference in any film I can think of, where we who have a memory of all three films, replicate in our minds the effect felt by the main characters in all three films - especially this one. A brilliant trick which evoke the memory of "Vertigo" and "La Jet&egrave;e" in the viewers mind, and thereby plant a memory just like in the mind of the main characters of these films. A memory which reflects the use of memory in the film, a memory encompassing a whole life of memories, from a young kid until his death. A memory of this film where we know the start (because the scene takes place in the third act) and with the reference we know the ending, but we still don't know how we're getting there. This film cleverly exist in a vortex in between these other two films, drawing a references here and there into its core which create a new jumbling but cohesive meaning. The result is presented from a subjective point of view, where the explanation of why and how exist in the other films. The other two films explained more thoroughly the overall story, the bigger picture, while this is the experience of the subjective journey at the center of its swirling madness. I can go on and on about the references to Hitchcock and the history of the subject, but it wouldn't tell you anything about whether the film succeeds in its mission and also, I'm sure you can find a better analysis elsewhere on the internet. :) A film doesn't have to be a complete original to be great, even remakes can be better than the original films, it just have to be great within its own framework. A theme which this film wants to confuse and confront the viewer with is madness, and what it is in humans and societies. And I feel it fall short in this aspect of the story compared to that of the subject of memories. It compares the madness of the majority (e.g. the twelve monkey's army)and the individual (e.g. Dr. Peters), as well as who we lock up and don't, in a muddled way which for me is one of the things that drags the overall rating down by a margin. Why I don't necessary think this film reaches the same level of greatness as the other two films mentioned, could have something to do with that this film wouldn't exist if it wasn't for the other films. It's a very good film that stands on its own legs, but it still needs the support from the other films holding each of its hands to remain upright and it still doesn't stand as tall as the others. It gives the subject a fresh perspective but not a new one, and never really starts taking its first wobbling steps towards a life of its own in that territory.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    12 Monkeys-Can't Go Ape Over It *
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Films dealing with the mentally ill always produce controversy. Films such as 1948's "The Snake Pit," and the award winning "One Flew Over the Cuckoo's Nest" were such films since they dealt with real people facing a personal crisis in their lives which led them down the path of irrational behavior. This film fails to achieve that as it's more a science- fiction type film. In a supporting role, Brad Pitt stole the film and Madeleine Stowe, as the psychiatrist, goes through a rapidly downward trend in her own life after meeting up with convict Bruce Willis. The film failed because it just didn't face reality.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very good time-travel whodunit
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    IndustriousAngel
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As time-travel stories go, I liked that one very much. Captivating performances from Pitt and Willis, and I liked the overall intensity and the claustrophobic camera/light. Very good and ingenious production design as usual with Gilliam, but in 12 Monkeys he also managed to keep everything under perfect control - he's a bit of a hit-and-miss director in my opinion. The mystery part works well, the different scenes in different times all fitting together like cogs in a well-oiled gearbox. Highly recommended, even if the re watch-value is not that high (knowing about all the twists takes away some of the fun, still rewatchable for the great performances). What keeps this from 10/10 for me is the ultimately depressing story.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A 29 Million budget Masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    eliel77
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    And to think that some decades ago you could do a first class sci-fi with a budget of 29 millions dollars ? Seems crazy, considering that most top productions nowadays surpass the 100 millions dollars, many going beyond 200 million. Twelve Monkeys succeed most in a field that many others fail, there is a script that is on the verge of perfection and a story perfectly developed. We travel between future and paste, real and surreal, and everything is well balanced and makes sense. The conclusion makes this one of the best time travel movies ever made, but don't get me wrong, this is not one of those movies specifically about time travel. Every time I watch Twelve Monkeys I get a higher concept of it, and it has become a classic to me. 9,5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wonderful Movie and Probably Terry Gilliam's Best
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dschyli
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As I saw this movie the first time it was just amazing. The different settings and story lines and also the acting was very appreciate. In my opinion it was one of Bruce Willis' best performances, Brad Pitt was also good in his role, he proved that he can play more difficult roles. In Se7en which was published the same year he did also a very good performance but his role in that movie was not so sophisticated. Twelve Monkeys may be Terry Gilliam's best movie, among Brazil which has also this kind of "Terry Gilliam Fantasy". But in a nutshell it is very difficult to describe that movie without spoilers. But in common the plot is that James Cole (Bruce Willis) is sent back from the year 2035 into 1996 to stop a pandemic that will cause the death of millions of people in the next two years. But now I have to stop because now the spoiler alert is alarming. But nevertheless you have to pay attention in every part of that movie. The only point that makes the movie not a masterpiece is that the role and the acting of Madeleine Stowe in this movie is not very convincing or interesting. But yet every single character is important for the movie. So pay attention and you will experience a nearly perfect movie. Maybe Terry Gilliam's next movies can spread that "Terry Gilliam Fantasy" of Twelve Monkeys.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gloomy atmosphere serves its purpose
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    soudkovahana
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You don't see very often movie that is as good as Twelve Monkeys. It's clever, it's unique, it doesn't have too much action but it's exciting and keeps your eyes wide awake for the whole time because you don't want to miss a second of this brilliant movie. This movie has one of the best performances from both stars, Pitt and Willis. When you try to act like a crazy person it's not actually that easy if you want it to look natural. Both actors played their parts with flair and made their characters just enough crazy to still believe them. The atmosphere of a gray, cold year of 1996 complete the story of a population that's gonna be destroyed perfectly. It's also interesting to see Terry Gilliam, who is mostly known for his rich imagination and wit, dealing with a movie, that in his very core is trying to be as dim as possible. Colors would only subvert the movie. The same goes for music which is so bland that you will not notice it most of the times. Nevertheless all this serves it's purpose because the movie, despite it's drowsy atmosphere or maybe because of it, is something that stays with you and makes it such a unique and unusual experience.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If You Think James Bond Is Escapism.....TRY THIS...!!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    werefox08
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Made in 1995, and Directed by the zany Terry Gilliam ...this a a superior sci. fi. flick. If you want escapism, and you want to rest your rational mind ...watch this 129 minute trip. The three main actors---Bruce Willis, Brad Pitt and Madeleine Stowe are great. The sets are astounding (without relying too much on C.G.I.) The movie purrs along at a good gallop ---so try not to miss a minute as the story goes back and forth in time...and the sub plots are deep. This was my first viewing and I will need to watch it again...(those pesky telephone calls !!!) I will be happy to have another look at this extremely well made film. I am sure it is one of those movies that one never forgets...because of its total originality ...Loved It....(You probably think it is 2013....are you sure ?)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bruce Willis goes on a mission to the past to seek a virus, and he meets Madeleine Stowe
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    msroz
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am quite taken by this very well done sci-fi movie in the time travel sub-genre. Sometimes Hollywood movies are dragged down by their female leads or else the kinds of characters that they are asked to portray. There is absolutely none of that here. Madeleine Stowe is a realistic woman and she brings the part to life, with just the right touches of compassion and doubt. Her emotional reaction to the difficult situation that Bruce Willis is in is surely one of the central features that hold this story together and make it rewarding. Willis is really good, as he has been in every movie I've ever seen him in, and that list is growing. He just gets right into his roles. The production design is more than enough to create both the future gizmos and the past that is under threat. The time travel anomaly of a person encountering himself when he goes back into the past is faced up to squarely by making it a key element of the story, and integrated by flashbacks. The director had "Twelve Monkeys" firmly under control. He had a very good script to work with and a capable cast. The result is a story that holds your attention, doesn't ever reveal too much at once, but enough to keep you in the ball game.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    MY REVIEW: The Time Travel Mystery
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sandeep Gupta
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Don't go by the title, it's not about animals. It's a pure science fiction based on the concept of time travel. The idea here is complex and even execution does not try to make it simpler for you. You need to provide your full attention to it in order to understand the sequence of events and correlate them to unsolve the mystery. The lead actors Bruce Willis, Madeleine Stowe play their part with perfection but it is Brad Pitt who steals the show with his portrayal of a maniac. The screenplay is water tight and background score is first-rate. There are lots of interesting conversations over understanding of human psyche. You would not like to miss it if time travel fantasies intrigue you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Army of the Twelve Monkeys
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    estebangonzalez10
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "I am mentally divergent, in that I am escaping certain unnamed realities that plague my life here. When I stop going there, I will be well. Are you also divergent, friend?" That is the question that the audience has to ask itself during this sci-fi mentally ill time traveling futuristic movie. Is the lead character mentally ill or is he really on a mission traveling through time in order to find a cure to a deadly virus that has wiped off nearly all the population and forced the few survivors to live underground? Director Terry Gilliam has created a memorable sci-fi flick that like all time traveling films has a few in-congruencies but still manages to hold the audience's attention. Gilliam is better known for his work in Monty Python, but he's also directed different types of genre films like The Fisher King (dramedy), Fear and Loathing in Las Vegas (adventure), and The Imaginarium of Doctor Parnassus (Fantasy). He has a pretty respectable filmography as a director, although I still think he did his best work in the 90's. This film has a strong screenplay, but it will be remembered for the strong performances from Bruce Willis and Brad Pitt. Twelve Monkeys is a dark futuristic film similar in some ways to Blade Runner although it kind of diverges all over the place with so many ideas. This is an inventive film but I don't know how many ideas were taken from Chris Marker's 1962 short film, La jetee, which inspired this movie. The screenplay was adapted by David Webb Peoples (Blade Runner, Unforgiven) and Janet Peoples. His influence from Blade Runner seems to be mixed in the screenplay here as well. This is a very fun sci-fi film although full of really weird moments. The film takes place sometime in the future after a deadly virus wiped out over 5 billion people and the few survivors were forced to live underground. James Cole (Bruce Willis) is a convict who is sent by a group of scientists to the past in order to gather information about the virus. The scientists want to study the virus so they can create a cure and live in the outside world once again. Cole is mistakenly sent to 1990 instead of 1996 which was the year in which the virus began spreading, and he ends up in a mental hospital after attacking several police officers. At the mental hospital he is treated by Dr. Railly (Madeleine Stowe) and he also meets another patient named Jeffrey Goines (Brad Pitt) who happens to be the son of a famous scientist (Christopher Plummer). Cole at first begins to search desperately for the "Army of the Twelve Monkeys" because they are believed to be the group responsible for spreading the virus, but later he begins to question himself and believe that he might actually be insane himself. This is a puzzle that he will have to piece together with the help of Railly. This is the puzzle that Gilliam invites the audience to solve along the way and keeps us guessing as the plot unfolds before our eyes. I'm not a huge fan of futuristic films, but Gilliam's vision here is pretty hypnotic and poetic. Most of the film actually takes place in the past, but there are several elements introduced that keep us guessing what will happen next. There were a few stand out scenes like the one in which Cole and Railly are at a movie theater and begin commenting on how despite having seen the movie before the perception of it changes every time, similar to what is happening with Cole through his time traveling. Does his presence in the past change things in the future? Can he find the virus on time in order to save the people in the future? These are a few questions that the film raises. The more you think about things the more flaws you will find, but that doesn't take away anything from this sci-fi film. I really liked Brad Pitt's performance here for which he received an Academy nomination, although he lost to Kevin Spacey (The Usual Suspects). The film runs a bit long, but it never ceases to entertain. Rating: 7,1/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Is he mad or are we? - Director Terry Gilliam
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Thommie Wallin
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film continues an ongoing thread of discussion in film history, about the subjective nature of memories and how they effect the perception of reality. It wears its specific references on its sleeves (and rightfully so): in the opening credits it says inspired by "La Jet&egrave;e" (1962) and later on the main characters literally watches "Vertigo" (1958) in a movie theater. The scene in "Vertigo" where they count the rings on the redwood tree align these films closest touching points, and reveal the overall story structure because they all exist in each of the three films. This is one of the most relevant use of a reference in any film I can think of, where we who have a memory of all three films, replicate in our minds the effect felt by the main characters in all three films - especially this one. A brilliant trick which evoke the memory of "Vertigo" and "La Jet&egrave;e" in the viewers mind, and thereby plant a memory just like in the mind of the main characters of these films. A memory which reflects the use of memory in the film, a memory encompassing a whole life of memories, from a young kid until his death. A memory of this film where we know the start (because the scene takes place in the third act) and with the reference we know the ending, but we still don't know how we're getting there. This film cleverly exist in a vortex in between these other two films, drawing a references here and there into its core which create a new jumbling but cohesive meaning. The result is presented from a subjective point of view, where the explanation of why and how exist in the other films. The other two films explained more thoroughly the overall story, the bigger picture, while this is the experience of the subjective journey at the center of its swirling madness. I can go on and on about the references to Hitchcock and the history of the subject, but it wouldn't tell you anything about whether the film succeeds in its mission and also, I'm sure you can find a better analysis elsewhere on the internet. :) A film doesn't have to be a complete original to be great, even remakes can be better than the original films, it just have to be great within its own framework. A theme which this film wants to confuse and confront the viewer with is madness, and what it is in humans and societies. And I feel it fall short in this aspect of the story compared to that of the subject of memories. It compares the madness of the majority (e.g. the twelve monkey's army)and the individual (e.g. Dr. Peters), as well as who we lock up and don't, in a muddled way which for me is one of the things that drags the overall rating down by a margin. Why I don't necessary think this film reaches the same level of greatness as the other two films mentioned, could have something to do with that this film wouldn't exist if it wasn't for the other films. It's a very good film that stands on its own legs, but it still needs the support from the other films holding each of its hands to remain upright and it still doesn't stand as tall as the others. It gives the subject a fresh perspective but not a new one, and never really starts taking its first wobbling steps towards a life of its own in that territory.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    12 Monkeys-Can't Go Ape Over It *
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Films dealing with the mentally ill always produce controversy. Films such as 1948's "The Snake Pit," and the award winning "One Flew Over the Cuckoo's Nest" were such films since they dealt with real people facing a personal crisis in their lives which led them down the path of irrational behavior. This film fails to achieve that as it's more a science- fiction type film. In a supporting role, Brad Pitt stole the film and Madeleine Stowe, as the psychiatrist, goes through a rapidly downward trend in her own life after meeting up with convict Bruce Willis. The film failed because it just didn't face reality.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very good time-travel whodunit
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    IndustriousAngel
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As time-travel stories go, I liked that one very much. Captivating performances from Pitt and Willis, and I liked the overall intensity and the claustrophobic camera/light. Very good and ingenious production design as usual with Gilliam, but in 12 Monkeys he also managed to keep everything under perfect control - he's a bit of a hit-and-miss director in my opinion. The mystery part works well, the different scenes in different times all fitting together like cogs in a well-oiled gearbox. Highly recommended, even if the re watch-value is not that high (knowing about all the twists takes away some of the fun, still rewatchable for the great performances). What keeps this from 10/10 for me is the ultimately depressing story.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A 29 Million budget Masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    eliel77
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    And to think that some decades ago you could do a first class sci-fi with a budget of 29 millions dollars ? Seems crazy, considering that most top productions nowadays surpass the 100 millions dollars, many going beyond 200 million. Twelve Monkeys succeed most in a field that many others fail, there is a script that is on the verge of perfection and a story perfectly developed. We travel between future and paste, real and surreal, and everything is well balanced and makes sense. The conclusion makes this one of the best time travel movies ever made, but don't get me wrong, this is not one of those movies specifically about time travel. Every time I watch Twelve Monkeys I get a higher concept of it, and it has become a classic to me. 9,5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wonderful Movie and Probably Terry Gilliam's Best
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dschyli
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As I saw this movie the first time it was just amazing. The different settings and story lines and also the acting was very appreciate. In my opinion it was one of Bruce Willis' best performances, Brad Pitt was also good in his role, he proved that he can play more difficult roles. In Se7en which was published the same year he did also a very good performance but his role in that movie was not so sophisticated. Twelve Monkeys may be Terry Gilliam's best movie, among Brazil which has also this kind of "Terry Gilliam Fantasy". But in a nutshell it is very difficult to describe that movie without spoilers. But in common the plot is that James Cole (Bruce Willis) is sent back from the year 2035 into 1996 to stop a pandemic that will cause the death of millions of people in the next two years. But now I have to stop because now the spoiler alert is alarming. But nevertheless you have to pay attention in every part of that movie. The only point that makes the movie not a masterpiece is that the role and the acting of Madeleine Stowe in this movie is not very convincing or interesting. But yet every single character is important for the movie. So pay attention and you will experience a nearly perfect movie. Maybe Terry Gilliam's next movies can spread that "Terry Gilliam Fantasy" of Twelve Monkeys.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gloomy atmosphere serves its purpose
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    soudkovahana
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You don't see very often movie that is as good as Twelve Monkeys. It's clever, it's unique, it doesn't have too much action but it's exciting and keeps your eyes wide awake for the whole time because you don't want to miss a second of this brilliant movie. This movie has one of the best performances from both stars, Pitt and Willis. When you try to act like a crazy person it's not actually that easy if you want it to look natural. Both actors played their parts with flair and made their characters just enough crazy to still believe them. The atmosphere of a gray, cold year of 1996 complete the story of a population that's gonna be destroyed perfectly. It's also interesting to see Terry Gilliam, who is mostly known for his rich imagination and wit, dealing with a movie, that in his very core is trying to be as dim as possible. Colors would only subvert the movie. The same goes for music which is so bland that you will not notice it most of the times. Nevertheless all this serves it's purpose because the movie, despite it's drowsy atmosphere or maybe because of it, is something that stays with you and makes it such a unique and unusual experience.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If You Think James Bond Is Escapism.....TRY THIS...!!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    werefox08
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Made in 1995, and Directed by the zany Terry Gilliam ...this a a superior sci. fi. flick. If you want escapism, and you want to rest your rational mind ...watch this 129 minute trip. The three main actors---Bruce Willis, Brad Pitt and Madeleine Stowe are great. The sets are astounding (without relying too much on C.G.I.) The movie purrs along at a good gallop ---so try not to miss a minute as the story goes back and forth in time...and the sub plots are deep. This was my first viewing and I will need to watch it again...(those pesky telephone calls !!!) I will be happy to have another look at this extremely well made film. I am sure it is one of those movies that one never forgets...because of its total originality ...Loved It....(You probably think it is 2013....are you sure ?)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bruce Willis goes on a mission to the past to seek a virus, and he meets Madeleine Stowe
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    msroz
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am quite taken by this very well done sci-fi movie in the time travel sub-genre. Sometimes Hollywood movies are dragged down by their female leads or else the kinds of characters that they are asked to portray. There is absolutely none of that here. Madeleine Stowe is a realistic woman and she brings the part to life, with just the right touches of compassion and doubt. Her emotional reaction to the difficult situation that Bruce Willis is in is surely one of the central features that hold this story together and make it rewarding. Willis is really good, as he has been in every movie I've ever seen him in, and that list is growing. He just gets right into his roles. The production design is more than enough to create both the future gizmos and the past that is under threat. The time travel anomaly of a person encountering himself when he goes back into the past is faced up to squarely by making it a key element of the story, and integrated by flashbacks. The director had "Twelve Monkeys" firmly under control. He had a very good script to work with and a capable cast. The result is a story that holds your attention, doesn't ever reveal too much at once, but enough to keep you in the ball game.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    MY REVIEW: The Time Travel Mystery
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sandeep Gupta
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Don't go by the title, it's not about animals. It's a pure science fiction based on the concept of time travel. The idea here is complex and even execution does not try to make it simpler for you. You need to provide your full attention to it in order to understand the sequence of events and correlate them to unsolve the mystery. The lead actors Bruce Willis, Madeleine Stowe play their part with perfection but it is Brad Pitt who steals the show with his portrayal of a maniac. The screenplay is water tight and background score is first-rate. There are lots of interesting conversations over understanding of human psyche. You would not like to miss it if time travel fantasies intrigue you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Army of the Twelve Monkeys
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    estebangonzalez10
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "I am mentally divergent, in that I am escaping certain unnamed realities that plague my life here. When I stop going there, I will be well. Are you also divergent, friend?" That is the question that the audience has to ask itself during this sci-fi mentally ill time traveling futuristic movie. Is the lead character mentally ill or is he really on a mission traveling through time in order to find a cure to a deadly virus that has wiped off nearly all the population and forced the few survivors to live underground? Director Terry Gilliam has created a memorable sci-fi flick that like all time traveling films has a few in-congruencies but still manages to hold the audience's attention. Gilliam is better known for his work in Monty Python, but he's also directed different types of genre films like The Fisher King (dramedy), Fear and Loathing in Las Vegas (adventure), and The Imaginarium of Doctor Parnassus (Fantasy). He has a pretty respectable filmography as a director, although I still think he did his best work in the 90's. This film has a strong screenplay, but it will be remembered for the strong performances from Bruce Willis and Brad Pitt. Twelve Monkeys is a dark futuristic film similar in some ways to Blade Runner although it kind of diverges all over the place with so many ideas. This is an inventive film but I don't know how many ideas were taken from Chris Marker's 1962 short film, La jetee, which inspired this movie. The screenplay was adapted by David Webb Peoples (Blade Runner, Unforgiven) and Janet Peoples. His influence from Blade Runner seems to be mixed in the screenplay here as well. This is a very fun sci-fi film although full of really weird moments. The film takes place sometime in the future after a deadly virus wiped out over 5 billion people and the few survivors were forced to live underground. James Cole (Bruce Willis) is a convict who is sent by a group of scientists to the past in order to gather information about the virus. The scientists want to study the virus so they can create a cure and live in the outside world once again. Cole is mistakenly sent to 1990 instead of 1996 which was the year in which the virus began spreading, and he ends up in a mental hospital after attacking several police officers. At the mental hospital he is treated by Dr. Railly (Madeleine Stowe) and he also meets another patient named Jeffrey Goines (Brad Pitt) who happens to be the son of a famous scientist (Christopher Plummer). Cole at first begins to search desperately for the "Army of the Twelve Monkeys" because they are believed to be the group responsible for spreading the virus, but later he begins to question himself and believe that he might actually be insane himself. This is a puzzle that he will have to piece together with the help of Railly. This is the puzzle that Gilliam invites the audience to solve along the way and keeps us guessing as the plot unfolds before our eyes. I'm not a huge fan of futuristic films, but Gilliam's vision here is pretty hypnotic and poetic. Most of the film actually takes place in the past, but there are several elements introduced that keep us guessing what will happen next. There were a few stand out scenes like the one in which Cole and Railly are at a movie theater and begin commenting on how despite having seen the movie before the perception of it changes every time, similar to what is happening with Cole through his time traveling. Does his presence in the past change things in the future? Can he find the virus on time in order to save the people in the future? These are a few questions that the film raises. The more you think about things the more flaws you will find, but that doesn't take away anything from this sci-fi film. I really liked Brad Pitt's performance here for which he received an Academy nomination, although he lost to Kevin Spacey (The Usual Suspects). The film runs a bit long, but it never ceases to entertain. Rating: 7,1/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Is he mad or are we? - Director Terry Gilliam
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Thommie Wallin
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film continues an ongoing thread of discussion in film history, about the subjective nature of memories and how they effect the perception of reality. It wears its specific references on its sleeves (and rightfully so): in the opening credits it says inspired by "La Jet&egrave;e" (1962) and later on the main characters literally watches "Vertigo" (1958) in a movie theater. The scene in "Vertigo" where they count the rings on the redwood tree align these films closest touching points, and reveal the overall story structure because they all exist in each of the three films. This is one of the most relevant use of a reference in any film I can think of, where we who have a memory of all three films, replicate in our minds the effect felt by the main characters in all three films - especially this one. A brilliant trick which evoke the memory of "Vertigo" and "La Jet&egrave;e" in the viewers mind, and thereby plant a memory just like in the mind of the main characters of these films. A memory which reflects the use of memory in the film, a memory encompassing a whole life of memories, from a young kid until his death. A memory of this film where we know the start (because the scene takes place in the third act) and with the reference we know the ending, but we still don't know how we're getting there. This film cleverly exist in a vortex in between these other two films, drawing a references here and there into its core which create a new jumbling but cohesive meaning. The result is presented from a subjective point of view, where the explanation of why and how exist in the other films. The other two films explained more thoroughly the overall story, the bigger picture, while this is the experience of the subjective journey at the center of its swirling madness. I can go on and on about the references to Hitchcock and the history of the subject, but it wouldn't tell you anything about whether the film succeeds in its mission and also, I'm sure you can find a better analysis elsewhere on the internet. :) A film doesn't have to be a complete original to be great, even remakes can be better than the original films, it just have to be great within its own framework. A theme which this film wants to confuse and confront the viewer with is madness, and what it is in humans and societies. And I feel it fall short in this aspect of the story compared to that of the subject of memories. It compares the madness of the majority (e.g. the twelve monkey's army)and the individual (e.g. Dr. Peters), as well as who we lock up and don't, in a muddled way which for me is one of the things that drags the overall rating down by a margin. Why I don't necessary think this film reaches the same level of greatness as the other two films mentioned, could have something to do with that this film wouldn't exist if it wasn't for the other films. It's a very good film that stands on its own legs, but it still needs the support from the other films holding each of its hands to remain upright and it still doesn't stand as tall as the others. It gives the subject a fresh perspective but not a new one, and never really starts taking its first wobbling steps towards a life of its own in that territory.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    12 Monkeys-Can't Go Ape Over It *
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Films dealing with the mentally ill always produce controversy. Films such as 1948's "The Snake Pit," and the award winning "One Flew Over the Cuckoo's Nest" were such films since they dealt with real people facing a personal crisis in their lives which led them down the path of irrational behavior. This film fails to achieve that as it's more a science- fiction type film. In a supporting role, Brad Pitt stole the film and Madeleine Stowe, as the psychiatrist, goes through a rapidly downward trend in her own life after meeting up with convict Bruce Willis. The film failed because it just didn't face reality.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very good time-travel whodunit
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    IndustriousAngel
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As time-travel stories go, I liked that one very much. Captivating performances from Pitt and Willis, and I liked the overall intensity and the claustrophobic camera/light. Very good and ingenious production design as usual with Gilliam, but in 12 Monkeys he also managed to keep everything under perfect control - he's a bit of a hit-and-miss director in my opinion. The mystery part works well, the different scenes in different times all fitting together like cogs in a well-oiled gearbox. Highly recommended, even if the re watch-value is not that high (knowing about all the twists takes away some of the fun, still rewatchable for the great performances). What keeps this from 10/10 for me is the ultimately depressing story.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A 29 Million budget Masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    eliel77
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    And to think that some decades ago you could do a first class sci-fi with a budget of 29 millions dollars ? Seems crazy, considering that most top productions nowadays surpass the 100 millions dollars, many going beyond 200 million. Twelve Monkeys succeed most in a field that many others fail, there is a script that is on the verge of perfection and a story perfectly developed. We travel between future and paste, real and surreal, and everything is well balanced and makes sense. The conclusion makes this one of the best time travel movies ever made, but don't get me wrong, this is not one of those movies specifically about time travel. Every time I watch Twelve Monkeys I get a higher concept of it, and it has become a classic to me. 9,5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wonderful Movie and Probably Terry Gilliam's Best
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dschyli
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As I saw this movie the first time it was just amazing. The different settings and story lines and also the acting was very appreciate. In my opinion it was one of Bruce Willis' best performances, Brad Pitt was also good in his role, he proved that he can play more difficult roles. In Se7en which was published the same year he did also a very good performance but his role in that movie was not so sophisticated. Twelve Monkeys may be Terry Gilliam's best movie, among Brazil which has also this kind of "Terry Gilliam Fantasy". But in a nutshell it is very difficult to describe that movie without spoilers. But in common the plot is that James Cole (Bruce Willis) is sent back from the year 2035 into 1996 to stop a pandemic that will cause the death of millions of people in the next two years. But now I have to stop because now the spoiler alert is alarming. But nevertheless you have to pay attention in every part of that movie. The only point that makes the movie not a masterpiece is that the role and the acting of Madeleine Stowe in this movie is not very convincing or interesting. But yet every single character is important for the movie. So pay attention and you will experience a nearly perfect movie. Maybe Terry Gilliam's next movies can spread that "Terry Gilliam Fantasy" of Twelve Monkeys.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gloomy atmosphere serves its purpose
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    soudkovahana
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You don't see very often movie that is as good as Twelve Monkeys. It's clever, it's unique, it doesn't have too much action but it's exciting and keeps your eyes wide awake for the whole time because you don't want to miss a second of this brilliant movie. This movie has one of the best performances from both stars, Pitt and Willis. When you try to act like a crazy person it's not actually that easy if you want it to look natural. Both actors played their parts with flair and made their characters just enough crazy to still believe them. The atmosphere of a gray, cold year of 1996 complete the story of a population that's gonna be destroyed perfectly. It's also interesting to see Terry Gilliam, who is mostly known for his rich imagination and wit, dealing with a movie, that in his very core is trying to be as dim as possible. Colors would only subvert the movie. The same goes for music which is so bland that you will not notice it most of the times. Nevertheless all this serves it's purpose because the movie, despite it's drowsy atmosphere or maybe because of it, is something that stays with you and makes it such a unique and unusual experience.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If You Think James Bond Is Escapism.....TRY THIS...!!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    werefox08
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Made in 1995, and Directed by the zany Terry Gilliam ...this a a superior sci. fi. flick. If you want escapism, and you want to rest your rational mind ...watch this 129 minute trip. The three main actors---Bruce Willis, Brad Pitt and Madeleine Stowe are great. The sets are astounding (without relying too much on C.G.I.) The movie purrs along at a good gallop ---so try not to miss a minute as the story goes back and forth in time...and the sub plots are deep. This was my first viewing and I will need to watch it again...(those pesky telephone calls !!!) I will be happy to have another look at this extremely well made film. I am sure it is one of those movies that one never forgets...because of its total originality ...Loved It....(You probably think it is 2013....are you sure ?)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bruce Willis goes on a mission to the past to seek a virus, and he meets Madeleine Stowe
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    msroz
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am quite taken by this very well done sci-fi movie in the time travel sub-genre. Sometimes Hollywood movies are dragged down by their female leads or else the kinds of characters that they are asked to portray. There is absolutely none of that here. Madeleine Stowe is a realistic woman and she brings the part to life, with just the right touches of compassion and doubt. Her emotional reaction to the difficult situation that Bruce Willis is in is surely one of the central features that hold this story together and make it rewarding. Willis is really good, as he has been in every movie I've ever seen him in, and that list is growing. He just gets right into his roles. The production design is more than enough to create both the future gizmos and the past that is under threat. The time travel anomaly of a person encountering himself when he goes back into the past is faced up to squarely by making it a key element of the story, and integrated by flashbacks. The director had "Twelve Monkeys" firmly under control. He had a very good script to work with and a capable cast. The result is a story that holds your attention, doesn't ever reveal too much at once, but enough to keep you in the ball game.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    MY REVIEW: The Time Travel Mystery
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sandeep Gupta
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Don't go by the title, it's not about animals. It's a pure science fiction based on the concept of time travel. The idea here is complex and even execution does not try to make it simpler for you. You need to provide your full attention to it in order to understand the sequence of events and correlate them to unsolve the mystery. The lead actors Bruce Willis, Madeleine Stowe play their part with perfection but it is Brad Pitt who steals the show with his portrayal of a maniac. The screenplay is water tight and background score is first-rate. There are lots of interesting conversations over understanding of human psyche. You would not like to miss it if time travel fantasies intrigue you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Army of the Twelve Monkeys
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    estebangonzalez10
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "I am mentally divergent, in that I am escaping certain unnamed realities that plague my life here. When I stop going there, I will be well. Are you also divergent, friend?" That is the question that the audience has to ask itself during this sci-fi mentally ill time traveling futuristic movie. Is the lead character mentally ill or is he really on a mission traveling through time in order to find a cure to a deadly virus that has wiped off nearly all the population and forced the few survivors to live underground? Director Terry Gilliam has created a memorable sci-fi flick that like all time traveling films has a few in-congruencies but still manages to hold the audience's attention. Gilliam is better known for his work in Monty Python, but he's also directed different types of genre films like The Fisher King (dramedy), Fear and Loathing in Las Vegas (adventure), and The Imaginarium of Doctor Parnassus (Fantasy). He has a pretty respectable filmography as a director, although I still think he did his best work in the 90's. This film has a strong screenplay, but it will be remembered for the strong performances from Bruce Willis and Brad Pitt. Twelve Monkeys is a dark futuristic film similar in some ways to Blade Runner although it kind of diverges all over the place with so many ideas. This is an inventive film but I don't know how many ideas were taken from Chris Marker's 1962 short film, La jetee, which inspired this movie. The screenplay was adapted by David Webb Peoples (Blade Runner, Unforgiven) and Janet Peoples. His influence from Blade Runner seems to be mixed in the screenplay here as well. This is a very fun sci-fi film although full of really weird moments. The film takes place sometime in the future after a deadly virus wiped out over 5 billion people and the few survivors were forced to live underground. James Cole (Bruce Willis) is a convict who is sent by a group of scientists to the past in order to gather information about the virus. The scientists want to study the virus so they can create a cure and live in the outside world once again. Cole is mistakenly sent to 1990 instead of 1996 which was the year in which the virus began spreading, and he ends up in a mental hospital after attacking several police officers. At the mental hospital he is treated by Dr. Railly (Madeleine Stowe) and he also meets another patient named Jeffrey Goines (Brad Pitt) who happens to be the son of a famous scientist (Christopher Plummer). Cole at first begins to search desperately for the "Army of the Twelve Monkeys" because they are believed to be the group responsible for spreading the virus, but later he begins to question himself and believe that he might actually be insane himself. This is a puzzle that he will have to piece together with the help of Railly. This is the puzzle that Gilliam invites the audience to solve along the way and keeps us guessing as the plot unfolds before our eyes. I'm not a huge fan of futuristic films, but Gilliam's vision here is pretty hypnotic and poetic. Most of the film actually takes place in the past, but there are several elements introduced that keep us guessing what will happen next. There were a few stand out scenes like the one in which Cole and Railly are at a movie theater and begin commenting on how despite having seen the movie before the perception of it changes every time, similar to what is happening with Cole through his time traveling. Does his presence in the past change things in the future? Can he find the virus on time in order to save the people in the future? These are a few questions that the film raises. The more you think about things the more flaws you will find, but that doesn't take away anything from this sci-fi film. I really liked Brad Pitt's performance here for which he received an Academy nomination, although he lost to Kevin Spacey (The Usual Suspects). The film runs a bit long, but it never ceases to entertain. Rating: 7,1/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Is he mad or are we? - Director Terry Gilliam
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Thommie Wallin
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film continues an ongoing thread of discussion in film history, about the subjective nature of memories and how they effect the perception of reality. It wears its specific references on its sleeves (and rightfully so): in the opening credits it says inspired by "La Jet&egrave;e" (1962) and later on the main characters literally watches "Vertigo" (1958) in a movie theater. The scene in "Vertigo" where they count the rings on the redwood tree align these films closest touching points, and reveal the overall story structure because they all exist in each of the three films. This is one of the most relevant use of a reference in any film I can think of, where we who have a memory of all three films, replicate in our minds the effect felt by the main characters in all three films - especially this one. A brilliant trick which evoke the memory of "Vertigo" and "La Jet&egrave;e" in the viewers mind, and thereby plant a memory just like in the mind of the main characters of these films. A memory which reflects the use of memory in the film, a memory encompassing a whole life of memories, from a young kid until his death. A memory of this film where we know the start (because the scene takes place in the third act) and with the reference we know the ending, but we still don't know how we're getting there. This film cleverly exist in a vortex in between these other two films, drawing a references here and there into its core which create a new jumbling but cohesive meaning. The result is presented from a subjective point of view, where the explanation of why and how exist in the other films. The other two films explained more thoroughly the overall story, the bigger picture, while this is the experience of the subjective journey at the center of its swirling madness. I can go on and on about the references to Hitchcock and the history of the subject, but it wouldn't tell you anything about whether the film succeeds in its mission and also, I'm sure you can find a better analysis elsewhere on the internet. :) A film doesn't have to be a complete original to be great, even remakes can be better than the original films, it just have to be great within its own framework. A theme which this film wants to confuse and confront the viewer with is madness, and what it is in humans and societies. And I feel it fall short in this aspect of the story compared to that of the subject of memories. It compares the madness of the majority (e.g. the twelve monkey's army)and the individual (e.g. Dr. Peters), as well as who we lock up and don't, in a muddled way which for me is one of the things that drags the overall rating down by a margin. Why I don't necessary think this film reaches the same level of greatness as the other two films mentioned, could have something to do with that this film wouldn't exist if it wasn't for the other films. It's a very good film that stands on its own legs, but it still needs the support from the other films holding each of its hands to remain upright and it still doesn't stand as tall as the others. It gives the subject a fresh perspective but not a new one, and never really starts taking its first wobbling steps towards a life of its own in that territory.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    12 Monkeys-Can't Go Ape Over It *
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Films dealing with the mentally ill always produce controversy. Films such as 1948's "The Snake Pit," and the award winning "One Flew Over the Cuckoo's Nest" were such films since they dealt with real people facing a personal crisis in their lives which led them down the path of irrational behavior. This film fails to achieve that as it's more a science- fiction type film. In a supporting role, Brad Pitt stole the film and Madeleine Stowe, as the psychiatrist, goes through a rapidly downward trend in her own life after meeting up with convict Bruce Willis. The film failed because it just didn't face reality.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very good time-travel whodunit
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    IndustriousAngel
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As time-travel stories go, I liked that one very much. Captivating performances from Pitt and Willis, and I liked the overall intensity and the claustrophobic camera/light. Very good and ingenious production design as usual with Gilliam, but in 12 Monkeys he also managed to keep everything under perfect control - he's a bit of a hit-and-miss director in my opinion. The mystery part works well, the different scenes in different times all fitting together like cogs in a well-oiled gearbox. Highly recommended, even if the re watch-value is not that high (knowing about all the twists takes away some of the fun, still rewatchable for the great performances). What keeps this from 10/10 for me is the ultimately depressing story.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A 29 Million budget Masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    eliel77
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    And to think that some decades ago you could do a first class sci-fi with a budget of 29 millions dollars ? Seems crazy, considering that most top productions nowadays surpass the 100 millions dollars, many going beyond 200 million. Twelve Monkeys succeed most in a field that many others fail, there is a script that is on the verge of perfection and a story perfectly developed. We travel between future and paste, real and surreal, and everything is well balanced and makes sense. The conclusion makes this one of the best time travel movies ever made, but don't get me wrong, this is not one of those movies specifically about time travel. Every time I watch Twelve Monkeys I get a higher concept of it, and it has become a classic to me. 9,5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wonderful Movie and Probably Terry Gilliam's Best
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dschyli
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As I saw this movie the first time it was just amazing. The different settings and story lines and also the acting was very appreciate. In my opinion it was one of Bruce Willis' best performances, Brad Pitt was also good in his role, he proved that he can play more difficult roles. In Se7en which was published the same year he did also a very good performance but his role in that movie was not so sophisticated. Twelve Monkeys may be Terry Gilliam's best movie, among Brazil which has also this kind of "Terry Gilliam Fantasy". But in a nutshell it is very difficult to describe that movie without spoilers. But in common the plot is that James Cole (Bruce Willis) is sent back from the year 2035 into 1996 to stop a pandemic that will cause the death of millions of people in the next two years. But now I have to stop because now the spoiler alert is alarming. But nevertheless you have to pay attention in every part of that movie. The only point that makes the movie not a masterpiece is that the role and the acting of Madeleine Stowe in this movie is not very convincing or interesting. But yet every single character is important for the movie. So pay attention and you will experience a nearly perfect movie. Maybe Terry Gilliam's next movies can spread that "Terry Gilliam Fantasy" of Twelve Monkeys.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gloomy atmosphere serves its purpose
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    soudkovahana
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You don't see very often movie that is as good as Twelve Monkeys. It's clever, it's unique, it doesn't have too much action but it's exciting and keeps your eyes wide awake for the whole time because you don't want to miss a second of this brilliant movie. This movie has one of the best performances from both stars, Pitt and Willis. When you try to act like a crazy person it's not actually that easy if you want it to look natural. Both actors played their parts with flair and made their characters just enough crazy to still believe them. The atmosphere of a gray, cold year of 1996 complete the story of a population that's gonna be destroyed perfectly. It's also interesting to see Terry Gilliam, who is mostly known for his rich imagination and wit, dealing with a movie, that in his very core is trying to be as dim as possible. Colors would only subvert the movie. The same goes for music which is so bland that you will not notice it most of the times. Nevertheless all this serves it's purpose because the movie, despite it's drowsy atmosphere or maybe because of it, is something that stays with you and makes it such a unique and unusual experience.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If You Think James Bond Is Escapism.....TRY THIS...!!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    werefox08
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Made in 1995, and Directed by the zany Terry Gilliam ...this a a superior sci. fi. flick. If you want escapism, and you want to rest your rational mind ...watch this 129 minute trip. The three main actors---Bruce Willis, Brad Pitt and Madeleine Stowe are great. The sets are astounding (without relying too much on C.G.I.) The movie purrs along at a good gallop ---so try not to miss a minute as the story goes back and forth in time...and the sub plots are deep. This was my first viewing and I will need to watch it again...(those pesky telephone calls !!!) I will be happy to have another look at this extremely well made film. I am sure it is one of those movies that one never forgets...because of its total originality ...Loved It....(You probably think it is 2013....are you sure ?)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bruce Willis goes on a mission to the past to seek a virus, and he meets Madeleine Stowe
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    msroz
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am quite taken by this very well done sci-fi movie in the time travel sub-genre. Sometimes Hollywood movies are dragged down by their female leads or else the kinds of characters that they are asked to portray. There is absolutely none of that here. Madeleine Stowe is a realistic woman and she brings the part to life, with just the right touches of compassion and doubt. Her emotional reaction to the difficult situation that Bruce Willis is in is surely one of the central features that hold this story together and make it rewarding. Willis is really good, as he has been in every movie I've ever seen him in, and that list is growing. He just gets right into his roles. The production design is more than enough to create both the future gizmos and the past that is under threat. The time travel anomaly of a person encountering himself when he goes back into the past is faced up to squarely by making it a key element of the story, and integrated by flashbacks. The director had "Twelve Monkeys" firmly under control. He had a very good script to work with and a capable cast. The result is a story that holds your attention, doesn't ever reveal too much at once, but enough to keep you in the ball game.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    MY REVIEW: The Time Travel Mystery
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sandeep Gupta
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Don't go by the title, it's not about animals. It's a pure science fiction based on the concept of time travel. The idea here is complex and even execution does not try to make it simpler for you. You need to provide your full attention to it in order to understand the sequence of events and correlate them to unsolve the mystery. The lead actors Bruce Willis, Madeleine Stowe play their part with perfection but it is Brad Pitt who steals the show with his portrayal of a maniac. The screenplay is water tight and background score is first-rate. There are lots of interesting conversations over understanding of human psyche. You would not like to miss it if time travel fantasies intrigue you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Army of the Twelve Monkeys
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    estebangonzalez10
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "I am mentally divergent, in that I am escaping certain unnamed realities that plague my life here. When I stop going there, I will be well. Are you also divergent, friend?" That is the question that the audience has to ask itself during this sci-fi mentally ill time traveling futuristic movie. Is the lead character mentally ill or is he really on a mission traveling through time in order to find a cure to a deadly virus that has wiped off nearly all the population and forced the few survivors to live underground? Director Terry Gilliam has created a memorable sci-fi flick that like all time traveling films has a few in-congruencies but still manages to hold the audience's attention. Gilliam is better known for his work in Monty Python, but he's also directed different types of genre films like The Fisher King (dramedy), Fear and Loathing in Las Vegas (adventure), and The Imaginarium of Doctor Parnassus (Fantasy). He has a pretty respectable filmography as a director, although I still think he did his best work in the 90's. This film has a strong screenplay, but it will be remembered for the strong performances from Bruce Willis and Brad Pitt. Twelve Monkeys is a dark futuristic film similar in some ways to Blade Runner although it kind of diverges all over the place with so many ideas. This is an inventive film but I don't know how many ideas were taken from Chris Marker's 1962 short film, La jetee, which inspired this movie. The screenplay was adapted by David Webb Peoples (Blade Runner, Unforgiven) and Janet Peoples. His influence from Blade Runner seems to be mixed in the screenplay here as well. This is a very fun sci-fi film although full of really weird moments. The film takes place sometime in the future after a deadly virus wiped out over 5 billion people and the few survivors were forced to live underground. James Cole (Bruce Willis) is a convict who is sent by a group of scientists to the past in order to gather information about the virus. The scientists want to study the virus so they can create a cure and live in the outside world once again. Cole is mistakenly sent to 1990 instead of 1996 which was the year in which the virus began spreading, and he ends up in a mental hospital after attacking several police officers. At the mental hospital he is treated by Dr. Railly (Madeleine Stowe) and he also meets another patient named Jeffrey Goines (Brad Pitt) who happens to be the son of a famous scientist (Christopher Plummer). Cole at first begins to search desperately for the "Army of the Twelve Monkeys" because they are believed to be the group responsible for spreading the virus, but later he begins to question himself and believe that he might actually be insane himself. This is a puzzle that he will have to piece together with the help of Railly. This is the puzzle that Gilliam invites the audience to solve along the way and keeps us guessing as the plot unfolds before our eyes. I'm not a huge fan of futuristic films, but Gilliam's vision here is pretty hypnotic and poetic. Most of the film actually takes place in the past, but there are several elements introduced that keep us guessing what will happen next. There were a few stand out scenes like the one in which Cole and Railly are at a movie theater and begin commenting on how despite having seen the movie before the perception of it changes every time, similar to what is happening with Cole through his time traveling. Does his presence in the past change things in the future? Can he find the virus on time in order to save the people in the future? These are a few questions that the film raises. The more you think about things the more flaws you will find, but that doesn't take away anything from this sci-fi film. I really liked Brad Pitt's performance here for which he received an Academy nomination, although he lost to Kevin Spacey (The Usual Suspects). The film runs a bit long, but it never ceases to entertain. Rating: 7,1/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Is he mad or are we? - Director Terry Gilliam
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Thommie Wallin
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film continues an ongoing thread of discussion in film history, about the subjective nature of memories and how they effect the perception of reality. It wears its specific references on its sleeves (and rightfully so): in the opening credits it says inspired by "La Jet&egrave;e" (1962) and later on the main characters literally watches "Vertigo" (1958) in a movie theater. The scene in "Vertigo" where they count the rings on the redwood tree align these films closest touching points, and reveal the overall story structure because they all exist in each of the three films. This is one of the most relevant use of a reference in any film I can think of, where we who have a memory of all three films, replicate in our minds the effect felt by the main characters in all three films - especially this one. A brilliant trick which evoke the memory of "Vertigo" and "La Jet&egrave;e" in the viewers mind, and thereby plant a memory just like in the mind of the main characters of these films. A memory which reflects the use of memory in the film, a memory encompassing a whole life of memories, from a young kid until his death. A memory of this film where we know the start (because the scene takes place in the third act) and with the reference we know the ending, but we still don't know how we're getting there. This film cleverly exist in a vortex in between these other two films, drawing a references here and there into its core which create a new jumbling but cohesive meaning. The result is presented from a subjective point of view, where the explanation of why and how exist in the other films. The other two films explained more thoroughly the overall story, the bigger picture, while this is the experience of the subjective journey at the center of its swirling madness. I can go on and on about the references to Hitchcock and the history of the subject, but it wouldn't tell you anything about whether the film succeeds in its mission and also, I'm sure you can find a better analysis elsewhere on the internet. :) A film doesn't have to be a complete original to be great, even remakes can be better than the original films, it just have to be great within its own framework. A theme which this film wants to confuse and confront the viewer with is madness, and what it is in humans and societies. And I feel it fall short in this aspect of the story compared to that of the subject of memories. It compares the madness of the majority (e.g. the twelve monkey's army)and the individual (e.g. Dr. Peters), as well as who we lock up and don't, in a muddled way which for me is one of the things that drags the overall rating down by a margin. Why I don't necessary think this film reaches the same level of greatness as the other two films mentioned, could have something to do with that this film wouldn't exist if it wasn't for the other films. It's a very good film that stands on its own legs, but it still needs the support from the other films holding each of its hands to remain upright and it still doesn't stand as tall as the others. It gives the subject a fresh perspective but not a new one, and never really starts taking its first wobbling steps towards a life of its own in that territory.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    12 Monkeys-Can't Go Ape Over It *
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Films dealing with the mentally ill always produce controversy. Films such as 1948's "The Snake Pit," and the award winning "One Flew Over the Cuckoo's Nest" were such films since they dealt with real people facing a personal crisis in their lives which led them down the path of irrational behavior. This film fails to achieve that as it's more a science- fiction type film. In a supporting role, Brad Pitt stole the film and Madeleine Stowe, as the psychiatrist, goes through a rapidly downward trend in her own life after meeting up with convict Bruce Willis. The film failed because it just didn't face reality.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very good time-travel whodunit
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    IndustriousAngel
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As time-travel stories go, I liked that one very much. Captivating performances from Pitt and Willis, and I liked the overall intensity and the claustrophobic camera/light. Very good and ingenious production design as usual with Gilliam, but in 12 Monkeys he also managed to keep everything under perfect control - he's a bit of a hit-and-miss director in my opinion. The mystery part works well, the different scenes in different times all fitting together like cogs in a well-oiled gearbox. Highly recommended, even if the re watch-value is not that high (knowing about all the twists takes away some of the fun, still rewatchable for the great performances). What keeps this from 10/10 for me is the ultimately depressing story.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A 29 Million budget Masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    eliel77
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    And to think that some decades ago you could do a first class sci-fi with a budget of 29 millions dollars ? Seems crazy, considering that most top productions nowadays surpass the 100 millions dollars, many going beyond 200 million. Twelve Monkeys succeed most in a field that many others fail, there is a script that is on the verge of perfection and a story perfectly developed. We travel between future and paste, real and surreal, and everything is well balanced and makes sense. The conclusion makes this one of the best time travel movies ever made, but don't get me wrong, this is not one of those movies specifically about time travel. Every time I watch Twelve Monkeys I get a higher concept of it, and it has become a classic to me. 9,5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wonderful Movie and Probably Terry Gilliam's Best
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dschyli
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As I saw this movie the first time it was just amazing. The different settings and story lines and also the acting was very appreciate. In my opinion it was one of Bruce Willis' best performances, Brad Pitt was also good in his role, he proved that he can play more difficult roles. In Se7en which was published the same year he did also a very good performance but his role in that movie was not so sophisticated. Twelve Monkeys may be Terry Gilliam's best movie, among Brazil which has also this kind of "Terry Gilliam Fantasy". But in a nutshell it is very difficult to describe that movie without spoilers. But in common the plot is that James Cole (Bruce Willis) is sent back from the year 2035 into 1996 to stop a pandemic that will cause the death of millions of people in the next two years. But now I have to stop because now the spoiler alert is alarming. But nevertheless you have to pay attention in every part of that movie. The only point that makes the movie not a masterpiece is that the role and the acting of Madeleine Stowe in this movie is not very convincing or interesting. But yet every single character is important for the movie. So pay attention and you will experience a nearly perfect movie. Maybe Terry Gilliam's next movies can spread that "Terry Gilliam Fantasy" of Twelve Monkeys.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gloomy atmosphere serves its purpose
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    soudkovahana
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You don't see very often movie that is as good as Twelve Monkeys. It's clever, it's unique, it doesn't have too much action but it's exciting and keeps your eyes wide awake for the whole time because you don't want to miss a second of this brilliant movie. This movie has one of the best performances from both stars, Pitt and Willis. When you try to act like a crazy person it's not actually that easy if you want it to look natural. Both actors played their parts with flair and made their characters just enough crazy to still believe them. The atmosphere of a gray, cold year of 1996 complete the story of a population that's gonna be destroyed perfectly. It's also interesting to see Terry Gilliam, who is mostly known for his rich imagination and wit, dealing with a movie, that in his very core is trying to be as dim as possible. Colors would only subvert the movie. The same goes for music which is so bland that you will not notice it most of the times. Nevertheless all this serves it's purpose because the movie, despite it's drowsy atmosphere or maybe because of it, is something that stays with you and makes it such a unique and unusual experience.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If You Think James Bond Is Escapism.....TRY THIS...!!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    werefox08
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Made in 1995, and Directed by the zany Terry Gilliam ...this a a superior sci. fi. flick. If you want escapism, and you want to rest your rational mind ...watch this 129 minute trip. The three main actors---Bruce Willis, Brad Pitt and Madeleine Stowe are great. The sets are astounding (without relying too much on C.G.I.) The movie purrs along at a good gallop ---so try not to miss a minute as the story goes back and forth in time...and the sub plots are deep. This was my first viewing and I will need to watch it again...(those pesky telephone calls !!!) I will be happy to have another look at this extremely well made film. I am sure it is one of those movies that one never forgets...because of its total originality ...Loved It....(You probably think it is 2013....are you sure ?)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bruce Willis goes on a mission to the past to seek a virus, and he meets Madeleine Stowe
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    msroz
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am quite taken by this very well done sci-fi movie in the time travel sub-genre. Sometimes Hollywood movies are dragged down by their female leads or else the kinds of characters that they are asked to portray. There is absolutely none of that here. Madeleine Stowe is a realistic woman and she brings the part to life, with just the right touches of compassion and doubt. Her emotional reaction to the difficult situation that Bruce Willis is in is surely one of the central features that hold this story together and make it rewarding. Willis is really good, as he has been in every movie I've ever seen him in, and that list is growing. He just gets right into his roles. The production design is more than enough to create both the future gizmos and the past that is under threat. The time travel anomaly of a person encountering himself when he goes back into the past is faced up to squarely by making it a key element of the story, and integrated by flashbacks. The director had "Twelve Monkeys" firmly under control. He had a very good script to work with and a capable cast. The result is a story that holds your attention, doesn't ever reveal too much at once, but enough to keep you in the ball game.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    MY REVIEW: The Time Travel Mystery
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sandeep Gupta
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Don't go by the title, it's not about animals. It's a pure science fiction based on the concept of time travel. The idea here is complex and even execution does not try to make it simpler for you. You need to provide your full attention to it in order to understand the sequence of events and correlate them to unsolve the mystery. The lead actors Bruce Willis, Madeleine Stowe play their part with perfection but it is Brad Pitt who steals the show with his portrayal of a maniac. The screenplay is water tight and background score is first-rate. There are lots of interesting conversations over understanding of human psyche. You would not like to miss it if time travel fantasies intrigue you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Army of the Twelve Monkeys
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    estebangonzalez10
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "I am mentally divergent, in that I am escaping certain unnamed realities that plague my life here. When I stop going there, I will be well. Are you also divergent, friend?" That is the question that the audience has to ask itself during this sci-fi mentally ill time traveling futuristic movie. Is the lead character mentally ill or is he really on a mission traveling through time in order to find a cure to a deadly virus that has wiped off nearly all the population and forced the few survivors to live underground? Director Terry Gilliam has created a memorable sci-fi flick that like all time traveling films has a few in-congruencies but still manages to hold the audience's attention. Gilliam is better known for his work in Monty Python, but he's also directed different types of genre films like The Fisher King (dramedy), Fear and Loathing in Las Vegas (adventure), and The Imaginarium of Doctor Parnassus (Fantasy). He has a pretty respectable filmography as a director, although I still think he did his best work in the 90's. This film has a strong screenplay, but it will be remembered for the strong performances from Bruce Willis and Brad Pitt. Twelve Monkeys is a dark futuristic film similar in some ways to Blade Runner although it kind of diverges all over the place with so many ideas. This is an inventive film but I don't know how many ideas were taken from Chris Marker's 1962 short film, La jetee, which inspired this movie. The screenplay was adapted by David Webb Peoples (Blade Runner, Unforgiven) and Janet Peoples. His influence from Blade Runner seems to be mixed in the screenplay here as well. This is a very fun sci-fi film although full of really weird moments. The film takes place sometime in the future after a deadly virus wiped out over 5 billion people and the few survivors were forced to live underground. James Cole (Bruce Willis) is a convict who is sent by a group of scientists to the past in order to gather information about the virus. The scientists want to study the virus so they can create a cure and live in the outside world once again. Cole is mistakenly sent to 1990 instead of 1996 which was the year in which the virus began spreading, and he ends up in a mental hospital after attacking several police officers. At the mental hospital he is treated by Dr. Railly (Madeleine Stowe) and he also meets another patient named Jeffrey Goines (Brad Pitt) who happens to be the son of a famous scientist (Christopher Plummer). Cole at first begins to search desperately for the "Army of the Twelve Monkeys" because they are believed to be the group responsible for spreading the virus, but later he begins to question himself and believe that he might actually be insane himself. This is a puzzle that he will have to piece together with the help of Railly. This is the puzzle that Gilliam invites the audience to solve along the way and keeps us guessing as the plot unfolds before our eyes. I'm not a huge fan of futuristic films, but Gilliam's vision here is pretty hypnotic and poetic. Most of the film actually takes place in the past, but there are several elements introduced that keep us guessing what will happen next. There were a few stand out scenes like the one in which Cole and Railly are at a movie theater and begin commenting on how despite having seen the movie before the perception of it changes every time, similar to what is happening with Cole through his time traveling. Does his presence in the past change things in the future? Can he find the virus on time in order to save the people in the future? These are a few questions that the film raises. The more you think about things the more flaws you will find, but that doesn't take away anything from this sci-fi film. I really liked Brad Pitt's performance here for which he received an Academy nomination, although he lost to Kevin Spacey (The Usual Suspects). The film runs a bit long, but it never ceases to entertain. Rating: 7,1/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Is he mad or are we? - Director Terry Gilliam
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Thommie Wallin
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film continues an ongoing thread of discussion in film history, about the subjective nature of memories and how they effect the perception of reality. It wears its specific references on its sleeves (and rightfully so): in the opening credits it says inspired by "La Jet&egrave;e" (1962) and later on the main characters literally watches "Vertigo" (1958) in a movie theater. The scene in "Vertigo" where they count the rings on the redwood tree align these films closest touching points, and reveal the overall story structure because they all exist in each of the three films. This is one of the most relevant use of a reference in any film I can think of, where we who have a memory of all three films, replicate in our minds the effect felt by the main characters in all three films - especially this one. A brilliant trick which evoke the memory of "Vertigo" and "La Jet&egrave;e" in the viewers mind, and thereby plant a memory just like in the mind of the main characters of these films. A memory which reflects the use of memory in the film, a memory encompassing a whole life of memories, from a young kid until his death. A memory of this film where we know the start (because the scene takes place in the third act) and with the reference we know the ending, but we still don't know how we're getting there. This film cleverly exist in a vortex in between these other two films, drawing a references here and there into its core which create a new jumbling but cohesive meaning. The result is presented from a subjective point of view, where the explanation of why and how exist in the other films. The other two films explained more thoroughly the overall story, the bigger picture, while this is the experience of the subjective journey at the center of its swirling madness. I can go on and on about the references to Hitchcock and the history of the subject, but it wouldn't tell you anything about whether the film succeeds in its mission and also, I'm sure you can find a better analysis elsewhere on the internet. :) A film doesn't have to be a complete original to be great, even remakes can be better than the original films, it just have to be great within its own framework. A theme which this film wants to confuse and confront the viewer with is madness, and what it is in humans and societies. And I feel it fall short in this aspect of the story compared to that of the subject of memories. It compares the madness of the majority (e.g. the twelve monkey's army)and the individual (e.g. Dr. Peters), as well as who we lock up and don't, in a muddled way which for me is one of the things that drags the overall rating down by a margin. Why I don't necessary think this film reaches the same level of greatness as the other two films mentioned, could have something to do with that this film wouldn't exist if it wasn't for the other films. It's a very good film that stands on its own legs, but it still needs the support from the other films holding each of its hands to remain upright and it still doesn't stand as tall as the others. It gives the subject a fresh perspective but not a new one, and never really starts taking its first wobbling steps towards a life of its own in that territory.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    12 Monkeys-Can't Go Ape Over It *
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Films dealing with the mentally ill always produce controversy. Films such as 1948's "The Snake Pit," and the award winning "One Flew Over the Cuckoo's Nest" were such films since they dealt with real people facing a personal crisis in their lives which led them down the path of irrational behavior. This film fails to achieve that as it's more a science- fiction type film. In a supporting role, Brad Pitt stole the film and Madeleine Stowe, as the psychiatrist, goes through a rapidly downward trend in her own life after meeting up with convict Bruce Willis. The film failed because it just didn't face reality.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very good time-travel whodunit
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    IndustriousAngel
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As time-travel stories go, I liked that one very much. Captivating performances from Pitt and Willis, and I liked the overall intensity and the claustrophobic camera/light. Very good and ingenious production design as usual with Gilliam, but in 12 Monkeys he also managed to keep everything under perfect control - he's a bit of a hit-and-miss director in my opinion. The mystery part works well, the different scenes in different times all fitting together like cogs in a well-oiled gearbox. Highly recommended, even if the re watch-value is not that high (knowing about all the twists takes away some of the fun, still rewatchable for the great performances). What keeps this from 10/10 for me is the ultimately depressing story.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A 29 Million budget Masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    eliel77
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    And to think that some decades ago you could do a first class sci-fi with a budget of 29 millions dollars ? Seems crazy, considering that most top productions nowadays surpass the 100 millions dollars, many going beyond 200 million. Twelve Monkeys succeed most in a field that many others fail, there is a script that is on the verge of perfection and a story perfectly developed. We travel between future and paste, real and surreal, and everything is well balanced and makes sense. The conclusion makes this one of the best time travel movies ever made, but don't get me wrong, this is not one of those movies specifically about time travel. Every time I watch Twelve Monkeys I get a higher concept of it, and it has become a classic to me. 9,5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wonderful Movie and Probably Terry Gilliam's Best
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dschyli
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As I saw this movie the first time it was just amazing. The different settings and story lines and also the acting was very appreciate. In my opinion it was one of Bruce Willis' best performances, Brad Pitt was also good in his role, he proved that he can play more difficult roles. In Se7en which was published the same year he did also a very good performance but his role in that movie was not so sophisticated. Twelve Monkeys may be Terry Gilliam's best movie, among Brazil which has also this kind of "Terry Gilliam Fantasy". But in a nutshell it is very difficult to describe that movie without spoilers. But in common the plot is that James Cole (Bruce Willis) is sent back from the year 2035 into 1996 to stop a pandemic that will cause the death of millions of people in the next two years. But now I have to stop because now the spoiler alert is alarming. But nevertheless you have to pay attention in every part of that movie. The only point that makes the movie not a masterpiece is that the role and the acting of Madeleine Stowe in this movie is not very convincing or interesting. But yet every single character is important for the movie. So pay attention and you will experience a nearly perfect movie. Maybe Terry Gilliam's next movies can spread that "Terry Gilliam Fantasy" of Twelve Monkeys.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gloomy atmosphere serves its purpose
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    soudkovahana
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You don't see very often movie that is as good as Twelve Monkeys. It's clever, it's unique, it doesn't have too much action but it's exciting and keeps your eyes wide awake for the whole time because you don't want to miss a second of this brilliant movie. This movie has one of the best performances from both stars, Pitt and Willis. When you try to act like a crazy person it's not actually that easy if you want it to look natural. Both actors played their parts with flair and made their characters just enough crazy to still believe them. The atmosphere of a gray, cold year of 1996 complete the story of a population that's gonna be destroyed perfectly. It's also interesting to see Terry Gilliam, who is mostly known for his rich imagination and wit, dealing with a movie, that in his very core is trying to be as dim as possible. Colors would only subvert the movie. The same goes for music which is so bland that you will not notice it most of the times. Nevertheless all this serves it's purpose because the movie, despite it's drowsy atmosphere or maybe because of it, is something that stays with you and makes it such a unique and unusual experience.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If You Think James Bond Is Escapism.....TRY THIS...!!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    werefox08
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Made in 1995, and Directed by the zany Terry Gilliam ...this a a superior sci. fi. flick. If you want escapism, and you want to rest your rational mind ...watch this 129 minute trip. The three main actors---Bruce Willis, Brad Pitt and Madeleine Stowe are great. The sets are astounding (without relying too much on C.G.I.) The movie purrs along at a good gallop ---so try not to miss a minute as the story goes back and forth in time...and the sub plots are deep. This was my first viewing and I will need to watch it again...(those pesky telephone calls !!!) I will be happy to have another look at this extremely well made film. I am sure it is one of those movies that one never forgets...because of its total originality ...Loved It....(You probably think it is 2013....are you sure ?)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bruce Willis goes on a mission to the past to seek a virus, and he meets Madeleine Stowe
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    msroz
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am quite taken by this very well done sci-fi movie in the time travel sub-genre. Sometimes Hollywood movies are dragged down by their female leads or else the kinds of characters that they are asked to portray. There is absolutely none of that here. Madeleine Stowe is a realistic woman and she brings the part to life, with just the right touches of compassion and doubt. Her emotional reaction to the difficult situation that Bruce Willis is in is surely one of the central features that hold this story together and make it rewarding. Willis is really good, as he has been in every movie I've ever seen him in, and that list is growing. He just gets right into his roles. The production design is more than enough to create both the future gizmos and the past that is under threat. The time travel anomaly of a person encountering himself when he goes back into the past is faced up to squarely by making it a key element of the story, and integrated by flashbacks. The director had "Twelve Monkeys" firmly under control. He had a very good script to work with and a capable cast. The result is a story that holds your attention, doesn't ever reveal too much at once, but enough to keep you in the ball game.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    MY REVIEW: The Time Travel Mystery
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sandeep Gupta
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Don't go by the title, it's not about animals. It's a pure science fiction based on the concept of time travel. The idea here is complex and even execution does not try to make it simpler for you. You need to provide your full attention to it in order to understand the sequence of events and correlate them to unsolve the mystery. The lead actors Bruce Willis, Madeleine Stowe play their part with perfection but it is Brad Pitt who steals the show with his portrayal of a maniac. The screenplay is water tight and background score is first-rate. There are lots of interesting conversations over understanding of human psyche. You would not like to miss it if time travel fantasies intrigue you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Army of the Twelve Monkeys
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    estebangonzalez10
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "I am mentally divergent, in that I am escaping certain unnamed realities that plague my life here. When I stop going there, I will be well. Are you also divergent, friend?" That is the question that the audience has to ask itself during this sci-fi mentally ill time traveling futuristic movie. Is the lead character mentally ill or is he really on a mission traveling through time in order to find a cure to a deadly virus that has wiped off nearly all the population and forced the few survivors to live underground? Director Terry Gilliam has created a memorable sci-fi flick that like all time traveling films has a few in-congruencies but still manages to hold the audience's attention. Gilliam is better known for his work in Monty Python, but he's also directed different types of genre films like The Fisher King (dramedy), Fear and Loathing in Las Vegas (adventure), and The Imaginarium of Doctor Parnassus (Fantasy). He has a pretty respectable filmography as a director, although I still think he did his best work in the 90's. This film has a strong screenplay, but it will be remembered for the strong performances from Bruce Willis and Brad Pitt. Twelve Monkeys is a dark futuristic film similar in some ways to Blade Runner although it kind of diverges all over the place with so many ideas. This is an inventive film but I don't know how many ideas were taken from Chris Marker's 1962 short film, La jetee, which inspired this movie. The screenplay was adapted by David Webb Peoples (Blade Runner, Unforgiven) and Janet Peoples. His influence from Blade Runner seems to be mixed in the screenplay here as well. This is a very fun sci-fi film although full of really weird moments. The film takes place sometime in the future after a deadly virus wiped out over 5 billion people and the few survivors were forced to live underground. James Cole (Bruce Willis) is a convict who is sent by a group of scientists to the past in order to gather information about the virus. The scientists want to study the virus so they can create a cure and live in the outside world once again. Cole is mistakenly sent to 1990 instead of 1996 which was the year in which the virus began spreading, and he ends up in a mental hospital after attacking several police officers. At the mental hospital he is treated by Dr. Railly (Madeleine Stowe) and he also meets another patient named Jeffrey Goines (Brad Pitt) who happens to be the son of a famous scientist (Christopher Plummer). Cole at first begins to search desperately for the "Army of the Twelve Monkeys" because they are believed to be the group responsible for spreading the virus, but later he begins to question himself and believe that he might actually be insane himself. This is a puzzle that he will have to piece together with the help of Railly. This is the puzzle that Gilliam invites the audience to solve along the way and keeps us guessing as the plot unfolds before our eyes. I'm not a huge fan of futuristic films, but Gilliam's vision here is pretty hypnotic and poetic. Most of the film actually takes place in the past, but there are several elements introduced that keep us guessing what will happen next. There were a few stand out scenes like the one in which Cole and Railly are at a movie theater and begin commenting on how despite having seen the movie before the perception of it changes every time, similar to what is happening with Cole through his time traveling. Does his presence in the past change things in the future? Can he find the virus on time in order to save the people in the future? These are a few questions that the film raises. The more you think about things the more flaws you will find, but that doesn't take away anything from this sci-fi film. I really liked Brad Pitt's performance here for which he received an Academy nomination, although he lost to Kevin Spacey (The Usual Suspects). The film runs a bit long, but it never ceases to entertain. Rating: 7,1/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Is he mad or are we? - Director Terry Gilliam
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Thommie Wallin
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film continues an ongoing thread of discussion in film history, about the subjective nature of memories and how they effect the perception of reality. It wears its specific references on its sleeves (and rightfully so): in the opening credits it says inspired by "La Jet&egrave;e" (1962) and later on the main characters literally watches "Vertigo" (1958) in a movie theater. The scene in "Vertigo" where they count the rings on the redwood tree align these films closest touching points, and reveal the overall story structure because they all exist in each of the three films. This is one of the most relevant use of a reference in any film I can think of, where we who have a memory of all three films, replicate in our minds the effect felt by the main characters in all three films - especially this one. A brilliant trick which evoke the memory of "Vertigo" and "La Jet&egrave;e" in the viewers mind, and thereby plant a memory just like in the mind of the main characters of these films. A memory which reflects the use of memory in the film, a memory encompassing a whole life of memories, from a young kid until his death. A memory of this film where we know the start (because the scene takes place in the third act) and with the reference we know the ending, but we still don't know how we're getting there. This film cleverly exist in a vortex in between these other two films, drawing a references here and there into its core which create a new jumbling but cohesive meaning. The result is presented from a subjective point of view, where the explanation of why and how exist in the other films. The other two films explained more thoroughly the overall story, the bigger picture, while this is the experience of the subjective journey at the center of its swirling madness. I can go on and on about the references to Hitchcock and the history of the subject, but it wouldn't tell you anything about whether the film succeeds in its mission and also, I'm sure you can find a better analysis elsewhere on the internet. :) A film doesn't have to be a complete original to be great, even remakes can be better than the original films, it just have to be great within its own framework. A theme which this film wants to confuse and confront the viewer with is madness, and what it is in humans and societies. And I feel it fall short in this aspect of the story compared to that of the subject of memories. It compares the madness of the majority (e.g. the twelve monkey's army)and the individual (e.g. Dr. Peters), as well as who we lock up and don't, in a muddled way which for me is one of the things that drags the overall rating down by a margin. Why I don't necessary think this film reaches the same level of greatness as the other two films mentioned, could have something to do with that this film wouldn't exist if it wasn't for the other films. It's a very good film that stands on its own legs, but it still needs the support from the other films holding each of its hands to remain upright and it still doesn't stand as tall as the others. It gives the subject a fresh perspective but not a new one, and never really starts taking its first wobbling steps towards a life of its own in that territory.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    12 Monkeys-Can't Go Ape Over It *
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Films dealing with the mentally ill always produce controversy. Films such as 1948's "The Snake Pit," and the award winning "One Flew Over the Cuckoo's Nest" were such films since they dealt with real people facing a personal crisis in their lives which led them down the path of irrational behavior. This film fails to achieve that as it's more a science- fiction type film. In a supporting role, Brad Pitt stole the film and Madeleine Stowe, as the psychiatrist, goes through a rapidly downward trend in her own life after meeting up with convict Bruce Willis. The film failed because it just didn't face reality.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very good time-travel whodunit
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    IndustriousAngel
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As time-travel stories go, I liked that one very much. Captivating performances from Pitt and Willis, and I liked the overall intensity and the claustrophobic camera/light. Very good and ingenious production design as usual with Gilliam, but in 12 Monkeys he also managed to keep everything under perfect control - he's a bit of a hit-and-miss director in my opinion. The mystery part works well, the different scenes in different times all fitting together like cogs in a well-oiled gearbox. Highly recommended, even if the re watch-value is not that high (knowing about all the twists takes away some of the fun, still rewatchable for the great performances). What keeps this from 10/10 for me is the ultimately depressing story.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A 29 Million budget Masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    eliel77
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    And to think that some decades ago you could do a first class sci-fi with a budget of 29 millions dollars ? Seems crazy, considering that most top productions nowadays surpass the 100 millions dollars, many going beyond 200 million. Twelve Monkeys succeed most in a field that many others fail, there is a script that is on the verge of perfection and a story perfectly developed. We travel between future and paste, real and surreal, and everything is well balanced and makes sense. The conclusion makes this one of the best time travel movies ever made, but don't get me wrong, this is not one of those movies specifically about time travel. Every time I watch Twelve Monkeys I get a higher concept of it, and it has become a classic to me. 9,5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wonderful Movie and Probably Terry Gilliam's Best
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dschyli
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As I saw this movie the first time it was just amazing. The different settings and story lines and also the acting was very appreciate. In my opinion it was one of Bruce Willis' best performances, Brad Pitt was also good in his role, he proved that he can play more difficult roles. In Se7en which was published the same year he did also a very good performance but his role in that movie was not so sophisticated. Twelve Monkeys may be Terry Gilliam's best movie, among Brazil which has also this kind of "Terry Gilliam Fantasy". But in a nutshell it is very difficult to describe that movie without spoilers. But in common the plot is that James Cole (Bruce Willis) is sent back from the year 2035 into 1996 to stop a pandemic that will cause the death of millions of people in the next two years. But now I have to stop because now the spoiler alert is alarming. But nevertheless you have to pay attention in every part of that movie. The only point that makes the movie not a masterpiece is that the role and the acting of Madeleine Stowe in this movie is not very convincing or interesting. But yet every single character is important for the movie. So pay attention and you will experience a nearly perfect movie. Maybe Terry Gilliam's next movies can spread that "Terry Gilliam Fantasy" of Twelve Monkeys.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gloomy atmosphere serves its purpose
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    soudkovahana
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You don't see very often movie that is as good as Twelve Monkeys. It's clever, it's unique, it doesn't have too much action but it's exciting and keeps your eyes wide awake for the whole time because you don't want to miss a second of this brilliant movie. This movie has one of the best performances from both stars, Pitt and Willis. When you try to act like a crazy person it's not actually that easy if you want it to look natural. Both actors played their parts with flair and made their characters just enough crazy to still believe them. The atmosphere of a gray, cold year of 1996 complete the story of a population that's gonna be destroyed perfectly. It's also interesting to see Terry Gilliam, who is mostly known for his rich imagination and wit, dealing with a movie, that in his very core is trying to be as dim as possible. Colors would only subvert the movie. The same goes for music which is so bland that you will not notice it most of the times. Nevertheless all this serves it's purpose because the movie, despite it's drowsy atmosphere or maybe because of it, is something that stays with you and makes it such a unique and unusual experience.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If You Think James Bond Is Escapism.....TRY THIS...!!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    werefox08
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Made in 1995, and Directed by the zany Terry Gilliam ...this a a superior sci. fi. flick. If you want escapism, and you want to rest your rational mind ...watch this 129 minute trip. The three main actors---Bruce Willis, Brad Pitt and Madeleine Stowe are great. The sets are astounding (without relying too much on C.G.I.) The movie purrs along at a good gallop ---so try not to miss a minute as the story goes back and forth in time...and the sub plots are deep. This was my first viewing and I will need to watch it again...(those pesky telephone calls !!!) I will be happy to have another look at this extremely well made film. I am sure it is one of those movies that one never forgets...because of its total originality ...Loved It....(You probably think it is 2013....are you sure ?)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bruce Willis goes on a mission to the past to seek a virus, and he meets Madeleine Stowe
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    msroz
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am quite taken by this very well done sci-fi movie in the time travel sub-genre. Sometimes Hollywood movies are dragged down by their female leads or else the kinds of characters that they are asked to portray. There is absolutely none of that here. Madeleine Stowe is a realistic woman and she brings the part to life, with just the right touches of compassion and doubt. Her emotional reaction to the difficult situation that Bruce Willis is in is surely one of the central features that hold this story together and make it rewarding. Willis is really good, as he has been in every movie I've ever seen him in, and that list is growing. He just gets right into his roles. The production design is more than enough to create both the future gizmos and the past that is under threat. The time travel anomaly of a person encountering himself when he goes back into the past is faced up to squarely by making it a key element of the story, and integrated by flashbacks. The director had "Twelve Monkeys" firmly under control. He had a very good script to work with and a capable cast. The result is a story that holds your attention, doesn't ever reveal too much at once, but enough to keep you in the ball game.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    MY REVIEW: The Time Travel Mystery
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sandeep Gupta
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Don't go by the title, it's not about animals. It's a pure science fiction based on the concept of time travel. The idea here is complex and even execution does not try to make it simpler for you. You need to provide your full attention to it in order to understand the sequence of events and correlate them to unsolve the mystery. The lead actors Bruce Willis, Madeleine Stowe play their part with perfection but it is Brad Pitt who steals the show with his portrayal of a maniac. The screenplay is water tight and background score is first-rate. There are lots of interesting conversations over understanding of human psyche. You would not like to miss it if time travel fantasies intrigue you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Army of the Twelve Monkeys
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    estebangonzalez10
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "I am mentally divergent, in that I am escaping certain unnamed realities that plague my life here. When I stop going there, I will be well. Are you also divergent, friend?" That is the question that the audience has to ask itself during this sci-fi mentally ill time traveling futuristic movie. Is the lead character mentally ill or is he really on a mission traveling through time in order to find a cure to a deadly virus that has wiped off nearly all the population and forced the few survivors to live underground? Director Terry Gilliam has created a memorable sci-fi flick that like all time traveling films has a few in-congruencies but still manages to hold the audience's attention. Gilliam is better known for his work in Monty Python, but he's also directed different types of genre films like The Fisher King (dramedy), Fear and Loathing in Las Vegas (adventure), and The Imaginarium of Doctor Parnassus (Fantasy). He has a pretty respectable filmography as a director, although I still think he did his best work in the 90's. This film has a strong screenplay, but it will be remembered for the strong performances from Bruce Willis and Brad Pitt. Twelve Monkeys is a dark futuristic film similar in some ways to Blade Runner although it kind of diverges all over the place with so many ideas. This is an inventive film but I don't know how many ideas were taken from Chris Marker's 1962 short film, La jetee, which inspired this movie. The screenplay was adapted by David Webb Peoples (Blade Runner, Unforgiven) and Janet Peoples. His influence from Blade Runner seems to be mixed in the screenplay here as well. This is a very fun sci-fi film although full of really weird moments. The film takes place sometime in the future after a deadly virus wiped out over 5 billion people and the few survivors were forced to live underground. James Cole (Bruce Willis) is a convict who is sent by a group of scientists to the past in order to gather information about the virus. The scientists want to study the virus so they can create a cure and live in the outside world once again. Cole is mistakenly sent to 1990 instead of 1996 which was the year in which the virus began spreading, and he ends up in a mental hospital after attacking several police officers. At the mental hospital he is treated by Dr. Railly (Madeleine Stowe) and he also meets another patient named Jeffrey Goines (Brad Pitt) who happens to be the son of a famous scientist (Christopher Plummer). Cole at first begins to search desperately for the "Army of the Twelve Monkeys" because they are believed to be the group responsible for spreading the virus, but later he begins to question himself and believe that he might actually be insane himself. This is a puzzle that he will have to piece together with the help of Railly. This is the puzzle that Gilliam invites the audience to solve along the way and keeps us guessing as the plot unfolds before our eyes. I'm not a huge fan of futuristic films, but Gilliam's vision here is pretty hypnotic and poetic. Most of the film actually takes place in the past, but there are several elements introduced that keep us guessing what will happen next. There were a few stand out scenes like the one in which Cole and Railly are at a movie theater and begin commenting on how despite having seen the movie before the perception of it changes every time, similar to what is happening with Cole through his time traveling. Does his presence in the past change things in the future? Can he find the virus on time in order to save the people in the future? These are a few questions that the film raises. The more you think about things the more flaws you will find, but that doesn't take away anything from this sci-fi film. I really liked Brad Pitt's performance here for which he received an Academy nomination, although he lost to Kevin Spacey (The Usual Suspects). The film runs a bit long, but it never ceases to entertain. Rating: 7,1/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Is he mad or are we? - Director Terry Gilliam
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Thommie Wallin
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film continues an ongoing thread of discussion in film history, about the subjective nature of memories and how they effect the perception of reality. It wears its specific references on its sleeves (and rightfully so): in the opening credits it says inspired by "La Jet&egrave;e" (1962) and later on the main characters literally watches "Vertigo" (1958) in a movie theater. The scene in "Vertigo" where they count the rings on the redwood tree align these films closest touching points, and reveal the overall story structure because they all exist in each of the three films. This is one of the most relevant use of a reference in any film I can think of, where we who have a memory of all three films, replicate in our minds the effect felt by the main characters in all three films - especially this one. A brilliant trick which evoke the memory of "Vertigo" and "La Jet&egrave;e" in the viewers mind, and thereby plant a memory just like in the mind of the main characters of these films. A memory which reflects the use of memory in the film, a memory encompassing a whole life of memories, from a young kid until his death. A memory of this film where we know the start (because the scene takes place in the third act) and with the reference we know the ending, but we still don't know how we're getting there. This film cleverly exist in a vortex in between these other two films, drawing a references here and there into its core which create a new jumbling but cohesive meaning. The result is presented from a subjective point of view, where the explanation of why and how exist in the other films. The other two films explained more thoroughly the overall story, the bigger picture, while this is the experience of the subjective journey at the center of its swirling madness. I can go on and on about the references to Hitchcock and the history of the subject, but it wouldn't tell you anything about whether the film succeeds in its mission and also, I'm sure you can find a better analysis elsewhere on the internet. :) A film doesn't have to be a complete original to be great, even remakes can be better than the original films, it just have to be great within its own framework. A theme which this film wants to confuse and confront the viewer with is madness, and what it is in humans and societies. And I feel it fall short in this aspect of the story compared to that of the subject of memories. It compares the madness of the majority (e.g. the twelve monkey's army)and the individual (e.g. Dr. Peters), as well as who we lock up and don't, in a muddled way which for me is one of the things that drags the overall rating down by a margin. Why I don't necessary think this film reaches the same level of greatness as the other two films mentioned, could have something to do with that this film wouldn't exist if it wasn't for the other films. It's a very good film that stands on its own legs, but it still needs the support from the other films holding each of its hands to remain upright and it still doesn't stand as tall as the others. It gives the subject a fresh perspective but not a new one, and never really starts taking its first wobbling steps towards a life of its own in that territory.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    12 Monkeys-Can't Go Ape Over It *
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Films dealing with the mentally ill always produce controversy. Films such as 1948's "The Snake Pit," and the award winning "One Flew Over the Cuckoo's Nest" were such films since they dealt with real people facing a personal crisis in their lives which led them down the path of irrational behavior. This film fails to achieve that as it's more a science- fiction type film. In a supporting role, Brad Pitt stole the film and Madeleine Stowe, as the psychiatrist, goes through a rapidly downward trend in her own life after meeting up with convict Bruce Willis. The film failed because it just didn't face reality.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very good time-travel whodunit
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    IndustriousAngel
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As time-travel stories go, I liked that one very much. Captivating performances from Pitt and Willis, and I liked the overall intensity and the claustrophobic camera/light. Very good and ingenious production design as usual with Gilliam, but in 12 Monkeys he also managed to keep everything under perfect control - he's a bit of a hit-and-miss director in my opinion. The mystery part works well, the different scenes in different times all fitting together like cogs in a well-oiled gearbox. Highly recommended, even if the re watch-value is not that high (knowing about all the twists takes away some of the fun, still rewatchable for the great performances). What keeps this from 10/10 for me is the ultimately depressing story.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A 29 Million budget Masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    eliel77
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    And to think that some decades ago you could do a first class sci-fi with a budget of 29 millions dollars ? Seems crazy, considering that most top productions nowadays surpass the 100 millions dollars, many going beyond 200 million. Twelve Monkeys succeed most in a field that many others fail, there is a script that is on the verge of perfection and a story perfectly developed. We travel between future and paste, real and surreal, and everything is well balanced and makes sense. The conclusion makes this one of the best time travel movies ever made, but don't get me wrong, this is not one of those movies specifically about time travel. Every time I watch Twelve Monkeys I get a higher concept of it, and it has become a classic to me. 9,5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wonderful Movie and Probably Terry Gilliam's Best
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dschyli
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As I saw this movie the first time it was just amazing. The different settings and story lines and also the acting was very appreciate. In my opinion it was one of Bruce Willis' best performances, Brad Pitt was also good in his role, he proved that he can play more difficult roles. In Se7en which was published the same year he did also a very good performance but his role in that movie was not so sophisticated. Twelve Monkeys may be Terry Gilliam's best movie, among Brazil which has also this kind of "Terry Gilliam Fantasy". But in a nutshell it is very difficult to describe that movie without spoilers. But in common the plot is that James Cole (Bruce Willis) is sent back from the year 2035 into 1996 to stop a pandemic that will cause the death of millions of people in the next two years. But now I have to stop because now the spoiler alert is alarming. But nevertheless you have to pay attention in every part of that movie. The only point that makes the movie not a masterpiece is that the role and the acting of Madeleine Stowe in this movie is not very convincing or interesting. But yet every single character is important for the movie. So pay attention and you will experience a nearly perfect movie. Maybe Terry Gilliam's next movies can spread that "Terry Gilliam Fantasy" of Twelve Monkeys.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gloomy atmosphere serves its purpose
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    soudkovahana
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You don't see very often movie that is as good as Twelve Monkeys. It's clever, it's unique, it doesn't have too much action but it's exciting and keeps your eyes wide awake for the whole time because you don't want to miss a second of this brilliant movie. This movie has one of the best performances from both stars, Pitt and Willis. When you try to act like a crazy person it's not actually that easy if you want it to look natural. Both actors played their parts with flair and made their characters just enough crazy to still believe them. The atmosphere of a gray, cold year of 1996 complete the story of a population that's gonna be destroyed perfectly. It's also interesting to see Terry Gilliam, who is mostly known for his rich imagination and wit, dealing with a movie, that in his very core is trying to be as dim as possible. Colors would only subvert the movie. The same goes for music which is so bland that you will not notice it most of the times. Nevertheless all this serves it's purpose because the movie, despite it's drowsy atmosphere or maybe because of it, is something that stays with you and makes it such a unique and unusual experience.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If You Think James Bond Is Escapism.....TRY THIS...!!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    werefox08
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Made in 1995, and Directed by the zany Terry Gilliam ...this a a superior sci. fi. flick. If you want escapism, and you want to rest your rational mind ...watch this 129 minute trip. The three main actors---Bruce Willis, Brad Pitt and Madeleine Stowe are great. The sets are astounding (without relying too much on C.G.I.) The movie purrs along at a good gallop ---so try not to miss a minute as the story goes back and forth in time...and the sub plots are deep. This was my first viewing and I will need to watch it again...(those pesky telephone calls !!!) I will be happy to have another look at this extremely well made film. I am sure it is one of those movies that one never forgets...because of its total originality ...Loved It....(You probably think it is 2013....are you sure ?)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bruce Willis goes on a mission to the past to seek a virus, and he meets Madeleine Stowe
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    msroz
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am quite taken by this very well done sci-fi movie in the time travel sub-genre. Sometimes Hollywood movies are dragged down by their female leads or else the kinds of characters that they are asked to portray. There is absolutely none of that here. Madeleine Stowe is a realistic woman and she brings the part to life, with just the right touches of compassion and doubt. Her emotional reaction to the difficult situation that Bruce Willis is in is surely one of the central features that hold this story together and make it rewarding. Willis is really good, as he has been in every movie I've ever seen him in, and that list is growing. He just gets right into his roles. The production design is more than enough to create both the future gizmos and the past that is under threat. The time travel anomaly of a person encountering himself when he goes back into the past is faced up to squarely by making it a key element of the story, and integrated by flashbacks. The director had "Twelve Monkeys" firmly under control. He had a very good script to work with and a capable cast. The result is a story that holds your attention, doesn't ever reveal too much at once, but enough to keep you in the ball game.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    MY REVIEW: The Time Travel Mystery
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sandeep Gupta
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Don't go by the title, it's not about animals. It's a pure science fiction based on the concept of time travel. The idea here is complex and even execution does not try to make it simpler for you. You need to provide your full attention to it in order to understand the sequence of events and correlate them to unsolve the mystery. The lead actors Bruce Willis, Madeleine Stowe play their part with perfection but it is Brad Pitt who steals the show with his portrayal of a maniac. The screenplay is water tight and background score is first-rate. There are lots of interesting conversations over understanding of human psyche. You would not like to miss it if time travel fantasies intrigue you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Army of the Twelve Monkeys
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    estebangonzalez10
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "I am mentally divergent, in that I am escaping certain unnamed realities that plague my life here. When I stop going there, I will be well. Are you also divergent, friend?" That is the question that the audience has to ask itself during this sci-fi mentally ill time traveling futuristic movie. Is the lead character mentally ill or is he really on a mission traveling through time in order to find a cure to a deadly virus that has wiped off nearly all the population and forced the few survivors to live underground? Director Terry Gilliam has created a memorable sci-fi flick that like all time traveling films has a few in-congruencies but still manages to hold the audience's attention. Gilliam is better known for his work in Monty Python, but he's also directed different types of genre films like The Fisher King (dramedy), Fear and Loathing in Las Vegas (adventure), and The Imaginarium of Doctor Parnassus (Fantasy). He has a pretty respectable filmography as a director, although I still think he did his best work in the 90's. This film has a strong screenplay, but it will be remembered for the strong performances from Bruce Willis and Brad Pitt. Twelve Monkeys is a dark futuristic film similar in some ways to Blade Runner although it kind of diverges all over the place with so many ideas. This is an inventive film but I don't know how many ideas were taken from Chris Marker's 1962 short film, La jetee, which inspired this movie. The screenplay was adapted by David Webb Peoples (Blade Runner, Unforgiven) and Janet Peoples. His influence from Blade Runner seems to be mixed in the screenplay here as well. This is a very fun sci-fi film although full of really weird moments. The film takes place sometime in the future after a deadly virus wiped out over 5 billion people and the few survivors were forced to live underground. James Cole (Bruce Willis) is a convict who is sent by a group of scientists to the past in order to gather information about the virus. The scientists want to study the virus so they can create a cure and live in the outside world once again. Cole is mistakenly sent to 1990 instead of 1996 which was the year in which the virus began spreading, and he ends up in a mental hospital after attacking several police officers. At the mental hospital he is treated by Dr. Railly (Madeleine Stowe) and he also meets another patient named Jeffrey Goines (Brad Pitt) who happens to be the son of a famous scientist (Christopher Plummer). Cole at first begins to search desperately for the "Army of the Twelve Monkeys" because they are believed to be the group responsible for spreading the virus, but later he begins to question himself and believe that he might actually be insane himself. This is a puzzle that he will have to piece together with the help of Railly. This is the puzzle that Gilliam invites the audience to solve along the way and keeps us guessing as the plot unfolds before our eyes. I'm not a huge fan of futuristic films, but Gilliam's vision here is pretty hypnotic and poetic. Most of the film actually takes place in the past, but there are several elements introduced that keep us guessing what will happen next. There were a few stand out scenes like the one in which Cole and Railly are at a movie theater and begin commenting on how despite having seen the movie before the perception of it changes every time, similar to what is happening with Cole through his time traveling. Does his presence in the past change things in the future? Can he find the virus on time in order to save the people in the future? These are a few questions that the film raises. The more you think about things the more flaws you will find, but that doesn't take away anything from this sci-fi film. I really liked Brad Pitt's performance here for which he received an Academy nomination, although he lost to Kevin Spacey (The Usual Suspects). The film runs a bit long, but it never ceases to entertain. Rating: 7,1/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Is he mad or are we? - Director Terry Gilliam
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Thommie Wallin
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film continues an ongoing thread of discussion in film history, about the subjective nature of memories and how they effect the perception of reality. It wears its specific references on its sleeves (and rightfully so): in the opening credits it says inspired by "La Jet&egrave;e" (1962) and later on the main characters literally watches "Vertigo" (1958) in a movie theater. The scene in "Vertigo" where they count the rings on the redwood tree align these films closest touching points, and reveal the overall story structure because they all exist in each of the three films. This is one of the most relevant use of a reference in any film I can think of, where we who have a memory of all three films, replicate in our minds the effect felt by the main characters in all three films - especially this one. A brilliant trick which evoke the memory of "Vertigo" and "La Jet&egrave;e" in the viewers mind, and thereby plant a memory just like in the mind of the main characters of these films. A memory which reflects the use of memory in the film, a memory encompassing a whole life of memories, from a young kid until his death. A memory of this film where we know the start (because the scene takes place in the third act) and with the reference we know the ending, but we still don't know how we're getting there. This film cleverly exist in a vortex in between these other two films, drawing a references here and there into its core which create a new jumbling but cohesive meaning. The result is presented from a subjective point of view, where the explanation of why and how exist in the other films. The other two films explained more thoroughly the overall story, the bigger picture, while this is the experience of the subjective journey at the center of its swirling madness. I can go on and on about the references to Hitchcock and the history of the subject, but it wouldn't tell you anything about whether the film succeeds in its mission and also, I'm sure you can find a better analysis elsewhere on the internet. :) A film doesn't have to be a complete original to be great, even remakes can be better than the original films, it just have to be great within its own framework. A theme which this film wants to confuse and confront the viewer with is madness, and what it is in humans and societies. And I feel it fall short in this aspect of the story compared to that of the subject of memories. It compares the madness of the majority (e.g. the twelve monkey's army)and the individual (e.g. Dr. Peters), as well as who we lock up and don't, in a muddled way which for me is one of the things that drags the overall rating down by a margin. Why I don't necessary think this film reaches the same level of greatness as the other two films mentioned, could have something to do with that this film wouldn't exist if it wasn't for the other films. It's a very good film that stands on its own legs, but it still needs the support from the other films holding each of its hands to remain upright and it still doesn't stand as tall as the others. It gives the subject a fresh perspective but not a new one, and never really starts taking its first wobbling steps towards a life of its own in that territory.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    12 Monkeys-Can't Go Ape Over It *
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Films dealing with the mentally ill always produce controversy. Films such as 1948's "The Snake Pit," and the award winning "One Flew Over the Cuckoo's Nest" were such films since they dealt with real people facing a personal crisis in their lives which led them down the path of irrational behavior. This film fails to achieve that as it's more a science- fiction type film. In a supporting role, Brad Pitt stole the film and Madeleine Stowe, as the psychiatrist, goes through a rapidly downward trend in her own life after meeting up with convict Bruce Willis. The film failed because it just didn't face reality.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very good time-travel whodunit
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    IndustriousAngel
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As time-travel stories go, I liked that one very much. Captivating performances from Pitt and Willis, and I liked the overall intensity and the claustrophobic camera/light. Very good and ingenious production design as usual with Gilliam, but in 12 Monkeys he also managed to keep everything under perfect control - he's a bit of a hit-and-miss director in my opinion. The mystery part works well, the different scenes in different times all fitting together like cogs in a well-oiled gearbox. Highly recommended, even if the re watch-value is not that high (knowing about all the twists takes away some of the fun, still rewatchable for the great performances). What keeps this from 10/10 for me is the ultimately depressing story.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A 29 Million budget Masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    eliel77
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    And to think that some decades ago you could do a first class sci-fi with a budget of 29 millions dollars ? Seems crazy, considering that most top productions nowadays surpass the 100 millions dollars, many going beyond 200 million. Twelve Monkeys succeed most in a field that many others fail, there is a script that is on the verge of perfection and a story perfectly developed. We travel between future and paste, real and surreal, and everything is well balanced and makes sense. The conclusion makes this one of the best time travel movies ever made, but don't get me wrong, this is not one of those movies specifically about time travel. Every time I watch Twelve Monkeys I get a higher concept of it, and it has become a classic to me. 9,5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wonderful Movie and Probably Terry Gilliam's Best
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dschyli
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As I saw this movie the first time it was just amazing. The different settings and story lines and also the acting was very appreciate. In my opinion it was one of Bruce Willis' best performances, Brad Pitt was also good in his role, he proved that he can play more difficult roles. In Se7en which was published the same year he did also a very good performance but his role in that movie was not so sophisticated. Twelve Monkeys may be Terry Gilliam's best movie, among Brazil which has also this kind of "Terry Gilliam Fantasy". But in a nutshell it is very difficult to describe that movie without spoilers. But in common the plot is that James Cole (Bruce Willis) is sent back from the year 2035 into 1996 to stop a pandemic that will cause the death of millions of people in the next two years. But now I have to stop because now the spoiler alert is alarming. But nevertheless you have to pay attention in every part of that movie. The only point that makes the movie not a masterpiece is that the role and the acting of Madeleine Stowe in this movie is not very convincing or interesting. But yet every single character is important for the movie. So pay attention and you will experience a nearly perfect movie. Maybe Terry Gilliam's next movies can spread that "Terry Gilliam Fantasy" of Twelve Monkeys.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gloomy atmosphere serves its purpose
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    soudkovahana
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You don't see very often movie that is as good as Twelve Monkeys. It's clever, it's unique, it doesn't have too much action but it's exciting and keeps your eyes wide awake for the whole time because you don't want to miss a second of this brilliant movie. This movie has one of the best performances from both stars, Pitt and Willis. When you try to act like a crazy person it's not actually that easy if you want it to look natural. Both actors played their parts with flair and made their characters just enough crazy to still believe them. The atmosphere of a gray, cold year of 1996 complete the story of a population that's gonna be destroyed perfectly. It's also interesting to see Terry Gilliam, who is mostly known for his rich imagination and wit, dealing with a movie, that in his very core is trying to be as dim as possible. Colors would only subvert the movie. The same goes for music which is so bland that you will not notice it most of the times. Nevertheless all this serves it's purpose because the movie, despite it's drowsy atmosphere or maybe because of it, is something that stays with you and makes it such a unique and unusual experience.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If You Think James Bond Is Escapism.....TRY THIS...!!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    werefox08
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Made in 1995, and Directed by the zany Terry Gilliam ...this a a superior sci. fi. flick. If you want escapism, and you want to rest your rational mind ...watch this 129 minute trip. The three main actors---Bruce Willis, Brad Pitt and Madeleine Stowe are great. The sets are astounding (without relying too much on C.G.I.) The movie purrs along at a good gallop ---so try not to miss a minute as the story goes back and forth in time...and the sub plots are deep. This was my first viewing and I will need to watch it again...(those pesky telephone calls !!!) I will be happy to have another look at this extremely well made film. I am sure it is one of those movies that one never forgets...because of its total originality ...Loved It....(You probably think it is 2013....are you sure ?)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bruce Willis goes on a mission to the past to seek a virus, and he meets Madeleine Stowe
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    msroz
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am quite taken by this very well done sci-fi movie in the time travel sub-genre. Sometimes Hollywood movies are dragged down by their female leads or else the kinds of characters that they are asked to portray. There is absolutely none of that here. Madeleine Stowe is a realistic woman and she brings the part to life, with just the right touches of compassion and doubt. Her emotional reaction to the difficult situation that Bruce Willis is in is surely one of the central features that hold this story together and make it rewarding. Willis is really good, as he has been in every movie I've ever seen him in, and that list is growing. He just gets right into his roles. The production design is more than enough to create both the future gizmos and the past that is under threat. The time travel anomaly of a person encountering himself when he goes back into the past is faced up to squarely by making it a key element of the story, and integrated by flashbacks. The director had "Twelve Monkeys" firmly under control. He had a very good script to work with and a capable cast. The result is a story that holds your attention, doesn't ever reveal too much at once, but enough to keep you in the ball game.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    MY REVIEW: The Time Travel Mystery
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sandeep Gupta
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Don't go by the title, it's not about animals. It's a pure science fiction based on the concept of time travel. The idea here is complex and even execution does not try to make it simpler for you. You need to provide your full attention to it in order to understand the sequence of events and correlate them to unsolve the mystery. The lead actors Bruce Willis, Madeleine Stowe play their part with perfection but it is Brad Pitt who steals the show with his portrayal of a maniac. The screenplay is water tight and background score is first-rate. There are lots of interesting conversations over understanding of human psyche. You would not like to miss it if time travel fantasies intrigue you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The Army of the Twelve Monkeys
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    estebangonzalez10
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "I am mentally divergent, in that I am escaping certain unnamed realities that plague my life here. When I stop going there, I will be well. Are you also divergent, friend?" That is the question that the audience has to ask itself during this sci-fi mentally ill time traveling futuristic movie. Is the lead character mentally ill or is he really on a mission traveling through time in order to find a cure to a deadly virus that has wiped off nearly all the population and forced the few survivors to live underground? Director Terry Gilliam has created a memorable sci-fi flick that like all time traveling films has a few in-congruencies but still manages to hold the audience's attention. Gilliam is better known for his work in Monty Python, but he's also directed different types of genre films like The Fisher King (dramedy), Fear and Loathing in Las Vegas (adventure), and The Imaginarium of Doctor Parnassus (Fantasy). He has a pretty respectable filmography as a director, although I still think he did his best work in the 90's. This film has a strong screenplay, but it will be remembered for the strong performances from Bruce Willis and Brad Pitt. Twelve Monkeys is a dark futuristic film similar in some ways to Blade Runner although it kind of diverges all over the place with so many ideas. This is an inventive film but I don't know how many ideas were taken from Chris Marker's 1962 short film, La jetee, which inspired this movie. The screenplay was adapted by David Webb Peoples (Blade Runner, Unforgiven) and Janet Peoples. His influence from Blade Runner seems to be mixed in the screenplay here as well. This is a very fun sci-fi film although full of really weird moments. The film takes place sometime in the future after a deadly virus wiped out over 5 billion people and the few survivors were forced to live underground. James Cole (Bruce Willis) is a convict who is sent by a group of scientists to the past in order to gather information about the virus. The scientists want to study the virus so they can create a cure and live in the outside world once again. Cole is mistakenly sent to 1990 instead of 1996 which was the year in which the virus began spreading, and he ends up in a mental hospital after attacking several police officers. At the mental hospital he is treated by Dr. Railly (Madeleine Stowe) and he also meets another patient named Jeffrey Goines (Brad Pitt) who happens to be the son of a famous scientist (Christopher Plummer). Cole at first begins to search desperately for the "Army of the Twelve Monkeys" because they are believed to be the group responsible for spreading the virus, but later he begins to question himself and believe that he might actually be insane himself. This is a puzzle that he will have to piece together with the help of Railly. This is the puzzle that Gilliam invites the audience to solve along the way and keeps us guessing as the plot unfolds before our eyes. I'm not a huge fan of futuristic films, but Gilliam's vision here is pretty hypnotic and poetic. Most of the film actually takes place in the past, but there are several elements introduced that keep us guessing what will happen next. There were a few stand out scenes like the one in which Cole and Railly are at a movie theater and begin commenting on how despite having seen the movie before the perception of it changes every time, similar to what is happening with Cole through his time traveling. Does his presence in the past change things in the future? Can he find the virus on time in order to save the people in the future? These are a few questions that the film raises. The more you think about things the more flaws you will find, but that doesn't take away anything from this sci-fi film. I really liked Brad Pitt's performance here for which he received an Academy nomination, although he lost to Kevin Spacey (The Usual Suspects). The film runs a bit long, but it never ceases to entertain. Rating: 7,1/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Is he mad or are we? - Director Terry Gilliam
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Thommie Wallin
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film continues an ongoing thread of discussion in film history, about the subjective nature of memories and how they effect the perception of reality. It wears its specific references on its sleeves (and rightfully so): in the opening credits it says inspired by "La Jet&egrave;e" (1962) and later on the main characters literally watches "Vertigo" (1958) in a movie theater. The scene in "Vertigo" where they count the rings on the redwood tree align these films closest touching points, and reveal the overall story structure because they all exist in each of the three films. This is one of the most relevant use of a reference in any film I can think of, where we who have a memory of all three films, replicate in our minds the effect felt by the main characters in all three films - especially this one. A brilliant trick which evoke the memory of "Vertigo" and "La Jet&egrave;e" in the viewers mind, and thereby plant a memory just like in the mind of the main characters of these films. A memory which reflects the use of memory in the film, a memory encompassing a whole life of memories, from a young kid until his death. A memory of this film where we know the start (because the scene takes place in the third act) and with the reference we know the ending, but we still don't know how we're getting there. This film cleverly exist in a vortex in between these other two films, drawing a references here and there into its core which create a new jumbling but cohesive meaning. The result is presented from a subjective point of view, where the explanation of why and how exist in the other films. The other two films explained more thoroughly the overall story, the bigger picture, while this is the experience of the subjective journey at the center of its swirling madness. I can go on and on about the references to Hitchcock and the history of the subject, but it wouldn't tell you anything about whether the film succeeds in its mission and also, I'm sure you can find a better analysis elsewhere on the internet. :) A film doesn't have to be a complete original to be great, even remakes can be better than the original films, it just have to be great within its own framework. A theme which this film wants to confuse and confront the viewer with is madness, and what it is in humans and societies. And I feel it fall short in this aspect of the story compared to that of the subject of memories. It compares the madness of the majority (e.g. the twelve monkey's army)and the individual (e.g. Dr. Peters), as well as who we lock up and don't, in a muddled way which for me is one of the things that drags the overall rating down by a margin. Why I don't necessary think this film reaches the same level of greatness as the other two films mentioned, could have something to do with that this film wouldn't exist if it wasn't for the other films. It's a very good film that stands on its own legs, but it still needs the support from the other films holding each of its hands to remain upright and it still doesn't stand as tall as the others. It gives the subject a fresh perspective but not a new one, and never really starts taking its first wobbling steps towards a life of its own in that territory.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    12 Monkeys-Can't Go Ape Over It *
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Films dealing with the mentally ill always produce controversy. Films such as 1948's "The Snake Pit," and the award winning "One Flew Over the Cuckoo's Nest" were such films since they dealt with real people facing a personal crisis in their lives which led them down the path of irrational behavior. This film fails to achieve that as it's more a science- fiction type film. In a supporting role, Brad Pitt stole the film and Madeleine Stowe, as the psychiatrist, goes through a rapidly downward trend in her own life after meeting up with convict Bruce Willis. The film failed because it just didn't face reality.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very good time-travel whodunit
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    IndustriousAngel
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As time-travel stories go, I liked that one very much. Captivating performances from Pitt and Willis, and I liked the overall intensity and the claustrophobic camera/light. Very good and ingenious production design as usual with Gilliam, but in 12 Monkeys he also managed to keep everything under perfect control - he's a bit of a hit-and-miss director in my opinion. The mystery part works well, the different scenes in different times all fitting together like cogs in a well-oiled gearbox. Highly recommended, even if the re watch-value is not that high (knowing about all the twists takes away some of the fun, still rewatchable for the great performances). What keeps this from 10/10 for me is the ultimately depressing story.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A 29 Million budget Masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    eliel77
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    And to think that some decades ago you could do a first class sci-fi with a budget of 29 millions dollars ? Seems crazy, considering that most top productions nowadays surpass the 100 millions dollars, many going beyond 200 million. Twelve Monkeys succeed most in a field that many others fail, there is a script that is on the verge of perfection and a story perfectly developed. We travel between future and paste, real and surreal, and everything is well balanced and makes sense. The conclusion makes this one of the best time travel movies ever made, but don't get me wrong, this is not one of those movies specifically about time travel. Every time I watch Twelve Monkeys I get a higher concept of it, and it has become a classic to me. 9,5/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wonderful Movie and Probably Terry Gilliam's Best
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dschyli
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As I saw this movie the first time it was just amazing. The different settings and story lines and also the acting was very appreciate. In my opinion it was one of Bruce Willis' best performances, Brad Pitt was also good in his role, he proved that he can play more difficult roles. In Se7en which was published the same year he did also a very good performance but his role in that movie was not so sophisticated. Twelve Monkeys may be Terry Gilliam's best movie, among Brazil which has also this kind of "Terry Gilliam Fantasy". But in a nutshell it is very difficult to describe that movie without spoilers. But in common the plot is that James Cole (Bruce Willis) is sent back from the year 2035 into 1996 to stop a pandemic that will cause the death of millions of people in the next two years. But now I have to stop because now the spoiler alert is alarming. But nevertheless you have to pay attention in every part of that movie. The only point that makes the movie not a masterpiece is that the role and the acting of Madeleine Stowe in this movie is not very convincing or interesting. But yet every single character is important for the movie. So pay attention and you will experience a nearly perfect movie. Maybe Terry Gilliam's next movies can spread that "Terry Gilliam Fantasy" of Twelve Monkeys.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
