<filme>
 <id>
  70
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0109831
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1994
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Quatro Casamentos E Um Funeral
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  7.0
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Over the course of five social occasions, a committed bachelor must consider the notion that he may have discovered love.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  The film follows the fortunes of Charles and his friends as they wonder if they will ever find true love and marry. Charles thinks he's found "Miss Right" in Carrie, an American. This British subtle comedy revolves around Charlie, his friends and the four weddings and one funeral which they attend.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Romance
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   wedding
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   friend
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   funeral
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   brother sister relationship
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   annulment
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Mike Newell
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Richard Curtis
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Hugh Grant
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Andie MacDowell
  </ator>
  <ator>
   James Fleet
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny and charming
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mcjoe1614
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let's be honest here. Unless you are one of these 'true-love' fanatics then you will find romantic comedies extremely lifeless, predictable and dull. For me, that's putting it kindly. However, Richard Curtis has always had a special touch with his films which have put them a head up over the rest of the sappy Hollywood stuff. 'Four weddings and a funeral' is a British rom-com that was delightful to watch. Hugh grant is such a funny actor, you can warm to him at once ; he is a rare talent. He also has great chemistry in the movie with this American beauty who he happens to meet upon multiple weddings. If this was just a love film on its own, it would be poor . Yet what makes 'four weddings' so compelling is the hilarious comedic script that is packed with all sorts of witty comments. Grant's group of friends in the movie are hilarious, and yes even Rowan Atkinson made it into the movie (although I would call his role more of a cameo). 'Four weddings and a funeral' was so popular at its time, that it received a 'best picture' nomination which is un-heard of for a rom-com. That should give you an idea of how good this movie is. Definitely worth watching - no matter what type of person you are, there is going to be something in here that will make you laugh :)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good For What It Is!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    g-bodyl
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Four Weddings and a Funeral is a British romantic comedy that is sometimes charming, but it mostly falls flat and gets lost in the mix of all romantic comedies out there. This film is entertaining, but forgettable. Writing this review, I can hardly remember what happens in the movie. Mike Newell's film is about a bachelor named Charles and he is seemingly the best man at many weddings. At the first wedding, he meets this girl and he thinks he finally falls in love. Over the course of several more weddings and a funeral, he gets the notion that maybe he has fallen for the wrong lady. The acting is pretty good for the most part. Hugh Grant is a charming British fellow and this film introduced him to the American audience. Simon Callow and John Hannah are really good and quite funny. Andie McDowell is pretty darn awful and she sounds like she's a robot. Overall, this is a decent but entirely forgettable British comedy. It has some good moments and some boring moments. Some of the jokes are quite funny especially the one involving the band, U2. Despite this being a solid film, I can't fathom how the film was nominated for Best Picture at the Oscars. It's only a date night film at best. I rate this film 7/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Mike Newell has directed a pleasant film about the importance of love.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FilmCriticLalitRao
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Through his comedy film, "Four weddings and a funeral", British director Mike Newell gives an excellent idea about how love and marriage are viewed by English people. His film is a quest for finding true love. It also depicts the importance of love over sex in relationships involving men and women. A good film which can be watched with family involves elements which are valued by family members. From that yardstick, a film about love and marriage can be a little offensive only if has some explicit hints about sex. However, English film four weddings and a funeral deliberately avoids any unnecessary mention of sex in order to portray itself as a clean film. The choice of an American actress who is wooed by a flippant British bachelor works well for this film as Andie MacDowell and Hugh Grant remain true to their on screen portrayals. In most films, minor characters are not developed but this film gives equal importance to minor characters who help viewers to understand the importance of friends in a person's life. Lastly, four weddings and a funeral is able to impress viewers as its spreads the message that there comes a time in each person's life when he/she has to become serious about marriage and must get married before it is too late.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Four Weddings and a Funeral: And Only That
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Elise Tarter
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    While I enjoy romantic comedies as much as or more than most, I found very little to appreciate in Four Weddings and a Funeral: It flits around from wedding to wedding employing a fairly large cast of characters, which, though interesting, the viewer never gets to know. The fatal flaw of Four Weddings is that it tells us about many significant friendships, relationships, and romances but rarely shows them to us in actual character interactions or dialogue. The supposedly deep and meaningful connections between characters were actually so threadbare as to cause audience confusion or worse, indifference. Here are a few examples: Charles and Fiona- We learn that they are long-time friends, but see her carp at Charles for his lateness and then confess her love for him, which is never mentioned again hereafter. Carrie and Hamish- She's flirting with Charles, in bed with him and then  engaged to Hamish. Things like this do happen, but she goes out especially with Charles for a fun, "dress-selecting" outing and then sleeps with him again before her wedding. This is the marriage that came from nowhere and made no sense other than a (poor) plot device. Gareth- He wears a silly-looking vest but makes fun of Scarlett's dress. He generally has a good time, drinks, dances, and then drops dead in a startling and therefore moderately comical manner. However, his funeral is treated seriously in the film and is supposed to carry great emotional weight with the viewer. Honestly, I barely had time to learn his name and a few superficial facts about him, but there was not enough "meat" in his character development to make my eyes even begin to grow misty when he died. Charles and Henrietta- They have a couple of tearful conversations, one complete with a dressing down, no steamy encounters, but suddenly, they're walking down the aisle But all of this may have been forgivable if the movie had spent any time with the side characters before bombarding us with the montage of weddings at the end. Henrietta/ "Duckface" gets married, happily, it seems, but the audience gets not one minute with her after Charles leaves her at the altar. This film skips over almost every relationship or character development worth showing, leaving it emotionally hollow, frustrating, and ultimately forgettable. I guess screenwriter Richard Curtis was getting warmed up for Love Actually, which succeeds in all the ways that Four Weddings and a Funeral failed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Four occasions to laugh, one to cry, five to meditate about love and life ....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ElMaruecan82
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Many romantic comedies end with the two leads finally reuniting for the final kiss and realizing that they're meant to live together. Though it doesn't necessarily imply that the following step is marriage, but we can bet on a long-term commitment. Basically, "Four Weddings and a Funeral" stands above all the 'romantic comedy' genre because it doesn't take its very essence for granted and turns into a delightful social commentary about the meaning of marital commitment even questioning its compatibility with real love. Can love last for life? If not definite answers, the film provides some hints through four martial experiences and one funeral, which is an occasion to think about life and death. Mike Newell finds the perfect balance between humor, slapstick and intelligence, all of them in a typically British flavor. And one thing for sure, the film's title doesn't lie about the content since the five titular events and their direct aftermaths occupy almost 95% of the screen time. And as viewers, we're (literally) invited to follow the adventures of one joyful bunch of friends. On the top of them, there's Hugh Grant as Charles, a handsome thirty something bachelor whose penetrating blue eyes betray a vulnerable sensitivity that doesn't fit his look. There is the tiny, exuberant Charlotte Coleman as Scarlett, a gay couple, Matthew (John Hannah) and Garrett played by the scene-stealing Simon Callow. Kristin Scott Thomas plays Fiona, hiding in a sophisticated composure the grief of never having conquered Charles' heart, and last but not least, there's Tom, Jack Fleet as the goofiest and clumsiest of the bunch, which is saying a lot. We never know exactly what these people do for a living, but it doesn't matter actually. Besides, we know them enough to understand the way they feel, behave or approach life and important matters, so the rest would only fill the script with unnecessary details. Have you noticed by the way that in most rom-coms, the jobs of the two lead hardly play a role, one is an architect, and another is a cook, so what? And have you also noticed that many romantic comedies only rely on the believability of its lead couple and some supporting characters, "Four Weddings and a Funeral" is an ensemble cast movie, and even more effective because it doesn't depend on a multi-linear plot, the solidarity, the complicity between the friends is the story's heart and greatest source for gags and amusement. I insist on the ensemble cast because truth is if Hugh Grant was perfect for the role that put him in America's showbiz map, and earned him a Golden Globe, the same can hardly be said about Andie McDowell. As much as I respect and appreciate the actress, it's hard to see the same sweetheart who turned Phil Connor's heart in "Groundhog Day". She doesn't deliver a bad performance per se, but a Razzie nomination (that thankfully the film was spared of) wouldn't have surprised me. It was hard to believe that Charles would be so infatuated in a woman who doesn't seem quite sure either about love, let alone marriage. Some would think this is what united them since they would be involved in the two weddings that didn't end. But something in Carrie suggested that she was more of a gold-digger type, while Charles is more a victim of his own idealism. Unsuccessful marriages end up being more insightful than the others, (if only because they do 'end up') and one of the merit of "Four Weddings and a Funeral" is to put the notion of commitment into perspective, to revalue the meaning of living and loving someone for life. In a way, the subtext is that we are never 100% sure to love someone then marriage is not necessarily a guarantee of happiness OR if we really love one person, then marriage would be totally meaningless. That's the idea conveyed by Gareth and Matthew's who'd be shown as the most solid and sincere couple, without any ceremony to 'validate' their union. The death of Gareth invites for these questions and works as a great dramatic relief in a relatively screwball comedy, thanks to Matthew's powerful eulogy, simple but realistically heart-breaking. But I guess I was a bit too serious in my review, and beyond the whole introspective facade, "Four Weddings and a Funeral" is also a cheerful celebration of the most special day of anyone's life, the day we have to say 'yes', this magical moment that sets a before and an after in our lives, that starts with solemnity and ends up with fun, alcohol, and maybe a few years later, regrets. It also allows other people to meet their match, soul-mates or one-night hits. Weddings are the premise of countless jokes, a nice twist on the forget-the-rings gag, embarrassing best man's speeches, some acts of pure desperation and a wonderfully comic moment with Rowan Atkinson as a priest in his first wedding. His five minutes are funnier than the whole 'Mr. Bean' film, in fact, the film reminds us that the world needs marriage, if only to have a great moment of fun and joy. "Four Weddings and one Funeral" was one of the biggest hits of the glorious 1994, earning two nominations for Best Screenplay and Best Picture. The material is so fresh and new on the field of romantic comedies that it's hard to tolerate such conventional moments like a declaration of love under the rain, and a cheesy line delivered by you-know-who, and it's only forgivable because the film immediately redeems itself through the great ending credits sequence and Elton John's version of "Chapel of Love", the credits sequences perfectly captures the positive, optimistic mood of the film, and even its not-to-be-taken-so-seriously quality. And it does fit the general message of the film that after all, maybe wedding, just like life, is not to be taken so seriously, and maybe that's the best way to make it work.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hated it when I saw it in '94, loved it last night
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rooprect
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I saw this film in '94, I was expecting something a little snappier & edgier like the rom-coms of the time (such as "Singles" or "When Harry Met Sally"). Instead, its low-key, subtle, British presentation caught me off guard and left me a little bit unfulfilled. I now realize that's because I was an idiot at the time. Subtlety is this film's strength, and Hugh Grant's performance is impeccable in that regard. There aren't a lot of wisecracking zingers or situational craziness, but Hugh's portrayal of a cute, clueless, British playboy is something he does par excellence. Andie McDowell's portrayal of a disconnected, almost soulless enigma is equally compelling, although on first viewing I didn't understand the character. The comedy comes through Hugh's strained reactions to the insane situations he finds himself in. Things happen that would reduce a normal human to hysterics, but Hugh is forced to ride it out with proper British decorum. For example, there's one scene where finds himself stuck at a table with EVERY ONE of his ex-girlfriends, trying to play it off as politely as possible while they take turns freaking out at him. Something to note: Unlike films like "Harry Met Sally" and "Singles" which focus equally on the characters, this movie is essentially from Hugh's viewpoint, and Andie's character is almost peripheral. With that in mind, it's not a standard love story between two people. Instead it's about one man stumbling through the concept of romance. If you like rom-coms that take a different approach, this is a good one for you to check out. I also recommend "Forget Paris" (about what happens to a couple AFTER 'happily ever after') and "Object of Beauty" (starring Andie McDowell & John Malkovich as a pair of dysfunctional, small-time con artists in love). If you're a Hugh Grant fan, you'll love this film, period.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny, but not one of my favourites
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I had heard some morally bad things about this movie and a number of people portrayed it in a bad light. I think is was because of the prostitute incident at the time of this movie that put me off it. In fact, the prostitute incident put a number of people I knew off of Hugh Grant. Personally I don't think that it was the media's business about whether Hugh Grant was caught with a prostitute, and more so the pressure put on his girlfriend at the time to forgive him. This movie is about four weddings and a funeral. In fact, there is only one scene in the movie that is not set at a wedding or the funeral. As one can tell by the title the movie is about marriage, but the conclusion that it comes to I inevitably disagree with. The movie is based around a group of friends who are always going to weddings. In fact, it is the time of life when everybody is getting married. Charles (Hugh Grant) always sleeps in and as such is always late to weddings. That is until his own when all of his friends make damn sure that he gets up in time. The movie explores death and marriage, and at one point - the low point - the conclusion is that not everybody is going to get married. This is true as Charles concludes, after he called a wedding off because he did not really want to marry Duck Face - Henrietta, that marriage was not for him - yet he still wanted the companionship of a girl. My opinion here is not that marriage was not for him, but rather that he is so scared to make a commitment to a woman that he would rather have a relationship that he can call off easily. The funeral is of a very cheerful chap who dies at the third wedding. This chap is the oldest and commands his friends to find a partner. He dies and they come to see that not everybody is going to get married. This is not true to the movie because, as one can expect, everybody ends up happily ever after. The thing the people I know did not appreciate about this movie was the ending where they say that they can have a perfect marriage relationship without getting married. This I do not really agree with because marriage involves commitments and promises, and if you are not willing to make these promises to the person, then you should not either consider marrying this person, or living with the person as if you were married.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Mostly enjoyable - needs a different ending
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    elspeth-11
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I really enjoyed most of this movie - the funeral was devastating. And unlike many, I really do enjoy the standard Hugh Grant (which, in fairness, was not yet "standard" when this movie was new). BUT (and I'm agreeing with everyone else here) Carrie, the Andie MacDowell character, has nothing going for her. She is not appealing in any way, and she's a slag. Additionally, the wedding to Duckface is totally unmotivated, and only contrived so that he can leave her at the altar without us hating him. Here is how it should have gone. The fourth wedding should have been between Charles and Carrie - once she's divorced, there is no impediment after all. Carrie - true to character - will be getting it on with someone else by the night before the wedding. Meanwhile, Charles discovers that he is really in love with Fiona (wasn't that the point of the movie? it's what I expected to happen). The deaf character discovers both these facts and the wedding can now be played as originally scripted.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    So overrated it should be criminal
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    summerskter
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is so frustratingly forgettable. It is a romance which makes absolutely no sense to the viewer. The object of affection is a promiscuous, threesome-having, cheating, superficial, self-absorbed woman named Carrie, which Andie Macdowell plays as if she were just a breezy, soft-spoken nice girl. Andie is so uncomfortable in this role that every single line is delivered in a monotone drawl. If you can get through her last line, "Is it still raining? I hadn't noticed," while they are standing in a downpour, without laughing, my hat's off to you. Without spoiling to much, let's just say if you value romance, like actual romance involving two people getting along, spending some quality non-sex time together, you are not going to find it in this hollow, mechanical movie. And when I mean hollow, I mean so completely insincere that anyone who lives in the real world would find the characters' behavior mystifying until the ending credits. I still don't understand what this movie was trying to say. I was 100% rooting for Hugh Grant (Charles) to end up with either of the two eligible women who are actually loyal and devoted to him, and who don't treat him and his feelings dismissively throughout the entire film, as Carrie does. So terribly disappointing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Typical Plot but Atypical Setting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    copperncherrio
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love Hugh Grant. You just cannot go wrong with Hugh Grant and romantic comedies, and Four Weddings & a Funeral is the perfect chick flick of romance, humor, and most importantly GREAT CONVERSATION. There are so many little scenes and snipets that are just brilliant little skits that are wrapped around into an interesting love story. Though the love isn't compelling between the two main characters and there could be minor plot tweaks, there's a lot of great things about this British film that I'm sorry that more films can't take away from. High expectations I had, and disappointed I was not. Possibly one of the greatest romantic comedies that I've witnessed thus far. Hugh Grant was superb, the leading gal was alright.. .but there is a great supporting cast. I can't hate a well written movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny and charming
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mcjoe1614
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let's be honest here. Unless you are one of these 'true-love' fanatics then you will find romantic comedies extremely lifeless, predictable and dull. For me, that's putting it kindly. However, Richard Curtis has always had a special touch with his films which have put them a head up over the rest of the sappy Hollywood stuff. 'Four weddings and a funeral' is a British rom-com that was delightful to watch. Hugh grant is such a funny actor, you can warm to him at once ; he is a rare talent. He also has great chemistry in the movie with this American beauty who he happens to meet upon multiple weddings. If this was just a love film on its own, it would be poor . Yet what makes 'four weddings' so compelling is the hilarious comedic script that is packed with all sorts of witty comments. Grant's group of friends in the movie are hilarious, and yes even Rowan Atkinson made it into the movie (although I would call his role more of a cameo). 'Four weddings and a funeral' was so popular at its time, that it received a 'best picture' nomination which is un-heard of for a rom-com. That should give you an idea of how good this movie is. Definitely worth watching - no matter what type of person you are, there is going to be something in here that will make you laugh :)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good For What It Is!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    g-bodyl
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Four Weddings and a Funeral is a British romantic comedy that is sometimes charming, but it mostly falls flat and gets lost in the mix of all romantic comedies out there. This film is entertaining, but forgettable. Writing this review, I can hardly remember what happens in the movie. Mike Newell's film is about a bachelor named Charles and he is seemingly the best man at many weddings. At the first wedding, he meets this girl and he thinks he finally falls in love. Over the course of several more weddings and a funeral, he gets the notion that maybe he has fallen for the wrong lady. The acting is pretty good for the most part. Hugh Grant is a charming British fellow and this film introduced him to the American audience. Simon Callow and John Hannah are really good and quite funny. Andie McDowell is pretty darn awful and she sounds like she's a robot. Overall, this is a decent but entirely forgettable British comedy. It has some good moments and some boring moments. Some of the jokes are quite funny especially the one involving the band, U2. Despite this being a solid film, I can't fathom how the film was nominated for Best Picture at the Oscars. It's only a date night film at best. I rate this film 7/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Mike Newell has directed a pleasant film about the importance of love.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FilmCriticLalitRao
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Through his comedy film, "Four weddings and a funeral", British director Mike Newell gives an excellent idea about how love and marriage are viewed by English people. His film is a quest for finding true love. It also depicts the importance of love over sex in relationships involving men and women. A good film which can be watched with family involves elements which are valued by family members. From that yardstick, a film about love and marriage can be a little offensive only if has some explicit hints about sex. However, English film four weddings and a funeral deliberately avoids any unnecessary mention of sex in order to portray itself as a clean film. The choice of an American actress who is wooed by a flippant British bachelor works well for this film as Andie MacDowell and Hugh Grant remain true to their on screen portrayals. In most films, minor characters are not developed but this film gives equal importance to minor characters who help viewers to understand the importance of friends in a person's life. Lastly, four weddings and a funeral is able to impress viewers as its spreads the message that there comes a time in each person's life when he/she has to become serious about marriage and must get married before it is too late.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Four Weddings and a Funeral: And Only That
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Elise Tarter
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    While I enjoy romantic comedies as much as or more than most, I found very little to appreciate in Four Weddings and a Funeral: It flits around from wedding to wedding employing a fairly large cast of characters, which, though interesting, the viewer never gets to know. The fatal flaw of Four Weddings is that it tells us about many significant friendships, relationships, and romances but rarely shows them to us in actual character interactions or dialogue. The supposedly deep and meaningful connections between characters were actually so threadbare as to cause audience confusion or worse, indifference. Here are a few examples: Charles and Fiona- We learn that they are long-time friends, but see her carp at Charles for his lateness and then confess her love for him, which is never mentioned again hereafter. Carrie and Hamish- She's flirting with Charles, in bed with him and then  engaged to Hamish. Things like this do happen, but she goes out especially with Charles for a fun, "dress-selecting" outing and then sleeps with him again before her wedding. This is the marriage that came from nowhere and made no sense other than a (poor) plot device. Gareth- He wears a silly-looking vest but makes fun of Scarlett's dress. He generally has a good time, drinks, dances, and then drops dead in a startling and therefore moderately comical manner. However, his funeral is treated seriously in the film and is supposed to carry great emotional weight with the viewer. Honestly, I barely had time to learn his name and a few superficial facts about him, but there was not enough "meat" in his character development to make my eyes even begin to grow misty when he died. Charles and Henrietta- They have a couple of tearful conversations, one complete with a dressing down, no steamy encounters, but suddenly, they're walking down the aisle But all of this may have been forgivable if the movie had spent any time with the side characters before bombarding us with the montage of weddings at the end. Henrietta/ "Duckface" gets married, happily, it seems, but the audience gets not one minute with her after Charles leaves her at the altar. This film skips over almost every relationship or character development worth showing, leaving it emotionally hollow, frustrating, and ultimately forgettable. I guess screenwriter Richard Curtis was getting warmed up for Love Actually, which succeeds in all the ways that Four Weddings and a Funeral failed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Four occasions to laugh, one to cry, five to meditate about love and life ....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ElMaruecan82
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Many romantic comedies end with the two leads finally reuniting for the final kiss and realizing that they're meant to live together. Though it doesn't necessarily imply that the following step is marriage, but we can bet on a long-term commitment. Basically, "Four Weddings and a Funeral" stands above all the 'romantic comedy' genre because it doesn't take its very essence for granted and turns into a delightful social commentary about the meaning of marital commitment even questioning its compatibility with real love. Can love last for life? If not definite answers, the film provides some hints through four martial experiences and one funeral, which is an occasion to think about life and death. Mike Newell finds the perfect balance between humor, slapstick and intelligence, all of them in a typically British flavor. And one thing for sure, the film's title doesn't lie about the content since the five titular events and their direct aftermaths occupy almost 95% of the screen time. And as viewers, we're (literally) invited to follow the adventures of one joyful bunch of friends. On the top of them, there's Hugh Grant as Charles, a handsome thirty something bachelor whose penetrating blue eyes betray a vulnerable sensitivity that doesn't fit his look. There is the tiny, exuberant Charlotte Coleman as Scarlett, a gay couple, Matthew (John Hannah) and Garrett played by the scene-stealing Simon Callow. Kristin Scott Thomas plays Fiona, hiding in a sophisticated composure the grief of never having conquered Charles' heart, and last but not least, there's Tom, Jack Fleet as the goofiest and clumsiest of the bunch, which is saying a lot. We never know exactly what these people do for a living, but it doesn't matter actually. Besides, we know them enough to understand the way they feel, behave or approach life and important matters, so the rest would only fill the script with unnecessary details. Have you noticed by the way that in most rom-coms, the jobs of the two lead hardly play a role, one is an architect, and another is a cook, so what? And have you also noticed that many romantic comedies only rely on the believability of its lead couple and some supporting characters, "Four Weddings and a Funeral" is an ensemble cast movie, and even more effective because it doesn't depend on a multi-linear plot, the solidarity, the complicity between the friends is the story's heart and greatest source for gags and amusement. I insist on the ensemble cast because truth is if Hugh Grant was perfect for the role that put him in America's showbiz map, and earned him a Golden Globe, the same can hardly be said about Andie McDowell. As much as I respect and appreciate the actress, it's hard to see the same sweetheart who turned Phil Connor's heart in "Groundhog Day". She doesn't deliver a bad performance per se, but a Razzie nomination (that thankfully the film was spared of) wouldn't have surprised me. It was hard to believe that Charles would be so infatuated in a woman who doesn't seem quite sure either about love, let alone marriage. Some would think this is what united them since they would be involved in the two weddings that didn't end. But something in Carrie suggested that she was more of a gold-digger type, while Charles is more a victim of his own idealism. Unsuccessful marriages end up being more insightful than the others, (if only because they do 'end up') and one of the merit of "Four Weddings and a Funeral" is to put the notion of commitment into perspective, to revalue the meaning of living and loving someone for life. In a way, the subtext is that we are never 100% sure to love someone then marriage is not necessarily a guarantee of happiness OR if we really love one person, then marriage would be totally meaningless. That's the idea conveyed by Gareth and Matthew's who'd be shown as the most solid and sincere couple, without any ceremony to 'validate' their union. The death of Gareth invites for these questions and works as a great dramatic relief in a relatively screwball comedy, thanks to Matthew's powerful eulogy, simple but realistically heart-breaking. But I guess I was a bit too serious in my review, and beyond the whole introspective facade, "Four Weddings and a Funeral" is also a cheerful celebration of the most special day of anyone's life, the day we have to say 'yes', this magical moment that sets a before and an after in our lives, that starts with solemnity and ends up with fun, alcohol, and maybe a few years later, regrets. It also allows other people to meet their match, soul-mates or one-night hits. Weddings are the premise of countless jokes, a nice twist on the forget-the-rings gag, embarrassing best man's speeches, some acts of pure desperation and a wonderfully comic moment with Rowan Atkinson as a priest in his first wedding. His five minutes are funnier than the whole 'Mr. Bean' film, in fact, the film reminds us that the world needs marriage, if only to have a great moment of fun and joy. "Four Weddings and one Funeral" was one of the biggest hits of the glorious 1994, earning two nominations for Best Screenplay and Best Picture. The material is so fresh and new on the field of romantic comedies that it's hard to tolerate such conventional moments like a declaration of love under the rain, and a cheesy line delivered by you-know-who, and it's only forgivable because the film immediately redeems itself through the great ending credits sequence and Elton John's version of "Chapel of Love", the credits sequences perfectly captures the positive, optimistic mood of the film, and even its not-to-be-taken-so-seriously quality. And it does fit the general message of the film that after all, maybe wedding, just like life, is not to be taken so seriously, and maybe that's the best way to make it work.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hated it when I saw it in '94, loved it last night
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rooprect
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I saw this film in '94, I was expecting something a little snappier & edgier like the rom-coms of the time (such as "Singles" or "When Harry Met Sally"). Instead, its low-key, subtle, British presentation caught me off guard and left me a little bit unfulfilled. I now realize that's because I was an idiot at the time. Subtlety is this film's strength, and Hugh Grant's performance is impeccable in that regard. There aren't a lot of wisecracking zingers or situational craziness, but Hugh's portrayal of a cute, clueless, British playboy is something he does par excellence. Andie McDowell's portrayal of a disconnected, almost soulless enigma is equally compelling, although on first viewing I didn't understand the character. The comedy comes through Hugh's strained reactions to the insane situations he finds himself in. Things happen that would reduce a normal human to hysterics, but Hugh is forced to ride it out with proper British decorum. For example, there's one scene where finds himself stuck at a table with EVERY ONE of his ex-girlfriends, trying to play it off as politely as possible while they take turns freaking out at him. Something to note: Unlike films like "Harry Met Sally" and "Singles" which focus equally on the characters, this movie is essentially from Hugh's viewpoint, and Andie's character is almost peripheral. With that in mind, it's not a standard love story between two people. Instead it's about one man stumbling through the concept of romance. If you like rom-coms that take a different approach, this is a good one for you to check out. I also recommend "Forget Paris" (about what happens to a couple AFTER 'happily ever after') and "Object of Beauty" (starring Andie McDowell & John Malkovich as a pair of dysfunctional, small-time con artists in love). If you're a Hugh Grant fan, you'll love this film, period.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny, but not one of my favourites
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I had heard some morally bad things about this movie and a number of people portrayed it in a bad light. I think is was because of the prostitute incident at the time of this movie that put me off it. In fact, the prostitute incident put a number of people I knew off of Hugh Grant. Personally I don't think that it was the media's business about whether Hugh Grant was caught with a prostitute, and more so the pressure put on his girlfriend at the time to forgive him. This movie is about four weddings and a funeral. In fact, there is only one scene in the movie that is not set at a wedding or the funeral. As one can tell by the title the movie is about marriage, but the conclusion that it comes to I inevitably disagree with. The movie is based around a group of friends who are always going to weddings. In fact, it is the time of life when everybody is getting married. Charles (Hugh Grant) always sleeps in and as such is always late to weddings. That is until his own when all of his friends make damn sure that he gets up in time. The movie explores death and marriage, and at one point - the low point - the conclusion is that not everybody is going to get married. This is true as Charles concludes, after he called a wedding off because he did not really want to marry Duck Face - Henrietta, that marriage was not for him - yet he still wanted the companionship of a girl. My opinion here is not that marriage was not for him, but rather that he is so scared to make a commitment to a woman that he would rather have a relationship that he can call off easily. The funeral is of a very cheerful chap who dies at the third wedding. This chap is the oldest and commands his friends to find a partner. He dies and they come to see that not everybody is going to get married. This is not true to the movie because, as one can expect, everybody ends up happily ever after. The thing the people I know did not appreciate about this movie was the ending where they say that they can have a perfect marriage relationship without getting married. This I do not really agree with because marriage involves commitments and promises, and if you are not willing to make these promises to the person, then you should not either consider marrying this person, or living with the person as if you were married.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Mostly enjoyable - needs a different ending
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    elspeth-11
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I really enjoyed most of this movie - the funeral was devastating. And unlike many, I really do enjoy the standard Hugh Grant (which, in fairness, was not yet "standard" when this movie was new). BUT (and I'm agreeing with everyone else here) Carrie, the Andie MacDowell character, has nothing going for her. She is not appealing in any way, and she's a slag. Additionally, the wedding to Duckface is totally unmotivated, and only contrived so that he can leave her at the altar without us hating him. Here is how it should have gone. The fourth wedding should have been between Charles and Carrie - once she's divorced, there is no impediment after all. Carrie - true to character - will be getting it on with someone else by the night before the wedding. Meanwhile, Charles discovers that he is really in love with Fiona (wasn't that the point of the movie? it's what I expected to happen). The deaf character discovers both these facts and the wedding can now be played as originally scripted.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    So overrated it should be criminal
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    summerskter
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is so frustratingly forgettable. It is a romance which makes absolutely no sense to the viewer. The object of affection is a promiscuous, threesome-having, cheating, superficial, self-absorbed woman named Carrie, which Andie Macdowell plays as if she were just a breezy, soft-spoken nice girl. Andie is so uncomfortable in this role that every single line is delivered in a monotone drawl. If you can get through her last line, "Is it still raining? I hadn't noticed," while they are standing in a downpour, without laughing, my hat's off to you. Without spoiling to much, let's just say if you value romance, like actual romance involving two people getting along, spending some quality non-sex time together, you are not going to find it in this hollow, mechanical movie. And when I mean hollow, I mean so completely insincere that anyone who lives in the real world would find the characters' behavior mystifying until the ending credits. I still don't understand what this movie was trying to say. I was 100% rooting for Hugh Grant (Charles) to end up with either of the two eligible women who are actually loyal and devoted to him, and who don't treat him and his feelings dismissively throughout the entire film, as Carrie does. So terribly disappointing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Typical Plot but Atypical Setting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    copperncherrio
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love Hugh Grant. You just cannot go wrong with Hugh Grant and romantic comedies, and Four Weddings & a Funeral is the perfect chick flick of romance, humor, and most importantly GREAT CONVERSATION. There are so many little scenes and snipets that are just brilliant little skits that are wrapped around into an interesting love story. Though the love isn't compelling between the two main characters and there could be minor plot tweaks, there's a lot of great things about this British film that I'm sorry that more films can't take away from. High expectations I had, and disappointed I was not. Possibly one of the greatest romantic comedies that I've witnessed thus far. Hugh Grant was superb, the leading gal was alright.. .but there is a great supporting cast. I can't hate a well written movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny and charming
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mcjoe1614
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let's be honest here. Unless you are one of these 'true-love' fanatics then you will find romantic comedies extremely lifeless, predictable and dull. For me, that's putting it kindly. However, Richard Curtis has always had a special touch with his films which have put them a head up over the rest of the sappy Hollywood stuff. 'Four weddings and a funeral' is a British rom-com that was delightful to watch. Hugh grant is such a funny actor, you can warm to him at once ; he is a rare talent. He also has great chemistry in the movie with this American beauty who he happens to meet upon multiple weddings. If this was just a love film on its own, it would be poor . Yet what makes 'four weddings' so compelling is the hilarious comedic script that is packed with all sorts of witty comments. Grant's group of friends in the movie are hilarious, and yes even Rowan Atkinson made it into the movie (although I would call his role more of a cameo). 'Four weddings and a funeral' was so popular at its time, that it received a 'best picture' nomination which is un-heard of for a rom-com. That should give you an idea of how good this movie is. Definitely worth watching - no matter what type of person you are, there is going to be something in here that will make you laugh :)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good For What It Is!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    g-bodyl
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Four Weddings and a Funeral is a British romantic comedy that is sometimes charming, but it mostly falls flat and gets lost in the mix of all romantic comedies out there. This film is entertaining, but forgettable. Writing this review, I can hardly remember what happens in the movie. Mike Newell's film is about a bachelor named Charles and he is seemingly the best man at many weddings. At the first wedding, he meets this girl and he thinks he finally falls in love. Over the course of several more weddings and a funeral, he gets the notion that maybe he has fallen for the wrong lady. The acting is pretty good for the most part. Hugh Grant is a charming British fellow and this film introduced him to the American audience. Simon Callow and John Hannah are really good and quite funny. Andie McDowell is pretty darn awful and she sounds like she's a robot. Overall, this is a decent but entirely forgettable British comedy. It has some good moments and some boring moments. Some of the jokes are quite funny especially the one involving the band, U2. Despite this being a solid film, I can't fathom how the film was nominated for Best Picture at the Oscars. It's only a date night film at best. I rate this film 7/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Mike Newell has directed a pleasant film about the importance of love.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FilmCriticLalitRao
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Through his comedy film, "Four weddings and a funeral", British director Mike Newell gives an excellent idea about how love and marriage are viewed by English people. His film is a quest for finding true love. It also depicts the importance of love over sex in relationships involving men and women. A good film which can be watched with family involves elements which are valued by family members. From that yardstick, a film about love and marriage can be a little offensive only if has some explicit hints about sex. However, English film four weddings and a funeral deliberately avoids any unnecessary mention of sex in order to portray itself as a clean film. The choice of an American actress who is wooed by a flippant British bachelor works well for this film as Andie MacDowell and Hugh Grant remain true to their on screen portrayals. In most films, minor characters are not developed but this film gives equal importance to minor characters who help viewers to understand the importance of friends in a person's life. Lastly, four weddings and a funeral is able to impress viewers as its spreads the message that there comes a time in each person's life when he/she has to become serious about marriage and must get married before it is too late.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Four Weddings and a Funeral: And Only That
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Elise Tarter
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    While I enjoy romantic comedies as much as or more than most, I found very little to appreciate in Four Weddings and a Funeral: It flits around from wedding to wedding employing a fairly large cast of characters, which, though interesting, the viewer never gets to know. The fatal flaw of Four Weddings is that it tells us about many significant friendships, relationships, and romances but rarely shows them to us in actual character interactions or dialogue. The supposedly deep and meaningful connections between characters were actually so threadbare as to cause audience confusion or worse, indifference. Here are a few examples: Charles and Fiona- We learn that they are long-time friends, but see her carp at Charles for his lateness and then confess her love for him, which is never mentioned again hereafter. Carrie and Hamish- She's flirting with Charles, in bed with him and then  engaged to Hamish. Things like this do happen, but she goes out especially with Charles for a fun, "dress-selecting" outing and then sleeps with him again before her wedding. This is the marriage that came from nowhere and made no sense other than a (poor) plot device. Gareth- He wears a silly-looking vest but makes fun of Scarlett's dress. He generally has a good time, drinks, dances, and then drops dead in a startling and therefore moderately comical manner. However, his funeral is treated seriously in the film and is supposed to carry great emotional weight with the viewer. Honestly, I barely had time to learn his name and a few superficial facts about him, but there was not enough "meat" in his character development to make my eyes even begin to grow misty when he died. Charles and Henrietta- They have a couple of tearful conversations, one complete with a dressing down, no steamy encounters, but suddenly, they're walking down the aisle But all of this may have been forgivable if the movie had spent any time with the side characters before bombarding us with the montage of weddings at the end. Henrietta/ "Duckface" gets married, happily, it seems, but the audience gets not one minute with her after Charles leaves her at the altar. This film skips over almost every relationship or character development worth showing, leaving it emotionally hollow, frustrating, and ultimately forgettable. I guess screenwriter Richard Curtis was getting warmed up for Love Actually, which succeeds in all the ways that Four Weddings and a Funeral failed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Four occasions to laugh, one to cry, five to meditate about love and life ....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ElMaruecan82
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Many romantic comedies end with the two leads finally reuniting for the final kiss and realizing that they're meant to live together. Though it doesn't necessarily imply that the following step is marriage, but we can bet on a long-term commitment. Basically, "Four Weddings and a Funeral" stands above all the 'romantic comedy' genre because it doesn't take its very essence for granted and turns into a delightful social commentary about the meaning of marital commitment even questioning its compatibility with real love. Can love last for life? If not definite answers, the film provides some hints through four martial experiences and one funeral, which is an occasion to think about life and death. Mike Newell finds the perfect balance between humor, slapstick and intelligence, all of them in a typically British flavor. And one thing for sure, the film's title doesn't lie about the content since the five titular events and their direct aftermaths occupy almost 95% of the screen time. And as viewers, we're (literally) invited to follow the adventures of one joyful bunch of friends. On the top of them, there's Hugh Grant as Charles, a handsome thirty something bachelor whose penetrating blue eyes betray a vulnerable sensitivity that doesn't fit his look. There is the tiny, exuberant Charlotte Coleman as Scarlett, a gay couple, Matthew (John Hannah) and Garrett played by the scene-stealing Simon Callow. Kristin Scott Thomas plays Fiona, hiding in a sophisticated composure the grief of never having conquered Charles' heart, and last but not least, there's Tom, Jack Fleet as the goofiest and clumsiest of the bunch, which is saying a lot. We never know exactly what these people do for a living, but it doesn't matter actually. Besides, we know them enough to understand the way they feel, behave or approach life and important matters, so the rest would only fill the script with unnecessary details. Have you noticed by the way that in most rom-coms, the jobs of the two lead hardly play a role, one is an architect, and another is a cook, so what? And have you also noticed that many romantic comedies only rely on the believability of its lead couple and some supporting characters, "Four Weddings and a Funeral" is an ensemble cast movie, and even more effective because it doesn't depend on a multi-linear plot, the solidarity, the complicity between the friends is the story's heart and greatest source for gags and amusement. I insist on the ensemble cast because truth is if Hugh Grant was perfect for the role that put him in America's showbiz map, and earned him a Golden Globe, the same can hardly be said about Andie McDowell. As much as I respect and appreciate the actress, it's hard to see the same sweetheart who turned Phil Connor's heart in "Groundhog Day". She doesn't deliver a bad performance per se, but a Razzie nomination (that thankfully the film was spared of) wouldn't have surprised me. It was hard to believe that Charles would be so infatuated in a woman who doesn't seem quite sure either about love, let alone marriage. Some would think this is what united them since they would be involved in the two weddings that didn't end. But something in Carrie suggested that she was more of a gold-digger type, while Charles is more a victim of his own idealism. Unsuccessful marriages end up being more insightful than the others, (if only because they do 'end up') and one of the merit of "Four Weddings and a Funeral" is to put the notion of commitment into perspective, to revalue the meaning of living and loving someone for life. In a way, the subtext is that we are never 100% sure to love someone then marriage is not necessarily a guarantee of happiness OR if we really love one person, then marriage would be totally meaningless. That's the idea conveyed by Gareth and Matthew's who'd be shown as the most solid and sincere couple, without any ceremony to 'validate' their union. The death of Gareth invites for these questions and works as a great dramatic relief in a relatively screwball comedy, thanks to Matthew's powerful eulogy, simple but realistically heart-breaking. But I guess I was a bit too serious in my review, and beyond the whole introspective facade, "Four Weddings and a Funeral" is also a cheerful celebration of the most special day of anyone's life, the day we have to say 'yes', this magical moment that sets a before and an after in our lives, that starts with solemnity and ends up with fun, alcohol, and maybe a few years later, regrets. It also allows other people to meet their match, soul-mates or one-night hits. Weddings are the premise of countless jokes, a nice twist on the forget-the-rings gag, embarrassing best man's speeches, some acts of pure desperation and a wonderfully comic moment with Rowan Atkinson as a priest in his first wedding. His five minutes are funnier than the whole 'Mr. Bean' film, in fact, the film reminds us that the world needs marriage, if only to have a great moment of fun and joy. "Four Weddings and one Funeral" was one of the biggest hits of the glorious 1994, earning two nominations for Best Screenplay and Best Picture. The material is so fresh and new on the field of romantic comedies that it's hard to tolerate such conventional moments like a declaration of love under the rain, and a cheesy line delivered by you-know-who, and it's only forgivable because the film immediately redeems itself through the great ending credits sequence and Elton John's version of "Chapel of Love", the credits sequences perfectly captures the positive, optimistic mood of the film, and even its not-to-be-taken-so-seriously quality. And it does fit the general message of the film that after all, maybe wedding, just like life, is not to be taken so seriously, and maybe that's the best way to make it work.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hated it when I saw it in '94, loved it last night
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rooprect
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I saw this film in '94, I was expecting something a little snappier & edgier like the rom-coms of the time (such as "Singles" or "When Harry Met Sally"). Instead, its low-key, subtle, British presentation caught me off guard and left me a little bit unfulfilled. I now realize that's because I was an idiot at the time. Subtlety is this film's strength, and Hugh Grant's performance is impeccable in that regard. There aren't a lot of wisecracking zingers or situational craziness, but Hugh's portrayal of a cute, clueless, British playboy is something he does par excellence. Andie McDowell's portrayal of a disconnected, almost soulless enigma is equally compelling, although on first viewing I didn't understand the character. The comedy comes through Hugh's strained reactions to the insane situations he finds himself in. Things happen that would reduce a normal human to hysterics, but Hugh is forced to ride it out with proper British decorum. For example, there's one scene where finds himself stuck at a table with EVERY ONE of his ex-girlfriends, trying to play it off as politely as possible while they take turns freaking out at him. Something to note: Unlike films like "Harry Met Sally" and "Singles" which focus equally on the characters, this movie is essentially from Hugh's viewpoint, and Andie's character is almost peripheral. With that in mind, it's not a standard love story between two people. Instead it's about one man stumbling through the concept of romance. If you like rom-coms that take a different approach, this is a good one for you to check out. I also recommend "Forget Paris" (about what happens to a couple AFTER 'happily ever after') and "Object of Beauty" (starring Andie McDowell & John Malkovich as a pair of dysfunctional, small-time con artists in love). If you're a Hugh Grant fan, you'll love this film, period.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny, but not one of my favourites
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I had heard some morally bad things about this movie and a number of people portrayed it in a bad light. I think is was because of the prostitute incident at the time of this movie that put me off it. In fact, the prostitute incident put a number of people I knew off of Hugh Grant. Personally I don't think that it was the media's business about whether Hugh Grant was caught with a prostitute, and more so the pressure put on his girlfriend at the time to forgive him. This movie is about four weddings and a funeral. In fact, there is only one scene in the movie that is not set at a wedding or the funeral. As one can tell by the title the movie is about marriage, but the conclusion that it comes to I inevitably disagree with. The movie is based around a group of friends who are always going to weddings. In fact, it is the time of life when everybody is getting married. Charles (Hugh Grant) always sleeps in and as such is always late to weddings. That is until his own when all of his friends make damn sure that he gets up in time. The movie explores death and marriage, and at one point - the low point - the conclusion is that not everybody is going to get married. This is true as Charles concludes, after he called a wedding off because he did not really want to marry Duck Face - Henrietta, that marriage was not for him - yet he still wanted the companionship of a girl. My opinion here is not that marriage was not for him, but rather that he is so scared to make a commitment to a woman that he would rather have a relationship that he can call off easily. The funeral is of a very cheerful chap who dies at the third wedding. This chap is the oldest and commands his friends to find a partner. He dies and they come to see that not everybody is going to get married. This is not true to the movie because, as one can expect, everybody ends up happily ever after. The thing the people I know did not appreciate about this movie was the ending where they say that they can have a perfect marriage relationship without getting married. This I do not really agree with because marriage involves commitments and promises, and if you are not willing to make these promises to the person, then you should not either consider marrying this person, or living with the person as if you were married.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Mostly enjoyable - needs a different ending
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    elspeth-11
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I really enjoyed most of this movie - the funeral was devastating. And unlike many, I really do enjoy the standard Hugh Grant (which, in fairness, was not yet "standard" when this movie was new). BUT (and I'm agreeing with everyone else here) Carrie, the Andie MacDowell character, has nothing going for her. She is not appealing in any way, and she's a slag. Additionally, the wedding to Duckface is totally unmotivated, and only contrived so that he can leave her at the altar without us hating him. Here is how it should have gone. The fourth wedding should have been between Charles and Carrie - once she's divorced, there is no impediment after all. Carrie - true to character - will be getting it on with someone else by the night before the wedding. Meanwhile, Charles discovers that he is really in love with Fiona (wasn't that the point of the movie? it's what I expected to happen). The deaf character discovers both these facts and the wedding can now be played as originally scripted.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    So overrated it should be criminal
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    summerskter
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is so frustratingly forgettable. It is a romance which makes absolutely no sense to the viewer. The object of affection is a promiscuous, threesome-having, cheating, superficial, self-absorbed woman named Carrie, which Andie Macdowell plays as if she were just a breezy, soft-spoken nice girl. Andie is so uncomfortable in this role that every single line is delivered in a monotone drawl. If you can get through her last line, "Is it still raining? I hadn't noticed," while they are standing in a downpour, without laughing, my hat's off to you. Without spoiling to much, let's just say if you value romance, like actual romance involving two people getting along, spending some quality non-sex time together, you are not going to find it in this hollow, mechanical movie. And when I mean hollow, I mean so completely insincere that anyone who lives in the real world would find the characters' behavior mystifying until the ending credits. I still don't understand what this movie was trying to say. I was 100% rooting for Hugh Grant (Charles) to end up with either of the two eligible women who are actually loyal and devoted to him, and who don't treat him and his feelings dismissively throughout the entire film, as Carrie does. So terribly disappointing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Typical Plot but Atypical Setting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    copperncherrio
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love Hugh Grant. You just cannot go wrong with Hugh Grant and romantic comedies, and Four Weddings & a Funeral is the perfect chick flick of romance, humor, and most importantly GREAT CONVERSATION. There are so many little scenes and snipets that are just brilliant little skits that are wrapped around into an interesting love story. Though the love isn't compelling between the two main characters and there could be minor plot tweaks, there's a lot of great things about this British film that I'm sorry that more films can't take away from. High expectations I had, and disappointed I was not. Possibly one of the greatest romantic comedies that I've witnessed thus far. Hugh Grant was superb, the leading gal was alright.. .but there is a great supporting cast. I can't hate a well written movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny and charming
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mcjoe1614
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let's be honest here. Unless you are one of these 'true-love' fanatics then you will find romantic comedies extremely lifeless, predictable and dull. For me, that's putting it kindly. However, Richard Curtis has always had a special touch with his films which have put them a head up over the rest of the sappy Hollywood stuff. 'Four weddings and a funeral' is a British rom-com that was delightful to watch. Hugh grant is such a funny actor, you can warm to him at once ; he is a rare talent. He also has great chemistry in the movie with this American beauty who he happens to meet upon multiple weddings. If this was just a love film on its own, it would be poor . Yet what makes 'four weddings' so compelling is the hilarious comedic script that is packed with all sorts of witty comments. Grant's group of friends in the movie are hilarious, and yes even Rowan Atkinson made it into the movie (although I would call his role more of a cameo). 'Four weddings and a funeral' was so popular at its time, that it received a 'best picture' nomination which is un-heard of for a rom-com. That should give you an idea of how good this movie is. Definitely worth watching - no matter what type of person you are, there is going to be something in here that will make you laugh :)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good For What It Is!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    g-bodyl
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Four Weddings and a Funeral is a British romantic comedy that is sometimes charming, but it mostly falls flat and gets lost in the mix of all romantic comedies out there. This film is entertaining, but forgettable. Writing this review, I can hardly remember what happens in the movie. Mike Newell's film is about a bachelor named Charles and he is seemingly the best man at many weddings. At the first wedding, he meets this girl and he thinks he finally falls in love. Over the course of several more weddings and a funeral, he gets the notion that maybe he has fallen for the wrong lady. The acting is pretty good for the most part. Hugh Grant is a charming British fellow and this film introduced him to the American audience. Simon Callow and John Hannah are really good and quite funny. Andie McDowell is pretty darn awful and she sounds like she's a robot. Overall, this is a decent but entirely forgettable British comedy. It has some good moments and some boring moments. Some of the jokes are quite funny especially the one involving the band, U2. Despite this being a solid film, I can't fathom how the film was nominated for Best Picture at the Oscars. It's only a date night film at best. I rate this film 7/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Mike Newell has directed a pleasant film about the importance of love.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FilmCriticLalitRao
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Through his comedy film, "Four weddings and a funeral", British director Mike Newell gives an excellent idea about how love and marriage are viewed by English people. His film is a quest for finding true love. It also depicts the importance of love over sex in relationships involving men and women. A good film which can be watched with family involves elements which are valued by family members. From that yardstick, a film about love and marriage can be a little offensive only if has some explicit hints about sex. However, English film four weddings and a funeral deliberately avoids any unnecessary mention of sex in order to portray itself as a clean film. The choice of an American actress who is wooed by a flippant British bachelor works well for this film as Andie MacDowell and Hugh Grant remain true to their on screen portrayals. In most films, minor characters are not developed but this film gives equal importance to minor characters who help viewers to understand the importance of friends in a person's life. Lastly, four weddings and a funeral is able to impress viewers as its spreads the message that there comes a time in each person's life when he/she has to become serious about marriage and must get married before it is too late.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Four Weddings and a Funeral: And Only That
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Elise Tarter
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    While I enjoy romantic comedies as much as or more than most, I found very little to appreciate in Four Weddings and a Funeral: It flits around from wedding to wedding employing a fairly large cast of characters, which, though interesting, the viewer never gets to know. The fatal flaw of Four Weddings is that it tells us about many significant friendships, relationships, and romances but rarely shows them to us in actual character interactions or dialogue. The supposedly deep and meaningful connections between characters were actually so threadbare as to cause audience confusion or worse, indifference. Here are a few examples: Charles and Fiona- We learn that they are long-time friends, but see her carp at Charles for his lateness and then confess her love for him, which is never mentioned again hereafter. Carrie and Hamish- She's flirting with Charles, in bed with him and then  engaged to Hamish. Things like this do happen, but she goes out especially with Charles for a fun, "dress-selecting" outing and then sleeps with him again before her wedding. This is the marriage that came from nowhere and made no sense other than a (poor) plot device. Gareth- He wears a silly-looking vest but makes fun of Scarlett's dress. He generally has a good time, drinks, dances, and then drops dead in a startling and therefore moderately comical manner. However, his funeral is treated seriously in the film and is supposed to carry great emotional weight with the viewer. Honestly, I barely had time to learn his name and a few superficial facts about him, but there was not enough "meat" in his character development to make my eyes even begin to grow misty when he died. Charles and Henrietta- They have a couple of tearful conversations, one complete with a dressing down, no steamy encounters, but suddenly, they're walking down the aisle But all of this may have been forgivable if the movie had spent any time with the side characters before bombarding us with the montage of weddings at the end. Henrietta/ "Duckface" gets married, happily, it seems, but the audience gets not one minute with her after Charles leaves her at the altar. This film skips over almost every relationship or character development worth showing, leaving it emotionally hollow, frustrating, and ultimately forgettable. I guess screenwriter Richard Curtis was getting warmed up for Love Actually, which succeeds in all the ways that Four Weddings and a Funeral failed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Four occasions to laugh, one to cry, five to meditate about love and life ....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ElMaruecan82
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Many romantic comedies end with the two leads finally reuniting for the final kiss and realizing that they're meant to live together. Though it doesn't necessarily imply that the following step is marriage, but we can bet on a long-term commitment. Basically, "Four Weddings and a Funeral" stands above all the 'romantic comedy' genre because it doesn't take its very essence for granted and turns into a delightful social commentary about the meaning of marital commitment even questioning its compatibility with real love. Can love last for life? If not definite answers, the film provides some hints through four martial experiences and one funeral, which is an occasion to think about life and death. Mike Newell finds the perfect balance between humor, slapstick and intelligence, all of them in a typically British flavor. And one thing for sure, the film's title doesn't lie about the content since the five titular events and their direct aftermaths occupy almost 95% of the screen time. And as viewers, we're (literally) invited to follow the adventures of one joyful bunch of friends. On the top of them, there's Hugh Grant as Charles, a handsome thirty something bachelor whose penetrating blue eyes betray a vulnerable sensitivity that doesn't fit his look. There is the tiny, exuberant Charlotte Coleman as Scarlett, a gay couple, Matthew (John Hannah) and Garrett played by the scene-stealing Simon Callow. Kristin Scott Thomas plays Fiona, hiding in a sophisticated composure the grief of never having conquered Charles' heart, and last but not least, there's Tom, Jack Fleet as the goofiest and clumsiest of the bunch, which is saying a lot. We never know exactly what these people do for a living, but it doesn't matter actually. Besides, we know them enough to understand the way they feel, behave or approach life and important matters, so the rest would only fill the script with unnecessary details. Have you noticed by the way that in most rom-coms, the jobs of the two lead hardly play a role, one is an architect, and another is a cook, so what? And have you also noticed that many romantic comedies only rely on the believability of its lead couple and some supporting characters, "Four Weddings and a Funeral" is an ensemble cast movie, and even more effective because it doesn't depend on a multi-linear plot, the solidarity, the complicity between the friends is the story's heart and greatest source for gags and amusement. I insist on the ensemble cast because truth is if Hugh Grant was perfect for the role that put him in America's showbiz map, and earned him a Golden Globe, the same can hardly be said about Andie McDowell. As much as I respect and appreciate the actress, it's hard to see the same sweetheart who turned Phil Connor's heart in "Groundhog Day". She doesn't deliver a bad performance per se, but a Razzie nomination (that thankfully the film was spared of) wouldn't have surprised me. It was hard to believe that Charles would be so infatuated in a woman who doesn't seem quite sure either about love, let alone marriage. Some would think this is what united them since they would be involved in the two weddings that didn't end. But something in Carrie suggested that she was more of a gold-digger type, while Charles is more a victim of his own idealism. Unsuccessful marriages end up being more insightful than the others, (if only because they do 'end up') and one of the merit of "Four Weddings and a Funeral" is to put the notion of commitment into perspective, to revalue the meaning of living and loving someone for life. In a way, the subtext is that we are never 100% sure to love someone then marriage is not necessarily a guarantee of happiness OR if we really love one person, then marriage would be totally meaningless. That's the idea conveyed by Gareth and Matthew's who'd be shown as the most solid and sincere couple, without any ceremony to 'validate' their union. The death of Gareth invites for these questions and works as a great dramatic relief in a relatively screwball comedy, thanks to Matthew's powerful eulogy, simple but realistically heart-breaking. But I guess I was a bit too serious in my review, and beyond the whole introspective facade, "Four Weddings and a Funeral" is also a cheerful celebration of the most special day of anyone's life, the day we have to say 'yes', this magical moment that sets a before and an after in our lives, that starts with solemnity and ends up with fun, alcohol, and maybe a few years later, regrets. It also allows other people to meet their match, soul-mates or one-night hits. Weddings are the premise of countless jokes, a nice twist on the forget-the-rings gag, embarrassing best man's speeches, some acts of pure desperation and a wonderfully comic moment with Rowan Atkinson as a priest in his first wedding. His five minutes are funnier than the whole 'Mr. Bean' film, in fact, the film reminds us that the world needs marriage, if only to have a great moment of fun and joy. "Four Weddings and one Funeral" was one of the biggest hits of the glorious 1994, earning two nominations for Best Screenplay and Best Picture. The material is so fresh and new on the field of romantic comedies that it's hard to tolerate such conventional moments like a declaration of love under the rain, and a cheesy line delivered by you-know-who, and it's only forgivable because the film immediately redeems itself through the great ending credits sequence and Elton John's version of "Chapel of Love", the credits sequences perfectly captures the positive, optimistic mood of the film, and even its not-to-be-taken-so-seriously quality. And it does fit the general message of the film that after all, maybe wedding, just like life, is not to be taken so seriously, and maybe that's the best way to make it work.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hated it when I saw it in '94, loved it last night
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rooprect
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I saw this film in '94, I was expecting something a little snappier & edgier like the rom-coms of the time (such as "Singles" or "When Harry Met Sally"). Instead, its low-key, subtle, British presentation caught me off guard and left me a little bit unfulfilled. I now realize that's because I was an idiot at the time. Subtlety is this film's strength, and Hugh Grant's performance is impeccable in that regard. There aren't a lot of wisecracking zingers or situational craziness, but Hugh's portrayal of a cute, clueless, British playboy is something he does par excellence. Andie McDowell's portrayal of a disconnected, almost soulless enigma is equally compelling, although on first viewing I didn't understand the character. The comedy comes through Hugh's strained reactions to the insane situations he finds himself in. Things happen that would reduce a normal human to hysterics, but Hugh is forced to ride it out with proper British decorum. For example, there's one scene where finds himself stuck at a table with EVERY ONE of his ex-girlfriends, trying to play it off as politely as possible while they take turns freaking out at him. Something to note: Unlike films like "Harry Met Sally" and "Singles" which focus equally on the characters, this movie is essentially from Hugh's viewpoint, and Andie's character is almost peripheral. With that in mind, it's not a standard love story between two people. Instead it's about one man stumbling through the concept of romance. If you like rom-coms that take a different approach, this is a good one for you to check out. I also recommend "Forget Paris" (about what happens to a couple AFTER 'happily ever after') and "Object of Beauty" (starring Andie McDowell & John Malkovich as a pair of dysfunctional, small-time con artists in love). If you're a Hugh Grant fan, you'll love this film, period.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny, but not one of my favourites
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I had heard some morally bad things about this movie and a number of people portrayed it in a bad light. I think is was because of the prostitute incident at the time of this movie that put me off it. In fact, the prostitute incident put a number of people I knew off of Hugh Grant. Personally I don't think that it was the media's business about whether Hugh Grant was caught with a prostitute, and more so the pressure put on his girlfriend at the time to forgive him. This movie is about four weddings and a funeral. In fact, there is only one scene in the movie that is not set at a wedding or the funeral. As one can tell by the title the movie is about marriage, but the conclusion that it comes to I inevitably disagree with. The movie is based around a group of friends who are always going to weddings. In fact, it is the time of life when everybody is getting married. Charles (Hugh Grant) always sleeps in and as such is always late to weddings. That is until his own when all of his friends make damn sure that he gets up in time. The movie explores death and marriage, and at one point - the low point - the conclusion is that not everybody is going to get married. This is true as Charles concludes, after he called a wedding off because he did not really want to marry Duck Face - Henrietta, that marriage was not for him - yet he still wanted the companionship of a girl. My opinion here is not that marriage was not for him, but rather that he is so scared to make a commitment to a woman that he would rather have a relationship that he can call off easily. The funeral is of a very cheerful chap who dies at the third wedding. This chap is the oldest and commands his friends to find a partner. He dies and they come to see that not everybody is going to get married. This is not true to the movie because, as one can expect, everybody ends up happily ever after. The thing the people I know did not appreciate about this movie was the ending where they say that they can have a perfect marriage relationship without getting married. This I do not really agree with because marriage involves commitments and promises, and if you are not willing to make these promises to the person, then you should not either consider marrying this person, or living with the person as if you were married.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Mostly enjoyable - needs a different ending
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    elspeth-11
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I really enjoyed most of this movie - the funeral was devastating. And unlike many, I really do enjoy the standard Hugh Grant (which, in fairness, was not yet "standard" when this movie was new). BUT (and I'm agreeing with everyone else here) Carrie, the Andie MacDowell character, has nothing going for her. She is not appealing in any way, and she's a slag. Additionally, the wedding to Duckface is totally unmotivated, and only contrived so that he can leave her at the altar without us hating him. Here is how it should have gone. The fourth wedding should have been between Charles and Carrie - once she's divorced, there is no impediment after all. Carrie - true to character - will be getting it on with someone else by the night before the wedding. Meanwhile, Charles discovers that he is really in love with Fiona (wasn't that the point of the movie? it's what I expected to happen). The deaf character discovers both these facts and the wedding can now be played as originally scripted.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    So overrated it should be criminal
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    summerskter
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is so frustratingly forgettable. It is a romance which makes absolutely no sense to the viewer. The object of affection is a promiscuous, threesome-having, cheating, superficial, self-absorbed woman named Carrie, which Andie Macdowell plays as if she were just a breezy, soft-spoken nice girl. Andie is so uncomfortable in this role that every single line is delivered in a monotone drawl. If you can get through her last line, "Is it still raining? I hadn't noticed," while they are standing in a downpour, without laughing, my hat's off to you. Without spoiling to much, let's just say if you value romance, like actual romance involving two people getting along, spending some quality non-sex time together, you are not going to find it in this hollow, mechanical movie. And when I mean hollow, I mean so completely insincere that anyone who lives in the real world would find the characters' behavior mystifying until the ending credits. I still don't understand what this movie was trying to say. I was 100% rooting for Hugh Grant (Charles) to end up with either of the two eligible women who are actually loyal and devoted to him, and who don't treat him and his feelings dismissively throughout the entire film, as Carrie does. So terribly disappointing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Typical Plot but Atypical Setting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    copperncherrio
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love Hugh Grant. You just cannot go wrong with Hugh Grant and romantic comedies, and Four Weddings & a Funeral is the perfect chick flick of romance, humor, and most importantly GREAT CONVERSATION. There are so many little scenes and snipets that are just brilliant little skits that are wrapped around into an interesting love story. Though the love isn't compelling between the two main characters and there could be minor plot tweaks, there's a lot of great things about this British film that I'm sorry that more films can't take away from. High expectations I had, and disappointed I was not. Possibly one of the greatest romantic comedies that I've witnessed thus far. Hugh Grant was superb, the leading gal was alright.. .but there is a great supporting cast. I can't hate a well written movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny and charming
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mcjoe1614
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let's be honest here. Unless you are one of these 'true-love' fanatics then you will find romantic comedies extremely lifeless, predictable and dull. For me, that's putting it kindly. However, Richard Curtis has always had a special touch with his films which have put them a head up over the rest of the sappy Hollywood stuff. 'Four weddings and a funeral' is a British rom-com that was delightful to watch. Hugh grant is such a funny actor, you can warm to him at once ; he is a rare talent. He also has great chemistry in the movie with this American beauty who he happens to meet upon multiple weddings. If this was just a love film on its own, it would be poor . Yet what makes 'four weddings' so compelling is the hilarious comedic script that is packed with all sorts of witty comments. Grant's group of friends in the movie are hilarious, and yes even Rowan Atkinson made it into the movie (although I would call his role more of a cameo). 'Four weddings and a funeral' was so popular at its time, that it received a 'best picture' nomination which is un-heard of for a rom-com. That should give you an idea of how good this movie is. Definitely worth watching - no matter what type of person you are, there is going to be something in here that will make you laugh :)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good For What It Is!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    g-bodyl
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Four Weddings and a Funeral is a British romantic comedy that is sometimes charming, but it mostly falls flat and gets lost in the mix of all romantic comedies out there. This film is entertaining, but forgettable. Writing this review, I can hardly remember what happens in the movie. Mike Newell's film is about a bachelor named Charles and he is seemingly the best man at many weddings. At the first wedding, he meets this girl and he thinks he finally falls in love. Over the course of several more weddings and a funeral, he gets the notion that maybe he has fallen for the wrong lady. The acting is pretty good for the most part. Hugh Grant is a charming British fellow and this film introduced him to the American audience. Simon Callow and John Hannah are really good and quite funny. Andie McDowell is pretty darn awful and she sounds like she's a robot. Overall, this is a decent but entirely forgettable British comedy. It has some good moments and some boring moments. Some of the jokes are quite funny especially the one involving the band, U2. Despite this being a solid film, I can't fathom how the film was nominated for Best Picture at the Oscars. It's only a date night film at best. I rate this film 7/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Mike Newell has directed a pleasant film about the importance of love.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FilmCriticLalitRao
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Through his comedy film, "Four weddings and a funeral", British director Mike Newell gives an excellent idea about how love and marriage are viewed by English people. His film is a quest for finding true love. It also depicts the importance of love over sex in relationships involving men and women. A good film which can be watched with family involves elements which are valued by family members. From that yardstick, a film about love and marriage can be a little offensive only if has some explicit hints about sex. However, English film four weddings and a funeral deliberately avoids any unnecessary mention of sex in order to portray itself as a clean film. The choice of an American actress who is wooed by a flippant British bachelor works well for this film as Andie MacDowell and Hugh Grant remain true to their on screen portrayals. In most films, minor characters are not developed but this film gives equal importance to minor characters who help viewers to understand the importance of friends in a person's life. Lastly, four weddings and a funeral is able to impress viewers as its spreads the message that there comes a time in each person's life when he/she has to become serious about marriage and must get married before it is too late.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Four Weddings and a Funeral: And Only That
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Elise Tarter
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    While I enjoy romantic comedies as much as or more than most, I found very little to appreciate in Four Weddings and a Funeral: It flits around from wedding to wedding employing a fairly large cast of characters, which, though interesting, the viewer never gets to know. The fatal flaw of Four Weddings is that it tells us about many significant friendships, relationships, and romances but rarely shows them to us in actual character interactions or dialogue. The supposedly deep and meaningful connections between characters were actually so threadbare as to cause audience confusion or worse, indifference. Here are a few examples: Charles and Fiona- We learn that they are long-time friends, but see her carp at Charles for his lateness and then confess her love for him, which is never mentioned again hereafter. Carrie and Hamish- She's flirting with Charles, in bed with him and then  engaged to Hamish. Things like this do happen, but she goes out especially with Charles for a fun, "dress-selecting" outing and then sleeps with him again before her wedding. This is the marriage that came from nowhere and made no sense other than a (poor) plot device. Gareth- He wears a silly-looking vest but makes fun of Scarlett's dress. He generally has a good time, drinks, dances, and then drops dead in a startling and therefore moderately comical manner. However, his funeral is treated seriously in the film and is supposed to carry great emotional weight with the viewer. Honestly, I barely had time to learn his name and a few superficial facts about him, but there was not enough "meat" in his character development to make my eyes even begin to grow misty when he died. Charles and Henrietta- They have a couple of tearful conversations, one complete with a dressing down, no steamy encounters, but suddenly, they're walking down the aisle But all of this may have been forgivable if the movie had spent any time with the side characters before bombarding us with the montage of weddings at the end. Henrietta/ "Duckface" gets married, happily, it seems, but the audience gets not one minute with her after Charles leaves her at the altar. This film skips over almost every relationship or character development worth showing, leaving it emotionally hollow, frustrating, and ultimately forgettable. I guess screenwriter Richard Curtis was getting warmed up for Love Actually, which succeeds in all the ways that Four Weddings and a Funeral failed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Four occasions to laugh, one to cry, five to meditate about love and life ....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ElMaruecan82
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Many romantic comedies end with the two leads finally reuniting for the final kiss and realizing that they're meant to live together. Though it doesn't necessarily imply that the following step is marriage, but we can bet on a long-term commitment. Basically, "Four Weddings and a Funeral" stands above all the 'romantic comedy' genre because it doesn't take its very essence for granted and turns into a delightful social commentary about the meaning of marital commitment even questioning its compatibility with real love. Can love last for life? If not definite answers, the film provides some hints through four martial experiences and one funeral, which is an occasion to think about life and death. Mike Newell finds the perfect balance between humor, slapstick and intelligence, all of them in a typically British flavor. And one thing for sure, the film's title doesn't lie about the content since the five titular events and their direct aftermaths occupy almost 95% of the screen time. And as viewers, we're (literally) invited to follow the adventures of one joyful bunch of friends. On the top of them, there's Hugh Grant as Charles, a handsome thirty something bachelor whose penetrating blue eyes betray a vulnerable sensitivity that doesn't fit his look. There is the tiny, exuberant Charlotte Coleman as Scarlett, a gay couple, Matthew (John Hannah) and Garrett played by the scene-stealing Simon Callow. Kristin Scott Thomas plays Fiona, hiding in a sophisticated composure the grief of never having conquered Charles' heart, and last but not least, there's Tom, Jack Fleet as the goofiest and clumsiest of the bunch, which is saying a lot. We never know exactly what these people do for a living, but it doesn't matter actually. Besides, we know them enough to understand the way they feel, behave or approach life and important matters, so the rest would only fill the script with unnecessary details. Have you noticed by the way that in most rom-coms, the jobs of the two lead hardly play a role, one is an architect, and another is a cook, so what? And have you also noticed that many romantic comedies only rely on the believability of its lead couple and some supporting characters, "Four Weddings and a Funeral" is an ensemble cast movie, and even more effective because it doesn't depend on a multi-linear plot, the solidarity, the complicity between the friends is the story's heart and greatest source for gags and amusement. I insist on the ensemble cast because truth is if Hugh Grant was perfect for the role that put him in America's showbiz map, and earned him a Golden Globe, the same can hardly be said about Andie McDowell. As much as I respect and appreciate the actress, it's hard to see the same sweetheart who turned Phil Connor's heart in "Groundhog Day". She doesn't deliver a bad performance per se, but a Razzie nomination (that thankfully the film was spared of) wouldn't have surprised me. It was hard to believe that Charles would be so infatuated in a woman who doesn't seem quite sure either about love, let alone marriage. Some would think this is what united them since they would be involved in the two weddings that didn't end. But something in Carrie suggested that she was more of a gold-digger type, while Charles is more a victim of his own idealism. Unsuccessful marriages end up being more insightful than the others, (if only because they do 'end up') and one of the merit of "Four Weddings and a Funeral" is to put the notion of commitment into perspective, to revalue the meaning of living and loving someone for life. In a way, the subtext is that we are never 100% sure to love someone then marriage is not necessarily a guarantee of happiness OR if we really love one person, then marriage would be totally meaningless. That's the idea conveyed by Gareth and Matthew's who'd be shown as the most solid and sincere couple, without any ceremony to 'validate' their union. The death of Gareth invites for these questions and works as a great dramatic relief in a relatively screwball comedy, thanks to Matthew's powerful eulogy, simple but realistically heart-breaking. But I guess I was a bit too serious in my review, and beyond the whole introspective facade, "Four Weddings and a Funeral" is also a cheerful celebration of the most special day of anyone's life, the day we have to say 'yes', this magical moment that sets a before and an after in our lives, that starts with solemnity and ends up with fun, alcohol, and maybe a few years later, regrets. It also allows other people to meet their match, soul-mates or one-night hits. Weddings are the premise of countless jokes, a nice twist on the forget-the-rings gag, embarrassing best man's speeches, some acts of pure desperation and a wonderfully comic moment with Rowan Atkinson as a priest in his first wedding. His five minutes are funnier than the whole 'Mr. Bean' film, in fact, the film reminds us that the world needs marriage, if only to have a great moment of fun and joy. "Four Weddings and one Funeral" was one of the biggest hits of the glorious 1994, earning two nominations for Best Screenplay and Best Picture. The material is so fresh and new on the field of romantic comedies that it's hard to tolerate such conventional moments like a declaration of love under the rain, and a cheesy line delivered by you-know-who, and it's only forgivable because the film immediately redeems itself through the great ending credits sequence and Elton John's version of "Chapel of Love", the credits sequences perfectly captures the positive, optimistic mood of the film, and even its not-to-be-taken-so-seriously quality. And it does fit the general message of the film that after all, maybe wedding, just like life, is not to be taken so seriously, and maybe that's the best way to make it work.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hated it when I saw it in '94, loved it last night
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rooprect
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I saw this film in '94, I was expecting something a little snappier & edgier like the rom-coms of the time (such as "Singles" or "When Harry Met Sally"). Instead, its low-key, subtle, British presentation caught me off guard and left me a little bit unfulfilled. I now realize that's because I was an idiot at the time. Subtlety is this film's strength, and Hugh Grant's performance is impeccable in that regard. There aren't a lot of wisecracking zingers or situational craziness, but Hugh's portrayal of a cute, clueless, British playboy is something he does par excellence. Andie McDowell's portrayal of a disconnected, almost soulless enigma is equally compelling, although on first viewing I didn't understand the character. The comedy comes through Hugh's strained reactions to the insane situations he finds himself in. Things happen that would reduce a normal human to hysterics, but Hugh is forced to ride it out with proper British decorum. For example, there's one scene where finds himself stuck at a table with EVERY ONE of his ex-girlfriends, trying to play it off as politely as possible while they take turns freaking out at him. Something to note: Unlike films like "Harry Met Sally" and "Singles" which focus equally on the characters, this movie is essentially from Hugh's viewpoint, and Andie's character is almost peripheral. With that in mind, it's not a standard love story between two people. Instead it's about one man stumbling through the concept of romance. If you like rom-coms that take a different approach, this is a good one for you to check out. I also recommend "Forget Paris" (about what happens to a couple AFTER 'happily ever after') and "Object of Beauty" (starring Andie McDowell & John Malkovich as a pair of dysfunctional, small-time con artists in love). If you're a Hugh Grant fan, you'll love this film, period.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny, but not one of my favourites
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I had heard some morally bad things about this movie and a number of people portrayed it in a bad light. I think is was because of the prostitute incident at the time of this movie that put me off it. In fact, the prostitute incident put a number of people I knew off of Hugh Grant. Personally I don't think that it was the media's business about whether Hugh Grant was caught with a prostitute, and more so the pressure put on his girlfriend at the time to forgive him. This movie is about four weddings and a funeral. In fact, there is only one scene in the movie that is not set at a wedding or the funeral. As one can tell by the title the movie is about marriage, but the conclusion that it comes to I inevitably disagree with. The movie is based around a group of friends who are always going to weddings. In fact, it is the time of life when everybody is getting married. Charles (Hugh Grant) always sleeps in and as such is always late to weddings. That is until his own when all of his friends make damn sure that he gets up in time. The movie explores death and marriage, and at one point - the low point - the conclusion is that not everybody is going to get married. This is true as Charles concludes, after he called a wedding off because he did not really want to marry Duck Face - Henrietta, that marriage was not for him - yet he still wanted the companionship of a girl. My opinion here is not that marriage was not for him, but rather that he is so scared to make a commitment to a woman that he would rather have a relationship that he can call off easily. The funeral is of a very cheerful chap who dies at the third wedding. This chap is the oldest and commands his friends to find a partner. He dies and they come to see that not everybody is going to get married. This is not true to the movie because, as one can expect, everybody ends up happily ever after. The thing the people I know did not appreciate about this movie was the ending where they say that they can have a perfect marriage relationship without getting married. This I do not really agree with because marriage involves commitments and promises, and if you are not willing to make these promises to the person, then you should not either consider marrying this person, or living with the person as if you were married.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Mostly enjoyable - needs a different ending
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    elspeth-11
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I really enjoyed most of this movie - the funeral was devastating. And unlike many, I really do enjoy the standard Hugh Grant (which, in fairness, was not yet "standard" when this movie was new). BUT (and I'm agreeing with everyone else here) Carrie, the Andie MacDowell character, has nothing going for her. She is not appealing in any way, and she's a slag. Additionally, the wedding to Duckface is totally unmotivated, and only contrived so that he can leave her at the altar without us hating him. Here is how it should have gone. The fourth wedding should have been between Charles and Carrie - once she's divorced, there is no impediment after all. Carrie - true to character - will be getting it on with someone else by the night before the wedding. Meanwhile, Charles discovers that he is really in love with Fiona (wasn't that the point of the movie? it's what I expected to happen). The deaf character discovers both these facts and the wedding can now be played as originally scripted.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    So overrated it should be criminal
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    summerskter
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is so frustratingly forgettable. It is a romance which makes absolutely no sense to the viewer. The object of affection is a promiscuous, threesome-having, cheating, superficial, self-absorbed woman named Carrie, which Andie Macdowell plays as if she were just a breezy, soft-spoken nice girl. Andie is so uncomfortable in this role that every single line is delivered in a monotone drawl. If you can get through her last line, "Is it still raining? I hadn't noticed," while they are standing in a downpour, without laughing, my hat's off to you. Without spoiling to much, let's just say if you value romance, like actual romance involving two people getting along, spending some quality non-sex time together, you are not going to find it in this hollow, mechanical movie. And when I mean hollow, I mean so completely insincere that anyone who lives in the real world would find the characters' behavior mystifying until the ending credits. I still don't understand what this movie was trying to say. I was 100% rooting for Hugh Grant (Charles) to end up with either of the two eligible women who are actually loyal and devoted to him, and who don't treat him and his feelings dismissively throughout the entire film, as Carrie does. So terribly disappointing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Typical Plot but Atypical Setting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    copperncherrio
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love Hugh Grant. You just cannot go wrong with Hugh Grant and romantic comedies, and Four Weddings & a Funeral is the perfect chick flick of romance, humor, and most importantly GREAT CONVERSATION. There are so many little scenes and snipets that are just brilliant little skits that are wrapped around into an interesting love story. Though the love isn't compelling between the two main characters and there could be minor plot tweaks, there's a lot of great things about this British film that I'm sorry that more films can't take away from. High expectations I had, and disappointed I was not. Possibly one of the greatest romantic comedies that I've witnessed thus far. Hugh Grant was superb, the leading gal was alright.. .but there is a great supporting cast. I can't hate a well written movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny and charming
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mcjoe1614
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let's be honest here. Unless you are one of these 'true-love' fanatics then you will find romantic comedies extremely lifeless, predictable and dull. For me, that's putting it kindly. However, Richard Curtis has always had a special touch with his films which have put them a head up over the rest of the sappy Hollywood stuff. 'Four weddings and a funeral' is a British rom-com that was delightful to watch. Hugh grant is such a funny actor, you can warm to him at once ; he is a rare talent. He also has great chemistry in the movie with this American beauty who he happens to meet upon multiple weddings. If this was just a love film on its own, it would be poor . Yet what makes 'four weddings' so compelling is the hilarious comedic script that is packed with all sorts of witty comments. Grant's group of friends in the movie are hilarious, and yes even Rowan Atkinson made it into the movie (although I would call his role more of a cameo). 'Four weddings and a funeral' was so popular at its time, that it received a 'best picture' nomination which is un-heard of for a rom-com. That should give you an idea of how good this movie is. Definitely worth watching - no matter what type of person you are, there is going to be something in here that will make you laugh :)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good For What It Is!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    g-bodyl
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Four Weddings and a Funeral is a British romantic comedy that is sometimes charming, but it mostly falls flat and gets lost in the mix of all romantic comedies out there. This film is entertaining, but forgettable. Writing this review, I can hardly remember what happens in the movie. Mike Newell's film is about a bachelor named Charles and he is seemingly the best man at many weddings. At the first wedding, he meets this girl and he thinks he finally falls in love. Over the course of several more weddings and a funeral, he gets the notion that maybe he has fallen for the wrong lady. The acting is pretty good for the most part. Hugh Grant is a charming British fellow and this film introduced him to the American audience. Simon Callow and John Hannah are really good and quite funny. Andie McDowell is pretty darn awful and she sounds like she's a robot. Overall, this is a decent but entirely forgettable British comedy. It has some good moments and some boring moments. Some of the jokes are quite funny especially the one involving the band, U2. Despite this being a solid film, I can't fathom how the film was nominated for Best Picture at the Oscars. It's only a date night film at best. I rate this film 7/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Mike Newell has directed a pleasant film about the importance of love.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FilmCriticLalitRao
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Through his comedy film, "Four weddings and a funeral", British director Mike Newell gives an excellent idea about how love and marriage are viewed by English people. His film is a quest for finding true love. It also depicts the importance of love over sex in relationships involving men and women. A good film which can be watched with family involves elements which are valued by family members. From that yardstick, a film about love and marriage can be a little offensive only if has some explicit hints about sex. However, English film four weddings and a funeral deliberately avoids any unnecessary mention of sex in order to portray itself as a clean film. The choice of an American actress who is wooed by a flippant British bachelor works well for this film as Andie MacDowell and Hugh Grant remain true to their on screen portrayals. In most films, minor characters are not developed but this film gives equal importance to minor characters who help viewers to understand the importance of friends in a person's life. Lastly, four weddings and a funeral is able to impress viewers as its spreads the message that there comes a time in each person's life when he/she has to become serious about marriage and must get married before it is too late.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Four Weddings and a Funeral: And Only That
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Elise Tarter
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    While I enjoy romantic comedies as much as or more than most, I found very little to appreciate in Four Weddings and a Funeral: It flits around from wedding to wedding employing a fairly large cast of characters, which, though interesting, the viewer never gets to know. The fatal flaw of Four Weddings is that it tells us about many significant friendships, relationships, and romances but rarely shows them to us in actual character interactions or dialogue. The supposedly deep and meaningful connections between characters were actually so threadbare as to cause audience confusion or worse, indifference. Here are a few examples: Charles and Fiona- We learn that they are long-time friends, but see her carp at Charles for his lateness and then confess her love for him, which is never mentioned again hereafter. Carrie and Hamish- She's flirting with Charles, in bed with him and then  engaged to Hamish. Things like this do happen, but she goes out especially with Charles for a fun, "dress-selecting" outing and then sleeps with him again before her wedding. This is the marriage that came from nowhere and made no sense other than a (poor) plot device. Gareth- He wears a silly-looking vest but makes fun of Scarlett's dress. He generally has a good time, drinks, dances, and then drops dead in a startling and therefore moderately comical manner. However, his funeral is treated seriously in the film and is supposed to carry great emotional weight with the viewer. Honestly, I barely had time to learn his name and a few superficial facts about him, but there was not enough "meat" in his character development to make my eyes even begin to grow misty when he died. Charles and Henrietta- They have a couple of tearful conversations, one complete with a dressing down, no steamy encounters, but suddenly, they're walking down the aisle But all of this may have been forgivable if the movie had spent any time with the side characters before bombarding us with the montage of weddings at the end. Henrietta/ "Duckface" gets married, happily, it seems, but the audience gets not one minute with her after Charles leaves her at the altar. This film skips over almost every relationship or character development worth showing, leaving it emotionally hollow, frustrating, and ultimately forgettable. I guess screenwriter Richard Curtis was getting warmed up for Love Actually, which succeeds in all the ways that Four Weddings and a Funeral failed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Four occasions to laugh, one to cry, five to meditate about love and life ....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ElMaruecan82
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Many romantic comedies end with the two leads finally reuniting for the final kiss and realizing that they're meant to live together. Though it doesn't necessarily imply that the following step is marriage, but we can bet on a long-term commitment. Basically, "Four Weddings and a Funeral" stands above all the 'romantic comedy' genre because it doesn't take its very essence for granted and turns into a delightful social commentary about the meaning of marital commitment even questioning its compatibility with real love. Can love last for life? If not definite answers, the film provides some hints through four martial experiences and one funeral, which is an occasion to think about life and death. Mike Newell finds the perfect balance between humor, slapstick and intelligence, all of them in a typically British flavor. And one thing for sure, the film's title doesn't lie about the content since the five titular events and their direct aftermaths occupy almost 95% of the screen time. And as viewers, we're (literally) invited to follow the adventures of one joyful bunch of friends. On the top of them, there's Hugh Grant as Charles, a handsome thirty something bachelor whose penetrating blue eyes betray a vulnerable sensitivity that doesn't fit his look. There is the tiny, exuberant Charlotte Coleman as Scarlett, a gay couple, Matthew (John Hannah) and Garrett played by the scene-stealing Simon Callow. Kristin Scott Thomas plays Fiona, hiding in a sophisticated composure the grief of never having conquered Charles' heart, and last but not least, there's Tom, Jack Fleet as the goofiest and clumsiest of the bunch, which is saying a lot. We never know exactly what these people do for a living, but it doesn't matter actually. Besides, we know them enough to understand the way they feel, behave or approach life and important matters, so the rest would only fill the script with unnecessary details. Have you noticed by the way that in most rom-coms, the jobs of the two lead hardly play a role, one is an architect, and another is a cook, so what? And have you also noticed that many romantic comedies only rely on the believability of its lead couple and some supporting characters, "Four Weddings and a Funeral" is an ensemble cast movie, and even more effective because it doesn't depend on a multi-linear plot, the solidarity, the complicity between the friends is the story's heart and greatest source for gags and amusement. I insist on the ensemble cast because truth is if Hugh Grant was perfect for the role that put him in America's showbiz map, and earned him a Golden Globe, the same can hardly be said about Andie McDowell. As much as I respect and appreciate the actress, it's hard to see the same sweetheart who turned Phil Connor's heart in "Groundhog Day". She doesn't deliver a bad performance per se, but a Razzie nomination (that thankfully the film was spared of) wouldn't have surprised me. It was hard to believe that Charles would be so infatuated in a woman who doesn't seem quite sure either about love, let alone marriage. Some would think this is what united them since they would be involved in the two weddings that didn't end. But something in Carrie suggested that she was more of a gold-digger type, while Charles is more a victim of his own idealism. Unsuccessful marriages end up being more insightful than the others, (if only because they do 'end up') and one of the merit of "Four Weddings and a Funeral" is to put the notion of commitment into perspective, to revalue the meaning of living and loving someone for life. In a way, the subtext is that we are never 100% sure to love someone then marriage is not necessarily a guarantee of happiness OR if we really love one person, then marriage would be totally meaningless. That's the idea conveyed by Gareth and Matthew's who'd be shown as the most solid and sincere couple, without any ceremony to 'validate' their union. The death of Gareth invites for these questions and works as a great dramatic relief in a relatively screwball comedy, thanks to Matthew's powerful eulogy, simple but realistically heart-breaking. But I guess I was a bit too serious in my review, and beyond the whole introspective facade, "Four Weddings and a Funeral" is also a cheerful celebration of the most special day of anyone's life, the day we have to say 'yes', this magical moment that sets a before and an after in our lives, that starts with solemnity and ends up with fun, alcohol, and maybe a few years later, regrets. It also allows other people to meet their match, soul-mates or one-night hits. Weddings are the premise of countless jokes, a nice twist on the forget-the-rings gag, embarrassing best man's speeches, some acts of pure desperation and a wonderfully comic moment with Rowan Atkinson as a priest in his first wedding. His five minutes are funnier than the whole 'Mr. Bean' film, in fact, the film reminds us that the world needs marriage, if only to have a great moment of fun and joy. "Four Weddings and one Funeral" was one of the biggest hits of the glorious 1994, earning two nominations for Best Screenplay and Best Picture. The material is so fresh and new on the field of romantic comedies that it's hard to tolerate such conventional moments like a declaration of love under the rain, and a cheesy line delivered by you-know-who, and it's only forgivable because the film immediately redeems itself through the great ending credits sequence and Elton John's version of "Chapel of Love", the credits sequences perfectly captures the positive, optimistic mood of the film, and even its not-to-be-taken-so-seriously quality. And it does fit the general message of the film that after all, maybe wedding, just like life, is not to be taken so seriously, and maybe that's the best way to make it work.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hated it when I saw it in '94, loved it last night
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rooprect
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I saw this film in '94, I was expecting something a little snappier & edgier like the rom-coms of the time (such as "Singles" or "When Harry Met Sally"). Instead, its low-key, subtle, British presentation caught me off guard and left me a little bit unfulfilled. I now realize that's because I was an idiot at the time. Subtlety is this film's strength, and Hugh Grant's performance is impeccable in that regard. There aren't a lot of wisecracking zingers or situational craziness, but Hugh's portrayal of a cute, clueless, British playboy is something he does par excellence. Andie McDowell's portrayal of a disconnected, almost soulless enigma is equally compelling, although on first viewing I didn't understand the character. The comedy comes through Hugh's strained reactions to the insane situations he finds himself in. Things happen that would reduce a normal human to hysterics, but Hugh is forced to ride it out with proper British decorum. For example, there's one scene where finds himself stuck at a table with EVERY ONE of his ex-girlfriends, trying to play it off as politely as possible while they take turns freaking out at him. Something to note: Unlike films like "Harry Met Sally" and "Singles" which focus equally on the characters, this movie is essentially from Hugh's viewpoint, and Andie's character is almost peripheral. With that in mind, it's not a standard love story between two people. Instead it's about one man stumbling through the concept of romance. If you like rom-coms that take a different approach, this is a good one for you to check out. I also recommend "Forget Paris" (about what happens to a couple AFTER 'happily ever after') and "Object of Beauty" (starring Andie McDowell & John Malkovich as a pair of dysfunctional, small-time con artists in love). If you're a Hugh Grant fan, you'll love this film, period.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny, but not one of my favourites
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I had heard some morally bad things about this movie and a number of people portrayed it in a bad light. I think is was because of the prostitute incident at the time of this movie that put me off it. In fact, the prostitute incident put a number of people I knew off of Hugh Grant. Personally I don't think that it was the media's business about whether Hugh Grant was caught with a prostitute, and more so the pressure put on his girlfriend at the time to forgive him. This movie is about four weddings and a funeral. In fact, there is only one scene in the movie that is not set at a wedding or the funeral. As one can tell by the title the movie is about marriage, but the conclusion that it comes to I inevitably disagree with. The movie is based around a group of friends who are always going to weddings. In fact, it is the time of life when everybody is getting married. Charles (Hugh Grant) always sleeps in and as such is always late to weddings. That is until his own when all of his friends make damn sure that he gets up in time. The movie explores death and marriage, and at one point - the low point - the conclusion is that not everybody is going to get married. This is true as Charles concludes, after he called a wedding off because he did not really want to marry Duck Face - Henrietta, that marriage was not for him - yet he still wanted the companionship of a girl. My opinion here is not that marriage was not for him, but rather that he is so scared to make a commitment to a woman that he would rather have a relationship that he can call off easily. The funeral is of a very cheerful chap who dies at the third wedding. This chap is the oldest and commands his friends to find a partner. He dies and they come to see that not everybody is going to get married. This is not true to the movie because, as one can expect, everybody ends up happily ever after. The thing the people I know did not appreciate about this movie was the ending where they say that they can have a perfect marriage relationship without getting married. This I do not really agree with because marriage involves commitments and promises, and if you are not willing to make these promises to the person, then you should not either consider marrying this person, or living with the person as if you were married.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Mostly enjoyable - needs a different ending
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    elspeth-11
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I really enjoyed most of this movie - the funeral was devastating. And unlike many, I really do enjoy the standard Hugh Grant (which, in fairness, was not yet "standard" when this movie was new). BUT (and I'm agreeing with everyone else here) Carrie, the Andie MacDowell character, has nothing going for her. She is not appealing in any way, and she's a slag. Additionally, the wedding to Duckface is totally unmotivated, and only contrived so that he can leave her at the altar without us hating him. Here is how it should have gone. The fourth wedding should have been between Charles and Carrie - once she's divorced, there is no impediment after all. Carrie - true to character - will be getting it on with someone else by the night before the wedding. Meanwhile, Charles discovers that he is really in love with Fiona (wasn't that the point of the movie? it's what I expected to happen). The deaf character discovers both these facts and the wedding can now be played as originally scripted.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    So overrated it should be criminal
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    summerskter
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is so frustratingly forgettable. It is a romance which makes absolutely no sense to the viewer. The object of affection is a promiscuous, threesome-having, cheating, superficial, self-absorbed woman named Carrie, which Andie Macdowell plays as if she were just a breezy, soft-spoken nice girl. Andie is so uncomfortable in this role that every single line is delivered in a monotone drawl. If you can get through her last line, "Is it still raining? I hadn't noticed," while they are standing in a downpour, without laughing, my hat's off to you. Without spoiling to much, let's just say if you value romance, like actual romance involving two people getting along, spending some quality non-sex time together, you are not going to find it in this hollow, mechanical movie. And when I mean hollow, I mean so completely insincere that anyone who lives in the real world would find the characters' behavior mystifying until the ending credits. I still don't understand what this movie was trying to say. I was 100% rooting for Hugh Grant (Charles) to end up with either of the two eligible women who are actually loyal and devoted to him, and who don't treat him and his feelings dismissively throughout the entire film, as Carrie does. So terribly disappointing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Typical Plot but Atypical Setting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    copperncherrio
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love Hugh Grant. You just cannot go wrong with Hugh Grant and romantic comedies, and Four Weddings & a Funeral is the perfect chick flick of romance, humor, and most importantly GREAT CONVERSATION. There are so many little scenes and snipets that are just brilliant little skits that are wrapped around into an interesting love story. Though the love isn't compelling between the two main characters and there could be minor plot tweaks, there's a lot of great things about this British film that I'm sorry that more films can't take away from. High expectations I had, and disappointed I was not. Possibly one of the greatest romantic comedies that I've witnessed thus far. Hugh Grant was superb, the leading gal was alright.. .but there is a great supporting cast. I can't hate a well written movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny and charming
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mcjoe1614
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let's be honest here. Unless you are one of these 'true-love' fanatics then you will find romantic comedies extremely lifeless, predictable and dull. For me, that's putting it kindly. However, Richard Curtis has always had a special touch with his films which have put them a head up over the rest of the sappy Hollywood stuff. 'Four weddings and a funeral' is a British rom-com that was delightful to watch. Hugh grant is such a funny actor, you can warm to him at once ; he is a rare talent. He also has great chemistry in the movie with this American beauty who he happens to meet upon multiple weddings. If this was just a love film on its own, it would be poor . Yet what makes 'four weddings' so compelling is the hilarious comedic script that is packed with all sorts of witty comments. Grant's group of friends in the movie are hilarious, and yes even Rowan Atkinson made it into the movie (although I would call his role more of a cameo). 'Four weddings and a funeral' was so popular at its time, that it received a 'best picture' nomination which is un-heard of for a rom-com. That should give you an idea of how good this movie is. Definitely worth watching - no matter what type of person you are, there is going to be something in here that will make you laugh :)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good For What It Is!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    g-bodyl
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Four Weddings and a Funeral is a British romantic comedy that is sometimes charming, but it mostly falls flat and gets lost in the mix of all romantic comedies out there. This film is entertaining, but forgettable. Writing this review, I can hardly remember what happens in the movie. Mike Newell's film is about a bachelor named Charles and he is seemingly the best man at many weddings. At the first wedding, he meets this girl and he thinks he finally falls in love. Over the course of several more weddings and a funeral, he gets the notion that maybe he has fallen for the wrong lady. The acting is pretty good for the most part. Hugh Grant is a charming British fellow and this film introduced him to the American audience. Simon Callow and John Hannah are really good and quite funny. Andie McDowell is pretty darn awful and she sounds like she's a robot. Overall, this is a decent but entirely forgettable British comedy. It has some good moments and some boring moments. Some of the jokes are quite funny especially the one involving the band, U2. Despite this being a solid film, I can't fathom how the film was nominated for Best Picture at the Oscars. It's only a date night film at best. I rate this film 7/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Mike Newell has directed a pleasant film about the importance of love.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FilmCriticLalitRao
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Through his comedy film, "Four weddings and a funeral", British director Mike Newell gives an excellent idea about how love and marriage are viewed by English people. His film is a quest for finding true love. It also depicts the importance of love over sex in relationships involving men and women. A good film which can be watched with family involves elements which are valued by family members. From that yardstick, a film about love and marriage can be a little offensive only if has some explicit hints about sex. However, English film four weddings and a funeral deliberately avoids any unnecessary mention of sex in order to portray itself as a clean film. The choice of an American actress who is wooed by a flippant British bachelor works well for this film as Andie MacDowell and Hugh Grant remain true to their on screen portrayals. In most films, minor characters are not developed but this film gives equal importance to minor characters who help viewers to understand the importance of friends in a person's life. Lastly, four weddings and a funeral is able to impress viewers as its spreads the message that there comes a time in each person's life when he/she has to become serious about marriage and must get married before it is too late.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Four Weddings and a Funeral: And Only That
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Elise Tarter
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    While I enjoy romantic comedies as much as or more than most, I found very little to appreciate in Four Weddings and a Funeral: It flits around from wedding to wedding employing a fairly large cast of characters, which, though interesting, the viewer never gets to know. The fatal flaw of Four Weddings is that it tells us about many significant friendships, relationships, and romances but rarely shows them to us in actual character interactions or dialogue. The supposedly deep and meaningful connections between characters were actually so threadbare as to cause audience confusion or worse, indifference. Here are a few examples: Charles and Fiona- We learn that they are long-time friends, but see her carp at Charles for his lateness and then confess her love for him, which is never mentioned again hereafter. Carrie and Hamish- She's flirting with Charles, in bed with him and then  engaged to Hamish. Things like this do happen, but she goes out especially with Charles for a fun, "dress-selecting" outing and then sleeps with him again before her wedding. This is the marriage that came from nowhere and made no sense other than a (poor) plot device. Gareth- He wears a silly-looking vest but makes fun of Scarlett's dress. He generally has a good time, drinks, dances, and then drops dead in a startling and therefore moderately comical manner. However, his funeral is treated seriously in the film and is supposed to carry great emotional weight with the viewer. Honestly, I barely had time to learn his name and a few superficial facts about him, but there was not enough "meat" in his character development to make my eyes even begin to grow misty when he died. Charles and Henrietta- They have a couple of tearful conversations, one complete with a dressing down, no steamy encounters, but suddenly, they're walking down the aisle But all of this may have been forgivable if the movie had spent any time with the side characters before bombarding us with the montage of weddings at the end. Henrietta/ "Duckface" gets married, happily, it seems, but the audience gets not one minute with her after Charles leaves her at the altar. This film skips over almost every relationship or character development worth showing, leaving it emotionally hollow, frustrating, and ultimately forgettable. I guess screenwriter Richard Curtis was getting warmed up for Love Actually, which succeeds in all the ways that Four Weddings and a Funeral failed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Four occasions to laugh, one to cry, five to meditate about love and life ....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ElMaruecan82
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Many romantic comedies end with the two leads finally reuniting for the final kiss and realizing that they're meant to live together. Though it doesn't necessarily imply that the following step is marriage, but we can bet on a long-term commitment. Basically, "Four Weddings and a Funeral" stands above all the 'romantic comedy' genre because it doesn't take its very essence for granted and turns into a delightful social commentary about the meaning of marital commitment even questioning its compatibility with real love. Can love last for life? If not definite answers, the film provides some hints through four martial experiences and one funeral, which is an occasion to think about life and death. Mike Newell finds the perfect balance between humor, slapstick and intelligence, all of them in a typically British flavor. And one thing for sure, the film's title doesn't lie about the content since the five titular events and their direct aftermaths occupy almost 95% of the screen time. And as viewers, we're (literally) invited to follow the adventures of one joyful bunch of friends. On the top of them, there's Hugh Grant as Charles, a handsome thirty something bachelor whose penetrating blue eyes betray a vulnerable sensitivity that doesn't fit his look. There is the tiny, exuberant Charlotte Coleman as Scarlett, a gay couple, Matthew (John Hannah) and Garrett played by the scene-stealing Simon Callow. Kristin Scott Thomas plays Fiona, hiding in a sophisticated composure the grief of never having conquered Charles' heart, and last but not least, there's Tom, Jack Fleet as the goofiest and clumsiest of the bunch, which is saying a lot. We never know exactly what these people do for a living, but it doesn't matter actually. Besides, we know them enough to understand the way they feel, behave or approach life and important matters, so the rest would only fill the script with unnecessary details. Have you noticed by the way that in most rom-coms, the jobs of the two lead hardly play a role, one is an architect, and another is a cook, so what? And have you also noticed that many romantic comedies only rely on the believability of its lead couple and some supporting characters, "Four Weddings and a Funeral" is an ensemble cast movie, and even more effective because it doesn't depend on a multi-linear plot, the solidarity, the complicity between the friends is the story's heart and greatest source for gags and amusement. I insist on the ensemble cast because truth is if Hugh Grant was perfect for the role that put him in America's showbiz map, and earned him a Golden Globe, the same can hardly be said about Andie McDowell. As much as I respect and appreciate the actress, it's hard to see the same sweetheart who turned Phil Connor's heart in "Groundhog Day". She doesn't deliver a bad performance per se, but a Razzie nomination (that thankfully the film was spared of) wouldn't have surprised me. It was hard to believe that Charles would be so infatuated in a woman who doesn't seem quite sure either about love, let alone marriage. Some would think this is what united them since they would be involved in the two weddings that didn't end. But something in Carrie suggested that she was more of a gold-digger type, while Charles is more a victim of his own idealism. Unsuccessful marriages end up being more insightful than the others, (if only because they do 'end up') and one of the merit of "Four Weddings and a Funeral" is to put the notion of commitment into perspective, to revalue the meaning of living and loving someone for life. In a way, the subtext is that we are never 100% sure to love someone then marriage is not necessarily a guarantee of happiness OR if we really love one person, then marriage would be totally meaningless. That's the idea conveyed by Gareth and Matthew's who'd be shown as the most solid and sincere couple, without any ceremony to 'validate' their union. The death of Gareth invites for these questions and works as a great dramatic relief in a relatively screwball comedy, thanks to Matthew's powerful eulogy, simple but realistically heart-breaking. But I guess I was a bit too serious in my review, and beyond the whole introspective facade, "Four Weddings and a Funeral" is also a cheerful celebration of the most special day of anyone's life, the day we have to say 'yes', this magical moment that sets a before and an after in our lives, that starts with solemnity and ends up with fun, alcohol, and maybe a few years later, regrets. It also allows other people to meet their match, soul-mates or one-night hits. Weddings are the premise of countless jokes, a nice twist on the forget-the-rings gag, embarrassing best man's speeches, some acts of pure desperation and a wonderfully comic moment with Rowan Atkinson as a priest in his first wedding. His five minutes are funnier than the whole 'Mr. Bean' film, in fact, the film reminds us that the world needs marriage, if only to have a great moment of fun and joy. "Four Weddings and one Funeral" was one of the biggest hits of the glorious 1994, earning two nominations for Best Screenplay and Best Picture. The material is so fresh and new on the field of romantic comedies that it's hard to tolerate such conventional moments like a declaration of love under the rain, and a cheesy line delivered by you-know-who, and it's only forgivable because the film immediately redeems itself through the great ending credits sequence and Elton John's version of "Chapel of Love", the credits sequences perfectly captures the positive, optimistic mood of the film, and even its not-to-be-taken-so-seriously quality. And it does fit the general message of the film that after all, maybe wedding, just like life, is not to be taken so seriously, and maybe that's the best way to make it work.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hated it when I saw it in '94, loved it last night
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rooprect
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I saw this film in '94, I was expecting something a little snappier & edgier like the rom-coms of the time (such as "Singles" or "When Harry Met Sally"). Instead, its low-key, subtle, British presentation caught me off guard and left me a little bit unfulfilled. I now realize that's because I was an idiot at the time. Subtlety is this film's strength, and Hugh Grant's performance is impeccable in that regard. There aren't a lot of wisecracking zingers or situational craziness, but Hugh's portrayal of a cute, clueless, British playboy is something he does par excellence. Andie McDowell's portrayal of a disconnected, almost soulless enigma is equally compelling, although on first viewing I didn't understand the character. The comedy comes through Hugh's strained reactions to the insane situations he finds himself in. Things happen that would reduce a normal human to hysterics, but Hugh is forced to ride it out with proper British decorum. For example, there's one scene where finds himself stuck at a table with EVERY ONE of his ex-girlfriends, trying to play it off as politely as possible while they take turns freaking out at him. Something to note: Unlike films like "Harry Met Sally" and "Singles" which focus equally on the characters, this movie is essentially from Hugh's viewpoint, and Andie's character is almost peripheral. With that in mind, it's not a standard love story between two people. Instead it's about one man stumbling through the concept of romance. If you like rom-coms that take a different approach, this is a good one for you to check out. I also recommend "Forget Paris" (about what happens to a couple AFTER 'happily ever after') and "Object of Beauty" (starring Andie McDowell & John Malkovich as a pair of dysfunctional, small-time con artists in love). If you're a Hugh Grant fan, you'll love this film, period.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny, but not one of my favourites
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I had heard some morally bad things about this movie and a number of people portrayed it in a bad light. I think is was because of the prostitute incident at the time of this movie that put me off it. In fact, the prostitute incident put a number of people I knew off of Hugh Grant. Personally I don't think that it was the media's business about whether Hugh Grant was caught with a prostitute, and more so the pressure put on his girlfriend at the time to forgive him. This movie is about four weddings and a funeral. In fact, there is only one scene in the movie that is not set at a wedding or the funeral. As one can tell by the title the movie is about marriage, but the conclusion that it comes to I inevitably disagree with. The movie is based around a group of friends who are always going to weddings. In fact, it is the time of life when everybody is getting married. Charles (Hugh Grant) always sleeps in and as such is always late to weddings. That is until his own when all of his friends make damn sure that he gets up in time. The movie explores death and marriage, and at one point - the low point - the conclusion is that not everybody is going to get married. This is true as Charles concludes, after he called a wedding off because he did not really want to marry Duck Face - Henrietta, that marriage was not for him - yet he still wanted the companionship of a girl. My opinion here is not that marriage was not for him, but rather that he is so scared to make a commitment to a woman that he would rather have a relationship that he can call off easily. The funeral is of a very cheerful chap who dies at the third wedding. This chap is the oldest and commands his friends to find a partner. He dies and they come to see that not everybody is going to get married. This is not true to the movie because, as one can expect, everybody ends up happily ever after. The thing the people I know did not appreciate about this movie was the ending where they say that they can have a perfect marriage relationship without getting married. This I do not really agree with because marriage involves commitments and promises, and if you are not willing to make these promises to the person, then you should not either consider marrying this person, or living with the person as if you were married.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Mostly enjoyable - needs a different ending
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    elspeth-11
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I really enjoyed most of this movie - the funeral was devastating. And unlike many, I really do enjoy the standard Hugh Grant (which, in fairness, was not yet "standard" when this movie was new). BUT (and I'm agreeing with everyone else here) Carrie, the Andie MacDowell character, has nothing going for her. She is not appealing in any way, and she's a slag. Additionally, the wedding to Duckface is totally unmotivated, and only contrived so that he can leave her at the altar without us hating him. Here is how it should have gone. The fourth wedding should have been between Charles and Carrie - once she's divorced, there is no impediment after all. Carrie - true to character - will be getting it on with someone else by the night before the wedding. Meanwhile, Charles discovers that he is really in love with Fiona (wasn't that the point of the movie? it's what I expected to happen). The deaf character discovers both these facts and the wedding can now be played as originally scripted.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    So overrated it should be criminal
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    summerskter
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is so frustratingly forgettable. It is a romance which makes absolutely no sense to the viewer. The object of affection is a promiscuous, threesome-having, cheating, superficial, self-absorbed woman named Carrie, which Andie Macdowell plays as if she were just a breezy, soft-spoken nice girl. Andie is so uncomfortable in this role that every single line is delivered in a monotone drawl. If you can get through her last line, "Is it still raining? I hadn't noticed," while they are standing in a downpour, without laughing, my hat's off to you. Without spoiling to much, let's just say if you value romance, like actual romance involving two people getting along, spending some quality non-sex time together, you are not going to find it in this hollow, mechanical movie. And when I mean hollow, I mean so completely insincere that anyone who lives in the real world would find the characters' behavior mystifying until the ending credits. I still don't understand what this movie was trying to say. I was 100% rooting for Hugh Grant (Charles) to end up with either of the two eligible women who are actually loyal and devoted to him, and who don't treat him and his feelings dismissively throughout the entire film, as Carrie does. So terribly disappointing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Typical Plot but Atypical Setting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    copperncherrio
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love Hugh Grant. You just cannot go wrong with Hugh Grant and romantic comedies, and Four Weddings & a Funeral is the perfect chick flick of romance, humor, and most importantly GREAT CONVERSATION. There are so many little scenes and snipets that are just brilliant little skits that are wrapped around into an interesting love story. Though the love isn't compelling between the two main characters and there could be minor plot tweaks, there's a lot of great things about this British film that I'm sorry that more films can't take away from. High expectations I had, and disappointed I was not. Possibly one of the greatest romantic comedies that I've witnessed thus far. Hugh Grant was superb, the leading gal was alright.. .but there is a great supporting cast. I can't hate a well written movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny and charming
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mcjoe1614
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let's be honest here. Unless you are one of these 'true-love' fanatics then you will find romantic comedies extremely lifeless, predictable and dull. For me, that's putting it kindly. However, Richard Curtis has always had a special touch with his films which have put them a head up over the rest of the sappy Hollywood stuff. 'Four weddings and a funeral' is a British rom-com that was delightful to watch. Hugh grant is such a funny actor, you can warm to him at once ; he is a rare talent. He also has great chemistry in the movie with this American beauty who he happens to meet upon multiple weddings. If this was just a love film on its own, it would be poor . Yet what makes 'four weddings' so compelling is the hilarious comedic script that is packed with all sorts of witty comments. Grant's group of friends in the movie are hilarious, and yes even Rowan Atkinson made it into the movie (although I would call his role more of a cameo). 'Four weddings and a funeral' was so popular at its time, that it received a 'best picture' nomination which is un-heard of for a rom-com. That should give you an idea of how good this movie is. Definitely worth watching - no matter what type of person you are, there is going to be something in here that will make you laugh :)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good For What It Is!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    g-bodyl
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Four Weddings and a Funeral is a British romantic comedy that is sometimes charming, but it mostly falls flat and gets lost in the mix of all romantic comedies out there. This film is entertaining, but forgettable. Writing this review, I can hardly remember what happens in the movie. Mike Newell's film is about a bachelor named Charles and he is seemingly the best man at many weddings. At the first wedding, he meets this girl and he thinks he finally falls in love. Over the course of several more weddings and a funeral, he gets the notion that maybe he has fallen for the wrong lady. The acting is pretty good for the most part. Hugh Grant is a charming British fellow and this film introduced him to the American audience. Simon Callow and John Hannah are really good and quite funny. Andie McDowell is pretty darn awful and she sounds like she's a robot. Overall, this is a decent but entirely forgettable British comedy. It has some good moments and some boring moments. Some of the jokes are quite funny especially the one involving the band, U2. Despite this being a solid film, I can't fathom how the film was nominated for Best Picture at the Oscars. It's only a date night film at best. I rate this film 7/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Mike Newell has directed a pleasant film about the importance of love.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FilmCriticLalitRao
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Through his comedy film, "Four weddings and a funeral", British director Mike Newell gives an excellent idea about how love and marriage are viewed by English people. His film is a quest for finding true love. It also depicts the importance of love over sex in relationships involving men and women. A good film which can be watched with family involves elements which are valued by family members. From that yardstick, a film about love and marriage can be a little offensive only if has some explicit hints about sex. However, English film four weddings and a funeral deliberately avoids any unnecessary mention of sex in order to portray itself as a clean film. The choice of an American actress who is wooed by a flippant British bachelor works well for this film as Andie MacDowell and Hugh Grant remain true to their on screen portrayals. In most films, minor characters are not developed but this film gives equal importance to minor characters who help viewers to understand the importance of friends in a person's life. Lastly, four weddings and a funeral is able to impress viewers as its spreads the message that there comes a time in each person's life when he/she has to become serious about marriage and must get married before it is too late.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Four Weddings and a Funeral: And Only That
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Elise Tarter
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    While I enjoy romantic comedies as much as or more than most, I found very little to appreciate in Four Weddings and a Funeral: It flits around from wedding to wedding employing a fairly large cast of characters, which, though interesting, the viewer never gets to know. The fatal flaw of Four Weddings is that it tells us about many significant friendships, relationships, and romances but rarely shows them to us in actual character interactions or dialogue. The supposedly deep and meaningful connections between characters were actually so threadbare as to cause audience confusion or worse, indifference. Here are a few examples: Charles and Fiona- We learn that they are long-time friends, but see her carp at Charles for his lateness and then confess her love for him, which is never mentioned again hereafter. Carrie and Hamish- She's flirting with Charles, in bed with him and then  engaged to Hamish. Things like this do happen, but she goes out especially with Charles for a fun, "dress-selecting" outing and then sleeps with him again before her wedding. This is the marriage that came from nowhere and made no sense other than a (poor) plot device. Gareth- He wears a silly-looking vest but makes fun of Scarlett's dress. He generally has a good time, drinks, dances, and then drops dead in a startling and therefore moderately comical manner. However, his funeral is treated seriously in the film and is supposed to carry great emotional weight with the viewer. Honestly, I barely had time to learn his name and a few superficial facts about him, but there was not enough "meat" in his character development to make my eyes even begin to grow misty when he died. Charles and Henrietta- They have a couple of tearful conversations, one complete with a dressing down, no steamy encounters, but suddenly, they're walking down the aisle But all of this may have been forgivable if the movie had spent any time with the side characters before bombarding us with the montage of weddings at the end. Henrietta/ "Duckface" gets married, happily, it seems, but the audience gets not one minute with her after Charles leaves her at the altar. This film skips over almost every relationship or character development worth showing, leaving it emotionally hollow, frustrating, and ultimately forgettable. I guess screenwriter Richard Curtis was getting warmed up for Love Actually, which succeeds in all the ways that Four Weddings and a Funeral failed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Four occasions to laugh, one to cry, five to meditate about love and life ....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ElMaruecan82
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Many romantic comedies end with the two leads finally reuniting for the final kiss and realizing that they're meant to live together. Though it doesn't necessarily imply that the following step is marriage, but we can bet on a long-term commitment. Basically, "Four Weddings and a Funeral" stands above all the 'romantic comedy' genre because it doesn't take its very essence for granted and turns into a delightful social commentary about the meaning of marital commitment even questioning its compatibility with real love. Can love last for life? If not definite answers, the film provides some hints through four martial experiences and one funeral, which is an occasion to think about life and death. Mike Newell finds the perfect balance between humor, slapstick and intelligence, all of them in a typically British flavor. And one thing for sure, the film's title doesn't lie about the content since the five titular events and their direct aftermaths occupy almost 95% of the screen time. And as viewers, we're (literally) invited to follow the adventures of one joyful bunch of friends. On the top of them, there's Hugh Grant as Charles, a handsome thirty something bachelor whose penetrating blue eyes betray a vulnerable sensitivity that doesn't fit his look. There is the tiny, exuberant Charlotte Coleman as Scarlett, a gay couple, Matthew (John Hannah) and Garrett played by the scene-stealing Simon Callow. Kristin Scott Thomas plays Fiona, hiding in a sophisticated composure the grief of never having conquered Charles' heart, and last but not least, there's Tom, Jack Fleet as the goofiest and clumsiest of the bunch, which is saying a lot. We never know exactly what these people do for a living, but it doesn't matter actually. Besides, we know them enough to understand the way they feel, behave or approach life and important matters, so the rest would only fill the script with unnecessary details. Have you noticed by the way that in most rom-coms, the jobs of the two lead hardly play a role, one is an architect, and another is a cook, so what? And have you also noticed that many romantic comedies only rely on the believability of its lead couple and some supporting characters, "Four Weddings and a Funeral" is an ensemble cast movie, and even more effective because it doesn't depend on a multi-linear plot, the solidarity, the complicity between the friends is the story's heart and greatest source for gags and amusement. I insist on the ensemble cast because truth is if Hugh Grant was perfect for the role that put him in America's showbiz map, and earned him a Golden Globe, the same can hardly be said about Andie McDowell. As much as I respect and appreciate the actress, it's hard to see the same sweetheart who turned Phil Connor's heart in "Groundhog Day". She doesn't deliver a bad performance per se, but a Razzie nomination (that thankfully the film was spared of) wouldn't have surprised me. It was hard to believe that Charles would be so infatuated in a woman who doesn't seem quite sure either about love, let alone marriage. Some would think this is what united them since they would be involved in the two weddings that didn't end. But something in Carrie suggested that she was more of a gold-digger type, while Charles is more a victim of his own idealism. Unsuccessful marriages end up being more insightful than the others, (if only because they do 'end up') and one of the merit of "Four Weddings and a Funeral" is to put the notion of commitment into perspective, to revalue the meaning of living and loving someone for life. In a way, the subtext is that we are never 100% sure to love someone then marriage is not necessarily a guarantee of happiness OR if we really love one person, then marriage would be totally meaningless. That's the idea conveyed by Gareth and Matthew's who'd be shown as the most solid and sincere couple, without any ceremony to 'validate' their union. The death of Gareth invites for these questions and works as a great dramatic relief in a relatively screwball comedy, thanks to Matthew's powerful eulogy, simple but realistically heart-breaking. But I guess I was a bit too serious in my review, and beyond the whole introspective facade, "Four Weddings and a Funeral" is also a cheerful celebration of the most special day of anyone's life, the day we have to say 'yes', this magical moment that sets a before and an after in our lives, that starts with solemnity and ends up with fun, alcohol, and maybe a few years later, regrets. It also allows other people to meet their match, soul-mates or one-night hits. Weddings are the premise of countless jokes, a nice twist on the forget-the-rings gag, embarrassing best man's speeches, some acts of pure desperation and a wonderfully comic moment with Rowan Atkinson as a priest in his first wedding. His five minutes are funnier than the whole 'Mr. Bean' film, in fact, the film reminds us that the world needs marriage, if only to have a great moment of fun and joy. "Four Weddings and one Funeral" was one of the biggest hits of the glorious 1994, earning two nominations for Best Screenplay and Best Picture. The material is so fresh and new on the field of romantic comedies that it's hard to tolerate such conventional moments like a declaration of love under the rain, and a cheesy line delivered by you-know-who, and it's only forgivable because the film immediately redeems itself through the great ending credits sequence and Elton John's version of "Chapel of Love", the credits sequences perfectly captures the positive, optimistic mood of the film, and even its not-to-be-taken-so-seriously quality. And it does fit the general message of the film that after all, maybe wedding, just like life, is not to be taken so seriously, and maybe that's the best way to make it work.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hated it when I saw it in '94, loved it last night
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rooprect
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I saw this film in '94, I was expecting something a little snappier & edgier like the rom-coms of the time (such as "Singles" or "When Harry Met Sally"). Instead, its low-key, subtle, British presentation caught me off guard and left me a little bit unfulfilled. I now realize that's because I was an idiot at the time. Subtlety is this film's strength, and Hugh Grant's performance is impeccable in that regard. There aren't a lot of wisecracking zingers or situational craziness, but Hugh's portrayal of a cute, clueless, British playboy is something he does par excellence. Andie McDowell's portrayal of a disconnected, almost soulless enigma is equally compelling, although on first viewing I didn't understand the character. The comedy comes through Hugh's strained reactions to the insane situations he finds himself in. Things happen that would reduce a normal human to hysterics, but Hugh is forced to ride it out with proper British decorum. For example, there's one scene where finds himself stuck at a table with EVERY ONE of his ex-girlfriends, trying to play it off as politely as possible while they take turns freaking out at him. Something to note: Unlike films like "Harry Met Sally" and "Singles" which focus equally on the characters, this movie is essentially from Hugh's viewpoint, and Andie's character is almost peripheral. With that in mind, it's not a standard love story between two people. Instead it's about one man stumbling through the concept of romance. If you like rom-coms that take a different approach, this is a good one for you to check out. I also recommend "Forget Paris" (about what happens to a couple AFTER 'happily ever after') and "Object of Beauty" (starring Andie McDowell & John Malkovich as a pair of dysfunctional, small-time con artists in love). If you're a Hugh Grant fan, you'll love this film, period.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny, but not one of my favourites
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I had heard some morally bad things about this movie and a number of people portrayed it in a bad light. I think is was because of the prostitute incident at the time of this movie that put me off it. In fact, the prostitute incident put a number of people I knew off of Hugh Grant. Personally I don't think that it was the media's business about whether Hugh Grant was caught with a prostitute, and more so the pressure put on his girlfriend at the time to forgive him. This movie is about four weddings and a funeral. In fact, there is only one scene in the movie that is not set at a wedding or the funeral. As one can tell by the title the movie is about marriage, but the conclusion that it comes to I inevitably disagree with. The movie is based around a group of friends who are always going to weddings. In fact, it is the time of life when everybody is getting married. Charles (Hugh Grant) always sleeps in and as such is always late to weddings. That is until his own when all of his friends make damn sure that he gets up in time. The movie explores death and marriage, and at one point - the low point - the conclusion is that not everybody is going to get married. This is true as Charles concludes, after he called a wedding off because he did not really want to marry Duck Face - Henrietta, that marriage was not for him - yet he still wanted the companionship of a girl. My opinion here is not that marriage was not for him, but rather that he is so scared to make a commitment to a woman that he would rather have a relationship that he can call off easily. The funeral is of a very cheerful chap who dies at the third wedding. This chap is the oldest and commands his friends to find a partner. He dies and they come to see that not everybody is going to get married. This is not true to the movie because, as one can expect, everybody ends up happily ever after. The thing the people I know did not appreciate about this movie was the ending where they say that they can have a perfect marriage relationship without getting married. This I do not really agree with because marriage involves commitments and promises, and if you are not willing to make these promises to the person, then you should not either consider marrying this person, or living with the person as if you were married.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Mostly enjoyable - needs a different ending
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    elspeth-11
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I really enjoyed most of this movie - the funeral was devastating. And unlike many, I really do enjoy the standard Hugh Grant (which, in fairness, was not yet "standard" when this movie was new). BUT (and I'm agreeing with everyone else here) Carrie, the Andie MacDowell character, has nothing going for her. She is not appealing in any way, and she's a slag. Additionally, the wedding to Duckface is totally unmotivated, and only contrived so that he can leave her at the altar without us hating him. Here is how it should have gone. The fourth wedding should have been between Charles and Carrie - once she's divorced, there is no impediment after all. Carrie - true to character - will be getting it on with someone else by the night before the wedding. Meanwhile, Charles discovers that he is really in love with Fiona (wasn't that the point of the movie? it's what I expected to happen). The deaf character discovers both these facts and the wedding can now be played as originally scripted.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    So overrated it should be criminal
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    summerskter
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is so frustratingly forgettable. It is a romance which makes absolutely no sense to the viewer. The object of affection is a promiscuous, threesome-having, cheating, superficial, self-absorbed woman named Carrie, which Andie Macdowell plays as if she were just a breezy, soft-spoken nice girl. Andie is so uncomfortable in this role that every single line is delivered in a monotone drawl. If you can get through her last line, "Is it still raining? I hadn't noticed," while they are standing in a downpour, without laughing, my hat's off to you. Without spoiling to much, let's just say if you value romance, like actual romance involving two people getting along, spending some quality non-sex time together, you are not going to find it in this hollow, mechanical movie. And when I mean hollow, I mean so completely insincere that anyone who lives in the real world would find the characters' behavior mystifying until the ending credits. I still don't understand what this movie was trying to say. I was 100% rooting for Hugh Grant (Charles) to end up with either of the two eligible women who are actually loyal and devoted to him, and who don't treat him and his feelings dismissively throughout the entire film, as Carrie does. So terribly disappointing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Typical Plot but Atypical Setting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    copperncherrio
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love Hugh Grant. You just cannot go wrong with Hugh Grant and romantic comedies, and Four Weddings & a Funeral is the perfect chick flick of romance, humor, and most importantly GREAT CONVERSATION. There are so many little scenes and snipets that are just brilliant little skits that are wrapped around into an interesting love story. Though the love isn't compelling between the two main characters and there could be minor plot tweaks, there's a lot of great things about this British film that I'm sorry that more films can't take away from. High expectations I had, and disappointed I was not. Possibly one of the greatest romantic comedies that I've witnessed thus far. Hugh Grant was superb, the leading gal was alright.. .but there is a great supporting cast. I can't hate a well written movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny and charming
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mcjoe1614
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let's be honest here. Unless you are one of these 'true-love' fanatics then you will find romantic comedies extremely lifeless, predictable and dull. For me, that's putting it kindly. However, Richard Curtis has always had a special touch with his films which have put them a head up over the rest of the sappy Hollywood stuff. 'Four weddings and a funeral' is a British rom-com that was delightful to watch. Hugh grant is such a funny actor, you can warm to him at once ; he is a rare talent. He also has great chemistry in the movie with this American beauty who he happens to meet upon multiple weddings. If this was just a love film on its own, it would be poor . Yet what makes 'four weddings' so compelling is the hilarious comedic script that is packed with all sorts of witty comments. Grant's group of friends in the movie are hilarious, and yes even Rowan Atkinson made it into the movie (although I would call his role more of a cameo). 'Four weddings and a funeral' was so popular at its time, that it received a 'best picture' nomination which is un-heard of for a rom-com. That should give you an idea of how good this movie is. Definitely worth watching - no matter what type of person you are, there is going to be something in here that will make you laugh :)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good For What It Is!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    g-bodyl
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Four Weddings and a Funeral is a British romantic comedy that is sometimes charming, but it mostly falls flat and gets lost in the mix of all romantic comedies out there. This film is entertaining, but forgettable. Writing this review, I can hardly remember what happens in the movie. Mike Newell's film is about a bachelor named Charles and he is seemingly the best man at many weddings. At the first wedding, he meets this girl and he thinks he finally falls in love. Over the course of several more weddings and a funeral, he gets the notion that maybe he has fallen for the wrong lady. The acting is pretty good for the most part. Hugh Grant is a charming British fellow and this film introduced him to the American audience. Simon Callow and John Hannah are really good and quite funny. Andie McDowell is pretty darn awful and she sounds like she's a robot. Overall, this is a decent but entirely forgettable British comedy. It has some good moments and some boring moments. Some of the jokes are quite funny especially the one involving the band, U2. Despite this being a solid film, I can't fathom how the film was nominated for Best Picture at the Oscars. It's only a date night film at best. I rate this film 7/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Mike Newell has directed a pleasant film about the importance of love.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FilmCriticLalitRao
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Through his comedy film, "Four weddings and a funeral", British director Mike Newell gives an excellent idea about how love and marriage are viewed by English people. His film is a quest for finding true love. It also depicts the importance of love over sex in relationships involving men and women. A good film which can be watched with family involves elements which are valued by family members. From that yardstick, a film about love and marriage can be a little offensive only if has some explicit hints about sex. However, English film four weddings and a funeral deliberately avoids any unnecessary mention of sex in order to portray itself as a clean film. The choice of an American actress who is wooed by a flippant British bachelor works well for this film as Andie MacDowell and Hugh Grant remain true to their on screen portrayals. In most films, minor characters are not developed but this film gives equal importance to minor characters who help viewers to understand the importance of friends in a person's life. Lastly, four weddings and a funeral is able to impress viewers as its spreads the message that there comes a time in each person's life when he/she has to become serious about marriage and must get married before it is too late.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Four Weddings and a Funeral: And Only That
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Elise Tarter
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    While I enjoy romantic comedies as much as or more than most, I found very little to appreciate in Four Weddings and a Funeral: It flits around from wedding to wedding employing a fairly large cast of characters, which, though interesting, the viewer never gets to know. The fatal flaw of Four Weddings is that it tells us about many significant friendships, relationships, and romances but rarely shows them to us in actual character interactions or dialogue. The supposedly deep and meaningful connections between characters were actually so threadbare as to cause audience confusion or worse, indifference. Here are a few examples: Charles and Fiona- We learn that they are long-time friends, but see her carp at Charles for his lateness and then confess her love for him, which is never mentioned again hereafter. Carrie and Hamish- She's flirting with Charles, in bed with him and then  engaged to Hamish. Things like this do happen, but she goes out especially with Charles for a fun, "dress-selecting" outing and then sleeps with him again before her wedding. This is the marriage that came from nowhere and made no sense other than a (poor) plot device. Gareth- He wears a silly-looking vest but makes fun of Scarlett's dress. He generally has a good time, drinks, dances, and then drops dead in a startling and therefore moderately comical manner. However, his funeral is treated seriously in the film and is supposed to carry great emotional weight with the viewer. Honestly, I barely had time to learn his name and a few superficial facts about him, but there was not enough "meat" in his character development to make my eyes even begin to grow misty when he died. Charles and Henrietta- They have a couple of tearful conversations, one complete with a dressing down, no steamy encounters, but suddenly, they're walking down the aisle But all of this may have been forgivable if the movie had spent any time with the side characters before bombarding us with the montage of weddings at the end. Henrietta/ "Duckface" gets married, happily, it seems, but the audience gets not one minute with her after Charles leaves her at the altar. This film skips over almost every relationship or character development worth showing, leaving it emotionally hollow, frustrating, and ultimately forgettable. I guess screenwriter Richard Curtis was getting warmed up for Love Actually, which succeeds in all the ways that Four Weddings and a Funeral failed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Four occasions to laugh, one to cry, five to meditate about love and life ....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ElMaruecan82
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Many romantic comedies end with the two leads finally reuniting for the final kiss and realizing that they're meant to live together. Though it doesn't necessarily imply that the following step is marriage, but we can bet on a long-term commitment. Basically, "Four Weddings and a Funeral" stands above all the 'romantic comedy' genre because it doesn't take its very essence for granted and turns into a delightful social commentary about the meaning of marital commitment even questioning its compatibility with real love. Can love last for life? If not definite answers, the film provides some hints through four martial experiences and one funeral, which is an occasion to think about life and death. Mike Newell finds the perfect balance between humor, slapstick and intelligence, all of them in a typically British flavor. And one thing for sure, the film's title doesn't lie about the content since the five titular events and their direct aftermaths occupy almost 95% of the screen time. And as viewers, we're (literally) invited to follow the adventures of one joyful bunch of friends. On the top of them, there's Hugh Grant as Charles, a handsome thirty something bachelor whose penetrating blue eyes betray a vulnerable sensitivity that doesn't fit his look. There is the tiny, exuberant Charlotte Coleman as Scarlett, a gay couple, Matthew (John Hannah) and Garrett played by the scene-stealing Simon Callow. Kristin Scott Thomas plays Fiona, hiding in a sophisticated composure the grief of never having conquered Charles' heart, and last but not least, there's Tom, Jack Fleet as the goofiest and clumsiest of the bunch, which is saying a lot. We never know exactly what these people do for a living, but it doesn't matter actually. Besides, we know them enough to understand the way they feel, behave or approach life and important matters, so the rest would only fill the script with unnecessary details. Have you noticed by the way that in most rom-coms, the jobs of the two lead hardly play a role, one is an architect, and another is a cook, so what? And have you also noticed that many romantic comedies only rely on the believability of its lead couple and some supporting characters, "Four Weddings and a Funeral" is an ensemble cast movie, and even more effective because it doesn't depend on a multi-linear plot, the solidarity, the complicity between the friends is the story's heart and greatest source for gags and amusement. I insist on the ensemble cast because truth is if Hugh Grant was perfect for the role that put him in America's showbiz map, and earned him a Golden Globe, the same can hardly be said about Andie McDowell. As much as I respect and appreciate the actress, it's hard to see the same sweetheart who turned Phil Connor's heart in "Groundhog Day". She doesn't deliver a bad performance per se, but a Razzie nomination (that thankfully the film was spared of) wouldn't have surprised me. It was hard to believe that Charles would be so infatuated in a woman who doesn't seem quite sure either about love, let alone marriage. Some would think this is what united them since they would be involved in the two weddings that didn't end. But something in Carrie suggested that she was more of a gold-digger type, while Charles is more a victim of his own idealism. Unsuccessful marriages end up being more insightful than the others, (if only because they do 'end up') and one of the merit of "Four Weddings and a Funeral" is to put the notion of commitment into perspective, to revalue the meaning of living and loving someone for life. In a way, the subtext is that we are never 100% sure to love someone then marriage is not necessarily a guarantee of happiness OR if we really love one person, then marriage would be totally meaningless. That's the idea conveyed by Gareth and Matthew's who'd be shown as the most solid and sincere couple, without any ceremony to 'validate' their union. The death of Gareth invites for these questions and works as a great dramatic relief in a relatively screwball comedy, thanks to Matthew's powerful eulogy, simple but realistically heart-breaking. But I guess I was a bit too serious in my review, and beyond the whole introspective facade, "Four Weddings and a Funeral" is also a cheerful celebration of the most special day of anyone's life, the day we have to say 'yes', this magical moment that sets a before and an after in our lives, that starts with solemnity and ends up with fun, alcohol, and maybe a few years later, regrets. It also allows other people to meet their match, soul-mates or one-night hits. Weddings are the premise of countless jokes, a nice twist on the forget-the-rings gag, embarrassing best man's speeches, some acts of pure desperation and a wonderfully comic moment with Rowan Atkinson as a priest in his first wedding. His five minutes are funnier than the whole 'Mr. Bean' film, in fact, the film reminds us that the world needs marriage, if only to have a great moment of fun and joy. "Four Weddings and one Funeral" was one of the biggest hits of the glorious 1994, earning two nominations for Best Screenplay and Best Picture. The material is so fresh and new on the field of romantic comedies that it's hard to tolerate such conventional moments like a declaration of love under the rain, and a cheesy line delivered by you-know-who, and it's only forgivable because the film immediately redeems itself through the great ending credits sequence and Elton John's version of "Chapel of Love", the credits sequences perfectly captures the positive, optimistic mood of the film, and even its not-to-be-taken-so-seriously quality. And it does fit the general message of the film that after all, maybe wedding, just like life, is not to be taken so seriously, and maybe that's the best way to make it work.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hated it when I saw it in '94, loved it last night
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rooprect
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I saw this film in '94, I was expecting something a little snappier & edgier like the rom-coms of the time (such as "Singles" or "When Harry Met Sally"). Instead, its low-key, subtle, British presentation caught me off guard and left me a little bit unfulfilled. I now realize that's because I was an idiot at the time. Subtlety is this film's strength, and Hugh Grant's performance is impeccable in that regard. There aren't a lot of wisecracking zingers or situational craziness, but Hugh's portrayal of a cute, clueless, British playboy is something he does par excellence. Andie McDowell's portrayal of a disconnected, almost soulless enigma is equally compelling, although on first viewing I didn't understand the character. The comedy comes through Hugh's strained reactions to the insane situations he finds himself in. Things happen that would reduce a normal human to hysterics, but Hugh is forced to ride it out with proper British decorum. For example, there's one scene where finds himself stuck at a table with EVERY ONE of his ex-girlfriends, trying to play it off as politely as possible while they take turns freaking out at him. Something to note: Unlike films like "Harry Met Sally" and "Singles" which focus equally on the characters, this movie is essentially from Hugh's viewpoint, and Andie's character is almost peripheral. With that in mind, it's not a standard love story between two people. Instead it's about one man stumbling through the concept of romance. If you like rom-coms that take a different approach, this is a good one for you to check out. I also recommend "Forget Paris" (about what happens to a couple AFTER 'happily ever after') and "Object of Beauty" (starring Andie McDowell & John Malkovich as a pair of dysfunctional, small-time con artists in love). If you're a Hugh Grant fan, you'll love this film, period.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny, but not one of my favourites
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I had heard some morally bad things about this movie and a number of people portrayed it in a bad light. I think is was because of the prostitute incident at the time of this movie that put me off it. In fact, the prostitute incident put a number of people I knew off of Hugh Grant. Personally I don't think that it was the media's business about whether Hugh Grant was caught with a prostitute, and more so the pressure put on his girlfriend at the time to forgive him. This movie is about four weddings and a funeral. In fact, there is only one scene in the movie that is not set at a wedding or the funeral. As one can tell by the title the movie is about marriage, but the conclusion that it comes to I inevitably disagree with. The movie is based around a group of friends who are always going to weddings. In fact, it is the time of life when everybody is getting married. Charles (Hugh Grant) always sleeps in and as such is always late to weddings. That is until his own when all of his friends make damn sure that he gets up in time. The movie explores death and marriage, and at one point - the low point - the conclusion is that not everybody is going to get married. This is true as Charles concludes, after he called a wedding off because he did not really want to marry Duck Face - Henrietta, that marriage was not for him - yet he still wanted the companionship of a girl. My opinion here is not that marriage was not for him, but rather that he is so scared to make a commitment to a woman that he would rather have a relationship that he can call off easily. The funeral is of a very cheerful chap who dies at the third wedding. This chap is the oldest and commands his friends to find a partner. He dies and they come to see that not everybody is going to get married. This is not true to the movie because, as one can expect, everybody ends up happily ever after. The thing the people I know did not appreciate about this movie was the ending where they say that they can have a perfect marriage relationship without getting married. This I do not really agree with because marriage involves commitments and promises, and if you are not willing to make these promises to the person, then you should not either consider marrying this person, or living with the person as if you were married.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Mostly enjoyable - needs a different ending
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    elspeth-11
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I really enjoyed most of this movie - the funeral was devastating. And unlike many, I really do enjoy the standard Hugh Grant (which, in fairness, was not yet "standard" when this movie was new). BUT (and I'm agreeing with everyone else here) Carrie, the Andie MacDowell character, has nothing going for her. She is not appealing in any way, and she's a slag. Additionally, the wedding to Duckface is totally unmotivated, and only contrived so that he can leave her at the altar without us hating him. Here is how it should have gone. The fourth wedding should have been between Charles and Carrie - once she's divorced, there is no impediment after all. Carrie - true to character - will be getting it on with someone else by the night before the wedding. Meanwhile, Charles discovers that he is really in love with Fiona (wasn't that the point of the movie? it's what I expected to happen). The deaf character discovers both these facts and the wedding can now be played as originally scripted.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    So overrated it should be criminal
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    summerskter
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is so frustratingly forgettable. It is a romance which makes absolutely no sense to the viewer. The object of affection is a promiscuous, threesome-having, cheating, superficial, self-absorbed woman named Carrie, which Andie Macdowell plays as if she were just a breezy, soft-spoken nice girl. Andie is so uncomfortable in this role that every single line is delivered in a monotone drawl. If you can get through her last line, "Is it still raining? I hadn't noticed," while they are standing in a downpour, without laughing, my hat's off to you. Without spoiling to much, let's just say if you value romance, like actual romance involving two people getting along, spending some quality non-sex time together, you are not going to find it in this hollow, mechanical movie. And when I mean hollow, I mean so completely insincere that anyone who lives in the real world would find the characters' behavior mystifying until the ending credits. I still don't understand what this movie was trying to say. I was 100% rooting for Hugh Grant (Charles) to end up with either of the two eligible women who are actually loyal and devoted to him, and who don't treat him and his feelings dismissively throughout the entire film, as Carrie does. So terribly disappointing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Typical Plot but Atypical Setting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    copperncherrio
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love Hugh Grant. You just cannot go wrong with Hugh Grant and romantic comedies, and Four Weddings & a Funeral is the perfect chick flick of romance, humor, and most importantly GREAT CONVERSATION. There are so many little scenes and snipets that are just brilliant little skits that are wrapped around into an interesting love story. Though the love isn't compelling between the two main characters and there could be minor plot tweaks, there's a lot of great things about this British film that I'm sorry that more films can't take away from. High expectations I had, and disappointed I was not. Possibly one of the greatest romantic comedies that I've witnessed thus far. Hugh Grant was superb, the leading gal was alright.. .but there is a great supporting cast. I can't hate a well written movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny and charming
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mcjoe1614
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Let's be honest here. Unless you are one of these 'true-love' fanatics then you will find romantic comedies extremely lifeless, predictable and dull. For me, that's putting it kindly. However, Richard Curtis has always had a special touch with his films which have put them a head up over the rest of the sappy Hollywood stuff. 'Four weddings and a funeral' is a British rom-com that was delightful to watch. Hugh grant is such a funny actor, you can warm to him at once ; he is a rare talent. He also has great chemistry in the movie with this American beauty who he happens to meet upon multiple weddings. If this was just a love film on its own, it would be poor . Yet what makes 'four weddings' so compelling is the hilarious comedic script that is packed with all sorts of witty comments. Grant's group of friends in the movie are hilarious, and yes even Rowan Atkinson made it into the movie (although I would call his role more of a cameo). 'Four weddings and a funeral' was so popular at its time, that it received a 'best picture' nomination which is un-heard of for a rom-com. That should give you an idea of how good this movie is. Definitely worth watching - no matter what type of person you are, there is going to be something in here that will make you laugh :)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good For What It Is!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    g-bodyl
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Four Weddings and a Funeral is a British romantic comedy that is sometimes charming, but it mostly falls flat and gets lost in the mix of all romantic comedies out there. This film is entertaining, but forgettable. Writing this review, I can hardly remember what happens in the movie. Mike Newell's film is about a bachelor named Charles and he is seemingly the best man at many weddings. At the first wedding, he meets this girl and he thinks he finally falls in love. Over the course of several more weddings and a funeral, he gets the notion that maybe he has fallen for the wrong lady. The acting is pretty good for the most part. Hugh Grant is a charming British fellow and this film introduced him to the American audience. Simon Callow and John Hannah are really good and quite funny. Andie McDowell is pretty darn awful and she sounds like she's a robot. Overall, this is a decent but entirely forgettable British comedy. It has some good moments and some boring moments. Some of the jokes are quite funny especially the one involving the band, U2. Despite this being a solid film, I can't fathom how the film was nominated for Best Picture at the Oscars. It's only a date night film at best. I rate this film 7/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Mike Newell has directed a pleasant film about the importance of love.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    FilmCriticLalitRao
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Through his comedy film, "Four weddings and a funeral", British director Mike Newell gives an excellent idea about how love and marriage are viewed by English people. His film is a quest for finding true love. It also depicts the importance of love over sex in relationships involving men and women. A good film which can be watched with family involves elements which are valued by family members. From that yardstick, a film about love and marriage can be a little offensive only if has some explicit hints about sex. However, English film four weddings and a funeral deliberately avoids any unnecessary mention of sex in order to portray itself as a clean film. The choice of an American actress who is wooed by a flippant British bachelor works well for this film as Andie MacDowell and Hugh Grant remain true to their on screen portrayals. In most films, minor characters are not developed but this film gives equal importance to minor characters who help viewers to understand the importance of friends in a person's life. Lastly, four weddings and a funeral is able to impress viewers as its spreads the message that there comes a time in each person's life when he/she has to become serious about marriage and must get married before it is too late.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Four Weddings and a Funeral: And Only That
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Elise Tarter
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    While I enjoy romantic comedies as much as or more than most, I found very little to appreciate in Four Weddings and a Funeral: It flits around from wedding to wedding employing a fairly large cast of characters, which, though interesting, the viewer never gets to know. The fatal flaw of Four Weddings is that it tells us about many significant friendships, relationships, and romances but rarely shows them to us in actual character interactions or dialogue. The supposedly deep and meaningful connections between characters were actually so threadbare as to cause audience confusion or worse, indifference. Here are a few examples: Charles and Fiona- We learn that they are long-time friends, but see her carp at Charles for his lateness and then confess her love for him, which is never mentioned again hereafter. Carrie and Hamish- She's flirting with Charles, in bed with him and then  engaged to Hamish. Things like this do happen, but she goes out especially with Charles for a fun, "dress-selecting" outing and then sleeps with him again before her wedding. This is the marriage that came from nowhere and made no sense other than a (poor) plot device. Gareth- He wears a silly-looking vest but makes fun of Scarlett's dress. He generally has a good time, drinks, dances, and then drops dead in a startling and therefore moderately comical manner. However, his funeral is treated seriously in the film and is supposed to carry great emotional weight with the viewer. Honestly, I barely had time to learn his name and a few superficial facts about him, but there was not enough "meat" in his character development to make my eyes even begin to grow misty when he died. Charles and Henrietta- They have a couple of tearful conversations, one complete with a dressing down, no steamy encounters, but suddenly, they're walking down the aisle But all of this may have been forgivable if the movie had spent any time with the side characters before bombarding us with the montage of weddings at the end. Henrietta/ "Duckface" gets married, happily, it seems, but the audience gets not one minute with her after Charles leaves her at the altar. This film skips over almost every relationship or character development worth showing, leaving it emotionally hollow, frustrating, and ultimately forgettable. I guess screenwriter Richard Curtis was getting warmed up for Love Actually, which succeeds in all the ways that Four Weddings and a Funeral failed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Four occasions to laugh, one to cry, five to meditate about love and life ....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ElMaruecan82
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Many romantic comedies end with the two leads finally reuniting for the final kiss and realizing that they're meant to live together. Though it doesn't necessarily imply that the following step is marriage, but we can bet on a long-term commitment. Basically, "Four Weddings and a Funeral" stands above all the 'romantic comedy' genre because it doesn't take its very essence for granted and turns into a delightful social commentary about the meaning of marital commitment even questioning its compatibility with real love. Can love last for life? If not definite answers, the film provides some hints through four martial experiences and one funeral, which is an occasion to think about life and death. Mike Newell finds the perfect balance between humor, slapstick and intelligence, all of them in a typically British flavor. And one thing for sure, the film's title doesn't lie about the content since the five titular events and their direct aftermaths occupy almost 95% of the screen time. And as viewers, we're (literally) invited to follow the adventures of one joyful bunch of friends. On the top of them, there's Hugh Grant as Charles, a handsome thirty something bachelor whose penetrating blue eyes betray a vulnerable sensitivity that doesn't fit his look. There is the tiny, exuberant Charlotte Coleman as Scarlett, a gay couple, Matthew (John Hannah) and Garrett played by the scene-stealing Simon Callow. Kristin Scott Thomas plays Fiona, hiding in a sophisticated composure the grief of never having conquered Charles' heart, and last but not least, there's Tom, Jack Fleet as the goofiest and clumsiest of the bunch, which is saying a lot. We never know exactly what these people do for a living, but it doesn't matter actually. Besides, we know them enough to understand the way they feel, behave or approach life and important matters, so the rest would only fill the script with unnecessary details. Have you noticed by the way that in most rom-coms, the jobs of the two lead hardly play a role, one is an architect, and another is a cook, so what? And have you also noticed that many romantic comedies only rely on the believability of its lead couple and some supporting characters, "Four Weddings and a Funeral" is an ensemble cast movie, and even more effective because it doesn't depend on a multi-linear plot, the solidarity, the complicity between the friends is the story's heart and greatest source for gags and amusement. I insist on the ensemble cast because truth is if Hugh Grant was perfect for the role that put him in America's showbiz map, and earned him a Golden Globe, the same can hardly be said about Andie McDowell. As much as I respect and appreciate the actress, it's hard to see the same sweetheart who turned Phil Connor's heart in "Groundhog Day". She doesn't deliver a bad performance per se, but a Razzie nomination (that thankfully the film was spared of) wouldn't have surprised me. It was hard to believe that Charles would be so infatuated in a woman who doesn't seem quite sure either about love, let alone marriage. Some would think this is what united them since they would be involved in the two weddings that didn't end. But something in Carrie suggested that she was more of a gold-digger type, while Charles is more a victim of his own idealism. Unsuccessful marriages end up being more insightful than the others, (if only because they do 'end up') and one of the merit of "Four Weddings and a Funeral" is to put the notion of commitment into perspective, to revalue the meaning of living and loving someone for life. In a way, the subtext is that we are never 100% sure to love someone then marriage is not necessarily a guarantee of happiness OR if we really love one person, then marriage would be totally meaningless. That's the idea conveyed by Gareth and Matthew's who'd be shown as the most solid and sincere couple, without any ceremony to 'validate' their union. The death of Gareth invites for these questions and works as a great dramatic relief in a relatively screwball comedy, thanks to Matthew's powerful eulogy, simple but realistically heart-breaking. But I guess I was a bit too serious in my review, and beyond the whole introspective facade, "Four Weddings and a Funeral" is also a cheerful celebration of the most special day of anyone's life, the day we have to say 'yes', this magical moment that sets a before and an after in our lives, that starts with solemnity and ends up with fun, alcohol, and maybe a few years later, regrets. It also allows other people to meet their match, soul-mates or one-night hits. Weddings are the premise of countless jokes, a nice twist on the forget-the-rings gag, embarrassing best man's speeches, some acts of pure desperation and a wonderfully comic moment with Rowan Atkinson as a priest in his first wedding. His five minutes are funnier than the whole 'Mr. Bean' film, in fact, the film reminds us that the world needs marriage, if only to have a great moment of fun and joy. "Four Weddings and one Funeral" was one of the biggest hits of the glorious 1994, earning two nominations for Best Screenplay and Best Picture. The material is so fresh and new on the field of romantic comedies that it's hard to tolerate such conventional moments like a declaration of love under the rain, and a cheesy line delivered by you-know-who, and it's only forgivable because the film immediately redeems itself through the great ending credits sequence and Elton John's version of "Chapel of Love", the credits sequences perfectly captures the positive, optimistic mood of the film, and even its not-to-be-taken-so-seriously quality. And it does fit the general message of the film that after all, maybe wedding, just like life, is not to be taken so seriously, and maybe that's the best way to make it work.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hated it when I saw it in '94, loved it last night
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    rooprect
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I saw this film in '94, I was expecting something a little snappier & edgier like the rom-coms of the time (such as "Singles" or "When Harry Met Sally"). Instead, its low-key, subtle, British presentation caught me off guard and left me a little bit unfulfilled. I now realize that's because I was an idiot at the time. Subtlety is this film's strength, and Hugh Grant's performance is impeccable in that regard. There aren't a lot of wisecracking zingers or situational craziness, but Hugh's portrayal of a cute, clueless, British playboy is something he does par excellence. Andie McDowell's portrayal of a disconnected, almost soulless enigma is equally compelling, although on first viewing I didn't understand the character. The comedy comes through Hugh's strained reactions to the insane situations he finds himself in. Things happen that would reduce a normal human to hysterics, but Hugh is forced to ride it out with proper British decorum. For example, there's one scene where finds himself stuck at a table with EVERY ONE of his ex-girlfriends, trying to play it off as politely as possible while they take turns freaking out at him. Something to note: Unlike films like "Harry Met Sally" and "Singles" which focus equally on the characters, this movie is essentially from Hugh's viewpoint, and Andie's character is almost peripheral. With that in mind, it's not a standard love story between two people. Instead it's about one man stumbling through the concept of romance. If you like rom-coms that take a different approach, this is a good one for you to check out. I also recommend "Forget Paris" (about what happens to a couple AFTER 'happily ever after') and "Object of Beauty" (starring Andie McDowell & John Malkovich as a pair of dysfunctional, small-time con artists in love). If you're a Hugh Grant fan, you'll love this film, period.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny, but not one of my favourites
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I had heard some morally bad things about this movie and a number of people portrayed it in a bad light. I think is was because of the prostitute incident at the time of this movie that put me off it. In fact, the prostitute incident put a number of people I knew off of Hugh Grant. Personally I don't think that it was the media's business about whether Hugh Grant was caught with a prostitute, and more so the pressure put on his girlfriend at the time to forgive him. This movie is about four weddings and a funeral. In fact, there is only one scene in the movie that is not set at a wedding or the funeral. As one can tell by the title the movie is about marriage, but the conclusion that it comes to I inevitably disagree with. The movie is based around a group of friends who are always going to weddings. In fact, it is the time of life when everybody is getting married. Charles (Hugh Grant) always sleeps in and as such is always late to weddings. That is until his own when all of his friends make damn sure that he gets up in time. The movie explores death and marriage, and at one point - the low point - the conclusion is that not everybody is going to get married. This is true as Charles concludes, after he called a wedding off because he did not really want to marry Duck Face - Henrietta, that marriage was not for him - yet he still wanted the companionship of a girl. My opinion here is not that marriage was not for him, but rather that he is so scared to make a commitment to a woman that he would rather have a relationship that he can call off easily. The funeral is of a very cheerful chap who dies at the third wedding. This chap is the oldest and commands his friends to find a partner. He dies and they come to see that not everybody is going to get married. This is not true to the movie because, as one can expect, everybody ends up happily ever after. The thing the people I know did not appreciate about this movie was the ending where they say that they can have a perfect marriage relationship without getting married. This I do not really agree with because marriage involves commitments and promises, and if you are not willing to make these promises to the person, then you should not either consider marrying this person, or living with the person as if you were married.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Mostly enjoyable - needs a different ending
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    elspeth-11
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I really enjoyed most of this movie - the funeral was devastating. And unlike many, I really do enjoy the standard Hugh Grant (which, in fairness, was not yet "standard" when this movie was new). BUT (and I'm agreeing with everyone else here) Carrie, the Andie MacDowell character, has nothing going for her. She is not appealing in any way, and she's a slag. Additionally, the wedding to Duckface is totally unmotivated, and only contrived so that he can leave her at the altar without us hating him. Here is how it should have gone. The fourth wedding should have been between Charles and Carrie - once she's divorced, there is no impediment after all. Carrie - true to character - will be getting it on with someone else by the night before the wedding. Meanwhile, Charles discovers that he is really in love with Fiona (wasn't that the point of the movie? it's what I expected to happen). The deaf character discovers both these facts and the wedding can now be played as originally scripted.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    So overrated it should be criminal
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    summerskter
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is so frustratingly forgettable. It is a romance which makes absolutely no sense to the viewer. The object of affection is a promiscuous, threesome-having, cheating, superficial, self-absorbed woman named Carrie, which Andie Macdowell plays as if she were just a breezy, soft-spoken nice girl. Andie is so uncomfortable in this role that every single line is delivered in a monotone drawl. If you can get through her last line, "Is it still raining? I hadn't noticed," while they are standing in a downpour, without laughing, my hat's off to you. Without spoiling to much, let's just say if you value romance, like actual romance involving two people getting along, spending some quality non-sex time together, you are not going to find it in this hollow, mechanical movie. And when I mean hollow, I mean so completely insincere that anyone who lives in the real world would find the characters' behavior mystifying until the ending credits. I still don't understand what this movie was trying to say. I was 100% rooting for Hugh Grant (Charles) to end up with either of the two eligible women who are actually loyal and devoted to him, and who don't treat him and his feelings dismissively throughout the entire film, as Carrie does. So terribly disappointing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Typical Plot but Atypical Setting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    copperncherrio
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love Hugh Grant. You just cannot go wrong with Hugh Grant and romantic comedies, and Four Weddings & a Funeral is the perfect chick flick of romance, humor, and most importantly GREAT CONVERSATION. There are so many little scenes and snipets that are just brilliant little skits that are wrapped around into an interesting love story. Though the love isn't compelling between the two main characters and there could be minor plot tweaks, there's a lot of great things about this British film that I'm sorry that more films can't take away from. High expectations I had, and disappointed I was not. Possibly one of the greatest romantic comedies that I've witnessed thus far. Hugh Grant was superb, the leading gal was alright.. .but there is a great supporting cast. I can't hate a well written movie.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
