<filme>
 <id>
  710
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0088794
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1985
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Minha Vida &eacute; um Desastre
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  7.1
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  A teenager has to deal with his girlfriend dumping him among family crises, homicidal paper boys, and a rival skier.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Lane Meyer is a depressed teen who loses his girlfriend Beth. Her given reason for breaking up is: "Lane, I think it'd be in my best interest if I dated somebody more popular. Better looking. Drives a nicer car." Anyway, poor Lane is left alone and thinks up treacherous ways of killing himself. He finally meets a French beauty called Monique and falls for her. Simultaneously, he must endure his mother's terrible cooking which literally slides off the table and his disgusting next door neighbour Ricky (and his mum) while he prepares for the skiing race of his life - to get his old girlfriend back!
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Romance
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   exchange student
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   teenager
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   skiing
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   suicide attempt
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   voice impersonator
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Savage Steve Holland
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Savage Steve Holland
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   John Cusack
  </ator>
  <ator>
   David Ogden Stiers
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Kim Darby
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Original But Bizarre.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    John Cusack plays Lane Myer, an unhappy high school student who has just been dumped by his beloved girlfriend, and becomes confused and despondent. He must also deal with out-of-touch parents(Kim Darby & David Ogden Stiers) and a electronics genius younger brother, who is trying to build a spaceship in the back yard. He then decides to commit suicide, but can't quite decide how to do it... Strange comedy(to say the least!) is undeniably funny at times, and Cusak is appealing, but film is so far off-the-wall, that it leaves the house altogether! Originality will only get you so far; there has to be some grounding in reality! Still, this does have its moments, and a surprisingly good heart, despite its premise. Once seen, it wont be quickly forgotten...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Silly, Sweet and Shrewd, It's the Moviegoer's Eighties in a Nutshell
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sean Lamberger
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Starring an in-his-element John Cusack, there's no question why this one's still remembered so fondly today: it's a great embodiment of everything one could expect to see from a zany '80s teen-geared comedy. Although Cusack plays his role with a typically dark slant (and many of the jokes are similarly themed), the film's general outlook is upbeat and silly, which makes for a tasty pairing. Occasionally it ventures too far into the realm of the absurd, such as the scene where Cusack's character daydreams a romancing pair of claymation cheeseburgers (which, naturally, pantomime to Van Halen), but it's also those dalliances into surrealism that provide many of its best moments. Funny as both a dated glimpse at life in the mid-eighties and a timeless relation to teenaged heartbreak, it's enriched by a sweet romantic subplot and a vast array of colorful supporting characters.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sheer Genius
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    eti55
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's a pity Savage Steve Holland didn't do more flicks. What he did with Better Off Dead was take the whole John Hughes 80s teen angst comedy and put it in full TILT mode. Everything about this movie is off center, from Layne Meyer's (played by John Cusack) total obsession with a heartless biotch of a g/f who dumps him (he has a picture of her on all of his shirt hangers), to the Chinese guy who taunts Layne while doing a perfect Howard Cosell imitation, to the insane paper boy obsessed with his two dollars, to Layne's younger brother who becomes a ladies man after reading a book on how to pick up trashy women (he also manages to build a space shuttle out of household items..again, after reading a book on it). There's even some trick skiing thrown in (it's set at a ski resort town). Yes, the end of the story is predictable (he gets the girl..the RIGHT girl); it's the way the movie gets there that's so warped. If you're the type of person that takes everything around them seriously including themselves, skip this movie. But if you like stuff that's stupid, silly and BENT (as yours truly does), definitely check this one out.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ranks up there with some of Johns Huges' best movies.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kdnor2011
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Better off Dead isn't quite as good as The Breakfast Club or Ferris Bueller's Day off, but I actually think it's better than 16 Candles and Weird Science. It does the two things that all John Hughes movies do really well. Have the quirky comedy that is really funny, and have the teenage kids actually act like teenage kids. It's interesting to see Dan Schnieder back in the 80s when he was just acting instead of working on shows like All That, Amanda Show, Drake and Josh, Zoey 101, and iCarly. He also makes me feel better about my weight, because at least I'm not as fat as him. The film is just funny, it gets all the quirky elements of being a teenager down that you can't help but laugh. And like I said earlier, it does a good job of showing how hard it is to be a teenager. Teens have to worry about their future, friends, love life, school work, peer pressure, and most have part time jobs. Like I said, it doesn't match Breakfast Club or Ferris bueller, but I like it more than 16 Candles and Weird Science.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Better Off...before I ever watched it
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    s k
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is a poor man's (or woman's) version of Ferris Bueller's Day Off, or Fast Times At Ridgemount High -- without the humor, heart, soul, charm, music, screen chemistry, or creativity of those films. It's a sophomoric attempt, at best, to display high school heartache, that fails miserably. There is not a single solitary likable character (with the possible exception of Monique); and I use the term character rather loosely when it comes to this disaster. The so-called characters are less dimensional than cartoon characters. In fact, I've seen Saturday morning cartoons that are better than this. (Hint: Beep-Beep) As such, there is no empathy evoked for any of them. Just the opposite -- I felt nothing but contempt and disdain for the characters, the writers, and the director. Coupled with the fact that the humor is Neanderthal-like (i.e. slipping on a banana peel), this apparent spoof is nothing but a colossal flop. It strains the mind trying to grasp how in the world this movie rates as high as it does on IMDb.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Surreal Teen Angst Flick
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    aramis-112-804880
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dumped by Beth, his girlfriend (of six months), Lane Meyer (John Cusak) no longer wants to live . . . until he tries to kill himself. Then he always has seconds thoughts, just a moment too late. Fortunately, Lane is a failure at suicide as he is at everything else. Then he catches the eye of a French exchange student who may be a lifesaver. But don't worry, this is no "American Pie." The version I saw had no nudity apart from swimsuits and a little in actual sexual situations (as in the time Lane and Beth are making out in a station wagon while vandals are stealing the tires). Believe me, in this movie the last thing Lane wants is a relationship with food. Lane and the bully who stole his girlfriend finally face off at the climactic skiing scene to prove who is the better man. But this movie is so unpredictable you can't even assume Lane will best the bully, or whether he will want Beth back if he does. It sounds like one of the drearier John Hughes vehicles or even a stupid "Hot Dog -- the Motion Picture"; but "Better Off Dead" is really a surreal romp through high school, where a geometry teacher (Vincent Schiavelli) is listened to with awe and laughed at with genuine delight when he cracks jokes based on mathematical formulas. This is a world where bike-riding gangs of paperboys roam the streets, shaking down customers for two dollars, and where Lane's little brother makes a fully-operational laser and learns the secret of picking up trashy women. "Better off Dead" is too weird to be taken seriously for one moment, and you might think this undercuts the emotional unpinning of the story. Who cares if it does? It's hilarious. Even the bullies, who steal Lane's girlfriend, are funny and surreal. David Ogden Stiers plays Lane's clueless father, while Lane's mother (Kim Darby -- "True Grit") is such a rotten cook she gives her family frozen entr&eacute;es for Christmas presents. Lane's best friend is the brain-blown Charles De Mar (a scene-stealing Curtis Armstrong) who wonders at the street value of "snow" he finds on a mountaintop and, hearing another friend snorts nasal spray, says, "Where can I score some?" While "Better Off Dead" is not a classic of the teen-angst genre like "Ferris Bueller's Day Off" -- unlike Ferris, "Dead" is almost impossible to prize out of the '80s -- it is surprisingly funny and though it sounds like a perfect dark comedy there isn't really a mean bone in its body.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    For an 80s Teen Comedy, this is not a bad movie at all
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I remember seeing this movie back when I was a teenager and it is one of those movies that I remember watching just because. My friend purchased a copy of it and I watched it and realised that it is actually a very good movie. It is quite funny and pretty way out with a number of the characters (especially the main character and his family) being larger than life. Some will claim that this is quite excessive and makes for a bad comedy, but I think rather it appeals to people with a certain twisted sense of humor (like me). The movie opens with the main character getting up and we quickly learn that he is obsessed with his girlfriend. We know that he is obsessed because his room is plastered with her picture, and he sleeps with one, and her face is on all of his clothes hangers. Unfortunately, she would rather date the stuck up snob of a ski captain. When he finds this out he becomes suicidal, but he knows that life really isn't all that bad and changes his mind at the last minute, only to have something happen that triggers it anyway (such as his mother bursting into the room, knocking the stool over and thus mostly completing his attempt to hang himself). There are a lot of weird things in the movie, such as the two Japanese who race everybody, one not speaking a word of English and the other having learnt English off of the wide world of sports. His mother is just simply strange (she cannot cook, even though she claims that she can, and she has an obsession with wearing bizarre costumes) and his brother his a technological genius who is able to pick up more women than he can. His father seems sane and boring, but he is obsessed with his garage, and freaks out because it keeps on blowing up. There is the girl that dates the entire basketball team, and the team communicates only in grunts. Finally there is the paper boy who is obsessed with getting his $2 that he rides his bike down the most dangerous mountain in the town and goes flying over at cliff (and still survives). This movie is basically about obsession and pushes them too such an extreme that it is basically laughable. There is the main character's obsession with Beth, the ski-captains' obsession with himself (which is destroyed when he is beaten by the main character), the main character's friend, who is obsessed with drugs, and because there are less illegal drugs in the town than in the Pope's bathroom, he tries everything else (such as snorting snow from the mountain). The movie really doesn't outright say "obsessions are bad" but rather it portrays it in a light in which we simply see them as an absolute absurdity. Still, it is a great movie. Favourite quote: tis a damn shame when folks go and throw away a perfectly good white boy like that.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the funniest
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Cyrus Cousins
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    So called "Comedies" of today often attempt to have an emotional plot, with humor thrown in along the way, but all too often end up emotionless and unfunny, in essence failing miserably in all respects. Better Off Dead is no such film; Lane is a relatable protagonist, and his friends, family, and rivals are all very human. The plot is unique and over the top, but grounded in a solid emotional foundation that we can all understand. The characters are a bunch of weirdos, but in the best possible way, and they find themselves in one hilarious situation after the next. Today's filmmakers could learn a lot about film from this gem of the 80s.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    80s quirkfest that never really works
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zetes
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've seen bits of this before, and it always seemed amusing. Watching it in whole, though, I was very unimpressed. It has a very unique and quirky sense of humor, but, in my opinion, it hardly ever works. John Cusack plays a teen whose super cute and popular girlfriend dumps him for a jock. He spends the rest of the movie moping while cute French exchange student Diane Franklin starts to fall for him. The movie tries to set itself apart from the John Hughes comedies with its oddness, but in reality it reinforces the same stereotypes that every other 80s teen comedy does. Some of the cast is amusing, especially fat dork neighbor Dan Schneider, whose mother hosts Franklin almost as if she's ordering a male order bride for her social outcast son, and Kim Darby as Cusack's spaced-out mom. Curtis Armstrong pretty much reprises his role as Booger from Revenge of the Nerds as Cusack's best friend. I barely laughed at all during the flick. Even stuff that seemed amusing wasn't doing anything for me. I've seen Holland and Cusack's followup film, One Crazy Summer, and I remember liking that one better.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Harold and Maude
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tieman64
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Now that's a real shame when folks be throwin' away a perfectly good white boy like that."  Black Guy (Better Off Dead) John Cusack established his persona as a Gen X icon with "The Sure Thing", the tale of a down-and-out teenager whose life goes from bad to worse after losing his girlfriend to a popular, good looking ski captain. Deciding that life's not worth living without the woman of his dreams, our hero repeatedly attempts suicide. Each suicide attempt, of course, goes comically awry. People forget that Cusack spent the 80s as the poster boy for teenage angst and humour. He managed to pull off being a dork whilst still being cute and cool; think of him as Ferris Bueller with bad luck. "Better Off Dead" plays to Cusack's strengths as an emotionally shut down depressive (it's "Grosse Point Blank" the teenage years) and an excellent orator of deadpan humour and detached one-liners, but the film suffers from the usual stereotypical characters and situations that plague most of these "teenage romance" movies. Still, the film possesses a fairly strong cast, has some good gags, and a quirky sense of humour, director Savage Holland frequently nose-diving his narrative into nonsensical, surreal, wacky and fantastically absurd sequences. Examples: the film features dancing hamburgers, ten-year-olds with hookers, and ends with a spaceship blasting out of a house. Realism be damned. 7.5/10  A cult hit in the 80s, "Better Off Dead" is nevertheless nowhere near as good as Hal Ashby's "Harold and Maude", the film it most resembles. Worth one viewing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Original But Bizarre.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    John Cusack plays Lane Myer, an unhappy high school student who has just been dumped by his beloved girlfriend, and becomes confused and despondent. He must also deal with out-of-touch parents(Kim Darby & David Ogden Stiers) and a electronics genius younger brother, who is trying to build a spaceship in the back yard. He then decides to commit suicide, but can't quite decide how to do it... Strange comedy(to say the least!) is undeniably funny at times, and Cusak is appealing, but film is so far off-the-wall, that it leaves the house altogether! Originality will only get you so far; there has to be some grounding in reality! Still, this does have its moments, and a surprisingly good heart, despite its premise. Once seen, it wont be quickly forgotten...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Silly, Sweet and Shrewd, It's the Moviegoer's Eighties in a Nutshell
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sean Lamberger
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Starring an in-his-element John Cusack, there's no question why this one's still remembered so fondly today: it's a great embodiment of everything one could expect to see from a zany '80s teen-geared comedy. Although Cusack plays his role with a typically dark slant (and many of the jokes are similarly themed), the film's general outlook is upbeat and silly, which makes for a tasty pairing. Occasionally it ventures too far into the realm of the absurd, such as the scene where Cusack's character daydreams a romancing pair of claymation cheeseburgers (which, naturally, pantomime to Van Halen), but it's also those dalliances into surrealism that provide many of its best moments. Funny as both a dated glimpse at life in the mid-eighties and a timeless relation to teenaged heartbreak, it's enriched by a sweet romantic subplot and a vast array of colorful supporting characters.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sheer Genius
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    eti55
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's a pity Savage Steve Holland didn't do more flicks. What he did with Better Off Dead was take the whole John Hughes 80s teen angst comedy and put it in full TILT mode. Everything about this movie is off center, from Layne Meyer's (played by John Cusack) total obsession with a heartless biotch of a g/f who dumps him (he has a picture of her on all of his shirt hangers), to the Chinese guy who taunts Layne while doing a perfect Howard Cosell imitation, to the insane paper boy obsessed with his two dollars, to Layne's younger brother who becomes a ladies man after reading a book on how to pick up trashy women (he also manages to build a space shuttle out of household items..again, after reading a book on it). There's even some trick skiing thrown in (it's set at a ski resort town). Yes, the end of the story is predictable (he gets the girl..the RIGHT girl); it's the way the movie gets there that's so warped. If you're the type of person that takes everything around them seriously including themselves, skip this movie. But if you like stuff that's stupid, silly and BENT (as yours truly does), definitely check this one out.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ranks up there with some of Johns Huges' best movies.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kdnor2011
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Better off Dead isn't quite as good as The Breakfast Club or Ferris Bueller's Day off, but I actually think it's better than 16 Candles and Weird Science. It does the two things that all John Hughes movies do really well. Have the quirky comedy that is really funny, and have the teenage kids actually act like teenage kids. It's interesting to see Dan Schnieder back in the 80s when he was just acting instead of working on shows like All That, Amanda Show, Drake and Josh, Zoey 101, and iCarly. He also makes me feel better about my weight, because at least I'm not as fat as him. The film is just funny, it gets all the quirky elements of being a teenager down that you can't help but laugh. And like I said earlier, it does a good job of showing how hard it is to be a teenager. Teens have to worry about their future, friends, love life, school work, peer pressure, and most have part time jobs. Like I said, it doesn't match Breakfast Club or Ferris bueller, but I like it more than 16 Candles and Weird Science.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Better Off...before I ever watched it
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    s k
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is a poor man's (or woman's) version of Ferris Bueller's Day Off, or Fast Times At Ridgemount High -- without the humor, heart, soul, charm, music, screen chemistry, or creativity of those films. It's a sophomoric attempt, at best, to display high school heartache, that fails miserably. There is not a single solitary likable character (with the possible exception of Monique); and I use the term character rather loosely when it comes to this disaster. The so-called characters are less dimensional than cartoon characters. In fact, I've seen Saturday morning cartoons that are better than this. (Hint: Beep-Beep) As such, there is no empathy evoked for any of them. Just the opposite -- I felt nothing but contempt and disdain for the characters, the writers, and the director. Coupled with the fact that the humor is Neanderthal-like (i.e. slipping on a banana peel), this apparent spoof is nothing but a colossal flop. It strains the mind trying to grasp how in the world this movie rates as high as it does on IMDb.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Surreal Teen Angst Flick
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    aramis-112-804880
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dumped by Beth, his girlfriend (of six months), Lane Meyer (John Cusak) no longer wants to live . . . until he tries to kill himself. Then he always has seconds thoughts, just a moment too late. Fortunately, Lane is a failure at suicide as he is at everything else. Then he catches the eye of a French exchange student who may be a lifesaver. But don't worry, this is no "American Pie." The version I saw had no nudity apart from swimsuits and a little in actual sexual situations (as in the time Lane and Beth are making out in a station wagon while vandals are stealing the tires). Believe me, in this movie the last thing Lane wants is a relationship with food. Lane and the bully who stole his girlfriend finally face off at the climactic skiing scene to prove who is the better man. But this movie is so unpredictable you can't even assume Lane will best the bully, or whether he will want Beth back if he does. It sounds like one of the drearier John Hughes vehicles or even a stupid "Hot Dog -- the Motion Picture"; but "Better Off Dead" is really a surreal romp through high school, where a geometry teacher (Vincent Schiavelli) is listened to with awe and laughed at with genuine delight when he cracks jokes based on mathematical formulas. This is a world where bike-riding gangs of paperboys roam the streets, shaking down customers for two dollars, and where Lane's little brother makes a fully-operational laser and learns the secret of picking up trashy women. "Better off Dead" is too weird to be taken seriously for one moment, and you might think this undercuts the emotional unpinning of the story. Who cares if it does? It's hilarious. Even the bullies, who steal Lane's girlfriend, are funny and surreal. David Ogden Stiers plays Lane's clueless father, while Lane's mother (Kim Darby -- "True Grit") is such a rotten cook she gives her family frozen entr&eacute;es for Christmas presents. Lane's best friend is the brain-blown Charles De Mar (a scene-stealing Curtis Armstrong) who wonders at the street value of "snow" he finds on a mountaintop and, hearing another friend snorts nasal spray, says, "Where can I score some?" While "Better Off Dead" is not a classic of the teen-angst genre like "Ferris Bueller's Day Off" -- unlike Ferris, "Dead" is almost impossible to prize out of the '80s -- it is surprisingly funny and though it sounds like a perfect dark comedy there isn't really a mean bone in its body.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    For an 80s Teen Comedy, this is not a bad movie at all
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I remember seeing this movie back when I was a teenager and it is one of those movies that I remember watching just because. My friend purchased a copy of it and I watched it and realised that it is actually a very good movie. It is quite funny and pretty way out with a number of the characters (especially the main character and his family) being larger than life. Some will claim that this is quite excessive and makes for a bad comedy, but I think rather it appeals to people with a certain twisted sense of humor (like me). The movie opens with the main character getting up and we quickly learn that he is obsessed with his girlfriend. We know that he is obsessed because his room is plastered with her picture, and he sleeps with one, and her face is on all of his clothes hangers. Unfortunately, she would rather date the stuck up snob of a ski captain. When he finds this out he becomes suicidal, but he knows that life really isn't all that bad and changes his mind at the last minute, only to have something happen that triggers it anyway (such as his mother bursting into the room, knocking the stool over and thus mostly completing his attempt to hang himself). There are a lot of weird things in the movie, such as the two Japanese who race everybody, one not speaking a word of English and the other having learnt English off of the wide world of sports. His mother is just simply strange (she cannot cook, even though she claims that she can, and she has an obsession with wearing bizarre costumes) and his brother his a technological genius who is able to pick up more women than he can. His father seems sane and boring, but he is obsessed with his garage, and freaks out because it keeps on blowing up. There is the girl that dates the entire basketball team, and the team communicates only in grunts. Finally there is the paper boy who is obsessed with getting his $2 that he rides his bike down the most dangerous mountain in the town and goes flying over at cliff (and still survives). This movie is basically about obsession and pushes them too such an extreme that it is basically laughable. There is the main character's obsession with Beth, the ski-captains' obsession with himself (which is destroyed when he is beaten by the main character), the main character's friend, who is obsessed with drugs, and because there are less illegal drugs in the town than in the Pope's bathroom, he tries everything else (such as snorting snow from the mountain). The movie really doesn't outright say "obsessions are bad" but rather it portrays it in a light in which we simply see them as an absolute absurdity. Still, it is a great movie. Favourite quote: tis a damn shame when folks go and throw away a perfectly good white boy like that.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the funniest
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Cyrus Cousins
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    So called "Comedies" of today often attempt to have an emotional plot, with humor thrown in along the way, but all too often end up emotionless and unfunny, in essence failing miserably in all respects. Better Off Dead is no such film; Lane is a relatable protagonist, and his friends, family, and rivals are all very human. The plot is unique and over the top, but grounded in a solid emotional foundation that we can all understand. The characters are a bunch of weirdos, but in the best possible way, and they find themselves in one hilarious situation after the next. Today's filmmakers could learn a lot about film from this gem of the 80s.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    80s quirkfest that never really works
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zetes
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've seen bits of this before, and it always seemed amusing. Watching it in whole, though, I was very unimpressed. It has a very unique and quirky sense of humor, but, in my opinion, it hardly ever works. John Cusack plays a teen whose super cute and popular girlfriend dumps him for a jock. He spends the rest of the movie moping while cute French exchange student Diane Franklin starts to fall for him. The movie tries to set itself apart from the John Hughes comedies with its oddness, but in reality it reinforces the same stereotypes that every other 80s teen comedy does. Some of the cast is amusing, especially fat dork neighbor Dan Schneider, whose mother hosts Franklin almost as if she's ordering a male order bride for her social outcast son, and Kim Darby as Cusack's spaced-out mom. Curtis Armstrong pretty much reprises his role as Booger from Revenge of the Nerds as Cusack's best friend. I barely laughed at all during the flick. Even stuff that seemed amusing wasn't doing anything for me. I've seen Holland and Cusack's followup film, One Crazy Summer, and I remember liking that one better.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Harold and Maude
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tieman64
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Now that's a real shame when folks be throwin' away a perfectly good white boy like that."  Black Guy (Better Off Dead) John Cusack established his persona as a Gen X icon with "The Sure Thing", the tale of a down-and-out teenager whose life goes from bad to worse after losing his girlfriend to a popular, good looking ski captain. Deciding that life's not worth living without the woman of his dreams, our hero repeatedly attempts suicide. Each suicide attempt, of course, goes comically awry. People forget that Cusack spent the 80s as the poster boy for teenage angst and humour. He managed to pull off being a dork whilst still being cute and cool; think of him as Ferris Bueller with bad luck. "Better Off Dead" plays to Cusack's strengths as an emotionally shut down depressive (it's "Grosse Point Blank" the teenage years) and an excellent orator of deadpan humour and detached one-liners, but the film suffers from the usual stereotypical characters and situations that plague most of these "teenage romance" movies. Still, the film possesses a fairly strong cast, has some good gags, and a quirky sense of humour, director Savage Holland frequently nose-diving his narrative into nonsensical, surreal, wacky and fantastically absurd sequences. Examples: the film features dancing hamburgers, ten-year-olds with hookers, and ends with a spaceship blasting out of a house. Realism be damned. 7.5/10  A cult hit in the 80s, "Better Off Dead" is nevertheless nowhere near as good as Hal Ashby's "Harold and Maude", the film it most resembles. Worth one viewing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Original But Bizarre.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    John Cusack plays Lane Myer, an unhappy high school student who has just been dumped by his beloved girlfriend, and becomes confused and despondent. He must also deal with out-of-touch parents(Kim Darby & David Ogden Stiers) and a electronics genius younger brother, who is trying to build a spaceship in the back yard. He then decides to commit suicide, but can't quite decide how to do it... Strange comedy(to say the least!) is undeniably funny at times, and Cusak is appealing, but film is so far off-the-wall, that it leaves the house altogether! Originality will only get you so far; there has to be some grounding in reality! Still, this does have its moments, and a surprisingly good heart, despite its premise. Once seen, it wont be quickly forgotten...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Silly, Sweet and Shrewd, It's the Moviegoer's Eighties in a Nutshell
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sean Lamberger
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Starring an in-his-element John Cusack, there's no question why this one's still remembered so fondly today: it's a great embodiment of everything one could expect to see from a zany '80s teen-geared comedy. Although Cusack plays his role with a typically dark slant (and many of the jokes are similarly themed), the film's general outlook is upbeat and silly, which makes for a tasty pairing. Occasionally it ventures too far into the realm of the absurd, such as the scene where Cusack's character daydreams a romancing pair of claymation cheeseburgers (which, naturally, pantomime to Van Halen), but it's also those dalliances into surrealism that provide many of its best moments. Funny as both a dated glimpse at life in the mid-eighties and a timeless relation to teenaged heartbreak, it's enriched by a sweet romantic subplot and a vast array of colorful supporting characters.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sheer Genius
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    eti55
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's a pity Savage Steve Holland didn't do more flicks. What he did with Better Off Dead was take the whole John Hughes 80s teen angst comedy and put it in full TILT mode. Everything about this movie is off center, from Layne Meyer's (played by John Cusack) total obsession with a heartless biotch of a g/f who dumps him (he has a picture of her on all of his shirt hangers), to the Chinese guy who taunts Layne while doing a perfect Howard Cosell imitation, to the insane paper boy obsessed with his two dollars, to Layne's younger brother who becomes a ladies man after reading a book on how to pick up trashy women (he also manages to build a space shuttle out of household items..again, after reading a book on it). There's even some trick skiing thrown in (it's set at a ski resort town). Yes, the end of the story is predictable (he gets the girl..the RIGHT girl); it's the way the movie gets there that's so warped. If you're the type of person that takes everything around them seriously including themselves, skip this movie. But if you like stuff that's stupid, silly and BENT (as yours truly does), definitely check this one out.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ranks up there with some of Johns Huges' best movies.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kdnor2011
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Better off Dead isn't quite as good as The Breakfast Club or Ferris Bueller's Day off, but I actually think it's better than 16 Candles and Weird Science. It does the two things that all John Hughes movies do really well. Have the quirky comedy that is really funny, and have the teenage kids actually act like teenage kids. It's interesting to see Dan Schnieder back in the 80s when he was just acting instead of working on shows like All That, Amanda Show, Drake and Josh, Zoey 101, and iCarly. He also makes me feel better about my weight, because at least I'm not as fat as him. The film is just funny, it gets all the quirky elements of being a teenager down that you can't help but laugh. And like I said earlier, it does a good job of showing how hard it is to be a teenager. Teens have to worry about their future, friends, love life, school work, peer pressure, and most have part time jobs. Like I said, it doesn't match Breakfast Club or Ferris bueller, but I like it more than 16 Candles and Weird Science.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Better Off...before I ever watched it
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    s k
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is a poor man's (or woman's) version of Ferris Bueller's Day Off, or Fast Times At Ridgemount High -- without the humor, heart, soul, charm, music, screen chemistry, or creativity of those films. It's a sophomoric attempt, at best, to display high school heartache, that fails miserably. There is not a single solitary likable character (with the possible exception of Monique); and I use the term character rather loosely when it comes to this disaster. The so-called characters are less dimensional than cartoon characters. In fact, I've seen Saturday morning cartoons that are better than this. (Hint: Beep-Beep) As such, there is no empathy evoked for any of them. Just the opposite -- I felt nothing but contempt and disdain for the characters, the writers, and the director. Coupled with the fact that the humor is Neanderthal-like (i.e. slipping on a banana peel), this apparent spoof is nothing but a colossal flop. It strains the mind trying to grasp how in the world this movie rates as high as it does on IMDb.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Surreal Teen Angst Flick
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    aramis-112-804880
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dumped by Beth, his girlfriend (of six months), Lane Meyer (John Cusak) no longer wants to live . . . until he tries to kill himself. Then he always has seconds thoughts, just a moment too late. Fortunately, Lane is a failure at suicide as he is at everything else. Then he catches the eye of a French exchange student who may be a lifesaver. But don't worry, this is no "American Pie." The version I saw had no nudity apart from swimsuits and a little in actual sexual situations (as in the time Lane and Beth are making out in a station wagon while vandals are stealing the tires). Believe me, in this movie the last thing Lane wants is a relationship with food. Lane and the bully who stole his girlfriend finally face off at the climactic skiing scene to prove who is the better man. But this movie is so unpredictable you can't even assume Lane will best the bully, or whether he will want Beth back if he does. It sounds like one of the drearier John Hughes vehicles or even a stupid "Hot Dog -- the Motion Picture"; but "Better Off Dead" is really a surreal romp through high school, where a geometry teacher (Vincent Schiavelli) is listened to with awe and laughed at with genuine delight when he cracks jokes based on mathematical formulas. This is a world where bike-riding gangs of paperboys roam the streets, shaking down customers for two dollars, and where Lane's little brother makes a fully-operational laser and learns the secret of picking up trashy women. "Better off Dead" is too weird to be taken seriously for one moment, and you might think this undercuts the emotional unpinning of the story. Who cares if it does? It's hilarious. Even the bullies, who steal Lane's girlfriend, are funny and surreal. David Ogden Stiers plays Lane's clueless father, while Lane's mother (Kim Darby -- "True Grit") is such a rotten cook she gives her family frozen entr&eacute;es for Christmas presents. Lane's best friend is the brain-blown Charles De Mar (a scene-stealing Curtis Armstrong) who wonders at the street value of "snow" he finds on a mountaintop and, hearing another friend snorts nasal spray, says, "Where can I score some?" While "Better Off Dead" is not a classic of the teen-angst genre like "Ferris Bueller's Day Off" -- unlike Ferris, "Dead" is almost impossible to prize out of the '80s -- it is surprisingly funny and though it sounds like a perfect dark comedy there isn't really a mean bone in its body.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    For an 80s Teen Comedy, this is not a bad movie at all
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I remember seeing this movie back when I was a teenager and it is one of those movies that I remember watching just because. My friend purchased a copy of it and I watched it and realised that it is actually a very good movie. It is quite funny and pretty way out with a number of the characters (especially the main character and his family) being larger than life. Some will claim that this is quite excessive and makes for a bad comedy, but I think rather it appeals to people with a certain twisted sense of humor (like me). The movie opens with the main character getting up and we quickly learn that he is obsessed with his girlfriend. We know that he is obsessed because his room is plastered with her picture, and he sleeps with one, and her face is on all of his clothes hangers. Unfortunately, she would rather date the stuck up snob of a ski captain. When he finds this out he becomes suicidal, but he knows that life really isn't all that bad and changes his mind at the last minute, only to have something happen that triggers it anyway (such as his mother bursting into the room, knocking the stool over and thus mostly completing his attempt to hang himself). There are a lot of weird things in the movie, such as the two Japanese who race everybody, one not speaking a word of English and the other having learnt English off of the wide world of sports. His mother is just simply strange (she cannot cook, even though she claims that she can, and she has an obsession with wearing bizarre costumes) and his brother his a technological genius who is able to pick up more women than he can. His father seems sane and boring, but he is obsessed with his garage, and freaks out because it keeps on blowing up. There is the girl that dates the entire basketball team, and the team communicates only in grunts. Finally there is the paper boy who is obsessed with getting his $2 that he rides his bike down the most dangerous mountain in the town and goes flying over at cliff (and still survives). This movie is basically about obsession and pushes them too such an extreme that it is basically laughable. There is the main character's obsession with Beth, the ski-captains' obsession with himself (which is destroyed when he is beaten by the main character), the main character's friend, who is obsessed with drugs, and because there are less illegal drugs in the town than in the Pope's bathroom, he tries everything else (such as snorting snow from the mountain). The movie really doesn't outright say "obsessions are bad" but rather it portrays it in a light in which we simply see them as an absolute absurdity. Still, it is a great movie. Favourite quote: tis a damn shame when folks go and throw away a perfectly good white boy like that.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the funniest
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Cyrus Cousins
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    So called "Comedies" of today often attempt to have an emotional plot, with humor thrown in along the way, but all too often end up emotionless and unfunny, in essence failing miserably in all respects. Better Off Dead is no such film; Lane is a relatable protagonist, and his friends, family, and rivals are all very human. The plot is unique and over the top, but grounded in a solid emotional foundation that we can all understand. The characters are a bunch of weirdos, but in the best possible way, and they find themselves in one hilarious situation after the next. Today's filmmakers could learn a lot about film from this gem of the 80s.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    80s quirkfest that never really works
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zetes
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've seen bits of this before, and it always seemed amusing. Watching it in whole, though, I was very unimpressed. It has a very unique and quirky sense of humor, but, in my opinion, it hardly ever works. John Cusack plays a teen whose super cute and popular girlfriend dumps him for a jock. He spends the rest of the movie moping while cute French exchange student Diane Franklin starts to fall for him. The movie tries to set itself apart from the John Hughes comedies with its oddness, but in reality it reinforces the same stereotypes that every other 80s teen comedy does. Some of the cast is amusing, especially fat dork neighbor Dan Schneider, whose mother hosts Franklin almost as if she's ordering a male order bride for her social outcast son, and Kim Darby as Cusack's spaced-out mom. Curtis Armstrong pretty much reprises his role as Booger from Revenge of the Nerds as Cusack's best friend. I barely laughed at all during the flick. Even stuff that seemed amusing wasn't doing anything for me. I've seen Holland and Cusack's followup film, One Crazy Summer, and I remember liking that one better.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Harold and Maude
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tieman64
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Now that's a real shame when folks be throwin' away a perfectly good white boy like that."  Black Guy (Better Off Dead) John Cusack established his persona as a Gen X icon with "The Sure Thing", the tale of a down-and-out teenager whose life goes from bad to worse after losing his girlfriend to a popular, good looking ski captain. Deciding that life's not worth living without the woman of his dreams, our hero repeatedly attempts suicide. Each suicide attempt, of course, goes comically awry. People forget that Cusack spent the 80s as the poster boy for teenage angst and humour. He managed to pull off being a dork whilst still being cute and cool; think of him as Ferris Bueller with bad luck. "Better Off Dead" plays to Cusack's strengths as an emotionally shut down depressive (it's "Grosse Point Blank" the teenage years) and an excellent orator of deadpan humour and detached one-liners, but the film suffers from the usual stereotypical characters and situations that plague most of these "teenage romance" movies. Still, the film possesses a fairly strong cast, has some good gags, and a quirky sense of humour, director Savage Holland frequently nose-diving his narrative into nonsensical, surreal, wacky and fantastically absurd sequences. Examples: the film features dancing hamburgers, ten-year-olds with hookers, and ends with a spaceship blasting out of a house. Realism be damned. 7.5/10  A cult hit in the 80s, "Better Off Dead" is nevertheless nowhere near as good as Hal Ashby's "Harold and Maude", the film it most resembles. Worth one viewing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Original But Bizarre.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    John Cusack plays Lane Myer, an unhappy high school student who has just been dumped by his beloved girlfriend, and becomes confused and despondent. He must also deal with out-of-touch parents(Kim Darby & David Ogden Stiers) and a electronics genius younger brother, who is trying to build a spaceship in the back yard. He then decides to commit suicide, but can't quite decide how to do it... Strange comedy(to say the least!) is undeniably funny at times, and Cusak is appealing, but film is so far off-the-wall, that it leaves the house altogether! Originality will only get you so far; there has to be some grounding in reality! Still, this does have its moments, and a surprisingly good heart, despite its premise. Once seen, it wont be quickly forgotten...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Silly, Sweet and Shrewd, It's the Moviegoer's Eighties in a Nutshell
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sean Lamberger
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Starring an in-his-element John Cusack, there's no question why this one's still remembered so fondly today: it's a great embodiment of everything one could expect to see from a zany '80s teen-geared comedy. Although Cusack plays his role with a typically dark slant (and many of the jokes are similarly themed), the film's general outlook is upbeat and silly, which makes for a tasty pairing. Occasionally it ventures too far into the realm of the absurd, such as the scene where Cusack's character daydreams a romancing pair of claymation cheeseburgers (which, naturally, pantomime to Van Halen), but it's also those dalliances into surrealism that provide many of its best moments. Funny as both a dated glimpse at life in the mid-eighties and a timeless relation to teenaged heartbreak, it's enriched by a sweet romantic subplot and a vast array of colorful supporting characters.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sheer Genius
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    eti55
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's a pity Savage Steve Holland didn't do more flicks. What he did with Better Off Dead was take the whole John Hughes 80s teen angst comedy and put it in full TILT mode. Everything about this movie is off center, from Layne Meyer's (played by John Cusack) total obsession with a heartless biotch of a g/f who dumps him (he has a picture of her on all of his shirt hangers), to the Chinese guy who taunts Layne while doing a perfect Howard Cosell imitation, to the insane paper boy obsessed with his two dollars, to Layne's younger brother who becomes a ladies man after reading a book on how to pick up trashy women (he also manages to build a space shuttle out of household items..again, after reading a book on it). There's even some trick skiing thrown in (it's set at a ski resort town). Yes, the end of the story is predictable (he gets the girl..the RIGHT girl); it's the way the movie gets there that's so warped. If you're the type of person that takes everything around them seriously including themselves, skip this movie. But if you like stuff that's stupid, silly and BENT (as yours truly does), definitely check this one out.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ranks up there with some of Johns Huges' best movies.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kdnor2011
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Better off Dead isn't quite as good as The Breakfast Club or Ferris Bueller's Day off, but I actually think it's better than 16 Candles and Weird Science. It does the two things that all John Hughes movies do really well. Have the quirky comedy that is really funny, and have the teenage kids actually act like teenage kids. It's interesting to see Dan Schnieder back in the 80s when he was just acting instead of working on shows like All That, Amanda Show, Drake and Josh, Zoey 101, and iCarly. He also makes me feel better about my weight, because at least I'm not as fat as him. The film is just funny, it gets all the quirky elements of being a teenager down that you can't help but laugh. And like I said earlier, it does a good job of showing how hard it is to be a teenager. Teens have to worry about their future, friends, love life, school work, peer pressure, and most have part time jobs. Like I said, it doesn't match Breakfast Club or Ferris bueller, but I like it more than 16 Candles and Weird Science.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Better Off...before I ever watched it
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    s k
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is a poor man's (or woman's) version of Ferris Bueller's Day Off, or Fast Times At Ridgemount High -- without the humor, heart, soul, charm, music, screen chemistry, or creativity of those films. It's a sophomoric attempt, at best, to display high school heartache, that fails miserably. There is not a single solitary likable character (with the possible exception of Monique); and I use the term character rather loosely when it comes to this disaster. The so-called characters are less dimensional than cartoon characters. In fact, I've seen Saturday morning cartoons that are better than this. (Hint: Beep-Beep) As such, there is no empathy evoked for any of them. Just the opposite -- I felt nothing but contempt and disdain for the characters, the writers, and the director. Coupled with the fact that the humor is Neanderthal-like (i.e. slipping on a banana peel), this apparent spoof is nothing but a colossal flop. It strains the mind trying to grasp how in the world this movie rates as high as it does on IMDb.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Surreal Teen Angst Flick
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    aramis-112-804880
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dumped by Beth, his girlfriend (of six months), Lane Meyer (John Cusak) no longer wants to live . . . until he tries to kill himself. Then he always has seconds thoughts, just a moment too late. Fortunately, Lane is a failure at suicide as he is at everything else. Then he catches the eye of a French exchange student who may be a lifesaver. But don't worry, this is no "American Pie." The version I saw had no nudity apart from swimsuits and a little in actual sexual situations (as in the time Lane and Beth are making out in a station wagon while vandals are stealing the tires). Believe me, in this movie the last thing Lane wants is a relationship with food. Lane and the bully who stole his girlfriend finally face off at the climactic skiing scene to prove who is the better man. But this movie is so unpredictable you can't even assume Lane will best the bully, or whether he will want Beth back if he does. It sounds like one of the drearier John Hughes vehicles or even a stupid "Hot Dog -- the Motion Picture"; but "Better Off Dead" is really a surreal romp through high school, where a geometry teacher (Vincent Schiavelli) is listened to with awe and laughed at with genuine delight when he cracks jokes based on mathematical formulas. This is a world where bike-riding gangs of paperboys roam the streets, shaking down customers for two dollars, and where Lane's little brother makes a fully-operational laser and learns the secret of picking up trashy women. "Better off Dead" is too weird to be taken seriously for one moment, and you might think this undercuts the emotional unpinning of the story. Who cares if it does? It's hilarious. Even the bullies, who steal Lane's girlfriend, are funny and surreal. David Ogden Stiers plays Lane's clueless father, while Lane's mother (Kim Darby -- "True Grit") is such a rotten cook she gives her family frozen entr&eacute;es for Christmas presents. Lane's best friend is the brain-blown Charles De Mar (a scene-stealing Curtis Armstrong) who wonders at the street value of "snow" he finds on a mountaintop and, hearing another friend snorts nasal spray, says, "Where can I score some?" While "Better Off Dead" is not a classic of the teen-angst genre like "Ferris Bueller's Day Off" -- unlike Ferris, "Dead" is almost impossible to prize out of the '80s -- it is surprisingly funny and though it sounds like a perfect dark comedy there isn't really a mean bone in its body.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    For an 80s Teen Comedy, this is not a bad movie at all
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I remember seeing this movie back when I was a teenager and it is one of those movies that I remember watching just because. My friend purchased a copy of it and I watched it and realised that it is actually a very good movie. It is quite funny and pretty way out with a number of the characters (especially the main character and his family) being larger than life. Some will claim that this is quite excessive and makes for a bad comedy, but I think rather it appeals to people with a certain twisted sense of humor (like me). The movie opens with the main character getting up and we quickly learn that he is obsessed with his girlfriend. We know that he is obsessed because his room is plastered with her picture, and he sleeps with one, and her face is on all of his clothes hangers. Unfortunately, she would rather date the stuck up snob of a ski captain. When he finds this out he becomes suicidal, but he knows that life really isn't all that bad and changes his mind at the last minute, only to have something happen that triggers it anyway (such as his mother bursting into the room, knocking the stool over and thus mostly completing his attempt to hang himself). There are a lot of weird things in the movie, such as the two Japanese who race everybody, one not speaking a word of English and the other having learnt English off of the wide world of sports. His mother is just simply strange (she cannot cook, even though she claims that she can, and she has an obsession with wearing bizarre costumes) and his brother his a technological genius who is able to pick up more women than he can. His father seems sane and boring, but he is obsessed with his garage, and freaks out because it keeps on blowing up. There is the girl that dates the entire basketball team, and the team communicates only in grunts. Finally there is the paper boy who is obsessed with getting his $2 that he rides his bike down the most dangerous mountain in the town and goes flying over at cliff (and still survives). This movie is basically about obsession and pushes them too such an extreme that it is basically laughable. There is the main character's obsession with Beth, the ski-captains' obsession with himself (which is destroyed when he is beaten by the main character), the main character's friend, who is obsessed with drugs, and because there are less illegal drugs in the town than in the Pope's bathroom, he tries everything else (such as snorting snow from the mountain). The movie really doesn't outright say "obsessions are bad" but rather it portrays it in a light in which we simply see them as an absolute absurdity. Still, it is a great movie. Favourite quote: tis a damn shame when folks go and throw away a perfectly good white boy like that.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the funniest
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Cyrus Cousins
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    So called "Comedies" of today often attempt to have an emotional plot, with humor thrown in along the way, but all too often end up emotionless and unfunny, in essence failing miserably in all respects. Better Off Dead is no such film; Lane is a relatable protagonist, and his friends, family, and rivals are all very human. The plot is unique and over the top, but grounded in a solid emotional foundation that we can all understand. The characters are a bunch of weirdos, but in the best possible way, and they find themselves in one hilarious situation after the next. Today's filmmakers could learn a lot about film from this gem of the 80s.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    80s quirkfest that never really works
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zetes
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've seen bits of this before, and it always seemed amusing. Watching it in whole, though, I was very unimpressed. It has a very unique and quirky sense of humor, but, in my opinion, it hardly ever works. John Cusack plays a teen whose super cute and popular girlfriend dumps him for a jock. He spends the rest of the movie moping while cute French exchange student Diane Franklin starts to fall for him. The movie tries to set itself apart from the John Hughes comedies with its oddness, but in reality it reinforces the same stereotypes that every other 80s teen comedy does. Some of the cast is amusing, especially fat dork neighbor Dan Schneider, whose mother hosts Franklin almost as if she's ordering a male order bride for her social outcast son, and Kim Darby as Cusack's spaced-out mom. Curtis Armstrong pretty much reprises his role as Booger from Revenge of the Nerds as Cusack's best friend. I barely laughed at all during the flick. Even stuff that seemed amusing wasn't doing anything for me. I've seen Holland and Cusack's followup film, One Crazy Summer, and I remember liking that one better.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Harold and Maude
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tieman64
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Now that's a real shame when folks be throwin' away a perfectly good white boy like that."  Black Guy (Better Off Dead) John Cusack established his persona as a Gen X icon with "The Sure Thing", the tale of a down-and-out teenager whose life goes from bad to worse after losing his girlfriend to a popular, good looking ski captain. Deciding that life's not worth living without the woman of his dreams, our hero repeatedly attempts suicide. Each suicide attempt, of course, goes comically awry. People forget that Cusack spent the 80s as the poster boy for teenage angst and humour. He managed to pull off being a dork whilst still being cute and cool; think of him as Ferris Bueller with bad luck. "Better Off Dead" plays to Cusack's strengths as an emotionally shut down depressive (it's "Grosse Point Blank" the teenage years) and an excellent orator of deadpan humour and detached one-liners, but the film suffers from the usual stereotypical characters and situations that plague most of these "teenage romance" movies. Still, the film possesses a fairly strong cast, has some good gags, and a quirky sense of humour, director Savage Holland frequently nose-diving his narrative into nonsensical, surreal, wacky and fantastically absurd sequences. Examples: the film features dancing hamburgers, ten-year-olds with hookers, and ends with a spaceship blasting out of a house. Realism be damned. 7.5/10  A cult hit in the 80s, "Better Off Dead" is nevertheless nowhere near as good as Hal Ashby's "Harold and Maude", the film it most resembles. Worth one viewing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Original But Bizarre.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    John Cusack plays Lane Myer, an unhappy high school student who has just been dumped by his beloved girlfriend, and becomes confused and despondent. He must also deal with out-of-touch parents(Kim Darby & David Ogden Stiers) and a electronics genius younger brother, who is trying to build a spaceship in the back yard. He then decides to commit suicide, but can't quite decide how to do it... Strange comedy(to say the least!) is undeniably funny at times, and Cusak is appealing, but film is so far off-the-wall, that it leaves the house altogether! Originality will only get you so far; there has to be some grounding in reality! Still, this does have its moments, and a surprisingly good heart, despite its premise. Once seen, it wont be quickly forgotten...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Silly, Sweet and Shrewd, It's the Moviegoer's Eighties in a Nutshell
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sean Lamberger
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Starring an in-his-element John Cusack, there's no question why this one's still remembered so fondly today: it's a great embodiment of everything one could expect to see from a zany '80s teen-geared comedy. Although Cusack plays his role with a typically dark slant (and many of the jokes are similarly themed), the film's general outlook is upbeat and silly, which makes for a tasty pairing. Occasionally it ventures too far into the realm of the absurd, such as the scene where Cusack's character daydreams a romancing pair of claymation cheeseburgers (which, naturally, pantomime to Van Halen), but it's also those dalliances into surrealism that provide many of its best moments. Funny as both a dated glimpse at life in the mid-eighties and a timeless relation to teenaged heartbreak, it's enriched by a sweet romantic subplot and a vast array of colorful supporting characters.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sheer Genius
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    eti55
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's a pity Savage Steve Holland didn't do more flicks. What he did with Better Off Dead was take the whole John Hughes 80s teen angst comedy and put it in full TILT mode. Everything about this movie is off center, from Layne Meyer's (played by John Cusack) total obsession with a heartless biotch of a g/f who dumps him (he has a picture of her on all of his shirt hangers), to the Chinese guy who taunts Layne while doing a perfect Howard Cosell imitation, to the insane paper boy obsessed with his two dollars, to Layne's younger brother who becomes a ladies man after reading a book on how to pick up trashy women (he also manages to build a space shuttle out of household items..again, after reading a book on it). There's even some trick skiing thrown in (it's set at a ski resort town). Yes, the end of the story is predictable (he gets the girl..the RIGHT girl); it's the way the movie gets there that's so warped. If you're the type of person that takes everything around them seriously including themselves, skip this movie. But if you like stuff that's stupid, silly and BENT (as yours truly does), definitely check this one out.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ranks up there with some of Johns Huges' best movies.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kdnor2011
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Better off Dead isn't quite as good as The Breakfast Club or Ferris Bueller's Day off, but I actually think it's better than 16 Candles and Weird Science. It does the two things that all John Hughes movies do really well. Have the quirky comedy that is really funny, and have the teenage kids actually act like teenage kids. It's interesting to see Dan Schnieder back in the 80s when he was just acting instead of working on shows like All That, Amanda Show, Drake and Josh, Zoey 101, and iCarly. He also makes me feel better about my weight, because at least I'm not as fat as him. The film is just funny, it gets all the quirky elements of being a teenager down that you can't help but laugh. And like I said earlier, it does a good job of showing how hard it is to be a teenager. Teens have to worry about their future, friends, love life, school work, peer pressure, and most have part time jobs. Like I said, it doesn't match Breakfast Club or Ferris bueller, but I like it more than 16 Candles and Weird Science.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Better Off...before I ever watched it
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    s k
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is a poor man's (or woman's) version of Ferris Bueller's Day Off, or Fast Times At Ridgemount High -- without the humor, heart, soul, charm, music, screen chemistry, or creativity of those films. It's a sophomoric attempt, at best, to display high school heartache, that fails miserably. There is not a single solitary likable character (with the possible exception of Monique); and I use the term character rather loosely when it comes to this disaster. The so-called characters are less dimensional than cartoon characters. In fact, I've seen Saturday morning cartoons that are better than this. (Hint: Beep-Beep) As such, there is no empathy evoked for any of them. Just the opposite -- I felt nothing but contempt and disdain for the characters, the writers, and the director. Coupled with the fact that the humor is Neanderthal-like (i.e. slipping on a banana peel), this apparent spoof is nothing but a colossal flop. It strains the mind trying to grasp how in the world this movie rates as high as it does on IMDb.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Surreal Teen Angst Flick
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    aramis-112-804880
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dumped by Beth, his girlfriend (of six months), Lane Meyer (John Cusak) no longer wants to live . . . until he tries to kill himself. Then he always has seconds thoughts, just a moment too late. Fortunately, Lane is a failure at suicide as he is at everything else. Then he catches the eye of a French exchange student who may be a lifesaver. But don't worry, this is no "American Pie." The version I saw had no nudity apart from swimsuits and a little in actual sexual situations (as in the time Lane and Beth are making out in a station wagon while vandals are stealing the tires). Believe me, in this movie the last thing Lane wants is a relationship with food. Lane and the bully who stole his girlfriend finally face off at the climactic skiing scene to prove who is the better man. But this movie is so unpredictable you can't even assume Lane will best the bully, or whether he will want Beth back if he does. It sounds like one of the drearier John Hughes vehicles or even a stupid "Hot Dog -- the Motion Picture"; but "Better Off Dead" is really a surreal romp through high school, where a geometry teacher (Vincent Schiavelli) is listened to with awe and laughed at with genuine delight when he cracks jokes based on mathematical formulas. This is a world where bike-riding gangs of paperboys roam the streets, shaking down customers for two dollars, and where Lane's little brother makes a fully-operational laser and learns the secret of picking up trashy women. "Better off Dead" is too weird to be taken seriously for one moment, and you might think this undercuts the emotional unpinning of the story. Who cares if it does? It's hilarious. Even the bullies, who steal Lane's girlfriend, are funny and surreal. David Ogden Stiers plays Lane's clueless father, while Lane's mother (Kim Darby -- "True Grit") is such a rotten cook she gives her family frozen entr&eacute;es for Christmas presents. Lane's best friend is the brain-blown Charles De Mar (a scene-stealing Curtis Armstrong) who wonders at the street value of "snow" he finds on a mountaintop and, hearing another friend snorts nasal spray, says, "Where can I score some?" While "Better Off Dead" is not a classic of the teen-angst genre like "Ferris Bueller's Day Off" -- unlike Ferris, "Dead" is almost impossible to prize out of the '80s -- it is surprisingly funny and though it sounds like a perfect dark comedy there isn't really a mean bone in its body.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    For an 80s Teen Comedy, this is not a bad movie at all
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I remember seeing this movie back when I was a teenager and it is one of those movies that I remember watching just because. My friend purchased a copy of it and I watched it and realised that it is actually a very good movie. It is quite funny and pretty way out with a number of the characters (especially the main character and his family) being larger than life. Some will claim that this is quite excessive and makes for a bad comedy, but I think rather it appeals to people with a certain twisted sense of humor (like me). The movie opens with the main character getting up and we quickly learn that he is obsessed with his girlfriend. We know that he is obsessed because his room is plastered with her picture, and he sleeps with one, and her face is on all of his clothes hangers. Unfortunately, she would rather date the stuck up snob of a ski captain. When he finds this out he becomes suicidal, but he knows that life really isn't all that bad and changes his mind at the last minute, only to have something happen that triggers it anyway (such as his mother bursting into the room, knocking the stool over and thus mostly completing his attempt to hang himself). There are a lot of weird things in the movie, such as the two Japanese who race everybody, one not speaking a word of English and the other having learnt English off of the wide world of sports. His mother is just simply strange (she cannot cook, even though she claims that she can, and she has an obsession with wearing bizarre costumes) and his brother his a technological genius who is able to pick up more women than he can. His father seems sane and boring, but he is obsessed with his garage, and freaks out because it keeps on blowing up. There is the girl that dates the entire basketball team, and the team communicates only in grunts. Finally there is the paper boy who is obsessed with getting his $2 that he rides his bike down the most dangerous mountain in the town and goes flying over at cliff (and still survives). This movie is basically about obsession and pushes them too such an extreme that it is basically laughable. There is the main character's obsession with Beth, the ski-captains' obsession with himself (which is destroyed when he is beaten by the main character), the main character's friend, who is obsessed with drugs, and because there are less illegal drugs in the town than in the Pope's bathroom, he tries everything else (such as snorting snow from the mountain). The movie really doesn't outright say "obsessions are bad" but rather it portrays it in a light in which we simply see them as an absolute absurdity. Still, it is a great movie. Favourite quote: tis a damn shame when folks go and throw away a perfectly good white boy like that.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the funniest
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Cyrus Cousins
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    So called "Comedies" of today often attempt to have an emotional plot, with humor thrown in along the way, but all too often end up emotionless and unfunny, in essence failing miserably in all respects. Better Off Dead is no such film; Lane is a relatable protagonist, and his friends, family, and rivals are all very human. The plot is unique and over the top, but grounded in a solid emotional foundation that we can all understand. The characters are a bunch of weirdos, but in the best possible way, and they find themselves in one hilarious situation after the next. Today's filmmakers could learn a lot about film from this gem of the 80s.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    80s quirkfest that never really works
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zetes
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've seen bits of this before, and it always seemed amusing. Watching it in whole, though, I was very unimpressed. It has a very unique and quirky sense of humor, but, in my opinion, it hardly ever works. John Cusack plays a teen whose super cute and popular girlfriend dumps him for a jock. He spends the rest of the movie moping while cute French exchange student Diane Franklin starts to fall for him. The movie tries to set itself apart from the John Hughes comedies with its oddness, but in reality it reinforces the same stereotypes that every other 80s teen comedy does. Some of the cast is amusing, especially fat dork neighbor Dan Schneider, whose mother hosts Franklin almost as if she's ordering a male order bride for her social outcast son, and Kim Darby as Cusack's spaced-out mom. Curtis Armstrong pretty much reprises his role as Booger from Revenge of the Nerds as Cusack's best friend. I barely laughed at all during the flick. Even stuff that seemed amusing wasn't doing anything for me. I've seen Holland and Cusack's followup film, One Crazy Summer, and I remember liking that one better.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Harold and Maude
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tieman64
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Now that's a real shame when folks be throwin' away a perfectly good white boy like that."  Black Guy (Better Off Dead) John Cusack established his persona as a Gen X icon with "The Sure Thing", the tale of a down-and-out teenager whose life goes from bad to worse after losing his girlfriend to a popular, good looking ski captain. Deciding that life's not worth living without the woman of his dreams, our hero repeatedly attempts suicide. Each suicide attempt, of course, goes comically awry. People forget that Cusack spent the 80s as the poster boy for teenage angst and humour. He managed to pull off being a dork whilst still being cute and cool; think of him as Ferris Bueller with bad luck. "Better Off Dead" plays to Cusack's strengths as an emotionally shut down depressive (it's "Grosse Point Blank" the teenage years) and an excellent orator of deadpan humour and detached one-liners, but the film suffers from the usual stereotypical characters and situations that plague most of these "teenage romance" movies. Still, the film possesses a fairly strong cast, has some good gags, and a quirky sense of humour, director Savage Holland frequently nose-diving his narrative into nonsensical, surreal, wacky and fantastically absurd sequences. Examples: the film features dancing hamburgers, ten-year-olds with hookers, and ends with a spaceship blasting out of a house. Realism be damned. 7.5/10  A cult hit in the 80s, "Better Off Dead" is nevertheless nowhere near as good as Hal Ashby's "Harold and Maude", the film it most resembles. Worth one viewing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Original But Bizarre.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    John Cusack plays Lane Myer, an unhappy high school student who has just been dumped by his beloved girlfriend, and becomes confused and despondent. He must also deal with out-of-touch parents(Kim Darby & David Ogden Stiers) and a electronics genius younger brother, who is trying to build a spaceship in the back yard. He then decides to commit suicide, but can't quite decide how to do it... Strange comedy(to say the least!) is undeniably funny at times, and Cusak is appealing, but film is so far off-the-wall, that it leaves the house altogether! Originality will only get you so far; there has to be some grounding in reality! Still, this does have its moments, and a surprisingly good heart, despite its premise. Once seen, it wont be quickly forgotten...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Silly, Sweet and Shrewd, It's the Moviegoer's Eighties in a Nutshell
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sean Lamberger
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Starring an in-his-element John Cusack, there's no question why this one's still remembered so fondly today: it's a great embodiment of everything one could expect to see from a zany '80s teen-geared comedy. Although Cusack plays his role with a typically dark slant (and many of the jokes are similarly themed), the film's general outlook is upbeat and silly, which makes for a tasty pairing. Occasionally it ventures too far into the realm of the absurd, such as the scene where Cusack's character daydreams a romancing pair of claymation cheeseburgers (which, naturally, pantomime to Van Halen), but it's also those dalliances into surrealism that provide many of its best moments. Funny as both a dated glimpse at life in the mid-eighties and a timeless relation to teenaged heartbreak, it's enriched by a sweet romantic subplot and a vast array of colorful supporting characters.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sheer Genius
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    eti55
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's a pity Savage Steve Holland didn't do more flicks. What he did with Better Off Dead was take the whole John Hughes 80s teen angst comedy and put it in full TILT mode. Everything about this movie is off center, from Layne Meyer's (played by John Cusack) total obsession with a heartless biotch of a g/f who dumps him (he has a picture of her on all of his shirt hangers), to the Chinese guy who taunts Layne while doing a perfect Howard Cosell imitation, to the insane paper boy obsessed with his two dollars, to Layne's younger brother who becomes a ladies man after reading a book on how to pick up trashy women (he also manages to build a space shuttle out of household items..again, after reading a book on it). There's even some trick skiing thrown in (it's set at a ski resort town). Yes, the end of the story is predictable (he gets the girl..the RIGHT girl); it's the way the movie gets there that's so warped. If you're the type of person that takes everything around them seriously including themselves, skip this movie. But if you like stuff that's stupid, silly and BENT (as yours truly does), definitely check this one out.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ranks up there with some of Johns Huges' best movies.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kdnor2011
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Better off Dead isn't quite as good as The Breakfast Club or Ferris Bueller's Day off, but I actually think it's better than 16 Candles and Weird Science. It does the two things that all John Hughes movies do really well. Have the quirky comedy that is really funny, and have the teenage kids actually act like teenage kids. It's interesting to see Dan Schnieder back in the 80s when he was just acting instead of working on shows like All That, Amanda Show, Drake and Josh, Zoey 101, and iCarly. He also makes me feel better about my weight, because at least I'm not as fat as him. The film is just funny, it gets all the quirky elements of being a teenager down that you can't help but laugh. And like I said earlier, it does a good job of showing how hard it is to be a teenager. Teens have to worry about their future, friends, love life, school work, peer pressure, and most have part time jobs. Like I said, it doesn't match Breakfast Club or Ferris bueller, but I like it more than 16 Candles and Weird Science.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Better Off...before I ever watched it
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    s k
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is a poor man's (or woman's) version of Ferris Bueller's Day Off, or Fast Times At Ridgemount High -- without the humor, heart, soul, charm, music, screen chemistry, or creativity of those films. It's a sophomoric attempt, at best, to display high school heartache, that fails miserably. There is not a single solitary likable character (with the possible exception of Monique); and I use the term character rather loosely when it comes to this disaster. The so-called characters are less dimensional than cartoon characters. In fact, I've seen Saturday morning cartoons that are better than this. (Hint: Beep-Beep) As such, there is no empathy evoked for any of them. Just the opposite -- I felt nothing but contempt and disdain for the characters, the writers, and the director. Coupled with the fact that the humor is Neanderthal-like (i.e. slipping on a banana peel), this apparent spoof is nothing but a colossal flop. It strains the mind trying to grasp how in the world this movie rates as high as it does on IMDb.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Surreal Teen Angst Flick
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    aramis-112-804880
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dumped by Beth, his girlfriend (of six months), Lane Meyer (John Cusak) no longer wants to live . . . until he tries to kill himself. Then he always has seconds thoughts, just a moment too late. Fortunately, Lane is a failure at suicide as he is at everything else. Then he catches the eye of a French exchange student who may be a lifesaver. But don't worry, this is no "American Pie." The version I saw had no nudity apart from swimsuits and a little in actual sexual situations (as in the time Lane and Beth are making out in a station wagon while vandals are stealing the tires). Believe me, in this movie the last thing Lane wants is a relationship with food. Lane and the bully who stole his girlfriend finally face off at the climactic skiing scene to prove who is the better man. But this movie is so unpredictable you can't even assume Lane will best the bully, or whether he will want Beth back if he does. It sounds like one of the drearier John Hughes vehicles or even a stupid "Hot Dog -- the Motion Picture"; but "Better Off Dead" is really a surreal romp through high school, where a geometry teacher (Vincent Schiavelli) is listened to with awe and laughed at with genuine delight when he cracks jokes based on mathematical formulas. This is a world where bike-riding gangs of paperboys roam the streets, shaking down customers for two dollars, and where Lane's little brother makes a fully-operational laser and learns the secret of picking up trashy women. "Better off Dead" is too weird to be taken seriously for one moment, and you might think this undercuts the emotional unpinning of the story. Who cares if it does? It's hilarious. Even the bullies, who steal Lane's girlfriend, are funny and surreal. David Ogden Stiers plays Lane's clueless father, while Lane's mother (Kim Darby -- "True Grit") is such a rotten cook she gives her family frozen entr&eacute;es for Christmas presents. Lane's best friend is the brain-blown Charles De Mar (a scene-stealing Curtis Armstrong) who wonders at the street value of "snow" he finds on a mountaintop and, hearing another friend snorts nasal spray, says, "Where can I score some?" While "Better Off Dead" is not a classic of the teen-angst genre like "Ferris Bueller's Day Off" -- unlike Ferris, "Dead" is almost impossible to prize out of the '80s -- it is surprisingly funny and though it sounds like a perfect dark comedy there isn't really a mean bone in its body.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    For an 80s Teen Comedy, this is not a bad movie at all
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I remember seeing this movie back when I was a teenager and it is one of those movies that I remember watching just because. My friend purchased a copy of it and I watched it and realised that it is actually a very good movie. It is quite funny and pretty way out with a number of the characters (especially the main character and his family) being larger than life. Some will claim that this is quite excessive and makes for a bad comedy, but I think rather it appeals to people with a certain twisted sense of humor (like me). The movie opens with the main character getting up and we quickly learn that he is obsessed with his girlfriend. We know that he is obsessed because his room is plastered with her picture, and he sleeps with one, and her face is on all of his clothes hangers. Unfortunately, she would rather date the stuck up snob of a ski captain. When he finds this out he becomes suicidal, but he knows that life really isn't all that bad and changes his mind at the last minute, only to have something happen that triggers it anyway (such as his mother bursting into the room, knocking the stool over and thus mostly completing his attempt to hang himself). There are a lot of weird things in the movie, such as the two Japanese who race everybody, one not speaking a word of English and the other having learnt English off of the wide world of sports. His mother is just simply strange (she cannot cook, even though she claims that she can, and she has an obsession with wearing bizarre costumes) and his brother his a technological genius who is able to pick up more women than he can. His father seems sane and boring, but he is obsessed with his garage, and freaks out because it keeps on blowing up. There is the girl that dates the entire basketball team, and the team communicates only in grunts. Finally there is the paper boy who is obsessed with getting his $2 that he rides his bike down the most dangerous mountain in the town and goes flying over at cliff (and still survives). This movie is basically about obsession and pushes them too such an extreme that it is basically laughable. There is the main character's obsession with Beth, the ski-captains' obsession with himself (which is destroyed when he is beaten by the main character), the main character's friend, who is obsessed with drugs, and because there are less illegal drugs in the town than in the Pope's bathroom, he tries everything else (such as snorting snow from the mountain). The movie really doesn't outright say "obsessions are bad" but rather it portrays it in a light in which we simply see them as an absolute absurdity. Still, it is a great movie. Favourite quote: tis a damn shame when folks go and throw away a perfectly good white boy like that.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the funniest
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Cyrus Cousins
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    So called "Comedies" of today often attempt to have an emotional plot, with humor thrown in along the way, but all too often end up emotionless and unfunny, in essence failing miserably in all respects. Better Off Dead is no such film; Lane is a relatable protagonist, and his friends, family, and rivals are all very human. The plot is unique and over the top, but grounded in a solid emotional foundation that we can all understand. The characters are a bunch of weirdos, but in the best possible way, and they find themselves in one hilarious situation after the next. Today's filmmakers could learn a lot about film from this gem of the 80s.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    80s quirkfest that never really works
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zetes
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've seen bits of this before, and it always seemed amusing. Watching it in whole, though, I was very unimpressed. It has a very unique and quirky sense of humor, but, in my opinion, it hardly ever works. John Cusack plays a teen whose super cute and popular girlfriend dumps him for a jock. He spends the rest of the movie moping while cute French exchange student Diane Franklin starts to fall for him. The movie tries to set itself apart from the John Hughes comedies with its oddness, but in reality it reinforces the same stereotypes that every other 80s teen comedy does. Some of the cast is amusing, especially fat dork neighbor Dan Schneider, whose mother hosts Franklin almost as if she's ordering a male order bride for her social outcast son, and Kim Darby as Cusack's spaced-out mom. Curtis Armstrong pretty much reprises his role as Booger from Revenge of the Nerds as Cusack's best friend. I barely laughed at all during the flick. Even stuff that seemed amusing wasn't doing anything for me. I've seen Holland and Cusack's followup film, One Crazy Summer, and I remember liking that one better.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Harold and Maude
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tieman64
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Now that's a real shame when folks be throwin' away a perfectly good white boy like that."  Black Guy (Better Off Dead) John Cusack established his persona as a Gen X icon with "The Sure Thing", the tale of a down-and-out teenager whose life goes from bad to worse after losing his girlfriend to a popular, good looking ski captain. Deciding that life's not worth living without the woman of his dreams, our hero repeatedly attempts suicide. Each suicide attempt, of course, goes comically awry. People forget that Cusack spent the 80s as the poster boy for teenage angst and humour. He managed to pull off being a dork whilst still being cute and cool; think of him as Ferris Bueller with bad luck. "Better Off Dead" plays to Cusack's strengths as an emotionally shut down depressive (it's "Grosse Point Blank" the teenage years) and an excellent orator of deadpan humour and detached one-liners, but the film suffers from the usual stereotypical characters and situations that plague most of these "teenage romance" movies. Still, the film possesses a fairly strong cast, has some good gags, and a quirky sense of humour, director Savage Holland frequently nose-diving his narrative into nonsensical, surreal, wacky and fantastically absurd sequences. Examples: the film features dancing hamburgers, ten-year-olds with hookers, and ends with a spaceship blasting out of a house. Realism be damned. 7.5/10  A cult hit in the 80s, "Better Off Dead" is nevertheless nowhere near as good as Hal Ashby's "Harold and Maude", the film it most resembles. Worth one viewing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Original But Bizarre.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    John Cusack plays Lane Myer, an unhappy high school student who has just been dumped by his beloved girlfriend, and becomes confused and despondent. He must also deal with out-of-touch parents(Kim Darby & David Ogden Stiers) and a electronics genius younger brother, who is trying to build a spaceship in the back yard. He then decides to commit suicide, but can't quite decide how to do it... Strange comedy(to say the least!) is undeniably funny at times, and Cusak is appealing, but film is so far off-the-wall, that it leaves the house altogether! Originality will only get you so far; there has to be some grounding in reality! Still, this does have its moments, and a surprisingly good heart, despite its premise. Once seen, it wont be quickly forgotten...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Silly, Sweet and Shrewd, It's the Moviegoer's Eighties in a Nutshell
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sean Lamberger
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Starring an in-his-element John Cusack, there's no question why this one's still remembered so fondly today: it's a great embodiment of everything one could expect to see from a zany '80s teen-geared comedy. Although Cusack plays his role with a typically dark slant (and many of the jokes are similarly themed), the film's general outlook is upbeat and silly, which makes for a tasty pairing. Occasionally it ventures too far into the realm of the absurd, such as the scene where Cusack's character daydreams a romancing pair of claymation cheeseburgers (which, naturally, pantomime to Van Halen), but it's also those dalliances into surrealism that provide many of its best moments. Funny as both a dated glimpse at life in the mid-eighties and a timeless relation to teenaged heartbreak, it's enriched by a sweet romantic subplot and a vast array of colorful supporting characters.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sheer Genius
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    eti55
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's a pity Savage Steve Holland didn't do more flicks. What he did with Better Off Dead was take the whole John Hughes 80s teen angst comedy and put it in full TILT mode. Everything about this movie is off center, from Layne Meyer's (played by John Cusack) total obsession with a heartless biotch of a g/f who dumps him (he has a picture of her on all of his shirt hangers), to the Chinese guy who taunts Layne while doing a perfect Howard Cosell imitation, to the insane paper boy obsessed with his two dollars, to Layne's younger brother who becomes a ladies man after reading a book on how to pick up trashy women (he also manages to build a space shuttle out of household items..again, after reading a book on it). There's even some trick skiing thrown in (it's set at a ski resort town). Yes, the end of the story is predictable (he gets the girl..the RIGHT girl); it's the way the movie gets there that's so warped. If you're the type of person that takes everything around them seriously including themselves, skip this movie. But if you like stuff that's stupid, silly and BENT (as yours truly does), definitely check this one out.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ranks up there with some of Johns Huges' best movies.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kdnor2011
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Better off Dead isn't quite as good as The Breakfast Club or Ferris Bueller's Day off, but I actually think it's better than 16 Candles and Weird Science. It does the two things that all John Hughes movies do really well. Have the quirky comedy that is really funny, and have the teenage kids actually act like teenage kids. It's interesting to see Dan Schnieder back in the 80s when he was just acting instead of working on shows like All That, Amanda Show, Drake and Josh, Zoey 101, and iCarly. He also makes me feel better about my weight, because at least I'm not as fat as him. The film is just funny, it gets all the quirky elements of being a teenager down that you can't help but laugh. And like I said earlier, it does a good job of showing how hard it is to be a teenager. Teens have to worry about their future, friends, love life, school work, peer pressure, and most have part time jobs. Like I said, it doesn't match Breakfast Club or Ferris bueller, but I like it more than 16 Candles and Weird Science.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Better Off...before I ever watched it
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    s k
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is a poor man's (or woman's) version of Ferris Bueller's Day Off, or Fast Times At Ridgemount High -- without the humor, heart, soul, charm, music, screen chemistry, or creativity of those films. It's a sophomoric attempt, at best, to display high school heartache, that fails miserably. There is not a single solitary likable character (with the possible exception of Monique); and I use the term character rather loosely when it comes to this disaster. The so-called characters are less dimensional than cartoon characters. In fact, I've seen Saturday morning cartoons that are better than this. (Hint: Beep-Beep) As such, there is no empathy evoked for any of them. Just the opposite -- I felt nothing but contempt and disdain for the characters, the writers, and the director. Coupled with the fact that the humor is Neanderthal-like (i.e. slipping on a banana peel), this apparent spoof is nothing but a colossal flop. It strains the mind trying to grasp how in the world this movie rates as high as it does on IMDb.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Surreal Teen Angst Flick
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    aramis-112-804880
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dumped by Beth, his girlfriend (of six months), Lane Meyer (John Cusak) no longer wants to live . . . until he tries to kill himself. Then he always has seconds thoughts, just a moment too late. Fortunately, Lane is a failure at suicide as he is at everything else. Then he catches the eye of a French exchange student who may be a lifesaver. But don't worry, this is no "American Pie." The version I saw had no nudity apart from swimsuits and a little in actual sexual situations (as in the time Lane and Beth are making out in a station wagon while vandals are stealing the tires). Believe me, in this movie the last thing Lane wants is a relationship with food. Lane and the bully who stole his girlfriend finally face off at the climactic skiing scene to prove who is the better man. But this movie is so unpredictable you can't even assume Lane will best the bully, or whether he will want Beth back if he does. It sounds like one of the drearier John Hughes vehicles or even a stupid "Hot Dog -- the Motion Picture"; but "Better Off Dead" is really a surreal romp through high school, where a geometry teacher (Vincent Schiavelli) is listened to with awe and laughed at with genuine delight when he cracks jokes based on mathematical formulas. This is a world where bike-riding gangs of paperboys roam the streets, shaking down customers for two dollars, and where Lane's little brother makes a fully-operational laser and learns the secret of picking up trashy women. "Better off Dead" is too weird to be taken seriously for one moment, and you might think this undercuts the emotional unpinning of the story. Who cares if it does? It's hilarious. Even the bullies, who steal Lane's girlfriend, are funny and surreal. David Ogden Stiers plays Lane's clueless father, while Lane's mother (Kim Darby -- "True Grit") is such a rotten cook she gives her family frozen entr&eacute;es for Christmas presents. Lane's best friend is the brain-blown Charles De Mar (a scene-stealing Curtis Armstrong) who wonders at the street value of "snow" he finds on a mountaintop and, hearing another friend snorts nasal spray, says, "Where can I score some?" While "Better Off Dead" is not a classic of the teen-angst genre like "Ferris Bueller's Day Off" -- unlike Ferris, "Dead" is almost impossible to prize out of the '80s -- it is surprisingly funny and though it sounds like a perfect dark comedy there isn't really a mean bone in its body.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    For an 80s Teen Comedy, this is not a bad movie at all
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I remember seeing this movie back when I was a teenager and it is one of those movies that I remember watching just because. My friend purchased a copy of it and I watched it and realised that it is actually a very good movie. It is quite funny and pretty way out with a number of the characters (especially the main character and his family) being larger than life. Some will claim that this is quite excessive and makes for a bad comedy, but I think rather it appeals to people with a certain twisted sense of humor (like me). The movie opens with the main character getting up and we quickly learn that he is obsessed with his girlfriend. We know that he is obsessed because his room is plastered with her picture, and he sleeps with one, and her face is on all of his clothes hangers. Unfortunately, she would rather date the stuck up snob of a ski captain. When he finds this out he becomes suicidal, but he knows that life really isn't all that bad and changes his mind at the last minute, only to have something happen that triggers it anyway (such as his mother bursting into the room, knocking the stool over and thus mostly completing his attempt to hang himself). There are a lot of weird things in the movie, such as the two Japanese who race everybody, one not speaking a word of English and the other having learnt English off of the wide world of sports. His mother is just simply strange (she cannot cook, even though she claims that she can, and she has an obsession with wearing bizarre costumes) and his brother his a technological genius who is able to pick up more women than he can. His father seems sane and boring, but he is obsessed with his garage, and freaks out because it keeps on blowing up. There is the girl that dates the entire basketball team, and the team communicates only in grunts. Finally there is the paper boy who is obsessed with getting his $2 that he rides his bike down the most dangerous mountain in the town and goes flying over at cliff (and still survives). This movie is basically about obsession and pushes them too such an extreme that it is basically laughable. There is the main character's obsession with Beth, the ski-captains' obsession with himself (which is destroyed when he is beaten by the main character), the main character's friend, who is obsessed with drugs, and because there are less illegal drugs in the town than in the Pope's bathroom, he tries everything else (such as snorting snow from the mountain). The movie really doesn't outright say "obsessions are bad" but rather it portrays it in a light in which we simply see them as an absolute absurdity. Still, it is a great movie. Favourite quote: tis a damn shame when folks go and throw away a perfectly good white boy like that.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the funniest
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Cyrus Cousins
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    So called "Comedies" of today often attempt to have an emotional plot, with humor thrown in along the way, but all too often end up emotionless and unfunny, in essence failing miserably in all respects. Better Off Dead is no such film; Lane is a relatable protagonist, and his friends, family, and rivals are all very human. The plot is unique and over the top, but grounded in a solid emotional foundation that we can all understand. The characters are a bunch of weirdos, but in the best possible way, and they find themselves in one hilarious situation after the next. Today's filmmakers could learn a lot about film from this gem of the 80s.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    80s quirkfest that never really works
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zetes
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've seen bits of this before, and it always seemed amusing. Watching it in whole, though, I was very unimpressed. It has a very unique and quirky sense of humor, but, in my opinion, it hardly ever works. John Cusack plays a teen whose super cute and popular girlfriend dumps him for a jock. He spends the rest of the movie moping while cute French exchange student Diane Franklin starts to fall for him. The movie tries to set itself apart from the John Hughes comedies with its oddness, but in reality it reinforces the same stereotypes that every other 80s teen comedy does. Some of the cast is amusing, especially fat dork neighbor Dan Schneider, whose mother hosts Franklin almost as if she's ordering a male order bride for her social outcast son, and Kim Darby as Cusack's spaced-out mom. Curtis Armstrong pretty much reprises his role as Booger from Revenge of the Nerds as Cusack's best friend. I barely laughed at all during the flick. Even stuff that seemed amusing wasn't doing anything for me. I've seen Holland and Cusack's followup film, One Crazy Summer, and I remember liking that one better.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Harold and Maude
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tieman64
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Now that's a real shame when folks be throwin' away a perfectly good white boy like that."  Black Guy (Better Off Dead) John Cusack established his persona as a Gen X icon with "The Sure Thing", the tale of a down-and-out teenager whose life goes from bad to worse after losing his girlfriend to a popular, good looking ski captain. Deciding that life's not worth living without the woman of his dreams, our hero repeatedly attempts suicide. Each suicide attempt, of course, goes comically awry. People forget that Cusack spent the 80s as the poster boy for teenage angst and humour. He managed to pull off being a dork whilst still being cute and cool; think of him as Ferris Bueller with bad luck. "Better Off Dead" plays to Cusack's strengths as an emotionally shut down depressive (it's "Grosse Point Blank" the teenage years) and an excellent orator of deadpan humour and detached one-liners, but the film suffers from the usual stereotypical characters and situations that plague most of these "teenage romance" movies. Still, the film possesses a fairly strong cast, has some good gags, and a quirky sense of humour, director Savage Holland frequently nose-diving his narrative into nonsensical, surreal, wacky and fantastically absurd sequences. Examples: the film features dancing hamburgers, ten-year-olds with hookers, and ends with a spaceship blasting out of a house. Realism be damned. 7.5/10  A cult hit in the 80s, "Better Off Dead" is nevertheless nowhere near as good as Hal Ashby's "Harold and Maude", the film it most resembles. Worth one viewing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Original But Bizarre.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    John Cusack plays Lane Myer, an unhappy high school student who has just been dumped by his beloved girlfriend, and becomes confused and despondent. He must also deal with out-of-touch parents(Kim Darby & David Ogden Stiers) and a electronics genius younger brother, who is trying to build a spaceship in the back yard. He then decides to commit suicide, but can't quite decide how to do it... Strange comedy(to say the least!) is undeniably funny at times, and Cusak is appealing, but film is so far off-the-wall, that it leaves the house altogether! Originality will only get you so far; there has to be some grounding in reality! Still, this does have its moments, and a surprisingly good heart, despite its premise. Once seen, it wont be quickly forgotten...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Silly, Sweet and Shrewd, It's the Moviegoer's Eighties in a Nutshell
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sean Lamberger
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Starring an in-his-element John Cusack, there's no question why this one's still remembered so fondly today: it's a great embodiment of everything one could expect to see from a zany '80s teen-geared comedy. Although Cusack plays his role with a typically dark slant (and many of the jokes are similarly themed), the film's general outlook is upbeat and silly, which makes for a tasty pairing. Occasionally it ventures too far into the realm of the absurd, such as the scene where Cusack's character daydreams a romancing pair of claymation cheeseburgers (which, naturally, pantomime to Van Halen), but it's also those dalliances into surrealism that provide many of its best moments. Funny as both a dated glimpse at life in the mid-eighties and a timeless relation to teenaged heartbreak, it's enriched by a sweet romantic subplot and a vast array of colorful supporting characters.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sheer Genius
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    eti55
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's a pity Savage Steve Holland didn't do more flicks. What he did with Better Off Dead was take the whole John Hughes 80s teen angst comedy and put it in full TILT mode. Everything about this movie is off center, from Layne Meyer's (played by John Cusack) total obsession with a heartless biotch of a g/f who dumps him (he has a picture of her on all of his shirt hangers), to the Chinese guy who taunts Layne while doing a perfect Howard Cosell imitation, to the insane paper boy obsessed with his two dollars, to Layne's younger brother who becomes a ladies man after reading a book on how to pick up trashy women (he also manages to build a space shuttle out of household items..again, after reading a book on it). There's even some trick skiing thrown in (it's set at a ski resort town). Yes, the end of the story is predictable (he gets the girl..the RIGHT girl); it's the way the movie gets there that's so warped. If you're the type of person that takes everything around them seriously including themselves, skip this movie. But if you like stuff that's stupid, silly and BENT (as yours truly does), definitely check this one out.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ranks up there with some of Johns Huges' best movies.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kdnor2011
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Better off Dead isn't quite as good as The Breakfast Club or Ferris Bueller's Day off, but I actually think it's better than 16 Candles and Weird Science. It does the two things that all John Hughes movies do really well. Have the quirky comedy that is really funny, and have the teenage kids actually act like teenage kids. It's interesting to see Dan Schnieder back in the 80s when he was just acting instead of working on shows like All That, Amanda Show, Drake and Josh, Zoey 101, and iCarly. He also makes me feel better about my weight, because at least I'm not as fat as him. The film is just funny, it gets all the quirky elements of being a teenager down that you can't help but laugh. And like I said earlier, it does a good job of showing how hard it is to be a teenager. Teens have to worry about their future, friends, love life, school work, peer pressure, and most have part time jobs. Like I said, it doesn't match Breakfast Club or Ferris bueller, but I like it more than 16 Candles and Weird Science.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Better Off...before I ever watched it
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    s k
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is a poor man's (or woman's) version of Ferris Bueller's Day Off, or Fast Times At Ridgemount High -- without the humor, heart, soul, charm, music, screen chemistry, or creativity of those films. It's a sophomoric attempt, at best, to display high school heartache, that fails miserably. There is not a single solitary likable character (with the possible exception of Monique); and I use the term character rather loosely when it comes to this disaster. The so-called characters are less dimensional than cartoon characters. In fact, I've seen Saturday morning cartoons that are better than this. (Hint: Beep-Beep) As such, there is no empathy evoked for any of them. Just the opposite -- I felt nothing but contempt and disdain for the characters, the writers, and the director. Coupled with the fact that the humor is Neanderthal-like (i.e. slipping on a banana peel), this apparent spoof is nothing but a colossal flop. It strains the mind trying to grasp how in the world this movie rates as high as it does on IMDb.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Surreal Teen Angst Flick
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    aramis-112-804880
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dumped by Beth, his girlfriend (of six months), Lane Meyer (John Cusak) no longer wants to live . . . until he tries to kill himself. Then he always has seconds thoughts, just a moment too late. Fortunately, Lane is a failure at suicide as he is at everything else. Then he catches the eye of a French exchange student who may be a lifesaver. But don't worry, this is no "American Pie." The version I saw had no nudity apart from swimsuits and a little in actual sexual situations (as in the time Lane and Beth are making out in a station wagon while vandals are stealing the tires). Believe me, in this movie the last thing Lane wants is a relationship with food. Lane and the bully who stole his girlfriend finally face off at the climactic skiing scene to prove who is the better man. But this movie is so unpredictable you can't even assume Lane will best the bully, or whether he will want Beth back if he does. It sounds like one of the drearier John Hughes vehicles or even a stupid "Hot Dog -- the Motion Picture"; but "Better Off Dead" is really a surreal romp through high school, where a geometry teacher (Vincent Schiavelli) is listened to with awe and laughed at with genuine delight when he cracks jokes based on mathematical formulas. This is a world where bike-riding gangs of paperboys roam the streets, shaking down customers for two dollars, and where Lane's little brother makes a fully-operational laser and learns the secret of picking up trashy women. "Better off Dead" is too weird to be taken seriously for one moment, and you might think this undercuts the emotional unpinning of the story. Who cares if it does? It's hilarious. Even the bullies, who steal Lane's girlfriend, are funny and surreal. David Ogden Stiers plays Lane's clueless father, while Lane's mother (Kim Darby -- "True Grit") is such a rotten cook she gives her family frozen entr&eacute;es for Christmas presents. Lane's best friend is the brain-blown Charles De Mar (a scene-stealing Curtis Armstrong) who wonders at the street value of "snow" he finds on a mountaintop and, hearing another friend snorts nasal spray, says, "Where can I score some?" While "Better Off Dead" is not a classic of the teen-angst genre like "Ferris Bueller's Day Off" -- unlike Ferris, "Dead" is almost impossible to prize out of the '80s -- it is surprisingly funny and though it sounds like a perfect dark comedy there isn't really a mean bone in its body.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    For an 80s Teen Comedy, this is not a bad movie at all
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I remember seeing this movie back when I was a teenager and it is one of those movies that I remember watching just because. My friend purchased a copy of it and I watched it and realised that it is actually a very good movie. It is quite funny and pretty way out with a number of the characters (especially the main character and his family) being larger than life. Some will claim that this is quite excessive and makes for a bad comedy, but I think rather it appeals to people with a certain twisted sense of humor (like me). The movie opens with the main character getting up and we quickly learn that he is obsessed with his girlfriend. We know that he is obsessed because his room is plastered with her picture, and he sleeps with one, and her face is on all of his clothes hangers. Unfortunately, she would rather date the stuck up snob of a ski captain. When he finds this out he becomes suicidal, but he knows that life really isn't all that bad and changes his mind at the last minute, only to have something happen that triggers it anyway (such as his mother bursting into the room, knocking the stool over and thus mostly completing his attempt to hang himself). There are a lot of weird things in the movie, such as the two Japanese who race everybody, one not speaking a word of English and the other having learnt English off of the wide world of sports. His mother is just simply strange (she cannot cook, even though she claims that she can, and she has an obsession with wearing bizarre costumes) and his brother his a technological genius who is able to pick up more women than he can. His father seems sane and boring, but he is obsessed with his garage, and freaks out because it keeps on blowing up. There is the girl that dates the entire basketball team, and the team communicates only in grunts. Finally there is the paper boy who is obsessed with getting his $2 that he rides his bike down the most dangerous mountain in the town and goes flying over at cliff (and still survives). This movie is basically about obsession and pushes them too such an extreme that it is basically laughable. There is the main character's obsession with Beth, the ski-captains' obsession with himself (which is destroyed when he is beaten by the main character), the main character's friend, who is obsessed with drugs, and because there are less illegal drugs in the town than in the Pope's bathroom, he tries everything else (such as snorting snow from the mountain). The movie really doesn't outright say "obsessions are bad" but rather it portrays it in a light in which we simply see them as an absolute absurdity. Still, it is a great movie. Favourite quote: tis a damn shame when folks go and throw away a perfectly good white boy like that.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the funniest
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Cyrus Cousins
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    So called "Comedies" of today often attempt to have an emotional plot, with humor thrown in along the way, but all too often end up emotionless and unfunny, in essence failing miserably in all respects. Better Off Dead is no such film; Lane is a relatable protagonist, and his friends, family, and rivals are all very human. The plot is unique and over the top, but grounded in a solid emotional foundation that we can all understand. The characters are a bunch of weirdos, but in the best possible way, and they find themselves in one hilarious situation after the next. Today's filmmakers could learn a lot about film from this gem of the 80s.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    80s quirkfest that never really works
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zetes
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've seen bits of this before, and it always seemed amusing. Watching it in whole, though, I was very unimpressed. It has a very unique and quirky sense of humor, but, in my opinion, it hardly ever works. John Cusack plays a teen whose super cute and popular girlfriend dumps him for a jock. He spends the rest of the movie moping while cute French exchange student Diane Franklin starts to fall for him. The movie tries to set itself apart from the John Hughes comedies with its oddness, but in reality it reinforces the same stereotypes that every other 80s teen comedy does. Some of the cast is amusing, especially fat dork neighbor Dan Schneider, whose mother hosts Franklin almost as if she's ordering a male order bride for her social outcast son, and Kim Darby as Cusack's spaced-out mom. Curtis Armstrong pretty much reprises his role as Booger from Revenge of the Nerds as Cusack's best friend. I barely laughed at all during the flick. Even stuff that seemed amusing wasn't doing anything for me. I've seen Holland and Cusack's followup film, One Crazy Summer, and I remember liking that one better.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Harold and Maude
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tieman64
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Now that's a real shame when folks be throwin' away a perfectly good white boy like that."  Black Guy (Better Off Dead) John Cusack established his persona as a Gen X icon with "The Sure Thing", the tale of a down-and-out teenager whose life goes from bad to worse after losing his girlfriend to a popular, good looking ski captain. Deciding that life's not worth living without the woman of his dreams, our hero repeatedly attempts suicide. Each suicide attempt, of course, goes comically awry. People forget that Cusack spent the 80s as the poster boy for teenage angst and humour. He managed to pull off being a dork whilst still being cute and cool; think of him as Ferris Bueller with bad luck. "Better Off Dead" plays to Cusack's strengths as an emotionally shut down depressive (it's "Grosse Point Blank" the teenage years) and an excellent orator of deadpan humour and detached one-liners, but the film suffers from the usual stereotypical characters and situations that plague most of these "teenage romance" movies. Still, the film possesses a fairly strong cast, has some good gags, and a quirky sense of humour, director Savage Holland frequently nose-diving his narrative into nonsensical, surreal, wacky and fantastically absurd sequences. Examples: the film features dancing hamburgers, ten-year-olds with hookers, and ends with a spaceship blasting out of a house. Realism be damned. 7.5/10  A cult hit in the 80s, "Better Off Dead" is nevertheless nowhere near as good as Hal Ashby's "Harold and Maude", the film it most resembles. Worth one viewing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Original But Bizarre.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    John Cusack plays Lane Myer, an unhappy high school student who has just been dumped by his beloved girlfriend, and becomes confused and despondent. He must also deal with out-of-touch parents(Kim Darby & David Ogden Stiers) and a electronics genius younger brother, who is trying to build a spaceship in the back yard. He then decides to commit suicide, but can't quite decide how to do it... Strange comedy(to say the least!) is undeniably funny at times, and Cusak is appealing, but film is so far off-the-wall, that it leaves the house altogether! Originality will only get you so far; there has to be some grounding in reality! Still, this does have its moments, and a surprisingly good heart, despite its premise. Once seen, it wont be quickly forgotten...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Silly, Sweet and Shrewd, It's the Moviegoer's Eighties in a Nutshell
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sean Lamberger
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Starring an in-his-element John Cusack, there's no question why this one's still remembered so fondly today: it's a great embodiment of everything one could expect to see from a zany '80s teen-geared comedy. Although Cusack plays his role with a typically dark slant (and many of the jokes are similarly themed), the film's general outlook is upbeat and silly, which makes for a tasty pairing. Occasionally it ventures too far into the realm of the absurd, such as the scene where Cusack's character daydreams a romancing pair of claymation cheeseburgers (which, naturally, pantomime to Van Halen), but it's also those dalliances into surrealism that provide many of its best moments. Funny as both a dated glimpse at life in the mid-eighties and a timeless relation to teenaged heartbreak, it's enriched by a sweet romantic subplot and a vast array of colorful supporting characters.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sheer Genius
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    eti55
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's a pity Savage Steve Holland didn't do more flicks. What he did with Better Off Dead was take the whole John Hughes 80s teen angst comedy and put it in full TILT mode. Everything about this movie is off center, from Layne Meyer's (played by John Cusack) total obsession with a heartless biotch of a g/f who dumps him (he has a picture of her on all of his shirt hangers), to the Chinese guy who taunts Layne while doing a perfect Howard Cosell imitation, to the insane paper boy obsessed with his two dollars, to Layne's younger brother who becomes a ladies man after reading a book on how to pick up trashy women (he also manages to build a space shuttle out of household items..again, after reading a book on it). There's even some trick skiing thrown in (it's set at a ski resort town). Yes, the end of the story is predictable (he gets the girl..the RIGHT girl); it's the way the movie gets there that's so warped. If you're the type of person that takes everything around them seriously including themselves, skip this movie. But if you like stuff that's stupid, silly and BENT (as yours truly does), definitely check this one out.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ranks up there with some of Johns Huges' best movies.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kdnor2011
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Better off Dead isn't quite as good as The Breakfast Club or Ferris Bueller's Day off, but I actually think it's better than 16 Candles and Weird Science. It does the two things that all John Hughes movies do really well. Have the quirky comedy that is really funny, and have the teenage kids actually act like teenage kids. It's interesting to see Dan Schnieder back in the 80s when he was just acting instead of working on shows like All That, Amanda Show, Drake and Josh, Zoey 101, and iCarly. He also makes me feel better about my weight, because at least I'm not as fat as him. The film is just funny, it gets all the quirky elements of being a teenager down that you can't help but laugh. And like I said earlier, it does a good job of showing how hard it is to be a teenager. Teens have to worry about their future, friends, love life, school work, peer pressure, and most have part time jobs. Like I said, it doesn't match Breakfast Club or Ferris bueller, but I like it more than 16 Candles and Weird Science.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Better Off...before I ever watched it
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    s k
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is a poor man's (or woman's) version of Ferris Bueller's Day Off, or Fast Times At Ridgemount High -- without the humor, heart, soul, charm, music, screen chemistry, or creativity of those films. It's a sophomoric attempt, at best, to display high school heartache, that fails miserably. There is not a single solitary likable character (with the possible exception of Monique); and I use the term character rather loosely when it comes to this disaster. The so-called characters are less dimensional than cartoon characters. In fact, I've seen Saturday morning cartoons that are better than this. (Hint: Beep-Beep) As such, there is no empathy evoked for any of them. Just the opposite -- I felt nothing but contempt and disdain for the characters, the writers, and the director. Coupled with the fact that the humor is Neanderthal-like (i.e. slipping on a banana peel), this apparent spoof is nothing but a colossal flop. It strains the mind trying to grasp how in the world this movie rates as high as it does on IMDb.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Surreal Teen Angst Flick
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    aramis-112-804880
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dumped by Beth, his girlfriend (of six months), Lane Meyer (John Cusak) no longer wants to live . . . until he tries to kill himself. Then he always has seconds thoughts, just a moment too late. Fortunately, Lane is a failure at suicide as he is at everything else. Then he catches the eye of a French exchange student who may be a lifesaver. But don't worry, this is no "American Pie." The version I saw had no nudity apart from swimsuits and a little in actual sexual situations (as in the time Lane and Beth are making out in a station wagon while vandals are stealing the tires). Believe me, in this movie the last thing Lane wants is a relationship with food. Lane and the bully who stole his girlfriend finally face off at the climactic skiing scene to prove who is the better man. But this movie is so unpredictable you can't even assume Lane will best the bully, or whether he will want Beth back if he does. It sounds like one of the drearier John Hughes vehicles or even a stupid "Hot Dog -- the Motion Picture"; but "Better Off Dead" is really a surreal romp through high school, where a geometry teacher (Vincent Schiavelli) is listened to with awe and laughed at with genuine delight when he cracks jokes based on mathematical formulas. This is a world where bike-riding gangs of paperboys roam the streets, shaking down customers for two dollars, and where Lane's little brother makes a fully-operational laser and learns the secret of picking up trashy women. "Better off Dead" is too weird to be taken seriously for one moment, and you might think this undercuts the emotional unpinning of the story. Who cares if it does? It's hilarious. Even the bullies, who steal Lane's girlfriend, are funny and surreal. David Ogden Stiers plays Lane's clueless father, while Lane's mother (Kim Darby -- "True Grit") is such a rotten cook she gives her family frozen entr&eacute;es for Christmas presents. Lane's best friend is the brain-blown Charles De Mar (a scene-stealing Curtis Armstrong) who wonders at the street value of "snow" he finds on a mountaintop and, hearing another friend snorts nasal spray, says, "Where can I score some?" While "Better Off Dead" is not a classic of the teen-angst genre like "Ferris Bueller's Day Off" -- unlike Ferris, "Dead" is almost impossible to prize out of the '80s -- it is surprisingly funny and though it sounds like a perfect dark comedy there isn't really a mean bone in its body.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    For an 80s Teen Comedy, this is not a bad movie at all
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I remember seeing this movie back when I was a teenager and it is one of those movies that I remember watching just because. My friend purchased a copy of it and I watched it and realised that it is actually a very good movie. It is quite funny and pretty way out with a number of the characters (especially the main character and his family) being larger than life. Some will claim that this is quite excessive and makes for a bad comedy, but I think rather it appeals to people with a certain twisted sense of humor (like me). The movie opens with the main character getting up and we quickly learn that he is obsessed with his girlfriend. We know that he is obsessed because his room is plastered with her picture, and he sleeps with one, and her face is on all of his clothes hangers. Unfortunately, she would rather date the stuck up snob of a ski captain. When he finds this out he becomes suicidal, but he knows that life really isn't all that bad and changes his mind at the last minute, only to have something happen that triggers it anyway (such as his mother bursting into the room, knocking the stool over and thus mostly completing his attempt to hang himself). There are a lot of weird things in the movie, such as the two Japanese who race everybody, one not speaking a word of English and the other having learnt English off of the wide world of sports. His mother is just simply strange (she cannot cook, even though she claims that she can, and she has an obsession with wearing bizarre costumes) and his brother his a technological genius who is able to pick up more women than he can. His father seems sane and boring, but he is obsessed with his garage, and freaks out because it keeps on blowing up. There is the girl that dates the entire basketball team, and the team communicates only in grunts. Finally there is the paper boy who is obsessed with getting his $2 that he rides his bike down the most dangerous mountain in the town and goes flying over at cliff (and still survives). This movie is basically about obsession and pushes them too such an extreme that it is basically laughable. There is the main character's obsession with Beth, the ski-captains' obsession with himself (which is destroyed when he is beaten by the main character), the main character's friend, who is obsessed with drugs, and because there are less illegal drugs in the town than in the Pope's bathroom, he tries everything else (such as snorting snow from the mountain). The movie really doesn't outright say "obsessions are bad" but rather it portrays it in a light in which we simply see them as an absolute absurdity. Still, it is a great movie. Favourite quote: tis a damn shame when folks go and throw away a perfectly good white boy like that.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the funniest
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Cyrus Cousins
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    So called "Comedies" of today often attempt to have an emotional plot, with humor thrown in along the way, but all too often end up emotionless and unfunny, in essence failing miserably in all respects. Better Off Dead is no such film; Lane is a relatable protagonist, and his friends, family, and rivals are all very human. The plot is unique and over the top, but grounded in a solid emotional foundation that we can all understand. The characters are a bunch of weirdos, but in the best possible way, and they find themselves in one hilarious situation after the next. Today's filmmakers could learn a lot about film from this gem of the 80s.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    80s quirkfest that never really works
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zetes
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've seen bits of this before, and it always seemed amusing. Watching it in whole, though, I was very unimpressed. It has a very unique and quirky sense of humor, but, in my opinion, it hardly ever works. John Cusack plays a teen whose super cute and popular girlfriend dumps him for a jock. He spends the rest of the movie moping while cute French exchange student Diane Franklin starts to fall for him. The movie tries to set itself apart from the John Hughes comedies with its oddness, but in reality it reinforces the same stereotypes that every other 80s teen comedy does. Some of the cast is amusing, especially fat dork neighbor Dan Schneider, whose mother hosts Franklin almost as if she's ordering a male order bride for her social outcast son, and Kim Darby as Cusack's spaced-out mom. Curtis Armstrong pretty much reprises his role as Booger from Revenge of the Nerds as Cusack's best friend. I barely laughed at all during the flick. Even stuff that seemed amusing wasn't doing anything for me. I've seen Holland and Cusack's followup film, One Crazy Summer, and I remember liking that one better.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Harold and Maude
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tieman64
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Now that's a real shame when folks be throwin' away a perfectly good white boy like that."  Black Guy (Better Off Dead) John Cusack established his persona as a Gen X icon with "The Sure Thing", the tale of a down-and-out teenager whose life goes from bad to worse after losing his girlfriend to a popular, good looking ski captain. Deciding that life's not worth living without the woman of his dreams, our hero repeatedly attempts suicide. Each suicide attempt, of course, goes comically awry. People forget that Cusack spent the 80s as the poster boy for teenage angst and humour. He managed to pull off being a dork whilst still being cute and cool; think of him as Ferris Bueller with bad luck. "Better Off Dead" plays to Cusack's strengths as an emotionally shut down depressive (it's "Grosse Point Blank" the teenage years) and an excellent orator of deadpan humour and detached one-liners, but the film suffers from the usual stereotypical characters and situations that plague most of these "teenage romance" movies. Still, the film possesses a fairly strong cast, has some good gags, and a quirky sense of humour, director Savage Holland frequently nose-diving his narrative into nonsensical, surreal, wacky and fantastically absurd sequences. Examples: the film features dancing hamburgers, ten-year-olds with hookers, and ends with a spaceship blasting out of a house. Realism be damned. 7.5/10  A cult hit in the 80s, "Better Off Dead" is nevertheless nowhere near as good as Hal Ashby's "Harold and Maude", the film it most resembles. Worth one viewing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Original But Bizarre.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    John Cusack plays Lane Myer, an unhappy high school student who has just been dumped by his beloved girlfriend, and becomes confused and despondent. He must also deal with out-of-touch parents(Kim Darby & David Ogden Stiers) and a electronics genius younger brother, who is trying to build a spaceship in the back yard. He then decides to commit suicide, but can't quite decide how to do it... Strange comedy(to say the least!) is undeniably funny at times, and Cusak is appealing, but film is so far off-the-wall, that it leaves the house altogether! Originality will only get you so far; there has to be some grounding in reality! Still, this does have its moments, and a surprisingly good heart, despite its premise. Once seen, it wont be quickly forgotten...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Silly, Sweet and Shrewd, It's the Moviegoer's Eighties in a Nutshell
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sean Lamberger
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Starring an in-his-element John Cusack, there's no question why this one's still remembered so fondly today: it's a great embodiment of everything one could expect to see from a zany '80s teen-geared comedy. Although Cusack plays his role with a typically dark slant (and many of the jokes are similarly themed), the film's general outlook is upbeat and silly, which makes for a tasty pairing. Occasionally it ventures too far into the realm of the absurd, such as the scene where Cusack's character daydreams a romancing pair of claymation cheeseburgers (which, naturally, pantomime to Van Halen), but it's also those dalliances into surrealism that provide many of its best moments. Funny as both a dated glimpse at life in the mid-eighties and a timeless relation to teenaged heartbreak, it's enriched by a sweet romantic subplot and a vast array of colorful supporting characters.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sheer Genius
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    eti55
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's a pity Savage Steve Holland didn't do more flicks. What he did with Better Off Dead was take the whole John Hughes 80s teen angst comedy and put it in full TILT mode. Everything about this movie is off center, from Layne Meyer's (played by John Cusack) total obsession with a heartless biotch of a g/f who dumps him (he has a picture of her on all of his shirt hangers), to the Chinese guy who taunts Layne while doing a perfect Howard Cosell imitation, to the insane paper boy obsessed with his two dollars, to Layne's younger brother who becomes a ladies man after reading a book on how to pick up trashy women (he also manages to build a space shuttle out of household items..again, after reading a book on it). There's even some trick skiing thrown in (it's set at a ski resort town). Yes, the end of the story is predictable (he gets the girl..the RIGHT girl); it's the way the movie gets there that's so warped. If you're the type of person that takes everything around them seriously including themselves, skip this movie. But if you like stuff that's stupid, silly and BENT (as yours truly does), definitely check this one out.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ranks up there with some of Johns Huges' best movies.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kdnor2011
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Better off Dead isn't quite as good as The Breakfast Club or Ferris Bueller's Day off, but I actually think it's better than 16 Candles and Weird Science. It does the two things that all John Hughes movies do really well. Have the quirky comedy that is really funny, and have the teenage kids actually act like teenage kids. It's interesting to see Dan Schnieder back in the 80s when he was just acting instead of working on shows like All That, Amanda Show, Drake and Josh, Zoey 101, and iCarly. He also makes me feel better about my weight, because at least I'm not as fat as him. The film is just funny, it gets all the quirky elements of being a teenager down that you can't help but laugh. And like I said earlier, it does a good job of showing how hard it is to be a teenager. Teens have to worry about their future, friends, love life, school work, peer pressure, and most have part time jobs. Like I said, it doesn't match Breakfast Club or Ferris bueller, but I like it more than 16 Candles and Weird Science.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Better Off...before I ever watched it
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    s k
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is a poor man's (or woman's) version of Ferris Bueller's Day Off, or Fast Times At Ridgemount High -- without the humor, heart, soul, charm, music, screen chemistry, or creativity of those films. It's a sophomoric attempt, at best, to display high school heartache, that fails miserably. There is not a single solitary likable character (with the possible exception of Monique); and I use the term character rather loosely when it comes to this disaster. The so-called characters are less dimensional than cartoon characters. In fact, I've seen Saturday morning cartoons that are better than this. (Hint: Beep-Beep) As such, there is no empathy evoked for any of them. Just the opposite -- I felt nothing but contempt and disdain for the characters, the writers, and the director. Coupled with the fact that the humor is Neanderthal-like (i.e. slipping on a banana peel), this apparent spoof is nothing but a colossal flop. It strains the mind trying to grasp how in the world this movie rates as high as it does on IMDb.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Surreal Teen Angst Flick
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    aramis-112-804880
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Dumped by Beth, his girlfriend (of six months), Lane Meyer (John Cusak) no longer wants to live . . . until he tries to kill himself. Then he always has seconds thoughts, just a moment too late. Fortunately, Lane is a failure at suicide as he is at everything else. Then he catches the eye of a French exchange student who may be a lifesaver. But don't worry, this is no "American Pie." The version I saw had no nudity apart from swimsuits and a little in actual sexual situations (as in the time Lane and Beth are making out in a station wagon while vandals are stealing the tires). Believe me, in this movie the last thing Lane wants is a relationship with food. Lane and the bully who stole his girlfriend finally face off at the climactic skiing scene to prove who is the better man. But this movie is so unpredictable you can't even assume Lane will best the bully, or whether he will want Beth back if he does. It sounds like one of the drearier John Hughes vehicles or even a stupid "Hot Dog -- the Motion Picture"; but "Better Off Dead" is really a surreal romp through high school, where a geometry teacher (Vincent Schiavelli) is listened to with awe and laughed at with genuine delight when he cracks jokes based on mathematical formulas. This is a world where bike-riding gangs of paperboys roam the streets, shaking down customers for two dollars, and where Lane's little brother makes a fully-operational laser and learns the secret of picking up trashy women. "Better off Dead" is too weird to be taken seriously for one moment, and you might think this undercuts the emotional unpinning of the story. Who cares if it does? It's hilarious. Even the bullies, who steal Lane's girlfriend, are funny and surreal. David Ogden Stiers plays Lane's clueless father, while Lane's mother (Kim Darby -- "True Grit") is such a rotten cook she gives her family frozen entr&eacute;es for Christmas presents. Lane's best friend is the brain-blown Charles De Mar (a scene-stealing Curtis Armstrong) who wonders at the street value of "snow" he finds on a mountaintop and, hearing another friend snorts nasal spray, says, "Where can I score some?" While "Better Off Dead" is not a classic of the teen-angst genre like "Ferris Bueller's Day Off" -- unlike Ferris, "Dead" is almost impossible to prize out of the '80s -- it is surprisingly funny and though it sounds like a perfect dark comedy there isn't really a mean bone in its body.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    For an 80s Teen Comedy, this is not a bad movie at all
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    david-sarkies
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I remember seeing this movie back when I was a teenager and it is one of those movies that I remember watching just because. My friend purchased a copy of it and I watched it and realised that it is actually a very good movie. It is quite funny and pretty way out with a number of the characters (especially the main character and his family) being larger than life. Some will claim that this is quite excessive and makes for a bad comedy, but I think rather it appeals to people with a certain twisted sense of humor (like me). The movie opens with the main character getting up and we quickly learn that he is obsessed with his girlfriend. We know that he is obsessed because his room is plastered with her picture, and he sleeps with one, and her face is on all of his clothes hangers. Unfortunately, she would rather date the stuck up snob of a ski captain. When he finds this out he becomes suicidal, but he knows that life really isn't all that bad and changes his mind at the last minute, only to have something happen that triggers it anyway (such as his mother bursting into the room, knocking the stool over and thus mostly completing his attempt to hang himself). There are a lot of weird things in the movie, such as the two Japanese who race everybody, one not speaking a word of English and the other having learnt English off of the wide world of sports. His mother is just simply strange (she cannot cook, even though she claims that she can, and she has an obsession with wearing bizarre costumes) and his brother his a technological genius who is able to pick up more women than he can. His father seems sane and boring, but he is obsessed with his garage, and freaks out because it keeps on blowing up. There is the girl that dates the entire basketball team, and the team communicates only in grunts. Finally there is the paper boy who is obsessed with getting his $2 that he rides his bike down the most dangerous mountain in the town and goes flying over at cliff (and still survives). This movie is basically about obsession and pushes them too such an extreme that it is basically laughable. There is the main character's obsession with Beth, the ski-captains' obsession with himself (which is destroyed when he is beaten by the main character), the main character's friend, who is obsessed with drugs, and because there are less illegal drugs in the town than in the Pope's bathroom, he tries everything else (such as snorting snow from the mountain). The movie really doesn't outright say "obsessions are bad" but rather it portrays it in a light in which we simply see them as an absolute absurdity. Still, it is a great movie. Favourite quote: tis a damn shame when folks go and throw away a perfectly good white boy like that.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the funniest
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Cyrus Cousins
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    So called "Comedies" of today often attempt to have an emotional plot, with humor thrown in along the way, but all too often end up emotionless and unfunny, in essence failing miserably in all respects. Better Off Dead is no such film; Lane is a relatable protagonist, and his friends, family, and rivals are all very human. The plot is unique and over the top, but grounded in a solid emotional foundation that we can all understand. The characters are a bunch of weirdos, but in the best possible way, and they find themselves in one hilarious situation after the next. Today's filmmakers could learn a lot about film from this gem of the 80s.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    80s quirkfest that never really works
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    zetes
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I've seen bits of this before, and it always seemed amusing. Watching it in whole, though, I was very unimpressed. It has a very unique and quirky sense of humor, but, in my opinion, it hardly ever works. John Cusack plays a teen whose super cute and popular girlfriend dumps him for a jock. He spends the rest of the movie moping while cute French exchange student Diane Franklin starts to fall for him. The movie tries to set itself apart from the John Hughes comedies with its oddness, but in reality it reinforces the same stereotypes that every other 80s teen comedy does. Some of the cast is amusing, especially fat dork neighbor Dan Schneider, whose mother hosts Franklin almost as if she's ordering a male order bride for her social outcast son, and Kim Darby as Cusack's spaced-out mom. Curtis Armstrong pretty much reprises his role as Booger from Revenge of the Nerds as Cusack's best friend. I barely laughed at all during the flick. Even stuff that seemed amusing wasn't doing anything for me. I've seen Holland and Cusack's followup film, One Crazy Summer, and I remember liking that one better.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Harold and Maude
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tieman64
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Now that's a real shame when folks be throwin' away a perfectly good white boy like that."  Black Guy (Better Off Dead) John Cusack established his persona as a Gen X icon with "The Sure Thing", the tale of a down-and-out teenager whose life goes from bad to worse after losing his girlfriend to a popular, good looking ski captain. Deciding that life's not worth living without the woman of his dreams, our hero repeatedly attempts suicide. Each suicide attempt, of course, goes comically awry. People forget that Cusack spent the 80s as the poster boy for teenage angst and humour. He managed to pull off being a dork whilst still being cute and cool; think of him as Ferris Bueller with bad luck. "Better Off Dead" plays to Cusack's strengths as an emotionally shut down depressive (it's "Grosse Point Blank" the teenage years) and an excellent orator of deadpan humour and detached one-liners, but the film suffers from the usual stereotypical characters and situations that plague most of these "teenage romance" movies. Still, the film possesses a fairly strong cast, has some good gags, and a quirky sense of humour, director Savage Holland frequently nose-diving his narrative into nonsensical, surreal, wacky and fantastically absurd sequences. Examples: the film features dancing hamburgers, ten-year-olds with hookers, and ends with a spaceship blasting out of a house. Realism be damned. 7.5/10  A cult hit in the 80s, "Better Off Dead" is nevertheless nowhere near as good as Hal Ashby's "Harold and Maude", the film it most resembles. Worth one viewing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
