<filme>
 <id>
  713
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0114057
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1995
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Othelo
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.8
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  The evil Iago pretends to be friend of Othello in order to manipulate him to serve his own end in the film version of this Shakespeare classic.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Iago convinces Othello, The Moor of Venice that his wife, Desdemona has been unfaithful. Iago is an evil, manipulative character with his own agenda. A plot of jealousy and rage transpires in this classic Shakespearean tale.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Romance
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   friend
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   jealousy
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   moor
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   racism
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   suspicion
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Oliver Parker
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   William Shakespeare
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Oliver Parker
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Laurence Fishburne
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Kenneth Branagh
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Ir&egrave;ne Jacob
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An excellent and very recommendable Othello
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Having loved Shakespeare's play since my third year at secondary school, and also the Welles and Olivier films, I heard much about this film. And I was very impressed; I am not sure whether I can add much to the other wonderful reviews here but I'll try. Some people may find this is not their most ideal Othello, some may despair at the cuts and the short length, but on its own and as a introduction to Shakespeare films it is very impressive. Just for the record, the Olivier film is perhaps the one I recommend the most for its amazing performances especially, though the Welles film is also superbly made, atmospheric and Welles himself directs and acts Othello in an extraordinary fashion. This Othello, this being said, is a very well made film, with beautiful locations and cinematography, and the score is suitably sweeping. The story even with the cuts is still the incredible, complex story that I fell in love with. The love scenes have such a haunting and erotic quality to them especially. The very final scene is perhaps a tad too drawn out but it is also very beautifully played especially by Fishburne and the last moments are moving. The dialogue is wonderful as you would expect, it is not always the Shakespearean language but it is still intelligent and thought-provoking with a lot of complexity. Oliver Parker brings an assured and efficient touch to his direction, and the acting is superb. Michael Maloney, Nicholas Farrell, Nathaniel Parker and especially Anna Patrick are excellent in support, but the standouts were Laurence Fishburne's brilliant and very powerful yet restrained Othello and Kenneth Branagh in a literally seething albeit sometimes human account of the evil-incarnate character of Iago. Irene Jacob wasn't quite as good, Desdemona is a very delicate and poignant character, and while Jacob does what she can looking suitably delicate and beautiful her performance was a little on the dull side for me. I also have to agree on a side note that those into opera should see or hear Verdi's Otello, the music is phenomenal and Iago's Credo is living proof in my opinion that the original source material can be improved upon as you see much more of Iago's villainy. Overall though for this 1995 Othello, this is an excellent film and while not my favourite I do recommend it. 8.5-9/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Only gets a 10 because you should see Branagh
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stancym-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I just watched the full length version of the play, televised by BBC in 1981 with Anthony Hopkins in the title role of Othello and Bob Hoskins playing Iago. It made me realize just how much the Fishburne/Branagh version from 1995 suffers by being cut to ribbons to fit in a much shorter time slot. The director finds time for sex scenes but leaves out scenes that are vital to fully understanding the background and the relationships and what is going on. The film is good, but should have been longer. Laurence Fishburne is good in the title role but not incredible, and again, he is missing some of his best lines due to editing. Irene Jacob is a bit weak as Desdemona and I do think it may have to do with English not being her native tongue. Kenneth Branagh as Iago virtually steals every scene he is in. He is just delicious. Fortunately he is in most of the scenes. He is evil even when he is about to make love to his wife, perhaps not in a way that she would like at all, from what I could tell. See it but then see one of the versions that does not have so much text cut out.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Is it my imagination....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Christopher Van
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ... or was Honest Iago actually smirking at the end, as he died? Loved how the Bard's iambic pentameter just rolled of Fishburne's tongue, with excellent clarity and emotion. And how Branagh made Honest Iago seem to celebrate his own evilness... This is a wonderful film. I have often thought that Shakespeare is inherently not film-friendly: He uses words to create pictures in our minds, which creates a perennial battle with the camera, which only knows to show us what we need to think and feel. Every effort to film Shakespeare ought really to be celebrated. It is not an easy thing to do.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not bad...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Hisham Amer
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/1/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    but could have been better. First of all, I would like to say that Laurence Fishburne's performance as Othello did not impress me. Although he is good, I think he maintains a bit too much dignity at the end of the film, making his tragedy less tragic. However, Keeth Branagh is amazing in this film. Like Glenn Close as the Marquise de Merteuil, but better, he makes Iago human, but still very sadistic. The beginning of the film is perfect. We see everything from the point of view of Iago, making us his accomplices in many ways, as he talks directly to us. Then, at the end, we lose him and Oliver Parker makes the great ending of the play way too long and we quickly get bored and annoyed at the melodrama of the last scene. Until the end, it is a great Shakespearian film. It is almost as if the same director as The Merchant of Venice (2004) made this. This is because both Parker and Redford adapt Shakespeare, not to make auteur films, like Orson Welles did, but to make them as Shakespeare would have were he alive at the time of cinema. Therefore, it would be a flawed but very good Shakespeare, but a worse auteur film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fishburne is Excellent
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Zekesboy2
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/3/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I don't pretend to be an authority on actors who have played Othello, but I've never witnessed a performance of the play, on film or on stage, wherein Othello was portrayed with more humanity and authenticity. According to the biographical notes, Fishburne never received any professional training as an actor. Perhaps this explains why his acting, in this beautifully edited film, comes over as so believable and so powerful. Instead of chewing the scenery in the approved fashion for such high-powered roles, Fishburne's portrayal is focused more on Othello's love for his wife, and on his profound sadness at her supposed betrayal, than on violence and vengeance. In a word, the performance is understated, and made far more impressive by Fishburne's extremely intelligent interpretation than it otherwise would have been. The acting throughout is superb, and the (abridged) speeches gain grace from their light editing. (Even Shakesspeare, after all, can be improved upon, now and again -- and if that be treason, make the most of it!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The First Version Of Othello In Which It Really Made Me Weep
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    profgandalf
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/1/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Students often ask me why I choose this version of Othello. Shakespeare's text is strongly truncated and the film contains material which earned it an "R" rating. I have several reasons for using this production: First, I had not seen a depiction of the Moor that actually made me sympathetic to Othello until I saw Fishburne play him. I saw James Earl Jones and Christopher Plummer play Othello and Iago on Broadway, and it was wonderful. Plummer's energy was especially noticeable. But in spite of Jone's incredible presence both physically and vocally, the character he played just seemed too passive to illicit from me a complete emotional purgation in the Aristotelian sense. Jones, in fact, affirmed what I felt when in an interview he noted that he had played Othello as passive--seeing Iago as basically doing him over. Unfortunately this sapped my grief for the character destruction. Thus, I felt sympathy for Jone's Moor but not the horror over his corruption by an evil man. In contrast, Fishburne's Othello is a strong and vigorous figure familiar with taking action. Thus, Iago's temptation to actively deal with what is presented to Othello as his wife's unfaithfulness is a perversion of the general's positive quality to be active not passive.1 The horror of the story is that this good quality in Othello becomes perverted. Fishburne's depiction is therefore classically tragic. Second, Fishburne is the first black actor to play Othello in a film. Both Orsen Wells and Anthony Hopkins did fine film versions, but they were white men in black face.2 Why is this important? Why should a Black actor be the Black man on the stage?3 Certainly in Shakespeare's day they used black face just as they used boys to make girls. Perhaps then, the reason is the same. Female actors bring a special quality to female roles on the Shakespearian stage because they understand best what Shakespeare's genius was trying to present. A gifted black actor should play the moor because his experience in a white dominated culture is vital to understanding what Shakespeare's genius recognized: the pain of being marginalized because of race. An important theme in Othello is isolation caused by racism. Although it is a mistake to insert American racism into a Shakespearian play, there can be little doubt that racism is still working among the characters. Many, including Desdimona's father, think that a union between a Venetian white Christian woman and a North African black Christian man is UNNATURAL. Third, Shakespeare was never G rated. He never has been. His stage productions were always typified by violence and strong language. But Shakespeare's genius uses these elements not as sensationialism but for artistic honesty.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Simply the best
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    artwk
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For me, the Lawrence Fishbourne version of "Othello" is the best ever put on film. His performance is excellent, while not overpowering the villainous Iago. And the title role is played by a black man, as it should be, rather than a white man with boot-polish on his face. The film's marginal eroticism has been criticised, but isn't eroticism at the very heart of the story? Olivier's "Othello" was essentially a film of the stage production, and for me the Orson Welles version was a failure, despite Welles' star performance, because most of the other actors were almost devoid of charisma. How could Desdemona possibly have been interested in a slob like Welles' Cassio? I have always found the original play unconvincing, for several reasons. Iago's motive, resentment of Cassio's promotion, seems too trivial for the tragedy it precipitates. At risk of committing heresy, I found the Verdi opera more convincing, with the soliloquy by Iago explaining his innate determination to commit evil. Also, given the closeness of Othello's friendship with Iago, his decision to bypass him in favour of Cassio makes little sense. Likewise, Othello's readiness to believe the worst of Desdemona, and the ease with which Iago leads him on to murder, makes the title character look quite pathetic, almost simple-minded. In this film, the cutting of the text to the absolute minimum helps to hide the play's inherent faults and tighten the action, and Fishbourne's wordless suffering speaks volumes that more than make up for the loss of Shakespeare's lines. I couldn't help comparing this film with Kenneth Brannagh's "Hamlet", the longest and most tedious of his self-advertisements, in which every long-winded speech was preserved intact. Here Brannagh's Iago is almost as good as Fishbourne's Othello, and he makes the most of the lines he has. To sum up, ten out of ten. I can only regret that Fishbourne is not offered more roles of this quality.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Great Modern Version of Shakespeare's Classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (sylviastel@aol.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/2/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My college professor says that Othello may be Shakespeare's finest drama. I don't know if I agree with him yet. I bought this video version of the film. First I love Kenneth BRanagh as Iago, he was perfectly complicated and worked very well in this adaptation. SUrprisingly, he didn't direct it but played a role. Lawrence Fishburne shows that American actors can play Shakespeare just as well as British actors can do. not that there was a British vs. American issue about it. In fact, if we all work together then Shakespeare can reach the masses which it richly deserves to do. Apart from other Shakespeare tragedies, this is dealt with the issue of race. Something that has existed since the beginning of time. The relationship between Iago and Emilia could have been better and shown the complicatedness of their union together. While Othello loves Desdemona with all his heart, he is weak for jealousy and fears losing her to a non-Moorish man like Cassio. It's quite a great scene at the end of the film but I won't reveal the ending. IT's just worth watching. I think they edited much of the lines to 2 hours but they always edit Shakespeare.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Othello
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It wasn't actually my choice to watch this film based on the story by William Shakespeare, it was part of a study in Secondary School. It wasn't directed by him, but I really like Kenneth Branagh in this film. Basically in the old days of England, black people weren't liked that much and were mostly slaves, and Othello (The Matrix's Laurence Fishburne) was a black man who tried to possibly become hero or king, whichever, of Denmark. At the same time, with his villainous lying skills, the nasty bastard servant Iago (the very well cast Branagh) tried to become king himself, and get people against each other. There are some good bloody moments, and good acting, I suppose I would want to see this again for my own purposes. Worth watching!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    very good adaptation
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    duane19
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/7/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I think this is a excellent adaptation. The scenery's wonderful (Cala Violina is a magnificent place and that's why the film was familiar to me because I go there often on holiday and the rock Othello's sat on is the one on which I used to catch crabs when I was younger... ^^), the actors, especially Branagh, are superb and I even was surprised by Laurence Fishburne's performance... Well everything's good, I think (although I don't like Othello saying 'Amen' like 'Hey men' instead of 'aaah men', and the place where Desdemona is in Venice is not the rights place, but those are details...) So, it's a very good film you Shakespearians should know. Welles' Othello possibly remains the best one because of its script. The ending's better because it's quicker but the text got much changed from the play. Also, the music of Othello (1995 version) composed by Charlie Mole is very beautiful I think.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An excellent and very recommendable Othello
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Having loved Shakespeare's play since my third year at secondary school, and also the Welles and Olivier films, I heard much about this film. And I was very impressed; I am not sure whether I can add much to the other wonderful reviews here but I'll try. Some people may find this is not their most ideal Othello, some may despair at the cuts and the short length, but on its own and as a introduction to Shakespeare films it is very impressive. Just for the record, the Olivier film is perhaps the one I recommend the most for its amazing performances especially, though the Welles film is also superbly made, atmospheric and Welles himself directs and acts Othello in an extraordinary fashion. This Othello, this being said, is a very well made film, with beautiful locations and cinematography, and the score is suitably sweeping. The story even with the cuts is still the incredible, complex story that I fell in love with. The love scenes have such a haunting and erotic quality to them especially. The very final scene is perhaps a tad too drawn out but it is also very beautifully played especially by Fishburne and the last moments are moving. The dialogue is wonderful as you would expect, it is not always the Shakespearean language but it is still intelligent and thought-provoking with a lot of complexity. Oliver Parker brings an assured and efficient touch to his direction, and the acting is superb. Michael Maloney, Nicholas Farrell, Nathaniel Parker and especially Anna Patrick are excellent in support, but the standouts were Laurence Fishburne's brilliant and very powerful yet restrained Othello and Kenneth Branagh in a literally seething albeit sometimes human account of the evil-incarnate character of Iago. Irene Jacob wasn't quite as good, Desdemona is a very delicate and poignant character, and while Jacob does what she can looking suitably delicate and beautiful her performance was a little on the dull side for me. I also have to agree on a side note that those into opera should see or hear Verdi's Otello, the music is phenomenal and Iago's Credo is living proof in my opinion that the original source material can be improved upon as you see much more of Iago's villainy. Overall though for this 1995 Othello, this is an excellent film and while not my favourite I do recommend it. 8.5-9/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Only gets a 10 because you should see Branagh
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stancym-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I just watched the full length version of the play, televised by BBC in 1981 with Anthony Hopkins in the title role of Othello and Bob Hoskins playing Iago. It made me realize just how much the Fishburne/Branagh version from 1995 suffers by being cut to ribbons to fit in a much shorter time slot. The director finds time for sex scenes but leaves out scenes that are vital to fully understanding the background and the relationships and what is going on. The film is good, but should have been longer. Laurence Fishburne is good in the title role but not incredible, and again, he is missing some of his best lines due to editing. Irene Jacob is a bit weak as Desdemona and I do think it may have to do with English not being her native tongue. Kenneth Branagh as Iago virtually steals every scene he is in. He is just delicious. Fortunately he is in most of the scenes. He is evil even when he is about to make love to his wife, perhaps not in a way that she would like at all, from what I could tell. See it but then see one of the versions that does not have so much text cut out.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Is it my imagination....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Christopher Van
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ... or was Honest Iago actually smirking at the end, as he died? Loved how the Bard's iambic pentameter just rolled of Fishburne's tongue, with excellent clarity and emotion. And how Branagh made Honest Iago seem to celebrate his own evilness... This is a wonderful film. I have often thought that Shakespeare is inherently not film-friendly: He uses words to create pictures in our minds, which creates a perennial battle with the camera, which only knows to show us what we need to think and feel. Every effort to film Shakespeare ought really to be celebrated. It is not an easy thing to do.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not bad...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Hisham Amer
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/1/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    but could have been better. First of all, I would like to say that Laurence Fishburne's performance as Othello did not impress me. Although he is good, I think he maintains a bit too much dignity at the end of the film, making his tragedy less tragic. However, Keeth Branagh is amazing in this film. Like Glenn Close as the Marquise de Merteuil, but better, he makes Iago human, but still very sadistic. The beginning of the film is perfect. We see everything from the point of view of Iago, making us his accomplices in many ways, as he talks directly to us. Then, at the end, we lose him and Oliver Parker makes the great ending of the play way too long and we quickly get bored and annoyed at the melodrama of the last scene. Until the end, it is a great Shakespearian film. It is almost as if the same director as The Merchant of Venice (2004) made this. This is because both Parker and Redford adapt Shakespeare, not to make auteur films, like Orson Welles did, but to make them as Shakespeare would have were he alive at the time of cinema. Therefore, it would be a flawed but very good Shakespeare, but a worse auteur film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fishburne is Excellent
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Zekesboy2
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/3/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I don't pretend to be an authority on actors who have played Othello, but I've never witnessed a performance of the play, on film or on stage, wherein Othello was portrayed with more humanity and authenticity. According to the biographical notes, Fishburne never received any professional training as an actor. Perhaps this explains why his acting, in this beautifully edited film, comes over as so believable and so powerful. Instead of chewing the scenery in the approved fashion for such high-powered roles, Fishburne's portrayal is focused more on Othello's love for his wife, and on his profound sadness at her supposed betrayal, than on violence and vengeance. In a word, the performance is understated, and made far more impressive by Fishburne's extremely intelligent interpretation than it otherwise would have been. The acting throughout is superb, and the (abridged) speeches gain grace from their light editing. (Even Shakesspeare, after all, can be improved upon, now and again -- and if that be treason, make the most of it!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The First Version Of Othello In Which It Really Made Me Weep
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    profgandalf
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/1/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Students often ask me why I choose this version of Othello. Shakespeare's text is strongly truncated and the film contains material which earned it an "R" rating. I have several reasons for using this production: First, I had not seen a depiction of the Moor that actually made me sympathetic to Othello until I saw Fishburne play him. I saw James Earl Jones and Christopher Plummer play Othello and Iago on Broadway, and it was wonderful. Plummer's energy was especially noticeable. But in spite of Jone's incredible presence both physically and vocally, the character he played just seemed too passive to illicit from me a complete emotional purgation in the Aristotelian sense. Jones, in fact, affirmed what I felt when in an interview he noted that he had played Othello as passive--seeing Iago as basically doing him over. Unfortunately this sapped my grief for the character destruction. Thus, I felt sympathy for Jone's Moor but not the horror over his corruption by an evil man. In contrast, Fishburne's Othello is a strong and vigorous figure familiar with taking action. Thus, Iago's temptation to actively deal with what is presented to Othello as his wife's unfaithfulness is a perversion of the general's positive quality to be active not passive.1 The horror of the story is that this good quality in Othello becomes perverted. Fishburne's depiction is therefore classically tragic. Second, Fishburne is the first black actor to play Othello in a film. Both Orsen Wells and Anthony Hopkins did fine film versions, but they were white men in black face.2 Why is this important? Why should a Black actor be the Black man on the stage?3 Certainly in Shakespeare's day they used black face just as they used boys to make girls. Perhaps then, the reason is the same. Female actors bring a special quality to female roles on the Shakespearian stage because they understand best what Shakespeare's genius was trying to present. A gifted black actor should play the moor because his experience in a white dominated culture is vital to understanding what Shakespeare's genius recognized: the pain of being marginalized because of race. An important theme in Othello is isolation caused by racism. Although it is a mistake to insert American racism into a Shakespearian play, there can be little doubt that racism is still working among the characters. Many, including Desdimona's father, think that a union between a Venetian white Christian woman and a North African black Christian man is UNNATURAL. Third, Shakespeare was never G rated. He never has been. His stage productions were always typified by violence and strong language. But Shakespeare's genius uses these elements not as sensationialism but for artistic honesty.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Simply the best
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    artwk
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For me, the Lawrence Fishbourne version of "Othello" is the best ever put on film. His performance is excellent, while not overpowering the villainous Iago. And the title role is played by a black man, as it should be, rather than a white man with boot-polish on his face. The film's marginal eroticism has been criticised, but isn't eroticism at the very heart of the story? Olivier's "Othello" was essentially a film of the stage production, and for me the Orson Welles version was a failure, despite Welles' star performance, because most of the other actors were almost devoid of charisma. How could Desdemona possibly have been interested in a slob like Welles' Cassio? I have always found the original play unconvincing, for several reasons. Iago's motive, resentment of Cassio's promotion, seems too trivial for the tragedy it precipitates. At risk of committing heresy, I found the Verdi opera more convincing, with the soliloquy by Iago explaining his innate determination to commit evil. Also, given the closeness of Othello's friendship with Iago, his decision to bypass him in favour of Cassio makes little sense. Likewise, Othello's readiness to believe the worst of Desdemona, and the ease with which Iago leads him on to murder, makes the title character look quite pathetic, almost simple-minded. In this film, the cutting of the text to the absolute minimum helps to hide the play's inherent faults and tighten the action, and Fishbourne's wordless suffering speaks volumes that more than make up for the loss of Shakespeare's lines. I couldn't help comparing this film with Kenneth Brannagh's "Hamlet", the longest and most tedious of his self-advertisements, in which every long-winded speech was preserved intact. Here Brannagh's Iago is almost as good as Fishbourne's Othello, and he makes the most of the lines he has. To sum up, ten out of ten. I can only regret that Fishbourne is not offered more roles of this quality.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Great Modern Version of Shakespeare's Classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (sylviastel@aol.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/2/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My college professor says that Othello may be Shakespeare's finest drama. I don't know if I agree with him yet. I bought this video version of the film. First I love Kenneth BRanagh as Iago, he was perfectly complicated and worked very well in this adaptation. SUrprisingly, he didn't direct it but played a role. Lawrence Fishburne shows that American actors can play Shakespeare just as well as British actors can do. not that there was a British vs. American issue about it. In fact, if we all work together then Shakespeare can reach the masses which it richly deserves to do. Apart from other Shakespeare tragedies, this is dealt with the issue of race. Something that has existed since the beginning of time. The relationship between Iago and Emilia could have been better and shown the complicatedness of their union together. While Othello loves Desdemona with all his heart, he is weak for jealousy and fears losing her to a non-Moorish man like Cassio. It's quite a great scene at the end of the film but I won't reveal the ending. IT's just worth watching. I think they edited much of the lines to 2 hours but they always edit Shakespeare.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Othello
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It wasn't actually my choice to watch this film based on the story by William Shakespeare, it was part of a study in Secondary School. It wasn't directed by him, but I really like Kenneth Branagh in this film. Basically in the old days of England, black people weren't liked that much and were mostly slaves, and Othello (The Matrix's Laurence Fishburne) was a black man who tried to possibly become hero or king, whichever, of Denmark. At the same time, with his villainous lying skills, the nasty bastard servant Iago (the very well cast Branagh) tried to become king himself, and get people against each other. There are some good bloody moments, and good acting, I suppose I would want to see this again for my own purposes. Worth watching!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    very good adaptation
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    duane19
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/7/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I think this is a excellent adaptation. The scenery's wonderful (Cala Violina is a magnificent place and that's why the film was familiar to me because I go there often on holiday and the rock Othello's sat on is the one on which I used to catch crabs when I was younger... ^^), the actors, especially Branagh, are superb and I even was surprised by Laurence Fishburne's performance... Well everything's good, I think (although I don't like Othello saying 'Amen' like 'Hey men' instead of 'aaah men', and the place where Desdemona is in Venice is not the rights place, but those are details...) So, it's a very good film you Shakespearians should know. Welles' Othello possibly remains the best one because of its script. The ending's better because it's quicker but the text got much changed from the play. Also, the music of Othello (1995 version) composed by Charlie Mole is very beautiful I think.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An excellent and very recommendable Othello
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Having loved Shakespeare's play since my third year at secondary school, and also the Welles and Olivier films, I heard much about this film. And I was very impressed; I am not sure whether I can add much to the other wonderful reviews here but I'll try. Some people may find this is not their most ideal Othello, some may despair at the cuts and the short length, but on its own and as a introduction to Shakespeare films it is very impressive. Just for the record, the Olivier film is perhaps the one I recommend the most for its amazing performances especially, though the Welles film is also superbly made, atmospheric and Welles himself directs and acts Othello in an extraordinary fashion. This Othello, this being said, is a very well made film, with beautiful locations and cinematography, and the score is suitably sweeping. The story even with the cuts is still the incredible, complex story that I fell in love with. The love scenes have such a haunting and erotic quality to them especially. The very final scene is perhaps a tad too drawn out but it is also very beautifully played especially by Fishburne and the last moments are moving. The dialogue is wonderful as you would expect, it is not always the Shakespearean language but it is still intelligent and thought-provoking with a lot of complexity. Oliver Parker brings an assured and efficient touch to his direction, and the acting is superb. Michael Maloney, Nicholas Farrell, Nathaniel Parker and especially Anna Patrick are excellent in support, but the standouts were Laurence Fishburne's brilliant and very powerful yet restrained Othello and Kenneth Branagh in a literally seething albeit sometimes human account of the evil-incarnate character of Iago. Irene Jacob wasn't quite as good, Desdemona is a very delicate and poignant character, and while Jacob does what she can looking suitably delicate and beautiful her performance was a little on the dull side for me. I also have to agree on a side note that those into opera should see or hear Verdi's Otello, the music is phenomenal and Iago's Credo is living proof in my opinion that the original source material can be improved upon as you see much more of Iago's villainy. Overall though for this 1995 Othello, this is an excellent film and while not my favourite I do recommend it. 8.5-9/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Only gets a 10 because you should see Branagh
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stancym-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I just watched the full length version of the play, televised by BBC in 1981 with Anthony Hopkins in the title role of Othello and Bob Hoskins playing Iago. It made me realize just how much the Fishburne/Branagh version from 1995 suffers by being cut to ribbons to fit in a much shorter time slot. The director finds time for sex scenes but leaves out scenes that are vital to fully understanding the background and the relationships and what is going on. The film is good, but should have been longer. Laurence Fishburne is good in the title role but not incredible, and again, he is missing some of his best lines due to editing. Irene Jacob is a bit weak as Desdemona and I do think it may have to do with English not being her native tongue. Kenneth Branagh as Iago virtually steals every scene he is in. He is just delicious. Fortunately he is in most of the scenes. He is evil even when he is about to make love to his wife, perhaps not in a way that she would like at all, from what I could tell. See it but then see one of the versions that does not have so much text cut out.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Is it my imagination....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Christopher Van
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ... or was Honest Iago actually smirking at the end, as he died? Loved how the Bard's iambic pentameter just rolled of Fishburne's tongue, with excellent clarity and emotion. And how Branagh made Honest Iago seem to celebrate his own evilness... This is a wonderful film. I have often thought that Shakespeare is inherently not film-friendly: He uses words to create pictures in our minds, which creates a perennial battle with the camera, which only knows to show us what we need to think and feel. Every effort to film Shakespeare ought really to be celebrated. It is not an easy thing to do.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not bad...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Hisham Amer
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/1/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    but could have been better. First of all, I would like to say that Laurence Fishburne's performance as Othello did not impress me. Although he is good, I think he maintains a bit too much dignity at the end of the film, making his tragedy less tragic. However, Keeth Branagh is amazing in this film. Like Glenn Close as the Marquise de Merteuil, but better, he makes Iago human, but still very sadistic. The beginning of the film is perfect. We see everything from the point of view of Iago, making us his accomplices in many ways, as he talks directly to us. Then, at the end, we lose him and Oliver Parker makes the great ending of the play way too long and we quickly get bored and annoyed at the melodrama of the last scene. Until the end, it is a great Shakespearian film. It is almost as if the same director as The Merchant of Venice (2004) made this. This is because both Parker and Redford adapt Shakespeare, not to make auteur films, like Orson Welles did, but to make them as Shakespeare would have were he alive at the time of cinema. Therefore, it would be a flawed but very good Shakespeare, but a worse auteur film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fishburne is Excellent
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Zekesboy2
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/3/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I don't pretend to be an authority on actors who have played Othello, but I've never witnessed a performance of the play, on film or on stage, wherein Othello was portrayed with more humanity and authenticity. According to the biographical notes, Fishburne never received any professional training as an actor. Perhaps this explains why his acting, in this beautifully edited film, comes over as so believable and so powerful. Instead of chewing the scenery in the approved fashion for such high-powered roles, Fishburne's portrayal is focused more on Othello's love for his wife, and on his profound sadness at her supposed betrayal, than on violence and vengeance. In a word, the performance is understated, and made far more impressive by Fishburne's extremely intelligent interpretation than it otherwise would have been. The acting throughout is superb, and the (abridged) speeches gain grace from their light editing. (Even Shakesspeare, after all, can be improved upon, now and again -- and if that be treason, make the most of it!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The First Version Of Othello In Which It Really Made Me Weep
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    profgandalf
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/1/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Students often ask me why I choose this version of Othello. Shakespeare's text is strongly truncated and the film contains material which earned it an "R" rating. I have several reasons for using this production: First, I had not seen a depiction of the Moor that actually made me sympathetic to Othello until I saw Fishburne play him. I saw James Earl Jones and Christopher Plummer play Othello and Iago on Broadway, and it was wonderful. Plummer's energy was especially noticeable. But in spite of Jone's incredible presence both physically and vocally, the character he played just seemed too passive to illicit from me a complete emotional purgation in the Aristotelian sense. Jones, in fact, affirmed what I felt when in an interview he noted that he had played Othello as passive--seeing Iago as basically doing him over. Unfortunately this sapped my grief for the character destruction. Thus, I felt sympathy for Jone's Moor but not the horror over his corruption by an evil man. In contrast, Fishburne's Othello is a strong and vigorous figure familiar with taking action. Thus, Iago's temptation to actively deal with what is presented to Othello as his wife's unfaithfulness is a perversion of the general's positive quality to be active not passive.1 The horror of the story is that this good quality in Othello becomes perverted. Fishburne's depiction is therefore classically tragic. Second, Fishburne is the first black actor to play Othello in a film. Both Orsen Wells and Anthony Hopkins did fine film versions, but they were white men in black face.2 Why is this important? Why should a Black actor be the Black man on the stage?3 Certainly in Shakespeare's day they used black face just as they used boys to make girls. Perhaps then, the reason is the same. Female actors bring a special quality to female roles on the Shakespearian stage because they understand best what Shakespeare's genius was trying to present. A gifted black actor should play the moor because his experience in a white dominated culture is vital to understanding what Shakespeare's genius recognized: the pain of being marginalized because of race. An important theme in Othello is isolation caused by racism. Although it is a mistake to insert American racism into a Shakespearian play, there can be little doubt that racism is still working among the characters. Many, including Desdimona's father, think that a union between a Venetian white Christian woman and a North African black Christian man is UNNATURAL. Third, Shakespeare was never G rated. He never has been. His stage productions were always typified by violence and strong language. But Shakespeare's genius uses these elements not as sensationialism but for artistic honesty.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Simply the best
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    artwk
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For me, the Lawrence Fishbourne version of "Othello" is the best ever put on film. His performance is excellent, while not overpowering the villainous Iago. And the title role is played by a black man, as it should be, rather than a white man with boot-polish on his face. The film's marginal eroticism has been criticised, but isn't eroticism at the very heart of the story? Olivier's "Othello" was essentially a film of the stage production, and for me the Orson Welles version was a failure, despite Welles' star performance, because most of the other actors were almost devoid of charisma. How could Desdemona possibly have been interested in a slob like Welles' Cassio? I have always found the original play unconvincing, for several reasons. Iago's motive, resentment of Cassio's promotion, seems too trivial for the tragedy it precipitates. At risk of committing heresy, I found the Verdi opera more convincing, with the soliloquy by Iago explaining his innate determination to commit evil. Also, given the closeness of Othello's friendship with Iago, his decision to bypass him in favour of Cassio makes little sense. Likewise, Othello's readiness to believe the worst of Desdemona, and the ease with which Iago leads him on to murder, makes the title character look quite pathetic, almost simple-minded. In this film, the cutting of the text to the absolute minimum helps to hide the play's inherent faults and tighten the action, and Fishbourne's wordless suffering speaks volumes that more than make up for the loss of Shakespeare's lines. I couldn't help comparing this film with Kenneth Brannagh's "Hamlet", the longest and most tedious of his self-advertisements, in which every long-winded speech was preserved intact. Here Brannagh's Iago is almost as good as Fishbourne's Othello, and he makes the most of the lines he has. To sum up, ten out of ten. I can only regret that Fishbourne is not offered more roles of this quality.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Great Modern Version of Shakespeare's Classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (sylviastel@aol.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/2/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My college professor says that Othello may be Shakespeare's finest drama. I don't know if I agree with him yet. I bought this video version of the film. First I love Kenneth BRanagh as Iago, he was perfectly complicated and worked very well in this adaptation. SUrprisingly, he didn't direct it but played a role. Lawrence Fishburne shows that American actors can play Shakespeare just as well as British actors can do. not that there was a British vs. American issue about it. In fact, if we all work together then Shakespeare can reach the masses which it richly deserves to do. Apart from other Shakespeare tragedies, this is dealt with the issue of race. Something that has existed since the beginning of time. The relationship between Iago and Emilia could have been better and shown the complicatedness of their union together. While Othello loves Desdemona with all his heart, he is weak for jealousy and fears losing her to a non-Moorish man like Cassio. It's quite a great scene at the end of the film but I won't reveal the ending. IT's just worth watching. I think they edited much of the lines to 2 hours but they always edit Shakespeare.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Othello
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It wasn't actually my choice to watch this film based on the story by William Shakespeare, it was part of a study in Secondary School. It wasn't directed by him, but I really like Kenneth Branagh in this film. Basically in the old days of England, black people weren't liked that much and were mostly slaves, and Othello (The Matrix's Laurence Fishburne) was a black man who tried to possibly become hero or king, whichever, of Denmark. At the same time, with his villainous lying skills, the nasty bastard servant Iago (the very well cast Branagh) tried to become king himself, and get people against each other. There are some good bloody moments, and good acting, I suppose I would want to see this again for my own purposes. Worth watching!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    very good adaptation
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    duane19
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/7/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I think this is a excellent adaptation. The scenery's wonderful (Cala Violina is a magnificent place and that's why the film was familiar to me because I go there often on holiday and the rock Othello's sat on is the one on which I used to catch crabs when I was younger... ^^), the actors, especially Branagh, are superb and I even was surprised by Laurence Fishburne's performance... Well everything's good, I think (although I don't like Othello saying 'Amen' like 'Hey men' instead of 'aaah men', and the place where Desdemona is in Venice is not the rights place, but those are details...) So, it's a very good film you Shakespearians should know. Welles' Othello possibly remains the best one because of its script. The ending's better because it's quicker but the text got much changed from the play. Also, the music of Othello (1995 version) composed by Charlie Mole is very beautiful I think.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An excellent and very recommendable Othello
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Having loved Shakespeare's play since my third year at secondary school, and also the Welles and Olivier films, I heard much about this film. And I was very impressed; I am not sure whether I can add much to the other wonderful reviews here but I'll try. Some people may find this is not their most ideal Othello, some may despair at the cuts and the short length, but on its own and as a introduction to Shakespeare films it is very impressive. Just for the record, the Olivier film is perhaps the one I recommend the most for its amazing performances especially, though the Welles film is also superbly made, atmospheric and Welles himself directs and acts Othello in an extraordinary fashion. This Othello, this being said, is a very well made film, with beautiful locations and cinematography, and the score is suitably sweeping. The story even with the cuts is still the incredible, complex story that I fell in love with. The love scenes have such a haunting and erotic quality to them especially. The very final scene is perhaps a tad too drawn out but it is also very beautifully played especially by Fishburne and the last moments are moving. The dialogue is wonderful as you would expect, it is not always the Shakespearean language but it is still intelligent and thought-provoking with a lot of complexity. Oliver Parker brings an assured and efficient touch to his direction, and the acting is superb. Michael Maloney, Nicholas Farrell, Nathaniel Parker and especially Anna Patrick are excellent in support, but the standouts were Laurence Fishburne's brilliant and very powerful yet restrained Othello and Kenneth Branagh in a literally seething albeit sometimes human account of the evil-incarnate character of Iago. Irene Jacob wasn't quite as good, Desdemona is a very delicate and poignant character, and while Jacob does what she can looking suitably delicate and beautiful her performance was a little on the dull side for me. I also have to agree on a side note that those into opera should see or hear Verdi's Otello, the music is phenomenal and Iago's Credo is living proof in my opinion that the original source material can be improved upon as you see much more of Iago's villainy. Overall though for this 1995 Othello, this is an excellent film and while not my favourite I do recommend it. 8.5-9/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Only gets a 10 because you should see Branagh
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stancym-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I just watched the full length version of the play, televised by BBC in 1981 with Anthony Hopkins in the title role of Othello and Bob Hoskins playing Iago. It made me realize just how much the Fishburne/Branagh version from 1995 suffers by being cut to ribbons to fit in a much shorter time slot. The director finds time for sex scenes but leaves out scenes that are vital to fully understanding the background and the relationships and what is going on. The film is good, but should have been longer. Laurence Fishburne is good in the title role but not incredible, and again, he is missing some of his best lines due to editing. Irene Jacob is a bit weak as Desdemona and I do think it may have to do with English not being her native tongue. Kenneth Branagh as Iago virtually steals every scene he is in. He is just delicious. Fortunately he is in most of the scenes. He is evil even when he is about to make love to his wife, perhaps not in a way that she would like at all, from what I could tell. See it but then see one of the versions that does not have so much text cut out.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Is it my imagination....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Christopher Van
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ... or was Honest Iago actually smirking at the end, as he died? Loved how the Bard's iambic pentameter just rolled of Fishburne's tongue, with excellent clarity and emotion. And how Branagh made Honest Iago seem to celebrate his own evilness... This is a wonderful film. I have often thought that Shakespeare is inherently not film-friendly: He uses words to create pictures in our minds, which creates a perennial battle with the camera, which only knows to show us what we need to think and feel. Every effort to film Shakespeare ought really to be celebrated. It is not an easy thing to do.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not bad...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Hisham Amer
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/1/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    but could have been better. First of all, I would like to say that Laurence Fishburne's performance as Othello did not impress me. Although he is good, I think he maintains a bit too much dignity at the end of the film, making his tragedy less tragic. However, Keeth Branagh is amazing in this film. Like Glenn Close as the Marquise de Merteuil, but better, he makes Iago human, but still very sadistic. The beginning of the film is perfect. We see everything from the point of view of Iago, making us his accomplices in many ways, as he talks directly to us. Then, at the end, we lose him and Oliver Parker makes the great ending of the play way too long and we quickly get bored and annoyed at the melodrama of the last scene. Until the end, it is a great Shakespearian film. It is almost as if the same director as The Merchant of Venice (2004) made this. This is because both Parker and Redford adapt Shakespeare, not to make auteur films, like Orson Welles did, but to make them as Shakespeare would have were he alive at the time of cinema. Therefore, it would be a flawed but very good Shakespeare, but a worse auteur film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fishburne is Excellent
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Zekesboy2
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/3/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I don't pretend to be an authority on actors who have played Othello, but I've never witnessed a performance of the play, on film or on stage, wherein Othello was portrayed with more humanity and authenticity. According to the biographical notes, Fishburne never received any professional training as an actor. Perhaps this explains why his acting, in this beautifully edited film, comes over as so believable and so powerful. Instead of chewing the scenery in the approved fashion for such high-powered roles, Fishburne's portrayal is focused more on Othello's love for his wife, and on his profound sadness at her supposed betrayal, than on violence and vengeance. In a word, the performance is understated, and made far more impressive by Fishburne's extremely intelligent interpretation than it otherwise would have been. The acting throughout is superb, and the (abridged) speeches gain grace from their light editing. (Even Shakesspeare, after all, can be improved upon, now and again -- and if that be treason, make the most of it!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The First Version Of Othello In Which It Really Made Me Weep
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    profgandalf
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/1/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Students often ask me why I choose this version of Othello. Shakespeare's text is strongly truncated and the film contains material which earned it an "R" rating. I have several reasons for using this production: First, I had not seen a depiction of the Moor that actually made me sympathetic to Othello until I saw Fishburne play him. I saw James Earl Jones and Christopher Plummer play Othello and Iago on Broadway, and it was wonderful. Plummer's energy was especially noticeable. But in spite of Jone's incredible presence both physically and vocally, the character he played just seemed too passive to illicit from me a complete emotional purgation in the Aristotelian sense. Jones, in fact, affirmed what I felt when in an interview he noted that he had played Othello as passive--seeing Iago as basically doing him over. Unfortunately this sapped my grief for the character destruction. Thus, I felt sympathy for Jone's Moor but not the horror over his corruption by an evil man. In contrast, Fishburne's Othello is a strong and vigorous figure familiar with taking action. Thus, Iago's temptation to actively deal with what is presented to Othello as his wife's unfaithfulness is a perversion of the general's positive quality to be active not passive.1 The horror of the story is that this good quality in Othello becomes perverted. Fishburne's depiction is therefore classically tragic. Second, Fishburne is the first black actor to play Othello in a film. Both Orsen Wells and Anthony Hopkins did fine film versions, but they were white men in black face.2 Why is this important? Why should a Black actor be the Black man on the stage?3 Certainly in Shakespeare's day they used black face just as they used boys to make girls. Perhaps then, the reason is the same. Female actors bring a special quality to female roles on the Shakespearian stage because they understand best what Shakespeare's genius was trying to present. A gifted black actor should play the moor because his experience in a white dominated culture is vital to understanding what Shakespeare's genius recognized: the pain of being marginalized because of race. An important theme in Othello is isolation caused by racism. Although it is a mistake to insert American racism into a Shakespearian play, there can be little doubt that racism is still working among the characters. Many, including Desdimona's father, think that a union between a Venetian white Christian woman and a North African black Christian man is UNNATURAL. Third, Shakespeare was never G rated. He never has been. His stage productions were always typified by violence and strong language. But Shakespeare's genius uses these elements not as sensationialism but for artistic honesty.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Simply the best
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    artwk
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For me, the Lawrence Fishbourne version of "Othello" is the best ever put on film. His performance is excellent, while not overpowering the villainous Iago. And the title role is played by a black man, as it should be, rather than a white man with boot-polish on his face. The film's marginal eroticism has been criticised, but isn't eroticism at the very heart of the story? Olivier's "Othello" was essentially a film of the stage production, and for me the Orson Welles version was a failure, despite Welles' star performance, because most of the other actors were almost devoid of charisma. How could Desdemona possibly have been interested in a slob like Welles' Cassio? I have always found the original play unconvincing, for several reasons. Iago's motive, resentment of Cassio's promotion, seems too trivial for the tragedy it precipitates. At risk of committing heresy, I found the Verdi opera more convincing, with the soliloquy by Iago explaining his innate determination to commit evil. Also, given the closeness of Othello's friendship with Iago, his decision to bypass him in favour of Cassio makes little sense. Likewise, Othello's readiness to believe the worst of Desdemona, and the ease with which Iago leads him on to murder, makes the title character look quite pathetic, almost simple-minded. In this film, the cutting of the text to the absolute minimum helps to hide the play's inherent faults and tighten the action, and Fishbourne's wordless suffering speaks volumes that more than make up for the loss of Shakespeare's lines. I couldn't help comparing this film with Kenneth Brannagh's "Hamlet", the longest and most tedious of his self-advertisements, in which every long-winded speech was preserved intact. Here Brannagh's Iago is almost as good as Fishbourne's Othello, and he makes the most of the lines he has. To sum up, ten out of ten. I can only regret that Fishbourne is not offered more roles of this quality.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Great Modern Version of Shakespeare's Classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (sylviastel@aol.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/2/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My college professor says that Othello may be Shakespeare's finest drama. I don't know if I agree with him yet. I bought this video version of the film. First I love Kenneth BRanagh as Iago, he was perfectly complicated and worked very well in this adaptation. SUrprisingly, he didn't direct it but played a role. Lawrence Fishburne shows that American actors can play Shakespeare just as well as British actors can do. not that there was a British vs. American issue about it. In fact, if we all work together then Shakespeare can reach the masses which it richly deserves to do. Apart from other Shakespeare tragedies, this is dealt with the issue of race. Something that has existed since the beginning of time. The relationship between Iago and Emilia could have been better and shown the complicatedness of their union together. While Othello loves Desdemona with all his heart, he is weak for jealousy and fears losing her to a non-Moorish man like Cassio. It's quite a great scene at the end of the film but I won't reveal the ending. IT's just worth watching. I think they edited much of the lines to 2 hours but they always edit Shakespeare.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Othello
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It wasn't actually my choice to watch this film based on the story by William Shakespeare, it was part of a study in Secondary School. It wasn't directed by him, but I really like Kenneth Branagh in this film. Basically in the old days of England, black people weren't liked that much and were mostly slaves, and Othello (The Matrix's Laurence Fishburne) was a black man who tried to possibly become hero or king, whichever, of Denmark. At the same time, with his villainous lying skills, the nasty bastard servant Iago (the very well cast Branagh) tried to become king himself, and get people against each other. There are some good bloody moments, and good acting, I suppose I would want to see this again for my own purposes. Worth watching!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    very good adaptation
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    duane19
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/7/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I think this is a excellent adaptation. The scenery's wonderful (Cala Violina is a magnificent place and that's why the film was familiar to me because I go there often on holiday and the rock Othello's sat on is the one on which I used to catch crabs when I was younger... ^^), the actors, especially Branagh, are superb and I even was surprised by Laurence Fishburne's performance... Well everything's good, I think (although I don't like Othello saying 'Amen' like 'Hey men' instead of 'aaah men', and the place where Desdemona is in Venice is not the rights place, but those are details...) So, it's a very good film you Shakespearians should know. Welles' Othello possibly remains the best one because of its script. The ending's better because it's quicker but the text got much changed from the play. Also, the music of Othello (1995 version) composed by Charlie Mole is very beautiful I think.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An excellent and very recommendable Othello
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Having loved Shakespeare's play since my third year at secondary school, and also the Welles and Olivier films, I heard much about this film. And I was very impressed; I am not sure whether I can add much to the other wonderful reviews here but I'll try. Some people may find this is not their most ideal Othello, some may despair at the cuts and the short length, but on its own and as a introduction to Shakespeare films it is very impressive. Just for the record, the Olivier film is perhaps the one I recommend the most for its amazing performances especially, though the Welles film is also superbly made, atmospheric and Welles himself directs and acts Othello in an extraordinary fashion. This Othello, this being said, is a very well made film, with beautiful locations and cinematography, and the score is suitably sweeping. The story even with the cuts is still the incredible, complex story that I fell in love with. The love scenes have such a haunting and erotic quality to them especially. The very final scene is perhaps a tad too drawn out but it is also very beautifully played especially by Fishburne and the last moments are moving. The dialogue is wonderful as you would expect, it is not always the Shakespearean language but it is still intelligent and thought-provoking with a lot of complexity. Oliver Parker brings an assured and efficient touch to his direction, and the acting is superb. Michael Maloney, Nicholas Farrell, Nathaniel Parker and especially Anna Patrick are excellent in support, but the standouts were Laurence Fishburne's brilliant and very powerful yet restrained Othello and Kenneth Branagh in a literally seething albeit sometimes human account of the evil-incarnate character of Iago. Irene Jacob wasn't quite as good, Desdemona is a very delicate and poignant character, and while Jacob does what she can looking suitably delicate and beautiful her performance was a little on the dull side for me. I also have to agree on a side note that those into opera should see or hear Verdi's Otello, the music is phenomenal and Iago's Credo is living proof in my opinion that the original source material can be improved upon as you see much more of Iago's villainy. Overall though for this 1995 Othello, this is an excellent film and while not my favourite I do recommend it. 8.5-9/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Only gets a 10 because you should see Branagh
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stancym-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/12/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I just watched the full length version of the play, televised by BBC in 1981 with Anthony Hopkins in the title role of Othello and Bob Hoskins playing Iago. It made me realize just how much the Fishburne/Branagh version from 1995 suffers by being cut to ribbons to fit in a much shorter time slot. The director finds time for sex scenes but leaves out scenes that are vital to fully understanding the background and the relationships and what is going on. The film is good, but should have been longer. Laurence Fishburne is good in the title role but not incredible, and again, he is missing some of his best lines due to editing. Irene Jacob is a bit weak as Desdemona and I do think it may have to do with English not being her native tongue. Kenneth Branagh as Iago virtually steals every scene he is in. He is just delicious. Fortunately he is in most of the scenes. He is evil even when he is about to make love to his wife, perhaps not in a way that she would like at all, from what I could tell. See it but then see one of the versions that does not have so much text cut out.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Is it my imagination....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Christopher Van
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    ... or was Honest Iago actually smirking at the end, as he died? Loved how the Bard's iambic pentameter just rolled of Fishburne's tongue, with excellent clarity and emotion. And how Branagh made Honest Iago seem to celebrate his own evilness... This is a wonderful film. I have often thought that Shakespeare is inherently not film-friendly: He uses words to create pictures in our minds, which creates a perennial battle with the camera, which only knows to show us what we need to think and feel. Every effort to film Shakespeare ought really to be celebrated. It is not an easy thing to do.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not bad...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Hisham Amer
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/1/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    but could have been better. First of all, I would like to say that Laurence Fishburne's performance as Othello did not impress me. Although he is good, I think he maintains a bit too much dignity at the end of the film, making his tragedy less tragic. However, Keeth Branagh is amazing in this film. Like Glenn Close as the Marquise de Merteuil, but better, he makes Iago human, but still very sadistic. The beginning of the film is perfect. We see everything from the point of view of Iago, making us his accomplices in many ways, as he talks directly to us. Then, at the end, we lose him and Oliver Parker makes the great ending of the play way too long and we quickly get bored and annoyed at the melodrama of the last scene. Until the end, it is a great Shakespearian film. It is almost as if the same director as The Merchant of Venice (2004) made this. This is because both Parker and Redford adapt Shakespeare, not to make auteur films, like Orson Welles did, but to make them as Shakespeare would have were he alive at the time of cinema. Therefore, it would be a flawed but very good Shakespeare, but a worse auteur film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fishburne is Excellent
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Zekesboy2
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/3/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I don't pretend to be an authority on actors who have played Othello, but I've never witnessed a performance of the play, on film or on stage, wherein Othello was portrayed with more humanity and authenticity. According to the biographical notes, Fishburne never received any professional training as an actor. Perhaps this explains why his acting, in this beautifully edited film, comes over as so believable and so powerful. Instead of chewing the scenery in the approved fashion for such high-powered roles, Fishburne's portrayal is focused more on Othello's love for his wife, and on his profound sadness at her supposed betrayal, than on violence and vengeance. In a word, the performance is understated, and made far more impressive by Fishburne's extremely intelligent interpretation than it otherwise would have been. The acting throughout is superb, and the (abridged) speeches gain grace from their light editing. (Even Shakesspeare, after all, can be improved upon, now and again -- and if that be treason, make the most of it!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The First Version Of Othello In Which It Really Made Me Weep
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    profgandalf
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/1/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Students often ask me why I choose this version of Othello. Shakespeare's text is strongly truncated and the film contains material which earned it an "R" rating. I have several reasons for using this production: First, I had not seen a depiction of the Moor that actually made me sympathetic to Othello until I saw Fishburne play him. I saw James Earl Jones and Christopher Plummer play Othello and Iago on Broadway, and it was wonderful. Plummer's energy was especially noticeable. But in spite of Jone's incredible presence both physically and vocally, the character he played just seemed too passive to illicit from me a complete emotional purgation in the Aristotelian sense. Jones, in fact, affirmed what I felt when in an interview he noted that he had played Othello as passive--seeing Iago as basically doing him over. Unfortunately this sapped my grief for the character destruction. Thus, I felt sympathy for Jone's Moor but not the horror over his corruption by an evil man. In contrast, Fishburne's Othello is a strong and vigorous figure familiar with taking action. Thus, Iago's temptation to actively deal with what is presented to Othello as his wife's unfaithfulness is a perversion of the general's positive quality to be active not passive.1 The horror of the story is that this good quality in Othello becomes perverted. Fishburne's depiction is therefore classically tragic. Second, Fishburne is the first black actor to play Othello in a film. Both Orsen Wells and Anthony Hopkins did fine film versions, but they were white men in black face.2 Why is this important? Why should a Black actor be the Black man on the stage?3 Certainly in Shakespeare's day they used black face just as they used boys to make girls. Perhaps then, the reason is the same. Female actors bring a special quality to female roles on the Shakespearian stage because they understand best what Shakespeare's genius was trying to present. A gifted black actor should play the moor because his experience in a white dominated culture is vital to understanding what Shakespeare's genius recognized: the pain of being marginalized because of race. An important theme in Othello is isolation caused by racism. Although it is a mistake to insert American racism into a Shakespearian play, there can be little doubt that racism is still working among the characters. Many, including Desdimona's father, think that a union between a Venetian white Christian woman and a North African black Christian man is UNNATURAL. Third, Shakespeare was never G rated. He never has been. His stage productions were always typified by violence and strong language. But Shakespeare's genius uses these elements not as sensationialism but for artistic honesty.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Simply the best
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    artwk
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For me, the Lawrence Fishbourne version of "Othello" is the best ever put on film. His performance is excellent, while not overpowering the villainous Iago. And the title role is played by a black man, as it should be, rather than a white man with boot-polish on his face. The film's marginal eroticism has been criticised, but isn't eroticism at the very heart of the story? Olivier's "Othello" was essentially a film of the stage production, and for me the Orson Welles version was a failure, despite Welles' star performance, because most of the other actors were almost devoid of charisma. How could Desdemona possibly have been interested in a slob like Welles' Cassio? I have always found the original play unconvincing, for several reasons. Iago's motive, resentment of Cassio's promotion, seems too trivial for the tragedy it precipitates. At risk of committing heresy, I found the Verdi opera more convincing, with the soliloquy by Iago explaining his innate determination to commit evil. Also, given the closeness of Othello's friendship with Iago, his decision to bypass him in favour of Cassio makes little sense. Likewise, Othello's readiness to believe the worst of Desdemona, and the ease with which Iago leads him on to murder, makes the title character look quite pathetic, almost simple-minded. In this film, the cutting of the text to the absolute minimum helps to hide the play's inherent faults and tighten the action, and Fishbourne's wordless suffering speaks volumes that more than make up for the loss of Shakespeare's lines. I couldn't help comparing this film with Kenneth Brannagh's "Hamlet", the longest and most tedious of his self-advertisements, in which every long-winded speech was preserved intact. Here Brannagh's Iago is almost as good as Fishbourne's Othello, and he makes the most of the lines he has. To sum up, ten out of ten. I can only regret that Fishbourne is not offered more roles of this quality.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Great Modern Version of Shakespeare's Classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (sylviastel@aol.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/2/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    My college professor says that Othello may be Shakespeare's finest drama. I don't know if I agree with him yet. I bought this video version of the film. First I love Kenneth BRanagh as Iago, he was perfectly complicated and worked very well in this adaptation. SUrprisingly, he didn't direct it but played a role. Lawrence Fishburne shows that American actors can play Shakespeare just as well as British actors can do. not that there was a British vs. American issue about it. In fact, if we all work together then Shakespeare can reach the masses which it richly deserves to do. Apart from other Shakespeare tragedies, this is dealt with the issue of race. Something that has existed since the beginning of time. The relationship between Iago and Emilia could have been better and shown the complicatedness of their union together. While Othello loves Desdemona with all his heart, he is weak for jealousy and fears losing her to a non-Moorish man like Cassio. It's quite a great scene at the end of the film but I won't reveal the ending. IT's just worth watching. I think they edited much of the lines to 2 hours but they always edit Shakespeare.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Othello
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It wasn't actually my choice to watch this film based on the story by William Shakespeare, it was part of a study in Secondary School. It wasn't directed by him, but I really like Kenneth Branagh in this film. Basically in the old days of England, black people weren't liked that much and were mostly slaves, and Othello (The Matrix's Laurence Fishburne) was a black man who tried to possibly become hero or king, whichever, of Denmark. At the same time, with his villainous lying skills, the nasty bastard servant Iago (the very well cast Branagh) tried to become king himself, and get people against each other. There are some good bloody moments, and good acting, I suppose I would want to see this again for my own purposes. Worth watching!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    very good adaptation
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    duane19
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/7/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I think this is a excellent adaptation. The scenery's wonderful (Cala Violina is a magnificent place and that's why the film was familiar to me because I go there often on holiday and the rock Othello's sat on is the one on which I used to catch crabs when I was younger... ^^), the actors, especially Branagh, are superb and I even was surprised by Laurence Fishburne's performance... Well everything's good, I think (although I don't like Othello saying 'Amen' like 'Hey men' instead of 'aaah men', and the place where Desdemona is in Venice is not the rights place, but those are details...) So, it's a very good film you Shakespearians should know. Welles' Othello possibly remains the best one because of its script. The ending's better because it's quicker but the text got much changed from the play. Also, the music of Othello (1995 version) composed by Charlie Mole is very beautiful I think.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
