<filme>
 <id>
  715
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0114681
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1995
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Um Sonho Sem Limites
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.7
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Suzanne Stone is an aspiring TV personality who will do anything to be in the spotlight- including enlisting 3 teenagers to kill her husband.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Suzanne Stone (Maretto) knows exactly what she wants. She wants to be a television newscaster and she is willing to do anything to get what she wants. What she lacks in intelligence, she makes up for in cold determination and diabolical wiles. As she pursues her goal with relentless focus, she is forced to destroy anything and anyone that may stand in her way, regardless of the ultimate cost or means necessary.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Crime
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   television
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   femme fatale
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   sex with minor
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   extramarital affair
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   media
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Gus Van Sant
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Joyce Maynard
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Buck Henry
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Nicole Kidman
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Matt Dillon
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Joaquin Phoenix
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Linear
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris L
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gus Van Sant delivered, in 1995, this not very interesting satire on the media and exposure, staging Nicole Kidman who is ready to die (and kill) for her moment of glory. The script is unfortunately too linear, not enough catchy, and the choice of showing the outcome in the first moments of the movie turns out to be a serious mistake, ruining some of the interest of story. Moreover, the documentary style, with those interviews, is quite heavy and doesn't seem to serve any real purpose. The actors seem a bit left to themselves, such as Joaquin Phoenix in one of his first roles, and deliver lacklustre performances, hot helped by characters that lack consistency. Finally, and more surprisingly, the photography is close to being bad and gives the impression of watching a banal TV movie, which is very disappointing considering what GVS is capable of.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Broadcast Wooze
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There have been Orwellian shout-outs and warnings about "False Realities" for ever. But that doesn't stop them from becoming real. People Magazine has absolutely nothing to do with "real" People. Fox News shamelessly proclaiming "Fair and Balanced", and so on. This is a smaller and much more low-budgeted Satire about TV and Celebrity and the blurring of "Truth" validated through Media than the great Network (1976) and the over rated Broadcast News (1987). But what it lacks in financing it makes up for in a witty, dark, and piercing Script along with Artsy, sure handed Direction. Add to that some spot on Performances by a fresh (at the time) Cast of Newcomers. It is a relevant and timeless Tale (adapted from a real Tabloid tragedy) that cuts sharply and is disturbing to watch at times and is a powerfully made and under rated Movie that is one of Gus Van Zant's best and still stands as top tier Nicole Kidman.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Really well done
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Red_Identity
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To Die For is a brilliantly intriguing black comedy/drama film with some truly fantastic performances at its core. Kidman can be hit or miss with me, but she's fantastic here, letting you see her character more and more, seeing her wheels turning as she calculated her every move. Kidman has never looked more amazing and she brings the electric charm that she's known for. It was really great seeing Casey Affleck in something that was done before 2007, and Phoenix was also another stand-out who brought a compelling character on screen in contrast to Suzanne's natural charisma. I'm glad I sought this one out and it stands as one of Kidman's finest performances.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    very good movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    natrlynn
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie has a lot of my fave actors, all great performances. The real-life character (Pam Smart) was sentenced to prison. While in prison, she took photos of herself in lingerie and seduced a guard. Later, she claimed she was seduced by the guard and forced to take 'nude' pics as leverage from the guard. She said that because she came forward with this information and told the truth, she was punished by being put on 24/7 lock-down for 70 days when in fact, that was her sentence for having seduced the guard. The movie doesn't show all of this but the movie does a very good job of expressing just how coo coo cachoo she really was. I never really liked Nicole Kidman but gained a great deal of respect for her after watching this movie. **I just read a review from someone who reviews movies quite often and even has (apparently) written books. The information this person gave in the review was completely inaccurate..(Suzanne did not kill her husband to get her mini-documentary on the air) just want to let people know that sometimes even online 'reviews' can be inaccurate**
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Intelligent and hilarious dark satire.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rockwell_Cronenberg
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you had told me that one of the greatest black comedies of the '90s was going to come from the director of Gerry and Drugstore Cowboy, I wouldn't have believed you. But man, Gus Van Sant really delivered here in what I think is easily the most unique work of his career. This isn't something that I would have expected from him at all and I really wish he would delve back into this genre because he is aces. From the genius opening credits sequence, which laces hard rock, razor-sharp editing and a fairy-tale score, you can tell that this is going to be a unique and bizarre experience. Unlike many films, Van Sant fully delivers on the promise from those opening minutes. I've never been a fan of structures that rely on using interviews with the characters to retrace the steps of the story, but I didn't seem to mind it as much here, probably due to how many laughs those interviews were able to pull out of me. It also helps that using that style plugs directly into the satire of the whole piece, a real biting commentary on the dangers and absurdity of popular media. Suzanne Stone, played with groundbreaking skill by Nicole Kidman, is one of the worst possible outcomes of our media-obsessed culture; an ignorant, vain and truly hopeless woman that couldn't be less likable if she tried. She is our plug in to the satire here and what follows is a delightfully twisted and bleak tale of a horrible woman doing horrible things. Looking up the film after watching it, I was amazed that it was actually based on true events. Van Sant creates an excellent style here, along with the help of a dreamy, unsettling and utterly hypnotizing score from Danny Elfman, but the true star is absolutely Kidman. I mentioned how I wanted Van Sant to do more films like this, but I desperately want Kidman to do more as well, because she is on fire. Suzanne Stone is an absolutely abhorrent creature and the best part of the film is that Kidman doesn't try to make her anything else. Most actresses, especially that early in their career, would feel the need to add something likable to the character or give some sort of a wink to the audience to let them know that she's in on the joke too, but Kidman goes for broke and dives into this character so completely. She's one of the most unlikeable characters I've ever seen in film, but Kidman is so absorbed in that role and the writing is so good that you can't look away from her, just having an urgent need to keep watching in the hopes that the bitch gets what's coming to her. A wickedly sharp, intelligent and brutally funny film with impressively unique work from everyone involved. It also features a David Cronenberg cameo that is my new favorite thing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Quirky, dark and clean?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bobsgrock
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To Die For is the kind of film you should only see if you understand the nature of television. And given the way in which TV seems to involve itself in every facet of our lives, this film should appeal to a lot more than perhaps it initially did. Gus Van Sant's stylishly-directed tale about a most ambitious woman's journey to attain fame and fortune as a TV journalist is filled with moments that at first seem strange and unrealistic but gradually you begin to realize this is a world of her own creation. Nicole Kidman's performance is campy with a dark twist, giving the exact type of emotional response one needs in watching this movie. At once she is beautiful and maniacal and what makes her performance even stronger is the acting she works against. Joaquin Phoenix gives a wonderfully nuanced and subtle performance as the young man who becomes enraptured with this woman who seems to represent to him every ideal he cannot experience in the real world so he must find in this woman through TV. Both a comic crime film as well as a vicious satire on the nature of television and its potential effects on its audience.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Weird And Awkward Story
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The price of fame is murder.Or at least it is in the mind of one woman in New Hampshire.That is the plot of the movie entitled,To Die For. It stars Nicole Kidman, Matt Dillon, and Joaquin Phoenix. Major supporting roles feature Illeana Douglas, Wayne Knight, Casey Affleck, Kurtwood Smith, Dan Hedaya, and Alison Folland.It was dark comedy film, made in a documentary format based on the novel of the same name by Joyce Maynard, which in turn was based on the Pamela Smart story. It was written by Buck Henry and directed by Gus Van Sant. Suzanne Stone has spent most of her life wanting to be famous; she's attractive, speaks well, and imagines herself to be intelligent, so she has set her sights on becoming a TV anchorwoman. However, opportunities for female broadcasters are hard to come by in Little Hope, New Hampshire, and she's convinced that her husband, the once handsome but now flabby restaurant manager Larry Maretto, is just getting in her way. Suzanne gets herself a spot hosting a weather report on a local public access station, and is preparing a documentary called "Teens Speak Out," which puts her in touch with a trio of high school students -- Jimmy, Russell, and Lydia -- who are even more desperate for attention than she is. When Suzanne hatches a plot to get Larry out of her life once and for all, she uses Jimmy, who has developed a serious crush on her, to do her dirty work, but Larry's sister Janice, who has long believed there was something fishy about Suzanne, eventually begins to realize what happened to her brother. Nicole Kidman gives a fine performance in this film as she won a Golden Globe award for her portrayal of Suzanne.This was a smart and wicked delight that one may truly enjoy inspite of its weird and awkward story for it was wonderfully told and brilliantly acted.It is a must-see not only for Nicole's fans but anyone who loves good films.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Based on a true story
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bg11215
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Of the reviews I just read on here, it seems that no one realizes that this was based on a true story, the Pam Smart case. She was a woman who manipulated her teenage lover into murdering her husband for her, so that she could be free to pursue the life she wanted. While certain events in the movie are dramatized, from what I know, it follows what actually happened pretty closely. It's based on the book written by Joyce Maynard. Well I tried to post with just the above written, but IMDb wouldn't let me. They said I must write a minimum of ten lines of text. So here they are. I don't know what else to say about the film really, it was so long ago that I saw it. But everyone who wrote a review it seemed evaluated it as if it were a made-up story, which it was not. It really happened. She's serving a life sentence in prison in upstate NY for the murder of her husband. True story.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Media Lords Strike Again
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nullness
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is my least favorite type of movie: Hollywood's attempt at showing how the rest of the country is stupid and brazen for celebrity. Yes, this is actually a subgenre of movies, though the opposite is a more accurate statement. "Black comedies" with goofy scores and over-the-top performances offer nothing: too superficial to be insightful, too withdrawn to be prescient, the only advantage they offer is for a certain type of bloated self-hating American to feel smugly superior to his/her compatriots and a false sense of camaraderie with the snobbish purveyors of tasteful propaganda of Hollywood who they would love to "rub elbows" with. What's worse, this movie is misogynist, portraying vapid proto-Stepford Wife Nicole Kidman (all too easily playing the dumb blonde winking at the camera) as a career woman hell bent on getting to the top of her field (this is a bad thing?) at the expense of her lazy husband's wishes to impregnate her and have her work at his business. What's far worse, however, is for a movie like this, so so-called "sophisticated" and "edgy" when it came out, to be so uselessly out of date. In the 21st century Television is grandpa's game and the cult of celebrity is open to anyone willing to work hard with air. A movie satirizing celebrity culture that isn't totally predictable and actually has something interesting to say? Now that I'd like to see, but it would have to be made by some of us dumb hicks east of Hollywood, and we'd never get ourselves away from the screens long enough to make it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great movie. A must see for any fan of good films.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cameronmarcusk
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To die for is simply said something to live for. The movie is incredible at every turn, definitely a must see for any fan of good films or more specifically Nicole Kidman. The acting throughout is inspiring, with every twist and turn, with every suspenseful beat and betrayal the action becomes more thrilling with every minute. Nicole Kidman is amazing throughout, and the action overall is enthralling. Nicole Kidman is a brilliant actress and it's movies like these that first led me to value her a talented and worthy actress, most definitely deserving of the golden globe, bafta, and academy award that she was given for her role as Virginia Woolf in the The Hours. Can't wait to see her next film "Trespass", can't get enough of her. http://bitly.com/o7TwhG
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Linear
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris L
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gus Van Sant delivered, in 1995, this not very interesting satire on the media and exposure, staging Nicole Kidman who is ready to die (and kill) for her moment of glory. The script is unfortunately too linear, not enough catchy, and the choice of showing the outcome in the first moments of the movie turns out to be a serious mistake, ruining some of the interest of story. Moreover, the documentary style, with those interviews, is quite heavy and doesn't seem to serve any real purpose. The actors seem a bit left to themselves, such as Joaquin Phoenix in one of his first roles, and deliver lacklustre performances, hot helped by characters that lack consistency. Finally, and more surprisingly, the photography is close to being bad and gives the impression of watching a banal TV movie, which is very disappointing considering what GVS is capable of.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Broadcast Wooze
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There have been Orwellian shout-outs and warnings about "False Realities" for ever. But that doesn't stop them from becoming real. People Magazine has absolutely nothing to do with "real" People. Fox News shamelessly proclaiming "Fair and Balanced", and so on. This is a smaller and much more low-budgeted Satire about TV and Celebrity and the blurring of "Truth" validated through Media than the great Network (1976) and the over rated Broadcast News (1987). But what it lacks in financing it makes up for in a witty, dark, and piercing Script along with Artsy, sure handed Direction. Add to that some spot on Performances by a fresh (at the time) Cast of Newcomers. It is a relevant and timeless Tale (adapted from a real Tabloid tragedy) that cuts sharply and is disturbing to watch at times and is a powerfully made and under rated Movie that is one of Gus Van Zant's best and still stands as top tier Nicole Kidman.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Really well done
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Red_Identity
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To Die For is a brilliantly intriguing black comedy/drama film with some truly fantastic performances at its core. Kidman can be hit or miss with me, but she's fantastic here, letting you see her character more and more, seeing her wheels turning as she calculated her every move. Kidman has never looked more amazing and she brings the electric charm that she's known for. It was really great seeing Casey Affleck in something that was done before 2007, and Phoenix was also another stand-out who brought a compelling character on screen in contrast to Suzanne's natural charisma. I'm glad I sought this one out and it stands as one of Kidman's finest performances.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    very good movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    natrlynn
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie has a lot of my fave actors, all great performances. The real-life character (Pam Smart) was sentenced to prison. While in prison, she took photos of herself in lingerie and seduced a guard. Later, she claimed she was seduced by the guard and forced to take 'nude' pics as leverage from the guard. She said that because she came forward with this information and told the truth, she was punished by being put on 24/7 lock-down for 70 days when in fact, that was her sentence for having seduced the guard. The movie doesn't show all of this but the movie does a very good job of expressing just how coo coo cachoo she really was. I never really liked Nicole Kidman but gained a great deal of respect for her after watching this movie. **I just read a review from someone who reviews movies quite often and even has (apparently) written books. The information this person gave in the review was completely inaccurate..(Suzanne did not kill her husband to get her mini-documentary on the air) just want to let people know that sometimes even online 'reviews' can be inaccurate**
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Intelligent and hilarious dark satire.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rockwell_Cronenberg
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you had told me that one of the greatest black comedies of the '90s was going to come from the director of Gerry and Drugstore Cowboy, I wouldn't have believed you. But man, Gus Van Sant really delivered here in what I think is easily the most unique work of his career. This isn't something that I would have expected from him at all and I really wish he would delve back into this genre because he is aces. From the genius opening credits sequence, which laces hard rock, razor-sharp editing and a fairy-tale score, you can tell that this is going to be a unique and bizarre experience. Unlike many films, Van Sant fully delivers on the promise from those opening minutes. I've never been a fan of structures that rely on using interviews with the characters to retrace the steps of the story, but I didn't seem to mind it as much here, probably due to how many laughs those interviews were able to pull out of me. It also helps that using that style plugs directly into the satire of the whole piece, a real biting commentary on the dangers and absurdity of popular media. Suzanne Stone, played with groundbreaking skill by Nicole Kidman, is one of the worst possible outcomes of our media-obsessed culture; an ignorant, vain and truly hopeless woman that couldn't be less likable if she tried. She is our plug in to the satire here and what follows is a delightfully twisted and bleak tale of a horrible woman doing horrible things. Looking up the film after watching it, I was amazed that it was actually based on true events. Van Sant creates an excellent style here, along with the help of a dreamy, unsettling and utterly hypnotizing score from Danny Elfman, but the true star is absolutely Kidman. I mentioned how I wanted Van Sant to do more films like this, but I desperately want Kidman to do more as well, because she is on fire. Suzanne Stone is an absolutely abhorrent creature and the best part of the film is that Kidman doesn't try to make her anything else. Most actresses, especially that early in their career, would feel the need to add something likable to the character or give some sort of a wink to the audience to let them know that she's in on the joke too, but Kidman goes for broke and dives into this character so completely. She's one of the most unlikeable characters I've ever seen in film, but Kidman is so absorbed in that role and the writing is so good that you can't look away from her, just having an urgent need to keep watching in the hopes that the bitch gets what's coming to her. A wickedly sharp, intelligent and brutally funny film with impressively unique work from everyone involved. It also features a David Cronenberg cameo that is my new favorite thing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Quirky, dark and clean?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bobsgrock
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To Die For is the kind of film you should only see if you understand the nature of television. And given the way in which TV seems to involve itself in every facet of our lives, this film should appeal to a lot more than perhaps it initially did. Gus Van Sant's stylishly-directed tale about a most ambitious woman's journey to attain fame and fortune as a TV journalist is filled with moments that at first seem strange and unrealistic but gradually you begin to realize this is a world of her own creation. Nicole Kidman's performance is campy with a dark twist, giving the exact type of emotional response one needs in watching this movie. At once she is beautiful and maniacal and what makes her performance even stronger is the acting she works against. Joaquin Phoenix gives a wonderfully nuanced and subtle performance as the young man who becomes enraptured with this woman who seems to represent to him every ideal he cannot experience in the real world so he must find in this woman through TV. Both a comic crime film as well as a vicious satire on the nature of television and its potential effects on its audience.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Weird And Awkward Story
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The price of fame is murder.Or at least it is in the mind of one woman in New Hampshire.That is the plot of the movie entitled,To Die For. It stars Nicole Kidman, Matt Dillon, and Joaquin Phoenix. Major supporting roles feature Illeana Douglas, Wayne Knight, Casey Affleck, Kurtwood Smith, Dan Hedaya, and Alison Folland.It was dark comedy film, made in a documentary format based on the novel of the same name by Joyce Maynard, which in turn was based on the Pamela Smart story. It was written by Buck Henry and directed by Gus Van Sant. Suzanne Stone has spent most of her life wanting to be famous; she's attractive, speaks well, and imagines herself to be intelligent, so she has set her sights on becoming a TV anchorwoman. However, opportunities for female broadcasters are hard to come by in Little Hope, New Hampshire, and she's convinced that her husband, the once handsome but now flabby restaurant manager Larry Maretto, is just getting in her way. Suzanne gets herself a spot hosting a weather report on a local public access station, and is preparing a documentary called "Teens Speak Out," which puts her in touch with a trio of high school students -- Jimmy, Russell, and Lydia -- who are even more desperate for attention than she is. When Suzanne hatches a plot to get Larry out of her life once and for all, she uses Jimmy, who has developed a serious crush on her, to do her dirty work, but Larry's sister Janice, who has long believed there was something fishy about Suzanne, eventually begins to realize what happened to her brother. Nicole Kidman gives a fine performance in this film as she won a Golden Globe award for her portrayal of Suzanne.This was a smart and wicked delight that one may truly enjoy inspite of its weird and awkward story for it was wonderfully told and brilliantly acted.It is a must-see not only for Nicole's fans but anyone who loves good films.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Based on a true story
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bg11215
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Of the reviews I just read on here, it seems that no one realizes that this was based on a true story, the Pam Smart case. She was a woman who manipulated her teenage lover into murdering her husband for her, so that she could be free to pursue the life she wanted. While certain events in the movie are dramatized, from what I know, it follows what actually happened pretty closely. It's based on the book written by Joyce Maynard. Well I tried to post with just the above written, but IMDb wouldn't let me. They said I must write a minimum of ten lines of text. So here they are. I don't know what else to say about the film really, it was so long ago that I saw it. But everyone who wrote a review it seemed evaluated it as if it were a made-up story, which it was not. It really happened. She's serving a life sentence in prison in upstate NY for the murder of her husband. True story.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Media Lords Strike Again
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nullness
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is my least favorite type of movie: Hollywood's attempt at showing how the rest of the country is stupid and brazen for celebrity. Yes, this is actually a subgenre of movies, though the opposite is a more accurate statement. "Black comedies" with goofy scores and over-the-top performances offer nothing: too superficial to be insightful, too withdrawn to be prescient, the only advantage they offer is for a certain type of bloated self-hating American to feel smugly superior to his/her compatriots and a false sense of camaraderie with the snobbish purveyors of tasteful propaganda of Hollywood who they would love to "rub elbows" with. What's worse, this movie is misogynist, portraying vapid proto-Stepford Wife Nicole Kidman (all too easily playing the dumb blonde winking at the camera) as a career woman hell bent on getting to the top of her field (this is a bad thing?) at the expense of her lazy husband's wishes to impregnate her and have her work at his business. What's far worse, however, is for a movie like this, so so-called "sophisticated" and "edgy" when it came out, to be so uselessly out of date. In the 21st century Television is grandpa's game and the cult of celebrity is open to anyone willing to work hard with air. A movie satirizing celebrity culture that isn't totally predictable and actually has something interesting to say? Now that I'd like to see, but it would have to be made by some of us dumb hicks east of Hollywood, and we'd never get ourselves away from the screens long enough to make it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great movie. A must see for any fan of good films.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cameronmarcusk
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To die for is simply said something to live for. The movie is incredible at every turn, definitely a must see for any fan of good films or more specifically Nicole Kidman. The acting throughout is inspiring, with every twist and turn, with every suspenseful beat and betrayal the action becomes more thrilling with every minute. Nicole Kidman is amazing throughout, and the action overall is enthralling. Nicole Kidman is a brilliant actress and it's movies like these that first led me to value her a talented and worthy actress, most definitely deserving of the golden globe, bafta, and academy award that she was given for her role as Virginia Woolf in the The Hours. Can't wait to see her next film "Trespass", can't get enough of her. http://bitly.com/o7TwhG
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Linear
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris L
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gus Van Sant delivered, in 1995, this not very interesting satire on the media and exposure, staging Nicole Kidman who is ready to die (and kill) for her moment of glory. The script is unfortunately too linear, not enough catchy, and the choice of showing the outcome in the first moments of the movie turns out to be a serious mistake, ruining some of the interest of story. Moreover, the documentary style, with those interviews, is quite heavy and doesn't seem to serve any real purpose. The actors seem a bit left to themselves, such as Joaquin Phoenix in one of his first roles, and deliver lacklustre performances, hot helped by characters that lack consistency. Finally, and more surprisingly, the photography is close to being bad and gives the impression of watching a banal TV movie, which is very disappointing considering what GVS is capable of.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Broadcast Wooze
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There have been Orwellian shout-outs and warnings about "False Realities" for ever. But that doesn't stop them from becoming real. People Magazine has absolutely nothing to do with "real" People. Fox News shamelessly proclaiming "Fair and Balanced", and so on. This is a smaller and much more low-budgeted Satire about TV and Celebrity and the blurring of "Truth" validated through Media than the great Network (1976) and the over rated Broadcast News (1987). But what it lacks in financing it makes up for in a witty, dark, and piercing Script along with Artsy, sure handed Direction. Add to that some spot on Performances by a fresh (at the time) Cast of Newcomers. It is a relevant and timeless Tale (adapted from a real Tabloid tragedy) that cuts sharply and is disturbing to watch at times and is a powerfully made and under rated Movie that is one of Gus Van Zant's best and still stands as top tier Nicole Kidman.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Really well done
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Red_Identity
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To Die For is a brilliantly intriguing black comedy/drama film with some truly fantastic performances at its core. Kidman can be hit or miss with me, but she's fantastic here, letting you see her character more and more, seeing her wheels turning as she calculated her every move. Kidman has never looked more amazing and she brings the electric charm that she's known for. It was really great seeing Casey Affleck in something that was done before 2007, and Phoenix was also another stand-out who brought a compelling character on screen in contrast to Suzanne's natural charisma. I'm glad I sought this one out and it stands as one of Kidman's finest performances.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    very good movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    natrlynn
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie has a lot of my fave actors, all great performances. The real-life character (Pam Smart) was sentenced to prison. While in prison, she took photos of herself in lingerie and seduced a guard. Later, she claimed she was seduced by the guard and forced to take 'nude' pics as leverage from the guard. She said that because she came forward with this information and told the truth, she was punished by being put on 24/7 lock-down for 70 days when in fact, that was her sentence for having seduced the guard. The movie doesn't show all of this but the movie does a very good job of expressing just how coo coo cachoo she really was. I never really liked Nicole Kidman but gained a great deal of respect for her after watching this movie. **I just read a review from someone who reviews movies quite often and even has (apparently) written books. The information this person gave in the review was completely inaccurate..(Suzanne did not kill her husband to get her mini-documentary on the air) just want to let people know that sometimes even online 'reviews' can be inaccurate**
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Intelligent and hilarious dark satire.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rockwell_Cronenberg
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you had told me that one of the greatest black comedies of the '90s was going to come from the director of Gerry and Drugstore Cowboy, I wouldn't have believed you. But man, Gus Van Sant really delivered here in what I think is easily the most unique work of his career. This isn't something that I would have expected from him at all and I really wish he would delve back into this genre because he is aces. From the genius opening credits sequence, which laces hard rock, razor-sharp editing and a fairy-tale score, you can tell that this is going to be a unique and bizarre experience. Unlike many films, Van Sant fully delivers on the promise from those opening minutes. I've never been a fan of structures that rely on using interviews with the characters to retrace the steps of the story, but I didn't seem to mind it as much here, probably due to how many laughs those interviews were able to pull out of me. It also helps that using that style plugs directly into the satire of the whole piece, a real biting commentary on the dangers and absurdity of popular media. Suzanne Stone, played with groundbreaking skill by Nicole Kidman, is one of the worst possible outcomes of our media-obsessed culture; an ignorant, vain and truly hopeless woman that couldn't be less likable if she tried. She is our plug in to the satire here and what follows is a delightfully twisted and bleak tale of a horrible woman doing horrible things. Looking up the film after watching it, I was amazed that it was actually based on true events. Van Sant creates an excellent style here, along with the help of a dreamy, unsettling and utterly hypnotizing score from Danny Elfman, but the true star is absolutely Kidman. I mentioned how I wanted Van Sant to do more films like this, but I desperately want Kidman to do more as well, because she is on fire. Suzanne Stone is an absolutely abhorrent creature and the best part of the film is that Kidman doesn't try to make her anything else. Most actresses, especially that early in their career, would feel the need to add something likable to the character or give some sort of a wink to the audience to let them know that she's in on the joke too, but Kidman goes for broke and dives into this character so completely. She's one of the most unlikeable characters I've ever seen in film, but Kidman is so absorbed in that role and the writing is so good that you can't look away from her, just having an urgent need to keep watching in the hopes that the bitch gets what's coming to her. A wickedly sharp, intelligent and brutally funny film with impressively unique work from everyone involved. It also features a David Cronenberg cameo that is my new favorite thing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Quirky, dark and clean?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bobsgrock
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To Die For is the kind of film you should only see if you understand the nature of television. And given the way in which TV seems to involve itself in every facet of our lives, this film should appeal to a lot more than perhaps it initially did. Gus Van Sant's stylishly-directed tale about a most ambitious woman's journey to attain fame and fortune as a TV journalist is filled with moments that at first seem strange and unrealistic but gradually you begin to realize this is a world of her own creation. Nicole Kidman's performance is campy with a dark twist, giving the exact type of emotional response one needs in watching this movie. At once she is beautiful and maniacal and what makes her performance even stronger is the acting she works against. Joaquin Phoenix gives a wonderfully nuanced and subtle performance as the young man who becomes enraptured with this woman who seems to represent to him every ideal he cannot experience in the real world so he must find in this woman through TV. Both a comic crime film as well as a vicious satire on the nature of television and its potential effects on its audience.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Weird And Awkward Story
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The price of fame is murder.Or at least it is in the mind of one woman in New Hampshire.That is the plot of the movie entitled,To Die For. It stars Nicole Kidman, Matt Dillon, and Joaquin Phoenix. Major supporting roles feature Illeana Douglas, Wayne Knight, Casey Affleck, Kurtwood Smith, Dan Hedaya, and Alison Folland.It was dark comedy film, made in a documentary format based on the novel of the same name by Joyce Maynard, which in turn was based on the Pamela Smart story. It was written by Buck Henry and directed by Gus Van Sant. Suzanne Stone has spent most of her life wanting to be famous; she's attractive, speaks well, and imagines herself to be intelligent, so she has set her sights on becoming a TV anchorwoman. However, opportunities for female broadcasters are hard to come by in Little Hope, New Hampshire, and she's convinced that her husband, the once handsome but now flabby restaurant manager Larry Maretto, is just getting in her way. Suzanne gets herself a spot hosting a weather report on a local public access station, and is preparing a documentary called "Teens Speak Out," which puts her in touch with a trio of high school students -- Jimmy, Russell, and Lydia -- who are even more desperate for attention than she is. When Suzanne hatches a plot to get Larry out of her life once and for all, she uses Jimmy, who has developed a serious crush on her, to do her dirty work, but Larry's sister Janice, who has long believed there was something fishy about Suzanne, eventually begins to realize what happened to her brother. Nicole Kidman gives a fine performance in this film as she won a Golden Globe award for her portrayal of Suzanne.This was a smart and wicked delight that one may truly enjoy inspite of its weird and awkward story for it was wonderfully told and brilliantly acted.It is a must-see not only for Nicole's fans but anyone who loves good films.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Based on a true story
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bg11215
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Of the reviews I just read on here, it seems that no one realizes that this was based on a true story, the Pam Smart case. She was a woman who manipulated her teenage lover into murdering her husband for her, so that she could be free to pursue the life she wanted. While certain events in the movie are dramatized, from what I know, it follows what actually happened pretty closely. It's based on the book written by Joyce Maynard. Well I tried to post with just the above written, but IMDb wouldn't let me. They said I must write a minimum of ten lines of text. So here they are. I don't know what else to say about the film really, it was so long ago that I saw it. But everyone who wrote a review it seemed evaluated it as if it were a made-up story, which it was not. It really happened. She's serving a life sentence in prison in upstate NY for the murder of her husband. True story.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Media Lords Strike Again
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nullness
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is my least favorite type of movie: Hollywood's attempt at showing how the rest of the country is stupid and brazen for celebrity. Yes, this is actually a subgenre of movies, though the opposite is a more accurate statement. "Black comedies" with goofy scores and over-the-top performances offer nothing: too superficial to be insightful, too withdrawn to be prescient, the only advantage they offer is for a certain type of bloated self-hating American to feel smugly superior to his/her compatriots and a false sense of camaraderie with the snobbish purveyors of tasteful propaganda of Hollywood who they would love to "rub elbows" with. What's worse, this movie is misogynist, portraying vapid proto-Stepford Wife Nicole Kidman (all too easily playing the dumb blonde winking at the camera) as a career woman hell bent on getting to the top of her field (this is a bad thing?) at the expense of her lazy husband's wishes to impregnate her and have her work at his business. What's far worse, however, is for a movie like this, so so-called "sophisticated" and "edgy" when it came out, to be so uselessly out of date. In the 21st century Television is grandpa's game and the cult of celebrity is open to anyone willing to work hard with air. A movie satirizing celebrity culture that isn't totally predictable and actually has something interesting to say? Now that I'd like to see, but it would have to be made by some of us dumb hicks east of Hollywood, and we'd never get ourselves away from the screens long enough to make it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great movie. A must see for any fan of good films.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cameronmarcusk
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To die for is simply said something to live for. The movie is incredible at every turn, definitely a must see for any fan of good films or more specifically Nicole Kidman. The acting throughout is inspiring, with every twist and turn, with every suspenseful beat and betrayal the action becomes more thrilling with every minute. Nicole Kidman is amazing throughout, and the action overall is enthralling. Nicole Kidman is a brilliant actress and it's movies like these that first led me to value her a talented and worthy actress, most definitely deserving of the golden globe, bafta, and academy award that she was given for her role as Virginia Woolf in the The Hours. Can't wait to see her next film "Trespass", can't get enough of her. http://bitly.com/o7TwhG
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Linear
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris L
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gus Van Sant delivered, in 1995, this not very interesting satire on the media and exposure, staging Nicole Kidman who is ready to die (and kill) for her moment of glory. The script is unfortunately too linear, not enough catchy, and the choice of showing the outcome in the first moments of the movie turns out to be a serious mistake, ruining some of the interest of story. Moreover, the documentary style, with those interviews, is quite heavy and doesn't seem to serve any real purpose. The actors seem a bit left to themselves, such as Joaquin Phoenix in one of his first roles, and deliver lacklustre performances, hot helped by characters that lack consistency. Finally, and more surprisingly, the photography is close to being bad and gives the impression of watching a banal TV movie, which is very disappointing considering what GVS is capable of.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Broadcast Wooze
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There have been Orwellian shout-outs and warnings about "False Realities" for ever. But that doesn't stop them from becoming real. People Magazine has absolutely nothing to do with "real" People. Fox News shamelessly proclaiming "Fair and Balanced", and so on. This is a smaller and much more low-budgeted Satire about TV and Celebrity and the blurring of "Truth" validated through Media than the great Network (1976) and the over rated Broadcast News (1987). But what it lacks in financing it makes up for in a witty, dark, and piercing Script along with Artsy, sure handed Direction. Add to that some spot on Performances by a fresh (at the time) Cast of Newcomers. It is a relevant and timeless Tale (adapted from a real Tabloid tragedy) that cuts sharply and is disturbing to watch at times and is a powerfully made and under rated Movie that is one of Gus Van Zant's best and still stands as top tier Nicole Kidman.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Really well done
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Red_Identity
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To Die For is a brilliantly intriguing black comedy/drama film with some truly fantastic performances at its core. Kidman can be hit or miss with me, but she's fantastic here, letting you see her character more and more, seeing her wheels turning as she calculated her every move. Kidman has never looked more amazing and she brings the electric charm that she's known for. It was really great seeing Casey Affleck in something that was done before 2007, and Phoenix was also another stand-out who brought a compelling character on screen in contrast to Suzanne's natural charisma. I'm glad I sought this one out and it stands as one of Kidman's finest performances.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    very good movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    natrlynn
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie has a lot of my fave actors, all great performances. The real-life character (Pam Smart) was sentenced to prison. While in prison, she took photos of herself in lingerie and seduced a guard. Later, she claimed she was seduced by the guard and forced to take 'nude' pics as leverage from the guard. She said that because she came forward with this information and told the truth, she was punished by being put on 24/7 lock-down for 70 days when in fact, that was her sentence for having seduced the guard. The movie doesn't show all of this but the movie does a very good job of expressing just how coo coo cachoo she really was. I never really liked Nicole Kidman but gained a great deal of respect for her after watching this movie. **I just read a review from someone who reviews movies quite often and even has (apparently) written books. The information this person gave in the review was completely inaccurate..(Suzanne did not kill her husband to get her mini-documentary on the air) just want to let people know that sometimes even online 'reviews' can be inaccurate**
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Intelligent and hilarious dark satire.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rockwell_Cronenberg
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you had told me that one of the greatest black comedies of the '90s was going to come from the director of Gerry and Drugstore Cowboy, I wouldn't have believed you. But man, Gus Van Sant really delivered here in what I think is easily the most unique work of his career. This isn't something that I would have expected from him at all and I really wish he would delve back into this genre because he is aces. From the genius opening credits sequence, which laces hard rock, razor-sharp editing and a fairy-tale score, you can tell that this is going to be a unique and bizarre experience. Unlike many films, Van Sant fully delivers on the promise from those opening minutes. I've never been a fan of structures that rely on using interviews with the characters to retrace the steps of the story, but I didn't seem to mind it as much here, probably due to how many laughs those interviews were able to pull out of me. It also helps that using that style plugs directly into the satire of the whole piece, a real biting commentary on the dangers and absurdity of popular media. Suzanne Stone, played with groundbreaking skill by Nicole Kidman, is one of the worst possible outcomes of our media-obsessed culture; an ignorant, vain and truly hopeless woman that couldn't be less likable if she tried. She is our plug in to the satire here and what follows is a delightfully twisted and bleak tale of a horrible woman doing horrible things. Looking up the film after watching it, I was amazed that it was actually based on true events. Van Sant creates an excellent style here, along with the help of a dreamy, unsettling and utterly hypnotizing score from Danny Elfman, but the true star is absolutely Kidman. I mentioned how I wanted Van Sant to do more films like this, but I desperately want Kidman to do more as well, because she is on fire. Suzanne Stone is an absolutely abhorrent creature and the best part of the film is that Kidman doesn't try to make her anything else. Most actresses, especially that early in their career, would feel the need to add something likable to the character or give some sort of a wink to the audience to let them know that she's in on the joke too, but Kidman goes for broke and dives into this character so completely. She's one of the most unlikeable characters I've ever seen in film, but Kidman is so absorbed in that role and the writing is so good that you can't look away from her, just having an urgent need to keep watching in the hopes that the bitch gets what's coming to her. A wickedly sharp, intelligent and brutally funny film with impressively unique work from everyone involved. It also features a David Cronenberg cameo that is my new favorite thing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Quirky, dark and clean?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bobsgrock
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To Die For is the kind of film you should only see if you understand the nature of television. And given the way in which TV seems to involve itself in every facet of our lives, this film should appeal to a lot more than perhaps it initially did. Gus Van Sant's stylishly-directed tale about a most ambitious woman's journey to attain fame and fortune as a TV journalist is filled with moments that at first seem strange and unrealistic but gradually you begin to realize this is a world of her own creation. Nicole Kidman's performance is campy with a dark twist, giving the exact type of emotional response one needs in watching this movie. At once she is beautiful and maniacal and what makes her performance even stronger is the acting she works against. Joaquin Phoenix gives a wonderfully nuanced and subtle performance as the young man who becomes enraptured with this woman who seems to represent to him every ideal he cannot experience in the real world so he must find in this woman through TV. Both a comic crime film as well as a vicious satire on the nature of television and its potential effects on its audience.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Weird And Awkward Story
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The price of fame is murder.Or at least it is in the mind of one woman in New Hampshire.That is the plot of the movie entitled,To Die For. It stars Nicole Kidman, Matt Dillon, and Joaquin Phoenix. Major supporting roles feature Illeana Douglas, Wayne Knight, Casey Affleck, Kurtwood Smith, Dan Hedaya, and Alison Folland.It was dark comedy film, made in a documentary format based on the novel of the same name by Joyce Maynard, which in turn was based on the Pamela Smart story. It was written by Buck Henry and directed by Gus Van Sant. Suzanne Stone has spent most of her life wanting to be famous; she's attractive, speaks well, and imagines herself to be intelligent, so she has set her sights on becoming a TV anchorwoman. However, opportunities for female broadcasters are hard to come by in Little Hope, New Hampshire, and she's convinced that her husband, the once handsome but now flabby restaurant manager Larry Maretto, is just getting in her way. Suzanne gets herself a spot hosting a weather report on a local public access station, and is preparing a documentary called "Teens Speak Out," which puts her in touch with a trio of high school students -- Jimmy, Russell, and Lydia -- who are even more desperate for attention than she is. When Suzanne hatches a plot to get Larry out of her life once and for all, she uses Jimmy, who has developed a serious crush on her, to do her dirty work, but Larry's sister Janice, who has long believed there was something fishy about Suzanne, eventually begins to realize what happened to her brother. Nicole Kidman gives a fine performance in this film as she won a Golden Globe award for her portrayal of Suzanne.This was a smart and wicked delight that one may truly enjoy inspite of its weird and awkward story for it was wonderfully told and brilliantly acted.It is a must-see not only for Nicole's fans but anyone who loves good films.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Based on a true story
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bg11215
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Of the reviews I just read on here, it seems that no one realizes that this was based on a true story, the Pam Smart case. She was a woman who manipulated her teenage lover into murdering her husband for her, so that she could be free to pursue the life she wanted. While certain events in the movie are dramatized, from what I know, it follows what actually happened pretty closely. It's based on the book written by Joyce Maynard. Well I tried to post with just the above written, but IMDb wouldn't let me. They said I must write a minimum of ten lines of text. So here they are. I don't know what else to say about the film really, it was so long ago that I saw it. But everyone who wrote a review it seemed evaluated it as if it were a made-up story, which it was not. It really happened. She's serving a life sentence in prison in upstate NY for the murder of her husband. True story.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Media Lords Strike Again
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nullness
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is my least favorite type of movie: Hollywood's attempt at showing how the rest of the country is stupid and brazen for celebrity. Yes, this is actually a subgenre of movies, though the opposite is a more accurate statement. "Black comedies" with goofy scores and over-the-top performances offer nothing: too superficial to be insightful, too withdrawn to be prescient, the only advantage they offer is for a certain type of bloated self-hating American to feel smugly superior to his/her compatriots and a false sense of camaraderie with the snobbish purveyors of tasteful propaganda of Hollywood who they would love to "rub elbows" with. What's worse, this movie is misogynist, portraying vapid proto-Stepford Wife Nicole Kidman (all too easily playing the dumb blonde winking at the camera) as a career woman hell bent on getting to the top of her field (this is a bad thing?) at the expense of her lazy husband's wishes to impregnate her and have her work at his business. What's far worse, however, is for a movie like this, so so-called "sophisticated" and "edgy" when it came out, to be so uselessly out of date. In the 21st century Television is grandpa's game and the cult of celebrity is open to anyone willing to work hard with air. A movie satirizing celebrity culture that isn't totally predictable and actually has something interesting to say? Now that I'd like to see, but it would have to be made by some of us dumb hicks east of Hollywood, and we'd never get ourselves away from the screens long enough to make it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great movie. A must see for any fan of good films.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cameronmarcusk
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To die for is simply said something to live for. The movie is incredible at every turn, definitely a must see for any fan of good films or more specifically Nicole Kidman. The acting throughout is inspiring, with every twist and turn, with every suspenseful beat and betrayal the action becomes more thrilling with every minute. Nicole Kidman is amazing throughout, and the action overall is enthralling. Nicole Kidman is a brilliant actress and it's movies like these that first led me to value her a talented and worthy actress, most definitely deserving of the golden globe, bafta, and academy award that she was given for her role as Virginia Woolf in the The Hours. Can't wait to see her next film "Trespass", can't get enough of her. http://bitly.com/o7TwhG
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Linear
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris L
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gus Van Sant delivered, in 1995, this not very interesting satire on the media and exposure, staging Nicole Kidman who is ready to die (and kill) for her moment of glory. The script is unfortunately too linear, not enough catchy, and the choice of showing the outcome in the first moments of the movie turns out to be a serious mistake, ruining some of the interest of story. Moreover, the documentary style, with those interviews, is quite heavy and doesn't seem to serve any real purpose. The actors seem a bit left to themselves, such as Joaquin Phoenix in one of his first roles, and deliver lacklustre performances, hot helped by characters that lack consistency. Finally, and more surprisingly, the photography is close to being bad and gives the impression of watching a banal TV movie, which is very disappointing considering what GVS is capable of.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Broadcast Wooze
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There have been Orwellian shout-outs and warnings about "False Realities" for ever. But that doesn't stop them from becoming real. People Magazine has absolutely nothing to do with "real" People. Fox News shamelessly proclaiming "Fair and Balanced", and so on. This is a smaller and much more low-budgeted Satire about TV and Celebrity and the blurring of "Truth" validated through Media than the great Network (1976) and the over rated Broadcast News (1987). But what it lacks in financing it makes up for in a witty, dark, and piercing Script along with Artsy, sure handed Direction. Add to that some spot on Performances by a fresh (at the time) Cast of Newcomers. It is a relevant and timeless Tale (adapted from a real Tabloid tragedy) that cuts sharply and is disturbing to watch at times and is a powerfully made and under rated Movie that is one of Gus Van Zant's best and still stands as top tier Nicole Kidman.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Really well done
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Red_Identity
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To Die For is a brilliantly intriguing black comedy/drama film with some truly fantastic performances at its core. Kidman can be hit or miss with me, but she's fantastic here, letting you see her character more and more, seeing her wheels turning as she calculated her every move. Kidman has never looked more amazing and she brings the electric charm that she's known for. It was really great seeing Casey Affleck in something that was done before 2007, and Phoenix was also another stand-out who brought a compelling character on screen in contrast to Suzanne's natural charisma. I'm glad I sought this one out and it stands as one of Kidman's finest performances.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    very good movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    natrlynn
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie has a lot of my fave actors, all great performances. The real-life character (Pam Smart) was sentenced to prison. While in prison, she took photos of herself in lingerie and seduced a guard. Later, she claimed she was seduced by the guard and forced to take 'nude' pics as leverage from the guard. She said that because she came forward with this information and told the truth, she was punished by being put on 24/7 lock-down for 70 days when in fact, that was her sentence for having seduced the guard. The movie doesn't show all of this but the movie does a very good job of expressing just how coo coo cachoo she really was. I never really liked Nicole Kidman but gained a great deal of respect for her after watching this movie. **I just read a review from someone who reviews movies quite often and even has (apparently) written books. The information this person gave in the review was completely inaccurate..(Suzanne did not kill her husband to get her mini-documentary on the air) just want to let people know that sometimes even online 'reviews' can be inaccurate**
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Intelligent and hilarious dark satire.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rockwell_Cronenberg
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you had told me that one of the greatest black comedies of the '90s was going to come from the director of Gerry and Drugstore Cowboy, I wouldn't have believed you. But man, Gus Van Sant really delivered here in what I think is easily the most unique work of his career. This isn't something that I would have expected from him at all and I really wish he would delve back into this genre because he is aces. From the genius opening credits sequence, which laces hard rock, razor-sharp editing and a fairy-tale score, you can tell that this is going to be a unique and bizarre experience. Unlike many films, Van Sant fully delivers on the promise from those opening minutes. I've never been a fan of structures that rely on using interviews with the characters to retrace the steps of the story, but I didn't seem to mind it as much here, probably due to how many laughs those interviews were able to pull out of me. It also helps that using that style plugs directly into the satire of the whole piece, a real biting commentary on the dangers and absurdity of popular media. Suzanne Stone, played with groundbreaking skill by Nicole Kidman, is one of the worst possible outcomes of our media-obsessed culture; an ignorant, vain and truly hopeless woman that couldn't be less likable if she tried. She is our plug in to the satire here and what follows is a delightfully twisted and bleak tale of a horrible woman doing horrible things. Looking up the film after watching it, I was amazed that it was actually based on true events. Van Sant creates an excellent style here, along with the help of a dreamy, unsettling and utterly hypnotizing score from Danny Elfman, but the true star is absolutely Kidman. I mentioned how I wanted Van Sant to do more films like this, but I desperately want Kidman to do more as well, because she is on fire. Suzanne Stone is an absolutely abhorrent creature and the best part of the film is that Kidman doesn't try to make her anything else. Most actresses, especially that early in their career, would feel the need to add something likable to the character or give some sort of a wink to the audience to let them know that she's in on the joke too, but Kidman goes for broke and dives into this character so completely. She's one of the most unlikeable characters I've ever seen in film, but Kidman is so absorbed in that role and the writing is so good that you can't look away from her, just having an urgent need to keep watching in the hopes that the bitch gets what's coming to her. A wickedly sharp, intelligent and brutally funny film with impressively unique work from everyone involved. It also features a David Cronenberg cameo that is my new favorite thing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Quirky, dark and clean?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bobsgrock
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To Die For is the kind of film you should only see if you understand the nature of television. And given the way in which TV seems to involve itself in every facet of our lives, this film should appeal to a lot more than perhaps it initially did. Gus Van Sant's stylishly-directed tale about a most ambitious woman's journey to attain fame and fortune as a TV journalist is filled with moments that at first seem strange and unrealistic but gradually you begin to realize this is a world of her own creation. Nicole Kidman's performance is campy with a dark twist, giving the exact type of emotional response one needs in watching this movie. At once she is beautiful and maniacal and what makes her performance even stronger is the acting she works against. Joaquin Phoenix gives a wonderfully nuanced and subtle performance as the young man who becomes enraptured with this woman who seems to represent to him every ideal he cannot experience in the real world so he must find in this woman through TV. Both a comic crime film as well as a vicious satire on the nature of television and its potential effects on its audience.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Weird And Awkward Story
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The price of fame is murder.Or at least it is in the mind of one woman in New Hampshire.That is the plot of the movie entitled,To Die For. It stars Nicole Kidman, Matt Dillon, and Joaquin Phoenix. Major supporting roles feature Illeana Douglas, Wayne Knight, Casey Affleck, Kurtwood Smith, Dan Hedaya, and Alison Folland.It was dark comedy film, made in a documentary format based on the novel of the same name by Joyce Maynard, which in turn was based on the Pamela Smart story. It was written by Buck Henry and directed by Gus Van Sant. Suzanne Stone has spent most of her life wanting to be famous; she's attractive, speaks well, and imagines herself to be intelligent, so she has set her sights on becoming a TV anchorwoman. However, opportunities for female broadcasters are hard to come by in Little Hope, New Hampshire, and she's convinced that her husband, the once handsome but now flabby restaurant manager Larry Maretto, is just getting in her way. Suzanne gets herself a spot hosting a weather report on a local public access station, and is preparing a documentary called "Teens Speak Out," which puts her in touch with a trio of high school students -- Jimmy, Russell, and Lydia -- who are even more desperate for attention than she is. When Suzanne hatches a plot to get Larry out of her life once and for all, she uses Jimmy, who has developed a serious crush on her, to do her dirty work, but Larry's sister Janice, who has long believed there was something fishy about Suzanne, eventually begins to realize what happened to her brother. Nicole Kidman gives a fine performance in this film as she won a Golden Globe award for her portrayal of Suzanne.This was a smart and wicked delight that one may truly enjoy inspite of its weird and awkward story for it was wonderfully told and brilliantly acted.It is a must-see not only for Nicole's fans but anyone who loves good films.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Based on a true story
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bg11215
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Of the reviews I just read on here, it seems that no one realizes that this was based on a true story, the Pam Smart case. She was a woman who manipulated her teenage lover into murdering her husband for her, so that she could be free to pursue the life she wanted. While certain events in the movie are dramatized, from what I know, it follows what actually happened pretty closely. It's based on the book written by Joyce Maynard. Well I tried to post with just the above written, but IMDb wouldn't let me. They said I must write a minimum of ten lines of text. So here they are. I don't know what else to say about the film really, it was so long ago that I saw it. But everyone who wrote a review it seemed evaluated it as if it were a made-up story, which it was not. It really happened. She's serving a life sentence in prison in upstate NY for the murder of her husband. True story.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Media Lords Strike Again
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nullness
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is my least favorite type of movie: Hollywood's attempt at showing how the rest of the country is stupid and brazen for celebrity. Yes, this is actually a subgenre of movies, though the opposite is a more accurate statement. "Black comedies" with goofy scores and over-the-top performances offer nothing: too superficial to be insightful, too withdrawn to be prescient, the only advantage they offer is for a certain type of bloated self-hating American to feel smugly superior to his/her compatriots and a false sense of camaraderie with the snobbish purveyors of tasteful propaganda of Hollywood who they would love to "rub elbows" with. What's worse, this movie is misogynist, portraying vapid proto-Stepford Wife Nicole Kidman (all too easily playing the dumb blonde winking at the camera) as a career woman hell bent on getting to the top of her field (this is a bad thing?) at the expense of her lazy husband's wishes to impregnate her and have her work at his business. What's far worse, however, is for a movie like this, so so-called "sophisticated" and "edgy" when it came out, to be so uselessly out of date. In the 21st century Television is grandpa's game and the cult of celebrity is open to anyone willing to work hard with air. A movie satirizing celebrity culture that isn't totally predictable and actually has something interesting to say? Now that I'd like to see, but it would have to be made by some of us dumb hicks east of Hollywood, and we'd never get ourselves away from the screens long enough to make it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great movie. A must see for any fan of good films.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cameronmarcusk
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To die for is simply said something to live for. The movie is incredible at every turn, definitely a must see for any fan of good films or more specifically Nicole Kidman. The acting throughout is inspiring, with every twist and turn, with every suspenseful beat and betrayal the action becomes more thrilling with every minute. Nicole Kidman is amazing throughout, and the action overall is enthralling. Nicole Kidman is a brilliant actress and it's movies like these that first led me to value her a talented and worthy actress, most definitely deserving of the golden globe, bafta, and academy award that she was given for her role as Virginia Woolf in the The Hours. Can't wait to see her next film "Trespass", can't get enough of her. http://bitly.com/o7TwhG
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Linear
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris L
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gus Van Sant delivered, in 1995, this not very interesting satire on the media and exposure, staging Nicole Kidman who is ready to die (and kill) for her moment of glory. The script is unfortunately too linear, not enough catchy, and the choice of showing the outcome in the first moments of the movie turns out to be a serious mistake, ruining some of the interest of story. Moreover, the documentary style, with those interviews, is quite heavy and doesn't seem to serve any real purpose. The actors seem a bit left to themselves, such as Joaquin Phoenix in one of his first roles, and deliver lacklustre performances, hot helped by characters that lack consistency. Finally, and more surprisingly, the photography is close to being bad and gives the impression of watching a banal TV movie, which is very disappointing considering what GVS is capable of.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Broadcast Wooze
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There have been Orwellian shout-outs and warnings about "False Realities" for ever. But that doesn't stop them from becoming real. People Magazine has absolutely nothing to do with "real" People. Fox News shamelessly proclaiming "Fair and Balanced", and so on. This is a smaller and much more low-budgeted Satire about TV and Celebrity and the blurring of "Truth" validated through Media than the great Network (1976) and the over rated Broadcast News (1987). But what it lacks in financing it makes up for in a witty, dark, and piercing Script along with Artsy, sure handed Direction. Add to that some spot on Performances by a fresh (at the time) Cast of Newcomers. It is a relevant and timeless Tale (adapted from a real Tabloid tragedy) that cuts sharply and is disturbing to watch at times and is a powerfully made and under rated Movie that is one of Gus Van Zant's best and still stands as top tier Nicole Kidman.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Really well done
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Red_Identity
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To Die For is a brilliantly intriguing black comedy/drama film with some truly fantastic performances at its core. Kidman can be hit or miss with me, but she's fantastic here, letting you see her character more and more, seeing her wheels turning as she calculated her every move. Kidman has never looked more amazing and she brings the electric charm that she's known for. It was really great seeing Casey Affleck in something that was done before 2007, and Phoenix was also another stand-out who brought a compelling character on screen in contrast to Suzanne's natural charisma. I'm glad I sought this one out and it stands as one of Kidman's finest performances.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    very good movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    natrlynn
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie has a lot of my fave actors, all great performances. The real-life character (Pam Smart) was sentenced to prison. While in prison, she took photos of herself in lingerie and seduced a guard. Later, she claimed she was seduced by the guard and forced to take 'nude' pics as leverage from the guard. She said that because she came forward with this information and told the truth, she was punished by being put on 24/7 lock-down for 70 days when in fact, that was her sentence for having seduced the guard. The movie doesn't show all of this but the movie does a very good job of expressing just how coo coo cachoo she really was. I never really liked Nicole Kidman but gained a great deal of respect for her after watching this movie. **I just read a review from someone who reviews movies quite often and even has (apparently) written books. The information this person gave in the review was completely inaccurate..(Suzanne did not kill her husband to get her mini-documentary on the air) just want to let people know that sometimes even online 'reviews' can be inaccurate**
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Intelligent and hilarious dark satire.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rockwell_Cronenberg
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you had told me that one of the greatest black comedies of the '90s was going to come from the director of Gerry and Drugstore Cowboy, I wouldn't have believed you. But man, Gus Van Sant really delivered here in what I think is easily the most unique work of his career. This isn't something that I would have expected from him at all and I really wish he would delve back into this genre because he is aces. From the genius opening credits sequence, which laces hard rock, razor-sharp editing and a fairy-tale score, you can tell that this is going to be a unique and bizarre experience. Unlike many films, Van Sant fully delivers on the promise from those opening minutes. I've never been a fan of structures that rely on using interviews with the characters to retrace the steps of the story, but I didn't seem to mind it as much here, probably due to how many laughs those interviews were able to pull out of me. It also helps that using that style plugs directly into the satire of the whole piece, a real biting commentary on the dangers and absurdity of popular media. Suzanne Stone, played with groundbreaking skill by Nicole Kidman, is one of the worst possible outcomes of our media-obsessed culture; an ignorant, vain and truly hopeless woman that couldn't be less likable if she tried. She is our plug in to the satire here and what follows is a delightfully twisted and bleak tale of a horrible woman doing horrible things. Looking up the film after watching it, I was amazed that it was actually based on true events. Van Sant creates an excellent style here, along with the help of a dreamy, unsettling and utterly hypnotizing score from Danny Elfman, but the true star is absolutely Kidman. I mentioned how I wanted Van Sant to do more films like this, but I desperately want Kidman to do more as well, because she is on fire. Suzanne Stone is an absolutely abhorrent creature and the best part of the film is that Kidman doesn't try to make her anything else. Most actresses, especially that early in their career, would feel the need to add something likable to the character or give some sort of a wink to the audience to let them know that she's in on the joke too, but Kidman goes for broke and dives into this character so completely. She's one of the most unlikeable characters I've ever seen in film, but Kidman is so absorbed in that role and the writing is so good that you can't look away from her, just having an urgent need to keep watching in the hopes that the bitch gets what's coming to her. A wickedly sharp, intelligent and brutally funny film with impressively unique work from everyone involved. It also features a David Cronenberg cameo that is my new favorite thing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Quirky, dark and clean?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bobsgrock
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To Die For is the kind of film you should only see if you understand the nature of television. And given the way in which TV seems to involve itself in every facet of our lives, this film should appeal to a lot more than perhaps it initially did. Gus Van Sant's stylishly-directed tale about a most ambitious woman's journey to attain fame and fortune as a TV journalist is filled with moments that at first seem strange and unrealistic but gradually you begin to realize this is a world of her own creation. Nicole Kidman's performance is campy with a dark twist, giving the exact type of emotional response one needs in watching this movie. At once she is beautiful and maniacal and what makes her performance even stronger is the acting she works against. Joaquin Phoenix gives a wonderfully nuanced and subtle performance as the young man who becomes enraptured with this woman who seems to represent to him every ideal he cannot experience in the real world so he must find in this woman through TV. Both a comic crime film as well as a vicious satire on the nature of television and its potential effects on its audience.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Weird And Awkward Story
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The price of fame is murder.Or at least it is in the mind of one woman in New Hampshire.That is the plot of the movie entitled,To Die For. It stars Nicole Kidman, Matt Dillon, and Joaquin Phoenix. Major supporting roles feature Illeana Douglas, Wayne Knight, Casey Affleck, Kurtwood Smith, Dan Hedaya, and Alison Folland.It was dark comedy film, made in a documentary format based on the novel of the same name by Joyce Maynard, which in turn was based on the Pamela Smart story. It was written by Buck Henry and directed by Gus Van Sant. Suzanne Stone has spent most of her life wanting to be famous; she's attractive, speaks well, and imagines herself to be intelligent, so she has set her sights on becoming a TV anchorwoman. However, opportunities for female broadcasters are hard to come by in Little Hope, New Hampshire, and she's convinced that her husband, the once handsome but now flabby restaurant manager Larry Maretto, is just getting in her way. Suzanne gets herself a spot hosting a weather report on a local public access station, and is preparing a documentary called "Teens Speak Out," which puts her in touch with a trio of high school students -- Jimmy, Russell, and Lydia -- who are even more desperate for attention than she is. When Suzanne hatches a plot to get Larry out of her life once and for all, she uses Jimmy, who has developed a serious crush on her, to do her dirty work, but Larry's sister Janice, who has long believed there was something fishy about Suzanne, eventually begins to realize what happened to her brother. Nicole Kidman gives a fine performance in this film as she won a Golden Globe award for her portrayal of Suzanne.This was a smart and wicked delight that one may truly enjoy inspite of its weird and awkward story for it was wonderfully told and brilliantly acted.It is a must-see not only for Nicole's fans but anyone who loves good films.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Based on a true story
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bg11215
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Of the reviews I just read on here, it seems that no one realizes that this was based on a true story, the Pam Smart case. She was a woman who manipulated her teenage lover into murdering her husband for her, so that she could be free to pursue the life she wanted. While certain events in the movie are dramatized, from what I know, it follows what actually happened pretty closely. It's based on the book written by Joyce Maynard. Well I tried to post with just the above written, but IMDb wouldn't let me. They said I must write a minimum of ten lines of text. So here they are. I don't know what else to say about the film really, it was so long ago that I saw it. But everyone who wrote a review it seemed evaluated it as if it were a made-up story, which it was not. It really happened. She's serving a life sentence in prison in upstate NY for the murder of her husband. True story.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Media Lords Strike Again
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nullness
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is my least favorite type of movie: Hollywood's attempt at showing how the rest of the country is stupid and brazen for celebrity. Yes, this is actually a subgenre of movies, though the opposite is a more accurate statement. "Black comedies" with goofy scores and over-the-top performances offer nothing: too superficial to be insightful, too withdrawn to be prescient, the only advantage they offer is for a certain type of bloated self-hating American to feel smugly superior to his/her compatriots and a false sense of camaraderie with the snobbish purveyors of tasteful propaganda of Hollywood who they would love to "rub elbows" with. What's worse, this movie is misogynist, portraying vapid proto-Stepford Wife Nicole Kidman (all too easily playing the dumb blonde winking at the camera) as a career woman hell bent on getting to the top of her field (this is a bad thing?) at the expense of her lazy husband's wishes to impregnate her and have her work at his business. What's far worse, however, is for a movie like this, so so-called "sophisticated" and "edgy" when it came out, to be so uselessly out of date. In the 21st century Television is grandpa's game and the cult of celebrity is open to anyone willing to work hard with air. A movie satirizing celebrity culture that isn't totally predictable and actually has something interesting to say? Now that I'd like to see, but it would have to be made by some of us dumb hicks east of Hollywood, and we'd never get ourselves away from the screens long enough to make it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great movie. A must see for any fan of good films.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cameronmarcusk
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To die for is simply said something to live for. The movie is incredible at every turn, definitely a must see for any fan of good films or more specifically Nicole Kidman. The acting throughout is inspiring, with every twist and turn, with every suspenseful beat and betrayal the action becomes more thrilling with every minute. Nicole Kidman is amazing throughout, and the action overall is enthralling. Nicole Kidman is a brilliant actress and it's movies like these that first led me to value her a talented and worthy actress, most definitely deserving of the golden globe, bafta, and academy award that she was given for her role as Virginia Woolf in the The Hours. Can't wait to see her next film "Trespass", can't get enough of her. http://bitly.com/o7TwhG
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Linear
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris L
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gus Van Sant delivered, in 1995, this not very interesting satire on the media and exposure, staging Nicole Kidman who is ready to die (and kill) for her moment of glory. The script is unfortunately too linear, not enough catchy, and the choice of showing the outcome in the first moments of the movie turns out to be a serious mistake, ruining some of the interest of story. Moreover, the documentary style, with those interviews, is quite heavy and doesn't seem to serve any real purpose. The actors seem a bit left to themselves, such as Joaquin Phoenix in one of his first roles, and deliver lacklustre performances, hot helped by characters that lack consistency. Finally, and more surprisingly, the photography is close to being bad and gives the impression of watching a banal TV movie, which is very disappointing considering what GVS is capable of.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Broadcast Wooze
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There have been Orwellian shout-outs and warnings about "False Realities" for ever. But that doesn't stop them from becoming real. People Magazine has absolutely nothing to do with "real" People. Fox News shamelessly proclaiming "Fair and Balanced", and so on. This is a smaller and much more low-budgeted Satire about TV and Celebrity and the blurring of "Truth" validated through Media than the great Network (1976) and the over rated Broadcast News (1987). But what it lacks in financing it makes up for in a witty, dark, and piercing Script along with Artsy, sure handed Direction. Add to that some spot on Performances by a fresh (at the time) Cast of Newcomers. It is a relevant and timeless Tale (adapted from a real Tabloid tragedy) that cuts sharply and is disturbing to watch at times and is a powerfully made and under rated Movie that is one of Gus Van Zant's best and still stands as top tier Nicole Kidman.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Really well done
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Red_Identity
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To Die For is a brilliantly intriguing black comedy/drama film with some truly fantastic performances at its core. Kidman can be hit or miss with me, but she's fantastic here, letting you see her character more and more, seeing her wheels turning as she calculated her every move. Kidman has never looked more amazing and she brings the electric charm that she's known for. It was really great seeing Casey Affleck in something that was done before 2007, and Phoenix was also another stand-out who brought a compelling character on screen in contrast to Suzanne's natural charisma. I'm glad I sought this one out and it stands as one of Kidman's finest performances.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    very good movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    natrlynn
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie has a lot of my fave actors, all great performances. The real-life character (Pam Smart) was sentenced to prison. While in prison, she took photos of herself in lingerie and seduced a guard. Later, she claimed she was seduced by the guard and forced to take 'nude' pics as leverage from the guard. She said that because she came forward with this information and told the truth, she was punished by being put on 24/7 lock-down for 70 days when in fact, that was her sentence for having seduced the guard. The movie doesn't show all of this but the movie does a very good job of expressing just how coo coo cachoo she really was. I never really liked Nicole Kidman but gained a great deal of respect for her after watching this movie. **I just read a review from someone who reviews movies quite often and even has (apparently) written books. The information this person gave in the review was completely inaccurate..(Suzanne did not kill her husband to get her mini-documentary on the air) just want to let people know that sometimes even online 'reviews' can be inaccurate**
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Intelligent and hilarious dark satire.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rockwell_Cronenberg
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you had told me that one of the greatest black comedies of the '90s was going to come from the director of Gerry and Drugstore Cowboy, I wouldn't have believed you. But man, Gus Van Sant really delivered here in what I think is easily the most unique work of his career. This isn't something that I would have expected from him at all and I really wish he would delve back into this genre because he is aces. From the genius opening credits sequence, which laces hard rock, razor-sharp editing and a fairy-tale score, you can tell that this is going to be a unique and bizarre experience. Unlike many films, Van Sant fully delivers on the promise from those opening minutes. I've never been a fan of structures that rely on using interviews with the characters to retrace the steps of the story, but I didn't seem to mind it as much here, probably due to how many laughs those interviews were able to pull out of me. It also helps that using that style plugs directly into the satire of the whole piece, a real biting commentary on the dangers and absurdity of popular media. Suzanne Stone, played with groundbreaking skill by Nicole Kidman, is one of the worst possible outcomes of our media-obsessed culture; an ignorant, vain and truly hopeless woman that couldn't be less likable if she tried. She is our plug in to the satire here and what follows is a delightfully twisted and bleak tale of a horrible woman doing horrible things. Looking up the film after watching it, I was amazed that it was actually based on true events. Van Sant creates an excellent style here, along with the help of a dreamy, unsettling and utterly hypnotizing score from Danny Elfman, but the true star is absolutely Kidman. I mentioned how I wanted Van Sant to do more films like this, but I desperately want Kidman to do more as well, because she is on fire. Suzanne Stone is an absolutely abhorrent creature and the best part of the film is that Kidman doesn't try to make her anything else. Most actresses, especially that early in their career, would feel the need to add something likable to the character or give some sort of a wink to the audience to let them know that she's in on the joke too, but Kidman goes for broke and dives into this character so completely. She's one of the most unlikeable characters I've ever seen in film, but Kidman is so absorbed in that role and the writing is so good that you can't look away from her, just having an urgent need to keep watching in the hopes that the bitch gets what's coming to her. A wickedly sharp, intelligent and brutally funny film with impressively unique work from everyone involved. It also features a David Cronenberg cameo that is my new favorite thing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Quirky, dark and clean?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bobsgrock
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To Die For is the kind of film you should only see if you understand the nature of television. And given the way in which TV seems to involve itself in every facet of our lives, this film should appeal to a lot more than perhaps it initially did. Gus Van Sant's stylishly-directed tale about a most ambitious woman's journey to attain fame and fortune as a TV journalist is filled with moments that at first seem strange and unrealistic but gradually you begin to realize this is a world of her own creation. Nicole Kidman's performance is campy with a dark twist, giving the exact type of emotional response one needs in watching this movie. At once she is beautiful and maniacal and what makes her performance even stronger is the acting she works against. Joaquin Phoenix gives a wonderfully nuanced and subtle performance as the young man who becomes enraptured with this woman who seems to represent to him every ideal he cannot experience in the real world so he must find in this woman through TV. Both a comic crime film as well as a vicious satire on the nature of television and its potential effects on its audience.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Weird And Awkward Story
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The price of fame is murder.Or at least it is in the mind of one woman in New Hampshire.That is the plot of the movie entitled,To Die For. It stars Nicole Kidman, Matt Dillon, and Joaquin Phoenix. Major supporting roles feature Illeana Douglas, Wayne Knight, Casey Affleck, Kurtwood Smith, Dan Hedaya, and Alison Folland.It was dark comedy film, made in a documentary format based on the novel of the same name by Joyce Maynard, which in turn was based on the Pamela Smart story. It was written by Buck Henry and directed by Gus Van Sant. Suzanne Stone has spent most of her life wanting to be famous; she's attractive, speaks well, and imagines herself to be intelligent, so she has set her sights on becoming a TV anchorwoman. However, opportunities for female broadcasters are hard to come by in Little Hope, New Hampshire, and she's convinced that her husband, the once handsome but now flabby restaurant manager Larry Maretto, is just getting in her way. Suzanne gets herself a spot hosting a weather report on a local public access station, and is preparing a documentary called "Teens Speak Out," which puts her in touch with a trio of high school students -- Jimmy, Russell, and Lydia -- who are even more desperate for attention than she is. When Suzanne hatches a plot to get Larry out of her life once and for all, she uses Jimmy, who has developed a serious crush on her, to do her dirty work, but Larry's sister Janice, who has long believed there was something fishy about Suzanne, eventually begins to realize what happened to her brother. Nicole Kidman gives a fine performance in this film as she won a Golden Globe award for her portrayal of Suzanne.This was a smart and wicked delight that one may truly enjoy inspite of its weird and awkward story for it was wonderfully told and brilliantly acted.It is a must-see not only for Nicole's fans but anyone who loves good films.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Based on a true story
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bg11215
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Of the reviews I just read on here, it seems that no one realizes that this was based on a true story, the Pam Smart case. She was a woman who manipulated her teenage lover into murdering her husband for her, so that she could be free to pursue the life she wanted. While certain events in the movie are dramatized, from what I know, it follows what actually happened pretty closely. It's based on the book written by Joyce Maynard. Well I tried to post with just the above written, but IMDb wouldn't let me. They said I must write a minimum of ten lines of text. So here they are. I don't know what else to say about the film really, it was so long ago that I saw it. But everyone who wrote a review it seemed evaluated it as if it were a made-up story, which it was not. It really happened. She's serving a life sentence in prison in upstate NY for the murder of her husband. True story.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Media Lords Strike Again
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nullness
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is my least favorite type of movie: Hollywood's attempt at showing how the rest of the country is stupid and brazen for celebrity. Yes, this is actually a subgenre of movies, though the opposite is a more accurate statement. "Black comedies" with goofy scores and over-the-top performances offer nothing: too superficial to be insightful, too withdrawn to be prescient, the only advantage they offer is for a certain type of bloated self-hating American to feel smugly superior to his/her compatriots and a false sense of camaraderie with the snobbish purveyors of tasteful propaganda of Hollywood who they would love to "rub elbows" with. What's worse, this movie is misogynist, portraying vapid proto-Stepford Wife Nicole Kidman (all too easily playing the dumb blonde winking at the camera) as a career woman hell bent on getting to the top of her field (this is a bad thing?) at the expense of her lazy husband's wishes to impregnate her and have her work at his business. What's far worse, however, is for a movie like this, so so-called "sophisticated" and "edgy" when it came out, to be so uselessly out of date. In the 21st century Television is grandpa's game and the cult of celebrity is open to anyone willing to work hard with air. A movie satirizing celebrity culture that isn't totally predictable and actually has something interesting to say? Now that I'd like to see, but it would have to be made by some of us dumb hicks east of Hollywood, and we'd never get ourselves away from the screens long enough to make it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great movie. A must see for any fan of good films.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cameronmarcusk
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To die for is simply said something to live for. The movie is incredible at every turn, definitely a must see for any fan of good films or more specifically Nicole Kidman. The acting throughout is inspiring, with every twist and turn, with every suspenseful beat and betrayal the action becomes more thrilling with every minute. Nicole Kidman is amazing throughout, and the action overall is enthralling. Nicole Kidman is a brilliant actress and it's movies like these that first led me to value her a talented and worthy actress, most definitely deserving of the golden globe, bafta, and academy award that she was given for her role as Virginia Woolf in the The Hours. Can't wait to see her next film "Trespass", can't get enough of her. http://bitly.com/o7TwhG
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Linear
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris L
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gus Van Sant delivered, in 1995, this not very interesting satire on the media and exposure, staging Nicole Kidman who is ready to die (and kill) for her moment of glory. The script is unfortunately too linear, not enough catchy, and the choice of showing the outcome in the first moments of the movie turns out to be a serious mistake, ruining some of the interest of story. Moreover, the documentary style, with those interviews, is quite heavy and doesn't seem to serve any real purpose. The actors seem a bit left to themselves, such as Joaquin Phoenix in one of his first roles, and deliver lacklustre performances, hot helped by characters that lack consistency. Finally, and more surprisingly, the photography is close to being bad and gives the impression of watching a banal TV movie, which is very disappointing considering what GVS is capable of.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Broadcast Wooze
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There have been Orwellian shout-outs and warnings about "False Realities" for ever. But that doesn't stop them from becoming real. People Magazine has absolutely nothing to do with "real" People. Fox News shamelessly proclaiming "Fair and Balanced", and so on. This is a smaller and much more low-budgeted Satire about TV and Celebrity and the blurring of "Truth" validated through Media than the great Network (1976) and the over rated Broadcast News (1987). But what it lacks in financing it makes up for in a witty, dark, and piercing Script along with Artsy, sure handed Direction. Add to that some spot on Performances by a fresh (at the time) Cast of Newcomers. It is a relevant and timeless Tale (adapted from a real Tabloid tragedy) that cuts sharply and is disturbing to watch at times and is a powerfully made and under rated Movie that is one of Gus Van Zant's best and still stands as top tier Nicole Kidman.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Really well done
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Red_Identity
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To Die For is a brilliantly intriguing black comedy/drama film with some truly fantastic performances at its core. Kidman can be hit or miss with me, but she's fantastic here, letting you see her character more and more, seeing her wheels turning as she calculated her every move. Kidman has never looked more amazing and she brings the electric charm that she's known for. It was really great seeing Casey Affleck in something that was done before 2007, and Phoenix was also another stand-out who brought a compelling character on screen in contrast to Suzanne's natural charisma. I'm glad I sought this one out and it stands as one of Kidman's finest performances.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    very good movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    natrlynn
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie has a lot of my fave actors, all great performances. The real-life character (Pam Smart) was sentenced to prison. While in prison, she took photos of herself in lingerie and seduced a guard. Later, she claimed she was seduced by the guard and forced to take 'nude' pics as leverage from the guard. She said that because she came forward with this information and told the truth, she was punished by being put on 24/7 lock-down for 70 days when in fact, that was her sentence for having seduced the guard. The movie doesn't show all of this but the movie does a very good job of expressing just how coo coo cachoo she really was. I never really liked Nicole Kidman but gained a great deal of respect for her after watching this movie. **I just read a review from someone who reviews movies quite often and even has (apparently) written books. The information this person gave in the review was completely inaccurate..(Suzanne did not kill her husband to get her mini-documentary on the air) just want to let people know that sometimes even online 'reviews' can be inaccurate**
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Intelligent and hilarious dark satire.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rockwell_Cronenberg
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you had told me that one of the greatest black comedies of the '90s was going to come from the director of Gerry and Drugstore Cowboy, I wouldn't have believed you. But man, Gus Van Sant really delivered here in what I think is easily the most unique work of his career. This isn't something that I would have expected from him at all and I really wish he would delve back into this genre because he is aces. From the genius opening credits sequence, which laces hard rock, razor-sharp editing and a fairy-tale score, you can tell that this is going to be a unique and bizarre experience. Unlike many films, Van Sant fully delivers on the promise from those opening minutes. I've never been a fan of structures that rely on using interviews with the characters to retrace the steps of the story, but I didn't seem to mind it as much here, probably due to how many laughs those interviews were able to pull out of me. It also helps that using that style plugs directly into the satire of the whole piece, a real biting commentary on the dangers and absurdity of popular media. Suzanne Stone, played with groundbreaking skill by Nicole Kidman, is one of the worst possible outcomes of our media-obsessed culture; an ignorant, vain and truly hopeless woman that couldn't be less likable if she tried. She is our plug in to the satire here and what follows is a delightfully twisted and bleak tale of a horrible woman doing horrible things. Looking up the film after watching it, I was amazed that it was actually based on true events. Van Sant creates an excellent style here, along with the help of a dreamy, unsettling and utterly hypnotizing score from Danny Elfman, but the true star is absolutely Kidman. I mentioned how I wanted Van Sant to do more films like this, but I desperately want Kidman to do more as well, because she is on fire. Suzanne Stone is an absolutely abhorrent creature and the best part of the film is that Kidman doesn't try to make her anything else. Most actresses, especially that early in their career, would feel the need to add something likable to the character or give some sort of a wink to the audience to let them know that she's in on the joke too, but Kidman goes for broke and dives into this character so completely. She's one of the most unlikeable characters I've ever seen in film, but Kidman is so absorbed in that role and the writing is so good that you can't look away from her, just having an urgent need to keep watching in the hopes that the bitch gets what's coming to her. A wickedly sharp, intelligent and brutally funny film with impressively unique work from everyone involved. It also features a David Cronenberg cameo that is my new favorite thing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Quirky, dark and clean?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bobsgrock
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To Die For is the kind of film you should only see if you understand the nature of television. And given the way in which TV seems to involve itself in every facet of our lives, this film should appeal to a lot more than perhaps it initially did. Gus Van Sant's stylishly-directed tale about a most ambitious woman's journey to attain fame and fortune as a TV journalist is filled with moments that at first seem strange and unrealistic but gradually you begin to realize this is a world of her own creation. Nicole Kidman's performance is campy with a dark twist, giving the exact type of emotional response one needs in watching this movie. At once she is beautiful and maniacal and what makes her performance even stronger is the acting she works against. Joaquin Phoenix gives a wonderfully nuanced and subtle performance as the young man who becomes enraptured with this woman who seems to represent to him every ideal he cannot experience in the real world so he must find in this woman through TV. Both a comic crime film as well as a vicious satire on the nature of television and its potential effects on its audience.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Weird And Awkward Story
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The price of fame is murder.Or at least it is in the mind of one woman in New Hampshire.That is the plot of the movie entitled,To Die For. It stars Nicole Kidman, Matt Dillon, and Joaquin Phoenix. Major supporting roles feature Illeana Douglas, Wayne Knight, Casey Affleck, Kurtwood Smith, Dan Hedaya, and Alison Folland.It was dark comedy film, made in a documentary format based on the novel of the same name by Joyce Maynard, which in turn was based on the Pamela Smart story. It was written by Buck Henry and directed by Gus Van Sant. Suzanne Stone has spent most of her life wanting to be famous; she's attractive, speaks well, and imagines herself to be intelligent, so she has set her sights on becoming a TV anchorwoman. However, opportunities for female broadcasters are hard to come by in Little Hope, New Hampshire, and she's convinced that her husband, the once handsome but now flabby restaurant manager Larry Maretto, is just getting in her way. Suzanne gets herself a spot hosting a weather report on a local public access station, and is preparing a documentary called "Teens Speak Out," which puts her in touch with a trio of high school students -- Jimmy, Russell, and Lydia -- who are even more desperate for attention than she is. When Suzanne hatches a plot to get Larry out of her life once and for all, she uses Jimmy, who has developed a serious crush on her, to do her dirty work, but Larry's sister Janice, who has long believed there was something fishy about Suzanne, eventually begins to realize what happened to her brother. Nicole Kidman gives a fine performance in this film as she won a Golden Globe award for her portrayal of Suzanne.This was a smart and wicked delight that one may truly enjoy inspite of its weird and awkward story for it was wonderfully told and brilliantly acted.It is a must-see not only for Nicole's fans but anyone who loves good films.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Based on a true story
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bg11215
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Of the reviews I just read on here, it seems that no one realizes that this was based on a true story, the Pam Smart case. She was a woman who manipulated her teenage lover into murdering her husband for her, so that she could be free to pursue the life she wanted. While certain events in the movie are dramatized, from what I know, it follows what actually happened pretty closely. It's based on the book written by Joyce Maynard. Well I tried to post with just the above written, but IMDb wouldn't let me. They said I must write a minimum of ten lines of text. So here they are. I don't know what else to say about the film really, it was so long ago that I saw it. But everyone who wrote a review it seemed evaluated it as if it were a made-up story, which it was not. It really happened. She's serving a life sentence in prison in upstate NY for the murder of her husband. True story.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Media Lords Strike Again
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nullness
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is my least favorite type of movie: Hollywood's attempt at showing how the rest of the country is stupid and brazen for celebrity. Yes, this is actually a subgenre of movies, though the opposite is a more accurate statement. "Black comedies" with goofy scores and over-the-top performances offer nothing: too superficial to be insightful, too withdrawn to be prescient, the only advantage they offer is for a certain type of bloated self-hating American to feel smugly superior to his/her compatriots and a false sense of camaraderie with the snobbish purveyors of tasteful propaganda of Hollywood who they would love to "rub elbows" with. What's worse, this movie is misogynist, portraying vapid proto-Stepford Wife Nicole Kidman (all too easily playing the dumb blonde winking at the camera) as a career woman hell bent on getting to the top of her field (this is a bad thing?) at the expense of her lazy husband's wishes to impregnate her and have her work at his business. What's far worse, however, is for a movie like this, so so-called "sophisticated" and "edgy" when it came out, to be so uselessly out of date. In the 21st century Television is grandpa's game and the cult of celebrity is open to anyone willing to work hard with air. A movie satirizing celebrity culture that isn't totally predictable and actually has something interesting to say? Now that I'd like to see, but it would have to be made by some of us dumb hicks east of Hollywood, and we'd never get ourselves away from the screens long enough to make it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great movie. A must see for any fan of good films.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cameronmarcusk
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To die for is simply said something to live for. The movie is incredible at every turn, definitely a must see for any fan of good films or more specifically Nicole Kidman. The acting throughout is inspiring, with every twist and turn, with every suspenseful beat and betrayal the action becomes more thrilling with every minute. Nicole Kidman is amazing throughout, and the action overall is enthralling. Nicole Kidman is a brilliant actress and it's movies like these that first led me to value her a talented and worthy actress, most definitely deserving of the golden globe, bafta, and academy award that she was given for her role as Virginia Woolf in the The Hours. Can't wait to see her next film "Trespass", can't get enough of her. http://bitly.com/o7TwhG
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Linear
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris L
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gus Van Sant delivered, in 1995, this not very interesting satire on the media and exposure, staging Nicole Kidman who is ready to die (and kill) for her moment of glory. The script is unfortunately too linear, not enough catchy, and the choice of showing the outcome in the first moments of the movie turns out to be a serious mistake, ruining some of the interest of story. Moreover, the documentary style, with those interviews, is quite heavy and doesn't seem to serve any real purpose. The actors seem a bit left to themselves, such as Joaquin Phoenix in one of his first roles, and deliver lacklustre performances, hot helped by characters that lack consistency. Finally, and more surprisingly, the photography is close to being bad and gives the impression of watching a banal TV movie, which is very disappointing considering what GVS is capable of.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Broadcast Wooze
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There have been Orwellian shout-outs and warnings about "False Realities" for ever. But that doesn't stop them from becoming real. People Magazine has absolutely nothing to do with "real" People. Fox News shamelessly proclaiming "Fair and Balanced", and so on. This is a smaller and much more low-budgeted Satire about TV and Celebrity and the blurring of "Truth" validated through Media than the great Network (1976) and the over rated Broadcast News (1987). But what it lacks in financing it makes up for in a witty, dark, and piercing Script along with Artsy, sure handed Direction. Add to that some spot on Performances by a fresh (at the time) Cast of Newcomers. It is a relevant and timeless Tale (adapted from a real Tabloid tragedy) that cuts sharply and is disturbing to watch at times and is a powerfully made and under rated Movie that is one of Gus Van Zant's best and still stands as top tier Nicole Kidman.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Really well done
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Red_Identity
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To Die For is a brilliantly intriguing black comedy/drama film with some truly fantastic performances at its core. Kidman can be hit or miss with me, but she's fantastic here, letting you see her character more and more, seeing her wheels turning as she calculated her every move. Kidman has never looked more amazing and she brings the electric charm that she's known for. It was really great seeing Casey Affleck in something that was done before 2007, and Phoenix was also another stand-out who brought a compelling character on screen in contrast to Suzanne's natural charisma. I'm glad I sought this one out and it stands as one of Kidman's finest performances.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    very good movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    natrlynn
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie has a lot of my fave actors, all great performances. The real-life character (Pam Smart) was sentenced to prison. While in prison, she took photos of herself in lingerie and seduced a guard. Later, she claimed she was seduced by the guard and forced to take 'nude' pics as leverage from the guard. She said that because she came forward with this information and told the truth, she was punished by being put on 24/7 lock-down for 70 days when in fact, that was her sentence for having seduced the guard. The movie doesn't show all of this but the movie does a very good job of expressing just how coo coo cachoo she really was. I never really liked Nicole Kidman but gained a great deal of respect for her after watching this movie. **I just read a review from someone who reviews movies quite often and even has (apparently) written books. The information this person gave in the review was completely inaccurate..(Suzanne did not kill her husband to get her mini-documentary on the air) just want to let people know that sometimes even online 'reviews' can be inaccurate**
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Intelligent and hilarious dark satire.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rockwell_Cronenberg
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you had told me that one of the greatest black comedies of the '90s was going to come from the director of Gerry and Drugstore Cowboy, I wouldn't have believed you. But man, Gus Van Sant really delivered here in what I think is easily the most unique work of his career. This isn't something that I would have expected from him at all and I really wish he would delve back into this genre because he is aces. From the genius opening credits sequence, which laces hard rock, razor-sharp editing and a fairy-tale score, you can tell that this is going to be a unique and bizarre experience. Unlike many films, Van Sant fully delivers on the promise from those opening minutes. I've never been a fan of structures that rely on using interviews with the characters to retrace the steps of the story, but I didn't seem to mind it as much here, probably due to how many laughs those interviews were able to pull out of me. It also helps that using that style plugs directly into the satire of the whole piece, a real biting commentary on the dangers and absurdity of popular media. Suzanne Stone, played with groundbreaking skill by Nicole Kidman, is one of the worst possible outcomes of our media-obsessed culture; an ignorant, vain and truly hopeless woman that couldn't be less likable if she tried. She is our plug in to the satire here and what follows is a delightfully twisted and bleak tale of a horrible woman doing horrible things. Looking up the film after watching it, I was amazed that it was actually based on true events. Van Sant creates an excellent style here, along with the help of a dreamy, unsettling and utterly hypnotizing score from Danny Elfman, but the true star is absolutely Kidman. I mentioned how I wanted Van Sant to do more films like this, but I desperately want Kidman to do more as well, because she is on fire. Suzanne Stone is an absolutely abhorrent creature and the best part of the film is that Kidman doesn't try to make her anything else. Most actresses, especially that early in their career, would feel the need to add something likable to the character or give some sort of a wink to the audience to let them know that she's in on the joke too, but Kidman goes for broke and dives into this character so completely. She's one of the most unlikeable characters I've ever seen in film, but Kidman is so absorbed in that role and the writing is so good that you can't look away from her, just having an urgent need to keep watching in the hopes that the bitch gets what's coming to her. A wickedly sharp, intelligent and brutally funny film with impressively unique work from everyone involved. It also features a David Cronenberg cameo that is my new favorite thing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Quirky, dark and clean?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bobsgrock
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To Die For is the kind of film you should only see if you understand the nature of television. And given the way in which TV seems to involve itself in every facet of our lives, this film should appeal to a lot more than perhaps it initially did. Gus Van Sant's stylishly-directed tale about a most ambitious woman's journey to attain fame and fortune as a TV journalist is filled with moments that at first seem strange and unrealistic but gradually you begin to realize this is a world of her own creation. Nicole Kidman's performance is campy with a dark twist, giving the exact type of emotional response one needs in watching this movie. At once she is beautiful and maniacal and what makes her performance even stronger is the acting she works against. Joaquin Phoenix gives a wonderfully nuanced and subtle performance as the young man who becomes enraptured with this woman who seems to represent to him every ideal he cannot experience in the real world so he must find in this woman through TV. Both a comic crime film as well as a vicious satire on the nature of television and its potential effects on its audience.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Weird And Awkward Story
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The price of fame is murder.Or at least it is in the mind of one woman in New Hampshire.That is the plot of the movie entitled,To Die For. It stars Nicole Kidman, Matt Dillon, and Joaquin Phoenix. Major supporting roles feature Illeana Douglas, Wayne Knight, Casey Affleck, Kurtwood Smith, Dan Hedaya, and Alison Folland.It was dark comedy film, made in a documentary format based on the novel of the same name by Joyce Maynard, which in turn was based on the Pamela Smart story. It was written by Buck Henry and directed by Gus Van Sant. Suzanne Stone has spent most of her life wanting to be famous; she's attractive, speaks well, and imagines herself to be intelligent, so she has set her sights on becoming a TV anchorwoman. However, opportunities for female broadcasters are hard to come by in Little Hope, New Hampshire, and she's convinced that her husband, the once handsome but now flabby restaurant manager Larry Maretto, is just getting in her way. Suzanne gets herself a spot hosting a weather report on a local public access station, and is preparing a documentary called "Teens Speak Out," which puts her in touch with a trio of high school students -- Jimmy, Russell, and Lydia -- who are even more desperate for attention than she is. When Suzanne hatches a plot to get Larry out of her life once and for all, she uses Jimmy, who has developed a serious crush on her, to do her dirty work, but Larry's sister Janice, who has long believed there was something fishy about Suzanne, eventually begins to realize what happened to her brother. Nicole Kidman gives a fine performance in this film as she won a Golden Globe award for her portrayal of Suzanne.This was a smart and wicked delight that one may truly enjoy inspite of its weird and awkward story for it was wonderfully told and brilliantly acted.It is a must-see not only for Nicole's fans but anyone who loves good films.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Based on a true story
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bg11215
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Of the reviews I just read on here, it seems that no one realizes that this was based on a true story, the Pam Smart case. She was a woman who manipulated her teenage lover into murdering her husband for her, so that she could be free to pursue the life she wanted. While certain events in the movie are dramatized, from what I know, it follows what actually happened pretty closely. It's based on the book written by Joyce Maynard. Well I tried to post with just the above written, but IMDb wouldn't let me. They said I must write a minimum of ten lines of text. So here they are. I don't know what else to say about the film really, it was so long ago that I saw it. But everyone who wrote a review it seemed evaluated it as if it were a made-up story, which it was not. It really happened. She's serving a life sentence in prison in upstate NY for the murder of her husband. True story.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Media Lords Strike Again
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nullness
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is my least favorite type of movie: Hollywood's attempt at showing how the rest of the country is stupid and brazen for celebrity. Yes, this is actually a subgenre of movies, though the opposite is a more accurate statement. "Black comedies" with goofy scores and over-the-top performances offer nothing: too superficial to be insightful, too withdrawn to be prescient, the only advantage they offer is for a certain type of bloated self-hating American to feel smugly superior to his/her compatriots and a false sense of camaraderie with the snobbish purveyors of tasteful propaganda of Hollywood who they would love to "rub elbows" with. What's worse, this movie is misogynist, portraying vapid proto-Stepford Wife Nicole Kidman (all too easily playing the dumb blonde winking at the camera) as a career woman hell bent on getting to the top of her field (this is a bad thing?) at the expense of her lazy husband's wishes to impregnate her and have her work at his business. What's far worse, however, is for a movie like this, so so-called "sophisticated" and "edgy" when it came out, to be so uselessly out of date. In the 21st century Television is grandpa's game and the cult of celebrity is open to anyone willing to work hard with air. A movie satirizing celebrity culture that isn't totally predictable and actually has something interesting to say? Now that I'd like to see, but it would have to be made by some of us dumb hicks east of Hollywood, and we'd never get ourselves away from the screens long enough to make it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great movie. A must see for any fan of good films.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cameronmarcusk
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To die for is simply said something to live for. The movie is incredible at every turn, definitely a must see for any fan of good films or more specifically Nicole Kidman. The acting throughout is inspiring, with every twist and turn, with every suspenseful beat and betrayal the action becomes more thrilling with every minute. Nicole Kidman is amazing throughout, and the action overall is enthralling. Nicole Kidman is a brilliant actress and it's movies like these that first led me to value her a talented and worthy actress, most definitely deserving of the golden globe, bafta, and academy award that she was given for her role as Virginia Woolf in the The Hours. Can't wait to see her next film "Trespass", can't get enough of her. http://bitly.com/o7TwhG
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Linear
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Chris L
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gus Van Sant delivered, in 1995, this not very interesting satire on the media and exposure, staging Nicole Kidman who is ready to die (and kill) for her moment of glory. The script is unfortunately too linear, not enough catchy, and the choice of showing the outcome in the first moments of the movie turns out to be a serious mistake, ruining some of the interest of story. Moreover, the documentary style, with those interviews, is quite heavy and doesn't seem to serve any real purpose. The actors seem a bit left to themselves, such as Joaquin Phoenix in one of his first roles, and deliver lacklustre performances, hot helped by characters that lack consistency. Finally, and more surprisingly, the photography is close to being bad and gives the impression of watching a banal TV movie, which is very disappointing considering what GVS is capable of.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Broadcast Wooze
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leonlouisricci
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There have been Orwellian shout-outs and warnings about "False Realities" for ever. But that doesn't stop them from becoming real. People Magazine has absolutely nothing to do with "real" People. Fox News shamelessly proclaiming "Fair and Balanced", and so on. This is a smaller and much more low-budgeted Satire about TV and Celebrity and the blurring of "Truth" validated through Media than the great Network (1976) and the over rated Broadcast News (1987). But what it lacks in financing it makes up for in a witty, dark, and piercing Script along with Artsy, sure handed Direction. Add to that some spot on Performances by a fresh (at the time) Cast of Newcomers. It is a relevant and timeless Tale (adapted from a real Tabloid tragedy) that cuts sharply and is disturbing to watch at times and is a powerfully made and under rated Movie that is one of Gus Van Zant's best and still stands as top tier Nicole Kidman.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Really well done
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Red_Identity
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To Die For is a brilliantly intriguing black comedy/drama film with some truly fantastic performances at its core. Kidman can be hit or miss with me, but she's fantastic here, letting you see her character more and more, seeing her wheels turning as she calculated her every move. Kidman has never looked more amazing and she brings the electric charm that she's known for. It was really great seeing Casey Affleck in something that was done before 2007, and Phoenix was also another stand-out who brought a compelling character on screen in contrast to Suzanne's natural charisma. I'm glad I sought this one out and it stands as one of Kidman's finest performances.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    very good movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    natrlynn
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie has a lot of my fave actors, all great performances. The real-life character (Pam Smart) was sentenced to prison. While in prison, she took photos of herself in lingerie and seduced a guard. Later, she claimed she was seduced by the guard and forced to take 'nude' pics as leverage from the guard. She said that because she came forward with this information and told the truth, she was punished by being put on 24/7 lock-down for 70 days when in fact, that was her sentence for having seduced the guard. The movie doesn't show all of this but the movie does a very good job of expressing just how coo coo cachoo she really was. I never really liked Nicole Kidman but gained a great deal of respect for her after watching this movie. **I just read a review from someone who reviews movies quite often and even has (apparently) written books. The information this person gave in the review was completely inaccurate..(Suzanne did not kill her husband to get her mini-documentary on the air) just want to let people know that sometimes even online 'reviews' can be inaccurate**
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Intelligent and hilarious dark satire.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rockwell_Cronenberg
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you had told me that one of the greatest black comedies of the '90s was going to come from the director of Gerry and Drugstore Cowboy, I wouldn't have believed you. But man, Gus Van Sant really delivered here in what I think is easily the most unique work of his career. This isn't something that I would have expected from him at all and I really wish he would delve back into this genre because he is aces. From the genius opening credits sequence, which laces hard rock, razor-sharp editing and a fairy-tale score, you can tell that this is going to be a unique and bizarre experience. Unlike many films, Van Sant fully delivers on the promise from those opening minutes. I've never been a fan of structures that rely on using interviews with the characters to retrace the steps of the story, but I didn't seem to mind it as much here, probably due to how many laughs those interviews were able to pull out of me. It also helps that using that style plugs directly into the satire of the whole piece, a real biting commentary on the dangers and absurdity of popular media. Suzanne Stone, played with groundbreaking skill by Nicole Kidman, is one of the worst possible outcomes of our media-obsessed culture; an ignorant, vain and truly hopeless woman that couldn't be less likable if she tried. She is our plug in to the satire here and what follows is a delightfully twisted and bleak tale of a horrible woman doing horrible things. Looking up the film after watching it, I was amazed that it was actually based on true events. Van Sant creates an excellent style here, along with the help of a dreamy, unsettling and utterly hypnotizing score from Danny Elfman, but the true star is absolutely Kidman. I mentioned how I wanted Van Sant to do more films like this, but I desperately want Kidman to do more as well, because she is on fire. Suzanne Stone is an absolutely abhorrent creature and the best part of the film is that Kidman doesn't try to make her anything else. Most actresses, especially that early in their career, would feel the need to add something likable to the character or give some sort of a wink to the audience to let them know that she's in on the joke too, but Kidman goes for broke and dives into this character so completely. She's one of the most unlikeable characters I've ever seen in film, but Kidman is so absorbed in that role and the writing is so good that you can't look away from her, just having an urgent need to keep watching in the hopes that the bitch gets what's coming to her. A wickedly sharp, intelligent and brutally funny film with impressively unique work from everyone involved. It also features a David Cronenberg cameo that is my new favorite thing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Quirky, dark and clean?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bobsgrock
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To Die For is the kind of film you should only see if you understand the nature of television. And given the way in which TV seems to involve itself in every facet of our lives, this film should appeal to a lot more than perhaps it initially did. Gus Van Sant's stylishly-directed tale about a most ambitious woman's journey to attain fame and fortune as a TV journalist is filled with moments that at first seem strange and unrealistic but gradually you begin to realize this is a world of her own creation. Nicole Kidman's performance is campy with a dark twist, giving the exact type of emotional response one needs in watching this movie. At once she is beautiful and maniacal and what makes her performance even stronger is the acting she works against. Joaquin Phoenix gives a wonderfully nuanced and subtle performance as the young man who becomes enraptured with this woman who seems to represent to him every ideal he cannot experience in the real world so he must find in this woman through TV. Both a comic crime film as well as a vicious satire on the nature of television and its potential effects on its audience.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Weird And Awkward Story
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The price of fame is murder.Or at least it is in the mind of one woman in New Hampshire.That is the plot of the movie entitled,To Die For. It stars Nicole Kidman, Matt Dillon, and Joaquin Phoenix. Major supporting roles feature Illeana Douglas, Wayne Knight, Casey Affleck, Kurtwood Smith, Dan Hedaya, and Alison Folland.It was dark comedy film, made in a documentary format based on the novel of the same name by Joyce Maynard, which in turn was based on the Pamela Smart story. It was written by Buck Henry and directed by Gus Van Sant. Suzanne Stone has spent most of her life wanting to be famous; she's attractive, speaks well, and imagines herself to be intelligent, so she has set her sights on becoming a TV anchorwoman. However, opportunities for female broadcasters are hard to come by in Little Hope, New Hampshire, and she's convinced that her husband, the once handsome but now flabby restaurant manager Larry Maretto, is just getting in her way. Suzanne gets herself a spot hosting a weather report on a local public access station, and is preparing a documentary called "Teens Speak Out," which puts her in touch with a trio of high school students -- Jimmy, Russell, and Lydia -- who are even more desperate for attention than she is. When Suzanne hatches a plot to get Larry out of her life once and for all, she uses Jimmy, who has developed a serious crush on her, to do her dirty work, but Larry's sister Janice, who has long believed there was something fishy about Suzanne, eventually begins to realize what happened to her brother. Nicole Kidman gives a fine performance in this film as she won a Golden Globe award for her portrayal of Suzanne.This was a smart and wicked delight that one may truly enjoy inspite of its weird and awkward story for it was wonderfully told and brilliantly acted.It is a must-see not only for Nicole's fans but anyone who loves good films.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Based on a true story
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bg11215
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Of the reviews I just read on here, it seems that no one realizes that this was based on a true story, the Pam Smart case. She was a woman who manipulated her teenage lover into murdering her husband for her, so that she could be free to pursue the life she wanted. While certain events in the movie are dramatized, from what I know, it follows what actually happened pretty closely. It's based on the book written by Joyce Maynard. Well I tried to post with just the above written, but IMDb wouldn't let me. They said I must write a minimum of ten lines of text. So here they are. I don't know what else to say about the film really, it was so long ago that I saw it. But everyone who wrote a review it seemed evaluated it as if it were a made-up story, which it was not. It really happened. She's serving a life sentence in prison in upstate NY for the murder of her husband. True story.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Media Lords Strike Again
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Nullness
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is my least favorite type of movie: Hollywood's attempt at showing how the rest of the country is stupid and brazen for celebrity. Yes, this is actually a subgenre of movies, though the opposite is a more accurate statement. "Black comedies" with goofy scores and over-the-top performances offer nothing: too superficial to be insightful, too withdrawn to be prescient, the only advantage they offer is for a certain type of bloated self-hating American to feel smugly superior to his/her compatriots and a false sense of camaraderie with the snobbish purveyors of tasteful propaganda of Hollywood who they would love to "rub elbows" with. What's worse, this movie is misogynist, portraying vapid proto-Stepford Wife Nicole Kidman (all too easily playing the dumb blonde winking at the camera) as a career woman hell bent on getting to the top of her field (this is a bad thing?) at the expense of her lazy husband's wishes to impregnate her and have her work at his business. What's far worse, however, is for a movie like this, so so-called "sophisticated" and "edgy" when it came out, to be so uselessly out of date. In the 21st century Television is grandpa's game and the cult of celebrity is open to anyone willing to work hard with air. A movie satirizing celebrity culture that isn't totally predictable and actually has something interesting to say? Now that I'd like to see, but it would have to be made by some of us dumb hicks east of Hollywood, and we'd never get ourselves away from the screens long enough to make it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great movie. A must see for any fan of good films.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cameronmarcusk
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To die for is simply said something to live for. The movie is incredible at every turn, definitely a must see for any fan of good films or more specifically Nicole Kidman. The acting throughout is inspiring, with every twist and turn, with every suspenseful beat and betrayal the action becomes more thrilling with every minute. Nicole Kidman is amazing throughout, and the action overall is enthralling. Nicole Kidman is a brilliant actress and it's movies like these that first led me to value her a talented and worthy actress, most definitely deserving of the golden globe, bafta, and academy award that she was given for her role as Virginia Woolf in the The Hours. Can't wait to see her next film "Trespass", can't get enough of her. http://bitly.com/o7TwhG
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
