<filme>
 <id>
  718
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0113403
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1995
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  In the Bleak Midwinter
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.9
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Out of work actor Joe volunteers to help try and save his sister's local church for the community by putting on a Christmas production of Hamlet, somewhat against the advice of his agent ... &nbsp;&raquo;
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Out of work actor Joe volunteers to help try and save his sister's local church for the community by putting on a Christmas production of Hamlet, somewhat against the advice of his agent Margaretta. As the cast he assembles are still available even at Christmas and are prepared to do it on a 'profit sharing' basis (that is, they may not get paid anything) he cannot expect - and does not get - the cream of the cream. But although they all bring their own problems and foibles along, something bigger starts to emerge in the perhaps aptly named village of Hope.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   christmas
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   actor
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   play
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   audition
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   actress
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Kenneth Branagh
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Kenneth Branagh
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Michael Maloney
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Richard Briers
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Hetta Charnley
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Written and directed from the gut
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andre Raymond
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/5/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In every writing class the teacher tells you to write what you know. Never has this been so true as when Branagh 'knocked out' this little gem. At the time Branagh was deep into pre-production of his own monumental film version of Hamlet and all the niggling questions he was asking himself about casting and directing choices were exorcised in this film. Branagh had just gone through a separation from his wife and long time collaborator Emma Thompson. All the Woody Allen-like angst the character goes through about his own recent break-up are the result of this. Rumors were rife all over the Internet about Branagh having meetings with George Lucas about playing Obi-Wan Kenobi in Star Wars The Phantom Menace... He was asked about them and denied them repeatedly. Branagh has some fun with all that as well. The director-writer dug deep and came up with a truly wonderful Christmas gift for movie-audiences. A charming and un-pretentious film that celebrates every person's need to be loved.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A truly grim experience
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (mike.hanlon@btclick.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Am I the only person in the Universe who hated this grim clichefest of a movie? Full of gangrenous, decaying ham, tiresomely twee, this horror ends up celebrating the ghastliest form of luvviedom that it should be sending up. The real mystery is how come so many people liked it. Is it the case that there are a lots of Americans out there who are taken in by this poor-man's Ealing-comedy as something terribly, authentically, 'English'? Could it be that having Kenneth Branagh in it is enough? No idea why this should be - the man is a booming, ghastly luvvie who can't act and can't direct. It was billed I seem to remember as a 'gentle comedy', two of the most terrifying words in the English language. Terrible terrible terrible. No more needs to be said.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sparkling. Witty. Vicious.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ken-583
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/5/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love this film -- to my mind it has only one flaw and that's the otherwise delicious Jennifer Saunders' off-the-mark attempt at an American accent. Well, there's a second flaw: This film isn't available on DVD -- and my VHS copy is nearly worn out! This is a film that will be funny to just about anyone, but it will have special resonance for theatre folk. The only other film to so expertly skewer a genre of the dramatic art is "Waiting for Guffman": What that did for community theatre, this does for Shakespeare. Branagh did an extraordinarily fine job of casting the film using a mix of actors ranging from the VERY well known to the soon-to-be well known. Each of them is playing at the top of his or her game.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A love letter to theatre,Acting ,Shakespeare & Love
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Kevin G Shinnick (nitesho@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/2/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Coming off the financial failure of two big films and the end of his marriage to Emma Thompson, Branagh wrote this witty, touching, and funny ode to the madness that goes on into putting on a show and acting, and the pure joy when ,against all odds, it turns out better than you could ever hope. Produced by Castle Rock and released on VHS by Columbia(after a small but critically successful theatrical run in the U.S. as MIDWINTER'S TALE), this is a film that deserves rediscovery and a decent DVD release. Seek it out. If you have any love of the theatre, this is a must own. The cast is full of familiar British faces,(Branagh himself does not appear,content with doing an admirable job of writing and directing) who all make their wonderful eccentric characters real and lovable.The nicest discovery is just how marvelous Joan Collins is at comedy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    LIVING Shakespeare
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    KFL
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/11/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To see Hamlet, you can see Branagh's celebrated production starring himself, John Gielgud, Derek Jacobi, Julie Christie, etc etc. And it is, in and of itself, a treat. Far better though to choose this unheralded gem, and see how Shakespeare really has an impact on people. The enthusiasm is palpable. "It changed my LIFE", Joe protests to his sister Molly in defending his decision to stage Hamlet, and indeed, you can't help but see his point. When the play cuts "too close to the bone" for Terry, for example, reminding him of his dysfunctional family situation. Or when the audience gasps in horror or delight during the actual production of the play. Branagh and the actors here really, truly believe that Hamlet is alive and relevant, even today; and watching this quite wonderful film, it is hard to disagree. Watch it to see Hamlet not for itself (Branagh's production, or Olivier, or numerous other spectacles will give you that), but for how it matters to us even today, and to understand why low-paid or unpaid actors are nevertheless willing to give 132% to present it all to us.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Shakespearean Feat
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bardlover
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/1/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of my all-time favorite movies. Anything Kenneth Branagh directs is magic, and this is one of his finest. Clearly based on his own experience as an avid Shakespearean actor and director (He was a member of the Royal Shakespeare Company before forming Renaissance Films.), he too has often said "I saw Hamlet when I was fifteen, and it changed my life." As a group of misfit actors (including a male homosexual Gertrude)struggle to get their play, William Shakespeare's Hamlet, ready to perform for the children of a small town, they encounter many problems, but in the end find love and the true essence of Shakespeare. Magnificent!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ya gotta love Shakespeare! No matter how it's twisted, it's great.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jambalayaval
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Nobody does Shakespeare better than Kenneth Branagh, and this time, he's taken it to a whole new level. Putting together one of the Bard's best works with no money in a cold, damp church at Christmas may sound like a greater tragedy than the play itself. The frustrated actor/director, the cast composed of a band of merry misfits, Joan Collins playing an agent (!) and the god-awful ideas for unique sets and costumes only add to the already engaging tale of passion and deception that is Hamlet. You can't take it too seriously. But the script is intelligently funny, the experienced cast hits their marks, and even those who don't like Shakespeared will be entertained. It's a comedy, it's a mystery, it's a classic...all rolled into one.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A real joy to watch.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gclane
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love British film, comedy, theatre and probably because of the intellectual content. It isn't mindless. I watched this with my family and we were all alternatively laughing, crying, laughing. The best bit is the machine gun. Trust me! The video cover had publicity stills in colour. It was a bit worrisome when it presented in glorious black and white. But you get used to it very quickly. My daughter hunted out the video, bought it and it is regularly viewed. The performances are very, very good. Especially Richard Briers, Michael Maloney and Julia Swahala. Jennifer Saunders grates and grates and grates. Watch this film and enjoy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Simply magnificent
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael Morrison (morrisonhimself@consultant.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/1/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Rating this movie, I gave it a 10 only because there wasn't a higher number allowed. Never having previously heard of this, I decided to take a chance on it one afternoon, though I generally avoid HBO, partly out of the lack of anything else important to do and partly because I saw Kenneth Branagh's name. How serendipitous. This almost perfect cinema experience moved me to tears, made me laugh, brought me to my feet applauding and cheering -- right here, perhaps foolishly, in my living room. Branagh is further evidence that God is no socialist: Branagh has looks, talent, and now deservedly has money and probably all the romance he wants to handle. In other words, he has everything, while so many of us have nothing. Proving, as I said, God is no socialist, equitably sharing the wealth. The cast of "In the Bleak Midwinter" is just simply magnificent. I can accept a quibble that some performances are a bit stereotyped (and one director wrote in this forum that anyone believing that just needs to accompany a troupe), but even if true, so what? I love theater people. I love theater people and that is perhaps the main reason I loved "In the Bleak Midwinter." As much as any film and more than most it shows stage actors in all their quirks and foibles, and in all their inherent humanity; it shows how the love for their craft, for their heritage and traditions, motivates them far more than does money or the chance of it, more than fame or the lack of it, and much, much more than does security. Actors portraying actors often can be seen shifting into another gear, but that doesn't happen here. Director Branagh and the excellent cast of superb performers provide a nearly seamless, nearly perfect production, beautifully written by Branagh. If there were room, each and every cast member should get a glowing tribute. Each and every one was great (even Joan Collins was great, though I can't help wondering: Is she EVER going to show any age on her?), and each and every one was a standout -- which might seem to be a contradiction, a paradox, but watch "In the Bleak Midwinter." You'll see what I mean. Bravo, bravo, bravo. "In the Bleak Midwinter" is simply magnificent.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Why must the show go on? - Because it's really worth it!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    javvie
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/1/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a wonderful comedy about actors and the process of acting. A director, brilliantly portrayed by Michael Maloney, is desperate to find a remedy for his depressive mood and has no better idea than to gather unemployed actors around him to stage "Hamlet" in a church. The stunning cast adds a lot to the warm feeling that this movie leaves you with. It is a must-see and the videotape also makes a lovely Christmas present!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Written and directed from the gut
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andre Raymond
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/5/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In every writing class the teacher tells you to write what you know. Never has this been so true as when Branagh 'knocked out' this little gem. At the time Branagh was deep into pre-production of his own monumental film version of Hamlet and all the niggling questions he was asking himself about casting and directing choices were exorcised in this film. Branagh had just gone through a separation from his wife and long time collaborator Emma Thompson. All the Woody Allen-like angst the character goes through about his own recent break-up are the result of this. Rumors were rife all over the Internet about Branagh having meetings with George Lucas about playing Obi-Wan Kenobi in Star Wars The Phantom Menace... He was asked about them and denied them repeatedly. Branagh has some fun with all that as well. The director-writer dug deep and came up with a truly wonderful Christmas gift for movie-audiences. A charming and un-pretentious film that celebrates every person's need to be loved.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A truly grim experience
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (mike.hanlon@btclick.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Am I the only person in the Universe who hated this grim clichefest of a movie? Full of gangrenous, decaying ham, tiresomely twee, this horror ends up celebrating the ghastliest form of luvviedom that it should be sending up. The real mystery is how come so many people liked it. Is it the case that there are a lots of Americans out there who are taken in by this poor-man's Ealing-comedy as something terribly, authentically, 'English'? Could it be that having Kenneth Branagh in it is enough? No idea why this should be - the man is a booming, ghastly luvvie who can't act and can't direct. It was billed I seem to remember as a 'gentle comedy', two of the most terrifying words in the English language. Terrible terrible terrible. No more needs to be said.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sparkling. Witty. Vicious.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ken-583
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/5/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love this film -- to my mind it has only one flaw and that's the otherwise delicious Jennifer Saunders' off-the-mark attempt at an American accent. Well, there's a second flaw: This film isn't available on DVD -- and my VHS copy is nearly worn out! This is a film that will be funny to just about anyone, but it will have special resonance for theatre folk. The only other film to so expertly skewer a genre of the dramatic art is "Waiting for Guffman": What that did for community theatre, this does for Shakespeare. Branagh did an extraordinarily fine job of casting the film using a mix of actors ranging from the VERY well known to the soon-to-be well known. Each of them is playing at the top of his or her game.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A love letter to theatre,Acting ,Shakespeare & Love
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Kevin G Shinnick (nitesho@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/2/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Coming off the financial failure of two big films and the end of his marriage to Emma Thompson, Branagh wrote this witty, touching, and funny ode to the madness that goes on into putting on a show and acting, and the pure joy when ,against all odds, it turns out better than you could ever hope. Produced by Castle Rock and released on VHS by Columbia(after a small but critically successful theatrical run in the U.S. as MIDWINTER'S TALE), this is a film that deserves rediscovery and a decent DVD release. Seek it out. If you have any love of the theatre, this is a must own. The cast is full of familiar British faces,(Branagh himself does not appear,content with doing an admirable job of writing and directing) who all make their wonderful eccentric characters real and lovable.The nicest discovery is just how marvelous Joan Collins is at comedy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    LIVING Shakespeare
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    KFL
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/11/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To see Hamlet, you can see Branagh's celebrated production starring himself, John Gielgud, Derek Jacobi, Julie Christie, etc etc. And it is, in and of itself, a treat. Far better though to choose this unheralded gem, and see how Shakespeare really has an impact on people. The enthusiasm is palpable. "It changed my LIFE", Joe protests to his sister Molly in defending his decision to stage Hamlet, and indeed, you can't help but see his point. When the play cuts "too close to the bone" for Terry, for example, reminding him of his dysfunctional family situation. Or when the audience gasps in horror or delight during the actual production of the play. Branagh and the actors here really, truly believe that Hamlet is alive and relevant, even today; and watching this quite wonderful film, it is hard to disagree. Watch it to see Hamlet not for itself (Branagh's production, or Olivier, or numerous other spectacles will give you that), but for how it matters to us even today, and to understand why low-paid or unpaid actors are nevertheless willing to give 132% to present it all to us.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Shakespearean Feat
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bardlover
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/1/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of my all-time favorite movies. Anything Kenneth Branagh directs is magic, and this is one of his finest. Clearly based on his own experience as an avid Shakespearean actor and director (He was a member of the Royal Shakespeare Company before forming Renaissance Films.), he too has often said "I saw Hamlet when I was fifteen, and it changed my life." As a group of misfit actors (including a male homosexual Gertrude)struggle to get their play, William Shakespeare's Hamlet, ready to perform for the children of a small town, they encounter many problems, but in the end find love and the true essence of Shakespeare. Magnificent!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ya gotta love Shakespeare! No matter how it's twisted, it's great.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jambalayaval
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Nobody does Shakespeare better than Kenneth Branagh, and this time, he's taken it to a whole new level. Putting together one of the Bard's best works with no money in a cold, damp church at Christmas may sound like a greater tragedy than the play itself. The frustrated actor/director, the cast composed of a band of merry misfits, Joan Collins playing an agent (!) and the god-awful ideas for unique sets and costumes only add to the already engaging tale of passion and deception that is Hamlet. You can't take it too seriously. But the script is intelligently funny, the experienced cast hits their marks, and even those who don't like Shakespeared will be entertained. It's a comedy, it's a mystery, it's a classic...all rolled into one.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A real joy to watch.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gclane
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love British film, comedy, theatre and probably because of the intellectual content. It isn't mindless. I watched this with my family and we were all alternatively laughing, crying, laughing. The best bit is the machine gun. Trust me! The video cover had publicity stills in colour. It was a bit worrisome when it presented in glorious black and white. But you get used to it very quickly. My daughter hunted out the video, bought it and it is regularly viewed. The performances are very, very good. Especially Richard Briers, Michael Maloney and Julia Swahala. Jennifer Saunders grates and grates and grates. Watch this film and enjoy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Simply magnificent
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael Morrison (morrisonhimself@consultant.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/1/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Rating this movie, I gave it a 10 only because there wasn't a higher number allowed. Never having previously heard of this, I decided to take a chance on it one afternoon, though I generally avoid HBO, partly out of the lack of anything else important to do and partly because I saw Kenneth Branagh's name. How serendipitous. This almost perfect cinema experience moved me to tears, made me laugh, brought me to my feet applauding and cheering -- right here, perhaps foolishly, in my living room. Branagh is further evidence that God is no socialist: Branagh has looks, talent, and now deservedly has money and probably all the romance he wants to handle. In other words, he has everything, while so many of us have nothing. Proving, as I said, God is no socialist, equitably sharing the wealth. The cast of "In the Bleak Midwinter" is just simply magnificent. I can accept a quibble that some performances are a bit stereotyped (and one director wrote in this forum that anyone believing that just needs to accompany a troupe), but even if true, so what? I love theater people. I love theater people and that is perhaps the main reason I loved "In the Bleak Midwinter." As much as any film and more than most it shows stage actors in all their quirks and foibles, and in all their inherent humanity; it shows how the love for their craft, for their heritage and traditions, motivates them far more than does money or the chance of it, more than fame or the lack of it, and much, much more than does security. Actors portraying actors often can be seen shifting into another gear, but that doesn't happen here. Director Branagh and the excellent cast of superb performers provide a nearly seamless, nearly perfect production, beautifully written by Branagh. If there were room, each and every cast member should get a glowing tribute. Each and every one was great (even Joan Collins was great, though I can't help wondering: Is she EVER going to show any age on her?), and each and every one was a standout -- which might seem to be a contradiction, a paradox, but watch "In the Bleak Midwinter." You'll see what I mean. Bravo, bravo, bravo. "In the Bleak Midwinter" is simply magnificent.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Why must the show go on? - Because it's really worth it!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    javvie
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/1/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a wonderful comedy about actors and the process of acting. A director, brilliantly portrayed by Michael Maloney, is desperate to find a remedy for his depressive mood and has no better idea than to gather unemployed actors around him to stage "Hamlet" in a church. The stunning cast adds a lot to the warm feeling that this movie leaves you with. It is a must-see and the videotape also makes a lovely Christmas present!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Written and directed from the gut
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andre Raymond
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/5/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In every writing class the teacher tells you to write what you know. Never has this been so true as when Branagh 'knocked out' this little gem. At the time Branagh was deep into pre-production of his own monumental film version of Hamlet and all the niggling questions he was asking himself about casting and directing choices were exorcised in this film. Branagh had just gone through a separation from his wife and long time collaborator Emma Thompson. All the Woody Allen-like angst the character goes through about his own recent break-up are the result of this. Rumors were rife all over the Internet about Branagh having meetings with George Lucas about playing Obi-Wan Kenobi in Star Wars The Phantom Menace... He was asked about them and denied them repeatedly. Branagh has some fun with all that as well. The director-writer dug deep and came up with a truly wonderful Christmas gift for movie-audiences. A charming and un-pretentious film that celebrates every person's need to be loved.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A truly grim experience
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (mike.hanlon@btclick.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Am I the only person in the Universe who hated this grim clichefest of a movie? Full of gangrenous, decaying ham, tiresomely twee, this horror ends up celebrating the ghastliest form of luvviedom that it should be sending up. The real mystery is how come so many people liked it. Is it the case that there are a lots of Americans out there who are taken in by this poor-man's Ealing-comedy as something terribly, authentically, 'English'? Could it be that having Kenneth Branagh in it is enough? No idea why this should be - the man is a booming, ghastly luvvie who can't act and can't direct. It was billed I seem to remember as a 'gentle comedy', two of the most terrifying words in the English language. Terrible terrible terrible. No more needs to be said.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sparkling. Witty. Vicious.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ken-583
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/5/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love this film -- to my mind it has only one flaw and that's the otherwise delicious Jennifer Saunders' off-the-mark attempt at an American accent. Well, there's a second flaw: This film isn't available on DVD -- and my VHS copy is nearly worn out! This is a film that will be funny to just about anyone, but it will have special resonance for theatre folk. The only other film to so expertly skewer a genre of the dramatic art is "Waiting for Guffman": What that did for community theatre, this does for Shakespeare. Branagh did an extraordinarily fine job of casting the film using a mix of actors ranging from the VERY well known to the soon-to-be well known. Each of them is playing at the top of his or her game.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A love letter to theatre,Acting ,Shakespeare & Love
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Kevin G Shinnick (nitesho@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/2/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Coming off the financial failure of two big films and the end of his marriage to Emma Thompson, Branagh wrote this witty, touching, and funny ode to the madness that goes on into putting on a show and acting, and the pure joy when ,against all odds, it turns out better than you could ever hope. Produced by Castle Rock and released on VHS by Columbia(after a small but critically successful theatrical run in the U.S. as MIDWINTER'S TALE), this is a film that deserves rediscovery and a decent DVD release. Seek it out. If you have any love of the theatre, this is a must own. The cast is full of familiar British faces,(Branagh himself does not appear,content with doing an admirable job of writing and directing) who all make their wonderful eccentric characters real and lovable.The nicest discovery is just how marvelous Joan Collins is at comedy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    LIVING Shakespeare
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    KFL
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/11/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To see Hamlet, you can see Branagh's celebrated production starring himself, John Gielgud, Derek Jacobi, Julie Christie, etc etc. And it is, in and of itself, a treat. Far better though to choose this unheralded gem, and see how Shakespeare really has an impact on people. The enthusiasm is palpable. "It changed my LIFE", Joe protests to his sister Molly in defending his decision to stage Hamlet, and indeed, you can't help but see his point. When the play cuts "too close to the bone" for Terry, for example, reminding him of his dysfunctional family situation. Or when the audience gasps in horror or delight during the actual production of the play. Branagh and the actors here really, truly believe that Hamlet is alive and relevant, even today; and watching this quite wonderful film, it is hard to disagree. Watch it to see Hamlet not for itself (Branagh's production, or Olivier, or numerous other spectacles will give you that), but for how it matters to us even today, and to understand why low-paid or unpaid actors are nevertheless willing to give 132% to present it all to us.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Shakespearean Feat
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bardlover
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/1/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of my all-time favorite movies. Anything Kenneth Branagh directs is magic, and this is one of his finest. Clearly based on his own experience as an avid Shakespearean actor and director (He was a member of the Royal Shakespeare Company before forming Renaissance Films.), he too has often said "I saw Hamlet when I was fifteen, and it changed my life." As a group of misfit actors (including a male homosexual Gertrude)struggle to get their play, William Shakespeare's Hamlet, ready to perform for the children of a small town, they encounter many problems, but in the end find love and the true essence of Shakespeare. Magnificent!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ya gotta love Shakespeare! No matter how it's twisted, it's great.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jambalayaval
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Nobody does Shakespeare better than Kenneth Branagh, and this time, he's taken it to a whole new level. Putting together one of the Bard's best works with no money in a cold, damp church at Christmas may sound like a greater tragedy than the play itself. The frustrated actor/director, the cast composed of a band of merry misfits, Joan Collins playing an agent (!) and the god-awful ideas for unique sets and costumes only add to the already engaging tale of passion and deception that is Hamlet. You can't take it too seriously. But the script is intelligently funny, the experienced cast hits their marks, and even those who don't like Shakespeared will be entertained. It's a comedy, it's a mystery, it's a classic...all rolled into one.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A real joy to watch.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gclane
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love British film, comedy, theatre and probably because of the intellectual content. It isn't mindless. I watched this with my family and we were all alternatively laughing, crying, laughing. The best bit is the machine gun. Trust me! The video cover had publicity stills in colour. It was a bit worrisome when it presented in glorious black and white. But you get used to it very quickly. My daughter hunted out the video, bought it and it is regularly viewed. The performances are very, very good. Especially Richard Briers, Michael Maloney and Julia Swahala. Jennifer Saunders grates and grates and grates. Watch this film and enjoy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Simply magnificent
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael Morrison (morrisonhimself@consultant.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/1/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Rating this movie, I gave it a 10 only because there wasn't a higher number allowed. Never having previously heard of this, I decided to take a chance on it one afternoon, though I generally avoid HBO, partly out of the lack of anything else important to do and partly because I saw Kenneth Branagh's name. How serendipitous. This almost perfect cinema experience moved me to tears, made me laugh, brought me to my feet applauding and cheering -- right here, perhaps foolishly, in my living room. Branagh is further evidence that God is no socialist: Branagh has looks, talent, and now deservedly has money and probably all the romance he wants to handle. In other words, he has everything, while so many of us have nothing. Proving, as I said, God is no socialist, equitably sharing the wealth. The cast of "In the Bleak Midwinter" is just simply magnificent. I can accept a quibble that some performances are a bit stereotyped (and one director wrote in this forum that anyone believing that just needs to accompany a troupe), but even if true, so what? I love theater people. I love theater people and that is perhaps the main reason I loved "In the Bleak Midwinter." As much as any film and more than most it shows stage actors in all their quirks and foibles, and in all their inherent humanity; it shows how the love for their craft, for their heritage and traditions, motivates them far more than does money or the chance of it, more than fame or the lack of it, and much, much more than does security. Actors portraying actors often can be seen shifting into another gear, but that doesn't happen here. Director Branagh and the excellent cast of superb performers provide a nearly seamless, nearly perfect production, beautifully written by Branagh. If there were room, each and every cast member should get a glowing tribute. Each and every one was great (even Joan Collins was great, though I can't help wondering: Is she EVER going to show any age on her?), and each and every one was a standout -- which might seem to be a contradiction, a paradox, but watch "In the Bleak Midwinter." You'll see what I mean. Bravo, bravo, bravo. "In the Bleak Midwinter" is simply magnificent.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Why must the show go on? - Because it's really worth it!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    javvie
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/1/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a wonderful comedy about actors and the process of acting. A director, brilliantly portrayed by Michael Maloney, is desperate to find a remedy for his depressive mood and has no better idea than to gather unemployed actors around him to stage "Hamlet" in a church. The stunning cast adds a lot to the warm feeling that this movie leaves you with. It is a must-see and the videotape also makes a lovely Christmas present!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Written and directed from the gut
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andre Raymond
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/5/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In every writing class the teacher tells you to write what you know. Never has this been so true as when Branagh 'knocked out' this little gem. At the time Branagh was deep into pre-production of his own monumental film version of Hamlet and all the niggling questions he was asking himself about casting and directing choices were exorcised in this film. Branagh had just gone through a separation from his wife and long time collaborator Emma Thompson. All the Woody Allen-like angst the character goes through about his own recent break-up are the result of this. Rumors were rife all over the Internet about Branagh having meetings with George Lucas about playing Obi-Wan Kenobi in Star Wars The Phantom Menace... He was asked about them and denied them repeatedly. Branagh has some fun with all that as well. The director-writer dug deep and came up with a truly wonderful Christmas gift for movie-audiences. A charming and un-pretentious film that celebrates every person's need to be loved.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A truly grim experience
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (mike.hanlon@btclick.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Am I the only person in the Universe who hated this grim clichefest of a movie? Full of gangrenous, decaying ham, tiresomely twee, this horror ends up celebrating the ghastliest form of luvviedom that it should be sending up. The real mystery is how come so many people liked it. Is it the case that there are a lots of Americans out there who are taken in by this poor-man's Ealing-comedy as something terribly, authentically, 'English'? Could it be that having Kenneth Branagh in it is enough? No idea why this should be - the man is a booming, ghastly luvvie who can't act and can't direct. It was billed I seem to remember as a 'gentle comedy', two of the most terrifying words in the English language. Terrible terrible terrible. No more needs to be said.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sparkling. Witty. Vicious.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ken-583
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/5/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love this film -- to my mind it has only one flaw and that's the otherwise delicious Jennifer Saunders' off-the-mark attempt at an American accent. Well, there's a second flaw: This film isn't available on DVD -- and my VHS copy is nearly worn out! This is a film that will be funny to just about anyone, but it will have special resonance for theatre folk. The only other film to so expertly skewer a genre of the dramatic art is "Waiting for Guffman": What that did for community theatre, this does for Shakespeare. Branagh did an extraordinarily fine job of casting the film using a mix of actors ranging from the VERY well known to the soon-to-be well known. Each of them is playing at the top of his or her game.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A love letter to theatre,Acting ,Shakespeare & Love
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Kevin G Shinnick (nitesho@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/2/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Coming off the financial failure of two big films and the end of his marriage to Emma Thompson, Branagh wrote this witty, touching, and funny ode to the madness that goes on into putting on a show and acting, and the pure joy when ,against all odds, it turns out better than you could ever hope. Produced by Castle Rock and released on VHS by Columbia(after a small but critically successful theatrical run in the U.S. as MIDWINTER'S TALE), this is a film that deserves rediscovery and a decent DVD release. Seek it out. If you have any love of the theatre, this is a must own. The cast is full of familiar British faces,(Branagh himself does not appear,content with doing an admirable job of writing and directing) who all make their wonderful eccentric characters real and lovable.The nicest discovery is just how marvelous Joan Collins is at comedy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    LIVING Shakespeare
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    KFL
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/11/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    To see Hamlet, you can see Branagh's celebrated production starring himself, John Gielgud, Derek Jacobi, Julie Christie, etc etc. And it is, in and of itself, a treat. Far better though to choose this unheralded gem, and see how Shakespeare really has an impact on people. The enthusiasm is palpable. "It changed my LIFE", Joe protests to his sister Molly in defending his decision to stage Hamlet, and indeed, you can't help but see his point. When the play cuts "too close to the bone" for Terry, for example, reminding him of his dysfunctional family situation. Or when the audience gasps in horror or delight during the actual production of the play. Branagh and the actors here really, truly believe that Hamlet is alive and relevant, even today; and watching this quite wonderful film, it is hard to disagree. Watch it to see Hamlet not for itself (Branagh's production, or Olivier, or numerous other spectacles will give you that), but for how it matters to us even today, and to understand why low-paid or unpaid actors are nevertheless willing to give 132% to present it all to us.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Shakespearean Feat
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bardlover
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/1/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of my all-time favorite movies. Anything Kenneth Branagh directs is magic, and this is one of his finest. Clearly based on his own experience as an avid Shakespearean actor and director (He was a member of the Royal Shakespeare Company before forming Renaissance Films.), he too has often said "I saw Hamlet when I was fifteen, and it changed my life." As a group of misfit actors (including a male homosexual Gertrude)struggle to get their play, William Shakespeare's Hamlet, ready to perform for the children of a small town, they encounter many problems, but in the end find love and the true essence of Shakespeare. Magnificent!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Ya gotta love Shakespeare! No matter how it's twisted, it's great.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jambalayaval
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/8/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Nobody does Shakespeare better than Kenneth Branagh, and this time, he's taken it to a whole new level. Putting together one of the Bard's best works with no money in a cold, damp church at Christmas may sound like a greater tragedy than the play itself. The frustrated actor/director, the cast composed of a band of merry misfits, Joan Collins playing an agent (!) and the god-awful ideas for unique sets and costumes only add to the already engaging tale of passion and deception that is Hamlet. You can't take it too seriously. But the script is intelligently funny, the experienced cast hits their marks, and even those who don't like Shakespeared will be entertained. It's a comedy, it's a mystery, it's a classic...all rolled into one.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A real joy to watch.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gclane
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love British film, comedy, theatre and probably because of the intellectual content. It isn't mindless. I watched this with my family and we were all alternatively laughing, crying, laughing. The best bit is the machine gun. Trust me! The video cover had publicity stills in colour. It was a bit worrisome when it presented in glorious black and white. But you get used to it very quickly. My daughter hunted out the video, bought it and it is regularly viewed. The performances are very, very good. Especially Richard Briers, Michael Maloney and Julia Swahala. Jennifer Saunders grates and grates and grates. Watch this film and enjoy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Simply magnificent
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael Morrison (morrisonhimself@consultant.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/1/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Rating this movie, I gave it a 10 only because there wasn't a higher number allowed. Never having previously heard of this, I decided to take a chance on it one afternoon, though I generally avoid HBO, partly out of the lack of anything else important to do and partly because I saw Kenneth Branagh's name. How serendipitous. This almost perfect cinema experience moved me to tears, made me laugh, brought me to my feet applauding and cheering -- right here, perhaps foolishly, in my living room. Branagh is further evidence that God is no socialist: Branagh has looks, talent, and now deservedly has money and probably all the romance he wants to handle. In other words, he has everything, while so many of us have nothing. Proving, as I said, God is no socialist, equitably sharing the wealth. The cast of "In the Bleak Midwinter" is just simply magnificent. I can accept a quibble that some performances are a bit stereotyped (and one director wrote in this forum that anyone believing that just needs to accompany a troupe), but even if true, so what? I love theater people. I love theater people and that is perhaps the main reason I loved "In the Bleak Midwinter." As much as any film and more than most it shows stage actors in all their quirks and foibles, and in all their inherent humanity; it shows how the love for their craft, for their heritage and traditions, motivates them far more than does money or the chance of it, more than fame or the lack of it, and much, much more than does security. Actors portraying actors often can be seen shifting into another gear, but that doesn't happen here. Director Branagh and the excellent cast of superb performers provide a nearly seamless, nearly perfect production, beautifully written by Branagh. If there were room, each and every cast member should get a glowing tribute. Each and every one was great (even Joan Collins was great, though I can't help wondering: Is she EVER going to show any age on her?), and each and every one was a standout -- which might seem to be a contradiction, a paradox, but watch "In the Bleak Midwinter." You'll see what I mean. Bravo, bravo, bravo. "In the Bleak Midwinter" is simply magnificent.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Why must the show go on? - Because it's really worth it!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    javvie
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/1/2004
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a wonderful comedy about actors and the process of acting. A director, brilliantly portrayed by Michael Maloney, is desperate to find a remedy for his depressive mood and has no better idea than to gather unemployed actors around him to stage "Hamlet" in a church. The stunning cast adds a lot to the warm feeling that this movie leaves you with. It is a must-see and the videotape also makes a lovely Christmas present!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
