<filme>
 <id>
  72
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0110475
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1994
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  O M&aacute;skara
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.8
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Bank clerk Stanley Ipkiss is transformed into a manic super-hero when he wears a mysterious mask.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Stanley Ipkiss is a bank clerk that is an incredibly nice man. Unfortunately, he is too nice for his own good and is a pushover when it comes to confrontations. After one of the worst days of his life, he finds a mask that depicts Loki, the Norse night god of mischief. Now, when he puts it on, he becomes his inner, self: a cartoony romantic wild man. However, a small time crime boss, Dorian Tyrel, comes across this character dubbed "The Mask" by the media. After Ipkiss's alter ego indirectly kills his friend in crime, Tyrel now wants this green-faced goon destroyed.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Crime
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Fantasy
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   mask
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   bank
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   bank clerk
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   gangster
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   loki
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Chuck Russell
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Michael Fallon
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Mark Verheiden
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Jim Carrey
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Cameron Diaz
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Peter Riegert
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny,Goofy and Beautifully Animated,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dillon Harris
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Mask is a great movie with a very insane and enjoyable storyline with a really good comedic cast.Its not my favourite Jim Carrey performance,but it is without a doubt one of his most memorable,it really showed just what a wacky and fun actor he really is,and thats why he is one of my favourite comedy actors.The best parts of the movie is without a doubt whenever Carrey has the mask on,its a perfect mix of animation and live action,all these scenes are really exaggerated and very funny,simply impossible not to enjoy.I also really liked Cameron Diaz in this,it was her first film and it really showed the world that she was both a talented,funny and of course very attractive actress.The Mask is without a doubt a must see for all fans of Jim Carrey. When Stanley Ipkiss (Jim Carrey) discovers a mask that transforms him into insane superhero,he uses it for his own fun,and to impress Tina Carlyle (Cameron Diaz),but gets in some big trouble with the law along the way.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unbearable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watching 'The Mask' is a lonely experience, like being the only sober person in a room full of maddening drunks. It revolves entirely around Jim Carrey's rubber-faced antics as the title character, which wouldn't be so bad if the movie wasn't a comedy wasteland, if Carrey once - just once - stumbled across a single entertaining moment during his desperately hyperactive flailing, or if the supporting characters had anything to do besides look on as the visual effects romp around in devastatingly unfunny fashion. I like Carrey a lot when he's actually acting ('The Truman Show', 'Eternal Sunshine of the Spotless Mind') but when he's like this I just squirm with embarrassment. Cameron Diaz is the sole bright, likable oasis of warmth to be found amongst the dead weight that makes up the rest of this unbearable racket.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A timeless classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TichMcLovin
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of my favourite movies as a kid, and a guilty pleasure as an adult. This movie has everything that a kid could be looking for in a movie. I introduced this to my 6 year old son recently and now its all he talks about, he mimics the various characters portrayed by The Mask and has even started getting his friends asking their mums and dads about it. 10/10 from me, for the simple fact that it doesn't exactly what its supposed to, entertain families. Its a fun filled story packed with that old school slap stick comedy mixed with some cartoon parodies, all seamlessly blended by the master of laughs, Jim Carrey.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Comedy Classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Paul Robinson
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The mask is a film for me that i like as much now as much as i did when i was a kid, but considering i'm really just a massive man-child it is to be expected. The film really being the perfect setup for Jim Carrey's comedy styling's. The plot follows Stanley Ipkiss, a typical working scrub. Who finds a Mask which turns him into a egotistical Cartoon character essentially. Who causes the ire of the local gangster. Jim Carrey leads the film fantastically, the zany nature of the story and his acting give the a comic book feel, giving it a timeless quality. The humour at times being very childlike, but at times having a real edge to it. The villain Dorian Tyrell played by Peter Greene is quite a ridiculous character in a lot of ways, with so many poor henchmen around him. But Greene does some how get over this and makes him pretty intimidating. The film also has Cameron Diaz possibly at her sexiest with a great entrance in to the movie, and Milo the dog contending with Carrey with some very funny moments. Things i did not quite like were the attempts at comedy involving the cops. I did like Peter Riegert cynical detective, but his inept partner was just plain annoying. A great film to take you back to your childhood and remind you how funny Jim Carrey can be.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Smokin', Everyone Was
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thesar-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Quick! (Just like the Mask) Let me tell you my story. Honestly, I don't remember if I saw this in theatres. I probably did, because what I do remember in early 1996, is buying the VHS copy of this movie and I watched it a grand total of 5-6 times in under a week. I recall watching The Mask over and over and never getting sick of it. Sure, I had plenty of other movies to watch, but this onewas so much fun. And it still is today. Recently, I bought this movie on BluRay, because I remember loving it, but haven't seen it in over 10 years. I seriously had just as much fun today as I did with those multiple viewings when I first bought the VHS. This movie really holds up from the many years since its release. It really is timeless. Goody-Man Stanley Ipkiss (Jim Carrey) is transformed into the daredevil Mask figure when he finds, and dons an ancient wooden mask, and his inner desires come out tenfold. He goes for the girl, inadvertently pisses off the mob and takes care of business as "The Mask" superhero/cartoon character that mild-mannered Stanley couldn't. The story isn't exactly new, even for 1994, but it's take on the age-old underdog/superhero is fresh, exciting and most of all HILARIOUS. As a matter of fact, when prepping and watching the movie to write this review, I was puzzled on which genre this movie fit in: Action/Adventure + SuperHero? Or Comedy + the rest mentioned? And as I found myself laughing and laughing, even after my 5+ original viewings, I settled on: This MUST be a comedywith a close second of Action/adventure + SuperHero. I think this is a very underrated film. It was a very old concept that was a ton of fun, thanks to Jim Carrey at his peak and newcomer, Cameron Diaz who (almost) stole every scene she was in. She was gorgeous and talented and it was hard to believe that this was her first outing. Honestly, as much as I do like her, but not so much every movie she's been in  though I do enjoy a lot of her films, she was fantastic in this. And I understand that dog was like a prop, I still LOVED little Milo. You have to suspend your disbelief a lot during this movie, so you might as well believe all the dog accomplished. This movie is so straight forward to typical movie viewers and still, it's a lot of fun. And it contains one of my all-time favorite scenes/songs in any movie: The Cuban Pete dance segment. Pricelessas was this movie. See it! It still holds up today and despite all the smoking, especially if you're against that, it's a helluva lot of fun.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I don't normally watch Jim Carry, but when i do, i do it right.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    LoneDoveProductions /MTN
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love the Mask. The movie was just like a big cartoon, and fortunately enough, I am immature enough to love this childish humor. The effects were acceptable because it was meant to look like a cartoon. The jokes were funny if you have a little bit of a child at heart. I may be overrating this film, and i feel as i am, but its just the love of these nostalgia cartoons that makes me love this film. I cant say anything more, its just him Carry's best film to me, and deserves a little more recognition. This movie set out a cartoon series(which was not as good since the joke of putting a cartoon in real life is gone) and eventually a sequel, which i did not enjoy much either. The beauty was Jim Carrys over the top acting in this role. It does not work in many characters but is PERFECT for the chaotic mask. My opinion, I'm overrating it a bit, but go watch it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    somebody stop me
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lagudafuad
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You just have to appreciate the technicality and the visual effects that went into the production of this massive hit. The Mask introduced a character that we all started to love and cherish, a hero that can do absolutely anything his mind thinks of. This slap stick comedy showed how Jim Carrey became a good lead actor; he carried the show right from the start to the final battle, doing everything we see in the Warner bros cartoons. After this massive hit, an animated series was also done, introducing more villains and more takes into the life of Stanley Ipkiss. This movie "The Mask" is based on a series of comic books of the same name; the comic is the product of Dark Horse Comics and The Mask was introduced in the 80's based on a concept by the publisher Mike Richardson and created by writer John Arcudi and artist Doug Mahnke. Like in this movie the comic series follows a magical mask and its owner Stanley Ipkiss. When the mask is worn the wearer can bend reality, do the impossible physically and survive the unbelievable. All this is based on the wearer's depth of imagination which The Mask will then surpass. The plot is about a Mr. nice guy, Stanley Ipkiss (Jim Carrey) whom the world seems to step on. Things took a turn around for Ipkiss when he came across a magical mask, which gave him powers to do the impossible. But The Mask was uncontrollable and Ipkiss stepped on toes which were ready to do anything to kill the man behind the mask. The movie is filled with thrilling visual effects, and a wonderful cast. Jim Carrey was just exceptional. The Mask was also Cameron Diaz's first acting role, which later pushed her up the ladder as she now features in major movies yearly. The Mask was a huge box office hit making over 350 million from its 23 million production cost, it was also a critical acclaim, leaving behind it a trail of catchphrases in its time like "smoking" or "somebody stop me". Its high box office status made the makers approach Jim Carrey for a sequel, which he turned down (as Carrey believes making sequels are not challenging). The ideas for the sequel were then used in the animated series, which spawned two seasons. Later after 11 years, a sequel was made but it was unrelated to the first or the animated series, it was titled Son of The Mask which received high negative reviews and was a box office bomb, as the visual effects and the plot were lame and out of place, putting in consideration that it was made with over 84 million. Our hero The Mask is best portrayed here in this beautiful movie and it is a keeper. www.lagsreviews.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Slapstick comedy that makes the world fixable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rosemary (zelda1964)
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jim Carrey (Ace Ventura: Pet Detective) is a zany comic who adds fun to any role he plays; Cameron Diaz (Head Above Water)is a wonderful talent in many films.In The Mask,we find Ipkiss(Carrey),getting bored with his everyday ho-hum bank job;On a chance,Stanley finds this mask that reaches inside to bring out retribution for the world's hard luck.As it happens,Diaz plays the lounge singer Ipkiss falls in love with.Dorian,a co- worker at the lounge,gets upset when Ipkiss (as the masked hero) averts his threat to steal all the savings.The cutest character is Milo,who plays Stanley's lovable pooch. I call this a marvelous film that really tickles the clich&eacute;d "funny bone".Bravo and cheers!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Perfect Vehicle For Jim Carrey
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Mask is a fantasy comedy that is based on a series of comic books published by Dark Horse Comics. The film stars Jim Carrey as Stanley Ipkiss, a man who finds the Mask of Loki that turns him into The Mask, a trickster uninhibited by anything, including physical reality. The supporting cast includes Peter Greene as mafia officer Dorian Tyrell, Amy Yasbeck as a newspaper reporter, Peter Riegert and Jim Doughan as two police detectives, Richard Jeni as Stanley's friend, Orestes Matacena as nightclub owner and mafia boss Niko, Ben Stein as a psychologist, and Cameron Diaz in her feature film debut as Stanley's love interest Tina Carlyle. Hyperactive mayhem results when a mild-manned banker discovers an ancient mask that transforms him into a zany prankster with superhuman powers in this special-effects-intensive comedy.Stanley Ipkiss is a decent-hearted but socially awkward guy who one night finds a strange mask. Stanley puts on the mask and the banker transforms into The Mask, a green-skinned, zoot-suited fireball. The rubber-faced Mask possesses the courage to do the wild, fun things that Stanley fears, including romancing Tina Carlyle. The larger narrative, involving the efforts of Tina's gangster boyfriend to destroy Stanley and use the mask's powers for evil, prove less interesting than the anarchic comic set pieces. The film delivered enough laughs as it is a perfect vehicle for the talents of Jim Carrey wherein he seems to have found a story and character that work together with manic energy.In addition to his physical talents, the film makes effective use of digital visual effects that bestow the Mask with superhuman speed, insane flexibility, and popping eyes out of a Tex Avery cartoon.The design is bright as a button and the transformation scenes real eye-poppers, but the film's best special effect is putty-faced Carrey with his razzle-dazzle star turn as the affable Stanley and his manic alter ego.This makes it a marvelously energetic and highly enjoyable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of my personal favorites as a child and still love it as a young adult!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin-thelordofthefu-48-460297
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    OK, I never read the comics this was based on, but in terms of judging a comic-book movie adaptation on it's own merits, I used to watch this a few more time as a little child at the mid-90s when it was released and I loved it as much as anyone else in this website even as a young adult. Sure, it may not be the best movie, but I've seen much much worse films and I think that this is one of Jim Carrey's best films in my opinion next to Liar Liar and Ace Ventura: Pet Detective. The story is pretty engaging and has some of my favorite moments throughout the film (the casino scene, the dancing sequence, the balloon animals, and the quotes "Somebody Stop Me!" and more), the script's humorous and made me laugh really hard, the special effects are the epitome of greatness, and the music is good, but the strongest aspect goes to the cast especially Jim Carry which I like the best and I liked his personality (going from a mild-mannered person to a wild and crazed superhero). Cameron Diaz and others did a great job with their roles and the villain is pretty good too. The pacing is brisk and the songs are good too. Overall, love this movie as a kid and still love it as an adult and it's definitely worth-watching!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny,Goofy and Beautifully Animated,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dillon Harris
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Mask is a great movie with a very insane and enjoyable storyline with a really good comedic cast.Its not my favourite Jim Carrey performance,but it is without a doubt one of his most memorable,it really showed just what a wacky and fun actor he really is,and thats why he is one of my favourite comedy actors.The best parts of the movie is without a doubt whenever Carrey has the mask on,its a perfect mix of animation and live action,all these scenes are really exaggerated and very funny,simply impossible not to enjoy.I also really liked Cameron Diaz in this,it was her first film and it really showed the world that she was both a talented,funny and of course very attractive actress.The Mask is without a doubt a must see for all fans of Jim Carrey. When Stanley Ipkiss (Jim Carrey) discovers a mask that transforms him into insane superhero,he uses it for his own fun,and to impress Tina Carlyle (Cameron Diaz),but gets in some big trouble with the law along the way.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unbearable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watching 'The Mask' is a lonely experience, like being the only sober person in a room full of maddening drunks. It revolves entirely around Jim Carrey's rubber-faced antics as the title character, which wouldn't be so bad if the movie wasn't a comedy wasteland, if Carrey once - just once - stumbled across a single entertaining moment during his desperately hyperactive flailing, or if the supporting characters had anything to do besides look on as the visual effects romp around in devastatingly unfunny fashion. I like Carrey a lot when he's actually acting ('The Truman Show', 'Eternal Sunshine of the Spotless Mind') but when he's like this I just squirm with embarrassment. Cameron Diaz is the sole bright, likable oasis of warmth to be found amongst the dead weight that makes up the rest of this unbearable racket.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A timeless classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TichMcLovin
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of my favourite movies as a kid, and a guilty pleasure as an adult. This movie has everything that a kid could be looking for in a movie. I introduced this to my 6 year old son recently and now its all he talks about, he mimics the various characters portrayed by The Mask and has even started getting his friends asking their mums and dads about it. 10/10 from me, for the simple fact that it doesn't exactly what its supposed to, entertain families. Its a fun filled story packed with that old school slap stick comedy mixed with some cartoon parodies, all seamlessly blended by the master of laughs, Jim Carrey.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Comedy Classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Paul Robinson
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The mask is a film for me that i like as much now as much as i did when i was a kid, but considering i'm really just a massive man-child it is to be expected. The film really being the perfect setup for Jim Carrey's comedy styling's. The plot follows Stanley Ipkiss, a typical working scrub. Who finds a Mask which turns him into a egotistical Cartoon character essentially. Who causes the ire of the local gangster. Jim Carrey leads the film fantastically, the zany nature of the story and his acting give the a comic book feel, giving it a timeless quality. The humour at times being very childlike, but at times having a real edge to it. The villain Dorian Tyrell played by Peter Greene is quite a ridiculous character in a lot of ways, with so many poor henchmen around him. But Greene does some how get over this and makes him pretty intimidating. The film also has Cameron Diaz possibly at her sexiest with a great entrance in to the movie, and Milo the dog contending with Carrey with some very funny moments. Things i did not quite like were the attempts at comedy involving the cops. I did like Peter Riegert cynical detective, but his inept partner was just plain annoying. A great film to take you back to your childhood and remind you how funny Jim Carrey can be.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Smokin', Everyone Was
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thesar-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Quick! (Just like the Mask) Let me tell you my story. Honestly, I don't remember if I saw this in theatres. I probably did, because what I do remember in early 1996, is buying the VHS copy of this movie and I watched it a grand total of 5-6 times in under a week. I recall watching The Mask over and over and never getting sick of it. Sure, I had plenty of other movies to watch, but this onewas so much fun. And it still is today. Recently, I bought this movie on BluRay, because I remember loving it, but haven't seen it in over 10 years. I seriously had just as much fun today as I did with those multiple viewings when I first bought the VHS. This movie really holds up from the many years since its release. It really is timeless. Goody-Man Stanley Ipkiss (Jim Carrey) is transformed into the daredevil Mask figure when he finds, and dons an ancient wooden mask, and his inner desires come out tenfold. He goes for the girl, inadvertently pisses off the mob and takes care of business as "The Mask" superhero/cartoon character that mild-mannered Stanley couldn't. The story isn't exactly new, even for 1994, but it's take on the age-old underdog/superhero is fresh, exciting and most of all HILARIOUS. As a matter of fact, when prepping and watching the movie to write this review, I was puzzled on which genre this movie fit in: Action/Adventure + SuperHero? Or Comedy + the rest mentioned? And as I found myself laughing and laughing, even after my 5+ original viewings, I settled on: This MUST be a comedywith a close second of Action/adventure + SuperHero. I think this is a very underrated film. It was a very old concept that was a ton of fun, thanks to Jim Carrey at his peak and newcomer, Cameron Diaz who (almost) stole every scene she was in. She was gorgeous and talented and it was hard to believe that this was her first outing. Honestly, as much as I do like her, but not so much every movie she's been in  though I do enjoy a lot of her films, she was fantastic in this. And I understand that dog was like a prop, I still LOVED little Milo. You have to suspend your disbelief a lot during this movie, so you might as well believe all the dog accomplished. This movie is so straight forward to typical movie viewers and still, it's a lot of fun. And it contains one of my all-time favorite scenes/songs in any movie: The Cuban Pete dance segment. Pricelessas was this movie. See it! It still holds up today and despite all the smoking, especially if you're against that, it's a helluva lot of fun.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I don't normally watch Jim Carry, but when i do, i do it right.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    LoneDoveProductions /MTN
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love the Mask. The movie was just like a big cartoon, and fortunately enough, I am immature enough to love this childish humor. The effects were acceptable because it was meant to look like a cartoon. The jokes were funny if you have a little bit of a child at heart. I may be overrating this film, and i feel as i am, but its just the love of these nostalgia cartoons that makes me love this film. I cant say anything more, its just him Carry's best film to me, and deserves a little more recognition. This movie set out a cartoon series(which was not as good since the joke of putting a cartoon in real life is gone) and eventually a sequel, which i did not enjoy much either. The beauty was Jim Carrys over the top acting in this role. It does not work in many characters but is PERFECT for the chaotic mask. My opinion, I'm overrating it a bit, but go watch it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    somebody stop me
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lagudafuad
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You just have to appreciate the technicality and the visual effects that went into the production of this massive hit. The Mask introduced a character that we all started to love and cherish, a hero that can do absolutely anything his mind thinks of. This slap stick comedy showed how Jim Carrey became a good lead actor; he carried the show right from the start to the final battle, doing everything we see in the Warner bros cartoons. After this massive hit, an animated series was also done, introducing more villains and more takes into the life of Stanley Ipkiss. This movie "The Mask" is based on a series of comic books of the same name; the comic is the product of Dark Horse Comics and The Mask was introduced in the 80's based on a concept by the publisher Mike Richardson and created by writer John Arcudi and artist Doug Mahnke. Like in this movie the comic series follows a magical mask and its owner Stanley Ipkiss. When the mask is worn the wearer can bend reality, do the impossible physically and survive the unbelievable. All this is based on the wearer's depth of imagination which The Mask will then surpass. The plot is about a Mr. nice guy, Stanley Ipkiss (Jim Carrey) whom the world seems to step on. Things took a turn around for Ipkiss when he came across a magical mask, which gave him powers to do the impossible. But The Mask was uncontrollable and Ipkiss stepped on toes which were ready to do anything to kill the man behind the mask. The movie is filled with thrilling visual effects, and a wonderful cast. Jim Carrey was just exceptional. The Mask was also Cameron Diaz's first acting role, which later pushed her up the ladder as she now features in major movies yearly. The Mask was a huge box office hit making over 350 million from its 23 million production cost, it was also a critical acclaim, leaving behind it a trail of catchphrases in its time like "smoking" or "somebody stop me". Its high box office status made the makers approach Jim Carrey for a sequel, which he turned down (as Carrey believes making sequels are not challenging). The ideas for the sequel were then used in the animated series, which spawned two seasons. Later after 11 years, a sequel was made but it was unrelated to the first or the animated series, it was titled Son of The Mask which received high negative reviews and was a box office bomb, as the visual effects and the plot were lame and out of place, putting in consideration that it was made with over 84 million. Our hero The Mask is best portrayed here in this beautiful movie and it is a keeper. www.lagsreviews.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Slapstick comedy that makes the world fixable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rosemary (zelda1964)
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jim Carrey (Ace Ventura: Pet Detective) is a zany comic who adds fun to any role he plays; Cameron Diaz (Head Above Water)is a wonderful talent in many films.In The Mask,we find Ipkiss(Carrey),getting bored with his everyday ho-hum bank job;On a chance,Stanley finds this mask that reaches inside to bring out retribution for the world's hard luck.As it happens,Diaz plays the lounge singer Ipkiss falls in love with.Dorian,a co- worker at the lounge,gets upset when Ipkiss (as the masked hero) averts his threat to steal all the savings.The cutest character is Milo,who plays Stanley's lovable pooch. I call this a marvelous film that really tickles the clich&eacute;d "funny bone".Bravo and cheers!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Perfect Vehicle For Jim Carrey
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Mask is a fantasy comedy that is based on a series of comic books published by Dark Horse Comics. The film stars Jim Carrey as Stanley Ipkiss, a man who finds the Mask of Loki that turns him into The Mask, a trickster uninhibited by anything, including physical reality. The supporting cast includes Peter Greene as mafia officer Dorian Tyrell, Amy Yasbeck as a newspaper reporter, Peter Riegert and Jim Doughan as two police detectives, Richard Jeni as Stanley's friend, Orestes Matacena as nightclub owner and mafia boss Niko, Ben Stein as a psychologist, and Cameron Diaz in her feature film debut as Stanley's love interest Tina Carlyle. Hyperactive mayhem results when a mild-manned banker discovers an ancient mask that transforms him into a zany prankster with superhuman powers in this special-effects-intensive comedy.Stanley Ipkiss is a decent-hearted but socially awkward guy who one night finds a strange mask. Stanley puts on the mask and the banker transforms into The Mask, a green-skinned, zoot-suited fireball. The rubber-faced Mask possesses the courage to do the wild, fun things that Stanley fears, including romancing Tina Carlyle. The larger narrative, involving the efforts of Tina's gangster boyfriend to destroy Stanley and use the mask's powers for evil, prove less interesting than the anarchic comic set pieces. The film delivered enough laughs as it is a perfect vehicle for the talents of Jim Carrey wherein he seems to have found a story and character that work together with manic energy.In addition to his physical talents, the film makes effective use of digital visual effects that bestow the Mask with superhuman speed, insane flexibility, and popping eyes out of a Tex Avery cartoon.The design is bright as a button and the transformation scenes real eye-poppers, but the film's best special effect is putty-faced Carrey with his razzle-dazzle star turn as the affable Stanley and his manic alter ego.This makes it a marvelously energetic and highly enjoyable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of my personal favorites as a child and still love it as a young adult!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin-thelordofthefu-48-460297
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    OK, I never read the comics this was based on, but in terms of judging a comic-book movie adaptation on it's own merits, I used to watch this a few more time as a little child at the mid-90s when it was released and I loved it as much as anyone else in this website even as a young adult. Sure, it may not be the best movie, but I've seen much much worse films and I think that this is one of Jim Carrey's best films in my opinion next to Liar Liar and Ace Ventura: Pet Detective. The story is pretty engaging and has some of my favorite moments throughout the film (the casino scene, the dancing sequence, the balloon animals, and the quotes "Somebody Stop Me!" and more), the script's humorous and made me laugh really hard, the special effects are the epitome of greatness, and the music is good, but the strongest aspect goes to the cast especially Jim Carry which I like the best and I liked his personality (going from a mild-mannered person to a wild and crazed superhero). Cameron Diaz and others did a great job with their roles and the villain is pretty good too. The pacing is brisk and the songs are good too. Overall, love this movie as a kid and still love it as an adult and it's definitely worth-watching!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny,Goofy and Beautifully Animated,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dillon Harris
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Mask is a great movie with a very insane and enjoyable storyline with a really good comedic cast.Its not my favourite Jim Carrey performance,but it is without a doubt one of his most memorable,it really showed just what a wacky and fun actor he really is,and thats why he is one of my favourite comedy actors.The best parts of the movie is without a doubt whenever Carrey has the mask on,its a perfect mix of animation and live action,all these scenes are really exaggerated and very funny,simply impossible not to enjoy.I also really liked Cameron Diaz in this,it was her first film and it really showed the world that she was both a talented,funny and of course very attractive actress.The Mask is without a doubt a must see for all fans of Jim Carrey. When Stanley Ipkiss (Jim Carrey) discovers a mask that transforms him into insane superhero,he uses it for his own fun,and to impress Tina Carlyle (Cameron Diaz),but gets in some big trouble with the law along the way.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unbearable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watching 'The Mask' is a lonely experience, like being the only sober person in a room full of maddening drunks. It revolves entirely around Jim Carrey's rubber-faced antics as the title character, which wouldn't be so bad if the movie wasn't a comedy wasteland, if Carrey once - just once - stumbled across a single entertaining moment during his desperately hyperactive flailing, or if the supporting characters had anything to do besides look on as the visual effects romp around in devastatingly unfunny fashion. I like Carrey a lot when he's actually acting ('The Truman Show', 'Eternal Sunshine of the Spotless Mind') but when he's like this I just squirm with embarrassment. Cameron Diaz is the sole bright, likable oasis of warmth to be found amongst the dead weight that makes up the rest of this unbearable racket.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A timeless classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TichMcLovin
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of my favourite movies as a kid, and a guilty pleasure as an adult. This movie has everything that a kid could be looking for in a movie. I introduced this to my 6 year old son recently and now its all he talks about, he mimics the various characters portrayed by The Mask and has even started getting his friends asking their mums and dads about it. 10/10 from me, for the simple fact that it doesn't exactly what its supposed to, entertain families. Its a fun filled story packed with that old school slap stick comedy mixed with some cartoon parodies, all seamlessly blended by the master of laughs, Jim Carrey.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Comedy Classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Paul Robinson
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The mask is a film for me that i like as much now as much as i did when i was a kid, but considering i'm really just a massive man-child it is to be expected. The film really being the perfect setup for Jim Carrey's comedy styling's. The plot follows Stanley Ipkiss, a typical working scrub. Who finds a Mask which turns him into a egotistical Cartoon character essentially. Who causes the ire of the local gangster. Jim Carrey leads the film fantastically, the zany nature of the story and his acting give the a comic book feel, giving it a timeless quality. The humour at times being very childlike, but at times having a real edge to it. The villain Dorian Tyrell played by Peter Greene is quite a ridiculous character in a lot of ways, with so many poor henchmen around him. But Greene does some how get over this and makes him pretty intimidating. The film also has Cameron Diaz possibly at her sexiest with a great entrance in to the movie, and Milo the dog contending with Carrey with some very funny moments. Things i did not quite like were the attempts at comedy involving the cops. I did like Peter Riegert cynical detective, but his inept partner was just plain annoying. A great film to take you back to your childhood and remind you how funny Jim Carrey can be.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Smokin', Everyone Was
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thesar-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Quick! (Just like the Mask) Let me tell you my story. Honestly, I don't remember if I saw this in theatres. I probably did, because what I do remember in early 1996, is buying the VHS copy of this movie and I watched it a grand total of 5-6 times in under a week. I recall watching The Mask over and over and never getting sick of it. Sure, I had plenty of other movies to watch, but this onewas so much fun. And it still is today. Recently, I bought this movie on BluRay, because I remember loving it, but haven't seen it in over 10 years. I seriously had just as much fun today as I did with those multiple viewings when I first bought the VHS. This movie really holds up from the many years since its release. It really is timeless. Goody-Man Stanley Ipkiss (Jim Carrey) is transformed into the daredevil Mask figure when he finds, and dons an ancient wooden mask, and his inner desires come out tenfold. He goes for the girl, inadvertently pisses off the mob and takes care of business as "The Mask" superhero/cartoon character that mild-mannered Stanley couldn't. The story isn't exactly new, even for 1994, but it's take on the age-old underdog/superhero is fresh, exciting and most of all HILARIOUS. As a matter of fact, when prepping and watching the movie to write this review, I was puzzled on which genre this movie fit in: Action/Adventure + SuperHero? Or Comedy + the rest mentioned? And as I found myself laughing and laughing, even after my 5+ original viewings, I settled on: This MUST be a comedywith a close second of Action/adventure + SuperHero. I think this is a very underrated film. It was a very old concept that was a ton of fun, thanks to Jim Carrey at his peak and newcomer, Cameron Diaz who (almost) stole every scene she was in. She was gorgeous and talented and it was hard to believe that this was her first outing. Honestly, as much as I do like her, but not so much every movie she's been in  though I do enjoy a lot of her films, she was fantastic in this. And I understand that dog was like a prop, I still LOVED little Milo. You have to suspend your disbelief a lot during this movie, so you might as well believe all the dog accomplished. This movie is so straight forward to typical movie viewers and still, it's a lot of fun. And it contains one of my all-time favorite scenes/songs in any movie: The Cuban Pete dance segment. Pricelessas was this movie. See it! It still holds up today and despite all the smoking, especially if you're against that, it's a helluva lot of fun.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I don't normally watch Jim Carry, but when i do, i do it right.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    LoneDoveProductions /MTN
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love the Mask. The movie was just like a big cartoon, and fortunately enough, I am immature enough to love this childish humor. The effects were acceptable because it was meant to look like a cartoon. The jokes were funny if you have a little bit of a child at heart. I may be overrating this film, and i feel as i am, but its just the love of these nostalgia cartoons that makes me love this film. I cant say anything more, its just him Carry's best film to me, and deserves a little more recognition. This movie set out a cartoon series(which was not as good since the joke of putting a cartoon in real life is gone) and eventually a sequel, which i did not enjoy much either. The beauty was Jim Carrys over the top acting in this role. It does not work in many characters but is PERFECT for the chaotic mask. My opinion, I'm overrating it a bit, but go watch it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    somebody stop me
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lagudafuad
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You just have to appreciate the technicality and the visual effects that went into the production of this massive hit. The Mask introduced a character that we all started to love and cherish, a hero that can do absolutely anything his mind thinks of. This slap stick comedy showed how Jim Carrey became a good lead actor; he carried the show right from the start to the final battle, doing everything we see in the Warner bros cartoons. After this massive hit, an animated series was also done, introducing more villains and more takes into the life of Stanley Ipkiss. This movie "The Mask" is based on a series of comic books of the same name; the comic is the product of Dark Horse Comics and The Mask was introduced in the 80's based on a concept by the publisher Mike Richardson and created by writer John Arcudi and artist Doug Mahnke. Like in this movie the comic series follows a magical mask and its owner Stanley Ipkiss. When the mask is worn the wearer can bend reality, do the impossible physically and survive the unbelievable. All this is based on the wearer's depth of imagination which The Mask will then surpass. The plot is about a Mr. nice guy, Stanley Ipkiss (Jim Carrey) whom the world seems to step on. Things took a turn around for Ipkiss when he came across a magical mask, which gave him powers to do the impossible. But The Mask was uncontrollable and Ipkiss stepped on toes which were ready to do anything to kill the man behind the mask. The movie is filled with thrilling visual effects, and a wonderful cast. Jim Carrey was just exceptional. The Mask was also Cameron Diaz's first acting role, which later pushed her up the ladder as she now features in major movies yearly. The Mask was a huge box office hit making over 350 million from its 23 million production cost, it was also a critical acclaim, leaving behind it a trail of catchphrases in its time like "smoking" or "somebody stop me". Its high box office status made the makers approach Jim Carrey for a sequel, which he turned down (as Carrey believes making sequels are not challenging). The ideas for the sequel were then used in the animated series, which spawned two seasons. Later after 11 years, a sequel was made but it was unrelated to the first or the animated series, it was titled Son of The Mask which received high negative reviews and was a box office bomb, as the visual effects and the plot were lame and out of place, putting in consideration that it was made with over 84 million. Our hero The Mask is best portrayed here in this beautiful movie and it is a keeper. www.lagsreviews.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Slapstick comedy that makes the world fixable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rosemary (zelda1964)
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jim Carrey (Ace Ventura: Pet Detective) is a zany comic who adds fun to any role he plays; Cameron Diaz (Head Above Water)is a wonderful talent in many films.In The Mask,we find Ipkiss(Carrey),getting bored with his everyday ho-hum bank job;On a chance,Stanley finds this mask that reaches inside to bring out retribution for the world's hard luck.As it happens,Diaz plays the lounge singer Ipkiss falls in love with.Dorian,a co- worker at the lounge,gets upset when Ipkiss (as the masked hero) averts his threat to steal all the savings.The cutest character is Milo,who plays Stanley's lovable pooch. I call this a marvelous film that really tickles the clich&eacute;d "funny bone".Bravo and cheers!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Perfect Vehicle For Jim Carrey
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Mask is a fantasy comedy that is based on a series of comic books published by Dark Horse Comics. The film stars Jim Carrey as Stanley Ipkiss, a man who finds the Mask of Loki that turns him into The Mask, a trickster uninhibited by anything, including physical reality. The supporting cast includes Peter Greene as mafia officer Dorian Tyrell, Amy Yasbeck as a newspaper reporter, Peter Riegert and Jim Doughan as two police detectives, Richard Jeni as Stanley's friend, Orestes Matacena as nightclub owner and mafia boss Niko, Ben Stein as a psychologist, and Cameron Diaz in her feature film debut as Stanley's love interest Tina Carlyle. Hyperactive mayhem results when a mild-manned banker discovers an ancient mask that transforms him into a zany prankster with superhuman powers in this special-effects-intensive comedy.Stanley Ipkiss is a decent-hearted but socially awkward guy who one night finds a strange mask. Stanley puts on the mask and the banker transforms into The Mask, a green-skinned, zoot-suited fireball. The rubber-faced Mask possesses the courage to do the wild, fun things that Stanley fears, including romancing Tina Carlyle. The larger narrative, involving the efforts of Tina's gangster boyfriend to destroy Stanley and use the mask's powers for evil, prove less interesting than the anarchic comic set pieces. The film delivered enough laughs as it is a perfect vehicle for the talents of Jim Carrey wherein he seems to have found a story and character that work together with manic energy.In addition to his physical talents, the film makes effective use of digital visual effects that bestow the Mask with superhuman speed, insane flexibility, and popping eyes out of a Tex Avery cartoon.The design is bright as a button and the transformation scenes real eye-poppers, but the film's best special effect is putty-faced Carrey with his razzle-dazzle star turn as the affable Stanley and his manic alter ego.This makes it a marvelously energetic and highly enjoyable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of my personal favorites as a child and still love it as a young adult!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin-thelordofthefu-48-460297
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    OK, I never read the comics this was based on, but in terms of judging a comic-book movie adaptation on it's own merits, I used to watch this a few more time as a little child at the mid-90s when it was released and I loved it as much as anyone else in this website even as a young adult. Sure, it may not be the best movie, but I've seen much much worse films and I think that this is one of Jim Carrey's best films in my opinion next to Liar Liar and Ace Ventura: Pet Detective. The story is pretty engaging and has some of my favorite moments throughout the film (the casino scene, the dancing sequence, the balloon animals, and the quotes "Somebody Stop Me!" and more), the script's humorous and made me laugh really hard, the special effects are the epitome of greatness, and the music is good, but the strongest aspect goes to the cast especially Jim Carry which I like the best and I liked his personality (going from a mild-mannered person to a wild and crazed superhero). Cameron Diaz and others did a great job with their roles and the villain is pretty good too. The pacing is brisk and the songs are good too. Overall, love this movie as a kid and still love it as an adult and it's definitely worth-watching!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny,Goofy and Beautifully Animated,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dillon Harris
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Mask is a great movie with a very insane and enjoyable storyline with a really good comedic cast.Its not my favourite Jim Carrey performance,but it is without a doubt one of his most memorable,it really showed just what a wacky and fun actor he really is,and thats why he is one of my favourite comedy actors.The best parts of the movie is without a doubt whenever Carrey has the mask on,its a perfect mix of animation and live action,all these scenes are really exaggerated and very funny,simply impossible not to enjoy.I also really liked Cameron Diaz in this,it was her first film and it really showed the world that she was both a talented,funny and of course very attractive actress.The Mask is without a doubt a must see for all fans of Jim Carrey. When Stanley Ipkiss (Jim Carrey) discovers a mask that transforms him into insane superhero,he uses it for his own fun,and to impress Tina Carlyle (Cameron Diaz),but gets in some big trouble with the law along the way.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unbearable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watching 'The Mask' is a lonely experience, like being the only sober person in a room full of maddening drunks. It revolves entirely around Jim Carrey's rubber-faced antics as the title character, which wouldn't be so bad if the movie wasn't a comedy wasteland, if Carrey once - just once - stumbled across a single entertaining moment during his desperately hyperactive flailing, or if the supporting characters had anything to do besides look on as the visual effects romp around in devastatingly unfunny fashion. I like Carrey a lot when he's actually acting ('The Truman Show', 'Eternal Sunshine of the Spotless Mind') but when he's like this I just squirm with embarrassment. Cameron Diaz is the sole bright, likable oasis of warmth to be found amongst the dead weight that makes up the rest of this unbearable racket.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A timeless classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TichMcLovin
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of my favourite movies as a kid, and a guilty pleasure as an adult. This movie has everything that a kid could be looking for in a movie. I introduced this to my 6 year old son recently and now its all he talks about, he mimics the various characters portrayed by The Mask and has even started getting his friends asking their mums and dads about it. 10/10 from me, for the simple fact that it doesn't exactly what its supposed to, entertain families. Its a fun filled story packed with that old school slap stick comedy mixed with some cartoon parodies, all seamlessly blended by the master of laughs, Jim Carrey.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Comedy Classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Paul Robinson
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The mask is a film for me that i like as much now as much as i did when i was a kid, but considering i'm really just a massive man-child it is to be expected. The film really being the perfect setup for Jim Carrey's comedy styling's. The plot follows Stanley Ipkiss, a typical working scrub. Who finds a Mask which turns him into a egotistical Cartoon character essentially. Who causes the ire of the local gangster. Jim Carrey leads the film fantastically, the zany nature of the story and his acting give the a comic book feel, giving it a timeless quality. The humour at times being very childlike, but at times having a real edge to it. The villain Dorian Tyrell played by Peter Greene is quite a ridiculous character in a lot of ways, with so many poor henchmen around him. But Greene does some how get over this and makes him pretty intimidating. The film also has Cameron Diaz possibly at her sexiest with a great entrance in to the movie, and Milo the dog contending with Carrey with some very funny moments. Things i did not quite like were the attempts at comedy involving the cops. I did like Peter Riegert cynical detective, but his inept partner was just plain annoying. A great film to take you back to your childhood and remind you how funny Jim Carrey can be.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Smokin', Everyone Was
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thesar-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Quick! (Just like the Mask) Let me tell you my story. Honestly, I don't remember if I saw this in theatres. I probably did, because what I do remember in early 1996, is buying the VHS copy of this movie and I watched it a grand total of 5-6 times in under a week. I recall watching The Mask over and over and never getting sick of it. Sure, I had plenty of other movies to watch, but this onewas so much fun. And it still is today. Recently, I bought this movie on BluRay, because I remember loving it, but haven't seen it in over 10 years. I seriously had just as much fun today as I did with those multiple viewings when I first bought the VHS. This movie really holds up from the many years since its release. It really is timeless. Goody-Man Stanley Ipkiss (Jim Carrey) is transformed into the daredevil Mask figure when he finds, and dons an ancient wooden mask, and his inner desires come out tenfold. He goes for the girl, inadvertently pisses off the mob and takes care of business as "The Mask" superhero/cartoon character that mild-mannered Stanley couldn't. The story isn't exactly new, even for 1994, but it's take on the age-old underdog/superhero is fresh, exciting and most of all HILARIOUS. As a matter of fact, when prepping and watching the movie to write this review, I was puzzled on which genre this movie fit in: Action/Adventure + SuperHero? Or Comedy + the rest mentioned? And as I found myself laughing and laughing, even after my 5+ original viewings, I settled on: This MUST be a comedywith a close second of Action/adventure + SuperHero. I think this is a very underrated film. It was a very old concept that was a ton of fun, thanks to Jim Carrey at his peak and newcomer, Cameron Diaz who (almost) stole every scene she was in. She was gorgeous and talented and it was hard to believe that this was her first outing. Honestly, as much as I do like her, but not so much every movie she's been in  though I do enjoy a lot of her films, she was fantastic in this. And I understand that dog was like a prop, I still LOVED little Milo. You have to suspend your disbelief a lot during this movie, so you might as well believe all the dog accomplished. This movie is so straight forward to typical movie viewers and still, it's a lot of fun. And it contains one of my all-time favorite scenes/songs in any movie: The Cuban Pete dance segment. Pricelessas was this movie. See it! It still holds up today and despite all the smoking, especially if you're against that, it's a helluva lot of fun.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I don't normally watch Jim Carry, but when i do, i do it right.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    LoneDoveProductions /MTN
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love the Mask. The movie was just like a big cartoon, and fortunately enough, I am immature enough to love this childish humor. The effects were acceptable because it was meant to look like a cartoon. The jokes were funny if you have a little bit of a child at heart. I may be overrating this film, and i feel as i am, but its just the love of these nostalgia cartoons that makes me love this film. I cant say anything more, its just him Carry's best film to me, and deserves a little more recognition. This movie set out a cartoon series(which was not as good since the joke of putting a cartoon in real life is gone) and eventually a sequel, which i did not enjoy much either. The beauty was Jim Carrys over the top acting in this role. It does not work in many characters but is PERFECT for the chaotic mask. My opinion, I'm overrating it a bit, but go watch it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    somebody stop me
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lagudafuad
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You just have to appreciate the technicality and the visual effects that went into the production of this massive hit. The Mask introduced a character that we all started to love and cherish, a hero that can do absolutely anything his mind thinks of. This slap stick comedy showed how Jim Carrey became a good lead actor; he carried the show right from the start to the final battle, doing everything we see in the Warner bros cartoons. After this massive hit, an animated series was also done, introducing more villains and more takes into the life of Stanley Ipkiss. This movie "The Mask" is based on a series of comic books of the same name; the comic is the product of Dark Horse Comics and The Mask was introduced in the 80's based on a concept by the publisher Mike Richardson and created by writer John Arcudi and artist Doug Mahnke. Like in this movie the comic series follows a magical mask and its owner Stanley Ipkiss. When the mask is worn the wearer can bend reality, do the impossible physically and survive the unbelievable. All this is based on the wearer's depth of imagination which The Mask will then surpass. The plot is about a Mr. nice guy, Stanley Ipkiss (Jim Carrey) whom the world seems to step on. Things took a turn around for Ipkiss when he came across a magical mask, which gave him powers to do the impossible. But The Mask was uncontrollable and Ipkiss stepped on toes which were ready to do anything to kill the man behind the mask. The movie is filled with thrilling visual effects, and a wonderful cast. Jim Carrey was just exceptional. The Mask was also Cameron Diaz's first acting role, which later pushed her up the ladder as she now features in major movies yearly. The Mask was a huge box office hit making over 350 million from its 23 million production cost, it was also a critical acclaim, leaving behind it a trail of catchphrases in its time like "smoking" or "somebody stop me". Its high box office status made the makers approach Jim Carrey for a sequel, which he turned down (as Carrey believes making sequels are not challenging). The ideas for the sequel were then used in the animated series, which spawned two seasons. Later after 11 years, a sequel was made but it was unrelated to the first or the animated series, it was titled Son of The Mask which received high negative reviews and was a box office bomb, as the visual effects and the plot were lame and out of place, putting in consideration that it was made with over 84 million. Our hero The Mask is best portrayed here in this beautiful movie and it is a keeper. www.lagsreviews.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Slapstick comedy that makes the world fixable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rosemary (zelda1964)
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jim Carrey (Ace Ventura: Pet Detective) is a zany comic who adds fun to any role he plays; Cameron Diaz (Head Above Water)is a wonderful talent in many films.In The Mask,we find Ipkiss(Carrey),getting bored with his everyday ho-hum bank job;On a chance,Stanley finds this mask that reaches inside to bring out retribution for the world's hard luck.As it happens,Diaz plays the lounge singer Ipkiss falls in love with.Dorian,a co- worker at the lounge,gets upset when Ipkiss (as the masked hero) averts his threat to steal all the savings.The cutest character is Milo,who plays Stanley's lovable pooch. I call this a marvelous film that really tickles the clich&eacute;d "funny bone".Bravo and cheers!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Perfect Vehicle For Jim Carrey
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Mask is a fantasy comedy that is based on a series of comic books published by Dark Horse Comics. The film stars Jim Carrey as Stanley Ipkiss, a man who finds the Mask of Loki that turns him into The Mask, a trickster uninhibited by anything, including physical reality. The supporting cast includes Peter Greene as mafia officer Dorian Tyrell, Amy Yasbeck as a newspaper reporter, Peter Riegert and Jim Doughan as two police detectives, Richard Jeni as Stanley's friend, Orestes Matacena as nightclub owner and mafia boss Niko, Ben Stein as a psychologist, and Cameron Diaz in her feature film debut as Stanley's love interest Tina Carlyle. Hyperactive mayhem results when a mild-manned banker discovers an ancient mask that transforms him into a zany prankster with superhuman powers in this special-effects-intensive comedy.Stanley Ipkiss is a decent-hearted but socially awkward guy who one night finds a strange mask. Stanley puts on the mask and the banker transforms into The Mask, a green-skinned, zoot-suited fireball. The rubber-faced Mask possesses the courage to do the wild, fun things that Stanley fears, including romancing Tina Carlyle. The larger narrative, involving the efforts of Tina's gangster boyfriend to destroy Stanley and use the mask's powers for evil, prove less interesting than the anarchic comic set pieces. The film delivered enough laughs as it is a perfect vehicle for the talents of Jim Carrey wherein he seems to have found a story and character that work together with manic energy.In addition to his physical talents, the film makes effective use of digital visual effects that bestow the Mask with superhuman speed, insane flexibility, and popping eyes out of a Tex Avery cartoon.The design is bright as a button and the transformation scenes real eye-poppers, but the film's best special effect is putty-faced Carrey with his razzle-dazzle star turn as the affable Stanley and his manic alter ego.This makes it a marvelously energetic and highly enjoyable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of my personal favorites as a child and still love it as a young adult!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin-thelordofthefu-48-460297
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    OK, I never read the comics this was based on, but in terms of judging a comic-book movie adaptation on it's own merits, I used to watch this a few more time as a little child at the mid-90s when it was released and I loved it as much as anyone else in this website even as a young adult. Sure, it may not be the best movie, but I've seen much much worse films and I think that this is one of Jim Carrey's best films in my opinion next to Liar Liar and Ace Ventura: Pet Detective. The story is pretty engaging and has some of my favorite moments throughout the film (the casino scene, the dancing sequence, the balloon animals, and the quotes "Somebody Stop Me!" and more), the script's humorous and made me laugh really hard, the special effects are the epitome of greatness, and the music is good, but the strongest aspect goes to the cast especially Jim Carry which I like the best and I liked his personality (going from a mild-mannered person to a wild and crazed superhero). Cameron Diaz and others did a great job with their roles and the villain is pretty good too. The pacing is brisk and the songs are good too. Overall, love this movie as a kid and still love it as an adult and it's definitely worth-watching!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny,Goofy and Beautifully Animated,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dillon Harris
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Mask is a great movie with a very insane and enjoyable storyline with a really good comedic cast.Its not my favourite Jim Carrey performance,but it is without a doubt one of his most memorable,it really showed just what a wacky and fun actor he really is,and thats why he is one of my favourite comedy actors.The best parts of the movie is without a doubt whenever Carrey has the mask on,its a perfect mix of animation and live action,all these scenes are really exaggerated and very funny,simply impossible not to enjoy.I also really liked Cameron Diaz in this,it was her first film and it really showed the world that she was both a talented,funny and of course very attractive actress.The Mask is without a doubt a must see for all fans of Jim Carrey. When Stanley Ipkiss (Jim Carrey) discovers a mask that transforms him into insane superhero,he uses it for his own fun,and to impress Tina Carlyle (Cameron Diaz),but gets in some big trouble with the law along the way.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unbearable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watching 'The Mask' is a lonely experience, like being the only sober person in a room full of maddening drunks. It revolves entirely around Jim Carrey's rubber-faced antics as the title character, which wouldn't be so bad if the movie wasn't a comedy wasteland, if Carrey once - just once - stumbled across a single entertaining moment during his desperately hyperactive flailing, or if the supporting characters had anything to do besides look on as the visual effects romp around in devastatingly unfunny fashion. I like Carrey a lot when he's actually acting ('The Truman Show', 'Eternal Sunshine of the Spotless Mind') but when he's like this I just squirm with embarrassment. Cameron Diaz is the sole bright, likable oasis of warmth to be found amongst the dead weight that makes up the rest of this unbearable racket.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A timeless classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TichMcLovin
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of my favourite movies as a kid, and a guilty pleasure as an adult. This movie has everything that a kid could be looking for in a movie. I introduced this to my 6 year old son recently and now its all he talks about, he mimics the various characters portrayed by The Mask and has even started getting his friends asking their mums and dads about it. 10/10 from me, for the simple fact that it doesn't exactly what its supposed to, entertain families. Its a fun filled story packed with that old school slap stick comedy mixed with some cartoon parodies, all seamlessly blended by the master of laughs, Jim Carrey.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Comedy Classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Paul Robinson
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The mask is a film for me that i like as much now as much as i did when i was a kid, but considering i'm really just a massive man-child it is to be expected. The film really being the perfect setup for Jim Carrey's comedy styling's. The plot follows Stanley Ipkiss, a typical working scrub. Who finds a Mask which turns him into a egotistical Cartoon character essentially. Who causes the ire of the local gangster. Jim Carrey leads the film fantastically, the zany nature of the story and his acting give the a comic book feel, giving it a timeless quality. The humour at times being very childlike, but at times having a real edge to it. The villain Dorian Tyrell played by Peter Greene is quite a ridiculous character in a lot of ways, with so many poor henchmen around him. But Greene does some how get over this and makes him pretty intimidating. The film also has Cameron Diaz possibly at her sexiest with a great entrance in to the movie, and Milo the dog contending with Carrey with some very funny moments. Things i did not quite like were the attempts at comedy involving the cops. I did like Peter Riegert cynical detective, but his inept partner was just plain annoying. A great film to take you back to your childhood and remind you how funny Jim Carrey can be.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Smokin', Everyone Was
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thesar-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Quick! (Just like the Mask) Let me tell you my story. Honestly, I don't remember if I saw this in theatres. I probably did, because what I do remember in early 1996, is buying the VHS copy of this movie and I watched it a grand total of 5-6 times in under a week. I recall watching The Mask over and over and never getting sick of it. Sure, I had plenty of other movies to watch, but this onewas so much fun. And it still is today. Recently, I bought this movie on BluRay, because I remember loving it, but haven't seen it in over 10 years. I seriously had just as much fun today as I did with those multiple viewings when I first bought the VHS. This movie really holds up from the many years since its release. It really is timeless. Goody-Man Stanley Ipkiss (Jim Carrey) is transformed into the daredevil Mask figure when he finds, and dons an ancient wooden mask, and his inner desires come out tenfold. He goes for the girl, inadvertently pisses off the mob and takes care of business as "The Mask" superhero/cartoon character that mild-mannered Stanley couldn't. The story isn't exactly new, even for 1994, but it's take on the age-old underdog/superhero is fresh, exciting and most of all HILARIOUS. As a matter of fact, when prepping and watching the movie to write this review, I was puzzled on which genre this movie fit in: Action/Adventure + SuperHero? Or Comedy + the rest mentioned? And as I found myself laughing and laughing, even after my 5+ original viewings, I settled on: This MUST be a comedywith a close second of Action/adventure + SuperHero. I think this is a very underrated film. It was a very old concept that was a ton of fun, thanks to Jim Carrey at his peak and newcomer, Cameron Diaz who (almost) stole every scene she was in. She was gorgeous and talented and it was hard to believe that this was her first outing. Honestly, as much as I do like her, but not so much every movie she's been in  though I do enjoy a lot of her films, she was fantastic in this. And I understand that dog was like a prop, I still LOVED little Milo. You have to suspend your disbelief a lot during this movie, so you might as well believe all the dog accomplished. This movie is so straight forward to typical movie viewers and still, it's a lot of fun. And it contains one of my all-time favorite scenes/songs in any movie: The Cuban Pete dance segment. Pricelessas was this movie. See it! It still holds up today and despite all the smoking, especially if you're against that, it's a helluva lot of fun.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I don't normally watch Jim Carry, but when i do, i do it right.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    LoneDoveProductions /MTN
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love the Mask. The movie was just like a big cartoon, and fortunately enough, I am immature enough to love this childish humor. The effects were acceptable because it was meant to look like a cartoon. The jokes were funny if you have a little bit of a child at heart. I may be overrating this film, and i feel as i am, but its just the love of these nostalgia cartoons that makes me love this film. I cant say anything more, its just him Carry's best film to me, and deserves a little more recognition. This movie set out a cartoon series(which was not as good since the joke of putting a cartoon in real life is gone) and eventually a sequel, which i did not enjoy much either. The beauty was Jim Carrys over the top acting in this role. It does not work in many characters but is PERFECT for the chaotic mask. My opinion, I'm overrating it a bit, but go watch it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    somebody stop me
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lagudafuad
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You just have to appreciate the technicality and the visual effects that went into the production of this massive hit. The Mask introduced a character that we all started to love and cherish, a hero that can do absolutely anything his mind thinks of. This slap stick comedy showed how Jim Carrey became a good lead actor; he carried the show right from the start to the final battle, doing everything we see in the Warner bros cartoons. After this massive hit, an animated series was also done, introducing more villains and more takes into the life of Stanley Ipkiss. This movie "The Mask" is based on a series of comic books of the same name; the comic is the product of Dark Horse Comics and The Mask was introduced in the 80's based on a concept by the publisher Mike Richardson and created by writer John Arcudi and artist Doug Mahnke. Like in this movie the comic series follows a magical mask and its owner Stanley Ipkiss. When the mask is worn the wearer can bend reality, do the impossible physically and survive the unbelievable. All this is based on the wearer's depth of imagination which The Mask will then surpass. The plot is about a Mr. nice guy, Stanley Ipkiss (Jim Carrey) whom the world seems to step on. Things took a turn around for Ipkiss when he came across a magical mask, which gave him powers to do the impossible. But The Mask was uncontrollable and Ipkiss stepped on toes which were ready to do anything to kill the man behind the mask. The movie is filled with thrilling visual effects, and a wonderful cast. Jim Carrey was just exceptional. The Mask was also Cameron Diaz's first acting role, which later pushed her up the ladder as she now features in major movies yearly. The Mask was a huge box office hit making over 350 million from its 23 million production cost, it was also a critical acclaim, leaving behind it a trail of catchphrases in its time like "smoking" or "somebody stop me". Its high box office status made the makers approach Jim Carrey for a sequel, which he turned down (as Carrey believes making sequels are not challenging). The ideas for the sequel were then used in the animated series, which spawned two seasons. Later after 11 years, a sequel was made but it was unrelated to the first or the animated series, it was titled Son of The Mask which received high negative reviews and was a box office bomb, as the visual effects and the plot were lame and out of place, putting in consideration that it was made with over 84 million. Our hero The Mask is best portrayed here in this beautiful movie and it is a keeper. www.lagsreviews.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Slapstick comedy that makes the world fixable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rosemary (zelda1964)
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jim Carrey (Ace Ventura: Pet Detective) is a zany comic who adds fun to any role he plays; Cameron Diaz (Head Above Water)is a wonderful talent in many films.In The Mask,we find Ipkiss(Carrey),getting bored with his everyday ho-hum bank job;On a chance,Stanley finds this mask that reaches inside to bring out retribution for the world's hard luck.As it happens,Diaz plays the lounge singer Ipkiss falls in love with.Dorian,a co- worker at the lounge,gets upset when Ipkiss (as the masked hero) averts his threat to steal all the savings.The cutest character is Milo,who plays Stanley's lovable pooch. I call this a marvelous film that really tickles the clich&eacute;d "funny bone".Bravo and cheers!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Perfect Vehicle For Jim Carrey
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Mask is a fantasy comedy that is based on a series of comic books published by Dark Horse Comics. The film stars Jim Carrey as Stanley Ipkiss, a man who finds the Mask of Loki that turns him into The Mask, a trickster uninhibited by anything, including physical reality. The supporting cast includes Peter Greene as mafia officer Dorian Tyrell, Amy Yasbeck as a newspaper reporter, Peter Riegert and Jim Doughan as two police detectives, Richard Jeni as Stanley's friend, Orestes Matacena as nightclub owner and mafia boss Niko, Ben Stein as a psychologist, and Cameron Diaz in her feature film debut as Stanley's love interest Tina Carlyle. Hyperactive mayhem results when a mild-manned banker discovers an ancient mask that transforms him into a zany prankster with superhuman powers in this special-effects-intensive comedy.Stanley Ipkiss is a decent-hearted but socially awkward guy who one night finds a strange mask. Stanley puts on the mask and the banker transforms into The Mask, a green-skinned, zoot-suited fireball. The rubber-faced Mask possesses the courage to do the wild, fun things that Stanley fears, including romancing Tina Carlyle. The larger narrative, involving the efforts of Tina's gangster boyfriend to destroy Stanley and use the mask's powers for evil, prove less interesting than the anarchic comic set pieces. The film delivered enough laughs as it is a perfect vehicle for the talents of Jim Carrey wherein he seems to have found a story and character that work together with manic energy.In addition to his physical talents, the film makes effective use of digital visual effects that bestow the Mask with superhuman speed, insane flexibility, and popping eyes out of a Tex Avery cartoon.The design is bright as a button and the transformation scenes real eye-poppers, but the film's best special effect is putty-faced Carrey with his razzle-dazzle star turn as the affable Stanley and his manic alter ego.This makes it a marvelously energetic and highly enjoyable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of my personal favorites as a child and still love it as a young adult!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin-thelordofthefu-48-460297
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    OK, I never read the comics this was based on, but in terms of judging a comic-book movie adaptation on it's own merits, I used to watch this a few more time as a little child at the mid-90s when it was released and I loved it as much as anyone else in this website even as a young adult. Sure, it may not be the best movie, but I've seen much much worse films and I think that this is one of Jim Carrey's best films in my opinion next to Liar Liar and Ace Ventura: Pet Detective. The story is pretty engaging and has some of my favorite moments throughout the film (the casino scene, the dancing sequence, the balloon animals, and the quotes "Somebody Stop Me!" and more), the script's humorous and made me laugh really hard, the special effects are the epitome of greatness, and the music is good, but the strongest aspect goes to the cast especially Jim Carry which I like the best and I liked his personality (going from a mild-mannered person to a wild and crazed superhero). Cameron Diaz and others did a great job with their roles and the villain is pretty good too. The pacing is brisk and the songs are good too. Overall, love this movie as a kid and still love it as an adult and it's definitely worth-watching!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny,Goofy and Beautifully Animated,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dillon Harris
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Mask is a great movie with a very insane and enjoyable storyline with a really good comedic cast.Its not my favourite Jim Carrey performance,but it is without a doubt one of his most memorable,it really showed just what a wacky and fun actor he really is,and thats why he is one of my favourite comedy actors.The best parts of the movie is without a doubt whenever Carrey has the mask on,its a perfect mix of animation and live action,all these scenes are really exaggerated and very funny,simply impossible not to enjoy.I also really liked Cameron Diaz in this,it was her first film and it really showed the world that she was both a talented,funny and of course very attractive actress.The Mask is without a doubt a must see for all fans of Jim Carrey. When Stanley Ipkiss (Jim Carrey) discovers a mask that transforms him into insane superhero,he uses it for his own fun,and to impress Tina Carlyle (Cameron Diaz),but gets in some big trouble with the law along the way.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unbearable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watching 'The Mask' is a lonely experience, like being the only sober person in a room full of maddening drunks. It revolves entirely around Jim Carrey's rubber-faced antics as the title character, which wouldn't be so bad if the movie wasn't a comedy wasteland, if Carrey once - just once - stumbled across a single entertaining moment during his desperately hyperactive flailing, or if the supporting characters had anything to do besides look on as the visual effects romp around in devastatingly unfunny fashion. I like Carrey a lot when he's actually acting ('The Truman Show', 'Eternal Sunshine of the Spotless Mind') but when he's like this I just squirm with embarrassment. Cameron Diaz is the sole bright, likable oasis of warmth to be found amongst the dead weight that makes up the rest of this unbearable racket.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A timeless classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TichMcLovin
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of my favourite movies as a kid, and a guilty pleasure as an adult. This movie has everything that a kid could be looking for in a movie. I introduced this to my 6 year old son recently and now its all he talks about, he mimics the various characters portrayed by The Mask and has even started getting his friends asking their mums and dads about it. 10/10 from me, for the simple fact that it doesn't exactly what its supposed to, entertain families. Its a fun filled story packed with that old school slap stick comedy mixed with some cartoon parodies, all seamlessly blended by the master of laughs, Jim Carrey.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Comedy Classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Paul Robinson
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The mask is a film for me that i like as much now as much as i did when i was a kid, but considering i'm really just a massive man-child it is to be expected. The film really being the perfect setup for Jim Carrey's comedy styling's. The plot follows Stanley Ipkiss, a typical working scrub. Who finds a Mask which turns him into a egotistical Cartoon character essentially. Who causes the ire of the local gangster. Jim Carrey leads the film fantastically, the zany nature of the story and his acting give the a comic book feel, giving it a timeless quality. The humour at times being very childlike, but at times having a real edge to it. The villain Dorian Tyrell played by Peter Greene is quite a ridiculous character in a lot of ways, with so many poor henchmen around him. But Greene does some how get over this and makes him pretty intimidating. The film also has Cameron Diaz possibly at her sexiest with a great entrance in to the movie, and Milo the dog contending with Carrey with some very funny moments. Things i did not quite like were the attempts at comedy involving the cops. I did like Peter Riegert cynical detective, but his inept partner was just plain annoying. A great film to take you back to your childhood and remind you how funny Jim Carrey can be.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Smokin', Everyone Was
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thesar-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Quick! (Just like the Mask) Let me tell you my story. Honestly, I don't remember if I saw this in theatres. I probably did, because what I do remember in early 1996, is buying the VHS copy of this movie and I watched it a grand total of 5-6 times in under a week. I recall watching The Mask over and over and never getting sick of it. Sure, I had plenty of other movies to watch, but this onewas so much fun. And it still is today. Recently, I bought this movie on BluRay, because I remember loving it, but haven't seen it in over 10 years. I seriously had just as much fun today as I did with those multiple viewings when I first bought the VHS. This movie really holds up from the many years since its release. It really is timeless. Goody-Man Stanley Ipkiss (Jim Carrey) is transformed into the daredevil Mask figure when he finds, and dons an ancient wooden mask, and his inner desires come out tenfold. He goes for the girl, inadvertently pisses off the mob and takes care of business as "The Mask" superhero/cartoon character that mild-mannered Stanley couldn't. The story isn't exactly new, even for 1994, but it's take on the age-old underdog/superhero is fresh, exciting and most of all HILARIOUS. As a matter of fact, when prepping and watching the movie to write this review, I was puzzled on which genre this movie fit in: Action/Adventure + SuperHero? Or Comedy + the rest mentioned? And as I found myself laughing and laughing, even after my 5+ original viewings, I settled on: This MUST be a comedywith a close second of Action/adventure + SuperHero. I think this is a very underrated film. It was a very old concept that was a ton of fun, thanks to Jim Carrey at his peak and newcomer, Cameron Diaz who (almost) stole every scene she was in. She was gorgeous and talented and it was hard to believe that this was her first outing. Honestly, as much as I do like her, but not so much every movie she's been in  though I do enjoy a lot of her films, she was fantastic in this. And I understand that dog was like a prop, I still LOVED little Milo. You have to suspend your disbelief a lot during this movie, so you might as well believe all the dog accomplished. This movie is so straight forward to typical movie viewers and still, it's a lot of fun. And it contains one of my all-time favorite scenes/songs in any movie: The Cuban Pete dance segment. Pricelessas was this movie. See it! It still holds up today and despite all the smoking, especially if you're against that, it's a helluva lot of fun.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I don't normally watch Jim Carry, but when i do, i do it right.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    LoneDoveProductions /MTN
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love the Mask. The movie was just like a big cartoon, and fortunately enough, I am immature enough to love this childish humor. The effects were acceptable because it was meant to look like a cartoon. The jokes were funny if you have a little bit of a child at heart. I may be overrating this film, and i feel as i am, but its just the love of these nostalgia cartoons that makes me love this film. I cant say anything more, its just him Carry's best film to me, and deserves a little more recognition. This movie set out a cartoon series(which was not as good since the joke of putting a cartoon in real life is gone) and eventually a sequel, which i did not enjoy much either. The beauty was Jim Carrys over the top acting in this role. It does not work in many characters but is PERFECT for the chaotic mask. My opinion, I'm overrating it a bit, but go watch it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    somebody stop me
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lagudafuad
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You just have to appreciate the technicality and the visual effects that went into the production of this massive hit. The Mask introduced a character that we all started to love and cherish, a hero that can do absolutely anything his mind thinks of. This slap stick comedy showed how Jim Carrey became a good lead actor; he carried the show right from the start to the final battle, doing everything we see in the Warner bros cartoons. After this massive hit, an animated series was also done, introducing more villains and more takes into the life of Stanley Ipkiss. This movie "The Mask" is based on a series of comic books of the same name; the comic is the product of Dark Horse Comics and The Mask was introduced in the 80's based on a concept by the publisher Mike Richardson and created by writer John Arcudi and artist Doug Mahnke. Like in this movie the comic series follows a magical mask and its owner Stanley Ipkiss. When the mask is worn the wearer can bend reality, do the impossible physically and survive the unbelievable. All this is based on the wearer's depth of imagination which The Mask will then surpass. The plot is about a Mr. nice guy, Stanley Ipkiss (Jim Carrey) whom the world seems to step on. Things took a turn around for Ipkiss when he came across a magical mask, which gave him powers to do the impossible. But The Mask was uncontrollable and Ipkiss stepped on toes which were ready to do anything to kill the man behind the mask. The movie is filled with thrilling visual effects, and a wonderful cast. Jim Carrey was just exceptional. The Mask was also Cameron Diaz's first acting role, which later pushed her up the ladder as she now features in major movies yearly. The Mask was a huge box office hit making over 350 million from its 23 million production cost, it was also a critical acclaim, leaving behind it a trail of catchphrases in its time like "smoking" or "somebody stop me". Its high box office status made the makers approach Jim Carrey for a sequel, which he turned down (as Carrey believes making sequels are not challenging). The ideas for the sequel were then used in the animated series, which spawned two seasons. Later after 11 years, a sequel was made but it was unrelated to the first or the animated series, it was titled Son of The Mask which received high negative reviews and was a box office bomb, as the visual effects and the plot were lame and out of place, putting in consideration that it was made with over 84 million. Our hero The Mask is best portrayed here in this beautiful movie and it is a keeper. www.lagsreviews.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Slapstick comedy that makes the world fixable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rosemary (zelda1964)
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jim Carrey (Ace Ventura: Pet Detective) is a zany comic who adds fun to any role he plays; Cameron Diaz (Head Above Water)is a wonderful talent in many films.In The Mask,we find Ipkiss(Carrey),getting bored with his everyday ho-hum bank job;On a chance,Stanley finds this mask that reaches inside to bring out retribution for the world's hard luck.As it happens,Diaz plays the lounge singer Ipkiss falls in love with.Dorian,a co- worker at the lounge,gets upset when Ipkiss (as the masked hero) averts his threat to steal all the savings.The cutest character is Milo,who plays Stanley's lovable pooch. I call this a marvelous film that really tickles the clich&eacute;d "funny bone".Bravo and cheers!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Perfect Vehicle For Jim Carrey
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Mask is a fantasy comedy that is based on a series of comic books published by Dark Horse Comics. The film stars Jim Carrey as Stanley Ipkiss, a man who finds the Mask of Loki that turns him into The Mask, a trickster uninhibited by anything, including physical reality. The supporting cast includes Peter Greene as mafia officer Dorian Tyrell, Amy Yasbeck as a newspaper reporter, Peter Riegert and Jim Doughan as two police detectives, Richard Jeni as Stanley's friend, Orestes Matacena as nightclub owner and mafia boss Niko, Ben Stein as a psychologist, and Cameron Diaz in her feature film debut as Stanley's love interest Tina Carlyle. Hyperactive mayhem results when a mild-manned banker discovers an ancient mask that transforms him into a zany prankster with superhuman powers in this special-effects-intensive comedy.Stanley Ipkiss is a decent-hearted but socially awkward guy who one night finds a strange mask. Stanley puts on the mask and the banker transforms into The Mask, a green-skinned, zoot-suited fireball. The rubber-faced Mask possesses the courage to do the wild, fun things that Stanley fears, including romancing Tina Carlyle. The larger narrative, involving the efforts of Tina's gangster boyfriend to destroy Stanley and use the mask's powers for evil, prove less interesting than the anarchic comic set pieces. The film delivered enough laughs as it is a perfect vehicle for the talents of Jim Carrey wherein he seems to have found a story and character that work together with manic energy.In addition to his physical talents, the film makes effective use of digital visual effects that bestow the Mask with superhuman speed, insane flexibility, and popping eyes out of a Tex Avery cartoon.The design is bright as a button and the transformation scenes real eye-poppers, but the film's best special effect is putty-faced Carrey with his razzle-dazzle star turn as the affable Stanley and his manic alter ego.This makes it a marvelously energetic and highly enjoyable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of my personal favorites as a child and still love it as a young adult!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin-thelordofthefu-48-460297
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    OK, I never read the comics this was based on, but in terms of judging a comic-book movie adaptation on it's own merits, I used to watch this a few more time as a little child at the mid-90s when it was released and I loved it as much as anyone else in this website even as a young adult. Sure, it may not be the best movie, but I've seen much much worse films and I think that this is one of Jim Carrey's best films in my opinion next to Liar Liar and Ace Ventura: Pet Detective. The story is pretty engaging and has some of my favorite moments throughout the film (the casino scene, the dancing sequence, the balloon animals, and the quotes "Somebody Stop Me!" and more), the script's humorous and made me laugh really hard, the special effects are the epitome of greatness, and the music is good, but the strongest aspect goes to the cast especially Jim Carry which I like the best and I liked his personality (going from a mild-mannered person to a wild and crazed superhero). Cameron Diaz and others did a great job with their roles and the villain is pretty good too. The pacing is brisk and the songs are good too. Overall, love this movie as a kid and still love it as an adult and it's definitely worth-watching!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny,Goofy and Beautifully Animated,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dillon Harris
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Mask is a great movie with a very insane and enjoyable storyline with a really good comedic cast.Its not my favourite Jim Carrey performance,but it is without a doubt one of his most memorable,it really showed just what a wacky and fun actor he really is,and thats why he is one of my favourite comedy actors.The best parts of the movie is without a doubt whenever Carrey has the mask on,its a perfect mix of animation and live action,all these scenes are really exaggerated and very funny,simply impossible not to enjoy.I also really liked Cameron Diaz in this,it was her first film and it really showed the world that she was both a talented,funny and of course very attractive actress.The Mask is without a doubt a must see for all fans of Jim Carrey. When Stanley Ipkiss (Jim Carrey) discovers a mask that transforms him into insane superhero,he uses it for his own fun,and to impress Tina Carlyle (Cameron Diaz),but gets in some big trouble with the law along the way.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unbearable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watching 'The Mask' is a lonely experience, like being the only sober person in a room full of maddening drunks. It revolves entirely around Jim Carrey's rubber-faced antics as the title character, which wouldn't be so bad if the movie wasn't a comedy wasteland, if Carrey once - just once - stumbled across a single entertaining moment during his desperately hyperactive flailing, or if the supporting characters had anything to do besides look on as the visual effects romp around in devastatingly unfunny fashion. I like Carrey a lot when he's actually acting ('The Truman Show', 'Eternal Sunshine of the Spotless Mind') but when he's like this I just squirm with embarrassment. Cameron Diaz is the sole bright, likable oasis of warmth to be found amongst the dead weight that makes up the rest of this unbearable racket.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A timeless classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TichMcLovin
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of my favourite movies as a kid, and a guilty pleasure as an adult. This movie has everything that a kid could be looking for in a movie. I introduced this to my 6 year old son recently and now its all he talks about, he mimics the various characters portrayed by The Mask and has even started getting his friends asking their mums and dads about it. 10/10 from me, for the simple fact that it doesn't exactly what its supposed to, entertain families. Its a fun filled story packed with that old school slap stick comedy mixed with some cartoon parodies, all seamlessly blended by the master of laughs, Jim Carrey.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Comedy Classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Paul Robinson
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The mask is a film for me that i like as much now as much as i did when i was a kid, but considering i'm really just a massive man-child it is to be expected. The film really being the perfect setup for Jim Carrey's comedy styling's. The plot follows Stanley Ipkiss, a typical working scrub. Who finds a Mask which turns him into a egotistical Cartoon character essentially. Who causes the ire of the local gangster. Jim Carrey leads the film fantastically, the zany nature of the story and his acting give the a comic book feel, giving it a timeless quality. The humour at times being very childlike, but at times having a real edge to it. The villain Dorian Tyrell played by Peter Greene is quite a ridiculous character in a lot of ways, with so many poor henchmen around him. But Greene does some how get over this and makes him pretty intimidating. The film also has Cameron Diaz possibly at her sexiest with a great entrance in to the movie, and Milo the dog contending with Carrey with some very funny moments. Things i did not quite like were the attempts at comedy involving the cops. I did like Peter Riegert cynical detective, but his inept partner was just plain annoying. A great film to take you back to your childhood and remind you how funny Jim Carrey can be.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Smokin', Everyone Was
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thesar-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Quick! (Just like the Mask) Let me tell you my story. Honestly, I don't remember if I saw this in theatres. I probably did, because what I do remember in early 1996, is buying the VHS copy of this movie and I watched it a grand total of 5-6 times in under a week. I recall watching The Mask over and over and never getting sick of it. Sure, I had plenty of other movies to watch, but this onewas so much fun. And it still is today. Recently, I bought this movie on BluRay, because I remember loving it, but haven't seen it in over 10 years. I seriously had just as much fun today as I did with those multiple viewings when I first bought the VHS. This movie really holds up from the many years since its release. It really is timeless. Goody-Man Stanley Ipkiss (Jim Carrey) is transformed into the daredevil Mask figure when he finds, and dons an ancient wooden mask, and his inner desires come out tenfold. He goes for the girl, inadvertently pisses off the mob and takes care of business as "The Mask" superhero/cartoon character that mild-mannered Stanley couldn't. The story isn't exactly new, even for 1994, but it's take on the age-old underdog/superhero is fresh, exciting and most of all HILARIOUS. As a matter of fact, when prepping and watching the movie to write this review, I was puzzled on which genre this movie fit in: Action/Adventure + SuperHero? Or Comedy + the rest mentioned? And as I found myself laughing and laughing, even after my 5+ original viewings, I settled on: This MUST be a comedywith a close second of Action/adventure + SuperHero. I think this is a very underrated film. It was a very old concept that was a ton of fun, thanks to Jim Carrey at his peak and newcomer, Cameron Diaz who (almost) stole every scene she was in. She was gorgeous and talented and it was hard to believe that this was her first outing. Honestly, as much as I do like her, but not so much every movie she's been in  though I do enjoy a lot of her films, she was fantastic in this. And I understand that dog was like a prop, I still LOVED little Milo. You have to suspend your disbelief a lot during this movie, so you might as well believe all the dog accomplished. This movie is so straight forward to typical movie viewers and still, it's a lot of fun. And it contains one of my all-time favorite scenes/songs in any movie: The Cuban Pete dance segment. Pricelessas was this movie. See it! It still holds up today and despite all the smoking, especially if you're against that, it's a helluva lot of fun.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I don't normally watch Jim Carry, but when i do, i do it right.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    LoneDoveProductions /MTN
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love the Mask. The movie was just like a big cartoon, and fortunately enough, I am immature enough to love this childish humor. The effects were acceptable because it was meant to look like a cartoon. The jokes were funny if you have a little bit of a child at heart. I may be overrating this film, and i feel as i am, but its just the love of these nostalgia cartoons that makes me love this film. I cant say anything more, its just him Carry's best film to me, and deserves a little more recognition. This movie set out a cartoon series(which was not as good since the joke of putting a cartoon in real life is gone) and eventually a sequel, which i did not enjoy much either. The beauty was Jim Carrys over the top acting in this role. It does not work in many characters but is PERFECT for the chaotic mask. My opinion, I'm overrating it a bit, but go watch it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    somebody stop me
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lagudafuad
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You just have to appreciate the technicality and the visual effects that went into the production of this massive hit. The Mask introduced a character that we all started to love and cherish, a hero that can do absolutely anything his mind thinks of. This slap stick comedy showed how Jim Carrey became a good lead actor; he carried the show right from the start to the final battle, doing everything we see in the Warner bros cartoons. After this massive hit, an animated series was also done, introducing more villains and more takes into the life of Stanley Ipkiss. This movie "The Mask" is based on a series of comic books of the same name; the comic is the product of Dark Horse Comics and The Mask was introduced in the 80's based on a concept by the publisher Mike Richardson and created by writer John Arcudi and artist Doug Mahnke. Like in this movie the comic series follows a magical mask and its owner Stanley Ipkiss. When the mask is worn the wearer can bend reality, do the impossible physically and survive the unbelievable. All this is based on the wearer's depth of imagination which The Mask will then surpass. The plot is about a Mr. nice guy, Stanley Ipkiss (Jim Carrey) whom the world seems to step on. Things took a turn around for Ipkiss when he came across a magical mask, which gave him powers to do the impossible. But The Mask was uncontrollable and Ipkiss stepped on toes which were ready to do anything to kill the man behind the mask. The movie is filled with thrilling visual effects, and a wonderful cast. Jim Carrey was just exceptional. The Mask was also Cameron Diaz's first acting role, which later pushed her up the ladder as she now features in major movies yearly. The Mask was a huge box office hit making over 350 million from its 23 million production cost, it was also a critical acclaim, leaving behind it a trail of catchphrases in its time like "smoking" or "somebody stop me". Its high box office status made the makers approach Jim Carrey for a sequel, which he turned down (as Carrey believes making sequels are not challenging). The ideas for the sequel were then used in the animated series, which spawned two seasons. Later after 11 years, a sequel was made but it was unrelated to the first or the animated series, it was titled Son of The Mask which received high negative reviews and was a box office bomb, as the visual effects and the plot were lame and out of place, putting in consideration that it was made with over 84 million. Our hero The Mask is best portrayed here in this beautiful movie and it is a keeper. www.lagsreviews.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Slapstick comedy that makes the world fixable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rosemary (zelda1964)
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jim Carrey (Ace Ventura: Pet Detective) is a zany comic who adds fun to any role he plays; Cameron Diaz (Head Above Water)is a wonderful talent in many films.In The Mask,we find Ipkiss(Carrey),getting bored with his everyday ho-hum bank job;On a chance,Stanley finds this mask that reaches inside to bring out retribution for the world's hard luck.As it happens,Diaz plays the lounge singer Ipkiss falls in love with.Dorian,a co- worker at the lounge,gets upset when Ipkiss (as the masked hero) averts his threat to steal all the savings.The cutest character is Milo,who plays Stanley's lovable pooch. I call this a marvelous film that really tickles the clich&eacute;d "funny bone".Bravo and cheers!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Perfect Vehicle For Jim Carrey
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Mask is a fantasy comedy that is based on a series of comic books published by Dark Horse Comics. The film stars Jim Carrey as Stanley Ipkiss, a man who finds the Mask of Loki that turns him into The Mask, a trickster uninhibited by anything, including physical reality. The supporting cast includes Peter Greene as mafia officer Dorian Tyrell, Amy Yasbeck as a newspaper reporter, Peter Riegert and Jim Doughan as two police detectives, Richard Jeni as Stanley's friend, Orestes Matacena as nightclub owner and mafia boss Niko, Ben Stein as a psychologist, and Cameron Diaz in her feature film debut as Stanley's love interest Tina Carlyle. Hyperactive mayhem results when a mild-manned banker discovers an ancient mask that transforms him into a zany prankster with superhuman powers in this special-effects-intensive comedy.Stanley Ipkiss is a decent-hearted but socially awkward guy who one night finds a strange mask. Stanley puts on the mask and the banker transforms into The Mask, a green-skinned, zoot-suited fireball. The rubber-faced Mask possesses the courage to do the wild, fun things that Stanley fears, including romancing Tina Carlyle. The larger narrative, involving the efforts of Tina's gangster boyfriend to destroy Stanley and use the mask's powers for evil, prove less interesting than the anarchic comic set pieces. The film delivered enough laughs as it is a perfect vehicle for the talents of Jim Carrey wherein he seems to have found a story and character that work together with manic energy.In addition to his physical talents, the film makes effective use of digital visual effects that bestow the Mask with superhuman speed, insane flexibility, and popping eyes out of a Tex Avery cartoon.The design is bright as a button and the transformation scenes real eye-poppers, but the film's best special effect is putty-faced Carrey with his razzle-dazzle star turn as the affable Stanley and his manic alter ego.This makes it a marvelously energetic and highly enjoyable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of my personal favorites as a child and still love it as a young adult!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin-thelordofthefu-48-460297
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    OK, I never read the comics this was based on, but in terms of judging a comic-book movie adaptation on it's own merits, I used to watch this a few more time as a little child at the mid-90s when it was released and I loved it as much as anyone else in this website even as a young adult. Sure, it may not be the best movie, but I've seen much much worse films and I think that this is one of Jim Carrey's best films in my opinion next to Liar Liar and Ace Ventura: Pet Detective. The story is pretty engaging and has some of my favorite moments throughout the film (the casino scene, the dancing sequence, the balloon animals, and the quotes "Somebody Stop Me!" and more), the script's humorous and made me laugh really hard, the special effects are the epitome of greatness, and the music is good, but the strongest aspect goes to the cast especially Jim Carry which I like the best and I liked his personality (going from a mild-mannered person to a wild and crazed superhero). Cameron Diaz and others did a great job with their roles and the villain is pretty good too. The pacing is brisk and the songs are good too. Overall, love this movie as a kid and still love it as an adult and it's definitely worth-watching!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny,Goofy and Beautifully Animated,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dillon Harris
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Mask is a great movie with a very insane and enjoyable storyline with a really good comedic cast.Its not my favourite Jim Carrey performance,but it is without a doubt one of his most memorable,it really showed just what a wacky and fun actor he really is,and thats why he is one of my favourite comedy actors.The best parts of the movie is without a doubt whenever Carrey has the mask on,its a perfect mix of animation and live action,all these scenes are really exaggerated and very funny,simply impossible not to enjoy.I also really liked Cameron Diaz in this,it was her first film and it really showed the world that she was both a talented,funny and of course very attractive actress.The Mask is without a doubt a must see for all fans of Jim Carrey. When Stanley Ipkiss (Jim Carrey) discovers a mask that transforms him into insane superhero,he uses it for his own fun,and to impress Tina Carlyle (Cameron Diaz),but gets in some big trouble with the law along the way.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unbearable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watching 'The Mask' is a lonely experience, like being the only sober person in a room full of maddening drunks. It revolves entirely around Jim Carrey's rubber-faced antics as the title character, which wouldn't be so bad if the movie wasn't a comedy wasteland, if Carrey once - just once - stumbled across a single entertaining moment during his desperately hyperactive flailing, or if the supporting characters had anything to do besides look on as the visual effects romp around in devastatingly unfunny fashion. I like Carrey a lot when he's actually acting ('The Truman Show', 'Eternal Sunshine of the Spotless Mind') but when he's like this I just squirm with embarrassment. Cameron Diaz is the sole bright, likable oasis of warmth to be found amongst the dead weight that makes up the rest of this unbearable racket.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A timeless classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TichMcLovin
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of my favourite movies as a kid, and a guilty pleasure as an adult. This movie has everything that a kid could be looking for in a movie. I introduced this to my 6 year old son recently and now its all he talks about, he mimics the various characters portrayed by The Mask and has even started getting his friends asking their mums and dads about it. 10/10 from me, for the simple fact that it doesn't exactly what its supposed to, entertain families. Its a fun filled story packed with that old school slap stick comedy mixed with some cartoon parodies, all seamlessly blended by the master of laughs, Jim Carrey.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Comedy Classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Paul Robinson
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The mask is a film for me that i like as much now as much as i did when i was a kid, but considering i'm really just a massive man-child it is to be expected. The film really being the perfect setup for Jim Carrey's comedy styling's. The plot follows Stanley Ipkiss, a typical working scrub. Who finds a Mask which turns him into a egotistical Cartoon character essentially. Who causes the ire of the local gangster. Jim Carrey leads the film fantastically, the zany nature of the story and his acting give the a comic book feel, giving it a timeless quality. The humour at times being very childlike, but at times having a real edge to it. The villain Dorian Tyrell played by Peter Greene is quite a ridiculous character in a lot of ways, with so many poor henchmen around him. But Greene does some how get over this and makes him pretty intimidating. The film also has Cameron Diaz possibly at her sexiest with a great entrance in to the movie, and Milo the dog contending with Carrey with some very funny moments. Things i did not quite like were the attempts at comedy involving the cops. I did like Peter Riegert cynical detective, but his inept partner was just plain annoying. A great film to take you back to your childhood and remind you how funny Jim Carrey can be.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Smokin', Everyone Was
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thesar-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Quick! (Just like the Mask) Let me tell you my story. Honestly, I don't remember if I saw this in theatres. I probably did, because what I do remember in early 1996, is buying the VHS copy of this movie and I watched it a grand total of 5-6 times in under a week. I recall watching The Mask over and over and never getting sick of it. Sure, I had plenty of other movies to watch, but this onewas so much fun. And it still is today. Recently, I bought this movie on BluRay, because I remember loving it, but haven't seen it in over 10 years. I seriously had just as much fun today as I did with those multiple viewings when I first bought the VHS. This movie really holds up from the many years since its release. It really is timeless. Goody-Man Stanley Ipkiss (Jim Carrey) is transformed into the daredevil Mask figure when he finds, and dons an ancient wooden mask, and his inner desires come out tenfold. He goes for the girl, inadvertently pisses off the mob and takes care of business as "The Mask" superhero/cartoon character that mild-mannered Stanley couldn't. The story isn't exactly new, even for 1994, but it's take on the age-old underdog/superhero is fresh, exciting and most of all HILARIOUS. As a matter of fact, when prepping and watching the movie to write this review, I was puzzled on which genre this movie fit in: Action/Adventure + SuperHero? Or Comedy + the rest mentioned? And as I found myself laughing and laughing, even after my 5+ original viewings, I settled on: This MUST be a comedywith a close second of Action/adventure + SuperHero. I think this is a very underrated film. It was a very old concept that was a ton of fun, thanks to Jim Carrey at his peak and newcomer, Cameron Diaz who (almost) stole every scene she was in. She was gorgeous and talented and it was hard to believe that this was her first outing. Honestly, as much as I do like her, but not so much every movie she's been in  though I do enjoy a lot of her films, she was fantastic in this. And I understand that dog was like a prop, I still LOVED little Milo. You have to suspend your disbelief a lot during this movie, so you might as well believe all the dog accomplished. This movie is so straight forward to typical movie viewers and still, it's a lot of fun. And it contains one of my all-time favorite scenes/songs in any movie: The Cuban Pete dance segment. Pricelessas was this movie. See it! It still holds up today and despite all the smoking, especially if you're against that, it's a helluva lot of fun.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I don't normally watch Jim Carry, but when i do, i do it right.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    LoneDoveProductions /MTN
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love the Mask. The movie was just like a big cartoon, and fortunately enough, I am immature enough to love this childish humor. The effects were acceptable because it was meant to look like a cartoon. The jokes were funny if you have a little bit of a child at heart. I may be overrating this film, and i feel as i am, but its just the love of these nostalgia cartoons that makes me love this film. I cant say anything more, its just him Carry's best film to me, and deserves a little more recognition. This movie set out a cartoon series(which was not as good since the joke of putting a cartoon in real life is gone) and eventually a sequel, which i did not enjoy much either. The beauty was Jim Carrys over the top acting in this role. It does not work in many characters but is PERFECT for the chaotic mask. My opinion, I'm overrating it a bit, but go watch it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    somebody stop me
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lagudafuad
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You just have to appreciate the technicality and the visual effects that went into the production of this massive hit. The Mask introduced a character that we all started to love and cherish, a hero that can do absolutely anything his mind thinks of. This slap stick comedy showed how Jim Carrey became a good lead actor; he carried the show right from the start to the final battle, doing everything we see in the Warner bros cartoons. After this massive hit, an animated series was also done, introducing more villains and more takes into the life of Stanley Ipkiss. This movie "The Mask" is based on a series of comic books of the same name; the comic is the product of Dark Horse Comics and The Mask was introduced in the 80's based on a concept by the publisher Mike Richardson and created by writer John Arcudi and artist Doug Mahnke. Like in this movie the comic series follows a magical mask and its owner Stanley Ipkiss. When the mask is worn the wearer can bend reality, do the impossible physically and survive the unbelievable. All this is based on the wearer's depth of imagination which The Mask will then surpass. The plot is about a Mr. nice guy, Stanley Ipkiss (Jim Carrey) whom the world seems to step on. Things took a turn around for Ipkiss when he came across a magical mask, which gave him powers to do the impossible. But The Mask was uncontrollable and Ipkiss stepped on toes which were ready to do anything to kill the man behind the mask. The movie is filled with thrilling visual effects, and a wonderful cast. Jim Carrey was just exceptional. The Mask was also Cameron Diaz's first acting role, which later pushed her up the ladder as she now features in major movies yearly. The Mask was a huge box office hit making over 350 million from its 23 million production cost, it was also a critical acclaim, leaving behind it a trail of catchphrases in its time like "smoking" or "somebody stop me". Its high box office status made the makers approach Jim Carrey for a sequel, which he turned down (as Carrey believes making sequels are not challenging). The ideas for the sequel were then used in the animated series, which spawned two seasons. Later after 11 years, a sequel was made but it was unrelated to the first or the animated series, it was titled Son of The Mask which received high negative reviews and was a box office bomb, as the visual effects and the plot were lame and out of place, putting in consideration that it was made with over 84 million. Our hero The Mask is best portrayed here in this beautiful movie and it is a keeper. www.lagsreviews.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Slapstick comedy that makes the world fixable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rosemary (zelda1964)
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jim Carrey (Ace Ventura: Pet Detective) is a zany comic who adds fun to any role he plays; Cameron Diaz (Head Above Water)is a wonderful talent in many films.In The Mask,we find Ipkiss(Carrey),getting bored with his everyday ho-hum bank job;On a chance,Stanley finds this mask that reaches inside to bring out retribution for the world's hard luck.As it happens,Diaz plays the lounge singer Ipkiss falls in love with.Dorian,a co- worker at the lounge,gets upset when Ipkiss (as the masked hero) averts his threat to steal all the savings.The cutest character is Milo,who plays Stanley's lovable pooch. I call this a marvelous film that really tickles the clich&eacute;d "funny bone".Bravo and cheers!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Perfect Vehicle For Jim Carrey
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Mask is a fantasy comedy that is based on a series of comic books published by Dark Horse Comics. The film stars Jim Carrey as Stanley Ipkiss, a man who finds the Mask of Loki that turns him into The Mask, a trickster uninhibited by anything, including physical reality. The supporting cast includes Peter Greene as mafia officer Dorian Tyrell, Amy Yasbeck as a newspaper reporter, Peter Riegert and Jim Doughan as two police detectives, Richard Jeni as Stanley's friend, Orestes Matacena as nightclub owner and mafia boss Niko, Ben Stein as a psychologist, and Cameron Diaz in her feature film debut as Stanley's love interest Tina Carlyle. Hyperactive mayhem results when a mild-manned banker discovers an ancient mask that transforms him into a zany prankster with superhuman powers in this special-effects-intensive comedy.Stanley Ipkiss is a decent-hearted but socially awkward guy who one night finds a strange mask. Stanley puts on the mask and the banker transforms into The Mask, a green-skinned, zoot-suited fireball. The rubber-faced Mask possesses the courage to do the wild, fun things that Stanley fears, including romancing Tina Carlyle. The larger narrative, involving the efforts of Tina's gangster boyfriend to destroy Stanley and use the mask's powers for evil, prove less interesting than the anarchic comic set pieces. The film delivered enough laughs as it is a perfect vehicle for the talents of Jim Carrey wherein he seems to have found a story and character that work together with manic energy.In addition to his physical talents, the film makes effective use of digital visual effects that bestow the Mask with superhuman speed, insane flexibility, and popping eyes out of a Tex Avery cartoon.The design is bright as a button and the transformation scenes real eye-poppers, but the film's best special effect is putty-faced Carrey with his razzle-dazzle star turn as the affable Stanley and his manic alter ego.This makes it a marvelously energetic and highly enjoyable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of my personal favorites as a child and still love it as a young adult!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin-thelordofthefu-48-460297
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    OK, I never read the comics this was based on, but in terms of judging a comic-book movie adaptation on it's own merits, I used to watch this a few more time as a little child at the mid-90s when it was released and I loved it as much as anyone else in this website even as a young adult. Sure, it may not be the best movie, but I've seen much much worse films and I think that this is one of Jim Carrey's best films in my opinion next to Liar Liar and Ace Ventura: Pet Detective. The story is pretty engaging and has some of my favorite moments throughout the film (the casino scene, the dancing sequence, the balloon animals, and the quotes "Somebody Stop Me!" and more), the script's humorous and made me laugh really hard, the special effects are the epitome of greatness, and the music is good, but the strongest aspect goes to the cast especially Jim Carry which I like the best and I liked his personality (going from a mild-mannered person to a wild and crazed superhero). Cameron Diaz and others did a great job with their roles and the villain is pretty good too. The pacing is brisk and the songs are good too. Overall, love this movie as a kid and still love it as an adult and it's definitely worth-watching!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny,Goofy and Beautifully Animated,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dillon Harris
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Mask is a great movie with a very insane and enjoyable storyline with a really good comedic cast.Its not my favourite Jim Carrey performance,but it is without a doubt one of his most memorable,it really showed just what a wacky and fun actor he really is,and thats why he is one of my favourite comedy actors.The best parts of the movie is without a doubt whenever Carrey has the mask on,its a perfect mix of animation and live action,all these scenes are really exaggerated and very funny,simply impossible not to enjoy.I also really liked Cameron Diaz in this,it was her first film and it really showed the world that she was both a talented,funny and of course very attractive actress.The Mask is without a doubt a must see for all fans of Jim Carrey. When Stanley Ipkiss (Jim Carrey) discovers a mask that transforms him into insane superhero,he uses it for his own fun,and to impress Tina Carlyle (Cameron Diaz),but gets in some big trouble with the law along the way.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unbearable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watching 'The Mask' is a lonely experience, like being the only sober person in a room full of maddening drunks. It revolves entirely around Jim Carrey's rubber-faced antics as the title character, which wouldn't be so bad if the movie wasn't a comedy wasteland, if Carrey once - just once - stumbled across a single entertaining moment during his desperately hyperactive flailing, or if the supporting characters had anything to do besides look on as the visual effects romp around in devastatingly unfunny fashion. I like Carrey a lot when he's actually acting ('The Truman Show', 'Eternal Sunshine of the Spotless Mind') but when he's like this I just squirm with embarrassment. Cameron Diaz is the sole bright, likable oasis of warmth to be found amongst the dead weight that makes up the rest of this unbearable racket.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A timeless classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TichMcLovin
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of my favourite movies as a kid, and a guilty pleasure as an adult. This movie has everything that a kid could be looking for in a movie. I introduced this to my 6 year old son recently and now its all he talks about, he mimics the various characters portrayed by The Mask and has even started getting his friends asking their mums and dads about it. 10/10 from me, for the simple fact that it doesn't exactly what its supposed to, entertain families. Its a fun filled story packed with that old school slap stick comedy mixed with some cartoon parodies, all seamlessly blended by the master of laughs, Jim Carrey.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Comedy Classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Paul Robinson
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The mask is a film for me that i like as much now as much as i did when i was a kid, but considering i'm really just a massive man-child it is to be expected. The film really being the perfect setup for Jim Carrey's comedy styling's. The plot follows Stanley Ipkiss, a typical working scrub. Who finds a Mask which turns him into a egotistical Cartoon character essentially. Who causes the ire of the local gangster. Jim Carrey leads the film fantastically, the zany nature of the story and his acting give the a comic book feel, giving it a timeless quality. The humour at times being very childlike, but at times having a real edge to it. The villain Dorian Tyrell played by Peter Greene is quite a ridiculous character in a lot of ways, with so many poor henchmen around him. But Greene does some how get over this and makes him pretty intimidating. The film also has Cameron Diaz possibly at her sexiest with a great entrance in to the movie, and Milo the dog contending with Carrey with some very funny moments. Things i did not quite like were the attempts at comedy involving the cops. I did like Peter Riegert cynical detective, but his inept partner was just plain annoying. A great film to take you back to your childhood and remind you how funny Jim Carrey can be.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Smokin', Everyone Was
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thesar-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Quick! (Just like the Mask) Let me tell you my story. Honestly, I don't remember if I saw this in theatres. I probably did, because what I do remember in early 1996, is buying the VHS copy of this movie and I watched it a grand total of 5-6 times in under a week. I recall watching The Mask over and over and never getting sick of it. Sure, I had plenty of other movies to watch, but this onewas so much fun. And it still is today. Recently, I bought this movie on BluRay, because I remember loving it, but haven't seen it in over 10 years. I seriously had just as much fun today as I did with those multiple viewings when I first bought the VHS. This movie really holds up from the many years since its release. It really is timeless. Goody-Man Stanley Ipkiss (Jim Carrey) is transformed into the daredevil Mask figure when he finds, and dons an ancient wooden mask, and his inner desires come out tenfold. He goes for the girl, inadvertently pisses off the mob and takes care of business as "The Mask" superhero/cartoon character that mild-mannered Stanley couldn't. The story isn't exactly new, even for 1994, but it's take on the age-old underdog/superhero is fresh, exciting and most of all HILARIOUS. As a matter of fact, when prepping and watching the movie to write this review, I was puzzled on which genre this movie fit in: Action/Adventure + SuperHero? Or Comedy + the rest mentioned? And as I found myself laughing and laughing, even after my 5+ original viewings, I settled on: This MUST be a comedywith a close second of Action/adventure + SuperHero. I think this is a very underrated film. It was a very old concept that was a ton of fun, thanks to Jim Carrey at his peak and newcomer, Cameron Diaz who (almost) stole every scene she was in. She was gorgeous and talented and it was hard to believe that this was her first outing. Honestly, as much as I do like her, but not so much every movie she's been in  though I do enjoy a lot of her films, she was fantastic in this. And I understand that dog was like a prop, I still LOVED little Milo. You have to suspend your disbelief a lot during this movie, so you might as well believe all the dog accomplished. This movie is so straight forward to typical movie viewers and still, it's a lot of fun. And it contains one of my all-time favorite scenes/songs in any movie: The Cuban Pete dance segment. Pricelessas was this movie. See it! It still holds up today and despite all the smoking, especially if you're against that, it's a helluva lot of fun.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I don't normally watch Jim Carry, but when i do, i do it right.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    LoneDoveProductions /MTN
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love the Mask. The movie was just like a big cartoon, and fortunately enough, I am immature enough to love this childish humor. The effects were acceptable because it was meant to look like a cartoon. The jokes were funny if you have a little bit of a child at heart. I may be overrating this film, and i feel as i am, but its just the love of these nostalgia cartoons that makes me love this film. I cant say anything more, its just him Carry's best film to me, and deserves a little more recognition. This movie set out a cartoon series(which was not as good since the joke of putting a cartoon in real life is gone) and eventually a sequel, which i did not enjoy much either. The beauty was Jim Carrys over the top acting in this role. It does not work in many characters but is PERFECT for the chaotic mask. My opinion, I'm overrating it a bit, but go watch it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    somebody stop me
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lagudafuad
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You just have to appreciate the technicality and the visual effects that went into the production of this massive hit. The Mask introduced a character that we all started to love and cherish, a hero that can do absolutely anything his mind thinks of. This slap stick comedy showed how Jim Carrey became a good lead actor; he carried the show right from the start to the final battle, doing everything we see in the Warner bros cartoons. After this massive hit, an animated series was also done, introducing more villains and more takes into the life of Stanley Ipkiss. This movie "The Mask" is based on a series of comic books of the same name; the comic is the product of Dark Horse Comics and The Mask was introduced in the 80's based on a concept by the publisher Mike Richardson and created by writer John Arcudi and artist Doug Mahnke. Like in this movie the comic series follows a magical mask and its owner Stanley Ipkiss. When the mask is worn the wearer can bend reality, do the impossible physically and survive the unbelievable. All this is based on the wearer's depth of imagination which The Mask will then surpass. The plot is about a Mr. nice guy, Stanley Ipkiss (Jim Carrey) whom the world seems to step on. Things took a turn around for Ipkiss when he came across a magical mask, which gave him powers to do the impossible. But The Mask was uncontrollable and Ipkiss stepped on toes which were ready to do anything to kill the man behind the mask. The movie is filled with thrilling visual effects, and a wonderful cast. Jim Carrey was just exceptional. The Mask was also Cameron Diaz's first acting role, which later pushed her up the ladder as she now features in major movies yearly. The Mask was a huge box office hit making over 350 million from its 23 million production cost, it was also a critical acclaim, leaving behind it a trail of catchphrases in its time like "smoking" or "somebody stop me". Its high box office status made the makers approach Jim Carrey for a sequel, which he turned down (as Carrey believes making sequels are not challenging). The ideas for the sequel were then used in the animated series, which spawned two seasons. Later after 11 years, a sequel was made but it was unrelated to the first or the animated series, it was titled Son of The Mask which received high negative reviews and was a box office bomb, as the visual effects and the plot were lame and out of place, putting in consideration that it was made with over 84 million. Our hero The Mask is best portrayed here in this beautiful movie and it is a keeper. www.lagsreviews.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Slapstick comedy that makes the world fixable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rosemary (zelda1964)
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jim Carrey (Ace Ventura: Pet Detective) is a zany comic who adds fun to any role he plays; Cameron Diaz (Head Above Water)is a wonderful talent in many films.In The Mask,we find Ipkiss(Carrey),getting bored with his everyday ho-hum bank job;On a chance,Stanley finds this mask that reaches inside to bring out retribution for the world's hard luck.As it happens,Diaz plays the lounge singer Ipkiss falls in love with.Dorian,a co- worker at the lounge,gets upset when Ipkiss (as the masked hero) averts his threat to steal all the savings.The cutest character is Milo,who plays Stanley's lovable pooch. I call this a marvelous film that really tickles the clich&eacute;d "funny bone".Bravo and cheers!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Perfect Vehicle For Jim Carrey
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Mask is a fantasy comedy that is based on a series of comic books published by Dark Horse Comics. The film stars Jim Carrey as Stanley Ipkiss, a man who finds the Mask of Loki that turns him into The Mask, a trickster uninhibited by anything, including physical reality. The supporting cast includes Peter Greene as mafia officer Dorian Tyrell, Amy Yasbeck as a newspaper reporter, Peter Riegert and Jim Doughan as two police detectives, Richard Jeni as Stanley's friend, Orestes Matacena as nightclub owner and mafia boss Niko, Ben Stein as a psychologist, and Cameron Diaz in her feature film debut as Stanley's love interest Tina Carlyle. Hyperactive mayhem results when a mild-manned banker discovers an ancient mask that transforms him into a zany prankster with superhuman powers in this special-effects-intensive comedy.Stanley Ipkiss is a decent-hearted but socially awkward guy who one night finds a strange mask. Stanley puts on the mask and the banker transforms into The Mask, a green-skinned, zoot-suited fireball. The rubber-faced Mask possesses the courage to do the wild, fun things that Stanley fears, including romancing Tina Carlyle. The larger narrative, involving the efforts of Tina's gangster boyfriend to destroy Stanley and use the mask's powers for evil, prove less interesting than the anarchic comic set pieces. The film delivered enough laughs as it is a perfect vehicle for the talents of Jim Carrey wherein he seems to have found a story and character that work together with manic energy.In addition to his physical talents, the film makes effective use of digital visual effects that bestow the Mask with superhuman speed, insane flexibility, and popping eyes out of a Tex Avery cartoon.The design is bright as a button and the transformation scenes real eye-poppers, but the film's best special effect is putty-faced Carrey with his razzle-dazzle star turn as the affable Stanley and his manic alter ego.This makes it a marvelously energetic and highly enjoyable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of my personal favorites as a child and still love it as a young adult!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin-thelordofthefu-48-460297
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    OK, I never read the comics this was based on, but in terms of judging a comic-book movie adaptation on it's own merits, I used to watch this a few more time as a little child at the mid-90s when it was released and I loved it as much as anyone else in this website even as a young adult. Sure, it may not be the best movie, but I've seen much much worse films and I think that this is one of Jim Carrey's best films in my opinion next to Liar Liar and Ace Ventura: Pet Detective. The story is pretty engaging and has some of my favorite moments throughout the film (the casino scene, the dancing sequence, the balloon animals, and the quotes "Somebody Stop Me!" and more), the script's humorous and made me laugh really hard, the special effects are the epitome of greatness, and the music is good, but the strongest aspect goes to the cast especially Jim Carry which I like the best and I liked his personality (going from a mild-mannered person to a wild and crazed superhero). Cameron Diaz and others did a great job with their roles and the villain is pretty good too. The pacing is brisk and the songs are good too. Overall, love this movie as a kid and still love it as an adult and it's definitely worth-watching!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny,Goofy and Beautifully Animated,
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dillon Harris
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Mask is a great movie with a very insane and enjoyable storyline with a really good comedic cast.Its not my favourite Jim Carrey performance,but it is without a doubt one of his most memorable,it really showed just what a wacky and fun actor he really is,and thats why he is one of my favourite comedy actors.The best parts of the movie is without a doubt whenever Carrey has the mask on,its a perfect mix of animation and live action,all these scenes are really exaggerated and very funny,simply impossible not to enjoy.I also really liked Cameron Diaz in this,it was her first film and it really showed the world that she was both a talented,funny and of course very attractive actress.The Mask is without a doubt a must see for all fans of Jim Carrey. When Stanley Ipkiss (Jim Carrey) discovers a mask that transforms him into insane superhero,he uses it for his own fun,and to impress Tina Carlyle (Cameron Diaz),but gets in some big trouble with the law along the way.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unbearable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mutty-mcflea
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Watching 'The Mask' is a lonely experience, like being the only sober person in a room full of maddening drunks. It revolves entirely around Jim Carrey's rubber-faced antics as the title character, which wouldn't be so bad if the movie wasn't a comedy wasteland, if Carrey once - just once - stumbled across a single entertaining moment during his desperately hyperactive flailing, or if the supporting characters had anything to do besides look on as the visual effects romp around in devastatingly unfunny fashion. I like Carrey a lot when he's actually acting ('The Truman Show', 'Eternal Sunshine of the Spotless Mind') but when he's like this I just squirm with embarrassment. Cameron Diaz is the sole bright, likable oasis of warmth to be found amongst the dead weight that makes up the rest of this unbearable racket.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A timeless classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TichMcLovin
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of my favourite movies as a kid, and a guilty pleasure as an adult. This movie has everything that a kid could be looking for in a movie. I introduced this to my 6 year old son recently and now its all he talks about, he mimics the various characters portrayed by The Mask and has even started getting his friends asking their mums and dads about it. 10/10 from me, for the simple fact that it doesn't exactly what its supposed to, entertain families. Its a fun filled story packed with that old school slap stick comedy mixed with some cartoon parodies, all seamlessly blended by the master of laughs, Jim Carrey.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Comedy Classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Paul Robinson
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The mask is a film for me that i like as much now as much as i did when i was a kid, but considering i'm really just a massive man-child it is to be expected. The film really being the perfect setup for Jim Carrey's comedy styling's. The plot follows Stanley Ipkiss, a typical working scrub. Who finds a Mask which turns him into a egotistical Cartoon character essentially. Who causes the ire of the local gangster. Jim Carrey leads the film fantastically, the zany nature of the story and his acting give the a comic book feel, giving it a timeless quality. The humour at times being very childlike, but at times having a real edge to it. The villain Dorian Tyrell played by Peter Greene is quite a ridiculous character in a lot of ways, with so many poor henchmen around him. But Greene does some how get over this and makes him pretty intimidating. The film also has Cameron Diaz possibly at her sexiest with a great entrance in to the movie, and Milo the dog contending with Carrey with some very funny moments. Things i did not quite like were the attempts at comedy involving the cops. I did like Peter Riegert cynical detective, but his inept partner was just plain annoying. A great film to take you back to your childhood and remind you how funny Jim Carrey can be.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Smokin', Everyone Was
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    thesar-2
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Quick! (Just like the Mask) Let me tell you my story. Honestly, I don't remember if I saw this in theatres. I probably did, because what I do remember in early 1996, is buying the VHS copy of this movie and I watched it a grand total of 5-6 times in under a week. I recall watching The Mask over and over and never getting sick of it. Sure, I had plenty of other movies to watch, but this onewas so much fun. And it still is today. Recently, I bought this movie on BluRay, because I remember loving it, but haven't seen it in over 10 years. I seriously had just as much fun today as I did with those multiple viewings when I first bought the VHS. This movie really holds up from the many years since its release. It really is timeless. Goody-Man Stanley Ipkiss (Jim Carrey) is transformed into the daredevil Mask figure when he finds, and dons an ancient wooden mask, and his inner desires come out tenfold. He goes for the girl, inadvertently pisses off the mob and takes care of business as "The Mask" superhero/cartoon character that mild-mannered Stanley couldn't. The story isn't exactly new, even for 1994, but it's take on the age-old underdog/superhero is fresh, exciting and most of all HILARIOUS. As a matter of fact, when prepping and watching the movie to write this review, I was puzzled on which genre this movie fit in: Action/Adventure + SuperHero? Or Comedy + the rest mentioned? And as I found myself laughing and laughing, even after my 5+ original viewings, I settled on: This MUST be a comedywith a close second of Action/adventure + SuperHero. I think this is a very underrated film. It was a very old concept that was a ton of fun, thanks to Jim Carrey at his peak and newcomer, Cameron Diaz who (almost) stole every scene she was in. She was gorgeous and talented and it was hard to believe that this was her first outing. Honestly, as much as I do like her, but not so much every movie she's been in  though I do enjoy a lot of her films, she was fantastic in this. And I understand that dog was like a prop, I still LOVED little Milo. You have to suspend your disbelief a lot during this movie, so you might as well believe all the dog accomplished. This movie is so straight forward to typical movie viewers and still, it's a lot of fun. And it contains one of my all-time favorite scenes/songs in any movie: The Cuban Pete dance segment. Pricelessas was this movie. See it! It still holds up today and despite all the smoking, especially if you're against that, it's a helluva lot of fun.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I don't normally watch Jim Carry, but when i do, i do it right.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    LoneDoveProductions /MTN
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I love the Mask. The movie was just like a big cartoon, and fortunately enough, I am immature enough to love this childish humor. The effects were acceptable because it was meant to look like a cartoon. The jokes were funny if you have a little bit of a child at heart. I may be overrating this film, and i feel as i am, but its just the love of these nostalgia cartoons that makes me love this film. I cant say anything more, its just him Carry's best film to me, and deserves a little more recognition. This movie set out a cartoon series(which was not as good since the joke of putting a cartoon in real life is gone) and eventually a sequel, which i did not enjoy much either. The beauty was Jim Carrys over the top acting in this role. It does not work in many characters but is PERFECT for the chaotic mask. My opinion, I'm overrating it a bit, but go watch it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    somebody stop me
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lagudafuad
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You just have to appreciate the technicality and the visual effects that went into the production of this massive hit. The Mask introduced a character that we all started to love and cherish, a hero that can do absolutely anything his mind thinks of. This slap stick comedy showed how Jim Carrey became a good lead actor; he carried the show right from the start to the final battle, doing everything we see in the Warner bros cartoons. After this massive hit, an animated series was also done, introducing more villains and more takes into the life of Stanley Ipkiss. This movie "The Mask" is based on a series of comic books of the same name; the comic is the product of Dark Horse Comics and The Mask was introduced in the 80's based on a concept by the publisher Mike Richardson and created by writer John Arcudi and artist Doug Mahnke. Like in this movie the comic series follows a magical mask and its owner Stanley Ipkiss. When the mask is worn the wearer can bend reality, do the impossible physically and survive the unbelievable. All this is based on the wearer's depth of imagination which The Mask will then surpass. The plot is about a Mr. nice guy, Stanley Ipkiss (Jim Carrey) whom the world seems to step on. Things took a turn around for Ipkiss when he came across a magical mask, which gave him powers to do the impossible. But The Mask was uncontrollable and Ipkiss stepped on toes which were ready to do anything to kill the man behind the mask. The movie is filled with thrilling visual effects, and a wonderful cast. Jim Carrey was just exceptional. The Mask was also Cameron Diaz's first acting role, which later pushed her up the ladder as she now features in major movies yearly. The Mask was a huge box office hit making over 350 million from its 23 million production cost, it was also a critical acclaim, leaving behind it a trail of catchphrases in its time like "smoking" or "somebody stop me". Its high box office status made the makers approach Jim Carrey for a sequel, which he turned down (as Carrey believes making sequels are not challenging). The ideas for the sequel were then used in the animated series, which spawned two seasons. Later after 11 years, a sequel was made but it was unrelated to the first or the animated series, it was titled Son of The Mask which received high negative reviews and was a box office bomb, as the visual effects and the plot were lame and out of place, putting in consideration that it was made with over 84 million. Our hero The Mask is best portrayed here in this beautiful movie and it is a keeper. www.lagsreviews.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Slapstick comedy that makes the world fixable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rosemary (zelda1964)
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Jim Carrey (Ace Ventura: Pet Detective) is a zany comic who adds fun to any role he plays; Cameron Diaz (Head Above Water)is a wonderful talent in many films.In The Mask,we find Ipkiss(Carrey),getting bored with his everyday ho-hum bank job;On a chance,Stanley finds this mask that reaches inside to bring out retribution for the world's hard luck.As it happens,Diaz plays the lounge singer Ipkiss falls in love with.Dorian,a co- worker at the lounge,gets upset when Ipkiss (as the masked hero) averts his threat to steal all the savings.The cutest character is Milo,who plays Stanley's lovable pooch. I call this a marvelous film that really tickles the clich&eacute;d "funny bone".Bravo and cheers!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Perfect Vehicle For Jim Carrey
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Mask is a fantasy comedy that is based on a series of comic books published by Dark Horse Comics. The film stars Jim Carrey as Stanley Ipkiss, a man who finds the Mask of Loki that turns him into The Mask, a trickster uninhibited by anything, including physical reality. The supporting cast includes Peter Greene as mafia officer Dorian Tyrell, Amy Yasbeck as a newspaper reporter, Peter Riegert and Jim Doughan as two police detectives, Richard Jeni as Stanley's friend, Orestes Matacena as nightclub owner and mafia boss Niko, Ben Stein as a psychologist, and Cameron Diaz in her feature film debut as Stanley's love interest Tina Carlyle. Hyperactive mayhem results when a mild-manned banker discovers an ancient mask that transforms him into a zany prankster with superhuman powers in this special-effects-intensive comedy.Stanley Ipkiss is a decent-hearted but socially awkward guy who one night finds a strange mask. Stanley puts on the mask and the banker transforms into The Mask, a green-skinned, zoot-suited fireball. The rubber-faced Mask possesses the courage to do the wild, fun things that Stanley fears, including romancing Tina Carlyle. The larger narrative, involving the efforts of Tina's gangster boyfriend to destroy Stanley and use the mask's powers for evil, prove less interesting than the anarchic comic set pieces. The film delivered enough laughs as it is a perfect vehicle for the talents of Jim Carrey wherein he seems to have found a story and character that work together with manic energy.In addition to his physical talents, the film makes effective use of digital visual effects that bestow the Mask with superhuman speed, insane flexibility, and popping eyes out of a Tex Avery cartoon.The design is bright as a button and the transformation scenes real eye-poppers, but the film's best special effect is putty-faced Carrey with his razzle-dazzle star turn as the affable Stanley and his manic alter ego.This makes it a marvelously energetic and highly enjoyable.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of my personal favorites as a child and still love it as a young adult!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin-thelordofthefu-48-460297
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    OK, I never read the comics this was based on, but in terms of judging a comic-book movie adaptation on it's own merits, I used to watch this a few more time as a little child at the mid-90s when it was released and I loved it as much as anyone else in this website even as a young adult. Sure, it may not be the best movie, but I've seen much much worse films and I think that this is one of Jim Carrey's best films in my opinion next to Liar Liar and Ace Ventura: Pet Detective. The story is pretty engaging and has some of my favorite moments throughout the film (the casino scene, the dancing sequence, the balloon animals, and the quotes "Somebody Stop Me!" and more), the script's humorous and made me laugh really hard, the special effects are the epitome of greatness, and the music is good, but the strongest aspect goes to the cast especially Jim Carry which I like the best and I liked his personality (going from a mild-mannered person to a wild and crazed superhero). Cameron Diaz and others did a great job with their roles and the villain is pretty good too. The pacing is brisk and the songs are good too. Overall, love this movie as a kid and still love it as an adult and it's definitely worth-watching!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
