<filme>
 <id>
  723
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0112571
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1995
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Somente Elas
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.1
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Jane is a night club singer, out of work. Robin is a quirky real estate agent looking for a ride-share to accompany her to California. Her advertisement is answered by Jane, who at first ... &nbsp;&raquo;
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Jane is a night club singer, out of work. Robin is a quirky real estate agent looking for a ride-share to accompany her to California. Her advertisement is answered by Jane, who at first was uncertain about her. A stop in Pittsburgh picks up a third, Holly, escaping a violent and drug-dealing partner. Girls on the road, reaching understanding, respect, and care for each other. But this trio is different - Jane a lesbian, Robin suffering with AIDS, Holly running from her past, seeking one-night stands and a good man.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   singer
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   on the road
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   lesbian
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   real estate agent
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   ups
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Herbert Ross
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Don Roos
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Whoopi Goldberg
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Mary-Louise Parker
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Drew Barrymore
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bit Soapy and Feministic, But Still Powerful!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    g-bodyl
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Boys on the Side is a powerful but sometimes amusing melodrama about the lives of three woman with different backgrounds coming together to celebrate the lives of women on their earnest road trip. This film may be a bit soapy and seems more like a Lifetime film, but this soapiness enhances the drama. This film may also be a little more on the feminist side, but I didn't mind that much since women are equal to men and should have their stories told as well. Herbert Ross's film is about a wisecracking club singer, an uptight saleswoman, and a young, free spirit all joining crossroads so they can travel cross-county from New York to California. The acting is very good. Whoopi Goldberg actually proves me wrong by showing she can be a good actress. Mary-Louise Parker has some very powerful scenes and should have been nominated an Oscar. Drew Barrymore is also very good and she seems to be my kind of girl. Overall, this is very powerful film about womenhood and some of the problems they face. People call this a chick flick, but is it really? I think guys should watch this film in order to gain a higher appreciation of women. This film is about bonds that will never be forgotten. I'm surprised how such a good movie this drama was. I rate this film 9/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good solid film - well done
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pik923
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Start with the cast - wonderful. From Whoopi Goldberg, Mary Louise Parker, Drew Barrymore - that's just for starters - a solid cast. Each one holds her own and rounds out the character with humor, sensitivity and a truthfulness. The script - good solid script - the director - Herbert Ross - he knew how to tell a story. And don't forget the soundtrack - love the music! Add to that one of the first scripts that looked at AIDS from the eyes of women. Not just a straight woman, but also a gay woman. How the characters both men and women deal with the issue, which is usually for Hollywood and the motion picture world, a male issue (the only other film I can immediately refer to as an AIDS film relating to women is the HBO film GIA). I highly recommend the film for all audiences - including teenagers. It deals with many delicate issues with great warmth, love, trust, humor and truthfulness. Thank you for this little gem!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny, sad, so entertaining. A definite must see.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin-hoare
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is my favorite film of all time. It has everything you want in a film. It is funny and has plenty of action throughout. It is also so sad, anyone who doesn't cry must be emotionally retarded. I especially love Mary Jane Parker in this film even though all the actors are great.The film has so many great lines in it too and who would have known Whoopi Goldberg has a decent singing voice. I strongly recommend everyone to watch this. Its just a shame i cant get this on region 2 DVD anywhere so i have to watch it on video which is not great.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A bore
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Gordon-11
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/8/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is about the friendship of three women who goes onto a road trip, after an accident that goes horribly wrong. I find the film incredibly plain and dull. The characters are not likable, and I do not care much for them. Holly, in particular, is annoying and stupid. The domestic violence part gains her some sympathy, but confessing it to the wrong person is plain silly. As a result, the plot becomes contrived. The way the story is told is plain, with almost no emotional ups and downs. The only thing that holds my interest is Robin's illness, but even that is not so well developed. Her condition could have been a lot more dramatic and touching, but the whole subplot fails to engage or captivate. In short, I find "Boys on the Side" boring. I can only say I am not the target audience of this film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sooooo chick-flick
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    marcslope
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/7/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Count the chick-flick conventions: The revenge on the abusive boyfriend; the three so-different young women bonding; the mother-daughter conflicts; the road trip; the scene where somebody sings "Happy Birthday" to somebody amid much general rejoicing; the adorable baby; the tear-wringing incurable-disease character; etc. It's well-written -- Don Roos, who later wrote the superb screenplay to "The Opposite of Sex," puts more curve on his dialog than most toiling in this genre -- but as with many sisters-united-in-adversity epics, it keeps wanting to yank emotions out of you rather than earn them honestly. The three leads are good, a young Matthew McConnaughey isn't yet annoying, and there are nice turns from Estelle Parsons and Anita Gillette, a Broadway baby decades earlier who matured into a proficient character actress. But Herb Ross is in his take-no-chances mode, and too much of the picture feels programmed and rote.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hit and Miss
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gcd70
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/2/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Largely a hit and miss comedy-drama, "Boys on the Side" is very melodramatic and not much better than a T.V. series. Helmer Herbert Ross again indulges the 'women's own pic', but this time he produces a movie not only nowhere near the calibre of his dramatically strong "Steel Magnolias", but also not even as interesting as the ordinary Ridley Scott road movie "Thelma and Louise" (there's a clever and apt reference to the ridiculous ending of that severely flawed film in this road movie). The girls in this flick have so many problems it's not funny, just mostly boring. Ross is unable to generate interest in the respective plights of Robin, Jane and Holly, and I for one was left hankering for a regular threesome who would stay on the road. The original screenplay from Don Roos attempts to tackle too many issues (murder, AIDS, single mothers and homosexuality to name a few), and in so doing fails to deal satisfactorily with any of them. Many of the relationship problems that arise are never properly dealt with or resolved. The show gets so weighed down with emotional baggage and unnecessary seriousness that what fun their is, gets lost in all the dreadfully morbid drudgery. Thus the comedy that does exist is drowned along with all the wild shenanigans. Add to this the fact that all the fellas are either schmucks or complete losers, and not only is it obvious the girls want to go it alone for a good reason, but it's also clear that this is an ordinary, forgettable film. Whoopi Goldberg has been infinitely better than this, and though both she and Mary Louise Parker (in a role similar to that in "Fried Green Tomatoes") are competent, we know they're both well below par here. As for Drew Barrymore, she still fails to show any of the promise she did as a young actress, and seems content to flaunt her bod. Though this may serve as a distraction for the men, her pretty looks are no substitute for raw talent, which she really needs to find before she is typecast. Like I said, this is very much hit and miss stuff, but more so the latter. "Boys on the Side" just never successfully influences the emotions, which "Steel Magnolias" did so easily with its quirky, lovable characters and simple theme. At least the trendy rock soundtrack which featured artists like The Cranberries and Annie Lennox saved some face. Saturday, August 5, 1995 - Waverley Pinewood Cinema
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Boys On the Side...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    fierypoeticgirl
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/12/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm sorry, but I did not like "Thelma and Louise." This movie had more depth to it even though it is sort of sappy at times; but still, it was good. Mary-Louise Parker stole the film with her frail health, yet she holds nothing back verbally. She is the one who settles the disputes while everyone else is so mixed up. Imagine that; the strength of a dying woman tying loose ends together before her passing away. During the trial in this movie when Mary's character was a witness for "Holly" played by Drew Barrymore, she was trying to say that women have a special bond that takes place just like men do, yet not as many women are hardly ever quick to judge men when they get together or maybe even assume they are "gay." We all just take it at fact value which is that it's "Boys' night out." Women are still being misunderstood when they remain friends like the three women were in this movie. I found the variety and versatility of characters and situations remarkably memorable. Superb job to everyone.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Boys on the Side
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/1/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film by The Sunshine Boys director Herbert Ross is quite a good drama with very small elements of comedy. Basically lesbian Jane (Whoopi Goldberg) is a night club singer, out of work. AIDS suffering Robin (Mary-Louise Parker) is a quirky real estate agent looking for a ride-share to accompany her to California, this is answered by at first unsure Jane. In Pittsburgh they pick up a third, one-night stand and man loving Holly (Drew Barrymore), escaping a violent and drug-dealing partner. It starts as a road trip, and focuses on reaching understanding, respect, and care for each other. I did trail off in a few places, but when I was paying attention, it was a very pleasant film. Good!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just may be one of the worst movies I've seen...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nomad492
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/12/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You know there is nothing on TV when there are three HBO channels in the hotel and this was the best there was. This is little more than PC story about characters that have no real interest. We have a lesbian, an AIDs patient, and a single pregnant woman who falls in love with an AZ cop. All of this, and there is not an interesting character in the bunch. The one redeeming part. Matthew McConaughey when he still had good hair. Okay, perhaps I'm being too hard. No, I'm not. The Wild Wild West with Will Smith still ranks as the worst movie made in recent memory and this one was not that bad. Well...not quite. Don't waste your time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's Time To Share A Light
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    George Attwood
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/9/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    BOYS ON THE SIDE **** Herbert Ross's last work, 'Boys On The Side' tells a unique, special story of the bonds between three women as they take a cross-country drive, end up in Nevado, and struggle through hardships, progressively developing in their character. Don Roos's screenplay is coherent and strong enough to make the transitions between the story's funny and dramatic moments smooth and generally effective for that matter. It's moral grounds are a bit too liberalized for my taste. Rating System ***** Excellent **** Good *** Fair ** Poor * Bad
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bit Soapy and Feministic, But Still Powerful!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    g-bodyl
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Boys on the Side is a powerful but sometimes amusing melodrama about the lives of three woman with different backgrounds coming together to celebrate the lives of women on their earnest road trip. This film may be a bit soapy and seems more like a Lifetime film, but this soapiness enhances the drama. This film may also be a little more on the feminist side, but I didn't mind that much since women are equal to men and should have their stories told as well. Herbert Ross's film is about a wisecracking club singer, an uptight saleswoman, and a young, free spirit all joining crossroads so they can travel cross-county from New York to California. The acting is very good. Whoopi Goldberg actually proves me wrong by showing she can be a good actress. Mary-Louise Parker has some very powerful scenes and should have been nominated an Oscar. Drew Barrymore is also very good and she seems to be my kind of girl. Overall, this is very powerful film about womenhood and some of the problems they face. People call this a chick flick, but is it really? I think guys should watch this film in order to gain a higher appreciation of women. This film is about bonds that will never be forgotten. I'm surprised how such a good movie this drama was. I rate this film 9/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good solid film - well done
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pik923
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Start with the cast - wonderful. From Whoopi Goldberg, Mary Louise Parker, Drew Barrymore - that's just for starters - a solid cast. Each one holds her own and rounds out the character with humor, sensitivity and a truthfulness. The script - good solid script - the director - Herbert Ross - he knew how to tell a story. And don't forget the soundtrack - love the music! Add to that one of the first scripts that looked at AIDS from the eyes of women. Not just a straight woman, but also a gay woman. How the characters both men and women deal with the issue, which is usually for Hollywood and the motion picture world, a male issue (the only other film I can immediately refer to as an AIDS film relating to women is the HBO film GIA). I highly recommend the film for all audiences - including teenagers. It deals with many delicate issues with great warmth, love, trust, humor and truthfulness. Thank you for this little gem!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny, sad, so entertaining. A definite must see.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin-hoare
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is my favorite film of all time. It has everything you want in a film. It is funny and has plenty of action throughout. It is also so sad, anyone who doesn't cry must be emotionally retarded. I especially love Mary Jane Parker in this film even though all the actors are great.The film has so many great lines in it too and who would have known Whoopi Goldberg has a decent singing voice. I strongly recommend everyone to watch this. Its just a shame i cant get this on region 2 DVD anywhere so i have to watch it on video which is not great.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A bore
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Gordon-11
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/8/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is about the friendship of three women who goes onto a road trip, after an accident that goes horribly wrong. I find the film incredibly plain and dull. The characters are not likable, and I do not care much for them. Holly, in particular, is annoying and stupid. The domestic violence part gains her some sympathy, but confessing it to the wrong person is plain silly. As a result, the plot becomes contrived. The way the story is told is plain, with almost no emotional ups and downs. The only thing that holds my interest is Robin's illness, but even that is not so well developed. Her condition could have been a lot more dramatic and touching, but the whole subplot fails to engage or captivate. In short, I find "Boys on the Side" boring. I can only say I am not the target audience of this film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sooooo chick-flick
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    marcslope
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/7/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Count the chick-flick conventions: The revenge on the abusive boyfriend; the three so-different young women bonding; the mother-daughter conflicts; the road trip; the scene where somebody sings "Happy Birthday" to somebody amid much general rejoicing; the adorable baby; the tear-wringing incurable-disease character; etc. It's well-written -- Don Roos, who later wrote the superb screenplay to "The Opposite of Sex," puts more curve on his dialog than most toiling in this genre -- but as with many sisters-united-in-adversity epics, it keeps wanting to yank emotions out of you rather than earn them honestly. The three leads are good, a young Matthew McConnaughey isn't yet annoying, and there are nice turns from Estelle Parsons and Anita Gillette, a Broadway baby decades earlier who matured into a proficient character actress. But Herb Ross is in his take-no-chances mode, and too much of the picture feels programmed and rote.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hit and Miss
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gcd70
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/2/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Largely a hit and miss comedy-drama, "Boys on the Side" is very melodramatic and not much better than a T.V. series. Helmer Herbert Ross again indulges the 'women's own pic', but this time he produces a movie not only nowhere near the calibre of his dramatically strong "Steel Magnolias", but also not even as interesting as the ordinary Ridley Scott road movie "Thelma and Louise" (there's a clever and apt reference to the ridiculous ending of that severely flawed film in this road movie). The girls in this flick have so many problems it's not funny, just mostly boring. Ross is unable to generate interest in the respective plights of Robin, Jane and Holly, and I for one was left hankering for a regular threesome who would stay on the road. The original screenplay from Don Roos attempts to tackle too many issues (murder, AIDS, single mothers and homosexuality to name a few), and in so doing fails to deal satisfactorily with any of them. Many of the relationship problems that arise are never properly dealt with or resolved. The show gets so weighed down with emotional baggage and unnecessary seriousness that what fun their is, gets lost in all the dreadfully morbid drudgery. Thus the comedy that does exist is drowned along with all the wild shenanigans. Add to this the fact that all the fellas are either schmucks or complete losers, and not only is it obvious the girls want to go it alone for a good reason, but it's also clear that this is an ordinary, forgettable film. Whoopi Goldberg has been infinitely better than this, and though both she and Mary Louise Parker (in a role similar to that in "Fried Green Tomatoes") are competent, we know they're both well below par here. As for Drew Barrymore, she still fails to show any of the promise she did as a young actress, and seems content to flaunt her bod. Though this may serve as a distraction for the men, her pretty looks are no substitute for raw talent, which she really needs to find before she is typecast. Like I said, this is very much hit and miss stuff, but more so the latter. "Boys on the Side" just never successfully influences the emotions, which "Steel Magnolias" did so easily with its quirky, lovable characters and simple theme. At least the trendy rock soundtrack which featured artists like The Cranberries and Annie Lennox saved some face. Saturday, August 5, 1995 - Waverley Pinewood Cinema
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Boys On the Side...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    fierypoeticgirl
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/12/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm sorry, but I did not like "Thelma and Louise." This movie had more depth to it even though it is sort of sappy at times; but still, it was good. Mary-Louise Parker stole the film with her frail health, yet she holds nothing back verbally. She is the one who settles the disputes while everyone else is so mixed up. Imagine that; the strength of a dying woman tying loose ends together before her passing away. During the trial in this movie when Mary's character was a witness for "Holly" played by Drew Barrymore, she was trying to say that women have a special bond that takes place just like men do, yet not as many women are hardly ever quick to judge men when they get together or maybe even assume they are "gay." We all just take it at fact value which is that it's "Boys' night out." Women are still being misunderstood when they remain friends like the three women were in this movie. I found the variety and versatility of characters and situations remarkably memorable. Superb job to everyone.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Boys on the Side
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/1/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film by The Sunshine Boys director Herbert Ross is quite a good drama with very small elements of comedy. Basically lesbian Jane (Whoopi Goldberg) is a night club singer, out of work. AIDS suffering Robin (Mary-Louise Parker) is a quirky real estate agent looking for a ride-share to accompany her to California, this is answered by at first unsure Jane. In Pittsburgh they pick up a third, one-night stand and man loving Holly (Drew Barrymore), escaping a violent and drug-dealing partner. It starts as a road trip, and focuses on reaching understanding, respect, and care for each other. I did trail off in a few places, but when I was paying attention, it was a very pleasant film. Good!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just may be one of the worst movies I've seen...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nomad492
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/12/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You know there is nothing on TV when there are three HBO channels in the hotel and this was the best there was. This is little more than PC story about characters that have no real interest. We have a lesbian, an AIDs patient, and a single pregnant woman who falls in love with an AZ cop. All of this, and there is not an interesting character in the bunch. The one redeeming part. Matthew McConaughey when he still had good hair. Okay, perhaps I'm being too hard. No, I'm not. The Wild Wild West with Will Smith still ranks as the worst movie made in recent memory and this one was not that bad. Well...not quite. Don't waste your time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's Time To Share A Light
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    George Attwood
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/9/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    BOYS ON THE SIDE **** Herbert Ross's last work, 'Boys On The Side' tells a unique, special story of the bonds between three women as they take a cross-country drive, end up in Nevado, and struggle through hardships, progressively developing in their character. Don Roos's screenplay is coherent and strong enough to make the transitions between the story's funny and dramatic moments smooth and generally effective for that matter. It's moral grounds are a bit too liberalized for my taste. Rating System ***** Excellent **** Good *** Fair ** Poor * Bad
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bit Soapy and Feministic, But Still Powerful!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    g-bodyl
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Boys on the Side is a powerful but sometimes amusing melodrama about the lives of three woman with different backgrounds coming together to celebrate the lives of women on their earnest road trip. This film may be a bit soapy and seems more like a Lifetime film, but this soapiness enhances the drama. This film may also be a little more on the feminist side, but I didn't mind that much since women are equal to men and should have their stories told as well. Herbert Ross's film is about a wisecracking club singer, an uptight saleswoman, and a young, free spirit all joining crossroads so they can travel cross-county from New York to California. The acting is very good. Whoopi Goldberg actually proves me wrong by showing she can be a good actress. Mary-Louise Parker has some very powerful scenes and should have been nominated an Oscar. Drew Barrymore is also very good and she seems to be my kind of girl. Overall, this is very powerful film about womenhood and some of the problems they face. People call this a chick flick, but is it really? I think guys should watch this film in order to gain a higher appreciation of women. This film is about bonds that will never be forgotten. I'm surprised how such a good movie this drama was. I rate this film 9/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good solid film - well done
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pik923
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Start with the cast - wonderful. From Whoopi Goldberg, Mary Louise Parker, Drew Barrymore - that's just for starters - a solid cast. Each one holds her own and rounds out the character with humor, sensitivity and a truthfulness. The script - good solid script - the director - Herbert Ross - he knew how to tell a story. And don't forget the soundtrack - love the music! Add to that one of the first scripts that looked at AIDS from the eyes of women. Not just a straight woman, but also a gay woman. How the characters both men and women deal with the issue, which is usually for Hollywood and the motion picture world, a male issue (the only other film I can immediately refer to as an AIDS film relating to women is the HBO film GIA). I highly recommend the film for all audiences - including teenagers. It deals with many delicate issues with great warmth, love, trust, humor and truthfulness. Thank you for this little gem!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny, sad, so entertaining. A definite must see.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin-hoare
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is my favorite film of all time. It has everything you want in a film. It is funny and has plenty of action throughout. It is also so sad, anyone who doesn't cry must be emotionally retarded. I especially love Mary Jane Parker in this film even though all the actors are great.The film has so many great lines in it too and who would have known Whoopi Goldberg has a decent singing voice. I strongly recommend everyone to watch this. Its just a shame i cant get this on region 2 DVD anywhere so i have to watch it on video which is not great.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A bore
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Gordon-11
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/8/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is about the friendship of three women who goes onto a road trip, after an accident that goes horribly wrong. I find the film incredibly plain and dull. The characters are not likable, and I do not care much for them. Holly, in particular, is annoying and stupid. The domestic violence part gains her some sympathy, but confessing it to the wrong person is plain silly. As a result, the plot becomes contrived. The way the story is told is plain, with almost no emotional ups and downs. The only thing that holds my interest is Robin's illness, but even that is not so well developed. Her condition could have been a lot more dramatic and touching, but the whole subplot fails to engage or captivate. In short, I find "Boys on the Side" boring. I can only say I am not the target audience of this film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sooooo chick-flick
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    marcslope
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/7/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Count the chick-flick conventions: The revenge on the abusive boyfriend; the three so-different young women bonding; the mother-daughter conflicts; the road trip; the scene where somebody sings "Happy Birthday" to somebody amid much general rejoicing; the adorable baby; the tear-wringing incurable-disease character; etc. It's well-written -- Don Roos, who later wrote the superb screenplay to "The Opposite of Sex," puts more curve on his dialog than most toiling in this genre -- but as with many sisters-united-in-adversity epics, it keeps wanting to yank emotions out of you rather than earn them honestly. The three leads are good, a young Matthew McConnaughey isn't yet annoying, and there are nice turns from Estelle Parsons and Anita Gillette, a Broadway baby decades earlier who matured into a proficient character actress. But Herb Ross is in his take-no-chances mode, and too much of the picture feels programmed and rote.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hit and Miss
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gcd70
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/2/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Largely a hit and miss comedy-drama, "Boys on the Side" is very melodramatic and not much better than a T.V. series. Helmer Herbert Ross again indulges the 'women's own pic', but this time he produces a movie not only nowhere near the calibre of his dramatically strong "Steel Magnolias", but also not even as interesting as the ordinary Ridley Scott road movie "Thelma and Louise" (there's a clever and apt reference to the ridiculous ending of that severely flawed film in this road movie). The girls in this flick have so many problems it's not funny, just mostly boring. Ross is unable to generate interest in the respective plights of Robin, Jane and Holly, and I for one was left hankering for a regular threesome who would stay on the road. The original screenplay from Don Roos attempts to tackle too many issues (murder, AIDS, single mothers and homosexuality to name a few), and in so doing fails to deal satisfactorily with any of them. Many of the relationship problems that arise are never properly dealt with or resolved. The show gets so weighed down with emotional baggage and unnecessary seriousness that what fun their is, gets lost in all the dreadfully morbid drudgery. Thus the comedy that does exist is drowned along with all the wild shenanigans. Add to this the fact that all the fellas are either schmucks or complete losers, and not only is it obvious the girls want to go it alone for a good reason, but it's also clear that this is an ordinary, forgettable film. Whoopi Goldberg has been infinitely better than this, and though both she and Mary Louise Parker (in a role similar to that in "Fried Green Tomatoes") are competent, we know they're both well below par here. As for Drew Barrymore, she still fails to show any of the promise she did as a young actress, and seems content to flaunt her bod. Though this may serve as a distraction for the men, her pretty looks are no substitute for raw talent, which she really needs to find before she is typecast. Like I said, this is very much hit and miss stuff, but more so the latter. "Boys on the Side" just never successfully influences the emotions, which "Steel Magnolias" did so easily with its quirky, lovable characters and simple theme. At least the trendy rock soundtrack which featured artists like The Cranberries and Annie Lennox saved some face. Saturday, August 5, 1995 - Waverley Pinewood Cinema
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Boys On the Side...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    fierypoeticgirl
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/12/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm sorry, but I did not like "Thelma and Louise." This movie had more depth to it even though it is sort of sappy at times; but still, it was good. Mary-Louise Parker stole the film with her frail health, yet she holds nothing back verbally. She is the one who settles the disputes while everyone else is so mixed up. Imagine that; the strength of a dying woman tying loose ends together before her passing away. During the trial in this movie when Mary's character was a witness for "Holly" played by Drew Barrymore, she was trying to say that women have a special bond that takes place just like men do, yet not as many women are hardly ever quick to judge men when they get together or maybe even assume they are "gay." We all just take it at fact value which is that it's "Boys' night out." Women are still being misunderstood when they remain friends like the three women were in this movie. I found the variety and versatility of characters and situations remarkably memorable. Superb job to everyone.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Boys on the Side
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/1/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film by The Sunshine Boys director Herbert Ross is quite a good drama with very small elements of comedy. Basically lesbian Jane (Whoopi Goldberg) is a night club singer, out of work. AIDS suffering Robin (Mary-Louise Parker) is a quirky real estate agent looking for a ride-share to accompany her to California, this is answered by at first unsure Jane. In Pittsburgh they pick up a third, one-night stand and man loving Holly (Drew Barrymore), escaping a violent and drug-dealing partner. It starts as a road trip, and focuses on reaching understanding, respect, and care for each other. I did trail off in a few places, but when I was paying attention, it was a very pleasant film. Good!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just may be one of the worst movies I've seen...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nomad492
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/12/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You know there is nothing on TV when there are three HBO channels in the hotel and this was the best there was. This is little more than PC story about characters that have no real interest. We have a lesbian, an AIDs patient, and a single pregnant woman who falls in love with an AZ cop. All of this, and there is not an interesting character in the bunch. The one redeeming part. Matthew McConaughey when he still had good hair. Okay, perhaps I'm being too hard. No, I'm not. The Wild Wild West with Will Smith still ranks as the worst movie made in recent memory and this one was not that bad. Well...not quite. Don't waste your time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's Time To Share A Light
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    George Attwood
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/9/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    BOYS ON THE SIDE **** Herbert Ross's last work, 'Boys On The Side' tells a unique, special story of the bonds between three women as they take a cross-country drive, end up in Nevado, and struggle through hardships, progressively developing in their character. Don Roos's screenplay is coherent and strong enough to make the transitions between the story's funny and dramatic moments smooth and generally effective for that matter. It's moral grounds are a bit too liberalized for my taste. Rating System ***** Excellent **** Good *** Fair ** Poor * Bad
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bit Soapy and Feministic, But Still Powerful!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    g-bodyl
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Boys on the Side is a powerful but sometimes amusing melodrama about the lives of three woman with different backgrounds coming together to celebrate the lives of women on their earnest road trip. This film may be a bit soapy and seems more like a Lifetime film, but this soapiness enhances the drama. This film may also be a little more on the feminist side, but I didn't mind that much since women are equal to men and should have their stories told as well. Herbert Ross's film is about a wisecracking club singer, an uptight saleswoman, and a young, free spirit all joining crossroads so they can travel cross-county from New York to California. The acting is very good. Whoopi Goldberg actually proves me wrong by showing she can be a good actress. Mary-Louise Parker has some very powerful scenes and should have been nominated an Oscar. Drew Barrymore is also very good and she seems to be my kind of girl. Overall, this is very powerful film about womenhood and some of the problems they face. People call this a chick flick, but is it really? I think guys should watch this film in order to gain a higher appreciation of women. This film is about bonds that will never be forgotten. I'm surprised how such a good movie this drama was. I rate this film 9/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good solid film - well done
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pik923
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Start with the cast - wonderful. From Whoopi Goldberg, Mary Louise Parker, Drew Barrymore - that's just for starters - a solid cast. Each one holds her own and rounds out the character with humor, sensitivity and a truthfulness. The script - good solid script - the director - Herbert Ross - he knew how to tell a story. And don't forget the soundtrack - love the music! Add to that one of the first scripts that looked at AIDS from the eyes of women. Not just a straight woman, but also a gay woman. How the characters both men and women deal with the issue, which is usually for Hollywood and the motion picture world, a male issue (the only other film I can immediately refer to as an AIDS film relating to women is the HBO film GIA). I highly recommend the film for all audiences - including teenagers. It deals with many delicate issues with great warmth, love, trust, humor and truthfulness. Thank you for this little gem!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Funny, sad, so entertaining. A definite must see.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gavin-hoare
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/3/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is my favorite film of all time. It has everything you want in a film. It is funny and has plenty of action throughout. It is also so sad, anyone who doesn't cry must be emotionally retarded. I especially love Mary Jane Parker in this film even though all the actors are great.The film has so many great lines in it too and who would have known Whoopi Goldberg has a decent singing voice. I strongly recommend everyone to watch this. Its just a shame i cant get this on region 2 DVD anywhere so i have to watch it on video which is not great.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A bore
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Gordon-11
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/8/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film is about the friendship of three women who goes onto a road trip, after an accident that goes horribly wrong. I find the film incredibly plain and dull. The characters are not likable, and I do not care much for them. Holly, in particular, is annoying and stupid. The domestic violence part gains her some sympathy, but confessing it to the wrong person is plain silly. As a result, the plot becomes contrived. The way the story is told is plain, with almost no emotional ups and downs. The only thing that holds my interest is Robin's illness, but even that is not so well developed. Her condition could have been a lot more dramatic and touching, but the whole subplot fails to engage or captivate. In short, I find "Boys on the Side" boring. I can only say I am not the target audience of this film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sooooo chick-flick
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    marcslope
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/7/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Count the chick-flick conventions: The revenge on the abusive boyfriend; the three so-different young women bonding; the mother-daughter conflicts; the road trip; the scene where somebody sings "Happy Birthday" to somebody amid much general rejoicing; the adorable baby; the tear-wringing incurable-disease character; etc. It's well-written -- Don Roos, who later wrote the superb screenplay to "The Opposite of Sex," puts more curve on his dialog than most toiling in this genre -- but as with many sisters-united-in-adversity epics, it keeps wanting to yank emotions out of you rather than earn them honestly. The three leads are good, a young Matthew McConnaughey isn't yet annoying, and there are nice turns from Estelle Parsons and Anita Gillette, a Broadway baby decades earlier who matured into a proficient character actress. But Herb Ross is in his take-no-chances mode, and too much of the picture feels programmed and rote.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hit and Miss
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    gcd70
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/2/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Largely a hit and miss comedy-drama, "Boys on the Side" is very melodramatic and not much better than a T.V. series. Helmer Herbert Ross again indulges the 'women's own pic', but this time he produces a movie not only nowhere near the calibre of his dramatically strong "Steel Magnolias", but also not even as interesting as the ordinary Ridley Scott road movie "Thelma and Louise" (there's a clever and apt reference to the ridiculous ending of that severely flawed film in this road movie). The girls in this flick have so many problems it's not funny, just mostly boring. Ross is unable to generate interest in the respective plights of Robin, Jane and Holly, and I for one was left hankering for a regular threesome who would stay on the road. The original screenplay from Don Roos attempts to tackle too many issues (murder, AIDS, single mothers and homosexuality to name a few), and in so doing fails to deal satisfactorily with any of them. Many of the relationship problems that arise are never properly dealt with or resolved. The show gets so weighed down with emotional baggage and unnecessary seriousness that what fun their is, gets lost in all the dreadfully morbid drudgery. Thus the comedy that does exist is drowned along with all the wild shenanigans. Add to this the fact that all the fellas are either schmucks or complete losers, and not only is it obvious the girls want to go it alone for a good reason, but it's also clear that this is an ordinary, forgettable film. Whoopi Goldberg has been infinitely better than this, and though both she and Mary Louise Parker (in a role similar to that in "Fried Green Tomatoes") are competent, we know they're both well below par here. As for Drew Barrymore, she still fails to show any of the promise she did as a young actress, and seems content to flaunt her bod. Though this may serve as a distraction for the men, her pretty looks are no substitute for raw talent, which she really needs to find before she is typecast. Like I said, this is very much hit and miss stuff, but more so the latter. "Boys on the Side" just never successfully influences the emotions, which "Steel Magnolias" did so easily with its quirky, lovable characters and simple theme. At least the trendy rock soundtrack which featured artists like The Cranberries and Annie Lennox saved some face. Saturday, August 5, 1995 - Waverley Pinewood Cinema
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Boys On the Side...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    fierypoeticgirl
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/12/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm sorry, but I did not like "Thelma and Louise." This movie had more depth to it even though it is sort of sappy at times; but still, it was good. Mary-Louise Parker stole the film with her frail health, yet she holds nothing back verbally. She is the one who settles the disputes while everyone else is so mixed up. Imagine that; the strength of a dying woman tying loose ends together before her passing away. During the trial in this movie when Mary's character was a witness for "Holly" played by Drew Barrymore, she was trying to say that women have a special bond that takes place just like men do, yet not as many women are hardly ever quick to judge men when they get together or maybe even assume they are "gay." We all just take it at fact value which is that it's "Boys' night out." Women are still being misunderstood when they remain friends like the three women were in this movie. I found the variety and versatility of characters and situations remarkably memorable. Superb job to everyone.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Boys on the Side
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/1/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film by The Sunshine Boys director Herbert Ross is quite a good drama with very small elements of comedy. Basically lesbian Jane (Whoopi Goldberg) is a night club singer, out of work. AIDS suffering Robin (Mary-Louise Parker) is a quirky real estate agent looking for a ride-share to accompany her to California, this is answered by at first unsure Jane. In Pittsburgh they pick up a third, one-night stand and man loving Holly (Drew Barrymore), escaping a violent and drug-dealing partner. It starts as a road trip, and focuses on reaching understanding, respect, and care for each other. I did trail off in a few places, but when I was paying attention, it was a very pleasant film. Good!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just may be one of the worst movies I've seen...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nomad492
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/12/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You know there is nothing on TV when there are three HBO channels in the hotel and this was the best there was. This is little more than PC story about characters that have no real interest. We have a lesbian, an AIDs patient, and a single pregnant woman who falls in love with an AZ cop. All of this, and there is not an interesting character in the bunch. The one redeeming part. Matthew McConaughey when he still had good hair. Okay, perhaps I'm being too hard. No, I'm not. The Wild Wild West with Will Smith still ranks as the worst movie made in recent memory and this one was not that bad. Well...not quite. Don't waste your time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's Time To Share A Light
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    George Attwood
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/9/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    BOYS ON THE SIDE **** Herbert Ross's last work, 'Boys On The Side' tells a unique, special story of the bonds between three women as they take a cross-country drive, end up in Nevado, and struggle through hardships, progressively developing in their character. Don Roos's screenplay is coherent and strong enough to make the transitions between the story's funny and dramatic moments smooth and generally effective for that matter. It's moral grounds are a bit too liberalized for my taste. Rating System ***** Excellent **** Good *** Fair ** Poor * Bad
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
