<filme>
 <id>
  725
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0109758
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1994
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  O Amor &eacute; Uma Grande Fantasia
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  3.8
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Elliot is going to the island of Eden to live out his submissive fantasies, but inadvertently photographs diamond smugglers at work. Smugglers, and detectives, follow him to the island, ... &nbsp;&raquo;
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Elliot is going to the island of Eden to live out his submissive fantasies, but inadvertently photographs diamond smugglers at work. Smugglers, and detectives, follow him to the island, where they try to retrieve the film. Elliot begins falling in love with Lisa, the head mistress of the island, and Lisa must evaluate her feelings about Elliot and her own motivations.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Thriller
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   island
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   love
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   mistress
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   smuggler
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   diamond
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Garry Marshall
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Anne Rice
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Deborah Amelon
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Dana Delany
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Dan Aykroyd
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Rosie O'Donnell
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Neither erotic nor funny - call trade descriptions!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mr_PCM
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Irritating voiceovers, amateur acting, corny dialogue that a porn star would be embarrassed to deliver, racial stereotypes, gratuitous nudity, hazy dream-like flashbacks, a performance by Rosie O'Donnell and Dan Aykroyd with a moustache - all the ingredients for a Razzie award-winning film - and win it did! Coupled with an overly long plot that regularly goes MIA, and drags when it does show up for duty, 1994's Exit to Eden makes notable turkey Gigli seem as romantic as Brief Encounte! It's all so comically bad it feels like it should be in German - a la the old late night movies found in the higher channel numbers in the early days of satellite TV. In the right hands, or with a more daring director or provocative censor, this film set in a holiday resort run by a dominatrix could have been quite interesting, but unfortunately tiptoes around anything more controversial than an occasional tap with a hairbrush. The laughable, risible plot involves a pair of jewel thieves and a pair of cops going undercover at a BDSM resort to retrieve a film canister containing photos of a jewel robbery, while various couples visualise and act out their assorted TV-friendly fantasies. That's pretty much all that is needed. It's hard to know what aspect of the film drags it down the most, but perennially bad actress Rosie O'Donnell probably takes the...er....Oscar! Her awful dialogue delivery, grating voice-over, and even her harsh New York accent for an LA cop is grating. Meanwhile the plot is almost incidental to the film, serving seemingly only as a way to string a few soft bondage scenes and awkward interactions together, and the reason for why the cops and thieves are there is largely forgotten for large portions of the film. But the scenes aren't particularly arousing enough for the film to be much of an erotic thriller, and the story isn't even remotely gripping enough to fulfil the thriller aspect either. Meanwhile Dan Aykroyd's hammy delivery, while seemingly perfect for Ghostbusters, seems to merely add to the film's overall corniness. When the plot finally does make a return to the film, it drags the already-meandering pace of the film down to an absolute crawl, and by the time the film approaches its 'climax' (and never was a term so inaccurate on so many levels) after nearly 2 hours, a life of celibacy may suddenly have some appeal. Ask for a refund of both your time and money. Dire.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very good show
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mckenzie2467-908-385498
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Exit To Eden was a wonderful, fun movie to watch. Dana Delaney was a stunning, wonderfully beautiful actress to watch, capturing your heart easily in her role. She was a real sweetheart, although it may be hard to envision a career Dominatrix acting as she did. Eliot was great, everyone did a wonderful job entertaining us with A). A good story, and B). Mildly erotic entertainment. This movie was a fairly predictable cop-drama with some erotic entertainment and a love story kicked in for good measure. Remember, we are watching TV, that thing you do because you want to go away for a couple of hours and feel good. Dan Ackroyd was good (although his partner definitely got the better deal :) ) Rosie O' Donnell kept me going, 'Euuuuggghhhh' through most of the movie, although she was funny... Bottom line, if you want HOT erotica, go somewhere else. If you want mild erotica and want to have fun for a couple of hours, if you want to get away for a while, take the Exit To Eden. It's a fun trip.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Call me crazy but I like this!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Wayne Malin (wwaayynnee51@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Photographer Elliot Slater (Paul Mercurio) is going to Eden--an island devoted to people who like S&M and BDMS. He's going to live out his dream as being a submissive man who loves being spanked. He accidentally photographs a vicious criminal named Omar (Stuart Wilson) getting drugs. Omar and helper Nina (Iman) follow Elliot to the island to get the film--and kill him. Police officers Sheila (Rosie O'Donnell) and Fred (Dan Aykroyd) are in hot pursuit. On the island the head--Mistress Lisa (Dan Delany)--takes it upon herself to "train Elliot--and starts falling in love which she has vowed never to do. This is an adaptation (a VERY loose one) of an Anne Rice book that is just about sex, bondage, S&M and the love between Elliot and Lisa. There's no stupid drug story. It's a very good and very adult book. The movie basically sanitizes the book a great deal (everyone's nude in the book--not here), throws the insights into sex out the window and adds nonstop wisecracks from O'Donnell. Now, I like O'Donnell and some of her lines ARE funny but the movie's tone keeps zigzagging between comedy, suspense, love and nudity. It's all over the place and never finds a comfortable footing. Also Iman is (to put it mildly) a terrible actress. Still I really like this! The island locale is just beautiful (it was shot in Hawaii) and the resort itself is incredible. There's plenty of casual female nudity--even Delany has a full frontal nude shot! There is some male nudity but mostly back views. Supposedly there were full frontal shots of Mercurio but they had to cut them or they would have gotten an X rating. That doesn't make a bit of sense...but the ratings board always is afraid of male nudity. Still, there are a lot of hunky guys wandering around wearing next to nothing. Also Paul Mercurio has a fantastic butt and you get plenty of views of it! In terms of acting this is pretty good. Mercurio struggles with his accent (it's half-Australian, half-American) but he's handsome, in good shape and has no problem in strutting around half-naked. His acting is good too:) Delany looks incredible and gives an excellent performance as a dominatrix. O'Donnell is throwing off jokes left and right. Some are funny and she does it so casually it makes them even funnier. Aykroyd however is wasted. Also the movie is a little bit too long. Still this is worth seeing for the beautiful locations, the casual nudity, some truly funny bits and acting. If you're easily offended by frank talk of S&M and nudity stay FAR away. A huge bomb when it came out but this (hopefully) might be rediscovered some day. There's also a cute joke at the very end of the closing credits. I give this an 8.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This Flick is Gross
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    writerasfilmcritic
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/11/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This pile of dung is one of the worst movies I've ever sat through. As others have pointed out, the only thing in it worth seeing is a momentary glimpse of Dana Delaney totally nude, including her luxuriant growth of pubic hair, obviously shot back in the days before Generation X began dominating the media with their peculiar aversion to anything natural, especially hair. Still, her brief nude scene is not enough for this piece of drek to find a permanent slot in your video library even if you got it for free. That Aussie jerk ruined it from the first moment he appeared on screen. Whoever gave him the idea that he could act, that he understood the first thing about photography, that his "croc hunter" accent was somehow cool, or that his big fat ass was sexy and ought to be shoved in our faces for an hour and a half? If you're not a woman or hopelessly gay, a movie where beefcake men run around in thongs is what we used to call a real gross-out. Admittedly, there were a handful of scenes containing cute, half-naked babes that deserved a second look, but otherwise, this horrible excuse for cinema was a groan from start to finish, actually worse than a bad "Loveboat" episode, if that is possible. Rosie O'Donnel wasn't exactly good in it but she was far from its worst feature, and that alone ought to tell you something. When she kissed her "submissive" at the end, she was far more convincing as a straight woman than he was as a straight man. Put another way, whoever had the idea to pair a dike with an obvious fairy and call it erotic ought to have their heads examined. I had to ask my old lady three or four separate times if anyone saw her take this piece of tripe from the library sale rack and am embarrassed we watched the whole thing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Really funny film using nudity gracefully and frequently.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jcannon-13
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have looked at this movie at least forty times. It is sheer pleasure. Lots of laughs. I enjoyed seeing Dana Delaaney in a very different role than I have usually seen her. Paul Mercurio too I had only seen before in his profession as a dancer. He is a superb dancer. At first I was surprised at the extent of nudity, but then realized, how else could they depict the island. Both Dana and Paul have great looking bodies and get to show them off throughout the movie. Paul's outstanding butt is highlighted in a scene between the two of them. Clever was the scene involving the buttered croissants. Really good flick!!! JFC
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Views about Exit to Eden
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RichieLovesGodHisFather
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/4/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When Tom Snyder had his talk show on cable years ago,they did a segment on this movie a lot of couples approved of it.Some were saying it helped their romance,as well as their relationships.But the makers of this movie failed to overlook something here.God Himself,and The written facts in the bible Worship God only.Mistresses,have become a world wide network.Many of them proclaiming themselves goddesses and demand to be worshiped.Gods 1st Commandment,Thou Shalt Not Have No Other gods Before Me.Also pertains to false gods,false goddesses,and so many who expect to be worshiped.Even in history former figures like Zeus,Apollo,Venus Athena and the list goes on.All of these so called gods,goddesses,and all those who expect to be worshiped have one thing in common.They are all mortal human beings,as was Zeus and so many others.When revelation finally does come,we may not be here too witness it It can happen a hundred years from now,nobody knows the exact time but God Himself.God is slow to anger and quick to forgive,but even churches rarely mention that Our God is a Jealous God.I doubt it I will see revelation in my life time,but if it come to pass,I'd love too see God set His world straight on His Ten Commandments,most especially His 1st Commandent.Amen
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    film making at it's most masochistic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Doug Galecawitz (dougg@evilnet.net)
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/1/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    i saw this film many years ago and have since mostly tried to block it out the memories of it. Unfortunately during a marathon session of psychotherapy this pile molten rat dung came to light, and i now blame it for ALL my social behavioral problems. To complain about acting, plot, direction, screen writing, et cetera, would completely miss the point and the central tragedy surrounding this film. At some point in time somebody thought it was a decent and sell-able idea to cut a handsome check to dan akroyrd (god bless him for elwood) and rosie o'donnell to put on bondage gear and strut around nude with bad wisecracks for the better part of a ninety minute movie. I'm not terribly original in my reviews of movies (nor anything in this life) and i don't think i'm the first in IMDb to point it out but there is a level of true masochism in casting photogenically impaired stars to star in a motion picture about sado-masochism and bondage. The irony (intended or not) can't be lost on people. This is truly one of the most awful things committed to film since Pink Flamingoes, which could always fall back on the cynical train wreck view of film as a reason to watch. No, someone took this seriously and perpetrated it in cold blood. PS Dana Delaney is kinda hot....... 2 out of ten only because there is no zero and i was too lazy to make it to one....
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Is it honestly trying to be an erotic comedy?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moonspinner55
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/10/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Completely misbegotten adaptation of Anne Rice's book about two cops (Dan Aykroyd and Rosie O'Donnell, a screen-teaming which should've been a hoot) working undercover at an S&M resort to capture a ring of crooks. Garry Marshall directed in a shamefully sloppy manner, without a clue as to how a general audience would feel about this kind of material; his narrative is so clogged with smarmy activity and failed gimmicks (like a voice-over from O'Donnell that is both unfunny and unnecessary) that the picture self-destructs even before the opening credits have finished! Highly unpleasant dud was a critical and commercial turkey, although O'Donnell has gotten mileage out of it by making "Exit to Eden" jokes at her own expense.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What you don't know..... is
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mistressladynite
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/10/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Exit to Eden.. gets a BUM rap from people that are narrow minded and do not have a clue what the movie was really about!! The "Lifestyle" that this movie was written about really exists. Maybe NOT to the point of a awesome island as in the movie, but there are a LARGE group of people out there in the world that LIVE that style of life. Exit to Eden touched on MANY true facts about the "lifestyle" and did a good job. It straight forwardly explained what the different roles are in the life of Dominates and submissives. Inside EVERYONE is a desire to be either one or the other. Some act out on it, others don't. (because they are afraid to!!) The "lifestyle" is not about sex, its about "power exchange" All of this was addressed in the movie. Those of you that do not understand this, and were looking for more "entertainment" were so busy wanting to be amused, that they missed the whole point of the movie. It was nice to see something so "vanilla" to come out and TRY to explain what others already know. GREAT movie.. Well done, funny, serious, and pretty complete, especially since they were trying to stay within the "vanilla" realm. NOT everything in the movie was "true to form" of the "lifestyle" but it sure touched a lot of things that were. Secretary was another good movie that portrays "the lifestyle". It was more real to life than you would imagine. So those of you that are naysayers.. don't you dare watch THAT one.. hahah it would give you something to "complain" about. Mistress Ladynite
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Tries to hard to be too much
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wnterstar
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/5/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I enjoyed watching this movie, even though I know it's not a great movie. I thought the acting was good, and the island of Eden was gorgeous. The erotic scenes were a mixed bag...there were a couple that were extremely erotic (got some good ideas there!) but others were Luke-warm at best. I think what kept this movie from being a good movie is that it was trying to be all things to everyone. It was a crime story, a comedy, an erotic sexcapade (sort of) and a romance. It also had too many morals to it (it's OK to explore your wild side, it's OK to relinquish control in certain situations, and the ever-popular love conquers everything). I haven't read this book (written by Anne Rice under the pseudonym of Anne Rampling) but I have read other erotica by her and I'm sure the book HAS to be better!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Neither erotic nor funny - call trade descriptions!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mr_PCM
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Irritating voiceovers, amateur acting, corny dialogue that a porn star would be embarrassed to deliver, racial stereotypes, gratuitous nudity, hazy dream-like flashbacks, a performance by Rosie O'Donnell and Dan Aykroyd with a moustache - all the ingredients for a Razzie award-winning film - and win it did! Coupled with an overly long plot that regularly goes MIA, and drags when it does show up for duty, 1994's Exit to Eden makes notable turkey Gigli seem as romantic as Brief Encounte! It's all so comically bad it feels like it should be in German - a la the old late night movies found in the higher channel numbers in the early days of satellite TV. In the right hands, or with a more daring director or provocative censor, this film set in a holiday resort run by a dominatrix could have been quite interesting, but unfortunately tiptoes around anything more controversial than an occasional tap with a hairbrush. The laughable, risible plot involves a pair of jewel thieves and a pair of cops going undercover at a BDSM resort to retrieve a film canister containing photos of a jewel robbery, while various couples visualise and act out their assorted TV-friendly fantasies. That's pretty much all that is needed. It's hard to know what aspect of the film drags it down the most, but perennially bad actress Rosie O'Donnell probably takes the...er....Oscar! Her awful dialogue delivery, grating voice-over, and even her harsh New York accent for an LA cop is grating. Meanwhile the plot is almost incidental to the film, serving seemingly only as a way to string a few soft bondage scenes and awkward interactions together, and the reason for why the cops and thieves are there is largely forgotten for large portions of the film. But the scenes aren't particularly arousing enough for the film to be much of an erotic thriller, and the story isn't even remotely gripping enough to fulfil the thriller aspect either. Meanwhile Dan Aykroyd's hammy delivery, while seemingly perfect for Ghostbusters, seems to merely add to the film's overall corniness. When the plot finally does make a return to the film, it drags the already-meandering pace of the film down to an absolute crawl, and by the time the film approaches its 'climax' (and never was a term so inaccurate on so many levels) after nearly 2 hours, a life of celibacy may suddenly have some appeal. Ask for a refund of both your time and money. Dire.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very good show
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mckenzie2467-908-385498
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Exit To Eden was a wonderful, fun movie to watch. Dana Delaney was a stunning, wonderfully beautiful actress to watch, capturing your heart easily in her role. She was a real sweetheart, although it may be hard to envision a career Dominatrix acting as she did. Eliot was great, everyone did a wonderful job entertaining us with A). A good story, and B). Mildly erotic entertainment. This movie was a fairly predictable cop-drama with some erotic entertainment and a love story kicked in for good measure. Remember, we are watching TV, that thing you do because you want to go away for a couple of hours and feel good. Dan Ackroyd was good (although his partner definitely got the better deal :) ) Rosie O' Donnell kept me going, 'Euuuuggghhhh' through most of the movie, although she was funny... Bottom line, if you want HOT erotica, go somewhere else. If you want mild erotica and want to have fun for a couple of hours, if you want to get away for a while, take the Exit To Eden. It's a fun trip.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Call me crazy but I like this!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Wayne Malin (wwaayynnee51@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Photographer Elliot Slater (Paul Mercurio) is going to Eden--an island devoted to people who like S&M and BDMS. He's going to live out his dream as being a submissive man who loves being spanked. He accidentally photographs a vicious criminal named Omar (Stuart Wilson) getting drugs. Omar and helper Nina (Iman) follow Elliot to the island to get the film--and kill him. Police officers Sheila (Rosie O'Donnell) and Fred (Dan Aykroyd) are in hot pursuit. On the island the head--Mistress Lisa (Dan Delany)--takes it upon herself to "train Elliot--and starts falling in love which she has vowed never to do. This is an adaptation (a VERY loose one) of an Anne Rice book that is just about sex, bondage, S&M and the love between Elliot and Lisa. There's no stupid drug story. It's a very good and very adult book. The movie basically sanitizes the book a great deal (everyone's nude in the book--not here), throws the insights into sex out the window and adds nonstop wisecracks from O'Donnell. Now, I like O'Donnell and some of her lines ARE funny but the movie's tone keeps zigzagging between comedy, suspense, love and nudity. It's all over the place and never finds a comfortable footing. Also Iman is (to put it mildly) a terrible actress. Still I really like this! The island locale is just beautiful (it was shot in Hawaii) and the resort itself is incredible. There's plenty of casual female nudity--even Delany has a full frontal nude shot! There is some male nudity but mostly back views. Supposedly there were full frontal shots of Mercurio but they had to cut them or they would have gotten an X rating. That doesn't make a bit of sense...but the ratings board always is afraid of male nudity. Still, there are a lot of hunky guys wandering around wearing next to nothing. Also Paul Mercurio has a fantastic butt and you get plenty of views of it! In terms of acting this is pretty good. Mercurio struggles with his accent (it's half-Australian, half-American) but he's handsome, in good shape and has no problem in strutting around half-naked. His acting is good too:) Delany looks incredible and gives an excellent performance as a dominatrix. O'Donnell is throwing off jokes left and right. Some are funny and she does it so casually it makes them even funnier. Aykroyd however is wasted. Also the movie is a little bit too long. Still this is worth seeing for the beautiful locations, the casual nudity, some truly funny bits and acting. If you're easily offended by frank talk of S&M and nudity stay FAR away. A huge bomb when it came out but this (hopefully) might be rediscovered some day. There's also a cute joke at the very end of the closing credits. I give this an 8.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This Flick is Gross
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    writerasfilmcritic
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/11/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This pile of dung is one of the worst movies I've ever sat through. As others have pointed out, the only thing in it worth seeing is a momentary glimpse of Dana Delaney totally nude, including her luxuriant growth of pubic hair, obviously shot back in the days before Generation X began dominating the media with their peculiar aversion to anything natural, especially hair. Still, her brief nude scene is not enough for this piece of drek to find a permanent slot in your video library even if you got it for free. That Aussie jerk ruined it from the first moment he appeared on screen. Whoever gave him the idea that he could act, that he understood the first thing about photography, that his "croc hunter" accent was somehow cool, or that his big fat ass was sexy and ought to be shoved in our faces for an hour and a half? If you're not a woman or hopelessly gay, a movie where beefcake men run around in thongs is what we used to call a real gross-out. Admittedly, there were a handful of scenes containing cute, half-naked babes that deserved a second look, but otherwise, this horrible excuse for cinema was a groan from start to finish, actually worse than a bad "Loveboat" episode, if that is possible. Rosie O'Donnel wasn't exactly good in it but she was far from its worst feature, and that alone ought to tell you something. When she kissed her "submissive" at the end, she was far more convincing as a straight woman than he was as a straight man. Put another way, whoever had the idea to pair a dike with an obvious fairy and call it erotic ought to have their heads examined. I had to ask my old lady three or four separate times if anyone saw her take this piece of tripe from the library sale rack and am embarrassed we watched the whole thing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Really funny film using nudity gracefully and frequently.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jcannon-13
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have looked at this movie at least forty times. It is sheer pleasure. Lots of laughs. I enjoyed seeing Dana Delaaney in a very different role than I have usually seen her. Paul Mercurio too I had only seen before in his profession as a dancer. He is a superb dancer. At first I was surprised at the extent of nudity, but then realized, how else could they depict the island. Both Dana and Paul have great looking bodies and get to show them off throughout the movie. Paul's outstanding butt is highlighted in a scene between the two of them. Clever was the scene involving the buttered croissants. Really good flick!!! JFC
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Views about Exit to Eden
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RichieLovesGodHisFather
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/4/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When Tom Snyder had his talk show on cable years ago,they did a segment on this movie a lot of couples approved of it.Some were saying it helped their romance,as well as their relationships.But the makers of this movie failed to overlook something here.God Himself,and The written facts in the bible Worship God only.Mistresses,have become a world wide network.Many of them proclaiming themselves goddesses and demand to be worshiped.Gods 1st Commandment,Thou Shalt Not Have No Other gods Before Me.Also pertains to false gods,false goddesses,and so many who expect to be worshiped.Even in history former figures like Zeus,Apollo,Venus Athena and the list goes on.All of these so called gods,goddesses,and all those who expect to be worshiped have one thing in common.They are all mortal human beings,as was Zeus and so many others.When revelation finally does come,we may not be here too witness it It can happen a hundred years from now,nobody knows the exact time but God Himself.God is slow to anger and quick to forgive,but even churches rarely mention that Our God is a Jealous God.I doubt it I will see revelation in my life time,but if it come to pass,I'd love too see God set His world straight on His Ten Commandments,most especially His 1st Commandent.Amen
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    film making at it's most masochistic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Doug Galecawitz (dougg@evilnet.net)
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/1/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    i saw this film many years ago and have since mostly tried to block it out the memories of it. Unfortunately during a marathon session of psychotherapy this pile molten rat dung came to light, and i now blame it for ALL my social behavioral problems. To complain about acting, plot, direction, screen writing, et cetera, would completely miss the point and the central tragedy surrounding this film. At some point in time somebody thought it was a decent and sell-able idea to cut a handsome check to dan akroyrd (god bless him for elwood) and rosie o'donnell to put on bondage gear and strut around nude with bad wisecracks for the better part of a ninety minute movie. I'm not terribly original in my reviews of movies (nor anything in this life) and i don't think i'm the first in IMDb to point it out but there is a level of true masochism in casting photogenically impaired stars to star in a motion picture about sado-masochism and bondage. The irony (intended or not) can't be lost on people. This is truly one of the most awful things committed to film since Pink Flamingoes, which could always fall back on the cynical train wreck view of film as a reason to watch. No, someone took this seriously and perpetrated it in cold blood. PS Dana Delaney is kinda hot....... 2 out of ten only because there is no zero and i was too lazy to make it to one....
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Is it honestly trying to be an erotic comedy?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moonspinner55
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/10/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Completely misbegotten adaptation of Anne Rice's book about two cops (Dan Aykroyd and Rosie O'Donnell, a screen-teaming which should've been a hoot) working undercover at an S&M resort to capture a ring of crooks. Garry Marshall directed in a shamefully sloppy manner, without a clue as to how a general audience would feel about this kind of material; his narrative is so clogged with smarmy activity and failed gimmicks (like a voice-over from O'Donnell that is both unfunny and unnecessary) that the picture self-destructs even before the opening credits have finished! Highly unpleasant dud was a critical and commercial turkey, although O'Donnell has gotten mileage out of it by making "Exit to Eden" jokes at her own expense.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What you don't know..... is
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mistressladynite
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/10/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Exit to Eden.. gets a BUM rap from people that are narrow minded and do not have a clue what the movie was really about!! The "Lifestyle" that this movie was written about really exists. Maybe NOT to the point of a awesome island as in the movie, but there are a LARGE group of people out there in the world that LIVE that style of life. Exit to Eden touched on MANY true facts about the "lifestyle" and did a good job. It straight forwardly explained what the different roles are in the life of Dominates and submissives. Inside EVERYONE is a desire to be either one or the other. Some act out on it, others don't. (because they are afraid to!!) The "lifestyle" is not about sex, its about "power exchange" All of this was addressed in the movie. Those of you that do not understand this, and were looking for more "entertainment" were so busy wanting to be amused, that they missed the whole point of the movie. It was nice to see something so "vanilla" to come out and TRY to explain what others already know. GREAT movie.. Well done, funny, serious, and pretty complete, especially since they were trying to stay within the "vanilla" realm. NOT everything in the movie was "true to form" of the "lifestyle" but it sure touched a lot of things that were. Secretary was another good movie that portrays "the lifestyle". It was more real to life than you would imagine. So those of you that are naysayers.. don't you dare watch THAT one.. hahah it would give you something to "complain" about. Mistress Ladynite
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Tries to hard to be too much
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wnterstar
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/5/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I enjoyed watching this movie, even though I know it's not a great movie. I thought the acting was good, and the island of Eden was gorgeous. The erotic scenes were a mixed bag...there were a couple that were extremely erotic (got some good ideas there!) but others were Luke-warm at best. I think what kept this movie from being a good movie is that it was trying to be all things to everyone. It was a crime story, a comedy, an erotic sexcapade (sort of) and a romance. It also had too many morals to it (it's OK to explore your wild side, it's OK to relinquish control in certain situations, and the ever-popular love conquers everything). I haven't read this book (written by Anne Rice under the pseudonym of Anne Rampling) but I have read other erotica by her and I'm sure the book HAS to be better!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Neither erotic nor funny - call trade descriptions!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mr_PCM
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Irritating voiceovers, amateur acting, corny dialogue that a porn star would be embarrassed to deliver, racial stereotypes, gratuitous nudity, hazy dream-like flashbacks, a performance by Rosie O'Donnell and Dan Aykroyd with a moustache - all the ingredients for a Razzie award-winning film - and win it did! Coupled with an overly long plot that regularly goes MIA, and drags when it does show up for duty, 1994's Exit to Eden makes notable turkey Gigli seem as romantic as Brief Encounte! It's all so comically bad it feels like it should be in German - a la the old late night movies found in the higher channel numbers in the early days of satellite TV. In the right hands, or with a more daring director or provocative censor, this film set in a holiday resort run by a dominatrix could have been quite interesting, but unfortunately tiptoes around anything more controversial than an occasional tap with a hairbrush. The laughable, risible plot involves a pair of jewel thieves and a pair of cops going undercover at a BDSM resort to retrieve a film canister containing photos of a jewel robbery, while various couples visualise and act out their assorted TV-friendly fantasies. That's pretty much all that is needed. It's hard to know what aspect of the film drags it down the most, but perennially bad actress Rosie O'Donnell probably takes the...er....Oscar! Her awful dialogue delivery, grating voice-over, and even her harsh New York accent for an LA cop is grating. Meanwhile the plot is almost incidental to the film, serving seemingly only as a way to string a few soft bondage scenes and awkward interactions together, and the reason for why the cops and thieves are there is largely forgotten for large portions of the film. But the scenes aren't particularly arousing enough for the film to be much of an erotic thriller, and the story isn't even remotely gripping enough to fulfil the thriller aspect either. Meanwhile Dan Aykroyd's hammy delivery, while seemingly perfect for Ghostbusters, seems to merely add to the film's overall corniness. When the plot finally does make a return to the film, it drags the already-meandering pace of the film down to an absolute crawl, and by the time the film approaches its 'climax' (and never was a term so inaccurate on so many levels) after nearly 2 hours, a life of celibacy may suddenly have some appeal. Ask for a refund of both your time and money. Dire.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very good show
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mckenzie2467-908-385498
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Exit To Eden was a wonderful, fun movie to watch. Dana Delaney was a stunning, wonderfully beautiful actress to watch, capturing your heart easily in her role. She was a real sweetheart, although it may be hard to envision a career Dominatrix acting as she did. Eliot was great, everyone did a wonderful job entertaining us with A). A good story, and B). Mildly erotic entertainment. This movie was a fairly predictable cop-drama with some erotic entertainment and a love story kicked in for good measure. Remember, we are watching TV, that thing you do because you want to go away for a couple of hours and feel good. Dan Ackroyd was good (although his partner definitely got the better deal :) ) Rosie O' Donnell kept me going, 'Euuuuggghhhh' through most of the movie, although she was funny... Bottom line, if you want HOT erotica, go somewhere else. If you want mild erotica and want to have fun for a couple of hours, if you want to get away for a while, take the Exit To Eden. It's a fun trip.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Call me crazy but I like this!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Wayne Malin (wwaayynnee51@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Photographer Elliot Slater (Paul Mercurio) is going to Eden--an island devoted to people who like S&M and BDMS. He's going to live out his dream as being a submissive man who loves being spanked. He accidentally photographs a vicious criminal named Omar (Stuart Wilson) getting drugs. Omar and helper Nina (Iman) follow Elliot to the island to get the film--and kill him. Police officers Sheila (Rosie O'Donnell) and Fred (Dan Aykroyd) are in hot pursuit. On the island the head--Mistress Lisa (Dan Delany)--takes it upon herself to "train Elliot--and starts falling in love which she has vowed never to do. This is an adaptation (a VERY loose one) of an Anne Rice book that is just about sex, bondage, S&M and the love between Elliot and Lisa. There's no stupid drug story. It's a very good and very adult book. The movie basically sanitizes the book a great deal (everyone's nude in the book--not here), throws the insights into sex out the window and adds nonstop wisecracks from O'Donnell. Now, I like O'Donnell and some of her lines ARE funny but the movie's tone keeps zigzagging between comedy, suspense, love and nudity. It's all over the place and never finds a comfortable footing. Also Iman is (to put it mildly) a terrible actress. Still I really like this! The island locale is just beautiful (it was shot in Hawaii) and the resort itself is incredible. There's plenty of casual female nudity--even Delany has a full frontal nude shot! There is some male nudity but mostly back views. Supposedly there were full frontal shots of Mercurio but they had to cut them or they would have gotten an X rating. That doesn't make a bit of sense...but the ratings board always is afraid of male nudity. Still, there are a lot of hunky guys wandering around wearing next to nothing. Also Paul Mercurio has a fantastic butt and you get plenty of views of it! In terms of acting this is pretty good. Mercurio struggles with his accent (it's half-Australian, half-American) but he's handsome, in good shape and has no problem in strutting around half-naked. His acting is good too:) Delany looks incredible and gives an excellent performance as a dominatrix. O'Donnell is throwing off jokes left and right. Some are funny and she does it so casually it makes them even funnier. Aykroyd however is wasted. Also the movie is a little bit too long. Still this is worth seeing for the beautiful locations, the casual nudity, some truly funny bits and acting. If you're easily offended by frank talk of S&M and nudity stay FAR away. A huge bomb when it came out but this (hopefully) might be rediscovered some day. There's also a cute joke at the very end of the closing credits. I give this an 8.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This Flick is Gross
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    writerasfilmcritic
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/11/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This pile of dung is one of the worst movies I've ever sat through. As others have pointed out, the only thing in it worth seeing is a momentary glimpse of Dana Delaney totally nude, including her luxuriant growth of pubic hair, obviously shot back in the days before Generation X began dominating the media with their peculiar aversion to anything natural, especially hair. Still, her brief nude scene is not enough for this piece of drek to find a permanent slot in your video library even if you got it for free. That Aussie jerk ruined it from the first moment he appeared on screen. Whoever gave him the idea that he could act, that he understood the first thing about photography, that his "croc hunter" accent was somehow cool, or that his big fat ass was sexy and ought to be shoved in our faces for an hour and a half? If you're not a woman or hopelessly gay, a movie where beefcake men run around in thongs is what we used to call a real gross-out. Admittedly, there were a handful of scenes containing cute, half-naked babes that deserved a second look, but otherwise, this horrible excuse for cinema was a groan from start to finish, actually worse than a bad "Loveboat" episode, if that is possible. Rosie O'Donnel wasn't exactly good in it but she was far from its worst feature, and that alone ought to tell you something. When she kissed her "submissive" at the end, she was far more convincing as a straight woman than he was as a straight man. Put another way, whoever had the idea to pair a dike with an obvious fairy and call it erotic ought to have their heads examined. I had to ask my old lady three or four separate times if anyone saw her take this piece of tripe from the library sale rack and am embarrassed we watched the whole thing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Really funny film using nudity gracefully and frequently.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jcannon-13
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have looked at this movie at least forty times. It is sheer pleasure. Lots of laughs. I enjoyed seeing Dana Delaaney in a very different role than I have usually seen her. Paul Mercurio too I had only seen before in his profession as a dancer. He is a superb dancer. At first I was surprised at the extent of nudity, but then realized, how else could they depict the island. Both Dana and Paul have great looking bodies and get to show them off throughout the movie. Paul's outstanding butt is highlighted in a scene between the two of them. Clever was the scene involving the buttered croissants. Really good flick!!! JFC
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Views about Exit to Eden
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RichieLovesGodHisFather
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/4/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When Tom Snyder had his talk show on cable years ago,they did a segment on this movie a lot of couples approved of it.Some were saying it helped their romance,as well as their relationships.But the makers of this movie failed to overlook something here.God Himself,and The written facts in the bible Worship God only.Mistresses,have become a world wide network.Many of them proclaiming themselves goddesses and demand to be worshiped.Gods 1st Commandment,Thou Shalt Not Have No Other gods Before Me.Also pertains to false gods,false goddesses,and so many who expect to be worshiped.Even in history former figures like Zeus,Apollo,Venus Athena and the list goes on.All of these so called gods,goddesses,and all those who expect to be worshiped have one thing in common.They are all mortal human beings,as was Zeus and so many others.When revelation finally does come,we may not be here too witness it It can happen a hundred years from now,nobody knows the exact time but God Himself.God is slow to anger and quick to forgive,but even churches rarely mention that Our God is a Jealous God.I doubt it I will see revelation in my life time,but if it come to pass,I'd love too see God set His world straight on His Ten Commandments,most especially His 1st Commandent.Amen
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    film making at it's most masochistic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Doug Galecawitz (dougg@evilnet.net)
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/1/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    i saw this film many years ago and have since mostly tried to block it out the memories of it. Unfortunately during a marathon session of psychotherapy this pile molten rat dung came to light, and i now blame it for ALL my social behavioral problems. To complain about acting, plot, direction, screen writing, et cetera, would completely miss the point and the central tragedy surrounding this film. At some point in time somebody thought it was a decent and sell-able idea to cut a handsome check to dan akroyrd (god bless him for elwood) and rosie o'donnell to put on bondage gear and strut around nude with bad wisecracks for the better part of a ninety minute movie. I'm not terribly original in my reviews of movies (nor anything in this life) and i don't think i'm the first in IMDb to point it out but there is a level of true masochism in casting photogenically impaired stars to star in a motion picture about sado-masochism and bondage. The irony (intended or not) can't be lost on people. This is truly one of the most awful things committed to film since Pink Flamingoes, which could always fall back on the cynical train wreck view of film as a reason to watch. No, someone took this seriously and perpetrated it in cold blood. PS Dana Delaney is kinda hot....... 2 out of ten only because there is no zero and i was too lazy to make it to one....
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Is it honestly trying to be an erotic comedy?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moonspinner55
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/10/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Completely misbegotten adaptation of Anne Rice's book about two cops (Dan Aykroyd and Rosie O'Donnell, a screen-teaming which should've been a hoot) working undercover at an S&M resort to capture a ring of crooks. Garry Marshall directed in a shamefully sloppy manner, without a clue as to how a general audience would feel about this kind of material; his narrative is so clogged with smarmy activity and failed gimmicks (like a voice-over from O'Donnell that is both unfunny and unnecessary) that the picture self-destructs even before the opening credits have finished! Highly unpleasant dud was a critical and commercial turkey, although O'Donnell has gotten mileage out of it by making "Exit to Eden" jokes at her own expense.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What you don't know..... is
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mistressladynite
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/10/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Exit to Eden.. gets a BUM rap from people that are narrow minded and do not have a clue what the movie was really about!! The "Lifestyle" that this movie was written about really exists. Maybe NOT to the point of a awesome island as in the movie, but there are a LARGE group of people out there in the world that LIVE that style of life. Exit to Eden touched on MANY true facts about the "lifestyle" and did a good job. It straight forwardly explained what the different roles are in the life of Dominates and submissives. Inside EVERYONE is a desire to be either one or the other. Some act out on it, others don't. (because they are afraid to!!) The "lifestyle" is not about sex, its about "power exchange" All of this was addressed in the movie. Those of you that do not understand this, and were looking for more "entertainment" were so busy wanting to be amused, that they missed the whole point of the movie. It was nice to see something so "vanilla" to come out and TRY to explain what others already know. GREAT movie.. Well done, funny, serious, and pretty complete, especially since they were trying to stay within the "vanilla" realm. NOT everything in the movie was "true to form" of the "lifestyle" but it sure touched a lot of things that were. Secretary was another good movie that portrays "the lifestyle". It was more real to life than you would imagine. So those of you that are naysayers.. don't you dare watch THAT one.. hahah it would give you something to "complain" about. Mistress Ladynite
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Tries to hard to be too much
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wnterstar
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/5/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I enjoyed watching this movie, even though I know it's not a great movie. I thought the acting was good, and the island of Eden was gorgeous. The erotic scenes were a mixed bag...there were a couple that were extremely erotic (got some good ideas there!) but others were Luke-warm at best. I think what kept this movie from being a good movie is that it was trying to be all things to everyone. It was a crime story, a comedy, an erotic sexcapade (sort of) and a romance. It also had too many morals to it (it's OK to explore your wild side, it's OK to relinquish control in certain situations, and the ever-popular love conquers everything). I haven't read this book (written by Anne Rice under the pseudonym of Anne Rampling) but I have read other erotica by her and I'm sure the book HAS to be better!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Neither erotic nor funny - call trade descriptions!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mr_PCM
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Irritating voiceovers, amateur acting, corny dialogue that a porn star would be embarrassed to deliver, racial stereotypes, gratuitous nudity, hazy dream-like flashbacks, a performance by Rosie O'Donnell and Dan Aykroyd with a moustache - all the ingredients for a Razzie award-winning film - and win it did! Coupled with an overly long plot that regularly goes MIA, and drags when it does show up for duty, 1994's Exit to Eden makes notable turkey Gigli seem as romantic as Brief Encounte! It's all so comically bad it feels like it should be in German - a la the old late night movies found in the higher channel numbers in the early days of satellite TV. In the right hands, or with a more daring director or provocative censor, this film set in a holiday resort run by a dominatrix could have been quite interesting, but unfortunately tiptoes around anything more controversial than an occasional tap with a hairbrush. The laughable, risible plot involves a pair of jewel thieves and a pair of cops going undercover at a BDSM resort to retrieve a film canister containing photos of a jewel robbery, while various couples visualise and act out their assorted TV-friendly fantasies. That's pretty much all that is needed. It's hard to know what aspect of the film drags it down the most, but perennially bad actress Rosie O'Donnell probably takes the...er....Oscar! Her awful dialogue delivery, grating voice-over, and even her harsh New York accent for an LA cop is grating. Meanwhile the plot is almost incidental to the film, serving seemingly only as a way to string a few soft bondage scenes and awkward interactions together, and the reason for why the cops and thieves are there is largely forgotten for large portions of the film. But the scenes aren't particularly arousing enough for the film to be much of an erotic thriller, and the story isn't even remotely gripping enough to fulfil the thriller aspect either. Meanwhile Dan Aykroyd's hammy delivery, while seemingly perfect for Ghostbusters, seems to merely add to the film's overall corniness. When the plot finally does make a return to the film, it drags the already-meandering pace of the film down to an absolute crawl, and by the time the film approaches its 'climax' (and never was a term so inaccurate on so many levels) after nearly 2 hours, a life of celibacy may suddenly have some appeal. Ask for a refund of both your time and money. Dire.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very good show
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mckenzie2467-908-385498
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Exit To Eden was a wonderful, fun movie to watch. Dana Delaney was a stunning, wonderfully beautiful actress to watch, capturing your heart easily in her role. She was a real sweetheart, although it may be hard to envision a career Dominatrix acting as she did. Eliot was great, everyone did a wonderful job entertaining us with A). A good story, and B). Mildly erotic entertainment. This movie was a fairly predictable cop-drama with some erotic entertainment and a love story kicked in for good measure. Remember, we are watching TV, that thing you do because you want to go away for a couple of hours and feel good. Dan Ackroyd was good (although his partner definitely got the better deal :) ) Rosie O' Donnell kept me going, 'Euuuuggghhhh' through most of the movie, although she was funny... Bottom line, if you want HOT erotica, go somewhere else. If you want mild erotica and want to have fun for a couple of hours, if you want to get away for a while, take the Exit To Eden. It's a fun trip.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Call me crazy but I like this!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Wayne Malin (wwaayynnee51@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Photographer Elliot Slater (Paul Mercurio) is going to Eden--an island devoted to people who like S&M and BDMS. He's going to live out his dream as being a submissive man who loves being spanked. He accidentally photographs a vicious criminal named Omar (Stuart Wilson) getting drugs. Omar and helper Nina (Iman) follow Elliot to the island to get the film--and kill him. Police officers Sheila (Rosie O'Donnell) and Fred (Dan Aykroyd) are in hot pursuit. On the island the head--Mistress Lisa (Dan Delany)--takes it upon herself to "train Elliot--and starts falling in love which she has vowed never to do. This is an adaptation (a VERY loose one) of an Anne Rice book that is just about sex, bondage, S&M and the love between Elliot and Lisa. There's no stupid drug story. It's a very good and very adult book. The movie basically sanitizes the book a great deal (everyone's nude in the book--not here), throws the insights into sex out the window and adds nonstop wisecracks from O'Donnell. Now, I like O'Donnell and some of her lines ARE funny but the movie's tone keeps zigzagging between comedy, suspense, love and nudity. It's all over the place and never finds a comfortable footing. Also Iman is (to put it mildly) a terrible actress. Still I really like this! The island locale is just beautiful (it was shot in Hawaii) and the resort itself is incredible. There's plenty of casual female nudity--even Delany has a full frontal nude shot! There is some male nudity but mostly back views. Supposedly there were full frontal shots of Mercurio but they had to cut them or they would have gotten an X rating. That doesn't make a bit of sense...but the ratings board always is afraid of male nudity. Still, there are a lot of hunky guys wandering around wearing next to nothing. Also Paul Mercurio has a fantastic butt and you get plenty of views of it! In terms of acting this is pretty good. Mercurio struggles with his accent (it's half-Australian, half-American) but he's handsome, in good shape and has no problem in strutting around half-naked. His acting is good too:) Delany looks incredible and gives an excellent performance as a dominatrix. O'Donnell is throwing off jokes left and right. Some are funny and she does it so casually it makes them even funnier. Aykroyd however is wasted. Also the movie is a little bit too long. Still this is worth seeing for the beautiful locations, the casual nudity, some truly funny bits and acting. If you're easily offended by frank talk of S&M and nudity stay FAR away. A huge bomb when it came out but this (hopefully) might be rediscovered some day. There's also a cute joke at the very end of the closing credits. I give this an 8.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This Flick is Gross
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    writerasfilmcritic
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/11/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This pile of dung is one of the worst movies I've ever sat through. As others have pointed out, the only thing in it worth seeing is a momentary glimpse of Dana Delaney totally nude, including her luxuriant growth of pubic hair, obviously shot back in the days before Generation X began dominating the media with their peculiar aversion to anything natural, especially hair. Still, her brief nude scene is not enough for this piece of drek to find a permanent slot in your video library even if you got it for free. That Aussie jerk ruined it from the first moment he appeared on screen. Whoever gave him the idea that he could act, that he understood the first thing about photography, that his "croc hunter" accent was somehow cool, or that his big fat ass was sexy and ought to be shoved in our faces for an hour and a half? If you're not a woman or hopelessly gay, a movie where beefcake men run around in thongs is what we used to call a real gross-out. Admittedly, there were a handful of scenes containing cute, half-naked babes that deserved a second look, but otherwise, this horrible excuse for cinema was a groan from start to finish, actually worse than a bad "Loveboat" episode, if that is possible. Rosie O'Donnel wasn't exactly good in it but she was far from its worst feature, and that alone ought to tell you something. When she kissed her "submissive" at the end, she was far more convincing as a straight woman than he was as a straight man. Put another way, whoever had the idea to pair a dike with an obvious fairy and call it erotic ought to have their heads examined. I had to ask my old lady three or four separate times if anyone saw her take this piece of tripe from the library sale rack and am embarrassed we watched the whole thing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Really funny film using nudity gracefully and frequently.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jcannon-13
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have looked at this movie at least forty times. It is sheer pleasure. Lots of laughs. I enjoyed seeing Dana Delaaney in a very different role than I have usually seen her. Paul Mercurio too I had only seen before in his profession as a dancer. He is a superb dancer. At first I was surprised at the extent of nudity, but then realized, how else could they depict the island. Both Dana and Paul have great looking bodies and get to show them off throughout the movie. Paul's outstanding butt is highlighted in a scene between the two of them. Clever was the scene involving the buttered croissants. Really good flick!!! JFC
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Views about Exit to Eden
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RichieLovesGodHisFather
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/4/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When Tom Snyder had his talk show on cable years ago,they did a segment on this movie a lot of couples approved of it.Some were saying it helped their romance,as well as their relationships.But the makers of this movie failed to overlook something here.God Himself,and The written facts in the bible Worship God only.Mistresses,have become a world wide network.Many of them proclaiming themselves goddesses and demand to be worshiped.Gods 1st Commandment,Thou Shalt Not Have No Other gods Before Me.Also pertains to false gods,false goddesses,and so many who expect to be worshiped.Even in history former figures like Zeus,Apollo,Venus Athena and the list goes on.All of these so called gods,goddesses,and all those who expect to be worshiped have one thing in common.They are all mortal human beings,as was Zeus and so many others.When revelation finally does come,we may not be here too witness it It can happen a hundred years from now,nobody knows the exact time but God Himself.God is slow to anger and quick to forgive,but even churches rarely mention that Our God is a Jealous God.I doubt it I will see revelation in my life time,but if it come to pass,I'd love too see God set His world straight on His Ten Commandments,most especially His 1st Commandent.Amen
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    film making at it's most masochistic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Doug Galecawitz (dougg@evilnet.net)
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/1/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    i saw this film many years ago and have since mostly tried to block it out the memories of it. Unfortunately during a marathon session of psychotherapy this pile molten rat dung came to light, and i now blame it for ALL my social behavioral problems. To complain about acting, plot, direction, screen writing, et cetera, would completely miss the point and the central tragedy surrounding this film. At some point in time somebody thought it was a decent and sell-able idea to cut a handsome check to dan akroyrd (god bless him for elwood) and rosie o'donnell to put on bondage gear and strut around nude with bad wisecracks for the better part of a ninety minute movie. I'm not terribly original in my reviews of movies (nor anything in this life) and i don't think i'm the first in IMDb to point it out but there is a level of true masochism in casting photogenically impaired stars to star in a motion picture about sado-masochism and bondage. The irony (intended or not) can't be lost on people. This is truly one of the most awful things committed to film since Pink Flamingoes, which could always fall back on the cynical train wreck view of film as a reason to watch. No, someone took this seriously and perpetrated it in cold blood. PS Dana Delaney is kinda hot....... 2 out of ten only because there is no zero and i was too lazy to make it to one....
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Is it honestly trying to be an erotic comedy?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moonspinner55
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/10/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Completely misbegotten adaptation of Anne Rice's book about two cops (Dan Aykroyd and Rosie O'Donnell, a screen-teaming which should've been a hoot) working undercover at an S&M resort to capture a ring of crooks. Garry Marshall directed in a shamefully sloppy manner, without a clue as to how a general audience would feel about this kind of material; his narrative is so clogged with smarmy activity and failed gimmicks (like a voice-over from O'Donnell that is both unfunny and unnecessary) that the picture self-destructs even before the opening credits have finished! Highly unpleasant dud was a critical and commercial turkey, although O'Donnell has gotten mileage out of it by making "Exit to Eden" jokes at her own expense.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What you don't know..... is
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mistressladynite
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/10/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Exit to Eden.. gets a BUM rap from people that are narrow minded and do not have a clue what the movie was really about!! The "Lifestyle" that this movie was written about really exists. Maybe NOT to the point of a awesome island as in the movie, but there are a LARGE group of people out there in the world that LIVE that style of life. Exit to Eden touched on MANY true facts about the "lifestyle" and did a good job. It straight forwardly explained what the different roles are in the life of Dominates and submissives. Inside EVERYONE is a desire to be either one or the other. Some act out on it, others don't. (because they are afraid to!!) The "lifestyle" is not about sex, its about "power exchange" All of this was addressed in the movie. Those of you that do not understand this, and were looking for more "entertainment" were so busy wanting to be amused, that they missed the whole point of the movie. It was nice to see something so "vanilla" to come out and TRY to explain what others already know. GREAT movie.. Well done, funny, serious, and pretty complete, especially since they were trying to stay within the "vanilla" realm. NOT everything in the movie was "true to form" of the "lifestyle" but it sure touched a lot of things that were. Secretary was another good movie that portrays "the lifestyle". It was more real to life than you would imagine. So those of you that are naysayers.. don't you dare watch THAT one.. hahah it would give you something to "complain" about. Mistress Ladynite
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Tries to hard to be too much
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wnterstar
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/5/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I enjoyed watching this movie, even though I know it's not a great movie. I thought the acting was good, and the island of Eden was gorgeous. The erotic scenes were a mixed bag...there were a couple that were extremely erotic (got some good ideas there!) but others were Luke-warm at best. I think what kept this movie from being a good movie is that it was trying to be all things to everyone. It was a crime story, a comedy, an erotic sexcapade (sort of) and a romance. It also had too many morals to it (it's OK to explore your wild side, it's OK to relinquish control in certain situations, and the ever-popular love conquers everything). I haven't read this book (written by Anne Rice under the pseudonym of Anne Rampling) but I have read other erotica by her and I'm sure the book HAS to be better!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Neither erotic nor funny - call trade descriptions!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mr_PCM
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Irritating voiceovers, amateur acting, corny dialogue that a porn star would be embarrassed to deliver, racial stereotypes, gratuitous nudity, hazy dream-like flashbacks, a performance by Rosie O'Donnell and Dan Aykroyd with a moustache - all the ingredients for a Razzie award-winning film - and win it did! Coupled with an overly long plot that regularly goes MIA, and drags when it does show up for duty, 1994's Exit to Eden makes notable turkey Gigli seem as romantic as Brief Encounte! It's all so comically bad it feels like it should be in German - a la the old late night movies found in the higher channel numbers in the early days of satellite TV. In the right hands, or with a more daring director or provocative censor, this film set in a holiday resort run by a dominatrix could have been quite interesting, but unfortunately tiptoes around anything more controversial than an occasional tap with a hairbrush. The laughable, risible plot involves a pair of jewel thieves and a pair of cops going undercover at a BDSM resort to retrieve a film canister containing photos of a jewel robbery, while various couples visualise and act out their assorted TV-friendly fantasies. That's pretty much all that is needed. It's hard to know what aspect of the film drags it down the most, but perennially bad actress Rosie O'Donnell probably takes the...er....Oscar! Her awful dialogue delivery, grating voice-over, and even her harsh New York accent for an LA cop is grating. Meanwhile the plot is almost incidental to the film, serving seemingly only as a way to string a few soft bondage scenes and awkward interactions together, and the reason for why the cops and thieves are there is largely forgotten for large portions of the film. But the scenes aren't particularly arousing enough for the film to be much of an erotic thriller, and the story isn't even remotely gripping enough to fulfil the thriller aspect either. Meanwhile Dan Aykroyd's hammy delivery, while seemingly perfect for Ghostbusters, seems to merely add to the film's overall corniness. When the plot finally does make a return to the film, it drags the already-meandering pace of the film down to an absolute crawl, and by the time the film approaches its 'climax' (and never was a term so inaccurate on so many levels) after nearly 2 hours, a life of celibacy may suddenly have some appeal. Ask for a refund of both your time and money. Dire.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very good show
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mckenzie2467-908-385498
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Exit To Eden was a wonderful, fun movie to watch. Dana Delaney was a stunning, wonderfully beautiful actress to watch, capturing your heart easily in her role. She was a real sweetheart, although it may be hard to envision a career Dominatrix acting as she did. Eliot was great, everyone did a wonderful job entertaining us with A). A good story, and B). Mildly erotic entertainment. This movie was a fairly predictable cop-drama with some erotic entertainment and a love story kicked in for good measure. Remember, we are watching TV, that thing you do because you want to go away for a couple of hours and feel good. Dan Ackroyd was good (although his partner definitely got the better deal :) ) Rosie O' Donnell kept me going, 'Euuuuggghhhh' through most of the movie, although she was funny... Bottom line, if you want HOT erotica, go somewhere else. If you want mild erotica and want to have fun for a couple of hours, if you want to get away for a while, take the Exit To Eden. It's a fun trip.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Call me crazy but I like this!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Wayne Malin (wwaayynnee51@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Photographer Elliot Slater (Paul Mercurio) is going to Eden--an island devoted to people who like S&M and BDMS. He's going to live out his dream as being a submissive man who loves being spanked. He accidentally photographs a vicious criminal named Omar (Stuart Wilson) getting drugs. Omar and helper Nina (Iman) follow Elliot to the island to get the film--and kill him. Police officers Sheila (Rosie O'Donnell) and Fred (Dan Aykroyd) are in hot pursuit. On the island the head--Mistress Lisa (Dan Delany)--takes it upon herself to "train Elliot--and starts falling in love which she has vowed never to do. This is an adaptation (a VERY loose one) of an Anne Rice book that is just about sex, bondage, S&M and the love between Elliot and Lisa. There's no stupid drug story. It's a very good and very adult book. The movie basically sanitizes the book a great deal (everyone's nude in the book--not here), throws the insights into sex out the window and adds nonstop wisecracks from O'Donnell. Now, I like O'Donnell and some of her lines ARE funny but the movie's tone keeps zigzagging between comedy, suspense, love and nudity. It's all over the place and never finds a comfortable footing. Also Iman is (to put it mildly) a terrible actress. Still I really like this! The island locale is just beautiful (it was shot in Hawaii) and the resort itself is incredible. There's plenty of casual female nudity--even Delany has a full frontal nude shot! There is some male nudity but mostly back views. Supposedly there were full frontal shots of Mercurio but they had to cut them or they would have gotten an X rating. That doesn't make a bit of sense...but the ratings board always is afraid of male nudity. Still, there are a lot of hunky guys wandering around wearing next to nothing. Also Paul Mercurio has a fantastic butt and you get plenty of views of it! In terms of acting this is pretty good. Mercurio struggles with his accent (it's half-Australian, half-American) but he's handsome, in good shape and has no problem in strutting around half-naked. His acting is good too:) Delany looks incredible and gives an excellent performance as a dominatrix. O'Donnell is throwing off jokes left and right. Some are funny and she does it so casually it makes them even funnier. Aykroyd however is wasted. Also the movie is a little bit too long. Still this is worth seeing for the beautiful locations, the casual nudity, some truly funny bits and acting. If you're easily offended by frank talk of S&M and nudity stay FAR away. A huge bomb when it came out but this (hopefully) might be rediscovered some day. There's also a cute joke at the very end of the closing credits. I give this an 8.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This Flick is Gross
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    writerasfilmcritic
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/11/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This pile of dung is one of the worst movies I've ever sat through. As others have pointed out, the only thing in it worth seeing is a momentary glimpse of Dana Delaney totally nude, including her luxuriant growth of pubic hair, obviously shot back in the days before Generation X began dominating the media with their peculiar aversion to anything natural, especially hair. Still, her brief nude scene is not enough for this piece of drek to find a permanent slot in your video library even if you got it for free. That Aussie jerk ruined it from the first moment he appeared on screen. Whoever gave him the idea that he could act, that he understood the first thing about photography, that his "croc hunter" accent was somehow cool, or that his big fat ass was sexy and ought to be shoved in our faces for an hour and a half? If you're not a woman or hopelessly gay, a movie where beefcake men run around in thongs is what we used to call a real gross-out. Admittedly, there were a handful of scenes containing cute, half-naked babes that deserved a second look, but otherwise, this horrible excuse for cinema was a groan from start to finish, actually worse than a bad "Loveboat" episode, if that is possible. Rosie O'Donnel wasn't exactly good in it but she was far from its worst feature, and that alone ought to tell you something. When she kissed her "submissive" at the end, she was far more convincing as a straight woman than he was as a straight man. Put another way, whoever had the idea to pair a dike with an obvious fairy and call it erotic ought to have their heads examined. I had to ask my old lady three or four separate times if anyone saw her take this piece of tripe from the library sale rack and am embarrassed we watched the whole thing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Really funny film using nudity gracefully and frequently.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jcannon-13
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have looked at this movie at least forty times. It is sheer pleasure. Lots of laughs. I enjoyed seeing Dana Delaaney in a very different role than I have usually seen her. Paul Mercurio too I had only seen before in his profession as a dancer. He is a superb dancer. At first I was surprised at the extent of nudity, but then realized, how else could they depict the island. Both Dana and Paul have great looking bodies and get to show them off throughout the movie. Paul's outstanding butt is highlighted in a scene between the two of them. Clever was the scene involving the buttered croissants. Really good flick!!! JFC
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Views about Exit to Eden
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RichieLovesGodHisFather
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/4/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When Tom Snyder had his talk show on cable years ago,they did a segment on this movie a lot of couples approved of it.Some were saying it helped their romance,as well as their relationships.But the makers of this movie failed to overlook something here.God Himself,and The written facts in the bible Worship God only.Mistresses,have become a world wide network.Many of them proclaiming themselves goddesses and demand to be worshiped.Gods 1st Commandment,Thou Shalt Not Have No Other gods Before Me.Also pertains to false gods,false goddesses,and so many who expect to be worshiped.Even in history former figures like Zeus,Apollo,Venus Athena and the list goes on.All of these so called gods,goddesses,and all those who expect to be worshiped have one thing in common.They are all mortal human beings,as was Zeus and so many others.When revelation finally does come,we may not be here too witness it It can happen a hundred years from now,nobody knows the exact time but God Himself.God is slow to anger and quick to forgive,but even churches rarely mention that Our God is a Jealous God.I doubt it I will see revelation in my life time,but if it come to pass,I'd love too see God set His world straight on His Ten Commandments,most especially His 1st Commandent.Amen
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    film making at it's most masochistic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Doug Galecawitz (dougg@evilnet.net)
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/1/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    i saw this film many years ago and have since mostly tried to block it out the memories of it. Unfortunately during a marathon session of psychotherapy this pile molten rat dung came to light, and i now blame it for ALL my social behavioral problems. To complain about acting, plot, direction, screen writing, et cetera, would completely miss the point and the central tragedy surrounding this film. At some point in time somebody thought it was a decent and sell-able idea to cut a handsome check to dan akroyrd (god bless him for elwood) and rosie o'donnell to put on bondage gear and strut around nude with bad wisecracks for the better part of a ninety minute movie. I'm not terribly original in my reviews of movies (nor anything in this life) and i don't think i'm the first in IMDb to point it out but there is a level of true masochism in casting photogenically impaired stars to star in a motion picture about sado-masochism and bondage. The irony (intended or not) can't be lost on people. This is truly one of the most awful things committed to film since Pink Flamingoes, which could always fall back on the cynical train wreck view of film as a reason to watch. No, someone took this seriously and perpetrated it in cold blood. PS Dana Delaney is kinda hot....... 2 out of ten only because there is no zero and i was too lazy to make it to one....
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Is it honestly trying to be an erotic comedy?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moonspinner55
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/10/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Completely misbegotten adaptation of Anne Rice's book about two cops (Dan Aykroyd and Rosie O'Donnell, a screen-teaming which should've been a hoot) working undercover at an S&M resort to capture a ring of crooks. Garry Marshall directed in a shamefully sloppy manner, without a clue as to how a general audience would feel about this kind of material; his narrative is so clogged with smarmy activity and failed gimmicks (like a voice-over from O'Donnell that is both unfunny and unnecessary) that the picture self-destructs even before the opening credits have finished! Highly unpleasant dud was a critical and commercial turkey, although O'Donnell has gotten mileage out of it by making "Exit to Eden" jokes at her own expense.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What you don't know..... is
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mistressladynite
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/10/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Exit to Eden.. gets a BUM rap from people that are narrow minded and do not have a clue what the movie was really about!! The "Lifestyle" that this movie was written about really exists. Maybe NOT to the point of a awesome island as in the movie, but there are a LARGE group of people out there in the world that LIVE that style of life. Exit to Eden touched on MANY true facts about the "lifestyle" and did a good job. It straight forwardly explained what the different roles are in the life of Dominates and submissives. Inside EVERYONE is a desire to be either one or the other. Some act out on it, others don't. (because they are afraid to!!) The "lifestyle" is not about sex, its about "power exchange" All of this was addressed in the movie. Those of you that do not understand this, and were looking for more "entertainment" were so busy wanting to be amused, that they missed the whole point of the movie. It was nice to see something so "vanilla" to come out and TRY to explain what others already know. GREAT movie.. Well done, funny, serious, and pretty complete, especially since they were trying to stay within the "vanilla" realm. NOT everything in the movie was "true to form" of the "lifestyle" but it sure touched a lot of things that were. Secretary was another good movie that portrays "the lifestyle". It was more real to life than you would imagine. So those of you that are naysayers.. don't you dare watch THAT one.. hahah it would give you something to "complain" about. Mistress Ladynite
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Tries to hard to be too much
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wnterstar
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/5/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I enjoyed watching this movie, even though I know it's not a great movie. I thought the acting was good, and the island of Eden was gorgeous. The erotic scenes were a mixed bag...there were a couple that were extremely erotic (got some good ideas there!) but others were Luke-warm at best. I think what kept this movie from being a good movie is that it was trying to be all things to everyone. It was a crime story, a comedy, an erotic sexcapade (sort of) and a romance. It also had too many morals to it (it's OK to explore your wild side, it's OK to relinquish control in certain situations, and the ever-popular love conquers everything). I haven't read this book (written by Anne Rice under the pseudonym of Anne Rampling) but I have read other erotica by her and I'm sure the book HAS to be better!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Neither erotic nor funny - call trade descriptions!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mr_PCM
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Irritating voiceovers, amateur acting, corny dialogue that a porn star would be embarrassed to deliver, racial stereotypes, gratuitous nudity, hazy dream-like flashbacks, a performance by Rosie O'Donnell and Dan Aykroyd with a moustache - all the ingredients for a Razzie award-winning film - and win it did! Coupled with an overly long plot that regularly goes MIA, and drags when it does show up for duty, 1994's Exit to Eden makes notable turkey Gigli seem as romantic as Brief Encounte! It's all so comically bad it feels like it should be in German - a la the old late night movies found in the higher channel numbers in the early days of satellite TV. In the right hands, or with a more daring director or provocative censor, this film set in a holiday resort run by a dominatrix could have been quite interesting, but unfortunately tiptoes around anything more controversial than an occasional tap with a hairbrush. The laughable, risible plot involves a pair of jewel thieves and a pair of cops going undercover at a BDSM resort to retrieve a film canister containing photos of a jewel robbery, while various couples visualise and act out their assorted TV-friendly fantasies. That's pretty much all that is needed. It's hard to know what aspect of the film drags it down the most, but perennially bad actress Rosie O'Donnell probably takes the...er....Oscar! Her awful dialogue delivery, grating voice-over, and even her harsh New York accent for an LA cop is grating. Meanwhile the plot is almost incidental to the film, serving seemingly only as a way to string a few soft bondage scenes and awkward interactions together, and the reason for why the cops and thieves are there is largely forgotten for large portions of the film. But the scenes aren't particularly arousing enough for the film to be much of an erotic thriller, and the story isn't even remotely gripping enough to fulfil the thriller aspect either. Meanwhile Dan Aykroyd's hammy delivery, while seemingly perfect for Ghostbusters, seems to merely add to the film's overall corniness. When the plot finally does make a return to the film, it drags the already-meandering pace of the film down to an absolute crawl, and by the time the film approaches its 'climax' (and never was a term so inaccurate on so many levels) after nearly 2 hours, a life of celibacy may suddenly have some appeal. Ask for a refund of both your time and money. Dire.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very good show
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mckenzie2467-908-385498
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Exit To Eden was a wonderful, fun movie to watch. Dana Delaney was a stunning, wonderfully beautiful actress to watch, capturing your heart easily in her role. She was a real sweetheart, although it may be hard to envision a career Dominatrix acting as she did. Eliot was great, everyone did a wonderful job entertaining us with A). A good story, and B). Mildly erotic entertainment. This movie was a fairly predictable cop-drama with some erotic entertainment and a love story kicked in for good measure. Remember, we are watching TV, that thing you do because you want to go away for a couple of hours and feel good. Dan Ackroyd was good (although his partner definitely got the better deal :) ) Rosie O' Donnell kept me going, 'Euuuuggghhhh' through most of the movie, although she was funny... Bottom line, if you want HOT erotica, go somewhere else. If you want mild erotica and want to have fun for a couple of hours, if you want to get away for a while, take the Exit To Eden. It's a fun trip.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Call me crazy but I like this!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Wayne Malin (wwaayynnee51@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Photographer Elliot Slater (Paul Mercurio) is going to Eden--an island devoted to people who like S&M and BDMS. He's going to live out his dream as being a submissive man who loves being spanked. He accidentally photographs a vicious criminal named Omar (Stuart Wilson) getting drugs. Omar and helper Nina (Iman) follow Elliot to the island to get the film--and kill him. Police officers Sheila (Rosie O'Donnell) and Fred (Dan Aykroyd) are in hot pursuit. On the island the head--Mistress Lisa (Dan Delany)--takes it upon herself to "train Elliot--and starts falling in love which she has vowed never to do. This is an adaptation (a VERY loose one) of an Anne Rice book that is just about sex, bondage, S&M and the love between Elliot and Lisa. There's no stupid drug story. It's a very good and very adult book. The movie basically sanitizes the book a great deal (everyone's nude in the book--not here), throws the insights into sex out the window and adds nonstop wisecracks from O'Donnell. Now, I like O'Donnell and some of her lines ARE funny but the movie's tone keeps zigzagging between comedy, suspense, love and nudity. It's all over the place and never finds a comfortable footing. Also Iman is (to put it mildly) a terrible actress. Still I really like this! The island locale is just beautiful (it was shot in Hawaii) and the resort itself is incredible. There's plenty of casual female nudity--even Delany has a full frontal nude shot! There is some male nudity but mostly back views. Supposedly there were full frontal shots of Mercurio but they had to cut them or they would have gotten an X rating. That doesn't make a bit of sense...but the ratings board always is afraid of male nudity. Still, there are a lot of hunky guys wandering around wearing next to nothing. Also Paul Mercurio has a fantastic butt and you get plenty of views of it! In terms of acting this is pretty good. Mercurio struggles with his accent (it's half-Australian, half-American) but he's handsome, in good shape and has no problem in strutting around half-naked. His acting is good too:) Delany looks incredible and gives an excellent performance as a dominatrix. O'Donnell is throwing off jokes left and right. Some are funny and she does it so casually it makes them even funnier. Aykroyd however is wasted. Also the movie is a little bit too long. Still this is worth seeing for the beautiful locations, the casual nudity, some truly funny bits and acting. If you're easily offended by frank talk of S&M and nudity stay FAR away. A huge bomb when it came out but this (hopefully) might be rediscovered some day. There's also a cute joke at the very end of the closing credits. I give this an 8.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This Flick is Gross
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    writerasfilmcritic
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/11/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This pile of dung is one of the worst movies I've ever sat through. As others have pointed out, the only thing in it worth seeing is a momentary glimpse of Dana Delaney totally nude, including her luxuriant growth of pubic hair, obviously shot back in the days before Generation X began dominating the media with their peculiar aversion to anything natural, especially hair. Still, her brief nude scene is not enough for this piece of drek to find a permanent slot in your video library even if you got it for free. That Aussie jerk ruined it from the first moment he appeared on screen. Whoever gave him the idea that he could act, that he understood the first thing about photography, that his "croc hunter" accent was somehow cool, or that his big fat ass was sexy and ought to be shoved in our faces for an hour and a half? If you're not a woman or hopelessly gay, a movie where beefcake men run around in thongs is what we used to call a real gross-out. Admittedly, there were a handful of scenes containing cute, half-naked babes that deserved a second look, but otherwise, this horrible excuse for cinema was a groan from start to finish, actually worse than a bad "Loveboat" episode, if that is possible. Rosie O'Donnel wasn't exactly good in it but she was far from its worst feature, and that alone ought to tell you something. When she kissed her "submissive" at the end, she was far more convincing as a straight woman than he was as a straight man. Put another way, whoever had the idea to pair a dike with an obvious fairy and call it erotic ought to have their heads examined. I had to ask my old lady three or four separate times if anyone saw her take this piece of tripe from the library sale rack and am embarrassed we watched the whole thing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Really funny film using nudity gracefully and frequently.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jcannon-13
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have looked at this movie at least forty times. It is sheer pleasure. Lots of laughs. I enjoyed seeing Dana Delaaney in a very different role than I have usually seen her. Paul Mercurio too I had only seen before in his profession as a dancer. He is a superb dancer. At first I was surprised at the extent of nudity, but then realized, how else could they depict the island. Both Dana and Paul have great looking bodies and get to show them off throughout the movie. Paul's outstanding butt is highlighted in a scene between the two of them. Clever was the scene involving the buttered croissants. Really good flick!!! JFC
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Views about Exit to Eden
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RichieLovesGodHisFather
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/4/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When Tom Snyder had his talk show on cable years ago,they did a segment on this movie a lot of couples approved of it.Some were saying it helped their romance,as well as their relationships.But the makers of this movie failed to overlook something here.God Himself,and The written facts in the bible Worship God only.Mistresses,have become a world wide network.Many of them proclaiming themselves goddesses and demand to be worshiped.Gods 1st Commandment,Thou Shalt Not Have No Other gods Before Me.Also pertains to false gods,false goddesses,and so many who expect to be worshiped.Even in history former figures like Zeus,Apollo,Venus Athena and the list goes on.All of these so called gods,goddesses,and all those who expect to be worshiped have one thing in common.They are all mortal human beings,as was Zeus and so many others.When revelation finally does come,we may not be here too witness it It can happen a hundred years from now,nobody knows the exact time but God Himself.God is slow to anger and quick to forgive,but even churches rarely mention that Our God is a Jealous God.I doubt it I will see revelation in my life time,but if it come to pass,I'd love too see God set His world straight on His Ten Commandments,most especially His 1st Commandent.Amen
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    film making at it's most masochistic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Doug Galecawitz (dougg@evilnet.net)
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/1/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    i saw this film many years ago and have since mostly tried to block it out the memories of it. Unfortunately during a marathon session of psychotherapy this pile molten rat dung came to light, and i now blame it for ALL my social behavioral problems. To complain about acting, plot, direction, screen writing, et cetera, would completely miss the point and the central tragedy surrounding this film. At some point in time somebody thought it was a decent and sell-able idea to cut a handsome check to dan akroyrd (god bless him for elwood) and rosie o'donnell to put on bondage gear and strut around nude with bad wisecracks for the better part of a ninety minute movie. I'm not terribly original in my reviews of movies (nor anything in this life) and i don't think i'm the first in IMDb to point it out but there is a level of true masochism in casting photogenically impaired stars to star in a motion picture about sado-masochism and bondage. The irony (intended or not) can't be lost on people. This is truly one of the most awful things committed to film since Pink Flamingoes, which could always fall back on the cynical train wreck view of film as a reason to watch. No, someone took this seriously and perpetrated it in cold blood. PS Dana Delaney is kinda hot....... 2 out of ten only because there is no zero and i was too lazy to make it to one....
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Is it honestly trying to be an erotic comedy?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moonspinner55
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/10/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Completely misbegotten adaptation of Anne Rice's book about two cops (Dan Aykroyd and Rosie O'Donnell, a screen-teaming which should've been a hoot) working undercover at an S&M resort to capture a ring of crooks. Garry Marshall directed in a shamefully sloppy manner, without a clue as to how a general audience would feel about this kind of material; his narrative is so clogged with smarmy activity and failed gimmicks (like a voice-over from O'Donnell that is both unfunny and unnecessary) that the picture self-destructs even before the opening credits have finished! Highly unpleasant dud was a critical and commercial turkey, although O'Donnell has gotten mileage out of it by making "Exit to Eden" jokes at her own expense.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What you don't know..... is
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mistressladynite
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/10/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Exit to Eden.. gets a BUM rap from people that are narrow minded and do not have a clue what the movie was really about!! The "Lifestyle" that this movie was written about really exists. Maybe NOT to the point of a awesome island as in the movie, but there are a LARGE group of people out there in the world that LIVE that style of life. Exit to Eden touched on MANY true facts about the "lifestyle" and did a good job. It straight forwardly explained what the different roles are in the life of Dominates and submissives. Inside EVERYONE is a desire to be either one or the other. Some act out on it, others don't. (because they are afraid to!!) The "lifestyle" is not about sex, its about "power exchange" All of this was addressed in the movie. Those of you that do not understand this, and were looking for more "entertainment" were so busy wanting to be amused, that they missed the whole point of the movie. It was nice to see something so "vanilla" to come out and TRY to explain what others already know. GREAT movie.. Well done, funny, serious, and pretty complete, especially since they were trying to stay within the "vanilla" realm. NOT everything in the movie was "true to form" of the "lifestyle" but it sure touched a lot of things that were. Secretary was another good movie that portrays "the lifestyle". It was more real to life than you would imagine. So those of you that are naysayers.. don't you dare watch THAT one.. hahah it would give you something to "complain" about. Mistress Ladynite
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Tries to hard to be too much
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wnterstar
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/5/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I enjoyed watching this movie, even though I know it's not a great movie. I thought the acting was good, and the island of Eden was gorgeous. The erotic scenes were a mixed bag...there were a couple that were extremely erotic (got some good ideas there!) but others were Luke-warm at best. I think what kept this movie from being a good movie is that it was trying to be all things to everyone. It was a crime story, a comedy, an erotic sexcapade (sort of) and a romance. It also had too many morals to it (it's OK to explore your wild side, it's OK to relinquish control in certain situations, and the ever-popular love conquers everything). I haven't read this book (written by Anne Rice under the pseudonym of Anne Rampling) but I have read other erotica by her and I'm sure the book HAS to be better!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Neither erotic nor funny - call trade descriptions!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Mr_PCM
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Irritating voiceovers, amateur acting, corny dialogue that a porn star would be embarrassed to deliver, racial stereotypes, gratuitous nudity, hazy dream-like flashbacks, a performance by Rosie O'Donnell and Dan Aykroyd with a moustache - all the ingredients for a Razzie award-winning film - and win it did! Coupled with an overly long plot that regularly goes MIA, and drags when it does show up for duty, 1994's Exit to Eden makes notable turkey Gigli seem as romantic as Brief Encounte! It's all so comically bad it feels like it should be in German - a la the old late night movies found in the higher channel numbers in the early days of satellite TV. In the right hands, or with a more daring director or provocative censor, this film set in a holiday resort run by a dominatrix could have been quite interesting, but unfortunately tiptoes around anything more controversial than an occasional tap with a hairbrush. The laughable, risible plot involves a pair of jewel thieves and a pair of cops going undercover at a BDSM resort to retrieve a film canister containing photos of a jewel robbery, while various couples visualise and act out their assorted TV-friendly fantasies. That's pretty much all that is needed. It's hard to know what aspect of the film drags it down the most, but perennially bad actress Rosie O'Donnell probably takes the...er....Oscar! Her awful dialogue delivery, grating voice-over, and even her harsh New York accent for an LA cop is grating. Meanwhile the plot is almost incidental to the film, serving seemingly only as a way to string a few soft bondage scenes and awkward interactions together, and the reason for why the cops and thieves are there is largely forgotten for large portions of the film. But the scenes aren't particularly arousing enough for the film to be much of an erotic thriller, and the story isn't even remotely gripping enough to fulfil the thriller aspect either. Meanwhile Dan Aykroyd's hammy delivery, while seemingly perfect for Ghostbusters, seems to merely add to the film's overall corniness. When the plot finally does make a return to the film, it drags the already-meandering pace of the film down to an absolute crawl, and by the time the film approaches its 'climax' (and never was a term so inaccurate on so many levels) after nearly 2 hours, a life of celibacy may suddenly have some appeal. Ask for a refund of both your time and money. Dire.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very good show
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mckenzie2467-908-385498
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Exit To Eden was a wonderful, fun movie to watch. Dana Delaney was a stunning, wonderfully beautiful actress to watch, capturing your heart easily in her role. She was a real sweetheart, although it may be hard to envision a career Dominatrix acting as she did. Eliot was great, everyone did a wonderful job entertaining us with A). A good story, and B). Mildly erotic entertainment. This movie was a fairly predictable cop-drama with some erotic entertainment and a love story kicked in for good measure. Remember, we are watching TV, that thing you do because you want to go away for a couple of hours and feel good. Dan Ackroyd was good (although his partner definitely got the better deal :) ) Rosie O' Donnell kept me going, 'Euuuuggghhhh' through most of the movie, although she was funny... Bottom line, if you want HOT erotica, go somewhere else. If you want mild erotica and want to have fun for a couple of hours, if you want to get away for a while, take the Exit To Eden. It's a fun trip.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Call me crazy but I like this!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Wayne Malin (wwaayynnee51@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Photographer Elliot Slater (Paul Mercurio) is going to Eden--an island devoted to people who like S&M and BDMS. He's going to live out his dream as being a submissive man who loves being spanked. He accidentally photographs a vicious criminal named Omar (Stuart Wilson) getting drugs. Omar and helper Nina (Iman) follow Elliot to the island to get the film--and kill him. Police officers Sheila (Rosie O'Donnell) and Fred (Dan Aykroyd) are in hot pursuit. On the island the head--Mistress Lisa (Dan Delany)--takes it upon herself to "train Elliot--and starts falling in love which she has vowed never to do. This is an adaptation (a VERY loose one) of an Anne Rice book that is just about sex, bondage, S&M and the love between Elliot and Lisa. There's no stupid drug story. It's a very good and very adult book. The movie basically sanitizes the book a great deal (everyone's nude in the book--not here), throws the insights into sex out the window and adds nonstop wisecracks from O'Donnell. Now, I like O'Donnell and some of her lines ARE funny but the movie's tone keeps zigzagging between comedy, suspense, love and nudity. It's all over the place and never finds a comfortable footing. Also Iman is (to put it mildly) a terrible actress. Still I really like this! The island locale is just beautiful (it was shot in Hawaii) and the resort itself is incredible. There's plenty of casual female nudity--even Delany has a full frontal nude shot! There is some male nudity but mostly back views. Supposedly there were full frontal shots of Mercurio but they had to cut them or they would have gotten an X rating. That doesn't make a bit of sense...but the ratings board always is afraid of male nudity. Still, there are a lot of hunky guys wandering around wearing next to nothing. Also Paul Mercurio has a fantastic butt and you get plenty of views of it! In terms of acting this is pretty good. Mercurio struggles with his accent (it's half-Australian, half-American) but he's handsome, in good shape and has no problem in strutting around half-naked. His acting is good too:) Delany looks incredible and gives an excellent performance as a dominatrix. O'Donnell is throwing off jokes left and right. Some are funny and she does it so casually it makes them even funnier. Aykroyd however is wasted. Also the movie is a little bit too long. Still this is worth seeing for the beautiful locations, the casual nudity, some truly funny bits and acting. If you're easily offended by frank talk of S&M and nudity stay FAR away. A huge bomb when it came out but this (hopefully) might be rediscovered some day. There's also a cute joke at the very end of the closing credits. I give this an 8.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This Flick is Gross
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    writerasfilmcritic
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/11/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This pile of dung is one of the worst movies I've ever sat through. As others have pointed out, the only thing in it worth seeing is a momentary glimpse of Dana Delaney totally nude, including her luxuriant growth of pubic hair, obviously shot back in the days before Generation X began dominating the media with their peculiar aversion to anything natural, especially hair. Still, her brief nude scene is not enough for this piece of drek to find a permanent slot in your video library even if you got it for free. That Aussie jerk ruined it from the first moment he appeared on screen. Whoever gave him the idea that he could act, that he understood the first thing about photography, that his "croc hunter" accent was somehow cool, or that his big fat ass was sexy and ought to be shoved in our faces for an hour and a half? If you're not a woman or hopelessly gay, a movie where beefcake men run around in thongs is what we used to call a real gross-out. Admittedly, there were a handful of scenes containing cute, half-naked babes that deserved a second look, but otherwise, this horrible excuse for cinema was a groan from start to finish, actually worse than a bad "Loveboat" episode, if that is possible. Rosie O'Donnel wasn't exactly good in it but she was far from its worst feature, and that alone ought to tell you something. When she kissed her "submissive" at the end, she was far more convincing as a straight woman than he was as a straight man. Put another way, whoever had the idea to pair a dike with an obvious fairy and call it erotic ought to have their heads examined. I had to ask my old lady three or four separate times if anyone saw her take this piece of tripe from the library sale rack and am embarrassed we watched the whole thing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Really funny film using nudity gracefully and frequently.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jcannon-13
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have looked at this movie at least forty times. It is sheer pleasure. Lots of laughs. I enjoyed seeing Dana Delaaney in a very different role than I have usually seen her. Paul Mercurio too I had only seen before in his profession as a dancer. He is a superb dancer. At first I was surprised at the extent of nudity, but then realized, how else could they depict the island. Both Dana and Paul have great looking bodies and get to show them off throughout the movie. Paul's outstanding butt is highlighted in a scene between the two of them. Clever was the scene involving the buttered croissants. Really good flick!!! JFC
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Views about Exit to Eden
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    RichieLovesGodHisFather
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/4/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When Tom Snyder had his talk show on cable years ago,they did a segment on this movie a lot of couples approved of it.Some were saying it helped their romance,as well as their relationships.But the makers of this movie failed to overlook something here.God Himself,and The written facts in the bible Worship God only.Mistresses,have become a world wide network.Many of them proclaiming themselves goddesses and demand to be worshiped.Gods 1st Commandment,Thou Shalt Not Have No Other gods Before Me.Also pertains to false gods,false goddesses,and so many who expect to be worshiped.Even in history former figures like Zeus,Apollo,Venus Athena and the list goes on.All of these so called gods,goddesses,and all those who expect to be worshiped have one thing in common.They are all mortal human beings,as was Zeus and so many others.When revelation finally does come,we may not be here too witness it It can happen a hundred years from now,nobody knows the exact time but God Himself.God is slow to anger and quick to forgive,but even churches rarely mention that Our God is a Jealous God.I doubt it I will see revelation in my life time,but if it come to pass,I'd love too see God set His world straight on His Ten Commandments,most especially His 1st Commandent.Amen
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    film making at it's most masochistic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Doug Galecawitz (dougg@evilnet.net)
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/1/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    i saw this film many years ago and have since mostly tried to block it out the memories of it. Unfortunately during a marathon session of psychotherapy this pile molten rat dung came to light, and i now blame it for ALL my social behavioral problems. To complain about acting, plot, direction, screen writing, et cetera, would completely miss the point and the central tragedy surrounding this film. At some point in time somebody thought it was a decent and sell-able idea to cut a handsome check to dan akroyrd (god bless him for elwood) and rosie o'donnell to put on bondage gear and strut around nude with bad wisecracks for the better part of a ninety minute movie. I'm not terribly original in my reviews of movies (nor anything in this life) and i don't think i'm the first in IMDb to point it out but there is a level of true masochism in casting photogenically impaired stars to star in a motion picture about sado-masochism and bondage. The irony (intended or not) can't be lost on people. This is truly one of the most awful things committed to film since Pink Flamingoes, which could always fall back on the cynical train wreck view of film as a reason to watch. No, someone took this seriously and perpetrated it in cold blood. PS Dana Delaney is kinda hot....... 2 out of ten only because there is no zero and i was too lazy to make it to one....
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Is it honestly trying to be an erotic comedy?
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moonspinner55
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/10/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Completely misbegotten adaptation of Anne Rice's book about two cops (Dan Aykroyd and Rosie O'Donnell, a screen-teaming which should've been a hoot) working undercover at an S&M resort to capture a ring of crooks. Garry Marshall directed in a shamefully sloppy manner, without a clue as to how a general audience would feel about this kind of material; his narrative is so clogged with smarmy activity and failed gimmicks (like a voice-over from O'Donnell that is both unfunny and unnecessary) that the picture self-destructs even before the opening credits have finished! Highly unpleasant dud was a critical and commercial turkey, although O'Donnell has gotten mileage out of it by making "Exit to Eden" jokes at her own expense.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What you don't know..... is
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mistressladynite
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/10/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Exit to Eden.. gets a BUM rap from people that are narrow minded and do not have a clue what the movie was really about!! The "Lifestyle" that this movie was written about really exists. Maybe NOT to the point of a awesome island as in the movie, but there are a LARGE group of people out there in the world that LIVE that style of life. Exit to Eden touched on MANY true facts about the "lifestyle" and did a good job. It straight forwardly explained what the different roles are in the life of Dominates and submissives. Inside EVERYONE is a desire to be either one or the other. Some act out on it, others don't. (because they are afraid to!!) The "lifestyle" is not about sex, its about "power exchange" All of this was addressed in the movie. Those of you that do not understand this, and were looking for more "entertainment" were so busy wanting to be amused, that they missed the whole point of the movie. It was nice to see something so "vanilla" to come out and TRY to explain what others already know. GREAT movie.. Well done, funny, serious, and pretty complete, especially since they were trying to stay within the "vanilla" realm. NOT everything in the movie was "true to form" of the "lifestyle" but it sure touched a lot of things that were. Secretary was another good movie that portrays "the lifestyle". It was more real to life than you would imagine. So those of you that are naysayers.. don't you dare watch THAT one.. hahah it would give you something to "complain" about. Mistress Ladynite
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Tries to hard to be too much
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    wnterstar
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/5/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I enjoyed watching this movie, even though I know it's not a great movie. I thought the acting was good, and the island of Eden was gorgeous. The erotic scenes were a mixed bag...there were a couple that were extremely erotic (got some good ideas there!) but others were Luke-warm at best. I think what kept this movie from being a good movie is that it was trying to be all things to everyone. It was a crime story, a comedy, an erotic sexcapade (sort of) and a romance. It also had too many morals to it (it's OK to explore your wild side, it's OK to relinquish control in certain situations, and the ever-popular love conquers everything). I haven't read this book (written by Anne Rice under the pseudonym of Anne Rampling) but I have read other erotica by her and I'm sure the book HAS to be better!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
