<filme>
 <id>
  727
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0110116
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1994
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Minha Amada Imortal
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  7.2
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  The life and death of the legendary Ludwig van Beethoven. Beside all the work he is known for, the composer once wrote a famous love letter to a nameless beloved and the movie tries to find... &nbsp;&raquo;
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  The life and death of the legendary Ludwig van Beethoven. Beside all the work he is known for, the composer once wrote a famous love letter to a nameless beloved and the movie tries to find out who this beloved was. Not easy as Beethoven has had many women in his life.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Biography
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Music
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   ludwig van beethoven
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   love letter
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   composer
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   death
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   love
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Bernard Rose
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Bernard Rose
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Gary Oldman
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Jeroen Krabb&eacute;
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Isabella Rossellini
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A brief review of Immortal Beloved.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cluso502
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Immortal Beloved disappointed me. Being both a fan of Gary Oldman and Beethoven I thought nothing could go wrong, and nothing did, as far as the soundtrack and Gary Oldman's performance were concerned. But Several other aspects of the film fell short. The cinematography was boring, costuming was historical, but plain, dialogue was not bad, but had very little substance, and the story-line was quite unsatisfying. Several character choices were unexplained. I never felt like I got to know any of the characters. And frankly the film seemed utterly pointless. I learned nothing and It had little artistic value. However it wasn't all bad, Gary Oldman had a few nice scenes with Marco Hofschneider, although they were cut short. The saddest part is that this film could have been a masterpiece if only it had different direction. I would love to re edit this film myself just to make the story flow in a more interesting direction. I recommend it if you can catch it for free and have nothing better to do. But never pay for this film. 6/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This film is perfect- the genius of his music combined with the complexity of his nature....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dee Ross
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For me - Beethoven stands alone in his genre - especially for his time. Too many historians worry about minute details in a famous person's life - and discredit stories that take a more artistic approach to revealing something about that person. No one knows all there is to know about a man from the 18th and 19th centuries - especially about his inner soul and what drives him to brilliance and raging behavior. The idea that there could have been someone unknown is enticing, and the concept of a film telling about Beethoven through the eyes of others is not a new one, but a format that allows more flexibility. I personally am glad they took this approach. Character development was therefore much more interesting. Oldman's performance was brilliant - and as is often the case with Oldman - you come to feel you are really watching Beethoven. The other personalities also were developed well - and his music was shown in the context of his times - sometimes harsh (his father's beatings) - sometimes tumultuous (the Napoleonic Wars) - sometimes full of love ( the women in his life who did adore him), - and sometimes driven by personal disappointment and anger (the onset of deafness and possibly an unrequited love.....) Beethoven took music to the next level - adding emotion to the beauty and structure already employed by others..... Some are shocked when I say that he was like the Led Zeppelin of the 19th Century - evoking new responses from listeners then, and still one of the few classical composers that you can play for anyone today and they will say "WOW!". Even those who really aren't fans of this kind of music. That is why they chose the 9th Symphony to celebrate the new millennium in 2000 GLOBALLY. Beethoven is universal and timeless. The movie is a wonderful way of sharing a moment with the maestro.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    historically and biographically inaccurate
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ursulahemard
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Not at all convinced. Why? Because this movie has numerous historical inaccuracies aka no chronological order: Ludwig van Beethoven's (17 December 1770  26 March 1827) total deafness occurs far too early, LvB is conducting personally works he actually never did, composing works in the wrong time order, etc. In addition to that, the movie takes too many liberties, to my taste, about the biographical facts, and to imply that that famous love-letter, written by LvB to his 'Immortal Beloved', would be ultimately his sister-in-law is just utterly preposterous. That letter was written and could have been addressed to several very well known ladies, we meet some of them during the movie, nevertheless no absolute certainty was proved until today. But it's most certainly not his sister-in-law, with whom he had so many conflicts and legal battles over years. The idea that LvB composed the 9th for his sister- in-law as a-forgive-me-for-making-your-life-a-hell is the director's personal fabrication and so is the feeble ending. Also, there is much more to LvB than his 5th, 9th and the Pathetique and it's a shame that even these were cut into bits and pieces and added here and there without any musicality to the frames, but rather as background music. There is short scene when a white pianist is accompanied by a black violinist playing the Kreutzer Sonata; it did ring a bell but I had to look it up. The 'mulatto' violinist was supposed to be George Bridgetower (11 October 177829 February 1860) an Afro-Polish-born virtuoso who had a quite tempestuous professional relationship with LvB. Such a shame that this was not more elaborately depicted in the movie. That could have been a great instructive scene. LvB is quite distorted here and even the great actor Gary Oldman can't save his dignity nor the voluptuous and expensive production. Actually Mr Oldman is over the top but I blame it on the pathetic direction. Watchable for the young, but not very instructive. p.s. Hearing the gorgeous Isabella Rossellini speak a couple of sentences in Hungarian made me smile :-)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Tale of solitude
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vincentiu
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Extraordinary cast. Impressive story. And a great Oldman. A precise ballet behind cages and traps. Delicate tale about love as more than feelings or ordinary fight. Portrait of a genius from sketch to final signature. And drops of music like fundamental character. A movie without definition. A trip fed by gentle touches and shadow of abyss. Build with intelligent science of details, it seems be a good novel. But, step by step, it is more. A cruel love story's faces, description of solitude and vain hope, exercise of cruelty and selfish, slices of pain and force of fly. And a gallery of women's portraits. As pictures of a snail. As games of existence's pieces. The film is wonderful for the gift to be a kind of parable. Beethoven may be everyone. Johanna is every person for who the other is only a geometrical figure.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Immortal Beloved - The life of the Great Ludwig Van.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MortenKristofferVebjornsen
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I first became of interest, in the music of classical category... I first heard the glorious tunes of Beethoven. They stunned me as a child, and still does... Much effort from Beethoven's side was put into his pieces of music. There have been many films to include them, in their repertoire of music. The once I have seen is few, but powerful to say it the least. "A Clockwork Orange" directed by Stanley Kubrick, that pioneered music with its synthesizing of the composers most famous works- The great "Ode to Joy" to name one though. The way Alex in "A Clockwork Orange" talks about Beethoven in that film, is like if he is a God- An icon of Heavenly proportions. I could agree, but to me he is a great composer, and his music captivate me- Inspire me and helps me in bad times, when does occur. Then we have this film with Gary Oldman taking on the ambitiousness to play the troubled composer. This is "Immortal Beloved"... With a pressure, emphasis on the "E" in Belov"e"d. The film takes place, in the life of Beethoven. His symphonies reflect every stage he have had in his life of deafness, one of his other obstacles. Since of deafness he became, his music could have stopped there. Had it not been for his shear determination to compose music that to him meant something indeed. And to his audience. In his life, Beethoven had many lovers- They all treated him badly, and when he dies... They mourns over that they could not treat him the way he deserved. Beethoven as an artist, deaf that he was- Was indeed eccentric, and treated them better than they did him. What I said about his symphonies with they being connected to his life and so... I will not go into detail about them, but I will say that when "Ode to Joy" comes bombastic at ya... You will feel indeed how he felt when he was subjected to violence by his father. Hence, the ultra-violence was not far away though. His father wanted, knowing that the boy had talent... told a set of aristocratic people that he was nine and could play like Mozart... The boy was twelve. Failed and beaten up, for only to escape this madman in the tunes of "Ode to Joy". It is Epic and beyond comprehension of understanding the shear magnitude of his ways to compose the music he did... Deaf indeed that he was. I salute it completely. Gary Oldman captures what I can think, the sadness, the joy and the misery this artist had- To perfection within the boundaries of the films limit. The cinematography is so, and so... Yet some scenes in palaces and scenes of gardens are to say it the least beautiful to look at, and that is great enough for me. Sometimes, the image could have been executed better, by injecting less light, and more natural light being let in. In the scenes where Karl Van Beethoven tries to commit suicide, the shots of him walking in the woods feels very flat- But in the films length of two magnificent hours- This does not apply whatsoever. Karl is by the way the son of Ludwig Van... Here his lovers appear once more. There was one, that became his obsession, his muse. His Immortal Beloved. The wife of his brother Caspar. To her, he leaves everything- His music and his estate. Originally to his brothers this was to be given. The sad thing, she waited on him at a hotel- Only to leave as he arrived, sad I became indeed. The film puts you under the skin of Beethoven, and let you feel his journey told through flashbacks of the people he socialized with- that mostly being his lovers, and his assistant Schindler, played by Jeroen Krabb&eacute;. The acting is superb and the execution of the director Bernard Rose is great, and he have really caught the essence of Beethoven. The Man, The Artist and The Father. It is a great film, easily enjoyable, if you are into Beethoven- Then this maximizes by the numbers. It is easy to understand and you will feel like you are being part of the events displayed in the film. Now... play some music of Beethoven while you read this review again- to gain the effect I did while writing it. Preferably, the ninth. The End.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A movie to be savored, rather than critiqued on historical accuracy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    I_saw_it_happen
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    People get tied up on whether or not this film portrays the life of Beethoven accurately; this misses the point of the film entirely. This is not so much a film about Beethoven, so much as the way in which he effected those around him, and inspired a devotion among his followers which lives to this day. If you consider a movie like, for instance, 'Shakespeare in Love'--- it's quite apparent to anyone who knows anything about Shakespeare that the film has only the faintest correlation to Shakespeare, which didn't seem to get in the way of people awarding THAT movie, and lauding praise on it, because Shakespeare was played as a hopeless romantic that everyone WANTS to believe in. While Immortal Beloved may share a similarity to S.I.L in it's, shall we say, creative interpretations, Immortal Beloved is a far superior film because it shows Beethoven in all aspects of his humanity. There's Beethoven as a Romantic rock star, there's the tender friend, the arrogant drunken bastard, the possessive misogynist, the pathetic misanthrope, all of it. Gary Oldman's role is superb. It is difficult to imagine anyone else in the role after seeing this movie. The acting is top-notch, albeit a bit melodramatic at points (Beethoven's assistant especially gets a bit heartfelt a bit often). There are a few scenes in this movie which are truly tearjerker moments. The scene in which 'Ode to Joy' is played is predictably great, even though it (like a lot of the film) feels a bit dated now. All in all, a rewarding and thoughtful piece on a man whose life was indeed complicated and monumental. Highly recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Idiotic Premise
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Richard Nathan (Richard-Nathan@att.net)
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/5/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After Beethoven died, love letters he had written to his "Immortal Beloved" were discovered. The name of the Immortal Beloved was not included in the letters. That all makes sense. However, in this film what is found is not letters but a will - in which Beethoven leaves his estate to his Immortal Beloved, but does not tell anyone who she is. Does that make sense to anyone? If he really wanted to leave her his estate, wouldn't it have occurred to him that it maybe it might have been a good idea to identify her by name? Are we supposed to think we was an idiot? Are we, perhaps, supposed to think he wrote the will while suffering from dementia? I can't think of any other reason why he would make a bequest to someone he declined to identify.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Forever Beethoven- visually audacious and musically majestic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I know that Immortal Beloved has been compared to Amadeus, and here I am going to keep my comparison brief, personally I don't think Immortal Beloved is quite as good as Amadeus, but I love both films with a passion. Ludwig Van Beethoven is my all time favourite classical music composer, and having watched Eroica with Ian Hart and the 3-part BBC dramatisation of Beethoven with Paul Rhys, I wanted to see what this film was like. My conclusion is that Immortal Beloved is a visually audacious, musically majestic and imaginative near-masterpiece. Immortal Beloved certainly looks stunning. The scenery is gorgeous, the costumes sumptuous and the cinematography fluid and beautiful. Seriously when you are transported to 18th century Vienna you feel like you have just come out of a time machine. There are also many effective scenes such as young Ludwig running away from his abusive father, Johanna visiting Beethoven as he lies dying in bed (one of the few times when a piece of classical music-the String Quartet Op.130 here- reduced me to tears in just one scene of one film), Beethoven resting his ear while playing the Moonlight Sonata, Beethoven with his back to the audience during the performance of the Choral Symphony and the performance of the Emperor concerto(I did read somewhere that during a concert when the orchestra wouldn't play the piece right, Beethoven stopped it and ordered for it to be played again). Even the use of Missa Solemnis was beautifully done, so hauntingly beautiful. The music is a revelation, pretty much the heart and soul of the film. It is a true delight from start to finish, I loved hearing the Moonlight and Pathetique sonatas, the Choral Symphony(the Ode to Joy movement has always been my favourite work of his), the Emperor Concerto,the violin concerto, Missa Solemnis and the 2nd movement of the 7th symphony as it was performed by the London Symphony Orchestra and conducted by Georg Solti. Bernard Rose is an unusual choice for director, having directed the gruesome horror film Caddyshack, but he does respectably as he seeks to identify the "immortal beloved" of Beethoven's will(to this day we don't know who Beethoven is referring to). The scripting is intelligent and moving, one might say it doesn't say much, but it has heart, and the story is solid, deep and doesn't meander. The acting is uniformly excellent. Jeroen Krabbe is fine as Anton Schindler, and Isabella Rosselini, Johanna ter Steege and Valeria Golino look beautiful and act very convincingly as the suspects of Beethoven's affections. I have to say though Gary Oldman does give the best performance of the film, while some scenes could have done with a touch more moderato it was a superb, charismatic and moving performance. I have read complaints that Oldman overacted, complaints I don't agree with at all. Just because Beethoven shouts a lot here, doesn't mean Oldman was overacting, and he certainly didn't overact in the final scene between him and Johanna, his acting was a masterclass of sheer poignancy there. Beethoven wasn't exactly a knight in shining armour now was he? He was rude, aggressive and reacted vehemently to even the smallest thing and probably traumatised by the memories of being abused by his alcoholic father. Beethoven also encountered alcoholism and increasing deafness, and by 1812 or so he was deaf completely. Overall, this is a wonderful, underrated film. Only problem with it? I did feel the ending was a little too open-and-shut, but maybe it is just me. I cannot deny though that this is a great film. 9.5/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Magnificent!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    potato2
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/8/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The year is 1827, and famed composer Ludwig van Beethoven has just died. He leaves his estate to someone only known as his "Immortal Beloved," so his secretary goes about finding out who she may be among his many lovers. This movie is absolutely beautiful. Beethoven's music, of course, is the soundtrack and also the main plot point, as the writer/director speculates on the events in the maestro's life that inspired each piece. The movie goes back and forth in time to each of the important people in Beethoven's life and we see his music evolve from much tragedy, some euphoria, and most of all, his passion for life. There is even a persuasive scene accounting for his deafness. With lavish costumes and picturesque Czech locations, it's lovely to look at but even more impressive is Gary Oldman's portrayal of Beethoven. Though playing a conceited, temperamental, and often angry man, Oldman still wins our sympathy and he is at his charismatic best. If you love Beethoven's music and/or period films, you'll enjoy this exciting biopic. Highly recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Immortally Performed!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SamuelSataniel
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/3/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The film is a very good look at the life and love of Ludwhig Beethoven. It is perhaps not one of the best films portraying a musician (Amadeus is perhaps far greater) but deserves to be observed. The best part of this film are the performances which are completely underrated. Gary Oldman who doesn't look the part makes it completely his own. He resembles the inner and outer life of this old genius. Gary Oldman himself a genius is great at performing genius. And the rest of the cast give a solid and strong framing for the entire story of Beethoven. This is a must see for fans of great acting and those who want to know the story of this immortal Man who shall live for all times.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A brief review of Immortal Beloved.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cluso502
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Immortal Beloved disappointed me. Being both a fan of Gary Oldman and Beethoven I thought nothing could go wrong, and nothing did, as far as the soundtrack and Gary Oldman's performance were concerned. But Several other aspects of the film fell short. The cinematography was boring, costuming was historical, but plain, dialogue was not bad, but had very little substance, and the story-line was quite unsatisfying. Several character choices were unexplained. I never felt like I got to know any of the characters. And frankly the film seemed utterly pointless. I learned nothing and It had little artistic value. However it wasn't all bad, Gary Oldman had a few nice scenes with Marco Hofschneider, although they were cut short. The saddest part is that this film could have been a masterpiece if only it had different direction. I would love to re edit this film myself just to make the story flow in a more interesting direction. I recommend it if you can catch it for free and have nothing better to do. But never pay for this film. 6/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This film is perfect- the genius of his music combined with the complexity of his nature....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dee Ross
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For me - Beethoven stands alone in his genre - especially for his time. Too many historians worry about minute details in a famous person's life - and discredit stories that take a more artistic approach to revealing something about that person. No one knows all there is to know about a man from the 18th and 19th centuries - especially about his inner soul and what drives him to brilliance and raging behavior. The idea that there could have been someone unknown is enticing, and the concept of a film telling about Beethoven through the eyes of others is not a new one, but a format that allows more flexibility. I personally am glad they took this approach. Character development was therefore much more interesting. Oldman's performance was brilliant - and as is often the case with Oldman - you come to feel you are really watching Beethoven. The other personalities also were developed well - and his music was shown in the context of his times - sometimes harsh (his father's beatings) - sometimes tumultuous (the Napoleonic Wars) - sometimes full of love ( the women in his life who did adore him), - and sometimes driven by personal disappointment and anger (the onset of deafness and possibly an unrequited love.....) Beethoven took music to the next level - adding emotion to the beauty and structure already employed by others..... Some are shocked when I say that he was like the Led Zeppelin of the 19th Century - evoking new responses from listeners then, and still one of the few classical composers that you can play for anyone today and they will say "WOW!". Even those who really aren't fans of this kind of music. That is why they chose the 9th Symphony to celebrate the new millennium in 2000 GLOBALLY. Beethoven is universal and timeless. The movie is a wonderful way of sharing a moment with the maestro.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    historically and biographically inaccurate
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ursulahemard
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Not at all convinced. Why? Because this movie has numerous historical inaccuracies aka no chronological order: Ludwig van Beethoven's (17 December 1770  26 March 1827) total deafness occurs far too early, LvB is conducting personally works he actually never did, composing works in the wrong time order, etc. In addition to that, the movie takes too many liberties, to my taste, about the biographical facts, and to imply that that famous love-letter, written by LvB to his 'Immortal Beloved', would be ultimately his sister-in-law is just utterly preposterous. That letter was written and could have been addressed to several very well known ladies, we meet some of them during the movie, nevertheless no absolute certainty was proved until today. But it's most certainly not his sister-in-law, with whom he had so many conflicts and legal battles over years. The idea that LvB composed the 9th for his sister- in-law as a-forgive-me-for-making-your-life-a-hell is the director's personal fabrication and so is the feeble ending. Also, there is much more to LvB than his 5th, 9th and the Pathetique and it's a shame that even these were cut into bits and pieces and added here and there without any musicality to the frames, but rather as background music. There is short scene when a white pianist is accompanied by a black violinist playing the Kreutzer Sonata; it did ring a bell but I had to look it up. The 'mulatto' violinist was supposed to be George Bridgetower (11 October 177829 February 1860) an Afro-Polish-born virtuoso who had a quite tempestuous professional relationship with LvB. Such a shame that this was not more elaborately depicted in the movie. That could have been a great instructive scene. LvB is quite distorted here and even the great actor Gary Oldman can't save his dignity nor the voluptuous and expensive production. Actually Mr Oldman is over the top but I blame it on the pathetic direction. Watchable for the young, but not very instructive. p.s. Hearing the gorgeous Isabella Rossellini speak a couple of sentences in Hungarian made me smile :-)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Tale of solitude
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vincentiu
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Extraordinary cast. Impressive story. And a great Oldman. A precise ballet behind cages and traps. Delicate tale about love as more than feelings or ordinary fight. Portrait of a genius from sketch to final signature. And drops of music like fundamental character. A movie without definition. A trip fed by gentle touches and shadow of abyss. Build with intelligent science of details, it seems be a good novel. But, step by step, it is more. A cruel love story's faces, description of solitude and vain hope, exercise of cruelty and selfish, slices of pain and force of fly. And a gallery of women's portraits. As pictures of a snail. As games of existence's pieces. The film is wonderful for the gift to be a kind of parable. Beethoven may be everyone. Johanna is every person for who the other is only a geometrical figure.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Immortal Beloved - The life of the Great Ludwig Van.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MortenKristofferVebjornsen
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I first became of interest, in the music of classical category... I first heard the glorious tunes of Beethoven. They stunned me as a child, and still does... Much effort from Beethoven's side was put into his pieces of music. There have been many films to include them, in their repertoire of music. The once I have seen is few, but powerful to say it the least. "A Clockwork Orange" directed by Stanley Kubrick, that pioneered music with its synthesizing of the composers most famous works- The great "Ode to Joy" to name one though. The way Alex in "A Clockwork Orange" talks about Beethoven in that film, is like if he is a God- An icon of Heavenly proportions. I could agree, but to me he is a great composer, and his music captivate me- Inspire me and helps me in bad times, when does occur. Then we have this film with Gary Oldman taking on the ambitiousness to play the troubled composer. This is "Immortal Beloved"... With a pressure, emphasis on the "E" in Belov"e"d. The film takes place, in the life of Beethoven. His symphonies reflect every stage he have had in his life of deafness, one of his other obstacles. Since of deafness he became, his music could have stopped there. Had it not been for his shear determination to compose music that to him meant something indeed. And to his audience. In his life, Beethoven had many lovers- They all treated him badly, and when he dies... They mourns over that they could not treat him the way he deserved. Beethoven as an artist, deaf that he was- Was indeed eccentric, and treated them better than they did him. What I said about his symphonies with they being connected to his life and so... I will not go into detail about them, but I will say that when "Ode to Joy" comes bombastic at ya... You will feel indeed how he felt when he was subjected to violence by his father. Hence, the ultra-violence was not far away though. His father wanted, knowing that the boy had talent... told a set of aristocratic people that he was nine and could play like Mozart... The boy was twelve. Failed and beaten up, for only to escape this madman in the tunes of "Ode to Joy". It is Epic and beyond comprehension of understanding the shear magnitude of his ways to compose the music he did... Deaf indeed that he was. I salute it completely. Gary Oldman captures what I can think, the sadness, the joy and the misery this artist had- To perfection within the boundaries of the films limit. The cinematography is so, and so... Yet some scenes in palaces and scenes of gardens are to say it the least beautiful to look at, and that is great enough for me. Sometimes, the image could have been executed better, by injecting less light, and more natural light being let in. In the scenes where Karl Van Beethoven tries to commit suicide, the shots of him walking in the woods feels very flat- But in the films length of two magnificent hours- This does not apply whatsoever. Karl is by the way the son of Ludwig Van... Here his lovers appear once more. There was one, that became his obsession, his muse. His Immortal Beloved. The wife of his brother Caspar. To her, he leaves everything- His music and his estate. Originally to his brothers this was to be given. The sad thing, she waited on him at a hotel- Only to leave as he arrived, sad I became indeed. The film puts you under the skin of Beethoven, and let you feel his journey told through flashbacks of the people he socialized with- that mostly being his lovers, and his assistant Schindler, played by Jeroen Krabb&eacute;. The acting is superb and the execution of the director Bernard Rose is great, and he have really caught the essence of Beethoven. The Man, The Artist and The Father. It is a great film, easily enjoyable, if you are into Beethoven- Then this maximizes by the numbers. It is easy to understand and you will feel like you are being part of the events displayed in the film. Now... play some music of Beethoven while you read this review again- to gain the effect I did while writing it. Preferably, the ninth. The End.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A movie to be savored, rather than critiqued on historical accuracy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    I_saw_it_happen
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    People get tied up on whether or not this film portrays the life of Beethoven accurately; this misses the point of the film entirely. This is not so much a film about Beethoven, so much as the way in which he effected those around him, and inspired a devotion among his followers which lives to this day. If you consider a movie like, for instance, 'Shakespeare in Love'--- it's quite apparent to anyone who knows anything about Shakespeare that the film has only the faintest correlation to Shakespeare, which didn't seem to get in the way of people awarding THAT movie, and lauding praise on it, because Shakespeare was played as a hopeless romantic that everyone WANTS to believe in. While Immortal Beloved may share a similarity to S.I.L in it's, shall we say, creative interpretations, Immortal Beloved is a far superior film because it shows Beethoven in all aspects of his humanity. There's Beethoven as a Romantic rock star, there's the tender friend, the arrogant drunken bastard, the possessive misogynist, the pathetic misanthrope, all of it. Gary Oldman's role is superb. It is difficult to imagine anyone else in the role after seeing this movie. The acting is top-notch, albeit a bit melodramatic at points (Beethoven's assistant especially gets a bit heartfelt a bit often). There are a few scenes in this movie which are truly tearjerker moments. The scene in which 'Ode to Joy' is played is predictably great, even though it (like a lot of the film) feels a bit dated now. All in all, a rewarding and thoughtful piece on a man whose life was indeed complicated and monumental. Highly recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Idiotic Premise
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Richard Nathan (Richard-Nathan@att.net)
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/5/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After Beethoven died, love letters he had written to his "Immortal Beloved" were discovered. The name of the Immortal Beloved was not included in the letters. That all makes sense. However, in this film what is found is not letters but a will - in which Beethoven leaves his estate to his Immortal Beloved, but does not tell anyone who she is. Does that make sense to anyone? If he really wanted to leave her his estate, wouldn't it have occurred to him that it maybe it might have been a good idea to identify her by name? Are we supposed to think we was an idiot? Are we, perhaps, supposed to think he wrote the will while suffering from dementia? I can't think of any other reason why he would make a bequest to someone he declined to identify.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Forever Beethoven- visually audacious and musically majestic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I know that Immortal Beloved has been compared to Amadeus, and here I am going to keep my comparison brief, personally I don't think Immortal Beloved is quite as good as Amadeus, but I love both films with a passion. Ludwig Van Beethoven is my all time favourite classical music composer, and having watched Eroica with Ian Hart and the 3-part BBC dramatisation of Beethoven with Paul Rhys, I wanted to see what this film was like. My conclusion is that Immortal Beloved is a visually audacious, musically majestic and imaginative near-masterpiece. Immortal Beloved certainly looks stunning. The scenery is gorgeous, the costumes sumptuous and the cinematography fluid and beautiful. Seriously when you are transported to 18th century Vienna you feel like you have just come out of a time machine. There are also many effective scenes such as young Ludwig running away from his abusive father, Johanna visiting Beethoven as he lies dying in bed (one of the few times when a piece of classical music-the String Quartet Op.130 here- reduced me to tears in just one scene of one film), Beethoven resting his ear while playing the Moonlight Sonata, Beethoven with his back to the audience during the performance of the Choral Symphony and the performance of the Emperor concerto(I did read somewhere that during a concert when the orchestra wouldn't play the piece right, Beethoven stopped it and ordered for it to be played again). Even the use of Missa Solemnis was beautifully done, so hauntingly beautiful. The music is a revelation, pretty much the heart and soul of the film. It is a true delight from start to finish, I loved hearing the Moonlight and Pathetique sonatas, the Choral Symphony(the Ode to Joy movement has always been my favourite work of his), the Emperor Concerto,the violin concerto, Missa Solemnis and the 2nd movement of the 7th symphony as it was performed by the London Symphony Orchestra and conducted by Georg Solti. Bernard Rose is an unusual choice for director, having directed the gruesome horror film Caddyshack, but he does respectably as he seeks to identify the "immortal beloved" of Beethoven's will(to this day we don't know who Beethoven is referring to). The scripting is intelligent and moving, one might say it doesn't say much, but it has heart, and the story is solid, deep and doesn't meander. The acting is uniformly excellent. Jeroen Krabbe is fine as Anton Schindler, and Isabella Rosselini, Johanna ter Steege and Valeria Golino look beautiful and act very convincingly as the suspects of Beethoven's affections. I have to say though Gary Oldman does give the best performance of the film, while some scenes could have done with a touch more moderato it was a superb, charismatic and moving performance. I have read complaints that Oldman overacted, complaints I don't agree with at all. Just because Beethoven shouts a lot here, doesn't mean Oldman was overacting, and he certainly didn't overact in the final scene between him and Johanna, his acting was a masterclass of sheer poignancy there. Beethoven wasn't exactly a knight in shining armour now was he? He was rude, aggressive and reacted vehemently to even the smallest thing and probably traumatised by the memories of being abused by his alcoholic father. Beethoven also encountered alcoholism and increasing deafness, and by 1812 or so he was deaf completely. Overall, this is a wonderful, underrated film. Only problem with it? I did feel the ending was a little too open-and-shut, but maybe it is just me. I cannot deny though that this is a great film. 9.5/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Magnificent!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    potato2
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/8/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The year is 1827, and famed composer Ludwig van Beethoven has just died. He leaves his estate to someone only known as his "Immortal Beloved," so his secretary goes about finding out who she may be among his many lovers. This movie is absolutely beautiful. Beethoven's music, of course, is the soundtrack and also the main plot point, as the writer/director speculates on the events in the maestro's life that inspired each piece. The movie goes back and forth in time to each of the important people in Beethoven's life and we see his music evolve from much tragedy, some euphoria, and most of all, his passion for life. There is even a persuasive scene accounting for his deafness. With lavish costumes and picturesque Czech locations, it's lovely to look at but even more impressive is Gary Oldman's portrayal of Beethoven. Though playing a conceited, temperamental, and often angry man, Oldman still wins our sympathy and he is at his charismatic best. If you love Beethoven's music and/or period films, you'll enjoy this exciting biopic. Highly recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Immortally Performed!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SamuelSataniel
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/3/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The film is a very good look at the life and love of Ludwhig Beethoven. It is perhaps not one of the best films portraying a musician (Amadeus is perhaps far greater) but deserves to be observed. The best part of this film are the performances which are completely underrated. Gary Oldman who doesn't look the part makes it completely his own. He resembles the inner and outer life of this old genius. Gary Oldman himself a genius is great at performing genius. And the rest of the cast give a solid and strong framing for the entire story of Beethoven. This is a must see for fans of great acting and those who want to know the story of this immortal Man who shall live for all times.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A brief review of Immortal Beloved.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cluso502
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Immortal Beloved disappointed me. Being both a fan of Gary Oldman and Beethoven I thought nothing could go wrong, and nothing did, as far as the soundtrack and Gary Oldman's performance were concerned. But Several other aspects of the film fell short. The cinematography was boring, costuming was historical, but plain, dialogue was not bad, but had very little substance, and the story-line was quite unsatisfying. Several character choices were unexplained. I never felt like I got to know any of the characters. And frankly the film seemed utterly pointless. I learned nothing and It had little artistic value. However it wasn't all bad, Gary Oldman had a few nice scenes with Marco Hofschneider, although they were cut short. The saddest part is that this film could have been a masterpiece if only it had different direction. I would love to re edit this film myself just to make the story flow in a more interesting direction. I recommend it if you can catch it for free and have nothing better to do. But never pay for this film. 6/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This film is perfect- the genius of his music combined with the complexity of his nature....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dee Ross
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For me - Beethoven stands alone in his genre - especially for his time. Too many historians worry about minute details in a famous person's life - and discredit stories that take a more artistic approach to revealing something about that person. No one knows all there is to know about a man from the 18th and 19th centuries - especially about his inner soul and what drives him to brilliance and raging behavior. The idea that there could have been someone unknown is enticing, and the concept of a film telling about Beethoven through the eyes of others is not a new one, but a format that allows more flexibility. I personally am glad they took this approach. Character development was therefore much more interesting. Oldman's performance was brilliant - and as is often the case with Oldman - you come to feel you are really watching Beethoven. The other personalities also were developed well - and his music was shown in the context of his times - sometimes harsh (his father's beatings) - sometimes tumultuous (the Napoleonic Wars) - sometimes full of love ( the women in his life who did adore him), - and sometimes driven by personal disappointment and anger (the onset of deafness and possibly an unrequited love.....) Beethoven took music to the next level - adding emotion to the beauty and structure already employed by others..... Some are shocked when I say that he was like the Led Zeppelin of the 19th Century - evoking new responses from listeners then, and still one of the few classical composers that you can play for anyone today and they will say "WOW!". Even those who really aren't fans of this kind of music. That is why they chose the 9th Symphony to celebrate the new millennium in 2000 GLOBALLY. Beethoven is universal and timeless. The movie is a wonderful way of sharing a moment with the maestro.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    historically and biographically inaccurate
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ursulahemard
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Not at all convinced. Why? Because this movie has numerous historical inaccuracies aka no chronological order: Ludwig van Beethoven's (17 December 1770  26 March 1827) total deafness occurs far too early, LvB is conducting personally works he actually never did, composing works in the wrong time order, etc. In addition to that, the movie takes too many liberties, to my taste, about the biographical facts, and to imply that that famous love-letter, written by LvB to his 'Immortal Beloved', would be ultimately his sister-in-law is just utterly preposterous. That letter was written and could have been addressed to several very well known ladies, we meet some of them during the movie, nevertheless no absolute certainty was proved until today. But it's most certainly not his sister-in-law, with whom he had so many conflicts and legal battles over years. The idea that LvB composed the 9th for his sister- in-law as a-forgive-me-for-making-your-life-a-hell is the director's personal fabrication and so is the feeble ending. Also, there is much more to LvB than his 5th, 9th and the Pathetique and it's a shame that even these were cut into bits and pieces and added here and there without any musicality to the frames, but rather as background music. There is short scene when a white pianist is accompanied by a black violinist playing the Kreutzer Sonata; it did ring a bell but I had to look it up. The 'mulatto' violinist was supposed to be George Bridgetower (11 October 177829 February 1860) an Afro-Polish-born virtuoso who had a quite tempestuous professional relationship with LvB. Such a shame that this was not more elaborately depicted in the movie. That could have been a great instructive scene. LvB is quite distorted here and even the great actor Gary Oldman can't save his dignity nor the voluptuous and expensive production. Actually Mr Oldman is over the top but I blame it on the pathetic direction. Watchable for the young, but not very instructive. p.s. Hearing the gorgeous Isabella Rossellini speak a couple of sentences in Hungarian made me smile :-)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Tale of solitude
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vincentiu
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Extraordinary cast. Impressive story. And a great Oldman. A precise ballet behind cages and traps. Delicate tale about love as more than feelings or ordinary fight. Portrait of a genius from sketch to final signature. And drops of music like fundamental character. A movie without definition. A trip fed by gentle touches and shadow of abyss. Build with intelligent science of details, it seems be a good novel. But, step by step, it is more. A cruel love story's faces, description of solitude and vain hope, exercise of cruelty and selfish, slices of pain and force of fly. And a gallery of women's portraits. As pictures of a snail. As games of existence's pieces. The film is wonderful for the gift to be a kind of parable. Beethoven may be everyone. Johanna is every person for who the other is only a geometrical figure.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Immortal Beloved - The life of the Great Ludwig Van.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MortenKristofferVebjornsen
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I first became of interest, in the music of classical category... I first heard the glorious tunes of Beethoven. They stunned me as a child, and still does... Much effort from Beethoven's side was put into his pieces of music. There have been many films to include them, in their repertoire of music. The once I have seen is few, but powerful to say it the least. "A Clockwork Orange" directed by Stanley Kubrick, that pioneered music with its synthesizing of the composers most famous works- The great "Ode to Joy" to name one though. The way Alex in "A Clockwork Orange" talks about Beethoven in that film, is like if he is a God- An icon of Heavenly proportions. I could agree, but to me he is a great composer, and his music captivate me- Inspire me and helps me in bad times, when does occur. Then we have this film with Gary Oldman taking on the ambitiousness to play the troubled composer. This is "Immortal Beloved"... With a pressure, emphasis on the "E" in Belov"e"d. The film takes place, in the life of Beethoven. His symphonies reflect every stage he have had in his life of deafness, one of his other obstacles. Since of deafness he became, his music could have stopped there. Had it not been for his shear determination to compose music that to him meant something indeed. And to his audience. In his life, Beethoven had many lovers- They all treated him badly, and when he dies... They mourns over that they could not treat him the way he deserved. Beethoven as an artist, deaf that he was- Was indeed eccentric, and treated them better than they did him. What I said about his symphonies with they being connected to his life and so... I will not go into detail about them, but I will say that when "Ode to Joy" comes bombastic at ya... You will feel indeed how he felt when he was subjected to violence by his father. Hence, the ultra-violence was not far away though. His father wanted, knowing that the boy had talent... told a set of aristocratic people that he was nine and could play like Mozart... The boy was twelve. Failed and beaten up, for only to escape this madman in the tunes of "Ode to Joy". It is Epic and beyond comprehension of understanding the shear magnitude of his ways to compose the music he did... Deaf indeed that he was. I salute it completely. Gary Oldman captures what I can think, the sadness, the joy and the misery this artist had- To perfection within the boundaries of the films limit. The cinematography is so, and so... Yet some scenes in palaces and scenes of gardens are to say it the least beautiful to look at, and that is great enough for me. Sometimes, the image could have been executed better, by injecting less light, and more natural light being let in. In the scenes where Karl Van Beethoven tries to commit suicide, the shots of him walking in the woods feels very flat- But in the films length of two magnificent hours- This does not apply whatsoever. Karl is by the way the son of Ludwig Van... Here his lovers appear once more. There was one, that became his obsession, his muse. His Immortal Beloved. The wife of his brother Caspar. To her, he leaves everything- His music and his estate. Originally to his brothers this was to be given. The sad thing, she waited on him at a hotel- Only to leave as he arrived, sad I became indeed. The film puts you under the skin of Beethoven, and let you feel his journey told through flashbacks of the people he socialized with- that mostly being his lovers, and his assistant Schindler, played by Jeroen Krabb&eacute;. The acting is superb and the execution of the director Bernard Rose is great, and he have really caught the essence of Beethoven. The Man, The Artist and The Father. It is a great film, easily enjoyable, if you are into Beethoven- Then this maximizes by the numbers. It is easy to understand and you will feel like you are being part of the events displayed in the film. Now... play some music of Beethoven while you read this review again- to gain the effect I did while writing it. Preferably, the ninth. The End.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A movie to be savored, rather than critiqued on historical accuracy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    I_saw_it_happen
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    People get tied up on whether or not this film portrays the life of Beethoven accurately; this misses the point of the film entirely. This is not so much a film about Beethoven, so much as the way in which he effected those around him, and inspired a devotion among his followers which lives to this day. If you consider a movie like, for instance, 'Shakespeare in Love'--- it's quite apparent to anyone who knows anything about Shakespeare that the film has only the faintest correlation to Shakespeare, which didn't seem to get in the way of people awarding THAT movie, and lauding praise on it, because Shakespeare was played as a hopeless romantic that everyone WANTS to believe in. While Immortal Beloved may share a similarity to S.I.L in it's, shall we say, creative interpretations, Immortal Beloved is a far superior film because it shows Beethoven in all aspects of his humanity. There's Beethoven as a Romantic rock star, there's the tender friend, the arrogant drunken bastard, the possessive misogynist, the pathetic misanthrope, all of it. Gary Oldman's role is superb. It is difficult to imagine anyone else in the role after seeing this movie. The acting is top-notch, albeit a bit melodramatic at points (Beethoven's assistant especially gets a bit heartfelt a bit often). There are a few scenes in this movie which are truly tearjerker moments. The scene in which 'Ode to Joy' is played is predictably great, even though it (like a lot of the film) feels a bit dated now. All in all, a rewarding and thoughtful piece on a man whose life was indeed complicated and monumental. Highly recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Idiotic Premise
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Richard Nathan (Richard-Nathan@att.net)
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/5/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After Beethoven died, love letters he had written to his "Immortal Beloved" were discovered. The name of the Immortal Beloved was not included in the letters. That all makes sense. However, in this film what is found is not letters but a will - in which Beethoven leaves his estate to his Immortal Beloved, but does not tell anyone who she is. Does that make sense to anyone? If he really wanted to leave her his estate, wouldn't it have occurred to him that it maybe it might have been a good idea to identify her by name? Are we supposed to think we was an idiot? Are we, perhaps, supposed to think he wrote the will while suffering from dementia? I can't think of any other reason why he would make a bequest to someone he declined to identify.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Forever Beethoven- visually audacious and musically majestic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I know that Immortal Beloved has been compared to Amadeus, and here I am going to keep my comparison brief, personally I don't think Immortal Beloved is quite as good as Amadeus, but I love both films with a passion. Ludwig Van Beethoven is my all time favourite classical music composer, and having watched Eroica with Ian Hart and the 3-part BBC dramatisation of Beethoven with Paul Rhys, I wanted to see what this film was like. My conclusion is that Immortal Beloved is a visually audacious, musically majestic and imaginative near-masterpiece. Immortal Beloved certainly looks stunning. The scenery is gorgeous, the costumes sumptuous and the cinematography fluid and beautiful. Seriously when you are transported to 18th century Vienna you feel like you have just come out of a time machine. There are also many effective scenes such as young Ludwig running away from his abusive father, Johanna visiting Beethoven as he lies dying in bed (one of the few times when a piece of classical music-the String Quartet Op.130 here- reduced me to tears in just one scene of one film), Beethoven resting his ear while playing the Moonlight Sonata, Beethoven with his back to the audience during the performance of the Choral Symphony and the performance of the Emperor concerto(I did read somewhere that during a concert when the orchestra wouldn't play the piece right, Beethoven stopped it and ordered for it to be played again). Even the use of Missa Solemnis was beautifully done, so hauntingly beautiful. The music is a revelation, pretty much the heart and soul of the film. It is a true delight from start to finish, I loved hearing the Moonlight and Pathetique sonatas, the Choral Symphony(the Ode to Joy movement has always been my favourite work of his), the Emperor Concerto,the violin concerto, Missa Solemnis and the 2nd movement of the 7th symphony as it was performed by the London Symphony Orchestra and conducted by Georg Solti. Bernard Rose is an unusual choice for director, having directed the gruesome horror film Caddyshack, but he does respectably as he seeks to identify the "immortal beloved" of Beethoven's will(to this day we don't know who Beethoven is referring to). The scripting is intelligent and moving, one might say it doesn't say much, but it has heart, and the story is solid, deep and doesn't meander. The acting is uniformly excellent. Jeroen Krabbe is fine as Anton Schindler, and Isabella Rosselini, Johanna ter Steege and Valeria Golino look beautiful and act very convincingly as the suspects of Beethoven's affections. I have to say though Gary Oldman does give the best performance of the film, while some scenes could have done with a touch more moderato it was a superb, charismatic and moving performance. I have read complaints that Oldman overacted, complaints I don't agree with at all. Just because Beethoven shouts a lot here, doesn't mean Oldman was overacting, and he certainly didn't overact in the final scene between him and Johanna, his acting was a masterclass of sheer poignancy there. Beethoven wasn't exactly a knight in shining armour now was he? He was rude, aggressive and reacted vehemently to even the smallest thing and probably traumatised by the memories of being abused by his alcoholic father. Beethoven also encountered alcoholism and increasing deafness, and by 1812 or so he was deaf completely. Overall, this is a wonderful, underrated film. Only problem with it? I did feel the ending was a little too open-and-shut, but maybe it is just me. I cannot deny though that this is a great film. 9.5/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Magnificent!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    potato2
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/8/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The year is 1827, and famed composer Ludwig van Beethoven has just died. He leaves his estate to someone only known as his "Immortal Beloved," so his secretary goes about finding out who she may be among his many lovers. This movie is absolutely beautiful. Beethoven's music, of course, is the soundtrack and also the main plot point, as the writer/director speculates on the events in the maestro's life that inspired each piece. The movie goes back and forth in time to each of the important people in Beethoven's life and we see his music evolve from much tragedy, some euphoria, and most of all, his passion for life. There is even a persuasive scene accounting for his deafness. With lavish costumes and picturesque Czech locations, it's lovely to look at but even more impressive is Gary Oldman's portrayal of Beethoven. Though playing a conceited, temperamental, and often angry man, Oldman still wins our sympathy and he is at his charismatic best. If you love Beethoven's music and/or period films, you'll enjoy this exciting biopic. Highly recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Immortally Performed!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SamuelSataniel
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/3/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The film is a very good look at the life and love of Ludwhig Beethoven. It is perhaps not one of the best films portraying a musician (Amadeus is perhaps far greater) but deserves to be observed. The best part of this film are the performances which are completely underrated. Gary Oldman who doesn't look the part makes it completely his own. He resembles the inner and outer life of this old genius. Gary Oldman himself a genius is great at performing genius. And the rest of the cast give a solid and strong framing for the entire story of Beethoven. This is a must see for fans of great acting and those who want to know the story of this immortal Man who shall live for all times.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A brief review of Immortal Beloved.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cluso502
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Immortal Beloved disappointed me. Being both a fan of Gary Oldman and Beethoven I thought nothing could go wrong, and nothing did, as far as the soundtrack and Gary Oldman's performance were concerned. But Several other aspects of the film fell short. The cinematography was boring, costuming was historical, but plain, dialogue was not bad, but had very little substance, and the story-line was quite unsatisfying. Several character choices were unexplained. I never felt like I got to know any of the characters. And frankly the film seemed utterly pointless. I learned nothing and It had little artistic value. However it wasn't all bad, Gary Oldman had a few nice scenes with Marco Hofschneider, although they were cut short. The saddest part is that this film could have been a masterpiece if only it had different direction. I would love to re edit this film myself just to make the story flow in a more interesting direction. I recommend it if you can catch it for free and have nothing better to do. But never pay for this film. 6/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This film is perfect- the genius of his music combined with the complexity of his nature....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dee Ross
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For me - Beethoven stands alone in his genre - especially for his time. Too many historians worry about minute details in a famous person's life - and discredit stories that take a more artistic approach to revealing something about that person. No one knows all there is to know about a man from the 18th and 19th centuries - especially about his inner soul and what drives him to brilliance and raging behavior. The idea that there could have been someone unknown is enticing, and the concept of a film telling about Beethoven through the eyes of others is not a new one, but a format that allows more flexibility. I personally am glad they took this approach. Character development was therefore much more interesting. Oldman's performance was brilliant - and as is often the case with Oldman - you come to feel you are really watching Beethoven. The other personalities also were developed well - and his music was shown in the context of his times - sometimes harsh (his father's beatings) - sometimes tumultuous (the Napoleonic Wars) - sometimes full of love ( the women in his life who did adore him), - and sometimes driven by personal disappointment and anger (the onset of deafness and possibly an unrequited love.....) Beethoven took music to the next level - adding emotion to the beauty and structure already employed by others..... Some are shocked when I say that he was like the Led Zeppelin of the 19th Century - evoking new responses from listeners then, and still one of the few classical composers that you can play for anyone today and they will say "WOW!". Even those who really aren't fans of this kind of music. That is why they chose the 9th Symphony to celebrate the new millennium in 2000 GLOBALLY. Beethoven is universal and timeless. The movie is a wonderful way of sharing a moment with the maestro.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    historically and biographically inaccurate
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ursulahemard
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Not at all convinced. Why? Because this movie has numerous historical inaccuracies aka no chronological order: Ludwig van Beethoven's (17 December 1770  26 March 1827) total deafness occurs far too early, LvB is conducting personally works he actually never did, composing works in the wrong time order, etc. In addition to that, the movie takes too many liberties, to my taste, about the biographical facts, and to imply that that famous love-letter, written by LvB to his 'Immortal Beloved', would be ultimately his sister-in-law is just utterly preposterous. That letter was written and could have been addressed to several very well known ladies, we meet some of them during the movie, nevertheless no absolute certainty was proved until today. But it's most certainly not his sister-in-law, with whom he had so many conflicts and legal battles over years. The idea that LvB composed the 9th for his sister- in-law as a-forgive-me-for-making-your-life-a-hell is the director's personal fabrication and so is the feeble ending. Also, there is much more to LvB than his 5th, 9th and the Pathetique and it's a shame that even these were cut into bits and pieces and added here and there without any musicality to the frames, but rather as background music. There is short scene when a white pianist is accompanied by a black violinist playing the Kreutzer Sonata; it did ring a bell but I had to look it up. The 'mulatto' violinist was supposed to be George Bridgetower (11 October 177829 February 1860) an Afro-Polish-born virtuoso who had a quite tempestuous professional relationship with LvB. Such a shame that this was not more elaborately depicted in the movie. That could have been a great instructive scene. LvB is quite distorted here and even the great actor Gary Oldman can't save his dignity nor the voluptuous and expensive production. Actually Mr Oldman is over the top but I blame it on the pathetic direction. Watchable for the young, but not very instructive. p.s. Hearing the gorgeous Isabella Rossellini speak a couple of sentences in Hungarian made me smile :-)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Tale of solitude
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vincentiu
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Extraordinary cast. Impressive story. And a great Oldman. A precise ballet behind cages and traps. Delicate tale about love as more than feelings or ordinary fight. Portrait of a genius from sketch to final signature. And drops of music like fundamental character. A movie without definition. A trip fed by gentle touches and shadow of abyss. Build with intelligent science of details, it seems be a good novel. But, step by step, it is more. A cruel love story's faces, description of solitude and vain hope, exercise of cruelty and selfish, slices of pain and force of fly. And a gallery of women's portraits. As pictures of a snail. As games of existence's pieces. The film is wonderful for the gift to be a kind of parable. Beethoven may be everyone. Johanna is every person for who the other is only a geometrical figure.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Immortal Beloved - The life of the Great Ludwig Van.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MortenKristofferVebjornsen
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I first became of interest, in the music of classical category... I first heard the glorious tunes of Beethoven. They stunned me as a child, and still does... Much effort from Beethoven's side was put into his pieces of music. There have been many films to include them, in their repertoire of music. The once I have seen is few, but powerful to say it the least. "A Clockwork Orange" directed by Stanley Kubrick, that pioneered music with its synthesizing of the composers most famous works- The great "Ode to Joy" to name one though. The way Alex in "A Clockwork Orange" talks about Beethoven in that film, is like if he is a God- An icon of Heavenly proportions. I could agree, but to me he is a great composer, and his music captivate me- Inspire me and helps me in bad times, when does occur. Then we have this film with Gary Oldman taking on the ambitiousness to play the troubled composer. This is "Immortal Beloved"... With a pressure, emphasis on the "E" in Belov"e"d. The film takes place, in the life of Beethoven. His symphonies reflect every stage he have had in his life of deafness, one of his other obstacles. Since of deafness he became, his music could have stopped there. Had it not been for his shear determination to compose music that to him meant something indeed. And to his audience. In his life, Beethoven had many lovers- They all treated him badly, and when he dies... They mourns over that they could not treat him the way he deserved. Beethoven as an artist, deaf that he was- Was indeed eccentric, and treated them better than they did him. What I said about his symphonies with they being connected to his life and so... I will not go into detail about them, but I will say that when "Ode to Joy" comes bombastic at ya... You will feel indeed how he felt when he was subjected to violence by his father. Hence, the ultra-violence was not far away though. His father wanted, knowing that the boy had talent... told a set of aristocratic people that he was nine and could play like Mozart... The boy was twelve. Failed and beaten up, for only to escape this madman in the tunes of "Ode to Joy". It is Epic and beyond comprehension of understanding the shear magnitude of his ways to compose the music he did... Deaf indeed that he was. I salute it completely. Gary Oldman captures what I can think, the sadness, the joy and the misery this artist had- To perfection within the boundaries of the films limit. The cinematography is so, and so... Yet some scenes in palaces and scenes of gardens are to say it the least beautiful to look at, and that is great enough for me. Sometimes, the image could have been executed better, by injecting less light, and more natural light being let in. In the scenes where Karl Van Beethoven tries to commit suicide, the shots of him walking in the woods feels very flat- But in the films length of two magnificent hours- This does not apply whatsoever. Karl is by the way the son of Ludwig Van... Here his lovers appear once more. There was one, that became his obsession, his muse. His Immortal Beloved. The wife of his brother Caspar. To her, he leaves everything- His music and his estate. Originally to his brothers this was to be given. The sad thing, she waited on him at a hotel- Only to leave as he arrived, sad I became indeed. The film puts you under the skin of Beethoven, and let you feel his journey told through flashbacks of the people he socialized with- that mostly being his lovers, and his assistant Schindler, played by Jeroen Krabb&eacute;. The acting is superb and the execution of the director Bernard Rose is great, and he have really caught the essence of Beethoven. The Man, The Artist and The Father. It is a great film, easily enjoyable, if you are into Beethoven- Then this maximizes by the numbers. It is easy to understand and you will feel like you are being part of the events displayed in the film. Now... play some music of Beethoven while you read this review again- to gain the effect I did while writing it. Preferably, the ninth. The End.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A movie to be savored, rather than critiqued on historical accuracy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    I_saw_it_happen
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    People get tied up on whether or not this film portrays the life of Beethoven accurately; this misses the point of the film entirely. This is not so much a film about Beethoven, so much as the way in which he effected those around him, and inspired a devotion among his followers which lives to this day. If you consider a movie like, for instance, 'Shakespeare in Love'--- it's quite apparent to anyone who knows anything about Shakespeare that the film has only the faintest correlation to Shakespeare, which didn't seem to get in the way of people awarding THAT movie, and lauding praise on it, because Shakespeare was played as a hopeless romantic that everyone WANTS to believe in. While Immortal Beloved may share a similarity to S.I.L in it's, shall we say, creative interpretations, Immortal Beloved is a far superior film because it shows Beethoven in all aspects of his humanity. There's Beethoven as a Romantic rock star, there's the tender friend, the arrogant drunken bastard, the possessive misogynist, the pathetic misanthrope, all of it. Gary Oldman's role is superb. It is difficult to imagine anyone else in the role after seeing this movie. The acting is top-notch, albeit a bit melodramatic at points (Beethoven's assistant especially gets a bit heartfelt a bit often). There are a few scenes in this movie which are truly tearjerker moments. The scene in which 'Ode to Joy' is played is predictably great, even though it (like a lot of the film) feels a bit dated now. All in all, a rewarding and thoughtful piece on a man whose life was indeed complicated and monumental. Highly recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Idiotic Premise
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Richard Nathan (Richard-Nathan@att.net)
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/5/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After Beethoven died, love letters he had written to his "Immortal Beloved" were discovered. The name of the Immortal Beloved was not included in the letters. That all makes sense. However, in this film what is found is not letters but a will - in which Beethoven leaves his estate to his Immortal Beloved, but does not tell anyone who she is. Does that make sense to anyone? If he really wanted to leave her his estate, wouldn't it have occurred to him that it maybe it might have been a good idea to identify her by name? Are we supposed to think we was an idiot? Are we, perhaps, supposed to think he wrote the will while suffering from dementia? I can't think of any other reason why he would make a bequest to someone he declined to identify.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Forever Beethoven- visually audacious and musically majestic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I know that Immortal Beloved has been compared to Amadeus, and here I am going to keep my comparison brief, personally I don't think Immortal Beloved is quite as good as Amadeus, but I love both films with a passion. Ludwig Van Beethoven is my all time favourite classical music composer, and having watched Eroica with Ian Hart and the 3-part BBC dramatisation of Beethoven with Paul Rhys, I wanted to see what this film was like. My conclusion is that Immortal Beloved is a visually audacious, musically majestic and imaginative near-masterpiece. Immortal Beloved certainly looks stunning. The scenery is gorgeous, the costumes sumptuous and the cinematography fluid and beautiful. Seriously when you are transported to 18th century Vienna you feel like you have just come out of a time machine. There are also many effective scenes such as young Ludwig running away from his abusive father, Johanna visiting Beethoven as he lies dying in bed (one of the few times when a piece of classical music-the String Quartet Op.130 here- reduced me to tears in just one scene of one film), Beethoven resting his ear while playing the Moonlight Sonata, Beethoven with his back to the audience during the performance of the Choral Symphony and the performance of the Emperor concerto(I did read somewhere that during a concert when the orchestra wouldn't play the piece right, Beethoven stopped it and ordered for it to be played again). Even the use of Missa Solemnis was beautifully done, so hauntingly beautiful. The music is a revelation, pretty much the heart and soul of the film. It is a true delight from start to finish, I loved hearing the Moonlight and Pathetique sonatas, the Choral Symphony(the Ode to Joy movement has always been my favourite work of his), the Emperor Concerto,the violin concerto, Missa Solemnis and the 2nd movement of the 7th symphony as it was performed by the London Symphony Orchestra and conducted by Georg Solti. Bernard Rose is an unusual choice for director, having directed the gruesome horror film Caddyshack, but he does respectably as he seeks to identify the "immortal beloved" of Beethoven's will(to this day we don't know who Beethoven is referring to). The scripting is intelligent and moving, one might say it doesn't say much, but it has heart, and the story is solid, deep and doesn't meander. The acting is uniformly excellent. Jeroen Krabbe is fine as Anton Schindler, and Isabella Rosselini, Johanna ter Steege and Valeria Golino look beautiful and act very convincingly as the suspects of Beethoven's affections. I have to say though Gary Oldman does give the best performance of the film, while some scenes could have done with a touch more moderato it was a superb, charismatic and moving performance. I have read complaints that Oldman overacted, complaints I don't agree with at all. Just because Beethoven shouts a lot here, doesn't mean Oldman was overacting, and he certainly didn't overact in the final scene between him and Johanna, his acting was a masterclass of sheer poignancy there. Beethoven wasn't exactly a knight in shining armour now was he? He was rude, aggressive and reacted vehemently to even the smallest thing and probably traumatised by the memories of being abused by his alcoholic father. Beethoven also encountered alcoholism and increasing deafness, and by 1812 or so he was deaf completely. Overall, this is a wonderful, underrated film. Only problem with it? I did feel the ending was a little too open-and-shut, but maybe it is just me. I cannot deny though that this is a great film. 9.5/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Magnificent!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    potato2
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/8/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The year is 1827, and famed composer Ludwig van Beethoven has just died. He leaves his estate to someone only known as his "Immortal Beloved," so his secretary goes about finding out who she may be among his many lovers. This movie is absolutely beautiful. Beethoven's music, of course, is the soundtrack and also the main plot point, as the writer/director speculates on the events in the maestro's life that inspired each piece. The movie goes back and forth in time to each of the important people in Beethoven's life and we see his music evolve from much tragedy, some euphoria, and most of all, his passion for life. There is even a persuasive scene accounting for his deafness. With lavish costumes and picturesque Czech locations, it's lovely to look at but even more impressive is Gary Oldman's portrayal of Beethoven. Though playing a conceited, temperamental, and often angry man, Oldman still wins our sympathy and he is at his charismatic best. If you love Beethoven's music and/or period films, you'll enjoy this exciting biopic. Highly recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Immortally Performed!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SamuelSataniel
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/3/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The film is a very good look at the life and love of Ludwhig Beethoven. It is perhaps not one of the best films portraying a musician (Amadeus is perhaps far greater) but deserves to be observed. The best part of this film are the performances which are completely underrated. Gary Oldman who doesn't look the part makes it completely his own. He resembles the inner and outer life of this old genius. Gary Oldman himself a genius is great at performing genius. And the rest of the cast give a solid and strong framing for the entire story of Beethoven. This is a must see for fans of great acting and those who want to know the story of this immortal Man who shall live for all times.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A brief review of Immortal Beloved.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cluso502
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Immortal Beloved disappointed me. Being both a fan of Gary Oldman and Beethoven I thought nothing could go wrong, and nothing did, as far as the soundtrack and Gary Oldman's performance were concerned. But Several other aspects of the film fell short. The cinematography was boring, costuming was historical, but plain, dialogue was not bad, but had very little substance, and the story-line was quite unsatisfying. Several character choices were unexplained. I never felt like I got to know any of the characters. And frankly the film seemed utterly pointless. I learned nothing and It had little artistic value. However it wasn't all bad, Gary Oldman had a few nice scenes with Marco Hofschneider, although they were cut short. The saddest part is that this film could have been a masterpiece if only it had different direction. I would love to re edit this film myself just to make the story flow in a more interesting direction. I recommend it if you can catch it for free and have nothing better to do. But never pay for this film. 6/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This film is perfect- the genius of his music combined with the complexity of his nature....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dee Ross
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For me - Beethoven stands alone in his genre - especially for his time. Too many historians worry about minute details in a famous person's life - and discredit stories that take a more artistic approach to revealing something about that person. No one knows all there is to know about a man from the 18th and 19th centuries - especially about his inner soul and what drives him to brilliance and raging behavior. The idea that there could have been someone unknown is enticing, and the concept of a film telling about Beethoven through the eyes of others is not a new one, but a format that allows more flexibility. I personally am glad they took this approach. Character development was therefore much more interesting. Oldman's performance was brilliant - and as is often the case with Oldman - you come to feel you are really watching Beethoven. The other personalities also were developed well - and his music was shown in the context of his times - sometimes harsh (his father's beatings) - sometimes tumultuous (the Napoleonic Wars) - sometimes full of love ( the women in his life who did adore him), - and sometimes driven by personal disappointment and anger (the onset of deafness and possibly an unrequited love.....) Beethoven took music to the next level - adding emotion to the beauty and structure already employed by others..... Some are shocked when I say that he was like the Led Zeppelin of the 19th Century - evoking new responses from listeners then, and still one of the few classical composers that you can play for anyone today and they will say "WOW!". Even those who really aren't fans of this kind of music. That is why they chose the 9th Symphony to celebrate the new millennium in 2000 GLOBALLY. Beethoven is universal and timeless. The movie is a wonderful way of sharing a moment with the maestro.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    historically and biographically inaccurate
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ursulahemard
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Not at all convinced. Why? Because this movie has numerous historical inaccuracies aka no chronological order: Ludwig van Beethoven's (17 December 1770  26 March 1827) total deafness occurs far too early, LvB is conducting personally works he actually never did, composing works in the wrong time order, etc. In addition to that, the movie takes too many liberties, to my taste, about the biographical facts, and to imply that that famous love-letter, written by LvB to his 'Immortal Beloved', would be ultimately his sister-in-law is just utterly preposterous. That letter was written and could have been addressed to several very well known ladies, we meet some of them during the movie, nevertheless no absolute certainty was proved until today. But it's most certainly not his sister-in-law, with whom he had so many conflicts and legal battles over years. The idea that LvB composed the 9th for his sister- in-law as a-forgive-me-for-making-your-life-a-hell is the director's personal fabrication and so is the feeble ending. Also, there is much more to LvB than his 5th, 9th and the Pathetique and it's a shame that even these were cut into bits and pieces and added here and there without any musicality to the frames, but rather as background music. There is short scene when a white pianist is accompanied by a black violinist playing the Kreutzer Sonata; it did ring a bell but I had to look it up. The 'mulatto' violinist was supposed to be George Bridgetower (11 October 177829 February 1860) an Afro-Polish-born virtuoso who had a quite tempestuous professional relationship with LvB. Such a shame that this was not more elaborately depicted in the movie. That could have been a great instructive scene. LvB is quite distorted here and even the great actor Gary Oldman can't save his dignity nor the voluptuous and expensive production. Actually Mr Oldman is over the top but I blame it on the pathetic direction. Watchable for the young, but not very instructive. p.s. Hearing the gorgeous Isabella Rossellini speak a couple of sentences in Hungarian made me smile :-)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Tale of solitude
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vincentiu
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Extraordinary cast. Impressive story. And a great Oldman. A precise ballet behind cages and traps. Delicate tale about love as more than feelings or ordinary fight. Portrait of a genius from sketch to final signature. And drops of music like fundamental character. A movie without definition. A trip fed by gentle touches and shadow of abyss. Build with intelligent science of details, it seems be a good novel. But, step by step, it is more. A cruel love story's faces, description of solitude and vain hope, exercise of cruelty and selfish, slices of pain and force of fly. And a gallery of women's portraits. As pictures of a snail. As games of existence's pieces. The film is wonderful for the gift to be a kind of parable. Beethoven may be everyone. Johanna is every person for who the other is only a geometrical figure.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Immortal Beloved - The life of the Great Ludwig Van.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MortenKristofferVebjornsen
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I first became of interest, in the music of classical category... I first heard the glorious tunes of Beethoven. They stunned me as a child, and still does... Much effort from Beethoven's side was put into his pieces of music. There have been many films to include them, in their repertoire of music. The once I have seen is few, but powerful to say it the least. "A Clockwork Orange" directed by Stanley Kubrick, that pioneered music with its synthesizing of the composers most famous works- The great "Ode to Joy" to name one though. The way Alex in "A Clockwork Orange" talks about Beethoven in that film, is like if he is a God- An icon of Heavenly proportions. I could agree, but to me he is a great composer, and his music captivate me- Inspire me and helps me in bad times, when does occur. Then we have this film with Gary Oldman taking on the ambitiousness to play the troubled composer. This is "Immortal Beloved"... With a pressure, emphasis on the "E" in Belov"e"d. The film takes place, in the life of Beethoven. His symphonies reflect every stage he have had in his life of deafness, one of his other obstacles. Since of deafness he became, his music could have stopped there. Had it not been for his shear determination to compose music that to him meant something indeed. And to his audience. In his life, Beethoven had many lovers- They all treated him badly, and when he dies... They mourns over that they could not treat him the way he deserved. Beethoven as an artist, deaf that he was- Was indeed eccentric, and treated them better than they did him. What I said about his symphonies with they being connected to his life and so... I will not go into detail about them, but I will say that when "Ode to Joy" comes bombastic at ya... You will feel indeed how he felt when he was subjected to violence by his father. Hence, the ultra-violence was not far away though. His father wanted, knowing that the boy had talent... told a set of aristocratic people that he was nine and could play like Mozart... The boy was twelve. Failed and beaten up, for only to escape this madman in the tunes of "Ode to Joy". It is Epic and beyond comprehension of understanding the shear magnitude of his ways to compose the music he did... Deaf indeed that he was. I salute it completely. Gary Oldman captures what I can think, the sadness, the joy and the misery this artist had- To perfection within the boundaries of the films limit. The cinematography is so, and so... Yet some scenes in palaces and scenes of gardens are to say it the least beautiful to look at, and that is great enough for me. Sometimes, the image could have been executed better, by injecting less light, and more natural light being let in. In the scenes where Karl Van Beethoven tries to commit suicide, the shots of him walking in the woods feels very flat- But in the films length of two magnificent hours- This does not apply whatsoever. Karl is by the way the son of Ludwig Van... Here his lovers appear once more. There was one, that became his obsession, his muse. His Immortal Beloved. The wife of his brother Caspar. To her, he leaves everything- His music and his estate. Originally to his brothers this was to be given. The sad thing, she waited on him at a hotel- Only to leave as he arrived, sad I became indeed. The film puts you under the skin of Beethoven, and let you feel his journey told through flashbacks of the people he socialized with- that mostly being his lovers, and his assistant Schindler, played by Jeroen Krabb&eacute;. The acting is superb and the execution of the director Bernard Rose is great, and he have really caught the essence of Beethoven. The Man, The Artist and The Father. It is a great film, easily enjoyable, if you are into Beethoven- Then this maximizes by the numbers. It is easy to understand and you will feel like you are being part of the events displayed in the film. Now... play some music of Beethoven while you read this review again- to gain the effect I did while writing it. Preferably, the ninth. The End.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A movie to be savored, rather than critiqued on historical accuracy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    I_saw_it_happen
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    People get tied up on whether or not this film portrays the life of Beethoven accurately; this misses the point of the film entirely. This is not so much a film about Beethoven, so much as the way in which he effected those around him, and inspired a devotion among his followers which lives to this day. If you consider a movie like, for instance, 'Shakespeare in Love'--- it's quite apparent to anyone who knows anything about Shakespeare that the film has only the faintest correlation to Shakespeare, which didn't seem to get in the way of people awarding THAT movie, and lauding praise on it, because Shakespeare was played as a hopeless romantic that everyone WANTS to believe in. While Immortal Beloved may share a similarity to S.I.L in it's, shall we say, creative interpretations, Immortal Beloved is a far superior film because it shows Beethoven in all aspects of his humanity. There's Beethoven as a Romantic rock star, there's the tender friend, the arrogant drunken bastard, the possessive misogynist, the pathetic misanthrope, all of it. Gary Oldman's role is superb. It is difficult to imagine anyone else in the role after seeing this movie. The acting is top-notch, albeit a bit melodramatic at points (Beethoven's assistant especially gets a bit heartfelt a bit often). There are a few scenes in this movie which are truly tearjerker moments. The scene in which 'Ode to Joy' is played is predictably great, even though it (like a lot of the film) feels a bit dated now. All in all, a rewarding and thoughtful piece on a man whose life was indeed complicated and monumental. Highly recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Idiotic Premise
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Richard Nathan (Richard-Nathan@att.net)
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/5/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After Beethoven died, love letters he had written to his "Immortal Beloved" were discovered. The name of the Immortal Beloved was not included in the letters. That all makes sense. However, in this film what is found is not letters but a will - in which Beethoven leaves his estate to his Immortal Beloved, but does not tell anyone who she is. Does that make sense to anyone? If he really wanted to leave her his estate, wouldn't it have occurred to him that it maybe it might have been a good idea to identify her by name? Are we supposed to think we was an idiot? Are we, perhaps, supposed to think he wrote the will while suffering from dementia? I can't think of any other reason why he would make a bequest to someone he declined to identify.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Forever Beethoven- visually audacious and musically majestic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I know that Immortal Beloved has been compared to Amadeus, and here I am going to keep my comparison brief, personally I don't think Immortal Beloved is quite as good as Amadeus, but I love both films with a passion. Ludwig Van Beethoven is my all time favourite classical music composer, and having watched Eroica with Ian Hart and the 3-part BBC dramatisation of Beethoven with Paul Rhys, I wanted to see what this film was like. My conclusion is that Immortal Beloved is a visually audacious, musically majestic and imaginative near-masterpiece. Immortal Beloved certainly looks stunning. The scenery is gorgeous, the costumes sumptuous and the cinematography fluid and beautiful. Seriously when you are transported to 18th century Vienna you feel like you have just come out of a time machine. There are also many effective scenes such as young Ludwig running away from his abusive father, Johanna visiting Beethoven as he lies dying in bed (one of the few times when a piece of classical music-the String Quartet Op.130 here- reduced me to tears in just one scene of one film), Beethoven resting his ear while playing the Moonlight Sonata, Beethoven with his back to the audience during the performance of the Choral Symphony and the performance of the Emperor concerto(I did read somewhere that during a concert when the orchestra wouldn't play the piece right, Beethoven stopped it and ordered for it to be played again). Even the use of Missa Solemnis was beautifully done, so hauntingly beautiful. The music is a revelation, pretty much the heart and soul of the film. It is a true delight from start to finish, I loved hearing the Moonlight and Pathetique sonatas, the Choral Symphony(the Ode to Joy movement has always been my favourite work of his), the Emperor Concerto,the violin concerto, Missa Solemnis and the 2nd movement of the 7th symphony as it was performed by the London Symphony Orchestra and conducted by Georg Solti. Bernard Rose is an unusual choice for director, having directed the gruesome horror film Caddyshack, but he does respectably as he seeks to identify the "immortal beloved" of Beethoven's will(to this day we don't know who Beethoven is referring to). The scripting is intelligent and moving, one might say it doesn't say much, but it has heart, and the story is solid, deep and doesn't meander. The acting is uniformly excellent. Jeroen Krabbe is fine as Anton Schindler, and Isabella Rosselini, Johanna ter Steege and Valeria Golino look beautiful and act very convincingly as the suspects of Beethoven's affections. I have to say though Gary Oldman does give the best performance of the film, while some scenes could have done with a touch more moderato it was a superb, charismatic and moving performance. I have read complaints that Oldman overacted, complaints I don't agree with at all. Just because Beethoven shouts a lot here, doesn't mean Oldman was overacting, and he certainly didn't overact in the final scene between him and Johanna, his acting was a masterclass of sheer poignancy there. Beethoven wasn't exactly a knight in shining armour now was he? He was rude, aggressive and reacted vehemently to even the smallest thing and probably traumatised by the memories of being abused by his alcoholic father. Beethoven also encountered alcoholism and increasing deafness, and by 1812 or so he was deaf completely. Overall, this is a wonderful, underrated film. Only problem with it? I did feel the ending was a little too open-and-shut, but maybe it is just me. I cannot deny though that this is a great film. 9.5/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Magnificent!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    potato2
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/8/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The year is 1827, and famed composer Ludwig van Beethoven has just died. He leaves his estate to someone only known as his "Immortal Beloved," so his secretary goes about finding out who she may be among his many lovers. This movie is absolutely beautiful. Beethoven's music, of course, is the soundtrack and also the main plot point, as the writer/director speculates on the events in the maestro's life that inspired each piece. The movie goes back and forth in time to each of the important people in Beethoven's life and we see his music evolve from much tragedy, some euphoria, and most of all, his passion for life. There is even a persuasive scene accounting for his deafness. With lavish costumes and picturesque Czech locations, it's lovely to look at but even more impressive is Gary Oldman's portrayal of Beethoven. Though playing a conceited, temperamental, and often angry man, Oldman still wins our sympathy and he is at his charismatic best. If you love Beethoven's music and/or period films, you'll enjoy this exciting biopic. Highly recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Immortally Performed!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SamuelSataniel
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/3/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The film is a very good look at the life and love of Ludwhig Beethoven. It is perhaps not one of the best films portraying a musician (Amadeus is perhaps far greater) but deserves to be observed. The best part of this film are the performances which are completely underrated. Gary Oldman who doesn't look the part makes it completely his own. He resembles the inner and outer life of this old genius. Gary Oldman himself a genius is great at performing genius. And the rest of the cast give a solid and strong framing for the entire story of Beethoven. This is a must see for fans of great acting and those who want to know the story of this immortal Man who shall live for all times.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A brief review of Immortal Beloved.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cluso502
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Immortal Beloved disappointed me. Being both a fan of Gary Oldman and Beethoven I thought nothing could go wrong, and nothing did, as far as the soundtrack and Gary Oldman's performance were concerned. But Several other aspects of the film fell short. The cinematography was boring, costuming was historical, but plain, dialogue was not bad, but had very little substance, and the story-line was quite unsatisfying. Several character choices were unexplained. I never felt like I got to know any of the characters. And frankly the film seemed utterly pointless. I learned nothing and It had little artistic value. However it wasn't all bad, Gary Oldman had a few nice scenes with Marco Hofschneider, although they were cut short. The saddest part is that this film could have been a masterpiece if only it had different direction. I would love to re edit this film myself just to make the story flow in a more interesting direction. I recommend it if you can catch it for free and have nothing better to do. But never pay for this film. 6/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This film is perfect- the genius of his music combined with the complexity of his nature....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dee Ross
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For me - Beethoven stands alone in his genre - especially for his time. Too many historians worry about minute details in a famous person's life - and discredit stories that take a more artistic approach to revealing something about that person. No one knows all there is to know about a man from the 18th and 19th centuries - especially about his inner soul and what drives him to brilliance and raging behavior. The idea that there could have been someone unknown is enticing, and the concept of a film telling about Beethoven through the eyes of others is not a new one, but a format that allows more flexibility. I personally am glad they took this approach. Character development was therefore much more interesting. Oldman's performance was brilliant - and as is often the case with Oldman - you come to feel you are really watching Beethoven. The other personalities also were developed well - and his music was shown in the context of his times - sometimes harsh (his father's beatings) - sometimes tumultuous (the Napoleonic Wars) - sometimes full of love ( the women in his life who did adore him), - and sometimes driven by personal disappointment and anger (the onset of deafness and possibly an unrequited love.....) Beethoven took music to the next level - adding emotion to the beauty and structure already employed by others..... Some are shocked when I say that he was like the Led Zeppelin of the 19th Century - evoking new responses from listeners then, and still one of the few classical composers that you can play for anyone today and they will say "WOW!". Even those who really aren't fans of this kind of music. That is why they chose the 9th Symphony to celebrate the new millennium in 2000 GLOBALLY. Beethoven is universal and timeless. The movie is a wonderful way of sharing a moment with the maestro.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    historically and biographically inaccurate
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ursulahemard
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Not at all convinced. Why? Because this movie has numerous historical inaccuracies aka no chronological order: Ludwig van Beethoven's (17 December 1770  26 March 1827) total deafness occurs far too early, LvB is conducting personally works he actually never did, composing works in the wrong time order, etc. In addition to that, the movie takes too many liberties, to my taste, about the biographical facts, and to imply that that famous love-letter, written by LvB to his 'Immortal Beloved', would be ultimately his sister-in-law is just utterly preposterous. That letter was written and could have been addressed to several very well known ladies, we meet some of them during the movie, nevertheless no absolute certainty was proved until today. But it's most certainly not his sister-in-law, with whom he had so many conflicts and legal battles over years. The idea that LvB composed the 9th for his sister- in-law as a-forgive-me-for-making-your-life-a-hell is the director's personal fabrication and so is the feeble ending. Also, there is much more to LvB than his 5th, 9th and the Pathetique and it's a shame that even these were cut into bits and pieces and added here and there without any musicality to the frames, but rather as background music. There is short scene when a white pianist is accompanied by a black violinist playing the Kreutzer Sonata; it did ring a bell but I had to look it up. The 'mulatto' violinist was supposed to be George Bridgetower (11 October 177829 February 1860) an Afro-Polish-born virtuoso who had a quite tempestuous professional relationship with LvB. Such a shame that this was not more elaborately depicted in the movie. That could have been a great instructive scene. LvB is quite distorted here and even the great actor Gary Oldman can't save his dignity nor the voluptuous and expensive production. Actually Mr Oldman is over the top but I blame it on the pathetic direction. Watchable for the young, but not very instructive. p.s. Hearing the gorgeous Isabella Rossellini speak a couple of sentences in Hungarian made me smile :-)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Tale of solitude
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vincentiu
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Extraordinary cast. Impressive story. And a great Oldman. A precise ballet behind cages and traps. Delicate tale about love as more than feelings or ordinary fight. Portrait of a genius from sketch to final signature. And drops of music like fundamental character. A movie without definition. A trip fed by gentle touches and shadow of abyss. Build with intelligent science of details, it seems be a good novel. But, step by step, it is more. A cruel love story's faces, description of solitude and vain hope, exercise of cruelty and selfish, slices of pain and force of fly. And a gallery of women's portraits. As pictures of a snail. As games of existence's pieces. The film is wonderful for the gift to be a kind of parable. Beethoven may be everyone. Johanna is every person for who the other is only a geometrical figure.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Immortal Beloved - The life of the Great Ludwig Van.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MortenKristofferVebjornsen
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I first became of interest, in the music of classical category... I first heard the glorious tunes of Beethoven. They stunned me as a child, and still does... Much effort from Beethoven's side was put into his pieces of music. There have been many films to include them, in their repertoire of music. The once I have seen is few, but powerful to say it the least. "A Clockwork Orange" directed by Stanley Kubrick, that pioneered music with its synthesizing of the composers most famous works- The great "Ode to Joy" to name one though. The way Alex in "A Clockwork Orange" talks about Beethoven in that film, is like if he is a God- An icon of Heavenly proportions. I could agree, but to me he is a great composer, and his music captivate me- Inspire me and helps me in bad times, when does occur. Then we have this film with Gary Oldman taking on the ambitiousness to play the troubled composer. This is "Immortal Beloved"... With a pressure, emphasis on the "E" in Belov"e"d. The film takes place, in the life of Beethoven. His symphonies reflect every stage he have had in his life of deafness, one of his other obstacles. Since of deafness he became, his music could have stopped there. Had it not been for his shear determination to compose music that to him meant something indeed. And to his audience. In his life, Beethoven had many lovers- They all treated him badly, and when he dies... They mourns over that they could not treat him the way he deserved. Beethoven as an artist, deaf that he was- Was indeed eccentric, and treated them better than they did him. What I said about his symphonies with they being connected to his life and so... I will not go into detail about them, but I will say that when "Ode to Joy" comes bombastic at ya... You will feel indeed how he felt when he was subjected to violence by his father. Hence, the ultra-violence was not far away though. His father wanted, knowing that the boy had talent... told a set of aristocratic people that he was nine and could play like Mozart... The boy was twelve. Failed and beaten up, for only to escape this madman in the tunes of "Ode to Joy". It is Epic and beyond comprehension of understanding the shear magnitude of his ways to compose the music he did... Deaf indeed that he was. I salute it completely. Gary Oldman captures what I can think, the sadness, the joy and the misery this artist had- To perfection within the boundaries of the films limit. The cinematography is so, and so... Yet some scenes in palaces and scenes of gardens are to say it the least beautiful to look at, and that is great enough for me. Sometimes, the image could have been executed better, by injecting less light, and more natural light being let in. In the scenes where Karl Van Beethoven tries to commit suicide, the shots of him walking in the woods feels very flat- But in the films length of two magnificent hours- This does not apply whatsoever. Karl is by the way the son of Ludwig Van... Here his lovers appear once more. There was one, that became his obsession, his muse. His Immortal Beloved. The wife of his brother Caspar. To her, he leaves everything- His music and his estate. Originally to his brothers this was to be given. The sad thing, she waited on him at a hotel- Only to leave as he arrived, sad I became indeed. The film puts you under the skin of Beethoven, and let you feel his journey told through flashbacks of the people he socialized with- that mostly being his lovers, and his assistant Schindler, played by Jeroen Krabb&eacute;. The acting is superb and the execution of the director Bernard Rose is great, and he have really caught the essence of Beethoven. The Man, The Artist and The Father. It is a great film, easily enjoyable, if you are into Beethoven- Then this maximizes by the numbers. It is easy to understand and you will feel like you are being part of the events displayed in the film. Now... play some music of Beethoven while you read this review again- to gain the effect I did while writing it. Preferably, the ninth. The End.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A movie to be savored, rather than critiqued on historical accuracy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    I_saw_it_happen
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    People get tied up on whether or not this film portrays the life of Beethoven accurately; this misses the point of the film entirely. This is not so much a film about Beethoven, so much as the way in which he effected those around him, and inspired a devotion among his followers which lives to this day. If you consider a movie like, for instance, 'Shakespeare in Love'--- it's quite apparent to anyone who knows anything about Shakespeare that the film has only the faintest correlation to Shakespeare, which didn't seem to get in the way of people awarding THAT movie, and lauding praise on it, because Shakespeare was played as a hopeless romantic that everyone WANTS to believe in. While Immortal Beloved may share a similarity to S.I.L in it's, shall we say, creative interpretations, Immortal Beloved is a far superior film because it shows Beethoven in all aspects of his humanity. There's Beethoven as a Romantic rock star, there's the tender friend, the arrogant drunken bastard, the possessive misogynist, the pathetic misanthrope, all of it. Gary Oldman's role is superb. It is difficult to imagine anyone else in the role after seeing this movie. The acting is top-notch, albeit a bit melodramatic at points (Beethoven's assistant especially gets a bit heartfelt a bit often). There are a few scenes in this movie which are truly tearjerker moments. The scene in which 'Ode to Joy' is played is predictably great, even though it (like a lot of the film) feels a bit dated now. All in all, a rewarding and thoughtful piece on a man whose life was indeed complicated and monumental. Highly recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Idiotic Premise
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Richard Nathan (Richard-Nathan@att.net)
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/5/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After Beethoven died, love letters he had written to his "Immortal Beloved" were discovered. The name of the Immortal Beloved was not included in the letters. That all makes sense. However, in this film what is found is not letters but a will - in which Beethoven leaves his estate to his Immortal Beloved, but does not tell anyone who she is. Does that make sense to anyone? If he really wanted to leave her his estate, wouldn't it have occurred to him that it maybe it might have been a good idea to identify her by name? Are we supposed to think we was an idiot? Are we, perhaps, supposed to think he wrote the will while suffering from dementia? I can't think of any other reason why he would make a bequest to someone he declined to identify.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Forever Beethoven- visually audacious and musically majestic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I know that Immortal Beloved has been compared to Amadeus, and here I am going to keep my comparison brief, personally I don't think Immortal Beloved is quite as good as Amadeus, but I love both films with a passion. Ludwig Van Beethoven is my all time favourite classical music composer, and having watched Eroica with Ian Hart and the 3-part BBC dramatisation of Beethoven with Paul Rhys, I wanted to see what this film was like. My conclusion is that Immortal Beloved is a visually audacious, musically majestic and imaginative near-masterpiece. Immortal Beloved certainly looks stunning. The scenery is gorgeous, the costumes sumptuous and the cinematography fluid and beautiful. Seriously when you are transported to 18th century Vienna you feel like you have just come out of a time machine. There are also many effective scenes such as young Ludwig running away from his abusive father, Johanna visiting Beethoven as he lies dying in bed (one of the few times when a piece of classical music-the String Quartet Op.130 here- reduced me to tears in just one scene of one film), Beethoven resting his ear while playing the Moonlight Sonata, Beethoven with his back to the audience during the performance of the Choral Symphony and the performance of the Emperor concerto(I did read somewhere that during a concert when the orchestra wouldn't play the piece right, Beethoven stopped it and ordered for it to be played again). Even the use of Missa Solemnis was beautifully done, so hauntingly beautiful. The music is a revelation, pretty much the heart and soul of the film. It is a true delight from start to finish, I loved hearing the Moonlight and Pathetique sonatas, the Choral Symphony(the Ode to Joy movement has always been my favourite work of his), the Emperor Concerto,the violin concerto, Missa Solemnis and the 2nd movement of the 7th symphony as it was performed by the London Symphony Orchestra and conducted by Georg Solti. Bernard Rose is an unusual choice for director, having directed the gruesome horror film Caddyshack, but he does respectably as he seeks to identify the "immortal beloved" of Beethoven's will(to this day we don't know who Beethoven is referring to). The scripting is intelligent and moving, one might say it doesn't say much, but it has heart, and the story is solid, deep and doesn't meander. The acting is uniformly excellent. Jeroen Krabbe is fine as Anton Schindler, and Isabella Rosselini, Johanna ter Steege and Valeria Golino look beautiful and act very convincingly as the suspects of Beethoven's affections. I have to say though Gary Oldman does give the best performance of the film, while some scenes could have done with a touch more moderato it was a superb, charismatic and moving performance. I have read complaints that Oldman overacted, complaints I don't agree with at all. Just because Beethoven shouts a lot here, doesn't mean Oldman was overacting, and he certainly didn't overact in the final scene between him and Johanna, his acting was a masterclass of sheer poignancy there. Beethoven wasn't exactly a knight in shining armour now was he? He was rude, aggressive and reacted vehemently to even the smallest thing and probably traumatised by the memories of being abused by his alcoholic father. Beethoven also encountered alcoholism and increasing deafness, and by 1812 or so he was deaf completely. Overall, this is a wonderful, underrated film. Only problem with it? I did feel the ending was a little too open-and-shut, but maybe it is just me. I cannot deny though that this is a great film. 9.5/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Magnificent!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    potato2
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/8/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The year is 1827, and famed composer Ludwig van Beethoven has just died. He leaves his estate to someone only known as his "Immortal Beloved," so his secretary goes about finding out who she may be among his many lovers. This movie is absolutely beautiful. Beethoven's music, of course, is the soundtrack and also the main plot point, as the writer/director speculates on the events in the maestro's life that inspired each piece. The movie goes back and forth in time to each of the important people in Beethoven's life and we see his music evolve from much tragedy, some euphoria, and most of all, his passion for life. There is even a persuasive scene accounting for his deafness. With lavish costumes and picturesque Czech locations, it's lovely to look at but even more impressive is Gary Oldman's portrayal of Beethoven. Though playing a conceited, temperamental, and often angry man, Oldman still wins our sympathy and he is at his charismatic best. If you love Beethoven's music and/or period films, you'll enjoy this exciting biopic. Highly recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Immortally Performed!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SamuelSataniel
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/3/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The film is a very good look at the life and love of Ludwhig Beethoven. It is perhaps not one of the best films portraying a musician (Amadeus is perhaps far greater) but deserves to be observed. The best part of this film are the performances which are completely underrated. Gary Oldman who doesn't look the part makes it completely his own. He resembles the inner and outer life of this old genius. Gary Oldman himself a genius is great at performing genius. And the rest of the cast give a solid and strong framing for the entire story of Beethoven. This is a must see for fans of great acting and those who want to know the story of this immortal Man who shall live for all times.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A brief review of Immortal Beloved.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cluso502
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Immortal Beloved disappointed me. Being both a fan of Gary Oldman and Beethoven I thought nothing could go wrong, and nothing did, as far as the soundtrack and Gary Oldman's performance were concerned. But Several other aspects of the film fell short. The cinematography was boring, costuming was historical, but plain, dialogue was not bad, but had very little substance, and the story-line was quite unsatisfying. Several character choices were unexplained. I never felt like I got to know any of the characters. And frankly the film seemed utterly pointless. I learned nothing and It had little artistic value. However it wasn't all bad, Gary Oldman had a few nice scenes with Marco Hofschneider, although they were cut short. The saddest part is that this film could have been a masterpiece if only it had different direction. I would love to re edit this film myself just to make the story flow in a more interesting direction. I recommend it if you can catch it for free and have nothing better to do. But never pay for this film. 6/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This film is perfect- the genius of his music combined with the complexity of his nature....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dee Ross
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For me - Beethoven stands alone in his genre - especially for his time. Too many historians worry about minute details in a famous person's life - and discredit stories that take a more artistic approach to revealing something about that person. No one knows all there is to know about a man from the 18th and 19th centuries - especially about his inner soul and what drives him to brilliance and raging behavior. The idea that there could have been someone unknown is enticing, and the concept of a film telling about Beethoven through the eyes of others is not a new one, but a format that allows more flexibility. I personally am glad they took this approach. Character development was therefore much more interesting. Oldman's performance was brilliant - and as is often the case with Oldman - you come to feel you are really watching Beethoven. The other personalities also were developed well - and his music was shown in the context of his times - sometimes harsh (his father's beatings) - sometimes tumultuous (the Napoleonic Wars) - sometimes full of love ( the women in his life who did adore him), - and sometimes driven by personal disappointment and anger (the onset of deafness and possibly an unrequited love.....) Beethoven took music to the next level - adding emotion to the beauty and structure already employed by others..... Some are shocked when I say that he was like the Led Zeppelin of the 19th Century - evoking new responses from listeners then, and still one of the few classical composers that you can play for anyone today and they will say "WOW!". Even those who really aren't fans of this kind of music. That is why they chose the 9th Symphony to celebrate the new millennium in 2000 GLOBALLY. Beethoven is universal and timeless. The movie is a wonderful way of sharing a moment with the maestro.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    historically and biographically inaccurate
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ursulahemard
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Not at all convinced. Why? Because this movie has numerous historical inaccuracies aka no chronological order: Ludwig van Beethoven's (17 December 1770  26 March 1827) total deafness occurs far too early, LvB is conducting personally works he actually never did, composing works in the wrong time order, etc. In addition to that, the movie takes too many liberties, to my taste, about the biographical facts, and to imply that that famous love-letter, written by LvB to his 'Immortal Beloved', would be ultimately his sister-in-law is just utterly preposterous. That letter was written and could have been addressed to several very well known ladies, we meet some of them during the movie, nevertheless no absolute certainty was proved until today. But it's most certainly not his sister-in-law, with whom he had so many conflicts and legal battles over years. The idea that LvB composed the 9th for his sister- in-law as a-forgive-me-for-making-your-life-a-hell is the director's personal fabrication and so is the feeble ending. Also, there is much more to LvB than his 5th, 9th and the Pathetique and it's a shame that even these were cut into bits and pieces and added here and there without any musicality to the frames, but rather as background music. There is short scene when a white pianist is accompanied by a black violinist playing the Kreutzer Sonata; it did ring a bell but I had to look it up. The 'mulatto' violinist was supposed to be George Bridgetower (11 October 177829 February 1860) an Afro-Polish-born virtuoso who had a quite tempestuous professional relationship with LvB. Such a shame that this was not more elaborately depicted in the movie. That could have been a great instructive scene. LvB is quite distorted here and even the great actor Gary Oldman can't save his dignity nor the voluptuous and expensive production. Actually Mr Oldman is over the top but I blame it on the pathetic direction. Watchable for the young, but not very instructive. p.s. Hearing the gorgeous Isabella Rossellini speak a couple of sentences in Hungarian made me smile :-)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Tale of solitude
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vincentiu
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Extraordinary cast. Impressive story. And a great Oldman. A precise ballet behind cages and traps. Delicate tale about love as more than feelings or ordinary fight. Portrait of a genius from sketch to final signature. And drops of music like fundamental character. A movie without definition. A trip fed by gentle touches and shadow of abyss. Build with intelligent science of details, it seems be a good novel. But, step by step, it is more. A cruel love story's faces, description of solitude and vain hope, exercise of cruelty and selfish, slices of pain and force of fly. And a gallery of women's portraits. As pictures of a snail. As games of existence's pieces. The film is wonderful for the gift to be a kind of parable. Beethoven may be everyone. Johanna is every person for who the other is only a geometrical figure.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Immortal Beloved - The life of the Great Ludwig Van.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MortenKristofferVebjornsen
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I first became of interest, in the music of classical category... I first heard the glorious tunes of Beethoven. They stunned me as a child, and still does... Much effort from Beethoven's side was put into his pieces of music. There have been many films to include them, in their repertoire of music. The once I have seen is few, but powerful to say it the least. "A Clockwork Orange" directed by Stanley Kubrick, that pioneered music with its synthesizing of the composers most famous works- The great "Ode to Joy" to name one though. The way Alex in "A Clockwork Orange" talks about Beethoven in that film, is like if he is a God- An icon of Heavenly proportions. I could agree, but to me he is a great composer, and his music captivate me- Inspire me and helps me in bad times, when does occur. Then we have this film with Gary Oldman taking on the ambitiousness to play the troubled composer. This is "Immortal Beloved"... With a pressure, emphasis on the "E" in Belov"e"d. The film takes place, in the life of Beethoven. His symphonies reflect every stage he have had in his life of deafness, one of his other obstacles. Since of deafness he became, his music could have stopped there. Had it not been for his shear determination to compose music that to him meant something indeed. And to his audience. In his life, Beethoven had many lovers- They all treated him badly, and when he dies... They mourns over that they could not treat him the way he deserved. Beethoven as an artist, deaf that he was- Was indeed eccentric, and treated them better than they did him. What I said about his symphonies with they being connected to his life and so... I will not go into detail about them, but I will say that when "Ode to Joy" comes bombastic at ya... You will feel indeed how he felt when he was subjected to violence by his father. Hence, the ultra-violence was not far away though. His father wanted, knowing that the boy had talent... told a set of aristocratic people that he was nine and could play like Mozart... The boy was twelve. Failed and beaten up, for only to escape this madman in the tunes of "Ode to Joy". It is Epic and beyond comprehension of understanding the shear magnitude of his ways to compose the music he did... Deaf indeed that he was. I salute it completely. Gary Oldman captures what I can think, the sadness, the joy and the misery this artist had- To perfection within the boundaries of the films limit. The cinematography is so, and so... Yet some scenes in palaces and scenes of gardens are to say it the least beautiful to look at, and that is great enough for me. Sometimes, the image could have been executed better, by injecting less light, and more natural light being let in. In the scenes where Karl Van Beethoven tries to commit suicide, the shots of him walking in the woods feels very flat- But in the films length of two magnificent hours- This does not apply whatsoever. Karl is by the way the son of Ludwig Van... Here his lovers appear once more. There was one, that became his obsession, his muse. His Immortal Beloved. The wife of his brother Caspar. To her, he leaves everything- His music and his estate. Originally to his brothers this was to be given. The sad thing, she waited on him at a hotel- Only to leave as he arrived, sad I became indeed. The film puts you under the skin of Beethoven, and let you feel his journey told through flashbacks of the people he socialized with- that mostly being his lovers, and his assistant Schindler, played by Jeroen Krabb&eacute;. The acting is superb and the execution of the director Bernard Rose is great, and he have really caught the essence of Beethoven. The Man, The Artist and The Father. It is a great film, easily enjoyable, if you are into Beethoven- Then this maximizes by the numbers. It is easy to understand and you will feel like you are being part of the events displayed in the film. Now... play some music of Beethoven while you read this review again- to gain the effect I did while writing it. Preferably, the ninth. The End.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A movie to be savored, rather than critiqued on historical accuracy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    I_saw_it_happen
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    People get tied up on whether or not this film portrays the life of Beethoven accurately; this misses the point of the film entirely. This is not so much a film about Beethoven, so much as the way in which he effected those around him, and inspired a devotion among his followers which lives to this day. If you consider a movie like, for instance, 'Shakespeare in Love'--- it's quite apparent to anyone who knows anything about Shakespeare that the film has only the faintest correlation to Shakespeare, which didn't seem to get in the way of people awarding THAT movie, and lauding praise on it, because Shakespeare was played as a hopeless romantic that everyone WANTS to believe in. While Immortal Beloved may share a similarity to S.I.L in it's, shall we say, creative interpretations, Immortal Beloved is a far superior film because it shows Beethoven in all aspects of his humanity. There's Beethoven as a Romantic rock star, there's the tender friend, the arrogant drunken bastard, the possessive misogynist, the pathetic misanthrope, all of it. Gary Oldman's role is superb. It is difficult to imagine anyone else in the role after seeing this movie. The acting is top-notch, albeit a bit melodramatic at points (Beethoven's assistant especially gets a bit heartfelt a bit often). There are a few scenes in this movie which are truly tearjerker moments. The scene in which 'Ode to Joy' is played is predictably great, even though it (like a lot of the film) feels a bit dated now. All in all, a rewarding and thoughtful piece on a man whose life was indeed complicated and monumental. Highly recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Idiotic Premise
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Richard Nathan (Richard-Nathan@att.net)
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/5/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After Beethoven died, love letters he had written to his "Immortal Beloved" were discovered. The name of the Immortal Beloved was not included in the letters. That all makes sense. However, in this film what is found is not letters but a will - in which Beethoven leaves his estate to his Immortal Beloved, but does not tell anyone who she is. Does that make sense to anyone? If he really wanted to leave her his estate, wouldn't it have occurred to him that it maybe it might have been a good idea to identify her by name? Are we supposed to think we was an idiot? Are we, perhaps, supposed to think he wrote the will while suffering from dementia? I can't think of any other reason why he would make a bequest to someone he declined to identify.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Forever Beethoven- visually audacious and musically majestic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I know that Immortal Beloved has been compared to Amadeus, and here I am going to keep my comparison brief, personally I don't think Immortal Beloved is quite as good as Amadeus, but I love both films with a passion. Ludwig Van Beethoven is my all time favourite classical music composer, and having watched Eroica with Ian Hart and the 3-part BBC dramatisation of Beethoven with Paul Rhys, I wanted to see what this film was like. My conclusion is that Immortal Beloved is a visually audacious, musically majestic and imaginative near-masterpiece. Immortal Beloved certainly looks stunning. The scenery is gorgeous, the costumes sumptuous and the cinematography fluid and beautiful. Seriously when you are transported to 18th century Vienna you feel like you have just come out of a time machine. There are also many effective scenes such as young Ludwig running away from his abusive father, Johanna visiting Beethoven as he lies dying in bed (one of the few times when a piece of classical music-the String Quartet Op.130 here- reduced me to tears in just one scene of one film), Beethoven resting his ear while playing the Moonlight Sonata, Beethoven with his back to the audience during the performance of the Choral Symphony and the performance of the Emperor concerto(I did read somewhere that during a concert when the orchestra wouldn't play the piece right, Beethoven stopped it and ordered for it to be played again). Even the use of Missa Solemnis was beautifully done, so hauntingly beautiful. The music is a revelation, pretty much the heart and soul of the film. It is a true delight from start to finish, I loved hearing the Moonlight and Pathetique sonatas, the Choral Symphony(the Ode to Joy movement has always been my favourite work of his), the Emperor Concerto,the violin concerto, Missa Solemnis and the 2nd movement of the 7th symphony as it was performed by the London Symphony Orchestra and conducted by Georg Solti. Bernard Rose is an unusual choice for director, having directed the gruesome horror film Caddyshack, but he does respectably as he seeks to identify the "immortal beloved" of Beethoven's will(to this day we don't know who Beethoven is referring to). The scripting is intelligent and moving, one might say it doesn't say much, but it has heart, and the story is solid, deep and doesn't meander. The acting is uniformly excellent. Jeroen Krabbe is fine as Anton Schindler, and Isabella Rosselini, Johanna ter Steege and Valeria Golino look beautiful and act very convincingly as the suspects of Beethoven's affections. I have to say though Gary Oldman does give the best performance of the film, while some scenes could have done with a touch more moderato it was a superb, charismatic and moving performance. I have read complaints that Oldman overacted, complaints I don't agree with at all. Just because Beethoven shouts a lot here, doesn't mean Oldman was overacting, and he certainly didn't overact in the final scene between him and Johanna, his acting was a masterclass of sheer poignancy there. Beethoven wasn't exactly a knight in shining armour now was he? He was rude, aggressive and reacted vehemently to even the smallest thing and probably traumatised by the memories of being abused by his alcoholic father. Beethoven also encountered alcoholism and increasing deafness, and by 1812 or so he was deaf completely. Overall, this is a wonderful, underrated film. Only problem with it? I did feel the ending was a little too open-and-shut, but maybe it is just me. I cannot deny though that this is a great film. 9.5/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Magnificent!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    potato2
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/8/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The year is 1827, and famed composer Ludwig van Beethoven has just died. He leaves his estate to someone only known as his "Immortal Beloved," so his secretary goes about finding out who she may be among his many lovers. This movie is absolutely beautiful. Beethoven's music, of course, is the soundtrack and also the main plot point, as the writer/director speculates on the events in the maestro's life that inspired each piece. The movie goes back and forth in time to each of the important people in Beethoven's life and we see his music evolve from much tragedy, some euphoria, and most of all, his passion for life. There is even a persuasive scene accounting for his deafness. With lavish costumes and picturesque Czech locations, it's lovely to look at but even more impressive is Gary Oldman's portrayal of Beethoven. Though playing a conceited, temperamental, and often angry man, Oldman still wins our sympathy and he is at his charismatic best. If you love Beethoven's music and/or period films, you'll enjoy this exciting biopic. Highly recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Immortally Performed!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SamuelSataniel
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/3/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The film is a very good look at the life and love of Ludwhig Beethoven. It is perhaps not one of the best films portraying a musician (Amadeus is perhaps far greater) but deserves to be observed. The best part of this film are the performances which are completely underrated. Gary Oldman who doesn't look the part makes it completely his own. He resembles the inner and outer life of this old genius. Gary Oldman himself a genius is great at performing genius. And the rest of the cast give a solid and strong framing for the entire story of Beethoven. This is a must see for fans of great acting and those who want to know the story of this immortal Man who shall live for all times.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A brief review of Immortal Beloved.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cluso502
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Immortal Beloved disappointed me. Being both a fan of Gary Oldman and Beethoven I thought nothing could go wrong, and nothing did, as far as the soundtrack and Gary Oldman's performance were concerned. But Several other aspects of the film fell short. The cinematography was boring, costuming was historical, but plain, dialogue was not bad, but had very little substance, and the story-line was quite unsatisfying. Several character choices were unexplained. I never felt like I got to know any of the characters. And frankly the film seemed utterly pointless. I learned nothing and It had little artistic value. However it wasn't all bad, Gary Oldman had a few nice scenes with Marco Hofschneider, although they were cut short. The saddest part is that this film could have been a masterpiece if only it had different direction. I would love to re edit this film myself just to make the story flow in a more interesting direction. I recommend it if you can catch it for free and have nothing better to do. But never pay for this film. 6/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This film is perfect- the genius of his music combined with the complexity of his nature....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dee Ross
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For me - Beethoven stands alone in his genre - especially for his time. Too many historians worry about minute details in a famous person's life - and discredit stories that take a more artistic approach to revealing something about that person. No one knows all there is to know about a man from the 18th and 19th centuries - especially about his inner soul and what drives him to brilliance and raging behavior. The idea that there could have been someone unknown is enticing, and the concept of a film telling about Beethoven through the eyes of others is not a new one, but a format that allows more flexibility. I personally am glad they took this approach. Character development was therefore much more interesting. Oldman's performance was brilliant - and as is often the case with Oldman - you come to feel you are really watching Beethoven. The other personalities also were developed well - and his music was shown in the context of his times - sometimes harsh (his father's beatings) - sometimes tumultuous (the Napoleonic Wars) - sometimes full of love ( the women in his life who did adore him), - and sometimes driven by personal disappointment and anger (the onset of deafness and possibly an unrequited love.....) Beethoven took music to the next level - adding emotion to the beauty and structure already employed by others..... Some are shocked when I say that he was like the Led Zeppelin of the 19th Century - evoking new responses from listeners then, and still one of the few classical composers that you can play for anyone today and they will say "WOW!". Even those who really aren't fans of this kind of music. That is why they chose the 9th Symphony to celebrate the new millennium in 2000 GLOBALLY. Beethoven is universal and timeless. The movie is a wonderful way of sharing a moment with the maestro.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    historically and biographically inaccurate
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ursulahemard
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Not at all convinced. Why? Because this movie has numerous historical inaccuracies aka no chronological order: Ludwig van Beethoven's (17 December 1770  26 March 1827) total deafness occurs far too early, LvB is conducting personally works he actually never did, composing works in the wrong time order, etc. In addition to that, the movie takes too many liberties, to my taste, about the biographical facts, and to imply that that famous love-letter, written by LvB to his 'Immortal Beloved', would be ultimately his sister-in-law is just utterly preposterous. That letter was written and could have been addressed to several very well known ladies, we meet some of them during the movie, nevertheless no absolute certainty was proved until today. But it's most certainly not his sister-in-law, with whom he had so many conflicts and legal battles over years. The idea that LvB composed the 9th for his sister- in-law as a-forgive-me-for-making-your-life-a-hell is the director's personal fabrication and so is the feeble ending. Also, there is much more to LvB than his 5th, 9th and the Pathetique and it's a shame that even these were cut into bits and pieces and added here and there without any musicality to the frames, but rather as background music. There is short scene when a white pianist is accompanied by a black violinist playing the Kreutzer Sonata; it did ring a bell but I had to look it up. The 'mulatto' violinist was supposed to be George Bridgetower (11 October 177829 February 1860) an Afro-Polish-born virtuoso who had a quite tempestuous professional relationship with LvB. Such a shame that this was not more elaborately depicted in the movie. That could have been a great instructive scene. LvB is quite distorted here and even the great actor Gary Oldman can't save his dignity nor the voluptuous and expensive production. Actually Mr Oldman is over the top but I blame it on the pathetic direction. Watchable for the young, but not very instructive. p.s. Hearing the gorgeous Isabella Rossellini speak a couple of sentences in Hungarian made me smile :-)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Tale of solitude
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vincentiu
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Extraordinary cast. Impressive story. And a great Oldman. A precise ballet behind cages and traps. Delicate tale about love as more than feelings or ordinary fight. Portrait of a genius from sketch to final signature. And drops of music like fundamental character. A movie without definition. A trip fed by gentle touches and shadow of abyss. Build with intelligent science of details, it seems be a good novel. But, step by step, it is more. A cruel love story's faces, description of solitude and vain hope, exercise of cruelty and selfish, slices of pain and force of fly. And a gallery of women's portraits. As pictures of a snail. As games of existence's pieces. The film is wonderful for the gift to be a kind of parable. Beethoven may be everyone. Johanna is every person for who the other is only a geometrical figure.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Immortal Beloved - The life of the Great Ludwig Van.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MortenKristofferVebjornsen
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I first became of interest, in the music of classical category... I first heard the glorious tunes of Beethoven. They stunned me as a child, and still does... Much effort from Beethoven's side was put into his pieces of music. There have been many films to include them, in their repertoire of music. The once I have seen is few, but powerful to say it the least. "A Clockwork Orange" directed by Stanley Kubrick, that pioneered music with its synthesizing of the composers most famous works- The great "Ode to Joy" to name one though. The way Alex in "A Clockwork Orange" talks about Beethoven in that film, is like if he is a God- An icon of Heavenly proportions. I could agree, but to me he is a great composer, and his music captivate me- Inspire me and helps me in bad times, when does occur. Then we have this film with Gary Oldman taking on the ambitiousness to play the troubled composer. This is "Immortal Beloved"... With a pressure, emphasis on the "E" in Belov"e"d. The film takes place, in the life of Beethoven. His symphonies reflect every stage he have had in his life of deafness, one of his other obstacles. Since of deafness he became, his music could have stopped there. Had it not been for his shear determination to compose music that to him meant something indeed. And to his audience. In his life, Beethoven had many lovers- They all treated him badly, and when he dies... They mourns over that they could not treat him the way he deserved. Beethoven as an artist, deaf that he was- Was indeed eccentric, and treated them better than they did him. What I said about his symphonies with they being connected to his life and so... I will not go into detail about them, but I will say that when "Ode to Joy" comes bombastic at ya... You will feel indeed how he felt when he was subjected to violence by his father. Hence, the ultra-violence was not far away though. His father wanted, knowing that the boy had talent... told a set of aristocratic people that he was nine and could play like Mozart... The boy was twelve. Failed and beaten up, for only to escape this madman in the tunes of "Ode to Joy". It is Epic and beyond comprehension of understanding the shear magnitude of his ways to compose the music he did... Deaf indeed that he was. I salute it completely. Gary Oldman captures what I can think, the sadness, the joy and the misery this artist had- To perfection within the boundaries of the films limit. The cinematography is so, and so... Yet some scenes in palaces and scenes of gardens are to say it the least beautiful to look at, and that is great enough for me. Sometimes, the image could have been executed better, by injecting less light, and more natural light being let in. In the scenes where Karl Van Beethoven tries to commit suicide, the shots of him walking in the woods feels very flat- But in the films length of two magnificent hours- This does not apply whatsoever. Karl is by the way the son of Ludwig Van... Here his lovers appear once more. There was one, that became his obsession, his muse. His Immortal Beloved. The wife of his brother Caspar. To her, he leaves everything- His music and his estate. Originally to his brothers this was to be given. The sad thing, she waited on him at a hotel- Only to leave as he arrived, sad I became indeed. The film puts you under the skin of Beethoven, and let you feel his journey told through flashbacks of the people he socialized with- that mostly being his lovers, and his assistant Schindler, played by Jeroen Krabb&eacute;. The acting is superb and the execution of the director Bernard Rose is great, and he have really caught the essence of Beethoven. The Man, The Artist and The Father. It is a great film, easily enjoyable, if you are into Beethoven- Then this maximizes by the numbers. It is easy to understand and you will feel like you are being part of the events displayed in the film. Now... play some music of Beethoven while you read this review again- to gain the effect I did while writing it. Preferably, the ninth. The End.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A movie to be savored, rather than critiqued on historical accuracy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    I_saw_it_happen
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    People get tied up on whether or not this film portrays the life of Beethoven accurately; this misses the point of the film entirely. This is not so much a film about Beethoven, so much as the way in which he effected those around him, and inspired a devotion among his followers which lives to this day. If you consider a movie like, for instance, 'Shakespeare in Love'--- it's quite apparent to anyone who knows anything about Shakespeare that the film has only the faintest correlation to Shakespeare, which didn't seem to get in the way of people awarding THAT movie, and lauding praise on it, because Shakespeare was played as a hopeless romantic that everyone WANTS to believe in. While Immortal Beloved may share a similarity to S.I.L in it's, shall we say, creative interpretations, Immortal Beloved is a far superior film because it shows Beethoven in all aspects of his humanity. There's Beethoven as a Romantic rock star, there's the tender friend, the arrogant drunken bastard, the possessive misogynist, the pathetic misanthrope, all of it. Gary Oldman's role is superb. It is difficult to imagine anyone else in the role after seeing this movie. The acting is top-notch, albeit a bit melodramatic at points (Beethoven's assistant especially gets a bit heartfelt a bit often). There are a few scenes in this movie which are truly tearjerker moments. The scene in which 'Ode to Joy' is played is predictably great, even though it (like a lot of the film) feels a bit dated now. All in all, a rewarding and thoughtful piece on a man whose life was indeed complicated and monumental. Highly recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Idiotic Premise
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Richard Nathan (Richard-Nathan@att.net)
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/5/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After Beethoven died, love letters he had written to his "Immortal Beloved" were discovered. The name of the Immortal Beloved was not included in the letters. That all makes sense. However, in this film what is found is not letters but a will - in which Beethoven leaves his estate to his Immortal Beloved, but does not tell anyone who she is. Does that make sense to anyone? If he really wanted to leave her his estate, wouldn't it have occurred to him that it maybe it might have been a good idea to identify her by name? Are we supposed to think we was an idiot? Are we, perhaps, supposed to think he wrote the will while suffering from dementia? I can't think of any other reason why he would make a bequest to someone he declined to identify.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Forever Beethoven- visually audacious and musically majestic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I know that Immortal Beloved has been compared to Amadeus, and here I am going to keep my comparison brief, personally I don't think Immortal Beloved is quite as good as Amadeus, but I love both films with a passion. Ludwig Van Beethoven is my all time favourite classical music composer, and having watched Eroica with Ian Hart and the 3-part BBC dramatisation of Beethoven with Paul Rhys, I wanted to see what this film was like. My conclusion is that Immortal Beloved is a visually audacious, musically majestic and imaginative near-masterpiece. Immortal Beloved certainly looks stunning. The scenery is gorgeous, the costumes sumptuous and the cinematography fluid and beautiful. Seriously when you are transported to 18th century Vienna you feel like you have just come out of a time machine. There are also many effective scenes such as young Ludwig running away from his abusive father, Johanna visiting Beethoven as he lies dying in bed (one of the few times when a piece of classical music-the String Quartet Op.130 here- reduced me to tears in just one scene of one film), Beethoven resting his ear while playing the Moonlight Sonata, Beethoven with his back to the audience during the performance of the Choral Symphony and the performance of the Emperor concerto(I did read somewhere that during a concert when the orchestra wouldn't play the piece right, Beethoven stopped it and ordered for it to be played again). Even the use of Missa Solemnis was beautifully done, so hauntingly beautiful. The music is a revelation, pretty much the heart and soul of the film. It is a true delight from start to finish, I loved hearing the Moonlight and Pathetique sonatas, the Choral Symphony(the Ode to Joy movement has always been my favourite work of his), the Emperor Concerto,the violin concerto, Missa Solemnis and the 2nd movement of the 7th symphony as it was performed by the London Symphony Orchestra and conducted by Georg Solti. Bernard Rose is an unusual choice for director, having directed the gruesome horror film Caddyshack, but he does respectably as he seeks to identify the "immortal beloved" of Beethoven's will(to this day we don't know who Beethoven is referring to). The scripting is intelligent and moving, one might say it doesn't say much, but it has heart, and the story is solid, deep and doesn't meander. The acting is uniformly excellent. Jeroen Krabbe is fine as Anton Schindler, and Isabella Rosselini, Johanna ter Steege and Valeria Golino look beautiful and act very convincingly as the suspects of Beethoven's affections. I have to say though Gary Oldman does give the best performance of the film, while some scenes could have done with a touch more moderato it was a superb, charismatic and moving performance. I have read complaints that Oldman overacted, complaints I don't agree with at all. Just because Beethoven shouts a lot here, doesn't mean Oldman was overacting, and he certainly didn't overact in the final scene between him and Johanna, his acting was a masterclass of sheer poignancy there. Beethoven wasn't exactly a knight in shining armour now was he? He was rude, aggressive and reacted vehemently to even the smallest thing and probably traumatised by the memories of being abused by his alcoholic father. Beethoven also encountered alcoholism and increasing deafness, and by 1812 or so he was deaf completely. Overall, this is a wonderful, underrated film. Only problem with it? I did feel the ending was a little too open-and-shut, but maybe it is just me. I cannot deny though that this is a great film. 9.5/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Magnificent!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    potato2
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/8/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The year is 1827, and famed composer Ludwig van Beethoven has just died. He leaves his estate to someone only known as his "Immortal Beloved," so his secretary goes about finding out who she may be among his many lovers. This movie is absolutely beautiful. Beethoven's music, of course, is the soundtrack and also the main plot point, as the writer/director speculates on the events in the maestro's life that inspired each piece. The movie goes back and forth in time to each of the important people in Beethoven's life and we see his music evolve from much tragedy, some euphoria, and most of all, his passion for life. There is even a persuasive scene accounting for his deafness. With lavish costumes and picturesque Czech locations, it's lovely to look at but even more impressive is Gary Oldman's portrayal of Beethoven. Though playing a conceited, temperamental, and often angry man, Oldman still wins our sympathy and he is at his charismatic best. If you love Beethoven's music and/or period films, you'll enjoy this exciting biopic. Highly recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Immortally Performed!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SamuelSataniel
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/3/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The film is a very good look at the life and love of Ludwhig Beethoven. It is perhaps not one of the best films portraying a musician (Amadeus is perhaps far greater) but deserves to be observed. The best part of this film are the performances which are completely underrated. Gary Oldman who doesn't look the part makes it completely his own. He resembles the inner and outer life of this old genius. Gary Oldman himself a genius is great at performing genius. And the rest of the cast give a solid and strong framing for the entire story of Beethoven. This is a must see for fans of great acting and those who want to know the story of this immortal Man who shall live for all times.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A brief review of Immortal Beloved.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cluso502
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Immortal Beloved disappointed me. Being both a fan of Gary Oldman and Beethoven I thought nothing could go wrong, and nothing did, as far as the soundtrack and Gary Oldman's performance were concerned. But Several other aspects of the film fell short. The cinematography was boring, costuming was historical, but plain, dialogue was not bad, but had very little substance, and the story-line was quite unsatisfying. Several character choices were unexplained. I never felt like I got to know any of the characters. And frankly the film seemed utterly pointless. I learned nothing and It had little artistic value. However it wasn't all bad, Gary Oldman had a few nice scenes with Marco Hofschneider, although they were cut short. The saddest part is that this film could have been a masterpiece if only it had different direction. I would love to re edit this film myself just to make the story flow in a more interesting direction. I recommend it if you can catch it for free and have nothing better to do. But never pay for this film. 6/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This film is perfect- the genius of his music combined with the complexity of his nature....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dee Ross
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For me - Beethoven stands alone in his genre - especially for his time. Too many historians worry about minute details in a famous person's life - and discredit stories that take a more artistic approach to revealing something about that person. No one knows all there is to know about a man from the 18th and 19th centuries - especially about his inner soul and what drives him to brilliance and raging behavior. The idea that there could have been someone unknown is enticing, and the concept of a film telling about Beethoven through the eyes of others is not a new one, but a format that allows more flexibility. I personally am glad they took this approach. Character development was therefore much more interesting. Oldman's performance was brilliant - and as is often the case with Oldman - you come to feel you are really watching Beethoven. The other personalities also were developed well - and his music was shown in the context of his times - sometimes harsh (his father's beatings) - sometimes tumultuous (the Napoleonic Wars) - sometimes full of love ( the women in his life who did adore him), - and sometimes driven by personal disappointment and anger (the onset of deafness and possibly an unrequited love.....) Beethoven took music to the next level - adding emotion to the beauty and structure already employed by others..... Some are shocked when I say that he was like the Led Zeppelin of the 19th Century - evoking new responses from listeners then, and still one of the few classical composers that you can play for anyone today and they will say "WOW!". Even those who really aren't fans of this kind of music. That is why they chose the 9th Symphony to celebrate the new millennium in 2000 GLOBALLY. Beethoven is universal and timeless. The movie is a wonderful way of sharing a moment with the maestro.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    historically and biographically inaccurate
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ursulahemard
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Not at all convinced. Why? Because this movie has numerous historical inaccuracies aka no chronological order: Ludwig van Beethoven's (17 December 1770  26 March 1827) total deafness occurs far too early, LvB is conducting personally works he actually never did, composing works in the wrong time order, etc. In addition to that, the movie takes too many liberties, to my taste, about the biographical facts, and to imply that that famous love-letter, written by LvB to his 'Immortal Beloved', would be ultimately his sister-in-law is just utterly preposterous. That letter was written and could have been addressed to several very well known ladies, we meet some of them during the movie, nevertheless no absolute certainty was proved until today. But it's most certainly not his sister-in-law, with whom he had so many conflicts and legal battles over years. The idea that LvB composed the 9th for his sister- in-law as a-forgive-me-for-making-your-life-a-hell is the director's personal fabrication and so is the feeble ending. Also, there is much more to LvB than his 5th, 9th and the Pathetique and it's a shame that even these were cut into bits and pieces and added here and there without any musicality to the frames, but rather as background music. There is short scene when a white pianist is accompanied by a black violinist playing the Kreutzer Sonata; it did ring a bell but I had to look it up. The 'mulatto' violinist was supposed to be George Bridgetower (11 October 177829 February 1860) an Afro-Polish-born virtuoso who had a quite tempestuous professional relationship with LvB. Such a shame that this was not more elaborately depicted in the movie. That could have been a great instructive scene. LvB is quite distorted here and even the great actor Gary Oldman can't save his dignity nor the voluptuous and expensive production. Actually Mr Oldman is over the top but I blame it on the pathetic direction. Watchable for the young, but not very instructive. p.s. Hearing the gorgeous Isabella Rossellini speak a couple of sentences in Hungarian made me smile :-)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Tale of solitude
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vincentiu
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Extraordinary cast. Impressive story. And a great Oldman. A precise ballet behind cages and traps. Delicate tale about love as more than feelings or ordinary fight. Portrait of a genius from sketch to final signature. And drops of music like fundamental character. A movie without definition. A trip fed by gentle touches and shadow of abyss. Build with intelligent science of details, it seems be a good novel. But, step by step, it is more. A cruel love story's faces, description of solitude and vain hope, exercise of cruelty and selfish, slices of pain and force of fly. And a gallery of women's portraits. As pictures of a snail. As games of existence's pieces. The film is wonderful for the gift to be a kind of parable. Beethoven may be everyone. Johanna is every person for who the other is only a geometrical figure.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Immortal Beloved - The life of the Great Ludwig Van.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MortenKristofferVebjornsen
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I first became of interest, in the music of classical category... I first heard the glorious tunes of Beethoven. They stunned me as a child, and still does... Much effort from Beethoven's side was put into his pieces of music. There have been many films to include them, in their repertoire of music. The once I have seen is few, but powerful to say it the least. "A Clockwork Orange" directed by Stanley Kubrick, that pioneered music with its synthesizing of the composers most famous works- The great "Ode to Joy" to name one though. The way Alex in "A Clockwork Orange" talks about Beethoven in that film, is like if he is a God- An icon of Heavenly proportions. I could agree, but to me he is a great composer, and his music captivate me- Inspire me and helps me in bad times, when does occur. Then we have this film with Gary Oldman taking on the ambitiousness to play the troubled composer. This is "Immortal Beloved"... With a pressure, emphasis on the "E" in Belov"e"d. The film takes place, in the life of Beethoven. His symphonies reflect every stage he have had in his life of deafness, one of his other obstacles. Since of deafness he became, his music could have stopped there. Had it not been for his shear determination to compose music that to him meant something indeed. And to his audience. In his life, Beethoven had many lovers- They all treated him badly, and when he dies... They mourns over that they could not treat him the way he deserved. Beethoven as an artist, deaf that he was- Was indeed eccentric, and treated them better than they did him. What I said about his symphonies with they being connected to his life and so... I will not go into detail about them, but I will say that when "Ode to Joy" comes bombastic at ya... You will feel indeed how he felt when he was subjected to violence by his father. Hence, the ultra-violence was not far away though. His father wanted, knowing that the boy had talent... told a set of aristocratic people that he was nine and could play like Mozart... The boy was twelve. Failed and beaten up, for only to escape this madman in the tunes of "Ode to Joy". It is Epic and beyond comprehension of understanding the shear magnitude of his ways to compose the music he did... Deaf indeed that he was. I salute it completely. Gary Oldman captures what I can think, the sadness, the joy and the misery this artist had- To perfection within the boundaries of the films limit. The cinematography is so, and so... Yet some scenes in palaces and scenes of gardens are to say it the least beautiful to look at, and that is great enough for me. Sometimes, the image could have been executed better, by injecting less light, and more natural light being let in. In the scenes where Karl Van Beethoven tries to commit suicide, the shots of him walking in the woods feels very flat- But in the films length of two magnificent hours- This does not apply whatsoever. Karl is by the way the son of Ludwig Van... Here his lovers appear once more. There was one, that became his obsession, his muse. His Immortal Beloved. The wife of his brother Caspar. To her, he leaves everything- His music and his estate. Originally to his brothers this was to be given. The sad thing, she waited on him at a hotel- Only to leave as he arrived, sad I became indeed. The film puts you under the skin of Beethoven, and let you feel his journey told through flashbacks of the people he socialized with- that mostly being his lovers, and his assistant Schindler, played by Jeroen Krabb&eacute;. The acting is superb and the execution of the director Bernard Rose is great, and he have really caught the essence of Beethoven. The Man, The Artist and The Father. It is a great film, easily enjoyable, if you are into Beethoven- Then this maximizes by the numbers. It is easy to understand and you will feel like you are being part of the events displayed in the film. Now... play some music of Beethoven while you read this review again- to gain the effect I did while writing it. Preferably, the ninth. The End.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A movie to be savored, rather than critiqued on historical accuracy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    I_saw_it_happen
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    People get tied up on whether or not this film portrays the life of Beethoven accurately; this misses the point of the film entirely. This is not so much a film about Beethoven, so much as the way in which he effected those around him, and inspired a devotion among his followers which lives to this day. If you consider a movie like, for instance, 'Shakespeare in Love'--- it's quite apparent to anyone who knows anything about Shakespeare that the film has only the faintest correlation to Shakespeare, which didn't seem to get in the way of people awarding THAT movie, and lauding praise on it, because Shakespeare was played as a hopeless romantic that everyone WANTS to believe in. While Immortal Beloved may share a similarity to S.I.L in it's, shall we say, creative interpretations, Immortal Beloved is a far superior film because it shows Beethoven in all aspects of his humanity. There's Beethoven as a Romantic rock star, there's the tender friend, the arrogant drunken bastard, the possessive misogynist, the pathetic misanthrope, all of it. Gary Oldman's role is superb. It is difficult to imagine anyone else in the role after seeing this movie. The acting is top-notch, albeit a bit melodramatic at points (Beethoven's assistant especially gets a bit heartfelt a bit often). There are a few scenes in this movie which are truly tearjerker moments. The scene in which 'Ode to Joy' is played is predictably great, even though it (like a lot of the film) feels a bit dated now. All in all, a rewarding and thoughtful piece on a man whose life was indeed complicated and monumental. Highly recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Idiotic Premise
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Richard Nathan (Richard-Nathan@att.net)
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/5/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After Beethoven died, love letters he had written to his "Immortal Beloved" were discovered. The name of the Immortal Beloved was not included in the letters. That all makes sense. However, in this film what is found is not letters but a will - in which Beethoven leaves his estate to his Immortal Beloved, but does not tell anyone who she is. Does that make sense to anyone? If he really wanted to leave her his estate, wouldn't it have occurred to him that it maybe it might have been a good idea to identify her by name? Are we supposed to think we was an idiot? Are we, perhaps, supposed to think he wrote the will while suffering from dementia? I can't think of any other reason why he would make a bequest to someone he declined to identify.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Forever Beethoven- visually audacious and musically majestic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I know that Immortal Beloved has been compared to Amadeus, and here I am going to keep my comparison brief, personally I don't think Immortal Beloved is quite as good as Amadeus, but I love both films with a passion. Ludwig Van Beethoven is my all time favourite classical music composer, and having watched Eroica with Ian Hart and the 3-part BBC dramatisation of Beethoven with Paul Rhys, I wanted to see what this film was like. My conclusion is that Immortal Beloved is a visually audacious, musically majestic and imaginative near-masterpiece. Immortal Beloved certainly looks stunning. The scenery is gorgeous, the costumes sumptuous and the cinematography fluid and beautiful. Seriously when you are transported to 18th century Vienna you feel like you have just come out of a time machine. There are also many effective scenes such as young Ludwig running away from his abusive father, Johanna visiting Beethoven as he lies dying in bed (one of the few times when a piece of classical music-the String Quartet Op.130 here- reduced me to tears in just one scene of one film), Beethoven resting his ear while playing the Moonlight Sonata, Beethoven with his back to the audience during the performance of the Choral Symphony and the performance of the Emperor concerto(I did read somewhere that during a concert when the orchestra wouldn't play the piece right, Beethoven stopped it and ordered for it to be played again). Even the use of Missa Solemnis was beautifully done, so hauntingly beautiful. The music is a revelation, pretty much the heart and soul of the film. It is a true delight from start to finish, I loved hearing the Moonlight and Pathetique sonatas, the Choral Symphony(the Ode to Joy movement has always been my favourite work of his), the Emperor Concerto,the violin concerto, Missa Solemnis and the 2nd movement of the 7th symphony as it was performed by the London Symphony Orchestra and conducted by Georg Solti. Bernard Rose is an unusual choice for director, having directed the gruesome horror film Caddyshack, but he does respectably as he seeks to identify the "immortal beloved" of Beethoven's will(to this day we don't know who Beethoven is referring to). The scripting is intelligent and moving, one might say it doesn't say much, but it has heart, and the story is solid, deep and doesn't meander. The acting is uniformly excellent. Jeroen Krabbe is fine as Anton Schindler, and Isabella Rosselini, Johanna ter Steege and Valeria Golino look beautiful and act very convincingly as the suspects of Beethoven's affections. I have to say though Gary Oldman does give the best performance of the film, while some scenes could have done with a touch more moderato it was a superb, charismatic and moving performance. I have read complaints that Oldman overacted, complaints I don't agree with at all. Just because Beethoven shouts a lot here, doesn't mean Oldman was overacting, and he certainly didn't overact in the final scene between him and Johanna, his acting was a masterclass of sheer poignancy there. Beethoven wasn't exactly a knight in shining armour now was he? He was rude, aggressive and reacted vehemently to even the smallest thing and probably traumatised by the memories of being abused by his alcoholic father. Beethoven also encountered alcoholism and increasing deafness, and by 1812 or so he was deaf completely. Overall, this is a wonderful, underrated film. Only problem with it? I did feel the ending was a little too open-and-shut, but maybe it is just me. I cannot deny though that this is a great film. 9.5/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Magnificent!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    potato2
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/8/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The year is 1827, and famed composer Ludwig van Beethoven has just died. He leaves his estate to someone only known as his "Immortal Beloved," so his secretary goes about finding out who she may be among his many lovers. This movie is absolutely beautiful. Beethoven's music, of course, is the soundtrack and also the main plot point, as the writer/director speculates on the events in the maestro's life that inspired each piece. The movie goes back and forth in time to each of the important people in Beethoven's life and we see his music evolve from much tragedy, some euphoria, and most of all, his passion for life. There is even a persuasive scene accounting for his deafness. With lavish costumes and picturesque Czech locations, it's lovely to look at but even more impressive is Gary Oldman's portrayal of Beethoven. Though playing a conceited, temperamental, and often angry man, Oldman still wins our sympathy and he is at his charismatic best. If you love Beethoven's music and/or period films, you'll enjoy this exciting biopic. Highly recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Immortally Performed!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SamuelSataniel
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/3/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The film is a very good look at the life and love of Ludwhig Beethoven. It is perhaps not one of the best films portraying a musician (Amadeus is perhaps far greater) but deserves to be observed. The best part of this film are the performances which are completely underrated. Gary Oldman who doesn't look the part makes it completely his own. He resembles the inner and outer life of this old genius. Gary Oldman himself a genius is great at performing genius. And the rest of the cast give a solid and strong framing for the entire story of Beethoven. This is a must see for fans of great acting and those who want to know the story of this immortal Man who shall live for all times.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A brief review of Immortal Beloved.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    cluso502
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Immortal Beloved disappointed me. Being both a fan of Gary Oldman and Beethoven I thought nothing could go wrong, and nothing did, as far as the soundtrack and Gary Oldman's performance were concerned. But Several other aspects of the film fell short. The cinematography was boring, costuming was historical, but plain, dialogue was not bad, but had very little substance, and the story-line was quite unsatisfying. Several character choices were unexplained. I never felt like I got to know any of the characters. And frankly the film seemed utterly pointless. I learned nothing and It had little artistic value. However it wasn't all bad, Gary Oldman had a few nice scenes with Marco Hofschneider, although they were cut short. The saddest part is that this film could have been a masterpiece if only it had different direction. I would love to re edit this film myself just to make the story flow in a more interesting direction. I recommend it if you can catch it for free and have nothing better to do. But never pay for this film. 6/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This film is perfect- the genius of his music combined with the complexity of his nature....
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dee Ross
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    For me - Beethoven stands alone in his genre - especially for his time. Too many historians worry about minute details in a famous person's life - and discredit stories that take a more artistic approach to revealing something about that person. No one knows all there is to know about a man from the 18th and 19th centuries - especially about his inner soul and what drives him to brilliance and raging behavior. The idea that there could have been someone unknown is enticing, and the concept of a film telling about Beethoven through the eyes of others is not a new one, but a format that allows more flexibility. I personally am glad they took this approach. Character development was therefore much more interesting. Oldman's performance was brilliant - and as is often the case with Oldman - you come to feel you are really watching Beethoven. The other personalities also were developed well - and his music was shown in the context of his times - sometimes harsh (his father's beatings) - sometimes tumultuous (the Napoleonic Wars) - sometimes full of love ( the women in his life who did adore him), - and sometimes driven by personal disappointment and anger (the onset of deafness and possibly an unrequited love.....) Beethoven took music to the next level - adding emotion to the beauty and structure already employed by others..... Some are shocked when I say that he was like the Led Zeppelin of the 19th Century - evoking new responses from listeners then, and still one of the few classical composers that you can play for anyone today and they will say "WOW!". Even those who really aren't fans of this kind of music. That is why they chose the 9th Symphony to celebrate the new millennium in 2000 GLOBALLY. Beethoven is universal and timeless. The movie is a wonderful way of sharing a moment with the maestro.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    historically and biographically inaccurate
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ursulahemard
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Not at all convinced. Why? Because this movie has numerous historical inaccuracies aka no chronological order: Ludwig van Beethoven's (17 December 1770  26 March 1827) total deafness occurs far too early, LvB is conducting personally works he actually never did, composing works in the wrong time order, etc. In addition to that, the movie takes too many liberties, to my taste, about the biographical facts, and to imply that that famous love-letter, written by LvB to his 'Immortal Beloved', would be ultimately his sister-in-law is just utterly preposterous. That letter was written and could have been addressed to several very well known ladies, we meet some of them during the movie, nevertheless no absolute certainty was proved until today. But it's most certainly not his sister-in-law, with whom he had so many conflicts and legal battles over years. The idea that LvB composed the 9th for his sister- in-law as a-forgive-me-for-making-your-life-a-hell is the director's personal fabrication and so is the feeble ending. Also, there is much more to LvB than his 5th, 9th and the Pathetique and it's a shame that even these were cut into bits and pieces and added here and there without any musicality to the frames, but rather as background music. There is short scene when a white pianist is accompanied by a black violinist playing the Kreutzer Sonata; it did ring a bell but I had to look it up. The 'mulatto' violinist was supposed to be George Bridgetower (11 October 177829 February 1860) an Afro-Polish-born virtuoso who had a quite tempestuous professional relationship with LvB. Such a shame that this was not more elaborately depicted in the movie. That could have been a great instructive scene. LvB is quite distorted here and even the great actor Gary Oldman can't save his dignity nor the voluptuous and expensive production. Actually Mr Oldman is over the top but I blame it on the pathetic direction. Watchable for the young, but not very instructive. p.s. Hearing the gorgeous Isabella Rossellini speak a couple of sentences in Hungarian made me smile :-)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Tale of solitude
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Vincentiu
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/12/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Extraordinary cast. Impressive story. And a great Oldman. A precise ballet behind cages and traps. Delicate tale about love as more than feelings or ordinary fight. Portrait of a genius from sketch to final signature. And drops of music like fundamental character. A movie without definition. A trip fed by gentle touches and shadow of abyss. Build with intelligent science of details, it seems be a good novel. But, step by step, it is more. A cruel love story's faces, description of solitude and vain hope, exercise of cruelty and selfish, slices of pain and force of fly. And a gallery of women's portraits. As pictures of a snail. As games of existence's pieces. The film is wonderful for the gift to be a kind of parable. Beethoven may be everyone. Johanna is every person for who the other is only a geometrical figure.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Immortal Beloved - The life of the Great Ludwig Van.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MortenKristofferVebjornsen
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    When I first became of interest, in the music of classical category... I first heard the glorious tunes of Beethoven. They stunned me as a child, and still does... Much effort from Beethoven's side was put into his pieces of music. There have been many films to include them, in their repertoire of music. The once I have seen is few, but powerful to say it the least. "A Clockwork Orange" directed by Stanley Kubrick, that pioneered music with its synthesizing of the composers most famous works- The great "Ode to Joy" to name one though. The way Alex in "A Clockwork Orange" talks about Beethoven in that film, is like if he is a God- An icon of Heavenly proportions. I could agree, but to me he is a great composer, and his music captivate me- Inspire me and helps me in bad times, when does occur. Then we have this film with Gary Oldman taking on the ambitiousness to play the troubled composer. This is "Immortal Beloved"... With a pressure, emphasis on the "E" in Belov"e"d. The film takes place, in the life of Beethoven. His symphonies reflect every stage he have had in his life of deafness, one of his other obstacles. Since of deafness he became, his music could have stopped there. Had it not been for his shear determination to compose music that to him meant something indeed. And to his audience. In his life, Beethoven had many lovers- They all treated him badly, and when he dies... They mourns over that they could not treat him the way he deserved. Beethoven as an artist, deaf that he was- Was indeed eccentric, and treated them better than they did him. What I said about his symphonies with they being connected to his life and so... I will not go into detail about them, but I will say that when "Ode to Joy" comes bombastic at ya... You will feel indeed how he felt when he was subjected to violence by his father. Hence, the ultra-violence was not far away though. His father wanted, knowing that the boy had talent... told a set of aristocratic people that he was nine and could play like Mozart... The boy was twelve. Failed and beaten up, for only to escape this madman in the tunes of "Ode to Joy". It is Epic and beyond comprehension of understanding the shear magnitude of his ways to compose the music he did... Deaf indeed that he was. I salute it completely. Gary Oldman captures what I can think, the sadness, the joy and the misery this artist had- To perfection within the boundaries of the films limit. The cinematography is so, and so... Yet some scenes in palaces and scenes of gardens are to say it the least beautiful to look at, and that is great enough for me. Sometimes, the image could have been executed better, by injecting less light, and more natural light being let in. In the scenes where Karl Van Beethoven tries to commit suicide, the shots of him walking in the woods feels very flat- But in the films length of two magnificent hours- This does not apply whatsoever. Karl is by the way the son of Ludwig Van... Here his lovers appear once more. There was one, that became his obsession, his muse. His Immortal Beloved. The wife of his brother Caspar. To her, he leaves everything- His music and his estate. Originally to his brothers this was to be given. The sad thing, she waited on him at a hotel- Only to leave as he arrived, sad I became indeed. The film puts you under the skin of Beethoven, and let you feel his journey told through flashbacks of the people he socialized with- that mostly being his lovers, and his assistant Schindler, played by Jeroen Krabb&eacute;. The acting is superb and the execution of the director Bernard Rose is great, and he have really caught the essence of Beethoven. The Man, The Artist and The Father. It is a great film, easily enjoyable, if you are into Beethoven- Then this maximizes by the numbers. It is easy to understand and you will feel like you are being part of the events displayed in the film. Now... play some music of Beethoven while you read this review again- to gain the effect I did while writing it. Preferably, the ninth. The End.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A movie to be savored, rather than critiqued on historical accuracy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    I_saw_it_happen
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    People get tied up on whether or not this film portrays the life of Beethoven accurately; this misses the point of the film entirely. This is not so much a film about Beethoven, so much as the way in which he effected those around him, and inspired a devotion among his followers which lives to this day. If you consider a movie like, for instance, 'Shakespeare in Love'--- it's quite apparent to anyone who knows anything about Shakespeare that the film has only the faintest correlation to Shakespeare, which didn't seem to get in the way of people awarding THAT movie, and lauding praise on it, because Shakespeare was played as a hopeless romantic that everyone WANTS to believe in. While Immortal Beloved may share a similarity to S.I.L in it's, shall we say, creative interpretations, Immortal Beloved is a far superior film because it shows Beethoven in all aspects of his humanity. There's Beethoven as a Romantic rock star, there's the tender friend, the arrogant drunken bastard, the possessive misogynist, the pathetic misanthrope, all of it. Gary Oldman's role is superb. It is difficult to imagine anyone else in the role after seeing this movie. The acting is top-notch, albeit a bit melodramatic at points (Beethoven's assistant especially gets a bit heartfelt a bit often). There are a few scenes in this movie which are truly tearjerker moments. The scene in which 'Ode to Joy' is played is predictably great, even though it (like a lot of the film) feels a bit dated now. All in all, a rewarding and thoughtful piece on a man whose life was indeed complicated and monumental. Highly recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Idiotic Premise
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Richard Nathan (Richard-Nathan@att.net)
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/5/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After Beethoven died, love letters he had written to his "Immortal Beloved" were discovered. The name of the Immortal Beloved was not included in the letters. That all makes sense. However, in this film what is found is not letters but a will - in which Beethoven leaves his estate to his Immortal Beloved, but does not tell anyone who she is. Does that make sense to anyone? If he really wanted to leave her his estate, wouldn't it have occurred to him that it maybe it might have been a good idea to identify her by name? Are we supposed to think we was an idiot? Are we, perhaps, supposed to think he wrote the will while suffering from dementia? I can't think of any other reason why he would make a bequest to someone he declined to identify.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Forever Beethoven- visually audacious and musically majestic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I know that Immortal Beloved has been compared to Amadeus, and here I am going to keep my comparison brief, personally I don't think Immortal Beloved is quite as good as Amadeus, but I love both films with a passion. Ludwig Van Beethoven is my all time favourite classical music composer, and having watched Eroica with Ian Hart and the 3-part BBC dramatisation of Beethoven with Paul Rhys, I wanted to see what this film was like. My conclusion is that Immortal Beloved is a visually audacious, musically majestic and imaginative near-masterpiece. Immortal Beloved certainly looks stunning. The scenery is gorgeous, the costumes sumptuous and the cinematography fluid and beautiful. Seriously when you are transported to 18th century Vienna you feel like you have just come out of a time machine. There are also many effective scenes such as young Ludwig running away from his abusive father, Johanna visiting Beethoven as he lies dying in bed (one of the few times when a piece of classical music-the String Quartet Op.130 here- reduced me to tears in just one scene of one film), Beethoven resting his ear while playing the Moonlight Sonata, Beethoven with his back to the audience during the performance of the Choral Symphony and the performance of the Emperor concerto(I did read somewhere that during a concert when the orchestra wouldn't play the piece right, Beethoven stopped it and ordered for it to be played again). Even the use of Missa Solemnis was beautifully done, so hauntingly beautiful. The music is a revelation, pretty much the heart and soul of the film. It is a true delight from start to finish, I loved hearing the Moonlight and Pathetique sonatas, the Choral Symphony(the Ode to Joy movement has always been my favourite work of his), the Emperor Concerto,the violin concerto, Missa Solemnis and the 2nd movement of the 7th symphony as it was performed by the London Symphony Orchestra and conducted by Georg Solti. Bernard Rose is an unusual choice for director, having directed the gruesome horror film Caddyshack, but he does respectably as he seeks to identify the "immortal beloved" of Beethoven's will(to this day we don't know who Beethoven is referring to). The scripting is intelligent and moving, one might say it doesn't say much, but it has heart, and the story is solid, deep and doesn't meander. The acting is uniformly excellent. Jeroen Krabbe is fine as Anton Schindler, and Isabella Rosselini, Johanna ter Steege and Valeria Golino look beautiful and act very convincingly as the suspects of Beethoven's affections. I have to say though Gary Oldman does give the best performance of the film, while some scenes could have done with a touch more moderato it was a superb, charismatic and moving performance. I have read complaints that Oldman overacted, complaints I don't agree with at all. Just because Beethoven shouts a lot here, doesn't mean Oldman was overacting, and he certainly didn't overact in the final scene between him and Johanna, his acting was a masterclass of sheer poignancy there. Beethoven wasn't exactly a knight in shining armour now was he? He was rude, aggressive and reacted vehemently to even the smallest thing and probably traumatised by the memories of being abused by his alcoholic father. Beethoven also encountered alcoholism and increasing deafness, and by 1812 or so he was deaf completely. Overall, this is a wonderful, underrated film. Only problem with it? I did feel the ending was a little too open-and-shut, but maybe it is just me. I cannot deny though that this is a great film. 9.5/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Magnificent!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    potato2
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/8/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The year is 1827, and famed composer Ludwig van Beethoven has just died. He leaves his estate to someone only known as his "Immortal Beloved," so his secretary goes about finding out who she may be among his many lovers. This movie is absolutely beautiful. Beethoven's music, of course, is the soundtrack and also the main plot point, as the writer/director speculates on the events in the maestro's life that inspired each piece. The movie goes back and forth in time to each of the important people in Beethoven's life and we see his music evolve from much tragedy, some euphoria, and most of all, his passion for life. There is even a persuasive scene accounting for his deafness. With lavish costumes and picturesque Czech locations, it's lovely to look at but even more impressive is Gary Oldman's portrayal of Beethoven. Though playing a conceited, temperamental, and often angry man, Oldman still wins our sympathy and he is at his charismatic best. If you love Beethoven's music and/or period films, you'll enjoy this exciting biopic. Highly recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Immortally Performed!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SamuelSataniel
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/3/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The film is a very good look at the life and love of Ludwhig Beethoven. It is perhaps not one of the best films portraying a musician (Amadeus is perhaps far greater) but deserves to be observed. The best part of this film are the performances which are completely underrated. Gary Oldman who doesn't look the part makes it completely his own. He resembles the inner and outer life of this old genius. Gary Oldman himself a genius is great at performing genius. And the rest of the cast give a solid and strong framing for the entire story of Beethoven. This is a must see for fans of great acting and those who want to know the story of this immortal Man who shall live for all times.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
