<filme>
 <id>
  729
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0110638
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1994
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Nell
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.3
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  In a remote woodland cabin, a small town doctor discovers Nell - a beautiful young hermit woman with many secrets.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Nell is a girl who's been brought up in an isolated world. The only people she knew were her mother and twin sister. They lived together in a cottage in the forest. Nobody has ever met Nell. After her mother's death, she's discovered by the local doctor Jerome. He's fascinated by her, since she speaks a mangled language, developed by her sister and herself growing up, "twin speak" if you will. But Paula, a psychology student, wants her observed in a laboratory. The judge decides they get three months to observe her in the forest, after which he'll decide about Nell's future.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   twin
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   psychology
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   forest
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   isolation
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   death
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Michael Apted
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Mark Handley
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   William Nicholson
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Jodie Foster
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Liam Neeson
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Natasha Richardson
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Emotional, yet simple, modest, and beautiful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Deepak Janardhan
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Nell, the movie is titled after the protagonist Nell, a wild girl who has grown up isolated in the woods. The lack of exposure, death of her twin sister, and tales narrated by her paralyzed hermit mother leaves her with an unusual behavior, distorted speech, fear of strangers and the real world. The story revolves around Dr. Jerome Lovell who discovers Nell, panic-stricken at the death of her mother. He tries his best to communicate with her, protect her from strangers, and lead her to a normal life. With time, he grows fond of her. When Jerome explores different options to grab Nell's attention and persuades her to respond, the movie gets intriguing. Dr. Jerome discusses Nell's case with Paula Olsen, who believes and proposes that institutionalization is the way to treat and protect Nell. Paula appeals to the court for the custody of Nell. However, Jerome counters that Nell will turn out to be an object of scientific research like other patients in such medical facilities. The court grants 3 months to both the appellants to observe Nell closely and prove their stance. However, after observing Nell's independence, routines, and response to Jerome, Paula is convinced that the impersonal medical procedures will not cure Nell. Therefore, she begins to assist Jerome in his efforts to understand Nell's language and interact with her. Jerome soon turns out to be Nell's "Guardian Angel". But during their stay together, Jerome and Paula also develop intimacy. Towards the climax, I was convinced that Jerome and Nell will lead a happy life together. However, the movie takes a smooth turn when Nell is seen as the same person but in the company of Jerome's friends. She is shown free, happy, and playing in the woods with Ruthie, Jerome and Paula's daughter. I am impressed by the remarkable performances of Jodie Foster and Liam Neeson. Jodie Foster's effort to justify Nell's appearance and behavior as a wild girl deserves a clamorous applause, mainly for her voice modulation, expressions, movements, and gestures. Liam Neeson's acting as Dr Jerome is significant. Particularly, the dramatic narration of his childhood to evoke Nell's reaction is spectacular. The portrayal of innocence and purity is heart-warming, when Nell vents out her feelings to Jerome and embraces him. Jerome's natural display of disappointment and anger is powerful, at the pathetic sight of Nell in the hospital. The impulsive reaction on realizing that he would lose Nell is admirable. Last but not the least, the choice of the pristine location in the movie, around Nell's wood cabin, certainly adds to the effectiveness of the plot. Firstly, if you are a fan of either Jodie Foster or Liam Neeson, you must not miss this movie. In general, "Nell" is worth your money and time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What the light has been made for...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stormwings
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is 18 now, there are reviews from zero to 10, so here is mine: Albert Einstein said "Imagination is more important than knowledge. For knowledge is limited..." Nell" shows that kind of knowledge which is behind the veil of Isis" and that's because some aware people got together to make this visible. It seems that we still need stories" to reach this, but stories are only a start and never a conclusion. Thou are beautiful, O my love, as Tirzah" - this world is full of grace if you begin trying to say it to anyone, because all you say is to yourself. Who's Tirzah?" Jerry Lovell asked, swimming, laughing... It always makes me shine. Alicia Foster's face at the very end shows all we need to know - during about 16 seconds. The most beautiful thing a camera ever could have been taken for; the light was made for.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    So much more than beautiful...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Paul Magne Haakonsen
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I remember seeing this movie when I was younger, and had a fair memory of how the movie was and that it was a rather good movie. Now in 2012, I decided to get the movie and have another look at it. And I am actually quite happy that I did buy it from Amazon, because this movie is more than good. "Nell" is a really beautiful story that will have you swept away and have you immersed into the story in no time. "Nell" tells a story of being human, accepting people for what and whom they are, it is a story of existence, but most importantly it is a story of the heart. I think this was actually the first or second movie I watched with Liam Neeson (playing Jerome Lovell) in it, and to this day, I still think this is his best and most memorable performance. Jodie Foster (playing Nell) is nothing short of extraordinary in this movie. Her performance is breathtakingly beautiful and so heartfelt. You really get caught up in the story, and you want to know what happens next. And the way Nell's story is revealed to you and how she grows, it is like you are right there with her. The director really did an awesome job on this movie. And the way Jodie Foster portrays Nell when exposed to the world and the life we take for granted is really good acting and amazing performing. She really makes Nell come to life as a real person. "Nell" really goes straight into your heart and soul and the story will be with you for a long, long time. And you might want to keep some tissues at hand, because the story is really touching, and really helped so greatly along by Jodie Foster. I know that I will be watching this movie again at some point, even though the story doesn't hold surprising twists and such, it is one that can bear being watched more than once.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jodie's zenith
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Matt James (matjpi@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In "Nell", Jodie Foster gives, arguably, the best performance of her life. Clearly, she invested deeply in the role and her genuine strength and inner beauty shine so brightly into the character that Nell's beauty and loneliness become completely convincing. The story is more idealistic than realistic (as allegories are wont to be) which is worth remembering throughout - not least when it comes to the courtroom scene. I appreciated the sentiment of that scene whilst privately wishing it had been a closed hearing (full for a custody hearing?) Despite some ragged plot problems (that USGS wouldn't know about the Kellty homestead, that Nell is in really good health, that the lads who deliver her groceries never appear to discuss the 'strange hermit woman' with anyone, and so on) the story staggers to the finish line with an overly idyllic ending. Liam Neeson and Natasha Richardson support well locking horns convincingly over which was to become Nell's champion until they realised that Nell wasn't a trophy for an academic white paper. Nell becomes the adopted child, the glue that binds Neeson and Richardson's characters' emotional attachment. The film has some poetic cinematography and good location. But it is Jodie Foster's ability to play crushingly tender moments (the mirror, the lake, the effective memory) that - I'm happy to admit - still bring me to tears and is why I don't watch it a lot. It's a good film for couples who either have, or want to have, children. When you see it, I hope you'll understand why.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Nell" is a Jodie Foster Triumph
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dale Haufrect (dhaufrect@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The 1994 film, "Nell", is an acting triumph for Jodie Foster. The screenplay is by William Nicholson and it was adapted from the remarkable play by Mark Hadley. Foster grows up as a Yeti in a remote forest having been raised by her mother who suffered from a speech disorder or aphasia after running to the woods escaping the rapist who had attacked her. "Nell" then grows to adulthood with little to say in favor of men, and little speech to begin with anyway. Modern society attempts to "treat" her, but Liam Neesam is able to convince the doctors to allow her some space for growing room and a period of adjustment in order to make a more gradual adjustment to society. This film is compelling from the moment it begins and holds ones attention to the very end. It is deserving of much praise for handling a delicate subject with loving care and empathy that permeates the film. The cinematography is overwhelming and makes one jealous of Nell's environment. It is a very good rent now on DVD and well worth the time involved. Neesam's portrayal of a family physician turned naturalist is equally as compelling as is that of Foster making for a very satisfying picture.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An entertaining film, but it lacks seriousness.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Luis Angel Gonzalez
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What I didn't like about this film is that it went more on the cheesy side of things, while it could have been a more serious and mature one. I would have really liked this story told on a more serious way, but as in many films with good stories, they tend to be ruined when they are chosen to be for all audiences. I'm not saying that it is bad to do that though, some movies are great that way, but this one, in my opinion, didn't need that. Now onto the acting, I didn't like Jodie Foster,her acting seemed forced to me. Liam and Natasha did good, but nothing special in their acting. All in all, this is an entertaining film that many may like, but for me it didn't do much.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fascinating Story That Turns A Bit Too "Feel Good" In The End
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sddavis63 (revsdd@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The subject matter is fascinating. Nell (Jodie Foster) is a young woman raised by her mother in a setting completely cut off from civilization. She knows nothing of the outside world and has had little if any interaction with other people throughout her life, to the point at which she's developed her own language. Discovered by a grocery store delivery boy when her mother died, she comes under the care and tutelage of Drs. Lovell and Olson (Liam Neesom and Natasha Richardson) who have to decide whether or not she should be taken from her isolated environment and introduced to the "real" world. The dilemma is very powerful. What right does anyone else have to decide for Nell how her life should be lived, especially when she's clearly capable of living on her own in the environment to which she's accustomed? Why should she be subject to court orders about her fate or to living in psychiatric hospitals when there's obviously nothing really wrong with her except that she's living a life that no one in the outside world can understand? Those are tough questions. The movie does a great job of developing the relationship between Nell and Lovell (and then also Olson) in a sensitive way, as both begin to care for Nell and want to be protective of her and her rights to choose. Jodie Foster was - I thought - surprisingly good in this role. She usually plays a stronger type, and - at least as the movie opens - Nell was a very vulnerable figure. I didn't know if Foster would work in such a role, but she pulled it off perfectly. I would criticize this film only for the overly happy ending. Beginning with Nell appearing in court, this took on a too "syrupy" fell in my opinion; everything in the end was far too happy to be believable - in my opinion anyway. But aside from that I thought this was a very well done movie and a very interesting story. (7/10)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Superb
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Gregory Kauffman
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was fortunate enough to see the original production of the play, its emotional impact was as profound as any I have experienced in the theatre. It is perhaps for this reason that I was left somewhat disappointed with this film. However, I recently looked at it again and found that it is truly a top film. Jodie Foster is a towering talent as an actor and this performance was as good or better than any she's given. Neeson and Richardson were also at the top of their game. And the story of a woman shut off from the world, and the world's perceptions of her, merely because she can't communicate to it, is profound in its implications. I should not have been surprised about being disappointed the first time. I also saw a stage production in Los Angeles of IDIOGLOSSIA and found that disappointing after the original. But this film is a wonderful film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A criminally under appreciated and overlooked, divine film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dragoneyed363
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Nell is one of those movies that captivated me in so many ways for so many reasons. It is powerful, poetic and astonishingly beautiful with a beautiful message and an overwhelming use of angelic material that makes my heart ache from how wonderful the attributes that this film tries to get across to it's audience are. The story is a bit familiar, yet they add so much pizazz that it makes it seem fresh and brand new. It really does handle all the subject matter so well and it is exquisitely executed. The directing and writing were amazing, and I thought the performances in particular were absolutely brilliant. Jodie Foster gave such character, life and believability to Nell that I don't think anyone else could have gave any better; she is truly spectacular and deserved that Oscar nomination, maybe even the win. The characters are well done and really likable for the performances and screenplay behind them so you actually care for them, which is what more movies need to try and do; make you care for the characters. Like I said, Nell is dramatic to the point where it's painful, in a good way, sort of, to watch this woman's innocent, undisturbed life play out and unfold, and you wish for anything that you can just make everyone see her point of view and you really hope everything pulls through for this brilliant character in the end. Nell definitely makes us wonder who are the real monsters of this world. The cinematography is excellent also and I found myself completely caught up in how awe-inspiring everything in the movie is at times, whether it's the cinematography, characters or story, which the story is absolutely gripping and fascinating, if you have not caught that by now. Nell seems to be a really overlooked film because most people do not see it for it's full potential of delight and cleverness. It has a few fans, but I never hear any talk of how wonderful it is from anyone. I thought it was excellent, and an astonishing watch, no, adventure, that I would love to live out again sometime soon.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    First rate
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Neil Welch
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Having previously watched Nell one night on my own, I prevailed upon my wife and children (when they were coming up to their teens) to watch it with me one evening. As expected, they fell about laughing as soon as Jodie Foster started talking in "chickabee" language. And then, also as expected, they were utterly absorbed as this unusual and involving story unfolded. For, make no mistake, the quality of Jodie Foster's performance is such that Nell becomes absolutely real, and the audience is intrigued at discovering the explanation for her strange development, and dreadfully, dreadfully worried about what will happen to her. Others have written much better informed and more thoughtful reviews about this film - I will just say that I thought it was an excellent film, and so did my family.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Emotional, yet simple, modest, and beautiful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Deepak Janardhan
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Nell, the movie is titled after the protagonist Nell, a wild girl who has grown up isolated in the woods. The lack of exposure, death of her twin sister, and tales narrated by her paralyzed hermit mother leaves her with an unusual behavior, distorted speech, fear of strangers and the real world. The story revolves around Dr. Jerome Lovell who discovers Nell, panic-stricken at the death of her mother. He tries his best to communicate with her, protect her from strangers, and lead her to a normal life. With time, he grows fond of her. When Jerome explores different options to grab Nell's attention and persuades her to respond, the movie gets intriguing. Dr. Jerome discusses Nell's case with Paula Olsen, who believes and proposes that institutionalization is the way to treat and protect Nell. Paula appeals to the court for the custody of Nell. However, Jerome counters that Nell will turn out to be an object of scientific research like other patients in such medical facilities. The court grants 3 months to both the appellants to observe Nell closely and prove their stance. However, after observing Nell's independence, routines, and response to Jerome, Paula is convinced that the impersonal medical procedures will not cure Nell. Therefore, she begins to assist Jerome in his efforts to understand Nell's language and interact with her. Jerome soon turns out to be Nell's "Guardian Angel". But during their stay together, Jerome and Paula also develop intimacy. Towards the climax, I was convinced that Jerome and Nell will lead a happy life together. However, the movie takes a smooth turn when Nell is seen as the same person but in the company of Jerome's friends. She is shown free, happy, and playing in the woods with Ruthie, Jerome and Paula's daughter. I am impressed by the remarkable performances of Jodie Foster and Liam Neeson. Jodie Foster's effort to justify Nell's appearance and behavior as a wild girl deserves a clamorous applause, mainly for her voice modulation, expressions, movements, and gestures. Liam Neeson's acting as Dr Jerome is significant. Particularly, the dramatic narration of his childhood to evoke Nell's reaction is spectacular. The portrayal of innocence and purity is heart-warming, when Nell vents out her feelings to Jerome and embraces him. Jerome's natural display of disappointment and anger is powerful, at the pathetic sight of Nell in the hospital. The impulsive reaction on realizing that he would lose Nell is admirable. Last but not the least, the choice of the pristine location in the movie, around Nell's wood cabin, certainly adds to the effectiveness of the plot. Firstly, if you are a fan of either Jodie Foster or Liam Neeson, you must not miss this movie. In general, "Nell" is worth your money and time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What the light has been made for...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stormwings
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is 18 now, there are reviews from zero to 10, so here is mine: Albert Einstein said "Imagination is more important than knowledge. For knowledge is limited..." Nell" shows that kind of knowledge which is behind the veil of Isis" and that's because some aware people got together to make this visible. It seems that we still need stories" to reach this, but stories are only a start and never a conclusion. Thou are beautiful, O my love, as Tirzah" - this world is full of grace if you begin trying to say it to anyone, because all you say is to yourself. Who's Tirzah?" Jerry Lovell asked, swimming, laughing... It always makes me shine. Alicia Foster's face at the very end shows all we need to know - during about 16 seconds. The most beautiful thing a camera ever could have been taken for; the light was made for.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    So much more than beautiful...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Paul Magne Haakonsen
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I remember seeing this movie when I was younger, and had a fair memory of how the movie was and that it was a rather good movie. Now in 2012, I decided to get the movie and have another look at it. And I am actually quite happy that I did buy it from Amazon, because this movie is more than good. "Nell" is a really beautiful story that will have you swept away and have you immersed into the story in no time. "Nell" tells a story of being human, accepting people for what and whom they are, it is a story of existence, but most importantly it is a story of the heart. I think this was actually the first or second movie I watched with Liam Neeson (playing Jerome Lovell) in it, and to this day, I still think this is his best and most memorable performance. Jodie Foster (playing Nell) is nothing short of extraordinary in this movie. Her performance is breathtakingly beautiful and so heartfelt. You really get caught up in the story, and you want to know what happens next. And the way Nell's story is revealed to you and how she grows, it is like you are right there with her. The director really did an awesome job on this movie. And the way Jodie Foster portrays Nell when exposed to the world and the life we take for granted is really good acting and amazing performing. She really makes Nell come to life as a real person. "Nell" really goes straight into your heart and soul and the story will be with you for a long, long time. And you might want to keep some tissues at hand, because the story is really touching, and really helped so greatly along by Jodie Foster. I know that I will be watching this movie again at some point, even though the story doesn't hold surprising twists and such, it is one that can bear being watched more than once.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jodie's zenith
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Matt James (matjpi@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In "Nell", Jodie Foster gives, arguably, the best performance of her life. Clearly, she invested deeply in the role and her genuine strength and inner beauty shine so brightly into the character that Nell's beauty and loneliness become completely convincing. The story is more idealistic than realistic (as allegories are wont to be) which is worth remembering throughout - not least when it comes to the courtroom scene. I appreciated the sentiment of that scene whilst privately wishing it had been a closed hearing (full for a custody hearing?) Despite some ragged plot problems (that USGS wouldn't know about the Kellty homestead, that Nell is in really good health, that the lads who deliver her groceries never appear to discuss the 'strange hermit woman' with anyone, and so on) the story staggers to the finish line with an overly idyllic ending. Liam Neeson and Natasha Richardson support well locking horns convincingly over which was to become Nell's champion until they realised that Nell wasn't a trophy for an academic white paper. Nell becomes the adopted child, the glue that binds Neeson and Richardson's characters' emotional attachment. The film has some poetic cinematography and good location. But it is Jodie Foster's ability to play crushingly tender moments (the mirror, the lake, the effective memory) that - I'm happy to admit - still bring me to tears and is why I don't watch it a lot. It's a good film for couples who either have, or want to have, children. When you see it, I hope you'll understand why.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Nell" is a Jodie Foster Triumph
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dale Haufrect (dhaufrect@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The 1994 film, "Nell", is an acting triumph for Jodie Foster. The screenplay is by William Nicholson and it was adapted from the remarkable play by Mark Hadley. Foster grows up as a Yeti in a remote forest having been raised by her mother who suffered from a speech disorder or aphasia after running to the woods escaping the rapist who had attacked her. "Nell" then grows to adulthood with little to say in favor of men, and little speech to begin with anyway. Modern society attempts to "treat" her, but Liam Neesam is able to convince the doctors to allow her some space for growing room and a period of adjustment in order to make a more gradual adjustment to society. This film is compelling from the moment it begins and holds ones attention to the very end. It is deserving of much praise for handling a delicate subject with loving care and empathy that permeates the film. The cinematography is overwhelming and makes one jealous of Nell's environment. It is a very good rent now on DVD and well worth the time involved. Neesam's portrayal of a family physician turned naturalist is equally as compelling as is that of Foster making for a very satisfying picture.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An entertaining film, but it lacks seriousness.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Luis Angel Gonzalez
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What I didn't like about this film is that it went more on the cheesy side of things, while it could have been a more serious and mature one. I would have really liked this story told on a more serious way, but as in many films with good stories, they tend to be ruined when they are chosen to be for all audiences. I'm not saying that it is bad to do that though, some movies are great that way, but this one, in my opinion, didn't need that. Now onto the acting, I didn't like Jodie Foster,her acting seemed forced to me. Liam and Natasha did good, but nothing special in their acting. All in all, this is an entertaining film that many may like, but for me it didn't do much.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fascinating Story That Turns A Bit Too "Feel Good" In The End
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sddavis63 (revsdd@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The subject matter is fascinating. Nell (Jodie Foster) is a young woman raised by her mother in a setting completely cut off from civilization. She knows nothing of the outside world and has had little if any interaction with other people throughout her life, to the point at which she's developed her own language. Discovered by a grocery store delivery boy when her mother died, she comes under the care and tutelage of Drs. Lovell and Olson (Liam Neesom and Natasha Richardson) who have to decide whether or not she should be taken from her isolated environment and introduced to the "real" world. The dilemma is very powerful. What right does anyone else have to decide for Nell how her life should be lived, especially when she's clearly capable of living on her own in the environment to which she's accustomed? Why should she be subject to court orders about her fate or to living in psychiatric hospitals when there's obviously nothing really wrong with her except that she's living a life that no one in the outside world can understand? Those are tough questions. The movie does a great job of developing the relationship between Nell and Lovell (and then also Olson) in a sensitive way, as both begin to care for Nell and want to be protective of her and her rights to choose. Jodie Foster was - I thought - surprisingly good in this role. She usually plays a stronger type, and - at least as the movie opens - Nell was a very vulnerable figure. I didn't know if Foster would work in such a role, but she pulled it off perfectly. I would criticize this film only for the overly happy ending. Beginning with Nell appearing in court, this took on a too "syrupy" fell in my opinion; everything in the end was far too happy to be believable - in my opinion anyway. But aside from that I thought this was a very well done movie and a very interesting story. (7/10)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Superb
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Gregory Kauffman
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was fortunate enough to see the original production of the play, its emotional impact was as profound as any I have experienced in the theatre. It is perhaps for this reason that I was left somewhat disappointed with this film. However, I recently looked at it again and found that it is truly a top film. Jodie Foster is a towering talent as an actor and this performance was as good or better than any she's given. Neeson and Richardson were also at the top of their game. And the story of a woman shut off from the world, and the world's perceptions of her, merely because she can't communicate to it, is profound in its implications. I should not have been surprised about being disappointed the first time. I also saw a stage production in Los Angeles of IDIOGLOSSIA and found that disappointing after the original. But this film is a wonderful film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A criminally under appreciated and overlooked, divine film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dragoneyed363
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Nell is one of those movies that captivated me in so many ways for so many reasons. It is powerful, poetic and astonishingly beautiful with a beautiful message and an overwhelming use of angelic material that makes my heart ache from how wonderful the attributes that this film tries to get across to it's audience are. The story is a bit familiar, yet they add so much pizazz that it makes it seem fresh and brand new. It really does handle all the subject matter so well and it is exquisitely executed. The directing and writing were amazing, and I thought the performances in particular were absolutely brilliant. Jodie Foster gave such character, life and believability to Nell that I don't think anyone else could have gave any better; she is truly spectacular and deserved that Oscar nomination, maybe even the win. The characters are well done and really likable for the performances and screenplay behind them so you actually care for them, which is what more movies need to try and do; make you care for the characters. Like I said, Nell is dramatic to the point where it's painful, in a good way, sort of, to watch this woman's innocent, undisturbed life play out and unfold, and you wish for anything that you can just make everyone see her point of view and you really hope everything pulls through for this brilliant character in the end. Nell definitely makes us wonder who are the real monsters of this world. The cinematography is excellent also and I found myself completely caught up in how awe-inspiring everything in the movie is at times, whether it's the cinematography, characters or story, which the story is absolutely gripping and fascinating, if you have not caught that by now. Nell seems to be a really overlooked film because most people do not see it for it's full potential of delight and cleverness. It has a few fans, but I never hear any talk of how wonderful it is from anyone. I thought it was excellent, and an astonishing watch, no, adventure, that I would love to live out again sometime soon.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    First rate
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Neil Welch
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Having previously watched Nell one night on my own, I prevailed upon my wife and children (when they were coming up to their teens) to watch it with me one evening. As expected, they fell about laughing as soon as Jodie Foster started talking in "chickabee" language. And then, also as expected, they were utterly absorbed as this unusual and involving story unfolded. For, make no mistake, the quality of Jodie Foster's performance is such that Nell becomes absolutely real, and the audience is intrigued at discovering the explanation for her strange development, and dreadfully, dreadfully worried about what will happen to her. Others have written much better informed and more thoughtful reviews about this film - I will just say that I thought it was an excellent film, and so did my family.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Emotional, yet simple, modest, and beautiful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Deepak Janardhan
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Nell, the movie is titled after the protagonist Nell, a wild girl who has grown up isolated in the woods. The lack of exposure, death of her twin sister, and tales narrated by her paralyzed hermit mother leaves her with an unusual behavior, distorted speech, fear of strangers and the real world. The story revolves around Dr. Jerome Lovell who discovers Nell, panic-stricken at the death of her mother. He tries his best to communicate with her, protect her from strangers, and lead her to a normal life. With time, he grows fond of her. When Jerome explores different options to grab Nell's attention and persuades her to respond, the movie gets intriguing. Dr. Jerome discusses Nell's case with Paula Olsen, who believes and proposes that institutionalization is the way to treat and protect Nell. Paula appeals to the court for the custody of Nell. However, Jerome counters that Nell will turn out to be an object of scientific research like other patients in such medical facilities. The court grants 3 months to both the appellants to observe Nell closely and prove their stance. However, after observing Nell's independence, routines, and response to Jerome, Paula is convinced that the impersonal medical procedures will not cure Nell. Therefore, she begins to assist Jerome in his efforts to understand Nell's language and interact with her. Jerome soon turns out to be Nell's "Guardian Angel". But during their stay together, Jerome and Paula also develop intimacy. Towards the climax, I was convinced that Jerome and Nell will lead a happy life together. However, the movie takes a smooth turn when Nell is seen as the same person but in the company of Jerome's friends. She is shown free, happy, and playing in the woods with Ruthie, Jerome and Paula's daughter. I am impressed by the remarkable performances of Jodie Foster and Liam Neeson. Jodie Foster's effort to justify Nell's appearance and behavior as a wild girl deserves a clamorous applause, mainly for her voice modulation, expressions, movements, and gestures. Liam Neeson's acting as Dr Jerome is significant. Particularly, the dramatic narration of his childhood to evoke Nell's reaction is spectacular. The portrayal of innocence and purity is heart-warming, when Nell vents out her feelings to Jerome and embraces him. Jerome's natural display of disappointment and anger is powerful, at the pathetic sight of Nell in the hospital. The impulsive reaction on realizing that he would lose Nell is admirable. Last but not the least, the choice of the pristine location in the movie, around Nell's wood cabin, certainly adds to the effectiveness of the plot. Firstly, if you are a fan of either Jodie Foster or Liam Neeson, you must not miss this movie. In general, "Nell" is worth your money and time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What the light has been made for...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stormwings
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is 18 now, there are reviews from zero to 10, so here is mine: Albert Einstein said "Imagination is more important than knowledge. For knowledge is limited..." Nell" shows that kind of knowledge which is behind the veil of Isis" and that's because some aware people got together to make this visible. It seems that we still need stories" to reach this, but stories are only a start and never a conclusion. Thou are beautiful, O my love, as Tirzah" - this world is full of grace if you begin trying to say it to anyone, because all you say is to yourself. Who's Tirzah?" Jerry Lovell asked, swimming, laughing... It always makes me shine. Alicia Foster's face at the very end shows all we need to know - during about 16 seconds. The most beautiful thing a camera ever could have been taken for; the light was made for.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    So much more than beautiful...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Paul Magne Haakonsen
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I remember seeing this movie when I was younger, and had a fair memory of how the movie was and that it was a rather good movie. Now in 2012, I decided to get the movie and have another look at it. And I am actually quite happy that I did buy it from Amazon, because this movie is more than good. "Nell" is a really beautiful story that will have you swept away and have you immersed into the story in no time. "Nell" tells a story of being human, accepting people for what and whom they are, it is a story of existence, but most importantly it is a story of the heart. I think this was actually the first or second movie I watched with Liam Neeson (playing Jerome Lovell) in it, and to this day, I still think this is his best and most memorable performance. Jodie Foster (playing Nell) is nothing short of extraordinary in this movie. Her performance is breathtakingly beautiful and so heartfelt. You really get caught up in the story, and you want to know what happens next. And the way Nell's story is revealed to you and how she grows, it is like you are right there with her. The director really did an awesome job on this movie. And the way Jodie Foster portrays Nell when exposed to the world and the life we take for granted is really good acting and amazing performing. She really makes Nell come to life as a real person. "Nell" really goes straight into your heart and soul and the story will be with you for a long, long time. And you might want to keep some tissues at hand, because the story is really touching, and really helped so greatly along by Jodie Foster. I know that I will be watching this movie again at some point, even though the story doesn't hold surprising twists and such, it is one that can bear being watched more than once.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jodie's zenith
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Matt James (matjpi@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In "Nell", Jodie Foster gives, arguably, the best performance of her life. Clearly, she invested deeply in the role and her genuine strength and inner beauty shine so brightly into the character that Nell's beauty and loneliness become completely convincing. The story is more idealistic than realistic (as allegories are wont to be) which is worth remembering throughout - not least when it comes to the courtroom scene. I appreciated the sentiment of that scene whilst privately wishing it had been a closed hearing (full for a custody hearing?) Despite some ragged plot problems (that USGS wouldn't know about the Kellty homestead, that Nell is in really good health, that the lads who deliver her groceries never appear to discuss the 'strange hermit woman' with anyone, and so on) the story staggers to the finish line with an overly idyllic ending. Liam Neeson and Natasha Richardson support well locking horns convincingly over which was to become Nell's champion until they realised that Nell wasn't a trophy for an academic white paper. Nell becomes the adopted child, the glue that binds Neeson and Richardson's characters' emotional attachment. The film has some poetic cinematography and good location. But it is Jodie Foster's ability to play crushingly tender moments (the mirror, the lake, the effective memory) that - I'm happy to admit - still bring me to tears and is why I don't watch it a lot. It's a good film for couples who either have, or want to have, children. When you see it, I hope you'll understand why.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Nell" is a Jodie Foster Triumph
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dale Haufrect (dhaufrect@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The 1994 film, "Nell", is an acting triumph for Jodie Foster. The screenplay is by William Nicholson and it was adapted from the remarkable play by Mark Hadley. Foster grows up as a Yeti in a remote forest having been raised by her mother who suffered from a speech disorder or aphasia after running to the woods escaping the rapist who had attacked her. "Nell" then grows to adulthood with little to say in favor of men, and little speech to begin with anyway. Modern society attempts to "treat" her, but Liam Neesam is able to convince the doctors to allow her some space for growing room and a period of adjustment in order to make a more gradual adjustment to society. This film is compelling from the moment it begins and holds ones attention to the very end. It is deserving of much praise for handling a delicate subject with loving care and empathy that permeates the film. The cinematography is overwhelming and makes one jealous of Nell's environment. It is a very good rent now on DVD and well worth the time involved. Neesam's portrayal of a family physician turned naturalist is equally as compelling as is that of Foster making for a very satisfying picture.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An entertaining film, but it lacks seriousness.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Luis Angel Gonzalez
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What I didn't like about this film is that it went more on the cheesy side of things, while it could have been a more serious and mature one. I would have really liked this story told on a more serious way, but as in many films with good stories, they tend to be ruined when they are chosen to be for all audiences. I'm not saying that it is bad to do that though, some movies are great that way, but this one, in my opinion, didn't need that. Now onto the acting, I didn't like Jodie Foster,her acting seemed forced to me. Liam and Natasha did good, but nothing special in their acting. All in all, this is an entertaining film that many may like, but for me it didn't do much.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fascinating Story That Turns A Bit Too "Feel Good" In The End
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sddavis63 (revsdd@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The subject matter is fascinating. Nell (Jodie Foster) is a young woman raised by her mother in a setting completely cut off from civilization. She knows nothing of the outside world and has had little if any interaction with other people throughout her life, to the point at which she's developed her own language. Discovered by a grocery store delivery boy when her mother died, she comes under the care and tutelage of Drs. Lovell and Olson (Liam Neesom and Natasha Richardson) who have to decide whether or not she should be taken from her isolated environment and introduced to the "real" world. The dilemma is very powerful. What right does anyone else have to decide for Nell how her life should be lived, especially when she's clearly capable of living on her own in the environment to which she's accustomed? Why should she be subject to court orders about her fate or to living in psychiatric hospitals when there's obviously nothing really wrong with her except that she's living a life that no one in the outside world can understand? Those are tough questions. The movie does a great job of developing the relationship between Nell and Lovell (and then also Olson) in a sensitive way, as both begin to care for Nell and want to be protective of her and her rights to choose. Jodie Foster was - I thought - surprisingly good in this role. She usually plays a stronger type, and - at least as the movie opens - Nell was a very vulnerable figure. I didn't know if Foster would work in such a role, but she pulled it off perfectly. I would criticize this film only for the overly happy ending. Beginning with Nell appearing in court, this took on a too "syrupy" fell in my opinion; everything in the end was far too happy to be believable - in my opinion anyway. But aside from that I thought this was a very well done movie and a very interesting story. (7/10)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Superb
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Gregory Kauffman
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was fortunate enough to see the original production of the play, its emotional impact was as profound as any I have experienced in the theatre. It is perhaps for this reason that I was left somewhat disappointed with this film. However, I recently looked at it again and found that it is truly a top film. Jodie Foster is a towering talent as an actor and this performance was as good or better than any she's given. Neeson and Richardson were also at the top of their game. And the story of a woman shut off from the world, and the world's perceptions of her, merely because she can't communicate to it, is profound in its implications. I should not have been surprised about being disappointed the first time. I also saw a stage production in Los Angeles of IDIOGLOSSIA and found that disappointing after the original. But this film is a wonderful film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A criminally under appreciated and overlooked, divine film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dragoneyed363
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Nell is one of those movies that captivated me in so many ways for so many reasons. It is powerful, poetic and astonishingly beautiful with a beautiful message and an overwhelming use of angelic material that makes my heart ache from how wonderful the attributes that this film tries to get across to it's audience are. The story is a bit familiar, yet they add so much pizazz that it makes it seem fresh and brand new. It really does handle all the subject matter so well and it is exquisitely executed. The directing and writing were amazing, and I thought the performances in particular were absolutely brilliant. Jodie Foster gave such character, life and believability to Nell that I don't think anyone else could have gave any better; she is truly spectacular and deserved that Oscar nomination, maybe even the win. The characters are well done and really likable for the performances and screenplay behind them so you actually care for them, which is what more movies need to try and do; make you care for the characters. Like I said, Nell is dramatic to the point where it's painful, in a good way, sort of, to watch this woman's innocent, undisturbed life play out and unfold, and you wish for anything that you can just make everyone see her point of view and you really hope everything pulls through for this brilliant character in the end. Nell definitely makes us wonder who are the real monsters of this world. The cinematography is excellent also and I found myself completely caught up in how awe-inspiring everything in the movie is at times, whether it's the cinematography, characters or story, which the story is absolutely gripping and fascinating, if you have not caught that by now. Nell seems to be a really overlooked film because most people do not see it for it's full potential of delight and cleverness. It has a few fans, but I never hear any talk of how wonderful it is from anyone. I thought it was excellent, and an astonishing watch, no, adventure, that I would love to live out again sometime soon.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    First rate
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Neil Welch
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Having previously watched Nell one night on my own, I prevailed upon my wife and children (when they were coming up to their teens) to watch it with me one evening. As expected, they fell about laughing as soon as Jodie Foster started talking in "chickabee" language. And then, also as expected, they were utterly absorbed as this unusual and involving story unfolded. For, make no mistake, the quality of Jodie Foster's performance is such that Nell becomes absolutely real, and the audience is intrigued at discovering the explanation for her strange development, and dreadfully, dreadfully worried about what will happen to her. Others have written much better informed and more thoughtful reviews about this film - I will just say that I thought it was an excellent film, and so did my family.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Emotional, yet simple, modest, and beautiful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Deepak Janardhan
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Nell, the movie is titled after the protagonist Nell, a wild girl who has grown up isolated in the woods. The lack of exposure, death of her twin sister, and tales narrated by her paralyzed hermit mother leaves her with an unusual behavior, distorted speech, fear of strangers and the real world. The story revolves around Dr. Jerome Lovell who discovers Nell, panic-stricken at the death of her mother. He tries his best to communicate with her, protect her from strangers, and lead her to a normal life. With time, he grows fond of her. When Jerome explores different options to grab Nell's attention and persuades her to respond, the movie gets intriguing. Dr. Jerome discusses Nell's case with Paula Olsen, who believes and proposes that institutionalization is the way to treat and protect Nell. Paula appeals to the court for the custody of Nell. However, Jerome counters that Nell will turn out to be an object of scientific research like other patients in such medical facilities. The court grants 3 months to both the appellants to observe Nell closely and prove their stance. However, after observing Nell's independence, routines, and response to Jerome, Paula is convinced that the impersonal medical procedures will not cure Nell. Therefore, she begins to assist Jerome in his efforts to understand Nell's language and interact with her. Jerome soon turns out to be Nell's "Guardian Angel". But during their stay together, Jerome and Paula also develop intimacy. Towards the climax, I was convinced that Jerome and Nell will lead a happy life together. However, the movie takes a smooth turn when Nell is seen as the same person but in the company of Jerome's friends. She is shown free, happy, and playing in the woods with Ruthie, Jerome and Paula's daughter. I am impressed by the remarkable performances of Jodie Foster and Liam Neeson. Jodie Foster's effort to justify Nell's appearance and behavior as a wild girl deserves a clamorous applause, mainly for her voice modulation, expressions, movements, and gestures. Liam Neeson's acting as Dr Jerome is significant. Particularly, the dramatic narration of his childhood to evoke Nell's reaction is spectacular. The portrayal of innocence and purity is heart-warming, when Nell vents out her feelings to Jerome and embraces him. Jerome's natural display of disappointment and anger is powerful, at the pathetic sight of Nell in the hospital. The impulsive reaction on realizing that he would lose Nell is admirable. Last but not the least, the choice of the pristine location in the movie, around Nell's wood cabin, certainly adds to the effectiveness of the plot. Firstly, if you are a fan of either Jodie Foster or Liam Neeson, you must not miss this movie. In general, "Nell" is worth your money and time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What the light has been made for...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stormwings
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is 18 now, there are reviews from zero to 10, so here is mine: Albert Einstein said "Imagination is more important than knowledge. For knowledge is limited..." Nell" shows that kind of knowledge which is behind the veil of Isis" and that's because some aware people got together to make this visible. It seems that we still need stories" to reach this, but stories are only a start and never a conclusion. Thou are beautiful, O my love, as Tirzah" - this world is full of grace if you begin trying to say it to anyone, because all you say is to yourself. Who's Tirzah?" Jerry Lovell asked, swimming, laughing... It always makes me shine. Alicia Foster's face at the very end shows all we need to know - during about 16 seconds. The most beautiful thing a camera ever could have been taken for; the light was made for.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    So much more than beautiful...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Paul Magne Haakonsen
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I remember seeing this movie when I was younger, and had a fair memory of how the movie was and that it was a rather good movie. Now in 2012, I decided to get the movie and have another look at it. And I am actually quite happy that I did buy it from Amazon, because this movie is more than good. "Nell" is a really beautiful story that will have you swept away and have you immersed into the story in no time. "Nell" tells a story of being human, accepting people for what and whom they are, it is a story of existence, but most importantly it is a story of the heart. I think this was actually the first or second movie I watched with Liam Neeson (playing Jerome Lovell) in it, and to this day, I still think this is his best and most memorable performance. Jodie Foster (playing Nell) is nothing short of extraordinary in this movie. Her performance is breathtakingly beautiful and so heartfelt. You really get caught up in the story, and you want to know what happens next. And the way Nell's story is revealed to you and how she grows, it is like you are right there with her. The director really did an awesome job on this movie. And the way Jodie Foster portrays Nell when exposed to the world and the life we take for granted is really good acting and amazing performing. She really makes Nell come to life as a real person. "Nell" really goes straight into your heart and soul and the story will be with you for a long, long time. And you might want to keep some tissues at hand, because the story is really touching, and really helped so greatly along by Jodie Foster. I know that I will be watching this movie again at some point, even though the story doesn't hold surprising twists and such, it is one that can bear being watched more than once.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jodie's zenith
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Matt James (matjpi@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In "Nell", Jodie Foster gives, arguably, the best performance of her life. Clearly, she invested deeply in the role and her genuine strength and inner beauty shine so brightly into the character that Nell's beauty and loneliness become completely convincing. The story is more idealistic than realistic (as allegories are wont to be) which is worth remembering throughout - not least when it comes to the courtroom scene. I appreciated the sentiment of that scene whilst privately wishing it had been a closed hearing (full for a custody hearing?) Despite some ragged plot problems (that USGS wouldn't know about the Kellty homestead, that Nell is in really good health, that the lads who deliver her groceries never appear to discuss the 'strange hermit woman' with anyone, and so on) the story staggers to the finish line with an overly idyllic ending. Liam Neeson and Natasha Richardson support well locking horns convincingly over which was to become Nell's champion until they realised that Nell wasn't a trophy for an academic white paper. Nell becomes the adopted child, the glue that binds Neeson and Richardson's characters' emotional attachment. The film has some poetic cinematography and good location. But it is Jodie Foster's ability to play crushingly tender moments (the mirror, the lake, the effective memory) that - I'm happy to admit - still bring me to tears and is why I don't watch it a lot. It's a good film for couples who either have, or want to have, children. When you see it, I hope you'll understand why.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Nell" is a Jodie Foster Triumph
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dale Haufrect (dhaufrect@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The 1994 film, "Nell", is an acting triumph for Jodie Foster. The screenplay is by William Nicholson and it was adapted from the remarkable play by Mark Hadley. Foster grows up as a Yeti in a remote forest having been raised by her mother who suffered from a speech disorder or aphasia after running to the woods escaping the rapist who had attacked her. "Nell" then grows to adulthood with little to say in favor of men, and little speech to begin with anyway. Modern society attempts to "treat" her, but Liam Neesam is able to convince the doctors to allow her some space for growing room and a period of adjustment in order to make a more gradual adjustment to society. This film is compelling from the moment it begins and holds ones attention to the very end. It is deserving of much praise for handling a delicate subject with loving care and empathy that permeates the film. The cinematography is overwhelming and makes one jealous of Nell's environment. It is a very good rent now on DVD and well worth the time involved. Neesam's portrayal of a family physician turned naturalist is equally as compelling as is that of Foster making for a very satisfying picture.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An entertaining film, but it lacks seriousness.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Luis Angel Gonzalez
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What I didn't like about this film is that it went more on the cheesy side of things, while it could have been a more serious and mature one. I would have really liked this story told on a more serious way, but as in many films with good stories, they tend to be ruined when they are chosen to be for all audiences. I'm not saying that it is bad to do that though, some movies are great that way, but this one, in my opinion, didn't need that. Now onto the acting, I didn't like Jodie Foster,her acting seemed forced to me. Liam and Natasha did good, but nothing special in their acting. All in all, this is an entertaining film that many may like, but for me it didn't do much.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fascinating Story That Turns A Bit Too "Feel Good" In The End
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sddavis63 (revsdd@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The subject matter is fascinating. Nell (Jodie Foster) is a young woman raised by her mother in a setting completely cut off from civilization. She knows nothing of the outside world and has had little if any interaction with other people throughout her life, to the point at which she's developed her own language. Discovered by a grocery store delivery boy when her mother died, she comes under the care and tutelage of Drs. Lovell and Olson (Liam Neesom and Natasha Richardson) who have to decide whether or not she should be taken from her isolated environment and introduced to the "real" world. The dilemma is very powerful. What right does anyone else have to decide for Nell how her life should be lived, especially when she's clearly capable of living on her own in the environment to which she's accustomed? Why should she be subject to court orders about her fate or to living in psychiatric hospitals when there's obviously nothing really wrong with her except that she's living a life that no one in the outside world can understand? Those are tough questions. The movie does a great job of developing the relationship between Nell and Lovell (and then also Olson) in a sensitive way, as both begin to care for Nell and want to be protective of her and her rights to choose. Jodie Foster was - I thought - surprisingly good in this role. She usually plays a stronger type, and - at least as the movie opens - Nell was a very vulnerable figure. I didn't know if Foster would work in such a role, but she pulled it off perfectly. I would criticize this film only for the overly happy ending. Beginning with Nell appearing in court, this took on a too "syrupy" fell in my opinion; everything in the end was far too happy to be believable - in my opinion anyway. But aside from that I thought this was a very well done movie and a very interesting story. (7/10)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Superb
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Gregory Kauffman
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was fortunate enough to see the original production of the play, its emotional impact was as profound as any I have experienced in the theatre. It is perhaps for this reason that I was left somewhat disappointed with this film. However, I recently looked at it again and found that it is truly a top film. Jodie Foster is a towering talent as an actor and this performance was as good or better than any she's given. Neeson and Richardson were also at the top of their game. And the story of a woman shut off from the world, and the world's perceptions of her, merely because she can't communicate to it, is profound in its implications. I should not have been surprised about being disappointed the first time. I also saw a stage production in Los Angeles of IDIOGLOSSIA and found that disappointing after the original. But this film is a wonderful film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A criminally under appreciated and overlooked, divine film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dragoneyed363
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Nell is one of those movies that captivated me in so many ways for so many reasons. It is powerful, poetic and astonishingly beautiful with a beautiful message and an overwhelming use of angelic material that makes my heart ache from how wonderful the attributes that this film tries to get across to it's audience are. The story is a bit familiar, yet they add so much pizazz that it makes it seem fresh and brand new. It really does handle all the subject matter so well and it is exquisitely executed. The directing and writing were amazing, and I thought the performances in particular were absolutely brilliant. Jodie Foster gave such character, life and believability to Nell that I don't think anyone else could have gave any better; she is truly spectacular and deserved that Oscar nomination, maybe even the win. The characters are well done and really likable for the performances and screenplay behind them so you actually care for them, which is what more movies need to try and do; make you care for the characters. Like I said, Nell is dramatic to the point where it's painful, in a good way, sort of, to watch this woman's innocent, undisturbed life play out and unfold, and you wish for anything that you can just make everyone see her point of view and you really hope everything pulls through for this brilliant character in the end. Nell definitely makes us wonder who are the real monsters of this world. The cinematography is excellent also and I found myself completely caught up in how awe-inspiring everything in the movie is at times, whether it's the cinematography, characters or story, which the story is absolutely gripping and fascinating, if you have not caught that by now. Nell seems to be a really overlooked film because most people do not see it for it's full potential of delight and cleverness. It has a few fans, but I never hear any talk of how wonderful it is from anyone. I thought it was excellent, and an astonishing watch, no, adventure, that I would love to live out again sometime soon.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    First rate
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Neil Welch
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Having previously watched Nell one night on my own, I prevailed upon my wife and children (when they were coming up to their teens) to watch it with me one evening. As expected, they fell about laughing as soon as Jodie Foster started talking in "chickabee" language. And then, also as expected, they were utterly absorbed as this unusual and involving story unfolded. For, make no mistake, the quality of Jodie Foster's performance is such that Nell becomes absolutely real, and the audience is intrigued at discovering the explanation for her strange development, and dreadfully, dreadfully worried about what will happen to her. Others have written much better informed and more thoughtful reviews about this film - I will just say that I thought it was an excellent film, and so did my family.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Emotional, yet simple, modest, and beautiful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Deepak Janardhan
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Nell, the movie is titled after the protagonist Nell, a wild girl who has grown up isolated in the woods. The lack of exposure, death of her twin sister, and tales narrated by her paralyzed hermit mother leaves her with an unusual behavior, distorted speech, fear of strangers and the real world. The story revolves around Dr. Jerome Lovell who discovers Nell, panic-stricken at the death of her mother. He tries his best to communicate with her, protect her from strangers, and lead her to a normal life. With time, he grows fond of her. When Jerome explores different options to grab Nell's attention and persuades her to respond, the movie gets intriguing. Dr. Jerome discusses Nell's case with Paula Olsen, who believes and proposes that institutionalization is the way to treat and protect Nell. Paula appeals to the court for the custody of Nell. However, Jerome counters that Nell will turn out to be an object of scientific research like other patients in such medical facilities. The court grants 3 months to both the appellants to observe Nell closely and prove their stance. However, after observing Nell's independence, routines, and response to Jerome, Paula is convinced that the impersonal medical procedures will not cure Nell. Therefore, she begins to assist Jerome in his efforts to understand Nell's language and interact with her. Jerome soon turns out to be Nell's "Guardian Angel". But during their stay together, Jerome and Paula also develop intimacy. Towards the climax, I was convinced that Jerome and Nell will lead a happy life together. However, the movie takes a smooth turn when Nell is seen as the same person but in the company of Jerome's friends. She is shown free, happy, and playing in the woods with Ruthie, Jerome and Paula's daughter. I am impressed by the remarkable performances of Jodie Foster and Liam Neeson. Jodie Foster's effort to justify Nell's appearance and behavior as a wild girl deserves a clamorous applause, mainly for her voice modulation, expressions, movements, and gestures. Liam Neeson's acting as Dr Jerome is significant. Particularly, the dramatic narration of his childhood to evoke Nell's reaction is spectacular. The portrayal of innocence and purity is heart-warming, when Nell vents out her feelings to Jerome and embraces him. Jerome's natural display of disappointment and anger is powerful, at the pathetic sight of Nell in the hospital. The impulsive reaction on realizing that he would lose Nell is admirable. Last but not the least, the choice of the pristine location in the movie, around Nell's wood cabin, certainly adds to the effectiveness of the plot. Firstly, if you are a fan of either Jodie Foster or Liam Neeson, you must not miss this movie. In general, "Nell" is worth your money and time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What the light has been made for...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stormwings
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is 18 now, there are reviews from zero to 10, so here is mine: Albert Einstein said "Imagination is more important than knowledge. For knowledge is limited..." Nell" shows that kind of knowledge which is behind the veil of Isis" and that's because some aware people got together to make this visible. It seems that we still need stories" to reach this, but stories are only a start and never a conclusion. Thou are beautiful, O my love, as Tirzah" - this world is full of grace if you begin trying to say it to anyone, because all you say is to yourself. Who's Tirzah?" Jerry Lovell asked, swimming, laughing... It always makes me shine. Alicia Foster's face at the very end shows all we need to know - during about 16 seconds. The most beautiful thing a camera ever could have been taken for; the light was made for.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    So much more than beautiful...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Paul Magne Haakonsen
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I remember seeing this movie when I was younger, and had a fair memory of how the movie was and that it was a rather good movie. Now in 2012, I decided to get the movie and have another look at it. And I am actually quite happy that I did buy it from Amazon, because this movie is more than good. "Nell" is a really beautiful story that will have you swept away and have you immersed into the story in no time. "Nell" tells a story of being human, accepting people for what and whom they are, it is a story of existence, but most importantly it is a story of the heart. I think this was actually the first or second movie I watched with Liam Neeson (playing Jerome Lovell) in it, and to this day, I still think this is his best and most memorable performance. Jodie Foster (playing Nell) is nothing short of extraordinary in this movie. Her performance is breathtakingly beautiful and so heartfelt. You really get caught up in the story, and you want to know what happens next. And the way Nell's story is revealed to you and how she grows, it is like you are right there with her. The director really did an awesome job on this movie. And the way Jodie Foster portrays Nell when exposed to the world and the life we take for granted is really good acting and amazing performing. She really makes Nell come to life as a real person. "Nell" really goes straight into your heart and soul and the story will be with you for a long, long time. And you might want to keep some tissues at hand, because the story is really touching, and really helped so greatly along by Jodie Foster. I know that I will be watching this movie again at some point, even though the story doesn't hold surprising twists and such, it is one that can bear being watched more than once.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jodie's zenith
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Matt James (matjpi@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In "Nell", Jodie Foster gives, arguably, the best performance of her life. Clearly, she invested deeply in the role and her genuine strength and inner beauty shine so brightly into the character that Nell's beauty and loneliness become completely convincing. The story is more idealistic than realistic (as allegories are wont to be) which is worth remembering throughout - not least when it comes to the courtroom scene. I appreciated the sentiment of that scene whilst privately wishing it had been a closed hearing (full for a custody hearing?) Despite some ragged plot problems (that USGS wouldn't know about the Kellty homestead, that Nell is in really good health, that the lads who deliver her groceries never appear to discuss the 'strange hermit woman' with anyone, and so on) the story staggers to the finish line with an overly idyllic ending. Liam Neeson and Natasha Richardson support well locking horns convincingly over which was to become Nell's champion until they realised that Nell wasn't a trophy for an academic white paper. Nell becomes the adopted child, the glue that binds Neeson and Richardson's characters' emotional attachment. The film has some poetic cinematography and good location. But it is Jodie Foster's ability to play crushingly tender moments (the mirror, the lake, the effective memory) that - I'm happy to admit - still bring me to tears and is why I don't watch it a lot. It's a good film for couples who either have, or want to have, children. When you see it, I hope you'll understand why.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Nell" is a Jodie Foster Triumph
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dale Haufrect (dhaufrect@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The 1994 film, "Nell", is an acting triumph for Jodie Foster. The screenplay is by William Nicholson and it was adapted from the remarkable play by Mark Hadley. Foster grows up as a Yeti in a remote forest having been raised by her mother who suffered from a speech disorder or aphasia after running to the woods escaping the rapist who had attacked her. "Nell" then grows to adulthood with little to say in favor of men, and little speech to begin with anyway. Modern society attempts to "treat" her, but Liam Neesam is able to convince the doctors to allow her some space for growing room and a period of adjustment in order to make a more gradual adjustment to society. This film is compelling from the moment it begins and holds ones attention to the very end. It is deserving of much praise for handling a delicate subject with loving care and empathy that permeates the film. The cinematography is overwhelming and makes one jealous of Nell's environment. It is a very good rent now on DVD and well worth the time involved. Neesam's portrayal of a family physician turned naturalist is equally as compelling as is that of Foster making for a very satisfying picture.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An entertaining film, but it lacks seriousness.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Luis Angel Gonzalez
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What I didn't like about this film is that it went more on the cheesy side of things, while it could have been a more serious and mature one. I would have really liked this story told on a more serious way, but as in many films with good stories, they tend to be ruined when they are chosen to be for all audiences. I'm not saying that it is bad to do that though, some movies are great that way, but this one, in my opinion, didn't need that. Now onto the acting, I didn't like Jodie Foster,her acting seemed forced to me. Liam and Natasha did good, but nothing special in their acting. All in all, this is an entertaining film that many may like, but for me it didn't do much.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fascinating Story That Turns A Bit Too "Feel Good" In The End
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sddavis63 (revsdd@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The subject matter is fascinating. Nell (Jodie Foster) is a young woman raised by her mother in a setting completely cut off from civilization. She knows nothing of the outside world and has had little if any interaction with other people throughout her life, to the point at which she's developed her own language. Discovered by a grocery store delivery boy when her mother died, she comes under the care and tutelage of Drs. Lovell and Olson (Liam Neesom and Natasha Richardson) who have to decide whether or not she should be taken from her isolated environment and introduced to the "real" world. The dilemma is very powerful. What right does anyone else have to decide for Nell how her life should be lived, especially when she's clearly capable of living on her own in the environment to which she's accustomed? Why should she be subject to court orders about her fate or to living in psychiatric hospitals when there's obviously nothing really wrong with her except that she's living a life that no one in the outside world can understand? Those are tough questions. The movie does a great job of developing the relationship between Nell and Lovell (and then also Olson) in a sensitive way, as both begin to care for Nell and want to be protective of her and her rights to choose. Jodie Foster was - I thought - surprisingly good in this role. She usually plays a stronger type, and - at least as the movie opens - Nell was a very vulnerable figure. I didn't know if Foster would work in such a role, but she pulled it off perfectly. I would criticize this film only for the overly happy ending. Beginning with Nell appearing in court, this took on a too "syrupy" fell in my opinion; everything in the end was far too happy to be believable - in my opinion anyway. But aside from that I thought this was a very well done movie and a very interesting story. (7/10)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Superb
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Gregory Kauffman
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was fortunate enough to see the original production of the play, its emotional impact was as profound as any I have experienced in the theatre. It is perhaps for this reason that I was left somewhat disappointed with this film. However, I recently looked at it again and found that it is truly a top film. Jodie Foster is a towering talent as an actor and this performance was as good or better than any she's given. Neeson and Richardson were also at the top of their game. And the story of a woman shut off from the world, and the world's perceptions of her, merely because she can't communicate to it, is profound in its implications. I should not have been surprised about being disappointed the first time. I also saw a stage production in Los Angeles of IDIOGLOSSIA and found that disappointing after the original. But this film is a wonderful film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A criminally under appreciated and overlooked, divine film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dragoneyed363
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Nell is one of those movies that captivated me in so many ways for so many reasons. It is powerful, poetic and astonishingly beautiful with a beautiful message and an overwhelming use of angelic material that makes my heart ache from how wonderful the attributes that this film tries to get across to it's audience are. The story is a bit familiar, yet they add so much pizazz that it makes it seem fresh and brand new. It really does handle all the subject matter so well and it is exquisitely executed. The directing and writing were amazing, and I thought the performances in particular were absolutely brilliant. Jodie Foster gave such character, life and believability to Nell that I don't think anyone else could have gave any better; she is truly spectacular and deserved that Oscar nomination, maybe even the win. The characters are well done and really likable for the performances and screenplay behind them so you actually care for them, which is what more movies need to try and do; make you care for the characters. Like I said, Nell is dramatic to the point where it's painful, in a good way, sort of, to watch this woman's innocent, undisturbed life play out and unfold, and you wish for anything that you can just make everyone see her point of view and you really hope everything pulls through for this brilliant character in the end. Nell definitely makes us wonder who are the real monsters of this world. The cinematography is excellent also and I found myself completely caught up in how awe-inspiring everything in the movie is at times, whether it's the cinematography, characters or story, which the story is absolutely gripping and fascinating, if you have not caught that by now. Nell seems to be a really overlooked film because most people do not see it for it's full potential of delight and cleverness. It has a few fans, but I never hear any talk of how wonderful it is from anyone. I thought it was excellent, and an astonishing watch, no, adventure, that I would love to live out again sometime soon.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    First rate
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Neil Welch
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Having previously watched Nell one night on my own, I prevailed upon my wife and children (when they were coming up to their teens) to watch it with me one evening. As expected, they fell about laughing as soon as Jodie Foster started talking in "chickabee" language. And then, also as expected, they were utterly absorbed as this unusual and involving story unfolded. For, make no mistake, the quality of Jodie Foster's performance is such that Nell becomes absolutely real, and the audience is intrigued at discovering the explanation for her strange development, and dreadfully, dreadfully worried about what will happen to her. Others have written much better informed and more thoughtful reviews about this film - I will just say that I thought it was an excellent film, and so did my family.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Emotional, yet simple, modest, and beautiful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Deepak Janardhan
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Nell, the movie is titled after the protagonist Nell, a wild girl who has grown up isolated in the woods. The lack of exposure, death of her twin sister, and tales narrated by her paralyzed hermit mother leaves her with an unusual behavior, distorted speech, fear of strangers and the real world. The story revolves around Dr. Jerome Lovell who discovers Nell, panic-stricken at the death of her mother. He tries his best to communicate with her, protect her from strangers, and lead her to a normal life. With time, he grows fond of her. When Jerome explores different options to grab Nell's attention and persuades her to respond, the movie gets intriguing. Dr. Jerome discusses Nell's case with Paula Olsen, who believes and proposes that institutionalization is the way to treat and protect Nell. Paula appeals to the court for the custody of Nell. However, Jerome counters that Nell will turn out to be an object of scientific research like other patients in such medical facilities. The court grants 3 months to both the appellants to observe Nell closely and prove their stance. However, after observing Nell's independence, routines, and response to Jerome, Paula is convinced that the impersonal medical procedures will not cure Nell. Therefore, she begins to assist Jerome in his efforts to understand Nell's language and interact with her. Jerome soon turns out to be Nell's "Guardian Angel". But during their stay together, Jerome and Paula also develop intimacy. Towards the climax, I was convinced that Jerome and Nell will lead a happy life together. However, the movie takes a smooth turn when Nell is seen as the same person but in the company of Jerome's friends. She is shown free, happy, and playing in the woods with Ruthie, Jerome and Paula's daughter. I am impressed by the remarkable performances of Jodie Foster and Liam Neeson. Jodie Foster's effort to justify Nell's appearance and behavior as a wild girl deserves a clamorous applause, mainly for her voice modulation, expressions, movements, and gestures. Liam Neeson's acting as Dr Jerome is significant. Particularly, the dramatic narration of his childhood to evoke Nell's reaction is spectacular. The portrayal of innocence and purity is heart-warming, when Nell vents out her feelings to Jerome and embraces him. Jerome's natural display of disappointment and anger is powerful, at the pathetic sight of Nell in the hospital. The impulsive reaction on realizing that he would lose Nell is admirable. Last but not the least, the choice of the pristine location in the movie, around Nell's wood cabin, certainly adds to the effectiveness of the plot. Firstly, if you are a fan of either Jodie Foster or Liam Neeson, you must not miss this movie. In general, "Nell" is worth your money and time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What the light has been made for...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stormwings
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is 18 now, there are reviews from zero to 10, so here is mine: Albert Einstein said "Imagination is more important than knowledge. For knowledge is limited..." Nell" shows that kind of knowledge which is behind the veil of Isis" and that's because some aware people got together to make this visible. It seems that we still need stories" to reach this, but stories are only a start and never a conclusion. Thou are beautiful, O my love, as Tirzah" - this world is full of grace if you begin trying to say it to anyone, because all you say is to yourself. Who's Tirzah?" Jerry Lovell asked, swimming, laughing... It always makes me shine. Alicia Foster's face at the very end shows all we need to know - during about 16 seconds. The most beautiful thing a camera ever could have been taken for; the light was made for.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    So much more than beautiful...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Paul Magne Haakonsen
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I remember seeing this movie when I was younger, and had a fair memory of how the movie was and that it was a rather good movie. Now in 2012, I decided to get the movie and have another look at it. And I am actually quite happy that I did buy it from Amazon, because this movie is more than good. "Nell" is a really beautiful story that will have you swept away and have you immersed into the story in no time. "Nell" tells a story of being human, accepting people for what and whom they are, it is a story of existence, but most importantly it is a story of the heart. I think this was actually the first or second movie I watched with Liam Neeson (playing Jerome Lovell) in it, and to this day, I still think this is his best and most memorable performance. Jodie Foster (playing Nell) is nothing short of extraordinary in this movie. Her performance is breathtakingly beautiful and so heartfelt. You really get caught up in the story, and you want to know what happens next. And the way Nell's story is revealed to you and how she grows, it is like you are right there with her. The director really did an awesome job on this movie. And the way Jodie Foster portrays Nell when exposed to the world and the life we take for granted is really good acting and amazing performing. She really makes Nell come to life as a real person. "Nell" really goes straight into your heart and soul and the story will be with you for a long, long time. And you might want to keep some tissues at hand, because the story is really touching, and really helped so greatly along by Jodie Foster. I know that I will be watching this movie again at some point, even though the story doesn't hold surprising twists and such, it is one that can bear being watched more than once.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jodie's zenith
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Matt James (matjpi@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In "Nell", Jodie Foster gives, arguably, the best performance of her life. Clearly, she invested deeply in the role and her genuine strength and inner beauty shine so brightly into the character that Nell's beauty and loneliness become completely convincing. The story is more idealistic than realistic (as allegories are wont to be) which is worth remembering throughout - not least when it comes to the courtroom scene. I appreciated the sentiment of that scene whilst privately wishing it had been a closed hearing (full for a custody hearing?) Despite some ragged plot problems (that USGS wouldn't know about the Kellty homestead, that Nell is in really good health, that the lads who deliver her groceries never appear to discuss the 'strange hermit woman' with anyone, and so on) the story staggers to the finish line with an overly idyllic ending. Liam Neeson and Natasha Richardson support well locking horns convincingly over which was to become Nell's champion until they realised that Nell wasn't a trophy for an academic white paper. Nell becomes the adopted child, the glue that binds Neeson and Richardson's characters' emotional attachment. The film has some poetic cinematography and good location. But it is Jodie Foster's ability to play crushingly tender moments (the mirror, the lake, the effective memory) that - I'm happy to admit - still bring me to tears and is why I don't watch it a lot. It's a good film for couples who either have, or want to have, children. When you see it, I hope you'll understand why.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Nell" is a Jodie Foster Triumph
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dale Haufrect (dhaufrect@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The 1994 film, "Nell", is an acting triumph for Jodie Foster. The screenplay is by William Nicholson and it was adapted from the remarkable play by Mark Hadley. Foster grows up as a Yeti in a remote forest having been raised by her mother who suffered from a speech disorder or aphasia after running to the woods escaping the rapist who had attacked her. "Nell" then grows to adulthood with little to say in favor of men, and little speech to begin with anyway. Modern society attempts to "treat" her, but Liam Neesam is able to convince the doctors to allow her some space for growing room and a period of adjustment in order to make a more gradual adjustment to society. This film is compelling from the moment it begins and holds ones attention to the very end. It is deserving of much praise for handling a delicate subject with loving care and empathy that permeates the film. The cinematography is overwhelming and makes one jealous of Nell's environment. It is a very good rent now on DVD and well worth the time involved. Neesam's portrayal of a family physician turned naturalist is equally as compelling as is that of Foster making for a very satisfying picture.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An entertaining film, but it lacks seriousness.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Luis Angel Gonzalez
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What I didn't like about this film is that it went more on the cheesy side of things, while it could have been a more serious and mature one. I would have really liked this story told on a more serious way, but as in many films with good stories, they tend to be ruined when they are chosen to be for all audiences. I'm not saying that it is bad to do that though, some movies are great that way, but this one, in my opinion, didn't need that. Now onto the acting, I didn't like Jodie Foster,her acting seemed forced to me. Liam and Natasha did good, but nothing special in their acting. All in all, this is an entertaining film that many may like, but for me it didn't do much.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fascinating Story That Turns A Bit Too "Feel Good" In The End
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sddavis63 (revsdd@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The subject matter is fascinating. Nell (Jodie Foster) is a young woman raised by her mother in a setting completely cut off from civilization. She knows nothing of the outside world and has had little if any interaction with other people throughout her life, to the point at which she's developed her own language. Discovered by a grocery store delivery boy when her mother died, she comes under the care and tutelage of Drs. Lovell and Olson (Liam Neesom and Natasha Richardson) who have to decide whether or not she should be taken from her isolated environment and introduced to the "real" world. The dilemma is very powerful. What right does anyone else have to decide for Nell how her life should be lived, especially when she's clearly capable of living on her own in the environment to which she's accustomed? Why should she be subject to court orders about her fate or to living in psychiatric hospitals when there's obviously nothing really wrong with her except that she's living a life that no one in the outside world can understand? Those are tough questions. The movie does a great job of developing the relationship between Nell and Lovell (and then also Olson) in a sensitive way, as both begin to care for Nell and want to be protective of her and her rights to choose. Jodie Foster was - I thought - surprisingly good in this role. She usually plays a stronger type, and - at least as the movie opens - Nell was a very vulnerable figure. I didn't know if Foster would work in such a role, but she pulled it off perfectly. I would criticize this film only for the overly happy ending. Beginning with Nell appearing in court, this took on a too "syrupy" fell in my opinion; everything in the end was far too happy to be believable - in my opinion anyway. But aside from that I thought this was a very well done movie and a very interesting story. (7/10)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Superb
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Gregory Kauffman
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was fortunate enough to see the original production of the play, its emotional impact was as profound as any I have experienced in the theatre. It is perhaps for this reason that I was left somewhat disappointed with this film. However, I recently looked at it again and found that it is truly a top film. Jodie Foster is a towering talent as an actor and this performance was as good or better than any she's given. Neeson and Richardson were also at the top of their game. And the story of a woman shut off from the world, and the world's perceptions of her, merely because she can't communicate to it, is profound in its implications. I should not have been surprised about being disappointed the first time. I also saw a stage production in Los Angeles of IDIOGLOSSIA and found that disappointing after the original. But this film is a wonderful film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A criminally under appreciated and overlooked, divine film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dragoneyed363
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Nell is one of those movies that captivated me in so many ways for so many reasons. It is powerful, poetic and astonishingly beautiful with a beautiful message and an overwhelming use of angelic material that makes my heart ache from how wonderful the attributes that this film tries to get across to it's audience are. The story is a bit familiar, yet they add so much pizazz that it makes it seem fresh and brand new. It really does handle all the subject matter so well and it is exquisitely executed. The directing and writing were amazing, and I thought the performances in particular were absolutely brilliant. Jodie Foster gave such character, life and believability to Nell that I don't think anyone else could have gave any better; she is truly spectacular and deserved that Oscar nomination, maybe even the win. The characters are well done and really likable for the performances and screenplay behind them so you actually care for them, which is what more movies need to try and do; make you care for the characters. Like I said, Nell is dramatic to the point where it's painful, in a good way, sort of, to watch this woman's innocent, undisturbed life play out and unfold, and you wish for anything that you can just make everyone see her point of view and you really hope everything pulls through for this brilliant character in the end. Nell definitely makes us wonder who are the real monsters of this world. The cinematography is excellent also and I found myself completely caught up in how awe-inspiring everything in the movie is at times, whether it's the cinematography, characters or story, which the story is absolutely gripping and fascinating, if you have not caught that by now. Nell seems to be a really overlooked film because most people do not see it for it's full potential of delight and cleverness. It has a few fans, but I never hear any talk of how wonderful it is from anyone. I thought it was excellent, and an astonishing watch, no, adventure, that I would love to live out again sometime soon.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    First rate
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Neil Welch
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Having previously watched Nell one night on my own, I prevailed upon my wife and children (when they were coming up to their teens) to watch it with me one evening. As expected, they fell about laughing as soon as Jodie Foster started talking in "chickabee" language. And then, also as expected, they were utterly absorbed as this unusual and involving story unfolded. For, make no mistake, the quality of Jodie Foster's performance is such that Nell becomes absolutely real, and the audience is intrigued at discovering the explanation for her strange development, and dreadfully, dreadfully worried about what will happen to her. Others have written much better informed and more thoughtful reviews about this film - I will just say that I thought it was an excellent film, and so did my family.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Emotional, yet simple, modest, and beautiful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Deepak Janardhan
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Nell, the movie is titled after the protagonist Nell, a wild girl who has grown up isolated in the woods. The lack of exposure, death of her twin sister, and tales narrated by her paralyzed hermit mother leaves her with an unusual behavior, distorted speech, fear of strangers and the real world. The story revolves around Dr. Jerome Lovell who discovers Nell, panic-stricken at the death of her mother. He tries his best to communicate with her, protect her from strangers, and lead her to a normal life. With time, he grows fond of her. When Jerome explores different options to grab Nell's attention and persuades her to respond, the movie gets intriguing. Dr. Jerome discusses Nell's case with Paula Olsen, who believes and proposes that institutionalization is the way to treat and protect Nell. Paula appeals to the court for the custody of Nell. However, Jerome counters that Nell will turn out to be an object of scientific research like other patients in such medical facilities. The court grants 3 months to both the appellants to observe Nell closely and prove their stance. However, after observing Nell's independence, routines, and response to Jerome, Paula is convinced that the impersonal medical procedures will not cure Nell. Therefore, she begins to assist Jerome in his efforts to understand Nell's language and interact with her. Jerome soon turns out to be Nell's "Guardian Angel". But during their stay together, Jerome and Paula also develop intimacy. Towards the climax, I was convinced that Jerome and Nell will lead a happy life together. However, the movie takes a smooth turn when Nell is seen as the same person but in the company of Jerome's friends. She is shown free, happy, and playing in the woods with Ruthie, Jerome and Paula's daughter. I am impressed by the remarkable performances of Jodie Foster and Liam Neeson. Jodie Foster's effort to justify Nell's appearance and behavior as a wild girl deserves a clamorous applause, mainly for her voice modulation, expressions, movements, and gestures. Liam Neeson's acting as Dr Jerome is significant. Particularly, the dramatic narration of his childhood to evoke Nell's reaction is spectacular. The portrayal of innocence and purity is heart-warming, when Nell vents out her feelings to Jerome and embraces him. Jerome's natural display of disappointment and anger is powerful, at the pathetic sight of Nell in the hospital. The impulsive reaction on realizing that he would lose Nell is admirable. Last but not the least, the choice of the pristine location in the movie, around Nell's wood cabin, certainly adds to the effectiveness of the plot. Firstly, if you are a fan of either Jodie Foster or Liam Neeson, you must not miss this movie. In general, "Nell" is worth your money and time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What the light has been made for...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stormwings
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is 18 now, there are reviews from zero to 10, so here is mine: Albert Einstein said "Imagination is more important than knowledge. For knowledge is limited..." Nell" shows that kind of knowledge which is behind the veil of Isis" and that's because some aware people got together to make this visible. It seems that we still need stories" to reach this, but stories are only a start and never a conclusion. Thou are beautiful, O my love, as Tirzah" - this world is full of grace if you begin trying to say it to anyone, because all you say is to yourself. Who's Tirzah?" Jerry Lovell asked, swimming, laughing... It always makes me shine. Alicia Foster's face at the very end shows all we need to know - during about 16 seconds. The most beautiful thing a camera ever could have been taken for; the light was made for.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    So much more than beautiful...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Paul Magne Haakonsen
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I remember seeing this movie when I was younger, and had a fair memory of how the movie was and that it was a rather good movie. Now in 2012, I decided to get the movie and have another look at it. And I am actually quite happy that I did buy it from Amazon, because this movie is more than good. "Nell" is a really beautiful story that will have you swept away and have you immersed into the story in no time. "Nell" tells a story of being human, accepting people for what and whom they are, it is a story of existence, but most importantly it is a story of the heart. I think this was actually the first or second movie I watched with Liam Neeson (playing Jerome Lovell) in it, and to this day, I still think this is his best and most memorable performance. Jodie Foster (playing Nell) is nothing short of extraordinary in this movie. Her performance is breathtakingly beautiful and so heartfelt. You really get caught up in the story, and you want to know what happens next. And the way Nell's story is revealed to you and how she grows, it is like you are right there with her. The director really did an awesome job on this movie. And the way Jodie Foster portrays Nell when exposed to the world and the life we take for granted is really good acting and amazing performing. She really makes Nell come to life as a real person. "Nell" really goes straight into your heart and soul and the story will be with you for a long, long time. And you might want to keep some tissues at hand, because the story is really touching, and really helped so greatly along by Jodie Foster. I know that I will be watching this movie again at some point, even though the story doesn't hold surprising twists and such, it is one that can bear being watched more than once.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jodie's zenith
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Matt James (matjpi@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In "Nell", Jodie Foster gives, arguably, the best performance of her life. Clearly, she invested deeply in the role and her genuine strength and inner beauty shine so brightly into the character that Nell's beauty and loneliness become completely convincing. The story is more idealistic than realistic (as allegories are wont to be) which is worth remembering throughout - not least when it comes to the courtroom scene. I appreciated the sentiment of that scene whilst privately wishing it had been a closed hearing (full for a custody hearing?) Despite some ragged plot problems (that USGS wouldn't know about the Kellty homestead, that Nell is in really good health, that the lads who deliver her groceries never appear to discuss the 'strange hermit woman' with anyone, and so on) the story staggers to the finish line with an overly idyllic ending. Liam Neeson and Natasha Richardson support well locking horns convincingly over which was to become Nell's champion until they realised that Nell wasn't a trophy for an academic white paper. Nell becomes the adopted child, the glue that binds Neeson and Richardson's characters' emotional attachment. The film has some poetic cinematography and good location. But it is Jodie Foster's ability to play crushingly tender moments (the mirror, the lake, the effective memory) that - I'm happy to admit - still bring me to tears and is why I don't watch it a lot. It's a good film for couples who either have, or want to have, children. When you see it, I hope you'll understand why.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Nell" is a Jodie Foster Triumph
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dale Haufrect (dhaufrect@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The 1994 film, "Nell", is an acting triumph for Jodie Foster. The screenplay is by William Nicholson and it was adapted from the remarkable play by Mark Hadley. Foster grows up as a Yeti in a remote forest having been raised by her mother who suffered from a speech disorder or aphasia after running to the woods escaping the rapist who had attacked her. "Nell" then grows to adulthood with little to say in favor of men, and little speech to begin with anyway. Modern society attempts to "treat" her, but Liam Neesam is able to convince the doctors to allow her some space for growing room and a period of adjustment in order to make a more gradual adjustment to society. This film is compelling from the moment it begins and holds ones attention to the very end. It is deserving of much praise for handling a delicate subject with loving care and empathy that permeates the film. The cinematography is overwhelming and makes one jealous of Nell's environment. It is a very good rent now on DVD and well worth the time involved. Neesam's portrayal of a family physician turned naturalist is equally as compelling as is that of Foster making for a very satisfying picture.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An entertaining film, but it lacks seriousness.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Luis Angel Gonzalez
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What I didn't like about this film is that it went more on the cheesy side of things, while it could have been a more serious and mature one. I would have really liked this story told on a more serious way, but as in many films with good stories, they tend to be ruined when they are chosen to be for all audiences. I'm not saying that it is bad to do that though, some movies are great that way, but this one, in my opinion, didn't need that. Now onto the acting, I didn't like Jodie Foster,her acting seemed forced to me. Liam and Natasha did good, but nothing special in their acting. All in all, this is an entertaining film that many may like, but for me it didn't do much.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fascinating Story That Turns A Bit Too "Feel Good" In The End
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sddavis63 (revsdd@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The subject matter is fascinating. Nell (Jodie Foster) is a young woman raised by her mother in a setting completely cut off from civilization. She knows nothing of the outside world and has had little if any interaction with other people throughout her life, to the point at which she's developed her own language. Discovered by a grocery store delivery boy when her mother died, she comes under the care and tutelage of Drs. Lovell and Olson (Liam Neesom and Natasha Richardson) who have to decide whether or not she should be taken from her isolated environment and introduced to the "real" world. The dilemma is very powerful. What right does anyone else have to decide for Nell how her life should be lived, especially when she's clearly capable of living on her own in the environment to which she's accustomed? Why should she be subject to court orders about her fate or to living in psychiatric hospitals when there's obviously nothing really wrong with her except that she's living a life that no one in the outside world can understand? Those are tough questions. The movie does a great job of developing the relationship between Nell and Lovell (and then also Olson) in a sensitive way, as both begin to care for Nell and want to be protective of her and her rights to choose. Jodie Foster was - I thought - surprisingly good in this role. She usually plays a stronger type, and - at least as the movie opens - Nell was a very vulnerable figure. I didn't know if Foster would work in such a role, but she pulled it off perfectly. I would criticize this film only for the overly happy ending. Beginning with Nell appearing in court, this took on a too "syrupy" fell in my opinion; everything in the end was far too happy to be believable - in my opinion anyway. But aside from that I thought this was a very well done movie and a very interesting story. (7/10)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Superb
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Gregory Kauffman
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was fortunate enough to see the original production of the play, its emotional impact was as profound as any I have experienced in the theatre. It is perhaps for this reason that I was left somewhat disappointed with this film. However, I recently looked at it again and found that it is truly a top film. Jodie Foster is a towering talent as an actor and this performance was as good or better than any she's given. Neeson and Richardson were also at the top of their game. And the story of a woman shut off from the world, and the world's perceptions of her, merely because she can't communicate to it, is profound in its implications. I should not have been surprised about being disappointed the first time. I also saw a stage production in Los Angeles of IDIOGLOSSIA and found that disappointing after the original. But this film is a wonderful film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A criminally under appreciated and overlooked, divine film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dragoneyed363
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Nell is one of those movies that captivated me in so many ways for so many reasons. It is powerful, poetic and astonishingly beautiful with a beautiful message and an overwhelming use of angelic material that makes my heart ache from how wonderful the attributes that this film tries to get across to it's audience are. The story is a bit familiar, yet they add so much pizazz that it makes it seem fresh and brand new. It really does handle all the subject matter so well and it is exquisitely executed. The directing and writing were amazing, and I thought the performances in particular were absolutely brilliant. Jodie Foster gave such character, life and believability to Nell that I don't think anyone else could have gave any better; she is truly spectacular and deserved that Oscar nomination, maybe even the win. The characters are well done and really likable for the performances and screenplay behind them so you actually care for them, which is what more movies need to try and do; make you care for the characters. Like I said, Nell is dramatic to the point where it's painful, in a good way, sort of, to watch this woman's innocent, undisturbed life play out and unfold, and you wish for anything that you can just make everyone see her point of view and you really hope everything pulls through for this brilliant character in the end. Nell definitely makes us wonder who are the real monsters of this world. The cinematography is excellent also and I found myself completely caught up in how awe-inspiring everything in the movie is at times, whether it's the cinematography, characters or story, which the story is absolutely gripping and fascinating, if you have not caught that by now. Nell seems to be a really overlooked film because most people do not see it for it's full potential of delight and cleverness. It has a few fans, but I never hear any talk of how wonderful it is from anyone. I thought it was excellent, and an astonishing watch, no, adventure, that I would love to live out again sometime soon.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    First rate
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Neil Welch
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Having previously watched Nell one night on my own, I prevailed upon my wife and children (when they were coming up to their teens) to watch it with me one evening. As expected, they fell about laughing as soon as Jodie Foster started talking in "chickabee" language. And then, also as expected, they were utterly absorbed as this unusual and involving story unfolded. For, make no mistake, the quality of Jodie Foster's performance is such that Nell becomes absolutely real, and the audience is intrigued at discovering the explanation for her strange development, and dreadfully, dreadfully worried about what will happen to her. Others have written much better informed and more thoughtful reviews about this film - I will just say that I thought it was an excellent film, and so did my family.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Emotional, yet simple, modest, and beautiful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Deepak Janardhan
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Nell, the movie is titled after the protagonist Nell, a wild girl who has grown up isolated in the woods. The lack of exposure, death of her twin sister, and tales narrated by her paralyzed hermit mother leaves her with an unusual behavior, distorted speech, fear of strangers and the real world. The story revolves around Dr. Jerome Lovell who discovers Nell, panic-stricken at the death of her mother. He tries his best to communicate with her, protect her from strangers, and lead her to a normal life. With time, he grows fond of her. When Jerome explores different options to grab Nell's attention and persuades her to respond, the movie gets intriguing. Dr. Jerome discusses Nell's case with Paula Olsen, who believes and proposes that institutionalization is the way to treat and protect Nell. Paula appeals to the court for the custody of Nell. However, Jerome counters that Nell will turn out to be an object of scientific research like other patients in such medical facilities. The court grants 3 months to both the appellants to observe Nell closely and prove their stance. However, after observing Nell's independence, routines, and response to Jerome, Paula is convinced that the impersonal medical procedures will not cure Nell. Therefore, she begins to assist Jerome in his efforts to understand Nell's language and interact with her. Jerome soon turns out to be Nell's "Guardian Angel". But during their stay together, Jerome and Paula also develop intimacy. Towards the climax, I was convinced that Jerome and Nell will lead a happy life together. However, the movie takes a smooth turn when Nell is seen as the same person but in the company of Jerome's friends. She is shown free, happy, and playing in the woods with Ruthie, Jerome and Paula's daughter. I am impressed by the remarkable performances of Jodie Foster and Liam Neeson. Jodie Foster's effort to justify Nell's appearance and behavior as a wild girl deserves a clamorous applause, mainly for her voice modulation, expressions, movements, and gestures. Liam Neeson's acting as Dr Jerome is significant. Particularly, the dramatic narration of his childhood to evoke Nell's reaction is spectacular. The portrayal of innocence and purity is heart-warming, when Nell vents out her feelings to Jerome and embraces him. Jerome's natural display of disappointment and anger is powerful, at the pathetic sight of Nell in the hospital. The impulsive reaction on realizing that he would lose Nell is admirable. Last but not the least, the choice of the pristine location in the movie, around Nell's wood cabin, certainly adds to the effectiveness of the plot. Firstly, if you are a fan of either Jodie Foster or Liam Neeson, you must not miss this movie. In general, "Nell" is worth your money and time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What the light has been made for...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stormwings
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is 18 now, there are reviews from zero to 10, so here is mine: Albert Einstein said "Imagination is more important than knowledge. For knowledge is limited..." Nell" shows that kind of knowledge which is behind the veil of Isis" and that's because some aware people got together to make this visible. It seems that we still need stories" to reach this, but stories are only a start and never a conclusion. Thou are beautiful, O my love, as Tirzah" - this world is full of grace if you begin trying to say it to anyone, because all you say is to yourself. Who's Tirzah?" Jerry Lovell asked, swimming, laughing... It always makes me shine. Alicia Foster's face at the very end shows all we need to know - during about 16 seconds. The most beautiful thing a camera ever could have been taken for; the light was made for.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    So much more than beautiful...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Paul Magne Haakonsen
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I remember seeing this movie when I was younger, and had a fair memory of how the movie was and that it was a rather good movie. Now in 2012, I decided to get the movie and have another look at it. And I am actually quite happy that I did buy it from Amazon, because this movie is more than good. "Nell" is a really beautiful story that will have you swept away and have you immersed into the story in no time. "Nell" tells a story of being human, accepting people for what and whom they are, it is a story of existence, but most importantly it is a story of the heart. I think this was actually the first or second movie I watched with Liam Neeson (playing Jerome Lovell) in it, and to this day, I still think this is his best and most memorable performance. Jodie Foster (playing Nell) is nothing short of extraordinary in this movie. Her performance is breathtakingly beautiful and so heartfelt. You really get caught up in the story, and you want to know what happens next. And the way Nell's story is revealed to you and how she grows, it is like you are right there with her. The director really did an awesome job on this movie. And the way Jodie Foster portrays Nell when exposed to the world and the life we take for granted is really good acting and amazing performing. She really makes Nell come to life as a real person. "Nell" really goes straight into your heart and soul and the story will be with you for a long, long time. And you might want to keep some tissues at hand, because the story is really touching, and really helped so greatly along by Jodie Foster. I know that I will be watching this movie again at some point, even though the story doesn't hold surprising twists and such, it is one that can bear being watched more than once.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jodie's zenith
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Matt James (matjpi@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In "Nell", Jodie Foster gives, arguably, the best performance of her life. Clearly, she invested deeply in the role and her genuine strength and inner beauty shine so brightly into the character that Nell's beauty and loneliness become completely convincing. The story is more idealistic than realistic (as allegories are wont to be) which is worth remembering throughout - not least when it comes to the courtroom scene. I appreciated the sentiment of that scene whilst privately wishing it had been a closed hearing (full for a custody hearing?) Despite some ragged plot problems (that USGS wouldn't know about the Kellty homestead, that Nell is in really good health, that the lads who deliver her groceries never appear to discuss the 'strange hermit woman' with anyone, and so on) the story staggers to the finish line with an overly idyllic ending. Liam Neeson and Natasha Richardson support well locking horns convincingly over which was to become Nell's champion until they realised that Nell wasn't a trophy for an academic white paper. Nell becomes the adopted child, the glue that binds Neeson and Richardson's characters' emotional attachment. The film has some poetic cinematography and good location. But it is Jodie Foster's ability to play crushingly tender moments (the mirror, the lake, the effective memory) that - I'm happy to admit - still bring me to tears and is why I don't watch it a lot. It's a good film for couples who either have, or want to have, children. When you see it, I hope you'll understand why.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Nell" is a Jodie Foster Triumph
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dale Haufrect (dhaufrect@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The 1994 film, "Nell", is an acting triumph for Jodie Foster. The screenplay is by William Nicholson and it was adapted from the remarkable play by Mark Hadley. Foster grows up as a Yeti in a remote forest having been raised by her mother who suffered from a speech disorder or aphasia after running to the woods escaping the rapist who had attacked her. "Nell" then grows to adulthood with little to say in favor of men, and little speech to begin with anyway. Modern society attempts to "treat" her, but Liam Neesam is able to convince the doctors to allow her some space for growing room and a period of adjustment in order to make a more gradual adjustment to society. This film is compelling from the moment it begins and holds ones attention to the very end. It is deserving of much praise for handling a delicate subject with loving care and empathy that permeates the film. The cinematography is overwhelming and makes one jealous of Nell's environment. It is a very good rent now on DVD and well worth the time involved. Neesam's portrayal of a family physician turned naturalist is equally as compelling as is that of Foster making for a very satisfying picture.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An entertaining film, but it lacks seriousness.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Luis Angel Gonzalez
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What I didn't like about this film is that it went more on the cheesy side of things, while it could have been a more serious and mature one. I would have really liked this story told on a more serious way, but as in many films with good stories, they tend to be ruined when they are chosen to be for all audiences. I'm not saying that it is bad to do that though, some movies are great that way, but this one, in my opinion, didn't need that. Now onto the acting, I didn't like Jodie Foster,her acting seemed forced to me. Liam and Natasha did good, but nothing special in their acting. All in all, this is an entertaining film that many may like, but for me it didn't do much.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fascinating Story That Turns A Bit Too "Feel Good" In The End
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sddavis63 (revsdd@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The subject matter is fascinating. Nell (Jodie Foster) is a young woman raised by her mother in a setting completely cut off from civilization. She knows nothing of the outside world and has had little if any interaction with other people throughout her life, to the point at which she's developed her own language. Discovered by a grocery store delivery boy when her mother died, she comes under the care and tutelage of Drs. Lovell and Olson (Liam Neesom and Natasha Richardson) who have to decide whether or not she should be taken from her isolated environment and introduced to the "real" world. The dilemma is very powerful. What right does anyone else have to decide for Nell how her life should be lived, especially when she's clearly capable of living on her own in the environment to which she's accustomed? Why should she be subject to court orders about her fate or to living in psychiatric hospitals when there's obviously nothing really wrong with her except that she's living a life that no one in the outside world can understand? Those are tough questions. The movie does a great job of developing the relationship between Nell and Lovell (and then also Olson) in a sensitive way, as both begin to care for Nell and want to be protective of her and her rights to choose. Jodie Foster was - I thought - surprisingly good in this role. She usually plays a stronger type, and - at least as the movie opens - Nell was a very vulnerable figure. I didn't know if Foster would work in such a role, but she pulled it off perfectly. I would criticize this film only for the overly happy ending. Beginning with Nell appearing in court, this took on a too "syrupy" fell in my opinion; everything in the end was far too happy to be believable - in my opinion anyway. But aside from that I thought this was a very well done movie and a very interesting story. (7/10)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Superb
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Gregory Kauffman
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was fortunate enough to see the original production of the play, its emotional impact was as profound as any I have experienced in the theatre. It is perhaps for this reason that I was left somewhat disappointed with this film. However, I recently looked at it again and found that it is truly a top film. Jodie Foster is a towering talent as an actor and this performance was as good or better than any she's given. Neeson and Richardson were also at the top of their game. And the story of a woman shut off from the world, and the world's perceptions of her, merely because she can't communicate to it, is profound in its implications. I should not have been surprised about being disappointed the first time. I also saw a stage production in Los Angeles of IDIOGLOSSIA and found that disappointing after the original. But this film is a wonderful film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A criminally under appreciated and overlooked, divine film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dragoneyed363
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Nell is one of those movies that captivated me in so many ways for so many reasons. It is powerful, poetic and astonishingly beautiful with a beautiful message and an overwhelming use of angelic material that makes my heart ache from how wonderful the attributes that this film tries to get across to it's audience are. The story is a bit familiar, yet they add so much pizazz that it makes it seem fresh and brand new. It really does handle all the subject matter so well and it is exquisitely executed. The directing and writing were amazing, and I thought the performances in particular were absolutely brilliant. Jodie Foster gave such character, life and believability to Nell that I don't think anyone else could have gave any better; she is truly spectacular and deserved that Oscar nomination, maybe even the win. The characters are well done and really likable for the performances and screenplay behind them so you actually care for them, which is what more movies need to try and do; make you care for the characters. Like I said, Nell is dramatic to the point where it's painful, in a good way, sort of, to watch this woman's innocent, undisturbed life play out and unfold, and you wish for anything that you can just make everyone see her point of view and you really hope everything pulls through for this brilliant character in the end. Nell definitely makes us wonder who are the real monsters of this world. The cinematography is excellent also and I found myself completely caught up in how awe-inspiring everything in the movie is at times, whether it's the cinematography, characters or story, which the story is absolutely gripping and fascinating, if you have not caught that by now. Nell seems to be a really overlooked film because most people do not see it for it's full potential of delight and cleverness. It has a few fans, but I never hear any talk of how wonderful it is from anyone. I thought it was excellent, and an astonishing watch, no, adventure, that I would love to live out again sometime soon.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    First rate
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Neil Welch
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Having previously watched Nell one night on my own, I prevailed upon my wife and children (when they were coming up to their teens) to watch it with me one evening. As expected, they fell about laughing as soon as Jodie Foster started talking in "chickabee" language. And then, also as expected, they were utterly absorbed as this unusual and involving story unfolded. For, make no mistake, the quality of Jodie Foster's performance is such that Nell becomes absolutely real, and the audience is intrigued at discovering the explanation for her strange development, and dreadfully, dreadfully worried about what will happen to her. Others have written much better informed and more thoughtful reviews about this film - I will just say that I thought it was an excellent film, and so did my family.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Emotional, yet simple, modest, and beautiful
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Deepak Janardhan
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Nell, the movie is titled after the protagonist Nell, a wild girl who has grown up isolated in the woods. The lack of exposure, death of her twin sister, and tales narrated by her paralyzed hermit mother leaves her with an unusual behavior, distorted speech, fear of strangers and the real world. The story revolves around Dr. Jerome Lovell who discovers Nell, panic-stricken at the death of her mother. He tries his best to communicate with her, protect her from strangers, and lead her to a normal life. With time, he grows fond of her. When Jerome explores different options to grab Nell's attention and persuades her to respond, the movie gets intriguing. Dr. Jerome discusses Nell's case with Paula Olsen, who believes and proposes that institutionalization is the way to treat and protect Nell. Paula appeals to the court for the custody of Nell. However, Jerome counters that Nell will turn out to be an object of scientific research like other patients in such medical facilities. The court grants 3 months to both the appellants to observe Nell closely and prove their stance. However, after observing Nell's independence, routines, and response to Jerome, Paula is convinced that the impersonal medical procedures will not cure Nell. Therefore, she begins to assist Jerome in his efforts to understand Nell's language and interact with her. Jerome soon turns out to be Nell's "Guardian Angel". But during their stay together, Jerome and Paula also develop intimacy. Towards the climax, I was convinced that Jerome and Nell will lead a happy life together. However, the movie takes a smooth turn when Nell is seen as the same person but in the company of Jerome's friends. She is shown free, happy, and playing in the woods with Ruthie, Jerome and Paula's daughter. I am impressed by the remarkable performances of Jodie Foster and Liam Neeson. Jodie Foster's effort to justify Nell's appearance and behavior as a wild girl deserves a clamorous applause, mainly for her voice modulation, expressions, movements, and gestures. Liam Neeson's acting as Dr Jerome is significant. Particularly, the dramatic narration of his childhood to evoke Nell's reaction is spectacular. The portrayal of innocence and purity is heart-warming, when Nell vents out her feelings to Jerome and embraces him. Jerome's natural display of disappointment and anger is powerful, at the pathetic sight of Nell in the hospital. The impulsive reaction on realizing that he would lose Nell is admirable. Last but not the least, the choice of the pristine location in the movie, around Nell's wood cabin, certainly adds to the effectiveness of the plot. Firstly, if you are a fan of either Jodie Foster or Liam Neeson, you must not miss this movie. In general, "Nell" is worth your money and time.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    What the light has been made for...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stormwings
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is 18 now, there are reviews from zero to 10, so here is mine: Albert Einstein said "Imagination is more important than knowledge. For knowledge is limited..." Nell" shows that kind of knowledge which is behind the veil of Isis" and that's because some aware people got together to make this visible. It seems that we still need stories" to reach this, but stories are only a start and never a conclusion. Thou are beautiful, O my love, as Tirzah" - this world is full of grace if you begin trying to say it to anyone, because all you say is to yourself. Who's Tirzah?" Jerry Lovell asked, swimming, laughing... It always makes me shine. Alicia Foster's face at the very end shows all we need to know - during about 16 seconds. The most beautiful thing a camera ever could have been taken for; the light was made for.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    So much more than beautiful...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Paul Magne Haakonsen
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I remember seeing this movie when I was younger, and had a fair memory of how the movie was and that it was a rather good movie. Now in 2012, I decided to get the movie and have another look at it. And I am actually quite happy that I did buy it from Amazon, because this movie is more than good. "Nell" is a really beautiful story that will have you swept away and have you immersed into the story in no time. "Nell" tells a story of being human, accepting people for what and whom they are, it is a story of existence, but most importantly it is a story of the heart. I think this was actually the first or second movie I watched with Liam Neeson (playing Jerome Lovell) in it, and to this day, I still think this is his best and most memorable performance. Jodie Foster (playing Nell) is nothing short of extraordinary in this movie. Her performance is breathtakingly beautiful and so heartfelt. You really get caught up in the story, and you want to know what happens next. And the way Nell's story is revealed to you and how she grows, it is like you are right there with her. The director really did an awesome job on this movie. And the way Jodie Foster portrays Nell when exposed to the world and the life we take for granted is really good acting and amazing performing. She really makes Nell come to life as a real person. "Nell" really goes straight into your heart and soul and the story will be with you for a long, long time. And you might want to keep some tissues at hand, because the story is really touching, and really helped so greatly along by Jodie Foster. I know that I will be watching this movie again at some point, even though the story doesn't hold surprising twists and such, it is one that can bear being watched more than once.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Jodie's zenith
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Matt James (matjpi@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In "Nell", Jodie Foster gives, arguably, the best performance of her life. Clearly, she invested deeply in the role and her genuine strength and inner beauty shine so brightly into the character that Nell's beauty and loneliness become completely convincing. The story is more idealistic than realistic (as allegories are wont to be) which is worth remembering throughout - not least when it comes to the courtroom scene. I appreciated the sentiment of that scene whilst privately wishing it had been a closed hearing (full for a custody hearing?) Despite some ragged plot problems (that USGS wouldn't know about the Kellty homestead, that Nell is in really good health, that the lads who deliver her groceries never appear to discuss the 'strange hermit woman' with anyone, and so on) the story staggers to the finish line with an overly idyllic ending. Liam Neeson and Natasha Richardson support well locking horns convincingly over which was to become Nell's champion until they realised that Nell wasn't a trophy for an academic white paper. Nell becomes the adopted child, the glue that binds Neeson and Richardson's characters' emotional attachment. The film has some poetic cinematography and good location. But it is Jodie Foster's ability to play crushingly tender moments (the mirror, the lake, the effective memory) that - I'm happy to admit - still bring me to tears and is why I don't watch it a lot. It's a good film for couples who either have, or want to have, children. When you see it, I hope you'll understand why.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "Nell" is a Jodie Foster Triumph
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dale Haufrect (dhaufrect@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The 1994 film, "Nell", is an acting triumph for Jodie Foster. The screenplay is by William Nicholson and it was adapted from the remarkable play by Mark Hadley. Foster grows up as a Yeti in a remote forest having been raised by her mother who suffered from a speech disorder or aphasia after running to the woods escaping the rapist who had attacked her. "Nell" then grows to adulthood with little to say in favor of men, and little speech to begin with anyway. Modern society attempts to "treat" her, but Liam Neesam is able to convince the doctors to allow her some space for growing room and a period of adjustment in order to make a more gradual adjustment to society. This film is compelling from the moment it begins and holds ones attention to the very end. It is deserving of much praise for handling a delicate subject with loving care and empathy that permeates the film. The cinematography is overwhelming and makes one jealous of Nell's environment. It is a very good rent now on DVD and well worth the time involved. Neesam's portrayal of a family physician turned naturalist is equally as compelling as is that of Foster making for a very satisfying picture.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An entertaining film, but it lacks seriousness.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Luis Angel Gonzalez
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What I didn't like about this film is that it went more on the cheesy side of things, while it could have been a more serious and mature one. I would have really liked this story told on a more serious way, but as in many films with good stories, they tend to be ruined when they are chosen to be for all audiences. I'm not saying that it is bad to do that though, some movies are great that way, but this one, in my opinion, didn't need that. Now onto the acting, I didn't like Jodie Foster,her acting seemed forced to me. Liam and Natasha did good, but nothing special in their acting. All in all, this is an entertaining film that many may like, but for me it didn't do much.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fascinating Story That Turns A Bit Too "Feel Good" In The End
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sddavis63 (revsdd@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The subject matter is fascinating. Nell (Jodie Foster) is a young woman raised by her mother in a setting completely cut off from civilization. She knows nothing of the outside world and has had little if any interaction with other people throughout her life, to the point at which she's developed her own language. Discovered by a grocery store delivery boy when her mother died, she comes under the care and tutelage of Drs. Lovell and Olson (Liam Neesom and Natasha Richardson) who have to decide whether or not she should be taken from her isolated environment and introduced to the "real" world. The dilemma is very powerful. What right does anyone else have to decide for Nell how her life should be lived, especially when she's clearly capable of living on her own in the environment to which she's accustomed? Why should she be subject to court orders about her fate or to living in psychiatric hospitals when there's obviously nothing really wrong with her except that she's living a life that no one in the outside world can understand? Those are tough questions. The movie does a great job of developing the relationship between Nell and Lovell (and then also Olson) in a sensitive way, as both begin to care for Nell and want to be protective of her and her rights to choose. Jodie Foster was - I thought - surprisingly good in this role. She usually plays a stronger type, and - at least as the movie opens - Nell was a very vulnerable figure. I didn't know if Foster would work in such a role, but she pulled it off perfectly. I would criticize this film only for the overly happy ending. Beginning with Nell appearing in court, this took on a too "syrupy" fell in my opinion; everything in the end was far too happy to be believable - in my opinion anyway. But aside from that I thought this was a very well done movie and a very interesting story. (7/10)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Superb
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Gregory Kauffman
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was fortunate enough to see the original production of the play, its emotional impact was as profound as any I have experienced in the theatre. It is perhaps for this reason that I was left somewhat disappointed with this film. However, I recently looked at it again and found that it is truly a top film. Jodie Foster is a towering talent as an actor and this performance was as good or better than any she's given. Neeson and Richardson were also at the top of their game. And the story of a woman shut off from the world, and the world's perceptions of her, merely because she can't communicate to it, is profound in its implications. I should not have been surprised about being disappointed the first time. I also saw a stage production in Los Angeles of IDIOGLOSSIA and found that disappointing after the original. But this film is a wonderful film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A criminally under appreciated and overlooked, divine film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dragoneyed363
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Nell is one of those movies that captivated me in so many ways for so many reasons. It is powerful, poetic and astonishingly beautiful with a beautiful message and an overwhelming use of angelic material that makes my heart ache from how wonderful the attributes that this film tries to get across to it's audience are. The story is a bit familiar, yet they add so much pizazz that it makes it seem fresh and brand new. It really does handle all the subject matter so well and it is exquisitely executed. The directing and writing were amazing, and I thought the performances in particular were absolutely brilliant. Jodie Foster gave such character, life and believability to Nell that I don't think anyone else could have gave any better; she is truly spectacular and deserved that Oscar nomination, maybe even the win. The characters are well done and really likable for the performances and screenplay behind them so you actually care for them, which is what more movies need to try and do; make you care for the characters. Like I said, Nell is dramatic to the point where it's painful, in a good way, sort of, to watch this woman's innocent, undisturbed life play out and unfold, and you wish for anything that you can just make everyone see her point of view and you really hope everything pulls through for this brilliant character in the end. Nell definitely makes us wonder who are the real monsters of this world. The cinematography is excellent also and I found myself completely caught up in how awe-inspiring everything in the movie is at times, whether it's the cinematography, characters or story, which the story is absolutely gripping and fascinating, if you have not caught that by now. Nell seems to be a really overlooked film because most people do not see it for it's full potential of delight and cleverness. It has a few fans, but I never hear any talk of how wonderful it is from anyone. I thought it was excellent, and an astonishing watch, no, adventure, that I would love to live out again sometime soon.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    First rate
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Neil Welch
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Having previously watched Nell one night on my own, I prevailed upon my wife and children (when they were coming up to their teens) to watch it with me one evening. As expected, they fell about laughing as soon as Jodie Foster started talking in "chickabee" language. And then, also as expected, they were utterly absorbed as this unusual and involving story unfolded. For, make no mistake, the quality of Jodie Foster's performance is such that Nell becomes absolutely real, and the audience is intrigued at discovering the explanation for her strange development, and dreadfully, dreadfully worried about what will happen to her. Others have written much better informed and more thoughtful reviews about this film - I will just say that I thought it was an excellent film, and so did my family.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
