<filme>
 <id>
  745
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0069198
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1972
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  A Classe Governante
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  7.4
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  A member of the House of Lords dies in a shockingly silly way, leaving his estate to his son. Unfortunately, his son is insane: he thinks he is Jesus Christ. The other somewhat-more ... &nbsp;&raquo;
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  A member of the House of Lords dies in a shockingly silly way, leaving his estate to his son. Unfortunately, his son is insane: he thinks he is Jesus Christ. The other somewhat-more respectable members of their family plot to steal the estate from him. Murder and mayhem ensues.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Music
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   house of lords
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   murder
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   wastrel
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   hospital
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   contraceptive
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Peter Medak
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Peter Barnes
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Peter O'Toole
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Alastair Sim
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Arthur Lowe
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pretentious and heavy handed ...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andrew Huggett
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'rich knobs and privileged a***holes can afford to be bonkers  ' The first 10 minutes or so of this film are quite interesting, with a good cast of British eccentrics (especially the splendid Alastair Sim and Arthur Lowe). I quite enjoyed the gathering at the start with the reading of the will and the arrival of the new Lord (and even the subsequent surreal song and dance routine with the ladies organising the local f&ecirc;te)  but it then descends into a complete pretentious mess. Very disappointing considering the talented actors deployed here. I nodded off just after Peter O'Toole had stopped thinking he was God and decided he was Jack the Ripper instead - this was partly because I'd had some wine with my meal, and not entirely down to the reactions this film provoked in me. The odd sequence at the end in the House of Lords reminded me of the final 2 episodes of the TV series 'the Prisoner' made 4 years prior to the release of this film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    good movie, brilliant Peter O'Toole
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    knightinarms
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I found the movie peculiar, at times it was simply enthralling, at times; it was a bit underwhelming, which makes it difficult for me to form a decided opinion of it especially as somebody who's not that familiar with that age or society. The charismatic Peter O' Toole shines gloriously through the course of it however; both as the frowned upon schizophrenic who believes he is Jesus Christ and as the revered headstrong aristocrat who secretly believes he is Jack the ripper.The movie which gradually becomes more and more satirical as it progresses symbolically connects the indifferent ruling class to the rise of such evils as Jack the ripper. A commendable acting performance from Peter O'Toole makes this symbolism all the more persuasive. Also, it shows how all the scheming manages to turn a harmless buffoon into a psychotic serial killer to the detriment of the perpetrators and his well wishers alike and how, upon this transition, he ironically gains acceptance into the society which had ridiculed him earlier. I would not go ahead and say its a 10 on 10 for me for there were instances where I felt a lack of continuity in the storyline, though its difficult to recall such incidents in particular, overall the movie didn't leave me as awestruck as some other movies which I've voted as a perfect 10. Its difficult to say how much of it was due to my lack of knowledge of that age or society and how much of it was due to gaps in the storyline itself. That said, the movie is definitely worth a watch, in fact, a second watch would be worth considering for somebody from outside of Britain, you might just pick up the odd joke you missed in the first viewing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bless Peter O'Toole! Bless the irreverent writer!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    CinefanR
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    They just don't make movies like this anymore! This is a delightfully insane, smart and ultimately unpredictable black comedy with Shakespearian and surrealistic undertones. It's great to finally see a script that does justice to Peter O'Toole's singular talents. A short description of the plot would be useless however, since the movie practically defies classification. The harsh criticism aimed at British aristocracy is merely a pretense for a deeper analysis of everything. Religion and freedom, love and happiness, "normality" and alienation, life and death, good and evil, society vs. the individual --- the human condition, basically--- everything is scrutinized and relentlessly exposed or challenged, with quirky humor, sarcasm, and - yes - compassion underneath it all. If you don't care for these topics, "then kindly leave the stage", says the hero. The splendid Peter O'Toole simply shines in this unconventional and difficult role, playing it to perfection and beyond. His intelligently nuanced tour-de-force performance is hilarious, disturbing and touching all together  "I'm being everybody", he says. Everything that comes out of Peter O'Toole's mouth has a Shakespearian ring to it. Everything about him has a distinctive elegance that is unparalleled to this day. The supporting cast is excellent; dialogs are cleverly built on multiple layers of symbolism; the music is fabulous. Each time you watch this movie, you'll pick up on something new. Well, there's much to be said, but watch it and judge for yourself. Get the full-length version of the movie, form Criterion Collection. "The Ruling Class" is a must-see, one of the best movies ever - timeless, profound, moving and truly unique.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A quirky fantasy becomes a turgid polemic over 2.5 hours
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What a sorry mess! "The Ruling Class" begins as full of promise and with wit and an irreverent willingness to defy convention and slowly (glacially!) mutates over its 2-1/2 hour running time into a directionless screed against Britain's aristocracy. Never willing to let the audience grasp their intentions on their own, again and again Peter Medak uses hamfisted characterizations and plot devices to convey author Peter Barnes' view that the titled in Britain are superficial, hypocritical, incestuous, calloused, categorically corrupt and evil, congenitally insane, the personification of Satan, and Jack the Ripper himself! And the members of the House of Lords? Why they're a bunch of stuffy old corpses. No, really! NO, REALLY! Every time you say to yourself "Yeah, I get it", the Two Peters reply "Oh, no you don't; not by a long shot!" and then proceed to tell you the same thing over and over and over and over and over again. Peter O'Toole is pretty good (although led down by comically bad make-up and wigs), but O'Toole is much better elsewhere. Unless you're an O'Toole completist, save yourself 2-1/2 hours of having tabloid-level editorializing rubbed in your face.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very accurate historically
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    baron_genitalstrassen
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Generally regarded as one of the best British horror films, The Ruling Class very nearly sank into obscurity shortly after being made. The film's distributors EMI disliked it so much that they wrote it off as a tax loss. Then Rod Stewart, who was married to Coral Browne at the time, allegedly tried to buy the negative so that he could have it destroyed - thereby preventing the public from seeing his wife in the nude. Fortunately, the film survived (though not in the way its director originally intended). The story focuses on a virginal 14th Earl of Gurney (O'Toole) who is exiled on a remote Scottish island. What he discovers, though, is he thinks he is Jesus Christ. It's a movie about religion, God, and the crisis of faith, with an ending that's either devoutly Christian (O'Toole's Jack Arnold Alexander Tancred Gurney continues praying right to the very end), or a nihilistic comment on God's absence from the universe. With such a colourful production history, "The Ruling Class" was always destined for fame. Yet its cult status actually has more to do with the film's content - there's a paedophile subplot, lots of occult rituals, sexual perversion, Alastair Sim in drag, and a resolutely downbeat finale that's as far removed from a happy ending as it's possible to get. And on top of all that, it's bloody scary. "The Ruling Class" is a movie that'll burn its way into your unconscious and give you nightmares for many years to come. "The Ruling Class" is also available in a 199-minute uncut version
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not a bad premise, but it's overly long and rather indulgent.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "The Ruling Class" is a film that is sure to offend--after all, the leading man (Peter O'Toole) thinks he is Jesus! Right away, this sort of idea eliminates many potential viewers who would just be too offended to see such a film--especially with scenes where O'Toole climbs up on a giant cross in his house in order to meditate or take a nap. Additionally, the film nails the final nails in the coffin of the traditional English class system--and probably offended quite a few tradition-bound Brits as well. As for me, I was less offended (especially in its skewering of the upper class) but more bothered because the execution of the plot left a bit to be desired. Specifically, it was overlong and overly indulgent. The film begins with the Earl of Gurney accidentally hanging himself while having a rant--during which he was wearing a tutu! Obviously, the guy was NOT in his right mind. However, his heir (O'Toole) is 100% bonkers--and thinks he's Jesus! Considering he's got a seat in the House of Lords the family thinks this is a serious problem! But they also want to have an heir and so they trick the new Earl into a marriage and a child is soon produced. Now that the heir is here, the family will either have O'Toole committed or cure him--they don't care which--they just know they can't have a loony representing the family in the House! The film has a lot to like. I love how, for absolutely no reason, the cast members periodically break into song and dance numbers. I also like the general premise that the monarchy has long outlived its usefulness. Finally, the Butler is wonderful, as once he inherits his fortune he doesn't care one bit about propriety and tells EVERYONE exactly what he'd been hiding all those years--and delivers some very funny lines. But, I also feel irritated that such a lovely idea is, at times, squandered because the film just goes on and on and on and on. Someone really needed to look at this film and make a few judicious cuts here and there or say 'enough' when it lost momentum because scenes were just overdone or lacked comedic timing. This is especially true near the end--a portion that should have taken about ten minutes but took 40! And, frankly, the Jack the Ripper angle was handled in a very, very unfunny way--and it could have been hilarious. Overall, an interesting and compelling failure. By the way, the Rorschach cards used by the psychiatrist in the film are two of the actual cards from this test. It's rare to see real cards in films or TV.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Schizophrenic. . . in a good way!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dougmcnair
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is sometimes brilliant, sometimes silly, sometimes surreal, sometimes tragic, sometimes wickedly satirical, and always schizophrenic (which is the whole point). It's also the only film in which Jesus Christ does the Varsity Drag. Peter O'Toole plays the paranoid schizophrenic heir to an English earldom, and as his relatives try to either cure him or commit him, what we think is being played for laughs slowly becomes something far darker. O'Toole's performance is brilliant, bringing out this man's almost unbearable pain as he tries to hold his mind together by escaping into whatever fantasy world he can manage. Unfortunately, escaping into a world where he is God and everyone loves each other does not work for society, so his family has to snap him out of that so he can become acceptable. At its core, the film is about what kind of insanity (and what kind of god) is acceptable in upper-class British society, and it makes its points on that score very well. But unfortunately, it's far too long; there are so many supporting characters with their own subplots that it gets bogged down in many places. But if you can last through the slow parts, you'll be rewarded with some unforgettable scenes before the end. Seven stars.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Marvelous Gallery of Grotesques
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    raymundohpl
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I recently watched the uncut version of this film on Turner Classic Movies in the wee hours of the morning and thoroughly enjoyed the performances of all the actors in it with the exception of the lead character J.C./Jack played by the redoubtable Peter O'Toole. The plot of a mad lord(God knows that there are way too many of them by far in the House of Lords both in the past and present) who believes himself to be a benevolent, loving "Peace, Man" Jesus Christ who is subsequently driven by the "scientific" vile machinations of a crazed German psychiatrist(who ends up needing his own head examined)to become a "sane" Jack the Ripper, is buttressed by the superb performances of the supporting cast. Peter O'Toole's "Tour de Force" performance which for the most part lauded by the other reviewers here, is too over-the-top which works within the context of this film for his role but I found O'Toole shamelessly mugging and leering without restraint(indeed like a real madman) which again works accidentally within the context of this film. After O'Toole has been branded "sane" as Jack the Ripper there are several huge closeups of his wide staring eyes--I swear I thought I was watching Joan Crawford as "Mommie Dearest" glaring in her best Kabuki "Mie"-grimace before letting her "Strait-Jacket" axe descend for some satisfying mayhem. Harry Andrews as O'Toole's pater, the 13th Lord Gurney turns in a short but satisfying appearance in his rigid iron-jawed unpleasant upper-crusty sod who offs himself whilst wearing unflattering raiment, William Mervyn and Coral Browne play two of the Gurneys, the nastiest "upper class" scum dripping with self-importance and probably a leaky colostomy bag! Mervyn excelled in portraying snooty, "stiff-upper-lipped" pompous nabobs with their noses in the air though I presume he was not like that in real life; Coral was just doing what came naturally, playing herself, i.e., being a nasty, caustic-tongued man-hungry bitch who got her hooks into horror legend Vincent Price in reality as Vinnie's last wife, James Villers as his specialty, a gormless pathetic gangling twit, Nigel Green as an "Electric Jehovah"(Nigel offed himself after this role, his life imitated his F-art), Michael Bryant as the crazed unscrupulous German psychiatrist, Hugh Burden as the harried mousy lawyer(Mr. Reeder indeed!), Graham Crowden as a gimlet-eyed "sanity officer" who bursts into a lively duet of the Eton Boating Song with O'Toole, Arthur Lowe as the one sympathetic character in the whole film, the Bolshie old manservant who gets framed for the murder done by O'Toole, and last but not least, the great Alastair Sim as the doddering old Bishop, shaking and trembling in fear in the best Kierkegaardian manner. These supporting actors along with Kay Walsh and Patsy Byrne, all work very well together but O'Toole, purposely, I'm sure, strikes a jarring note in the whole film as the huge stinking turd floating in the middle of the punchbowl. You can't miss him but wish he were a little less noticeable! All in all, 10 Stars, Excellent All Around, even with O'Toole's shameless overacting, and chewing up the scenery, which I am sure was his original intent for the overall theme of this gem of a film. The director, Peter Medak(The Changeling, Species II, The Krays) does an absolutely rip-roaring job here and is to be highly commended for this film, which may indeed be his masterpiece!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "How do you know you're God?" ... "I found that in prayer I was talking to myself."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moonspinner55
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gross, frequently tasteless satire, much as if Kubrick's "Dr. Strangelove" were transplanted to England's House of Lords and then played at the wrong speed. After the Earl of Gurney accidentally kills himself during one of his fetish games, the 14th Earl--son Jack--is groomed to accept the crown. Once mad Jack--who believes himself to be Christ--undergoes a mental transformation on the night of his son's birth and self-metamorphoses into Jack the Ripper, the plot (thin to begin with) becomes a dartboard for the one-liners (some of which are very funny and are a compensation). Peter Barnes adapted his play for the screen, the kind of material upper-crust audiences like to label 'savage'; he was reciprocated with a game cast and a fine director in Peter Medak, yet these nutty fantasies are merely clotheslines for Barnes to hang his maddening soliloquies on. Peter O'Toole (with cartoony strawberry-blond hair) has some terrific moments early on, particularly in the musical send-ups, but later begins to bellow and rarely stops. The film is too full of targets, and too nasty overall, for its extreme length...it doesn't even look good. ** from ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Long but with some insanity to keep the cobwebs out. O'Toole is electric.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    secondtake
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Ruling Class (1972) This is a peculiar, long, hilarious and tedious movie, depending on your taste and probably your age. Parts of it have always made me perk up and laugh, but it works the same theme (of the exhaustion of the old British ways) to death. Peter O'Toole lets it all hang out here, for sure, as Jesus, and as a crazed new British Lord (including a famous final section where he gives a speech to the House of Lords, which is filled with cobwebbed skeletons). It's not really supposed to be haunting or scary, but it's slightly gruesome comedy is pointed, for sure. And funny. If you don't laugh or at least give a crooked smile to the battle between two men who think they are god--O'Toole as the Jesus God and Nigel Green as an Old Testament God, and the Electric Messiah (both). It's crazy and crazed and yet what else do you expect? Someone said it perfectly when they called it a "comedy with tragic relief." O'Toole won an Oscar for his efforts (and he played his part for free). The American version of the movie has 6 minutes missing, though probably the wrong 6 minutes. A good editing might remove an hour and have a faster and more punchy movie. Still, it is what it is, and there's nothing quite like it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pretentious and heavy handed ...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andrew Huggett
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'rich knobs and privileged a***holes can afford to be bonkers  ' The first 10 minutes or so of this film are quite interesting, with a good cast of British eccentrics (especially the splendid Alastair Sim and Arthur Lowe). I quite enjoyed the gathering at the start with the reading of the will and the arrival of the new Lord (and even the subsequent surreal song and dance routine with the ladies organising the local f&ecirc;te)  but it then descends into a complete pretentious mess. Very disappointing considering the talented actors deployed here. I nodded off just after Peter O'Toole had stopped thinking he was God and decided he was Jack the Ripper instead - this was partly because I'd had some wine with my meal, and not entirely down to the reactions this film provoked in me. The odd sequence at the end in the House of Lords reminded me of the final 2 episodes of the TV series 'the Prisoner' made 4 years prior to the release of this film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    good movie, brilliant Peter O'Toole
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    knightinarms
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I found the movie peculiar, at times it was simply enthralling, at times; it was a bit underwhelming, which makes it difficult for me to form a decided opinion of it especially as somebody who's not that familiar with that age or society. The charismatic Peter O' Toole shines gloriously through the course of it however; both as the frowned upon schizophrenic who believes he is Jesus Christ and as the revered headstrong aristocrat who secretly believes he is Jack the ripper.The movie which gradually becomes more and more satirical as it progresses symbolically connects the indifferent ruling class to the rise of such evils as Jack the ripper. A commendable acting performance from Peter O'Toole makes this symbolism all the more persuasive. Also, it shows how all the scheming manages to turn a harmless buffoon into a psychotic serial killer to the detriment of the perpetrators and his well wishers alike and how, upon this transition, he ironically gains acceptance into the society which had ridiculed him earlier. I would not go ahead and say its a 10 on 10 for me for there were instances where I felt a lack of continuity in the storyline, though its difficult to recall such incidents in particular, overall the movie didn't leave me as awestruck as some other movies which I've voted as a perfect 10. Its difficult to say how much of it was due to my lack of knowledge of that age or society and how much of it was due to gaps in the storyline itself. That said, the movie is definitely worth a watch, in fact, a second watch would be worth considering for somebody from outside of Britain, you might just pick up the odd joke you missed in the first viewing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bless Peter O'Toole! Bless the irreverent writer!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    CinefanR
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    They just don't make movies like this anymore! This is a delightfully insane, smart and ultimately unpredictable black comedy with Shakespearian and surrealistic undertones. It's great to finally see a script that does justice to Peter O'Toole's singular talents. A short description of the plot would be useless however, since the movie practically defies classification. The harsh criticism aimed at British aristocracy is merely a pretense for a deeper analysis of everything. Religion and freedom, love and happiness, "normality" and alienation, life and death, good and evil, society vs. the individual --- the human condition, basically--- everything is scrutinized and relentlessly exposed or challenged, with quirky humor, sarcasm, and - yes - compassion underneath it all. If you don't care for these topics, "then kindly leave the stage", says the hero. The splendid Peter O'Toole simply shines in this unconventional and difficult role, playing it to perfection and beyond. His intelligently nuanced tour-de-force performance is hilarious, disturbing and touching all together  "I'm being everybody", he says. Everything that comes out of Peter O'Toole's mouth has a Shakespearian ring to it. Everything about him has a distinctive elegance that is unparalleled to this day. The supporting cast is excellent; dialogs are cleverly built on multiple layers of symbolism; the music is fabulous. Each time you watch this movie, you'll pick up on something new. Well, there's much to be said, but watch it and judge for yourself. Get the full-length version of the movie, form Criterion Collection. "The Ruling Class" is a must-see, one of the best movies ever - timeless, profound, moving and truly unique.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A quirky fantasy becomes a turgid polemic over 2.5 hours
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What a sorry mess! "The Ruling Class" begins as full of promise and with wit and an irreverent willingness to defy convention and slowly (glacially!) mutates over its 2-1/2 hour running time into a directionless screed against Britain's aristocracy. Never willing to let the audience grasp their intentions on their own, again and again Peter Medak uses hamfisted characterizations and plot devices to convey author Peter Barnes' view that the titled in Britain are superficial, hypocritical, incestuous, calloused, categorically corrupt and evil, congenitally insane, the personification of Satan, and Jack the Ripper himself! And the members of the House of Lords? Why they're a bunch of stuffy old corpses. No, really! NO, REALLY! Every time you say to yourself "Yeah, I get it", the Two Peters reply "Oh, no you don't; not by a long shot!" and then proceed to tell you the same thing over and over and over and over and over again. Peter O'Toole is pretty good (although led down by comically bad make-up and wigs), but O'Toole is much better elsewhere. Unless you're an O'Toole completist, save yourself 2-1/2 hours of having tabloid-level editorializing rubbed in your face.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very accurate historically
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    baron_genitalstrassen
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Generally regarded as one of the best British horror films, The Ruling Class very nearly sank into obscurity shortly after being made. The film's distributors EMI disliked it so much that they wrote it off as a tax loss. Then Rod Stewart, who was married to Coral Browne at the time, allegedly tried to buy the negative so that he could have it destroyed - thereby preventing the public from seeing his wife in the nude. Fortunately, the film survived (though not in the way its director originally intended). The story focuses on a virginal 14th Earl of Gurney (O'Toole) who is exiled on a remote Scottish island. What he discovers, though, is he thinks he is Jesus Christ. It's a movie about religion, God, and the crisis of faith, with an ending that's either devoutly Christian (O'Toole's Jack Arnold Alexander Tancred Gurney continues praying right to the very end), or a nihilistic comment on God's absence from the universe. With such a colourful production history, "The Ruling Class" was always destined for fame. Yet its cult status actually has more to do with the film's content - there's a paedophile subplot, lots of occult rituals, sexual perversion, Alastair Sim in drag, and a resolutely downbeat finale that's as far removed from a happy ending as it's possible to get. And on top of all that, it's bloody scary. "The Ruling Class" is a movie that'll burn its way into your unconscious and give you nightmares for many years to come. "The Ruling Class" is also available in a 199-minute uncut version
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not a bad premise, but it's overly long and rather indulgent.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "The Ruling Class" is a film that is sure to offend--after all, the leading man (Peter O'Toole) thinks he is Jesus! Right away, this sort of idea eliminates many potential viewers who would just be too offended to see such a film--especially with scenes where O'Toole climbs up on a giant cross in his house in order to meditate or take a nap. Additionally, the film nails the final nails in the coffin of the traditional English class system--and probably offended quite a few tradition-bound Brits as well. As for me, I was less offended (especially in its skewering of the upper class) but more bothered because the execution of the plot left a bit to be desired. Specifically, it was overlong and overly indulgent. The film begins with the Earl of Gurney accidentally hanging himself while having a rant--during which he was wearing a tutu! Obviously, the guy was NOT in his right mind. However, his heir (O'Toole) is 100% bonkers--and thinks he's Jesus! Considering he's got a seat in the House of Lords the family thinks this is a serious problem! But they also want to have an heir and so they trick the new Earl into a marriage and a child is soon produced. Now that the heir is here, the family will either have O'Toole committed or cure him--they don't care which--they just know they can't have a loony representing the family in the House! The film has a lot to like. I love how, for absolutely no reason, the cast members periodically break into song and dance numbers. I also like the general premise that the monarchy has long outlived its usefulness. Finally, the Butler is wonderful, as once he inherits his fortune he doesn't care one bit about propriety and tells EVERYONE exactly what he'd been hiding all those years--and delivers some very funny lines. But, I also feel irritated that such a lovely idea is, at times, squandered because the film just goes on and on and on and on. Someone really needed to look at this film and make a few judicious cuts here and there or say 'enough' when it lost momentum because scenes were just overdone or lacked comedic timing. This is especially true near the end--a portion that should have taken about ten minutes but took 40! And, frankly, the Jack the Ripper angle was handled in a very, very unfunny way--and it could have been hilarious. Overall, an interesting and compelling failure. By the way, the Rorschach cards used by the psychiatrist in the film are two of the actual cards from this test. It's rare to see real cards in films or TV.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Schizophrenic. . . in a good way!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dougmcnair
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is sometimes brilliant, sometimes silly, sometimes surreal, sometimes tragic, sometimes wickedly satirical, and always schizophrenic (which is the whole point). It's also the only film in which Jesus Christ does the Varsity Drag. Peter O'Toole plays the paranoid schizophrenic heir to an English earldom, and as his relatives try to either cure him or commit him, what we think is being played for laughs slowly becomes something far darker. O'Toole's performance is brilliant, bringing out this man's almost unbearable pain as he tries to hold his mind together by escaping into whatever fantasy world he can manage. Unfortunately, escaping into a world where he is God and everyone loves each other does not work for society, so his family has to snap him out of that so he can become acceptable. At its core, the film is about what kind of insanity (and what kind of god) is acceptable in upper-class British society, and it makes its points on that score very well. But unfortunately, it's far too long; there are so many supporting characters with their own subplots that it gets bogged down in many places. But if you can last through the slow parts, you'll be rewarded with some unforgettable scenes before the end. Seven stars.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Marvelous Gallery of Grotesques
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    raymundohpl
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I recently watched the uncut version of this film on Turner Classic Movies in the wee hours of the morning and thoroughly enjoyed the performances of all the actors in it with the exception of the lead character J.C./Jack played by the redoubtable Peter O'Toole. The plot of a mad lord(God knows that there are way too many of them by far in the House of Lords both in the past and present) who believes himself to be a benevolent, loving "Peace, Man" Jesus Christ who is subsequently driven by the "scientific" vile machinations of a crazed German psychiatrist(who ends up needing his own head examined)to become a "sane" Jack the Ripper, is buttressed by the superb performances of the supporting cast. Peter O'Toole's "Tour de Force" performance which for the most part lauded by the other reviewers here, is too over-the-top which works within the context of this film for his role but I found O'Toole shamelessly mugging and leering without restraint(indeed like a real madman) which again works accidentally within the context of this film. After O'Toole has been branded "sane" as Jack the Ripper there are several huge closeups of his wide staring eyes--I swear I thought I was watching Joan Crawford as "Mommie Dearest" glaring in her best Kabuki "Mie"-grimace before letting her "Strait-Jacket" axe descend for some satisfying mayhem. Harry Andrews as O'Toole's pater, the 13th Lord Gurney turns in a short but satisfying appearance in his rigid iron-jawed unpleasant upper-crusty sod who offs himself whilst wearing unflattering raiment, William Mervyn and Coral Browne play two of the Gurneys, the nastiest "upper class" scum dripping with self-importance and probably a leaky colostomy bag! Mervyn excelled in portraying snooty, "stiff-upper-lipped" pompous nabobs with their noses in the air though I presume he was not like that in real life; Coral was just doing what came naturally, playing herself, i.e., being a nasty, caustic-tongued man-hungry bitch who got her hooks into horror legend Vincent Price in reality as Vinnie's last wife, James Villers as his specialty, a gormless pathetic gangling twit, Nigel Green as an "Electric Jehovah"(Nigel offed himself after this role, his life imitated his F-art), Michael Bryant as the crazed unscrupulous German psychiatrist, Hugh Burden as the harried mousy lawyer(Mr. Reeder indeed!), Graham Crowden as a gimlet-eyed "sanity officer" who bursts into a lively duet of the Eton Boating Song with O'Toole, Arthur Lowe as the one sympathetic character in the whole film, the Bolshie old manservant who gets framed for the murder done by O'Toole, and last but not least, the great Alastair Sim as the doddering old Bishop, shaking and trembling in fear in the best Kierkegaardian manner. These supporting actors along with Kay Walsh and Patsy Byrne, all work very well together but O'Toole, purposely, I'm sure, strikes a jarring note in the whole film as the huge stinking turd floating in the middle of the punchbowl. You can't miss him but wish he were a little less noticeable! All in all, 10 Stars, Excellent All Around, even with O'Toole's shameless overacting, and chewing up the scenery, which I am sure was his original intent for the overall theme of this gem of a film. The director, Peter Medak(The Changeling, Species II, The Krays) does an absolutely rip-roaring job here and is to be highly commended for this film, which may indeed be his masterpiece!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "How do you know you're God?" ... "I found that in prayer I was talking to myself."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moonspinner55
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gross, frequently tasteless satire, much as if Kubrick's "Dr. Strangelove" were transplanted to England's House of Lords and then played at the wrong speed. After the Earl of Gurney accidentally kills himself during one of his fetish games, the 14th Earl--son Jack--is groomed to accept the crown. Once mad Jack--who believes himself to be Christ--undergoes a mental transformation on the night of his son's birth and self-metamorphoses into Jack the Ripper, the plot (thin to begin with) becomes a dartboard for the one-liners (some of which are very funny and are a compensation). Peter Barnes adapted his play for the screen, the kind of material upper-crust audiences like to label 'savage'; he was reciprocated with a game cast and a fine director in Peter Medak, yet these nutty fantasies are merely clotheslines for Barnes to hang his maddening soliloquies on. Peter O'Toole (with cartoony strawberry-blond hair) has some terrific moments early on, particularly in the musical send-ups, but later begins to bellow and rarely stops. The film is too full of targets, and too nasty overall, for its extreme length...it doesn't even look good. ** from ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Long but with some insanity to keep the cobwebs out. O'Toole is electric.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    secondtake
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Ruling Class (1972) This is a peculiar, long, hilarious and tedious movie, depending on your taste and probably your age. Parts of it have always made me perk up and laugh, but it works the same theme (of the exhaustion of the old British ways) to death. Peter O'Toole lets it all hang out here, for sure, as Jesus, and as a crazed new British Lord (including a famous final section where he gives a speech to the House of Lords, which is filled with cobwebbed skeletons). It's not really supposed to be haunting or scary, but it's slightly gruesome comedy is pointed, for sure. And funny. If you don't laugh or at least give a crooked smile to the battle between two men who think they are god--O'Toole as the Jesus God and Nigel Green as an Old Testament God, and the Electric Messiah (both). It's crazy and crazed and yet what else do you expect? Someone said it perfectly when they called it a "comedy with tragic relief." O'Toole won an Oscar for his efforts (and he played his part for free). The American version of the movie has 6 minutes missing, though probably the wrong 6 minutes. A good editing might remove an hour and have a faster and more punchy movie. Still, it is what it is, and there's nothing quite like it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pretentious and heavy handed ...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andrew Huggett
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'rich knobs and privileged a***holes can afford to be bonkers  ' The first 10 minutes or so of this film are quite interesting, with a good cast of British eccentrics (especially the splendid Alastair Sim and Arthur Lowe). I quite enjoyed the gathering at the start with the reading of the will and the arrival of the new Lord (and even the subsequent surreal song and dance routine with the ladies organising the local f&ecirc;te)  but it then descends into a complete pretentious mess. Very disappointing considering the talented actors deployed here. I nodded off just after Peter O'Toole had stopped thinking he was God and decided he was Jack the Ripper instead - this was partly because I'd had some wine with my meal, and not entirely down to the reactions this film provoked in me. The odd sequence at the end in the House of Lords reminded me of the final 2 episodes of the TV series 'the Prisoner' made 4 years prior to the release of this film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    good movie, brilliant Peter O'Toole
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    knightinarms
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I found the movie peculiar, at times it was simply enthralling, at times; it was a bit underwhelming, which makes it difficult for me to form a decided opinion of it especially as somebody who's not that familiar with that age or society. The charismatic Peter O' Toole shines gloriously through the course of it however; both as the frowned upon schizophrenic who believes he is Jesus Christ and as the revered headstrong aristocrat who secretly believes he is Jack the ripper.The movie which gradually becomes more and more satirical as it progresses symbolically connects the indifferent ruling class to the rise of such evils as Jack the ripper. A commendable acting performance from Peter O'Toole makes this symbolism all the more persuasive. Also, it shows how all the scheming manages to turn a harmless buffoon into a psychotic serial killer to the detriment of the perpetrators and his well wishers alike and how, upon this transition, he ironically gains acceptance into the society which had ridiculed him earlier. I would not go ahead and say its a 10 on 10 for me for there were instances where I felt a lack of continuity in the storyline, though its difficult to recall such incidents in particular, overall the movie didn't leave me as awestruck as some other movies which I've voted as a perfect 10. Its difficult to say how much of it was due to my lack of knowledge of that age or society and how much of it was due to gaps in the storyline itself. That said, the movie is definitely worth a watch, in fact, a second watch would be worth considering for somebody from outside of Britain, you might just pick up the odd joke you missed in the first viewing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bless Peter O'Toole! Bless the irreverent writer!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    CinefanR
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    They just don't make movies like this anymore! This is a delightfully insane, smart and ultimately unpredictable black comedy with Shakespearian and surrealistic undertones. It's great to finally see a script that does justice to Peter O'Toole's singular talents. A short description of the plot would be useless however, since the movie practically defies classification. The harsh criticism aimed at British aristocracy is merely a pretense for a deeper analysis of everything. Religion and freedom, love and happiness, "normality" and alienation, life and death, good and evil, society vs. the individual --- the human condition, basically--- everything is scrutinized and relentlessly exposed or challenged, with quirky humor, sarcasm, and - yes - compassion underneath it all. If you don't care for these topics, "then kindly leave the stage", says the hero. The splendid Peter O'Toole simply shines in this unconventional and difficult role, playing it to perfection and beyond. His intelligently nuanced tour-de-force performance is hilarious, disturbing and touching all together  "I'm being everybody", he says. Everything that comes out of Peter O'Toole's mouth has a Shakespearian ring to it. Everything about him has a distinctive elegance that is unparalleled to this day. The supporting cast is excellent; dialogs are cleverly built on multiple layers of symbolism; the music is fabulous. Each time you watch this movie, you'll pick up on something new. Well, there's much to be said, but watch it and judge for yourself. Get the full-length version of the movie, form Criterion Collection. "The Ruling Class" is a must-see, one of the best movies ever - timeless, profound, moving and truly unique.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A quirky fantasy becomes a turgid polemic over 2.5 hours
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What a sorry mess! "The Ruling Class" begins as full of promise and with wit and an irreverent willingness to defy convention and slowly (glacially!) mutates over its 2-1/2 hour running time into a directionless screed against Britain's aristocracy. Never willing to let the audience grasp their intentions on their own, again and again Peter Medak uses hamfisted characterizations and plot devices to convey author Peter Barnes' view that the titled in Britain are superficial, hypocritical, incestuous, calloused, categorically corrupt and evil, congenitally insane, the personification of Satan, and Jack the Ripper himself! And the members of the House of Lords? Why they're a bunch of stuffy old corpses. No, really! NO, REALLY! Every time you say to yourself "Yeah, I get it", the Two Peters reply "Oh, no you don't; not by a long shot!" and then proceed to tell you the same thing over and over and over and over and over again. Peter O'Toole is pretty good (although led down by comically bad make-up and wigs), but O'Toole is much better elsewhere. Unless you're an O'Toole completist, save yourself 2-1/2 hours of having tabloid-level editorializing rubbed in your face.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very accurate historically
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    baron_genitalstrassen
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Generally regarded as one of the best British horror films, The Ruling Class very nearly sank into obscurity shortly after being made. The film's distributors EMI disliked it so much that they wrote it off as a tax loss. Then Rod Stewart, who was married to Coral Browne at the time, allegedly tried to buy the negative so that he could have it destroyed - thereby preventing the public from seeing his wife in the nude. Fortunately, the film survived (though not in the way its director originally intended). The story focuses on a virginal 14th Earl of Gurney (O'Toole) who is exiled on a remote Scottish island. What he discovers, though, is he thinks he is Jesus Christ. It's a movie about religion, God, and the crisis of faith, with an ending that's either devoutly Christian (O'Toole's Jack Arnold Alexander Tancred Gurney continues praying right to the very end), or a nihilistic comment on God's absence from the universe. With such a colourful production history, "The Ruling Class" was always destined for fame. Yet its cult status actually has more to do with the film's content - there's a paedophile subplot, lots of occult rituals, sexual perversion, Alastair Sim in drag, and a resolutely downbeat finale that's as far removed from a happy ending as it's possible to get. And on top of all that, it's bloody scary. "The Ruling Class" is a movie that'll burn its way into your unconscious and give you nightmares for many years to come. "The Ruling Class" is also available in a 199-minute uncut version
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not a bad premise, but it's overly long and rather indulgent.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "The Ruling Class" is a film that is sure to offend--after all, the leading man (Peter O'Toole) thinks he is Jesus! Right away, this sort of idea eliminates many potential viewers who would just be too offended to see such a film--especially with scenes where O'Toole climbs up on a giant cross in his house in order to meditate or take a nap. Additionally, the film nails the final nails in the coffin of the traditional English class system--and probably offended quite a few tradition-bound Brits as well. As for me, I was less offended (especially in its skewering of the upper class) but more bothered because the execution of the plot left a bit to be desired. Specifically, it was overlong and overly indulgent. The film begins with the Earl of Gurney accidentally hanging himself while having a rant--during which he was wearing a tutu! Obviously, the guy was NOT in his right mind. However, his heir (O'Toole) is 100% bonkers--and thinks he's Jesus! Considering he's got a seat in the House of Lords the family thinks this is a serious problem! But they also want to have an heir and so they trick the new Earl into a marriage and a child is soon produced. Now that the heir is here, the family will either have O'Toole committed or cure him--they don't care which--they just know they can't have a loony representing the family in the House! The film has a lot to like. I love how, for absolutely no reason, the cast members periodically break into song and dance numbers. I also like the general premise that the monarchy has long outlived its usefulness. Finally, the Butler is wonderful, as once he inherits his fortune he doesn't care one bit about propriety and tells EVERYONE exactly what he'd been hiding all those years--and delivers some very funny lines. But, I also feel irritated that such a lovely idea is, at times, squandered because the film just goes on and on and on and on. Someone really needed to look at this film and make a few judicious cuts here and there or say 'enough' when it lost momentum because scenes were just overdone or lacked comedic timing. This is especially true near the end--a portion that should have taken about ten minutes but took 40! And, frankly, the Jack the Ripper angle was handled in a very, very unfunny way--and it could have been hilarious. Overall, an interesting and compelling failure. By the way, the Rorschach cards used by the psychiatrist in the film are two of the actual cards from this test. It's rare to see real cards in films or TV.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Schizophrenic. . . in a good way!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dougmcnair
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is sometimes brilliant, sometimes silly, sometimes surreal, sometimes tragic, sometimes wickedly satirical, and always schizophrenic (which is the whole point). It's also the only film in which Jesus Christ does the Varsity Drag. Peter O'Toole plays the paranoid schizophrenic heir to an English earldom, and as his relatives try to either cure him or commit him, what we think is being played for laughs slowly becomes something far darker. O'Toole's performance is brilliant, bringing out this man's almost unbearable pain as he tries to hold his mind together by escaping into whatever fantasy world he can manage. Unfortunately, escaping into a world where he is God and everyone loves each other does not work for society, so his family has to snap him out of that so he can become acceptable. At its core, the film is about what kind of insanity (and what kind of god) is acceptable in upper-class British society, and it makes its points on that score very well. But unfortunately, it's far too long; there are so many supporting characters with their own subplots that it gets bogged down in many places. But if you can last through the slow parts, you'll be rewarded with some unforgettable scenes before the end. Seven stars.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Marvelous Gallery of Grotesques
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    raymundohpl
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I recently watched the uncut version of this film on Turner Classic Movies in the wee hours of the morning and thoroughly enjoyed the performances of all the actors in it with the exception of the lead character J.C./Jack played by the redoubtable Peter O'Toole. The plot of a mad lord(God knows that there are way too many of them by far in the House of Lords both in the past and present) who believes himself to be a benevolent, loving "Peace, Man" Jesus Christ who is subsequently driven by the "scientific" vile machinations of a crazed German psychiatrist(who ends up needing his own head examined)to become a "sane" Jack the Ripper, is buttressed by the superb performances of the supporting cast. Peter O'Toole's "Tour de Force" performance which for the most part lauded by the other reviewers here, is too over-the-top which works within the context of this film for his role but I found O'Toole shamelessly mugging and leering without restraint(indeed like a real madman) which again works accidentally within the context of this film. After O'Toole has been branded "sane" as Jack the Ripper there are several huge closeups of his wide staring eyes--I swear I thought I was watching Joan Crawford as "Mommie Dearest" glaring in her best Kabuki "Mie"-grimace before letting her "Strait-Jacket" axe descend for some satisfying mayhem. Harry Andrews as O'Toole's pater, the 13th Lord Gurney turns in a short but satisfying appearance in his rigid iron-jawed unpleasant upper-crusty sod who offs himself whilst wearing unflattering raiment, William Mervyn and Coral Browne play two of the Gurneys, the nastiest "upper class" scum dripping with self-importance and probably a leaky colostomy bag! Mervyn excelled in portraying snooty, "stiff-upper-lipped" pompous nabobs with their noses in the air though I presume he was not like that in real life; Coral was just doing what came naturally, playing herself, i.e., being a nasty, caustic-tongued man-hungry bitch who got her hooks into horror legend Vincent Price in reality as Vinnie's last wife, James Villers as his specialty, a gormless pathetic gangling twit, Nigel Green as an "Electric Jehovah"(Nigel offed himself after this role, his life imitated his F-art), Michael Bryant as the crazed unscrupulous German psychiatrist, Hugh Burden as the harried mousy lawyer(Mr. Reeder indeed!), Graham Crowden as a gimlet-eyed "sanity officer" who bursts into a lively duet of the Eton Boating Song with O'Toole, Arthur Lowe as the one sympathetic character in the whole film, the Bolshie old manservant who gets framed for the murder done by O'Toole, and last but not least, the great Alastair Sim as the doddering old Bishop, shaking and trembling in fear in the best Kierkegaardian manner. These supporting actors along with Kay Walsh and Patsy Byrne, all work very well together but O'Toole, purposely, I'm sure, strikes a jarring note in the whole film as the huge stinking turd floating in the middle of the punchbowl. You can't miss him but wish he were a little less noticeable! All in all, 10 Stars, Excellent All Around, even with O'Toole's shameless overacting, and chewing up the scenery, which I am sure was his original intent for the overall theme of this gem of a film. The director, Peter Medak(The Changeling, Species II, The Krays) does an absolutely rip-roaring job here and is to be highly commended for this film, which may indeed be his masterpiece!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "How do you know you're God?" ... "I found that in prayer I was talking to myself."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moonspinner55
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gross, frequently tasteless satire, much as if Kubrick's "Dr. Strangelove" were transplanted to England's House of Lords and then played at the wrong speed. After the Earl of Gurney accidentally kills himself during one of his fetish games, the 14th Earl--son Jack--is groomed to accept the crown. Once mad Jack--who believes himself to be Christ--undergoes a mental transformation on the night of his son's birth and self-metamorphoses into Jack the Ripper, the plot (thin to begin with) becomes a dartboard for the one-liners (some of which are very funny and are a compensation). Peter Barnes adapted his play for the screen, the kind of material upper-crust audiences like to label 'savage'; he was reciprocated with a game cast and a fine director in Peter Medak, yet these nutty fantasies are merely clotheslines for Barnes to hang his maddening soliloquies on. Peter O'Toole (with cartoony strawberry-blond hair) has some terrific moments early on, particularly in the musical send-ups, but later begins to bellow and rarely stops. The film is too full of targets, and too nasty overall, for its extreme length...it doesn't even look good. ** from ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Long but with some insanity to keep the cobwebs out. O'Toole is electric.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    secondtake
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Ruling Class (1972) This is a peculiar, long, hilarious and tedious movie, depending on your taste and probably your age. Parts of it have always made me perk up and laugh, but it works the same theme (of the exhaustion of the old British ways) to death. Peter O'Toole lets it all hang out here, for sure, as Jesus, and as a crazed new British Lord (including a famous final section where he gives a speech to the House of Lords, which is filled with cobwebbed skeletons). It's not really supposed to be haunting or scary, but it's slightly gruesome comedy is pointed, for sure. And funny. If you don't laugh or at least give a crooked smile to the battle between two men who think they are god--O'Toole as the Jesus God and Nigel Green as an Old Testament God, and the Electric Messiah (both). It's crazy and crazed and yet what else do you expect? Someone said it perfectly when they called it a "comedy with tragic relief." O'Toole won an Oscar for his efforts (and he played his part for free). The American version of the movie has 6 minutes missing, though probably the wrong 6 minutes. A good editing might remove an hour and have a faster and more punchy movie. Still, it is what it is, and there's nothing quite like it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pretentious and heavy handed ...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andrew Huggett
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'rich knobs and privileged a***holes can afford to be bonkers  ' The first 10 minutes or so of this film are quite interesting, with a good cast of British eccentrics (especially the splendid Alastair Sim and Arthur Lowe). I quite enjoyed the gathering at the start with the reading of the will and the arrival of the new Lord (and even the subsequent surreal song and dance routine with the ladies organising the local f&ecirc;te)  but it then descends into a complete pretentious mess. Very disappointing considering the talented actors deployed here. I nodded off just after Peter O'Toole had stopped thinking he was God and decided he was Jack the Ripper instead - this was partly because I'd had some wine with my meal, and not entirely down to the reactions this film provoked in me. The odd sequence at the end in the House of Lords reminded me of the final 2 episodes of the TV series 'the Prisoner' made 4 years prior to the release of this film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    good movie, brilliant Peter O'Toole
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    knightinarms
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I found the movie peculiar, at times it was simply enthralling, at times; it was a bit underwhelming, which makes it difficult for me to form a decided opinion of it especially as somebody who's not that familiar with that age or society. The charismatic Peter O' Toole shines gloriously through the course of it however; both as the frowned upon schizophrenic who believes he is Jesus Christ and as the revered headstrong aristocrat who secretly believes he is Jack the ripper.The movie which gradually becomes more and more satirical as it progresses symbolically connects the indifferent ruling class to the rise of such evils as Jack the ripper. A commendable acting performance from Peter O'Toole makes this symbolism all the more persuasive. Also, it shows how all the scheming manages to turn a harmless buffoon into a psychotic serial killer to the detriment of the perpetrators and his well wishers alike and how, upon this transition, he ironically gains acceptance into the society which had ridiculed him earlier. I would not go ahead and say its a 10 on 10 for me for there were instances where I felt a lack of continuity in the storyline, though its difficult to recall such incidents in particular, overall the movie didn't leave me as awestruck as some other movies which I've voted as a perfect 10. Its difficult to say how much of it was due to my lack of knowledge of that age or society and how much of it was due to gaps in the storyline itself. That said, the movie is definitely worth a watch, in fact, a second watch would be worth considering for somebody from outside of Britain, you might just pick up the odd joke you missed in the first viewing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bless Peter O'Toole! Bless the irreverent writer!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    CinefanR
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    They just don't make movies like this anymore! This is a delightfully insane, smart and ultimately unpredictable black comedy with Shakespearian and surrealistic undertones. It's great to finally see a script that does justice to Peter O'Toole's singular talents. A short description of the plot would be useless however, since the movie practically defies classification. The harsh criticism aimed at British aristocracy is merely a pretense for a deeper analysis of everything. Religion and freedom, love and happiness, "normality" and alienation, life and death, good and evil, society vs. the individual --- the human condition, basically--- everything is scrutinized and relentlessly exposed or challenged, with quirky humor, sarcasm, and - yes - compassion underneath it all. If you don't care for these topics, "then kindly leave the stage", says the hero. The splendid Peter O'Toole simply shines in this unconventional and difficult role, playing it to perfection and beyond. His intelligently nuanced tour-de-force performance is hilarious, disturbing and touching all together  "I'm being everybody", he says. Everything that comes out of Peter O'Toole's mouth has a Shakespearian ring to it. Everything about him has a distinctive elegance that is unparalleled to this day. The supporting cast is excellent; dialogs are cleverly built on multiple layers of symbolism; the music is fabulous. Each time you watch this movie, you'll pick up on something new. Well, there's much to be said, but watch it and judge for yourself. Get the full-length version of the movie, form Criterion Collection. "The Ruling Class" is a must-see, one of the best movies ever - timeless, profound, moving and truly unique.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A quirky fantasy becomes a turgid polemic over 2.5 hours
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What a sorry mess! "The Ruling Class" begins as full of promise and with wit and an irreverent willingness to defy convention and slowly (glacially!) mutates over its 2-1/2 hour running time into a directionless screed against Britain's aristocracy. Never willing to let the audience grasp their intentions on their own, again and again Peter Medak uses hamfisted characterizations and plot devices to convey author Peter Barnes' view that the titled in Britain are superficial, hypocritical, incestuous, calloused, categorically corrupt and evil, congenitally insane, the personification of Satan, and Jack the Ripper himself! And the members of the House of Lords? Why they're a bunch of stuffy old corpses. No, really! NO, REALLY! Every time you say to yourself "Yeah, I get it", the Two Peters reply "Oh, no you don't; not by a long shot!" and then proceed to tell you the same thing over and over and over and over and over again. Peter O'Toole is pretty good (although led down by comically bad make-up and wigs), but O'Toole is much better elsewhere. Unless you're an O'Toole completist, save yourself 2-1/2 hours of having tabloid-level editorializing rubbed in your face.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very accurate historically
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    baron_genitalstrassen
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Generally regarded as one of the best British horror films, The Ruling Class very nearly sank into obscurity shortly after being made. The film's distributors EMI disliked it so much that they wrote it off as a tax loss. Then Rod Stewart, who was married to Coral Browne at the time, allegedly tried to buy the negative so that he could have it destroyed - thereby preventing the public from seeing his wife in the nude. Fortunately, the film survived (though not in the way its director originally intended). The story focuses on a virginal 14th Earl of Gurney (O'Toole) who is exiled on a remote Scottish island. What he discovers, though, is he thinks he is Jesus Christ. It's a movie about religion, God, and the crisis of faith, with an ending that's either devoutly Christian (O'Toole's Jack Arnold Alexander Tancred Gurney continues praying right to the very end), or a nihilistic comment on God's absence from the universe. With such a colourful production history, "The Ruling Class" was always destined for fame. Yet its cult status actually has more to do with the film's content - there's a paedophile subplot, lots of occult rituals, sexual perversion, Alastair Sim in drag, and a resolutely downbeat finale that's as far removed from a happy ending as it's possible to get. And on top of all that, it's bloody scary. "The Ruling Class" is a movie that'll burn its way into your unconscious and give you nightmares for many years to come. "The Ruling Class" is also available in a 199-minute uncut version
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not a bad premise, but it's overly long and rather indulgent.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "The Ruling Class" is a film that is sure to offend--after all, the leading man (Peter O'Toole) thinks he is Jesus! Right away, this sort of idea eliminates many potential viewers who would just be too offended to see such a film--especially with scenes where O'Toole climbs up on a giant cross in his house in order to meditate or take a nap. Additionally, the film nails the final nails in the coffin of the traditional English class system--and probably offended quite a few tradition-bound Brits as well. As for me, I was less offended (especially in its skewering of the upper class) but more bothered because the execution of the plot left a bit to be desired. Specifically, it was overlong and overly indulgent. The film begins with the Earl of Gurney accidentally hanging himself while having a rant--during which he was wearing a tutu! Obviously, the guy was NOT in his right mind. However, his heir (O'Toole) is 100% bonkers--and thinks he's Jesus! Considering he's got a seat in the House of Lords the family thinks this is a serious problem! But they also want to have an heir and so they trick the new Earl into a marriage and a child is soon produced. Now that the heir is here, the family will either have O'Toole committed or cure him--they don't care which--they just know they can't have a loony representing the family in the House! The film has a lot to like. I love how, for absolutely no reason, the cast members periodically break into song and dance numbers. I also like the general premise that the monarchy has long outlived its usefulness. Finally, the Butler is wonderful, as once he inherits his fortune he doesn't care one bit about propriety and tells EVERYONE exactly what he'd been hiding all those years--and delivers some very funny lines. But, I also feel irritated that such a lovely idea is, at times, squandered because the film just goes on and on and on and on. Someone really needed to look at this film and make a few judicious cuts here and there or say 'enough' when it lost momentum because scenes were just overdone or lacked comedic timing. This is especially true near the end--a portion that should have taken about ten minutes but took 40! And, frankly, the Jack the Ripper angle was handled in a very, very unfunny way--and it could have been hilarious. Overall, an interesting and compelling failure. By the way, the Rorschach cards used by the psychiatrist in the film are two of the actual cards from this test. It's rare to see real cards in films or TV.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Schizophrenic. . . in a good way!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dougmcnair
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is sometimes brilliant, sometimes silly, sometimes surreal, sometimes tragic, sometimes wickedly satirical, and always schizophrenic (which is the whole point). It's also the only film in which Jesus Christ does the Varsity Drag. Peter O'Toole plays the paranoid schizophrenic heir to an English earldom, and as his relatives try to either cure him or commit him, what we think is being played for laughs slowly becomes something far darker. O'Toole's performance is brilliant, bringing out this man's almost unbearable pain as he tries to hold his mind together by escaping into whatever fantasy world he can manage. Unfortunately, escaping into a world where he is God and everyone loves each other does not work for society, so his family has to snap him out of that so he can become acceptable. At its core, the film is about what kind of insanity (and what kind of god) is acceptable in upper-class British society, and it makes its points on that score very well. But unfortunately, it's far too long; there are so many supporting characters with their own subplots that it gets bogged down in many places. But if you can last through the slow parts, you'll be rewarded with some unforgettable scenes before the end. Seven stars.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Marvelous Gallery of Grotesques
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    raymundohpl
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I recently watched the uncut version of this film on Turner Classic Movies in the wee hours of the morning and thoroughly enjoyed the performances of all the actors in it with the exception of the lead character J.C./Jack played by the redoubtable Peter O'Toole. The plot of a mad lord(God knows that there are way too many of them by far in the House of Lords both in the past and present) who believes himself to be a benevolent, loving "Peace, Man" Jesus Christ who is subsequently driven by the "scientific" vile machinations of a crazed German psychiatrist(who ends up needing his own head examined)to become a "sane" Jack the Ripper, is buttressed by the superb performances of the supporting cast. Peter O'Toole's "Tour de Force" performance which for the most part lauded by the other reviewers here, is too over-the-top which works within the context of this film for his role but I found O'Toole shamelessly mugging and leering without restraint(indeed like a real madman) which again works accidentally within the context of this film. After O'Toole has been branded "sane" as Jack the Ripper there are several huge closeups of his wide staring eyes--I swear I thought I was watching Joan Crawford as "Mommie Dearest" glaring in her best Kabuki "Mie"-grimace before letting her "Strait-Jacket" axe descend for some satisfying mayhem. Harry Andrews as O'Toole's pater, the 13th Lord Gurney turns in a short but satisfying appearance in his rigid iron-jawed unpleasant upper-crusty sod who offs himself whilst wearing unflattering raiment, William Mervyn and Coral Browne play two of the Gurneys, the nastiest "upper class" scum dripping with self-importance and probably a leaky colostomy bag! Mervyn excelled in portraying snooty, "stiff-upper-lipped" pompous nabobs with their noses in the air though I presume he was not like that in real life; Coral was just doing what came naturally, playing herself, i.e., being a nasty, caustic-tongued man-hungry bitch who got her hooks into horror legend Vincent Price in reality as Vinnie's last wife, James Villers as his specialty, a gormless pathetic gangling twit, Nigel Green as an "Electric Jehovah"(Nigel offed himself after this role, his life imitated his F-art), Michael Bryant as the crazed unscrupulous German psychiatrist, Hugh Burden as the harried mousy lawyer(Mr. Reeder indeed!), Graham Crowden as a gimlet-eyed "sanity officer" who bursts into a lively duet of the Eton Boating Song with O'Toole, Arthur Lowe as the one sympathetic character in the whole film, the Bolshie old manservant who gets framed for the murder done by O'Toole, and last but not least, the great Alastair Sim as the doddering old Bishop, shaking and trembling in fear in the best Kierkegaardian manner. These supporting actors along with Kay Walsh and Patsy Byrne, all work very well together but O'Toole, purposely, I'm sure, strikes a jarring note in the whole film as the huge stinking turd floating in the middle of the punchbowl. You can't miss him but wish he were a little less noticeable! All in all, 10 Stars, Excellent All Around, even with O'Toole's shameless overacting, and chewing up the scenery, which I am sure was his original intent for the overall theme of this gem of a film. The director, Peter Medak(The Changeling, Species II, The Krays) does an absolutely rip-roaring job here and is to be highly commended for this film, which may indeed be his masterpiece!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "How do you know you're God?" ... "I found that in prayer I was talking to myself."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moonspinner55
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gross, frequently tasteless satire, much as if Kubrick's "Dr. Strangelove" were transplanted to England's House of Lords and then played at the wrong speed. After the Earl of Gurney accidentally kills himself during one of his fetish games, the 14th Earl--son Jack--is groomed to accept the crown. Once mad Jack--who believes himself to be Christ--undergoes a mental transformation on the night of his son's birth and self-metamorphoses into Jack the Ripper, the plot (thin to begin with) becomes a dartboard for the one-liners (some of which are very funny and are a compensation). Peter Barnes adapted his play for the screen, the kind of material upper-crust audiences like to label 'savage'; he was reciprocated with a game cast and a fine director in Peter Medak, yet these nutty fantasies are merely clotheslines for Barnes to hang his maddening soliloquies on. Peter O'Toole (with cartoony strawberry-blond hair) has some terrific moments early on, particularly in the musical send-ups, but later begins to bellow and rarely stops. The film is too full of targets, and too nasty overall, for its extreme length...it doesn't even look good. ** from ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Long but with some insanity to keep the cobwebs out. O'Toole is electric.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    secondtake
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Ruling Class (1972) This is a peculiar, long, hilarious and tedious movie, depending on your taste and probably your age. Parts of it have always made me perk up and laugh, but it works the same theme (of the exhaustion of the old British ways) to death. Peter O'Toole lets it all hang out here, for sure, as Jesus, and as a crazed new British Lord (including a famous final section where he gives a speech to the House of Lords, which is filled with cobwebbed skeletons). It's not really supposed to be haunting or scary, but it's slightly gruesome comedy is pointed, for sure. And funny. If you don't laugh or at least give a crooked smile to the battle between two men who think they are god--O'Toole as the Jesus God and Nigel Green as an Old Testament God, and the Electric Messiah (both). It's crazy and crazed and yet what else do you expect? Someone said it perfectly when they called it a "comedy with tragic relief." O'Toole won an Oscar for his efforts (and he played his part for free). The American version of the movie has 6 minutes missing, though probably the wrong 6 minutes. A good editing might remove an hour and have a faster and more punchy movie. Still, it is what it is, and there's nothing quite like it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pretentious and heavy handed ...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andrew Huggett
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'rich knobs and privileged a***holes can afford to be bonkers  ' The first 10 minutes or so of this film are quite interesting, with a good cast of British eccentrics (especially the splendid Alastair Sim and Arthur Lowe). I quite enjoyed the gathering at the start with the reading of the will and the arrival of the new Lord (and even the subsequent surreal song and dance routine with the ladies organising the local f&ecirc;te)  but it then descends into a complete pretentious mess. Very disappointing considering the talented actors deployed here. I nodded off just after Peter O'Toole had stopped thinking he was God and decided he was Jack the Ripper instead - this was partly because I'd had some wine with my meal, and not entirely down to the reactions this film provoked in me. The odd sequence at the end in the House of Lords reminded me of the final 2 episodes of the TV series 'the Prisoner' made 4 years prior to the release of this film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    good movie, brilliant Peter O'Toole
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    knightinarms
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I found the movie peculiar, at times it was simply enthralling, at times; it was a bit underwhelming, which makes it difficult for me to form a decided opinion of it especially as somebody who's not that familiar with that age or society. The charismatic Peter O' Toole shines gloriously through the course of it however; both as the frowned upon schizophrenic who believes he is Jesus Christ and as the revered headstrong aristocrat who secretly believes he is Jack the ripper.The movie which gradually becomes more and more satirical as it progresses symbolically connects the indifferent ruling class to the rise of such evils as Jack the ripper. A commendable acting performance from Peter O'Toole makes this symbolism all the more persuasive. Also, it shows how all the scheming manages to turn a harmless buffoon into a psychotic serial killer to the detriment of the perpetrators and his well wishers alike and how, upon this transition, he ironically gains acceptance into the society which had ridiculed him earlier. I would not go ahead and say its a 10 on 10 for me for there were instances where I felt a lack of continuity in the storyline, though its difficult to recall such incidents in particular, overall the movie didn't leave me as awestruck as some other movies which I've voted as a perfect 10. Its difficult to say how much of it was due to my lack of knowledge of that age or society and how much of it was due to gaps in the storyline itself. That said, the movie is definitely worth a watch, in fact, a second watch would be worth considering for somebody from outside of Britain, you might just pick up the odd joke you missed in the first viewing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bless Peter O'Toole! Bless the irreverent writer!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    CinefanR
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    They just don't make movies like this anymore! This is a delightfully insane, smart and ultimately unpredictable black comedy with Shakespearian and surrealistic undertones. It's great to finally see a script that does justice to Peter O'Toole's singular talents. A short description of the plot would be useless however, since the movie practically defies classification. The harsh criticism aimed at British aristocracy is merely a pretense for a deeper analysis of everything. Religion and freedom, love and happiness, "normality" and alienation, life and death, good and evil, society vs. the individual --- the human condition, basically--- everything is scrutinized and relentlessly exposed or challenged, with quirky humor, sarcasm, and - yes - compassion underneath it all. If you don't care for these topics, "then kindly leave the stage", says the hero. The splendid Peter O'Toole simply shines in this unconventional and difficult role, playing it to perfection and beyond. His intelligently nuanced tour-de-force performance is hilarious, disturbing and touching all together  "I'm being everybody", he says. Everything that comes out of Peter O'Toole's mouth has a Shakespearian ring to it. Everything about him has a distinctive elegance that is unparalleled to this day. The supporting cast is excellent; dialogs are cleverly built on multiple layers of symbolism; the music is fabulous. Each time you watch this movie, you'll pick up on something new. Well, there's much to be said, but watch it and judge for yourself. Get the full-length version of the movie, form Criterion Collection. "The Ruling Class" is a must-see, one of the best movies ever - timeless, profound, moving and truly unique.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A quirky fantasy becomes a turgid polemic over 2.5 hours
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What a sorry mess! "The Ruling Class" begins as full of promise and with wit and an irreverent willingness to defy convention and slowly (glacially!) mutates over its 2-1/2 hour running time into a directionless screed against Britain's aristocracy. Never willing to let the audience grasp their intentions on their own, again and again Peter Medak uses hamfisted characterizations and plot devices to convey author Peter Barnes' view that the titled in Britain are superficial, hypocritical, incestuous, calloused, categorically corrupt and evil, congenitally insane, the personification of Satan, and Jack the Ripper himself! And the members of the House of Lords? Why they're a bunch of stuffy old corpses. No, really! NO, REALLY! Every time you say to yourself "Yeah, I get it", the Two Peters reply "Oh, no you don't; not by a long shot!" and then proceed to tell you the same thing over and over and over and over and over again. Peter O'Toole is pretty good (although led down by comically bad make-up and wigs), but O'Toole is much better elsewhere. Unless you're an O'Toole completist, save yourself 2-1/2 hours of having tabloid-level editorializing rubbed in your face.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very accurate historically
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    baron_genitalstrassen
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Generally regarded as one of the best British horror films, The Ruling Class very nearly sank into obscurity shortly after being made. The film's distributors EMI disliked it so much that they wrote it off as a tax loss. Then Rod Stewart, who was married to Coral Browne at the time, allegedly tried to buy the negative so that he could have it destroyed - thereby preventing the public from seeing his wife in the nude. Fortunately, the film survived (though not in the way its director originally intended). The story focuses on a virginal 14th Earl of Gurney (O'Toole) who is exiled on a remote Scottish island. What he discovers, though, is he thinks he is Jesus Christ. It's a movie about religion, God, and the crisis of faith, with an ending that's either devoutly Christian (O'Toole's Jack Arnold Alexander Tancred Gurney continues praying right to the very end), or a nihilistic comment on God's absence from the universe. With such a colourful production history, "The Ruling Class" was always destined for fame. Yet its cult status actually has more to do with the film's content - there's a paedophile subplot, lots of occult rituals, sexual perversion, Alastair Sim in drag, and a resolutely downbeat finale that's as far removed from a happy ending as it's possible to get. And on top of all that, it's bloody scary. "The Ruling Class" is a movie that'll burn its way into your unconscious and give you nightmares for many years to come. "The Ruling Class" is also available in a 199-minute uncut version
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not a bad premise, but it's overly long and rather indulgent.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "The Ruling Class" is a film that is sure to offend--after all, the leading man (Peter O'Toole) thinks he is Jesus! Right away, this sort of idea eliminates many potential viewers who would just be too offended to see such a film--especially with scenes where O'Toole climbs up on a giant cross in his house in order to meditate or take a nap. Additionally, the film nails the final nails in the coffin of the traditional English class system--and probably offended quite a few tradition-bound Brits as well. As for me, I was less offended (especially in its skewering of the upper class) but more bothered because the execution of the plot left a bit to be desired. Specifically, it was overlong and overly indulgent. The film begins with the Earl of Gurney accidentally hanging himself while having a rant--during which he was wearing a tutu! Obviously, the guy was NOT in his right mind. However, his heir (O'Toole) is 100% bonkers--and thinks he's Jesus! Considering he's got a seat in the House of Lords the family thinks this is a serious problem! But they also want to have an heir and so they trick the new Earl into a marriage and a child is soon produced. Now that the heir is here, the family will either have O'Toole committed or cure him--they don't care which--they just know they can't have a loony representing the family in the House! The film has a lot to like. I love how, for absolutely no reason, the cast members periodically break into song and dance numbers. I also like the general premise that the monarchy has long outlived its usefulness. Finally, the Butler is wonderful, as once he inherits his fortune he doesn't care one bit about propriety and tells EVERYONE exactly what he'd been hiding all those years--and delivers some very funny lines. But, I also feel irritated that such a lovely idea is, at times, squandered because the film just goes on and on and on and on. Someone really needed to look at this film and make a few judicious cuts here and there or say 'enough' when it lost momentum because scenes were just overdone or lacked comedic timing. This is especially true near the end--a portion that should have taken about ten minutes but took 40! And, frankly, the Jack the Ripper angle was handled in a very, very unfunny way--and it could have been hilarious. Overall, an interesting and compelling failure. By the way, the Rorschach cards used by the psychiatrist in the film are two of the actual cards from this test. It's rare to see real cards in films or TV.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Schizophrenic. . . in a good way!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dougmcnair
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is sometimes brilliant, sometimes silly, sometimes surreal, sometimes tragic, sometimes wickedly satirical, and always schizophrenic (which is the whole point). It's also the only film in which Jesus Christ does the Varsity Drag. Peter O'Toole plays the paranoid schizophrenic heir to an English earldom, and as his relatives try to either cure him or commit him, what we think is being played for laughs slowly becomes something far darker. O'Toole's performance is brilliant, bringing out this man's almost unbearable pain as he tries to hold his mind together by escaping into whatever fantasy world he can manage. Unfortunately, escaping into a world where he is God and everyone loves each other does not work for society, so his family has to snap him out of that so he can become acceptable. At its core, the film is about what kind of insanity (and what kind of god) is acceptable in upper-class British society, and it makes its points on that score very well. But unfortunately, it's far too long; there are so many supporting characters with their own subplots that it gets bogged down in many places. But if you can last through the slow parts, you'll be rewarded with some unforgettable scenes before the end. Seven stars.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Marvelous Gallery of Grotesques
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    raymundohpl
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I recently watched the uncut version of this film on Turner Classic Movies in the wee hours of the morning and thoroughly enjoyed the performances of all the actors in it with the exception of the lead character J.C./Jack played by the redoubtable Peter O'Toole. The plot of a mad lord(God knows that there are way too many of them by far in the House of Lords both in the past and present) who believes himself to be a benevolent, loving "Peace, Man" Jesus Christ who is subsequently driven by the "scientific" vile machinations of a crazed German psychiatrist(who ends up needing his own head examined)to become a "sane" Jack the Ripper, is buttressed by the superb performances of the supporting cast. Peter O'Toole's "Tour de Force" performance which for the most part lauded by the other reviewers here, is too over-the-top which works within the context of this film for his role but I found O'Toole shamelessly mugging and leering without restraint(indeed like a real madman) which again works accidentally within the context of this film. After O'Toole has been branded "sane" as Jack the Ripper there are several huge closeups of his wide staring eyes--I swear I thought I was watching Joan Crawford as "Mommie Dearest" glaring in her best Kabuki "Mie"-grimace before letting her "Strait-Jacket" axe descend for some satisfying mayhem. Harry Andrews as O'Toole's pater, the 13th Lord Gurney turns in a short but satisfying appearance in his rigid iron-jawed unpleasant upper-crusty sod who offs himself whilst wearing unflattering raiment, William Mervyn and Coral Browne play two of the Gurneys, the nastiest "upper class" scum dripping with self-importance and probably a leaky colostomy bag! Mervyn excelled in portraying snooty, "stiff-upper-lipped" pompous nabobs with their noses in the air though I presume he was not like that in real life; Coral was just doing what came naturally, playing herself, i.e., being a nasty, caustic-tongued man-hungry bitch who got her hooks into horror legend Vincent Price in reality as Vinnie's last wife, James Villers as his specialty, a gormless pathetic gangling twit, Nigel Green as an "Electric Jehovah"(Nigel offed himself after this role, his life imitated his F-art), Michael Bryant as the crazed unscrupulous German psychiatrist, Hugh Burden as the harried mousy lawyer(Mr. Reeder indeed!), Graham Crowden as a gimlet-eyed "sanity officer" who bursts into a lively duet of the Eton Boating Song with O'Toole, Arthur Lowe as the one sympathetic character in the whole film, the Bolshie old manservant who gets framed for the murder done by O'Toole, and last but not least, the great Alastair Sim as the doddering old Bishop, shaking and trembling in fear in the best Kierkegaardian manner. These supporting actors along with Kay Walsh and Patsy Byrne, all work very well together but O'Toole, purposely, I'm sure, strikes a jarring note in the whole film as the huge stinking turd floating in the middle of the punchbowl. You can't miss him but wish he were a little less noticeable! All in all, 10 Stars, Excellent All Around, even with O'Toole's shameless overacting, and chewing up the scenery, which I am sure was his original intent for the overall theme of this gem of a film. The director, Peter Medak(The Changeling, Species II, The Krays) does an absolutely rip-roaring job here and is to be highly commended for this film, which may indeed be his masterpiece!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "How do you know you're God?" ... "I found that in prayer I was talking to myself."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moonspinner55
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gross, frequently tasteless satire, much as if Kubrick's "Dr. Strangelove" were transplanted to England's House of Lords and then played at the wrong speed. After the Earl of Gurney accidentally kills himself during one of his fetish games, the 14th Earl--son Jack--is groomed to accept the crown. Once mad Jack--who believes himself to be Christ--undergoes a mental transformation on the night of his son's birth and self-metamorphoses into Jack the Ripper, the plot (thin to begin with) becomes a dartboard for the one-liners (some of which are very funny and are a compensation). Peter Barnes adapted his play for the screen, the kind of material upper-crust audiences like to label 'savage'; he was reciprocated with a game cast and a fine director in Peter Medak, yet these nutty fantasies are merely clotheslines for Barnes to hang his maddening soliloquies on. Peter O'Toole (with cartoony strawberry-blond hair) has some terrific moments early on, particularly in the musical send-ups, but later begins to bellow and rarely stops. The film is too full of targets, and too nasty overall, for its extreme length...it doesn't even look good. ** from ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Long but with some insanity to keep the cobwebs out. O'Toole is electric.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    secondtake
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Ruling Class (1972) This is a peculiar, long, hilarious and tedious movie, depending on your taste and probably your age. Parts of it have always made me perk up and laugh, but it works the same theme (of the exhaustion of the old British ways) to death. Peter O'Toole lets it all hang out here, for sure, as Jesus, and as a crazed new British Lord (including a famous final section where he gives a speech to the House of Lords, which is filled with cobwebbed skeletons). It's not really supposed to be haunting or scary, but it's slightly gruesome comedy is pointed, for sure. And funny. If you don't laugh or at least give a crooked smile to the battle between two men who think they are god--O'Toole as the Jesus God and Nigel Green as an Old Testament God, and the Electric Messiah (both). It's crazy and crazed and yet what else do you expect? Someone said it perfectly when they called it a "comedy with tragic relief." O'Toole won an Oscar for his efforts (and he played his part for free). The American version of the movie has 6 minutes missing, though probably the wrong 6 minutes. A good editing might remove an hour and have a faster and more punchy movie. Still, it is what it is, and there's nothing quite like it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pretentious and heavy handed ...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Andrew Huggett
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    'rich knobs and privileged a***holes can afford to be bonkers  ' The first 10 minutes or so of this film are quite interesting, with a good cast of British eccentrics (especially the splendid Alastair Sim and Arthur Lowe). I quite enjoyed the gathering at the start with the reading of the will and the arrival of the new Lord (and even the subsequent surreal song and dance routine with the ladies organising the local f&ecirc;te)  but it then descends into a complete pretentious mess. Very disappointing considering the talented actors deployed here. I nodded off just after Peter O'Toole had stopped thinking he was God and decided he was Jack the Ripper instead - this was partly because I'd had some wine with my meal, and not entirely down to the reactions this film provoked in me. The odd sequence at the end in the House of Lords reminded me of the final 2 episodes of the TV series 'the Prisoner' made 4 years prior to the release of this film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    good movie, brilliant Peter O'Toole
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    knightinarms
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I found the movie peculiar, at times it was simply enthralling, at times; it was a bit underwhelming, which makes it difficult for me to form a decided opinion of it especially as somebody who's not that familiar with that age or society. The charismatic Peter O' Toole shines gloriously through the course of it however; both as the frowned upon schizophrenic who believes he is Jesus Christ and as the revered headstrong aristocrat who secretly believes he is Jack the ripper.The movie which gradually becomes more and more satirical as it progresses symbolically connects the indifferent ruling class to the rise of such evils as Jack the ripper. A commendable acting performance from Peter O'Toole makes this symbolism all the more persuasive. Also, it shows how all the scheming manages to turn a harmless buffoon into a psychotic serial killer to the detriment of the perpetrators and his well wishers alike and how, upon this transition, he ironically gains acceptance into the society which had ridiculed him earlier. I would not go ahead and say its a 10 on 10 for me for there were instances where I felt a lack of continuity in the storyline, though its difficult to recall such incidents in particular, overall the movie didn't leave me as awestruck as some other movies which I've voted as a perfect 10. Its difficult to say how much of it was due to my lack of knowledge of that age or society and how much of it was due to gaps in the storyline itself. That said, the movie is definitely worth a watch, in fact, a second watch would be worth considering for somebody from outside of Britain, you might just pick up the odd joke you missed in the first viewing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Bless Peter O'Toole! Bless the irreverent writer!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    CinefanR
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    They just don't make movies like this anymore! This is a delightfully insane, smart and ultimately unpredictable black comedy with Shakespearian and surrealistic undertones. It's great to finally see a script that does justice to Peter O'Toole's singular talents. A short description of the plot would be useless however, since the movie practically defies classification. The harsh criticism aimed at British aristocracy is merely a pretense for a deeper analysis of everything. Religion and freedom, love and happiness, "normality" and alienation, life and death, good and evil, society vs. the individual --- the human condition, basically--- everything is scrutinized and relentlessly exposed or challenged, with quirky humor, sarcasm, and - yes - compassion underneath it all. If you don't care for these topics, "then kindly leave the stage", says the hero. The splendid Peter O'Toole simply shines in this unconventional and difficult role, playing it to perfection and beyond. His intelligently nuanced tour-de-force performance is hilarious, disturbing and touching all together  "I'm being everybody", he says. Everything that comes out of Peter O'Toole's mouth has a Shakespearian ring to it. Everything about him has a distinctive elegance that is unparalleled to this day. The supporting cast is excellent; dialogs are cleverly built on multiple layers of symbolism; the music is fabulous. Each time you watch this movie, you'll pick up on something new. Well, there's much to be said, but watch it and judge for yourself. Get the full-length version of the movie, form Criterion Collection. "The Ruling Class" is a must-see, one of the best movies ever - timeless, profound, moving and truly unique.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A quirky fantasy becomes a turgid polemic over 2.5 hours
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What a sorry mess! "The Ruling Class" begins as full of promise and with wit and an irreverent willingness to defy convention and slowly (glacially!) mutates over its 2-1/2 hour running time into a directionless screed against Britain's aristocracy. Never willing to let the audience grasp their intentions on their own, again and again Peter Medak uses hamfisted characterizations and plot devices to convey author Peter Barnes' view that the titled in Britain are superficial, hypocritical, incestuous, calloused, categorically corrupt and evil, congenitally insane, the personification of Satan, and Jack the Ripper himself! And the members of the House of Lords? Why they're a bunch of stuffy old corpses. No, really! NO, REALLY! Every time you say to yourself "Yeah, I get it", the Two Peters reply "Oh, no you don't; not by a long shot!" and then proceed to tell you the same thing over and over and over and over and over again. Peter O'Toole is pretty good (although led down by comically bad make-up and wigs), but O'Toole is much better elsewhere. Unless you're an O'Toole completist, save yourself 2-1/2 hours of having tabloid-level editorializing rubbed in your face.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very accurate historically
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    baron_genitalstrassen
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Generally regarded as one of the best British horror films, The Ruling Class very nearly sank into obscurity shortly after being made. The film's distributors EMI disliked it so much that they wrote it off as a tax loss. Then Rod Stewart, who was married to Coral Browne at the time, allegedly tried to buy the negative so that he could have it destroyed - thereby preventing the public from seeing his wife in the nude. Fortunately, the film survived (though not in the way its director originally intended). The story focuses on a virginal 14th Earl of Gurney (O'Toole) who is exiled on a remote Scottish island. What he discovers, though, is he thinks he is Jesus Christ. It's a movie about religion, God, and the crisis of faith, with an ending that's either devoutly Christian (O'Toole's Jack Arnold Alexander Tancred Gurney continues praying right to the very end), or a nihilistic comment on God's absence from the universe. With such a colourful production history, "The Ruling Class" was always destined for fame. Yet its cult status actually has more to do with the film's content - there's a paedophile subplot, lots of occult rituals, sexual perversion, Alastair Sim in drag, and a resolutely downbeat finale that's as far removed from a happy ending as it's possible to get. And on top of all that, it's bloody scary. "The Ruling Class" is a movie that'll burn its way into your unconscious and give you nightmares for many years to come. "The Ruling Class" is also available in a 199-minute uncut version
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Not a bad premise, but it's overly long and rather indulgent.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "The Ruling Class" is a film that is sure to offend--after all, the leading man (Peter O'Toole) thinks he is Jesus! Right away, this sort of idea eliminates many potential viewers who would just be too offended to see such a film--especially with scenes where O'Toole climbs up on a giant cross in his house in order to meditate or take a nap. Additionally, the film nails the final nails in the coffin of the traditional English class system--and probably offended quite a few tradition-bound Brits as well. As for me, I was less offended (especially in its skewering of the upper class) but more bothered because the execution of the plot left a bit to be desired. Specifically, it was overlong and overly indulgent. The film begins with the Earl of Gurney accidentally hanging himself while having a rant--during which he was wearing a tutu! Obviously, the guy was NOT in his right mind. However, his heir (O'Toole) is 100% bonkers--and thinks he's Jesus! Considering he's got a seat in the House of Lords the family thinks this is a serious problem! But they also want to have an heir and so they trick the new Earl into a marriage and a child is soon produced. Now that the heir is here, the family will either have O'Toole committed or cure him--they don't care which--they just know they can't have a loony representing the family in the House! The film has a lot to like. I love how, for absolutely no reason, the cast members periodically break into song and dance numbers. I also like the general premise that the monarchy has long outlived its usefulness. Finally, the Butler is wonderful, as once he inherits his fortune he doesn't care one bit about propriety and tells EVERYONE exactly what he'd been hiding all those years--and delivers some very funny lines. But, I also feel irritated that such a lovely idea is, at times, squandered because the film just goes on and on and on and on. Someone really needed to look at this film and make a few judicious cuts here and there or say 'enough' when it lost momentum because scenes were just overdone or lacked comedic timing. This is especially true near the end--a portion that should have taken about ten minutes but took 40! And, frankly, the Jack the Ripper angle was handled in a very, very unfunny way--and it could have been hilarious. Overall, an interesting and compelling failure. By the way, the Rorschach cards used by the psychiatrist in the film are two of the actual cards from this test. It's rare to see real cards in films or TV.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Schizophrenic. . . in a good way!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    dougmcnair
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is sometimes brilliant, sometimes silly, sometimes surreal, sometimes tragic, sometimes wickedly satirical, and always schizophrenic (which is the whole point). It's also the only film in which Jesus Christ does the Varsity Drag. Peter O'Toole plays the paranoid schizophrenic heir to an English earldom, and as his relatives try to either cure him or commit him, what we think is being played for laughs slowly becomes something far darker. O'Toole's performance is brilliant, bringing out this man's almost unbearable pain as he tries to hold his mind together by escaping into whatever fantasy world he can manage. Unfortunately, escaping into a world where he is God and everyone loves each other does not work for society, so his family has to snap him out of that so he can become acceptable. At its core, the film is about what kind of insanity (and what kind of god) is acceptable in upper-class British society, and it makes its points on that score very well. But unfortunately, it's far too long; there are so many supporting characters with their own subplots that it gets bogged down in many places. But if you can last through the slow parts, you'll be rewarded with some unforgettable scenes before the end. Seven stars.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Marvelous Gallery of Grotesques
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    raymundohpl
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/2/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I recently watched the uncut version of this film on Turner Classic Movies in the wee hours of the morning and thoroughly enjoyed the performances of all the actors in it with the exception of the lead character J.C./Jack played by the redoubtable Peter O'Toole. The plot of a mad lord(God knows that there are way too many of them by far in the House of Lords both in the past and present) who believes himself to be a benevolent, loving "Peace, Man" Jesus Christ who is subsequently driven by the "scientific" vile machinations of a crazed German psychiatrist(who ends up needing his own head examined)to become a "sane" Jack the Ripper, is buttressed by the superb performances of the supporting cast. Peter O'Toole's "Tour de Force" performance which for the most part lauded by the other reviewers here, is too over-the-top which works within the context of this film for his role but I found O'Toole shamelessly mugging and leering without restraint(indeed like a real madman) which again works accidentally within the context of this film. After O'Toole has been branded "sane" as Jack the Ripper there are several huge closeups of his wide staring eyes--I swear I thought I was watching Joan Crawford as "Mommie Dearest" glaring in her best Kabuki "Mie"-grimace before letting her "Strait-Jacket" axe descend for some satisfying mayhem. Harry Andrews as O'Toole's pater, the 13th Lord Gurney turns in a short but satisfying appearance in his rigid iron-jawed unpleasant upper-crusty sod who offs himself whilst wearing unflattering raiment, William Mervyn and Coral Browne play two of the Gurneys, the nastiest "upper class" scum dripping with self-importance and probably a leaky colostomy bag! Mervyn excelled in portraying snooty, "stiff-upper-lipped" pompous nabobs with their noses in the air though I presume he was not like that in real life; Coral was just doing what came naturally, playing herself, i.e., being a nasty, caustic-tongued man-hungry bitch who got her hooks into horror legend Vincent Price in reality as Vinnie's last wife, James Villers as his specialty, a gormless pathetic gangling twit, Nigel Green as an "Electric Jehovah"(Nigel offed himself after this role, his life imitated his F-art), Michael Bryant as the crazed unscrupulous German psychiatrist, Hugh Burden as the harried mousy lawyer(Mr. Reeder indeed!), Graham Crowden as a gimlet-eyed "sanity officer" who bursts into a lively duet of the Eton Boating Song with O'Toole, Arthur Lowe as the one sympathetic character in the whole film, the Bolshie old manservant who gets framed for the murder done by O'Toole, and last but not least, the great Alastair Sim as the doddering old Bishop, shaking and trembling in fear in the best Kierkegaardian manner. These supporting actors along with Kay Walsh and Patsy Byrne, all work very well together but O'Toole, purposely, I'm sure, strikes a jarring note in the whole film as the huge stinking turd floating in the middle of the punchbowl. You can't miss him but wish he were a little less noticeable! All in all, 10 Stars, Excellent All Around, even with O'Toole's shameless overacting, and chewing up the scenery, which I am sure was his original intent for the overall theme of this gem of a film. The director, Peter Medak(The Changeling, Species II, The Krays) does an absolutely rip-roaring job here and is to be highly commended for this film, which may indeed be his masterpiece!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    "How do you know you're God?" ... "I found that in prayer I was talking to myself."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moonspinner55
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Gross, frequently tasteless satire, much as if Kubrick's "Dr. Strangelove" were transplanted to England's House of Lords and then played at the wrong speed. After the Earl of Gurney accidentally kills himself during one of his fetish games, the 14th Earl--son Jack--is groomed to accept the crown. Once mad Jack--who believes himself to be Christ--undergoes a mental transformation on the night of his son's birth and self-metamorphoses into Jack the Ripper, the plot (thin to begin with) becomes a dartboard for the one-liners (some of which are very funny and are a compensation). Peter Barnes adapted his play for the screen, the kind of material upper-crust audiences like to label 'savage'; he was reciprocated with a game cast and a fine director in Peter Medak, yet these nutty fantasies are merely clotheslines for Barnes to hang his maddening soliloquies on. Peter O'Toole (with cartoony strawberry-blond hair) has some terrific moments early on, particularly in the musical send-ups, but later begins to bellow and rarely stops. The film is too full of targets, and too nasty overall, for its extreme length...it doesn't even look good. ** from ****
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Long but with some insanity to keep the cobwebs out. O'Toole is electric.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    secondtake
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Ruling Class (1972) This is a peculiar, long, hilarious and tedious movie, depending on your taste and probably your age. Parts of it have always made me perk up and laugh, but it works the same theme (of the exhaustion of the old British ways) to death. Peter O'Toole lets it all hang out here, for sure, as Jesus, and as a crazed new British Lord (including a famous final section where he gives a speech to the House of Lords, which is filled with cobwebbed skeletons). It's not really supposed to be haunting or scary, but it's slightly gruesome comedy is pointed, for sure. And funny. If you don't laugh or at least give a crooked smile to the battle between two men who think they are god--O'Toole as the Jesus God and Nigel Green as an Old Testament God, and the Electric Messiah (both). It's crazy and crazed and yet what else do you expect? Someone said it perfectly when they called it a "comedy with tragic relief." O'Toole won an Oscar for his efforts (and he played his part for free). The American version of the movie has 6 minutes missing, though probably the wrong 6 minutes. A good editing might remove an hour and have a faster and more punchy movie. Still, it is what it is, and there's nothing quite like it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
