<filme>
 <id>
  750
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0118607
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1997
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Amistad
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  7.1
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  About a 1839 mutiny aboard a slave ship that is traveling towards the northeastern coast of America. Much of the story involves a court-room drama about the free man who led the revolt.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Amistad is the name of a slave ship traveling from Cuba to the U.S. in 1839. It is carrying a cargo of Africans who have been sold into slavery in Cuba, taken on board, and chained in the cargo hold of the ship. As the ship is crossing from Cuba to the U.S., Cinque, who was a tribal leader in Africa, leads a mutiny and takes over the ship. They continue to sail, hoping to find help when they land. Instead, when they reach the United States, they are imprisoned as runaway slaves. They don't speak a word of English, and it seems like they are doomed to die for killing their captors when an abolitionist lawyer decides to take their case, arguing that they were free citizens of another country and not slaves at all. The case finally gets to the Supreme Court, where John Quincy Adams makes an impassioned and eloquent plea for their release.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   History
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Mystery
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   ship
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   mutiny
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   slave ship
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   africa
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   freedom
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Steven Spielberg
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   David Franzoni
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Djimon Hounsou
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Matthew McConaughey
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Anthony Hopkins
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Slave Courtroom Drama.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Steven Spielberg directs this authentic looking film that tells the story of African tribal leader Cinque(Djimon Hounsou) who is sold into slavery by another tribe and is on a ship from Cuba to the U.S. when he leads a revolt against their cruel captors, killing them. The crew is later captured and put on trial as being murderous runaway slaves, when an abolitionist lawyer(played by Mathew McConaughey) comes to their defense, but, despite winning the case, is undermined by a presidential appeal, so turns to former president John Quincy Adams(played magnificently by Anthony Hopkins) to plead the case before the U.S Supreme Court. Good drama has fine acting by all, harrowing ship-board recreation of the slave revolt, though has its fair share of dramatic lulls as well, though does have a memorable end.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    'Amistad' is one of the most powerful movies I have ever seen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    janet-turpie-johnstone
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Stories such as this need to be continually told and retold - for every generation produces its great and awful people and circumstances. For me, Amistad gave me the most profound memory I can never lose "I will call to the past, to the beginning of time and beg them to come and help me. they will come, I will draw them into me. I am the whole reason they have existed at all." How many of us can acknowledge the reconditeness of this remarkable human strength, We know our past and our future, we are a continuous stream of life and each generational makes the past important and the past declares the present. As one with an Aboriginal heritage this for me is great truth.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Such a Potent History Lesson!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    g-bodyl
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Amistad is a surprisingly great movie that is a welcome addition into the filmography of Steven Spielberg. It has some courtroom clich&eacute;s and some typical Spielberg drama fluff, but it overcomes those minor obstacles to be a powerful, sometimes-disturbing film about a group of people who yearn for their freedom. The editing is also choppy and sometimes it is hard to pick up what's going on, but this story moved me so much, I didn't care if the editing was sub-par. Amistad, based on a true story, is about a group of African slaves who attempt to escape from their captors, but they are recaptured and sent to America for trial. Now these blacks will have to endure unfairness and racial hatred to find out their fates. The acting is powerful. This is the movie where Djimon Hounsou becomes a star and this movie shows why. His performance as the so-called "alpha male" nearly moved me to tears. Anthony Hopkins, who played John Quincy Adams, delivers one of the best speeches you'll ever hear in the movies. Matthew McConaughey, in one of his early non-romantic roles does a wonderful job. I really love Morgan Freeman, but I'm disappointed he didn't do much in the film. Overall, this is a powerhouse film that shows expert Spielberg direction and wonderful acting. The editing is questionable, but I'll let it slide for a film like this. I honestly didn't expect this to be good as it was so I'm quite happy. I rate this film 9/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Another Spielberg's Masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    denis888
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I haven't watched this movie till very recently and wow, what a movie it has been! This is a sheer work of a genius who is by all means Mr. Steven Spielberg. He does not do anything wrong again and again, and thus in this movie he did a great job, too. The very topic of slavery is so painful and disturbing that it would be wrong to make a sweetly home-video drama with no blood or brutality. Nay, sirs, Amistad did exactly the right job - the movie showed slavery as it is - brutal, bloody, bad, gory, evil, malicious, greedy, horrific and unpardonable. The casting is perfect and there are no bad actors in this movie at all. Even the small part of Anna Paquin as Isabella of Spain is a real gem, what say can we of bigger and even better parts by impeccable Morgan Freeman and Anthony Hopkins? The film is very heavy, full of really unpleasant violence scenes but this all is not for the violence's sake. Nay, again, this all served the ultimate goal - to depict the inhuman nature of human trade, and this excellent movie did that well
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    one of good Steven film forever
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    masanseemay20
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Yes! It is an amazing another great movie from my best director Steven Spielberg. It says story of some slaves who were brought by ship called Amistad. superb cast and crew! my best actor Morgan freeman acts well. I always like to watch to Steven film first off all. recently I watched his latest great movie War horse. after watching some of his great films I became fan of this director and do watch his films continually. He makes every thing beautifully as much as he can. Another great is its music. woww!! what a heartbreaking violin in last scenes. john William makes it perfect. finally, well directed and well acted film forever.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    All About African Slavery
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Amistad is a historical film directed by Steven Spielberg.The movie stars a talented cast that includes Morgan Freeman,Anthony Hopkins,Djimon Hounsou,Matthew McConaughey,Nigel Hawthorne,Stellan Skarsg&aring;rd,Harry Blackmun and Anna Paquin. It was based on the true story of an uprising in 1839 by newly captured African slaves that took place aboard the ship La Amistad off the coast of Cuba, the subsequent voyage to the Northeastern United States, and the legal battle that followed their capture by a United States revenue cutter. It shows how, even though the case was won at the federal district court level, it was appealed by President Martin Van Buren to the Supreme Court, and how former President John Quincy Adams took part in the proceedings. The movie opens showing Cinque and the other Africans in a violent takeover of the Amistad. Captured, they are imprisoned in New England where former slave Theodore Joadson, viewing the rebels as "freedom fighters," approaches property lawyer Baldwin, who attempts to prove the Africans were "stolen goods" because they were kidnapped. Running for re-election, President Martin Van Buren overturns the lower court's decision in favor of the Africans. Former President John Quincy Adams is reluctant to become involved, but when the case moves on to the Supreme Court, Adams stirs emotions with a powerful defense. The story line occasionally cuts away to Spain where the young Queen Isabella plays with dolls; she later debated the Amistad case with seven U.S. presidents. Amistad is worth seeing just for people to know about this important story, this moment in history.This is the most straightforward, understated, and powerful big-screen representation of the slavery in recent movie history. And for that, it should be recommended to everyone.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Masterful directing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bitesizemoviereview dotblogspotdotcom
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Combine an award-winning director, a talented cast, a poignant musical score and breathtaking cinematography with one of the darkest hours of world history, and you get Amistad, widely regarded as the definitive film about the trans-Atlantic slave trade. While the plot is focused on the Amistad case, the film itself reverberates with the broader issue of slavery, including anti-slavery figures such as John Quincy Adams. My favorite scene was when the African men enter a church and thumb through an illustrated Bible, able to identify with the sufferings of Christ, after which Spielberg ingeniously shows the masts of three ships, resembling the three crosses. Brilliant and heartbreaking, Amistad captures the struggle of these men and a very determined lawyer to win their freedom. With masterful directing, Spielberg draws upon the lessons of history to forge an acclaimed film that celebrates hope and freedom even in the darkest of times. http://bitesizemoviereview.blogspot.com/
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Extremely worthwhile for the historical perspective, IMO
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bob Pr.
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This tells the story of potential African slaves, the cargo on "Amistad," a Spanish sailing ship, who revolted (1839) and ended up in American jails and courts. -- Will they be hung for killing their captors? -- Or 'property' that will be returned to their purchasers? The film traces their journey from Africa through various US courts and their outcomes that often intermixed with the looming domestic political issue, a sleeping gorilla: that of 1840s pre-Civil War slavery in the U.S. south. The scenes in Africa and shipboard of the treatment of captured slaves have some unsettling ("R" rated) cruelty. But "Amistad" is largely a drama of historical courtroom events (IMO, grossly accurate with exceptions that will be minor to many, major to a few). Hopkins (as a lawyer, the former president, John Quincy Adams) got a deserved Oscar nomination for his supporting role. Freeman plays quite well a wholly invented, minor role (as a former slave & successful businessman in the 1840s North--who you trying to kid, Spielberg?!?!). McConaughey does a great job as the initial lawyer representing the Africans. Hounsu, as the captive African chief, is also very good. This film provides a fascinating U.S. history lesson brought very much alive. Wikipedia has several articles pertinent to this: see both "Amistad" (for the film, related places, writings, actual events, etc.) and also "Tecora" (the Portuguese slave ship which took the Africans to Cuba); these help those who are interested to distinguish much of who, where & when this film captures or distorts historical truths. See also the "Did You Know?" section on IMDb's "Amistad" main page; this covers some points not in the Wikipedia articles. I was extremely glad I saw this film for the knowledge gained despite its sometimes dramatized departures from utter truths.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Schindler's list for Amerika (cinematheque)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leplatypus
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As someone said it in the movie, the slaves had nothing to fear from their masters because as they work for them, they wouldn't be killed. So for me the only difference between slavery and holocaust is the lack of genocide. Besides this, it's the same oppression, the same racism: just see the way of how slaves were treated during the crossing and they are similar to the future extermination camps. But it's true that somewhere condemnation of slavery isn't as known as holocaust. Maybe the unfortunate explanation is that the masters are not beaten ones like Germany but as the movie shows the entire enlightened nations. As Tocqueville wrote, slavery was a shameful thorn in America democracy and Spielberg as a humanist American filmmaker couldn't avoid the subject. And he did in his own way, the same than in "Schindler's", that is to say showing that courage and hope are more powerful that the darkest time, the worst atrocities. Foretelling his later "Minority reports" or "Munich", he throws a very critic look at authorities and for the first apparition of POTUS in his work (a real plague in a lot of American movies) and whispers critics that could have pleased his colleague Stone. But his optimism is also visually contagious: compare the first terrifying look of Cinque and his latter appearances and you can see an happy hand. The only flaw of the movie is finally his title because it's doesn't tell very much what's about: "Amistad vs the people of America" would have been better... Pairing: "Schindler's list": before it, the allies were also evil forces...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Exquisitely made feelgood schlock which ultimately tells a big lie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    patrick powell
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As a film, as entertainment, as a night at the flicks, as a great way to spend well over two hours wallowing in non-stop feelgoodery Amistad is superb, and Steven Spielberg does quite brilliantly what only he and a few others can achieve. The acting is the finest, his actors are the finest, his script is the finest, his direction in which he balances action with reflection is the finest, and no doubt as for cinematography, sound design, editing and the rest a man of Spielberg's stature in the industry is able to employ the finest professionals working in film-making and he so obviously does so. So why do I feel that at the end of the day Spielberg's Amistad is simply nothing but 154 minutes of appalling sentimental schlock and, worse, appalling and dishonest sentimental schlock. I have no doubt that after watching Amistad Americans in their thousands have left the cinemas or turned off their DVD player and thought to themselves or even said out aloud: We are the finest nation on Earth and while we exist, the world is truly a better place. Well, perhaps all those who did and do so might care to pause a moment or two and ask themselves why the proportion of black and coloured inmates in U.S. jails compared to whites is still higher than the proportion of blacks and coloureds which make up the population of the U.S. They might care to ask themselves why a higher proportion of blacks and coloureds are unemployed, live in poverty and have a far lower standard of education. They might care to ask themselves why, almost 60 years after the hearing of the Amistad case before the Supreme Court the so-called Jim Crow laws were enacted denying blacks anything but equality with whites. But it's just a film, you might be saying, come on, don't be so uptight about it. Well, granted that it's not just the Americans but we Brits and the French, the Germans, the Russians, in fact every nation on earth who regularly chose to rewrite its history in films, novels, plays and poetry the calumny is not isolated or even unusual. We Brits like to bang on about what a civilising influence our glorious empire was and ignore completely the misery its establishment engendered and the huge number of deaths that were thought necessary for it to continue civilising 'savages'. And what after all, you might care to argue, is the 'truth'? One man's truth is another man's folly, perhaps, or one man's open mind is another man's gullibility. Well, I'll gracefully take the point but respond by pointing out the facts I cited above of the comparative freedoms and affluence of blacks and coloureds compared to whites in America. And I might ask why, when Hurricane Katrina devastated large parts of New Orleans, was hardly any assistance offered for several days? Why, it might be something to do with the fact that establishment America didn't and doesn't quite rate a black chocolate city like New Orleans has high as rather more top-drawer municipalities (although down-at-heel white communities aren't exactly privileged). And when we talk of 'establishment America', we might add that Hollywood and its filmmakers are one of its essential constituent parts. By all means enjoy Amistad as a film, a piece of fiction, but please don't run away with the idea that despite portraying historical incidents - although one larded with fictional characters: Morgan Freeman's dandified citizen is especially offensive, particularly since every other black face in the film is, if not an African from the Amistad, a servant or pauper. The incessant and remorseless feelgood soundtrack should serve as a warning: on and on and on it goes, all patriotic flutes, trumpets, syrupy strings. A good case could be made about accompanying some film soundtracks with the notice that 'this soundtrack can adversely influence your judgement'. When a 15-minute scene of a grand American figure such as John Quincy Adams grandly making grandly patriotic observations has a backdrop of such a patriotic melange of flutes, trumpets and strings, you just know something very rum is going on. Giving Amistad a rating presents a real problem: as filmmaking it is very fine indeed and Spielberg is a filmmaker almost without peer. But unfortunately a film which sets out to do what he has attempted to do needs more, not least true honesty, so this one, Stevie, can only get a five, because five is halfway between zero and ten.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Slave Courtroom Drama.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Steven Spielberg directs this authentic looking film that tells the story of African tribal leader Cinque(Djimon Hounsou) who is sold into slavery by another tribe and is on a ship from Cuba to the U.S. when he leads a revolt against their cruel captors, killing them. The crew is later captured and put on trial as being murderous runaway slaves, when an abolitionist lawyer(played by Mathew McConaughey) comes to their defense, but, despite winning the case, is undermined by a presidential appeal, so turns to former president John Quincy Adams(played magnificently by Anthony Hopkins) to plead the case before the U.S Supreme Court. Good drama has fine acting by all, harrowing ship-board recreation of the slave revolt, though has its fair share of dramatic lulls as well, though does have a memorable end.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    'Amistad' is one of the most powerful movies I have ever seen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    janet-turpie-johnstone
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Stories such as this need to be continually told and retold - for every generation produces its great and awful people and circumstances. For me, Amistad gave me the most profound memory I can never lose "I will call to the past, to the beginning of time and beg them to come and help me. they will come, I will draw them into me. I am the whole reason they have existed at all." How many of us can acknowledge the reconditeness of this remarkable human strength, We know our past and our future, we are a continuous stream of life and each generational makes the past important and the past declares the present. As one with an Aboriginal heritage this for me is great truth.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Such a Potent History Lesson!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    g-bodyl
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Amistad is a surprisingly great movie that is a welcome addition into the filmography of Steven Spielberg. It has some courtroom clich&eacute;s and some typical Spielberg drama fluff, but it overcomes those minor obstacles to be a powerful, sometimes-disturbing film about a group of people who yearn for their freedom. The editing is also choppy and sometimes it is hard to pick up what's going on, but this story moved me so much, I didn't care if the editing was sub-par. Amistad, based on a true story, is about a group of African slaves who attempt to escape from their captors, but they are recaptured and sent to America for trial. Now these blacks will have to endure unfairness and racial hatred to find out their fates. The acting is powerful. This is the movie where Djimon Hounsou becomes a star and this movie shows why. His performance as the so-called "alpha male" nearly moved me to tears. Anthony Hopkins, who played John Quincy Adams, delivers one of the best speeches you'll ever hear in the movies. Matthew McConaughey, in one of his early non-romantic roles does a wonderful job. I really love Morgan Freeman, but I'm disappointed he didn't do much in the film. Overall, this is a powerhouse film that shows expert Spielberg direction and wonderful acting. The editing is questionable, but I'll let it slide for a film like this. I honestly didn't expect this to be good as it was so I'm quite happy. I rate this film 9/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Another Spielberg's Masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    denis888
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I haven't watched this movie till very recently and wow, what a movie it has been! This is a sheer work of a genius who is by all means Mr. Steven Spielberg. He does not do anything wrong again and again, and thus in this movie he did a great job, too. The very topic of slavery is so painful and disturbing that it would be wrong to make a sweetly home-video drama with no blood or brutality. Nay, sirs, Amistad did exactly the right job - the movie showed slavery as it is - brutal, bloody, bad, gory, evil, malicious, greedy, horrific and unpardonable. The casting is perfect and there are no bad actors in this movie at all. Even the small part of Anna Paquin as Isabella of Spain is a real gem, what say can we of bigger and even better parts by impeccable Morgan Freeman and Anthony Hopkins? The film is very heavy, full of really unpleasant violence scenes but this all is not for the violence's sake. Nay, again, this all served the ultimate goal - to depict the inhuman nature of human trade, and this excellent movie did that well
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    one of good Steven film forever
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    masanseemay20
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Yes! It is an amazing another great movie from my best director Steven Spielberg. It says story of some slaves who were brought by ship called Amistad. superb cast and crew! my best actor Morgan freeman acts well. I always like to watch to Steven film first off all. recently I watched his latest great movie War horse. after watching some of his great films I became fan of this director and do watch his films continually. He makes every thing beautifully as much as he can. Another great is its music. woww!! what a heartbreaking violin in last scenes. john William makes it perfect. finally, well directed and well acted film forever.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    All About African Slavery
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Amistad is a historical film directed by Steven Spielberg.The movie stars a talented cast that includes Morgan Freeman,Anthony Hopkins,Djimon Hounsou,Matthew McConaughey,Nigel Hawthorne,Stellan Skarsg&aring;rd,Harry Blackmun and Anna Paquin. It was based on the true story of an uprising in 1839 by newly captured African slaves that took place aboard the ship La Amistad off the coast of Cuba, the subsequent voyage to the Northeastern United States, and the legal battle that followed their capture by a United States revenue cutter. It shows how, even though the case was won at the federal district court level, it was appealed by President Martin Van Buren to the Supreme Court, and how former President John Quincy Adams took part in the proceedings. The movie opens showing Cinque and the other Africans in a violent takeover of the Amistad. Captured, they are imprisoned in New England where former slave Theodore Joadson, viewing the rebels as "freedom fighters," approaches property lawyer Baldwin, who attempts to prove the Africans were "stolen goods" because they were kidnapped. Running for re-election, President Martin Van Buren overturns the lower court's decision in favor of the Africans. Former President John Quincy Adams is reluctant to become involved, but when the case moves on to the Supreme Court, Adams stirs emotions with a powerful defense. The story line occasionally cuts away to Spain where the young Queen Isabella plays with dolls; she later debated the Amistad case with seven U.S. presidents. Amistad is worth seeing just for people to know about this important story, this moment in history.This is the most straightforward, understated, and powerful big-screen representation of the slavery in recent movie history. And for that, it should be recommended to everyone.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Masterful directing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bitesizemoviereview dotblogspotdotcom
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Combine an award-winning director, a talented cast, a poignant musical score and breathtaking cinematography with one of the darkest hours of world history, and you get Amistad, widely regarded as the definitive film about the trans-Atlantic slave trade. While the plot is focused on the Amistad case, the film itself reverberates with the broader issue of slavery, including anti-slavery figures such as John Quincy Adams. My favorite scene was when the African men enter a church and thumb through an illustrated Bible, able to identify with the sufferings of Christ, after which Spielberg ingeniously shows the masts of three ships, resembling the three crosses. Brilliant and heartbreaking, Amistad captures the struggle of these men and a very determined lawyer to win their freedom. With masterful directing, Spielberg draws upon the lessons of history to forge an acclaimed film that celebrates hope and freedom even in the darkest of times. http://bitesizemoviereview.blogspot.com/
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Extremely worthwhile for the historical perspective, IMO
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bob Pr.
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This tells the story of potential African slaves, the cargo on "Amistad," a Spanish sailing ship, who revolted (1839) and ended up in American jails and courts. -- Will they be hung for killing their captors? -- Or 'property' that will be returned to their purchasers? The film traces their journey from Africa through various US courts and their outcomes that often intermixed with the looming domestic political issue, a sleeping gorilla: that of 1840s pre-Civil War slavery in the U.S. south. The scenes in Africa and shipboard of the treatment of captured slaves have some unsettling ("R" rated) cruelty. But "Amistad" is largely a drama of historical courtroom events (IMO, grossly accurate with exceptions that will be minor to many, major to a few). Hopkins (as a lawyer, the former president, John Quincy Adams) got a deserved Oscar nomination for his supporting role. Freeman plays quite well a wholly invented, minor role (as a former slave & successful businessman in the 1840s North--who you trying to kid, Spielberg?!?!). McConaughey does a great job as the initial lawyer representing the Africans. Hounsu, as the captive African chief, is also very good. This film provides a fascinating U.S. history lesson brought very much alive. Wikipedia has several articles pertinent to this: see both "Amistad" (for the film, related places, writings, actual events, etc.) and also "Tecora" (the Portuguese slave ship which took the Africans to Cuba); these help those who are interested to distinguish much of who, where & when this film captures or distorts historical truths. See also the "Did You Know?" section on IMDb's "Amistad" main page; this covers some points not in the Wikipedia articles. I was extremely glad I saw this film for the knowledge gained despite its sometimes dramatized departures from utter truths.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Schindler's list for Amerika (cinematheque)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leplatypus
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As someone said it in the movie, the slaves had nothing to fear from their masters because as they work for them, they wouldn't be killed. So for me the only difference between slavery and holocaust is the lack of genocide. Besides this, it's the same oppression, the same racism: just see the way of how slaves were treated during the crossing and they are similar to the future extermination camps. But it's true that somewhere condemnation of slavery isn't as known as holocaust. Maybe the unfortunate explanation is that the masters are not beaten ones like Germany but as the movie shows the entire enlightened nations. As Tocqueville wrote, slavery was a shameful thorn in America democracy and Spielberg as a humanist American filmmaker couldn't avoid the subject. And he did in his own way, the same than in "Schindler's", that is to say showing that courage and hope are more powerful that the darkest time, the worst atrocities. Foretelling his later "Minority reports" or "Munich", he throws a very critic look at authorities and for the first apparition of POTUS in his work (a real plague in a lot of American movies) and whispers critics that could have pleased his colleague Stone. But his optimism is also visually contagious: compare the first terrifying look of Cinque and his latter appearances and you can see an happy hand. The only flaw of the movie is finally his title because it's doesn't tell very much what's about: "Amistad vs the people of America" would have been better... Pairing: "Schindler's list": before it, the allies were also evil forces...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Exquisitely made feelgood schlock which ultimately tells a big lie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    patrick powell
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As a film, as entertainment, as a night at the flicks, as a great way to spend well over two hours wallowing in non-stop feelgoodery Amistad is superb, and Steven Spielberg does quite brilliantly what only he and a few others can achieve. The acting is the finest, his actors are the finest, his script is the finest, his direction in which he balances action with reflection is the finest, and no doubt as for cinematography, sound design, editing and the rest a man of Spielberg's stature in the industry is able to employ the finest professionals working in film-making and he so obviously does so. So why do I feel that at the end of the day Spielberg's Amistad is simply nothing but 154 minutes of appalling sentimental schlock and, worse, appalling and dishonest sentimental schlock. I have no doubt that after watching Amistad Americans in their thousands have left the cinemas or turned off their DVD player and thought to themselves or even said out aloud: We are the finest nation on Earth and while we exist, the world is truly a better place. Well, perhaps all those who did and do so might care to pause a moment or two and ask themselves why the proportion of black and coloured inmates in U.S. jails compared to whites is still higher than the proportion of blacks and coloureds which make up the population of the U.S. They might care to ask themselves why a higher proportion of blacks and coloureds are unemployed, live in poverty and have a far lower standard of education. They might care to ask themselves why, almost 60 years after the hearing of the Amistad case before the Supreme Court the so-called Jim Crow laws were enacted denying blacks anything but equality with whites. But it's just a film, you might be saying, come on, don't be so uptight about it. Well, granted that it's not just the Americans but we Brits and the French, the Germans, the Russians, in fact every nation on earth who regularly chose to rewrite its history in films, novels, plays and poetry the calumny is not isolated or even unusual. We Brits like to bang on about what a civilising influence our glorious empire was and ignore completely the misery its establishment engendered and the huge number of deaths that were thought necessary for it to continue civilising 'savages'. And what after all, you might care to argue, is the 'truth'? One man's truth is another man's folly, perhaps, or one man's open mind is another man's gullibility. Well, I'll gracefully take the point but respond by pointing out the facts I cited above of the comparative freedoms and affluence of blacks and coloureds compared to whites in America. And I might ask why, when Hurricane Katrina devastated large parts of New Orleans, was hardly any assistance offered for several days? Why, it might be something to do with the fact that establishment America didn't and doesn't quite rate a black chocolate city like New Orleans has high as rather more top-drawer municipalities (although down-at-heel white communities aren't exactly privileged). And when we talk of 'establishment America', we might add that Hollywood and its filmmakers are one of its essential constituent parts. By all means enjoy Amistad as a film, a piece of fiction, but please don't run away with the idea that despite portraying historical incidents - although one larded with fictional characters: Morgan Freeman's dandified citizen is especially offensive, particularly since every other black face in the film is, if not an African from the Amistad, a servant or pauper. The incessant and remorseless feelgood soundtrack should serve as a warning: on and on and on it goes, all patriotic flutes, trumpets, syrupy strings. A good case could be made about accompanying some film soundtracks with the notice that 'this soundtrack can adversely influence your judgement'. When a 15-minute scene of a grand American figure such as John Quincy Adams grandly making grandly patriotic observations has a backdrop of such a patriotic melange of flutes, trumpets and strings, you just know something very rum is going on. Giving Amistad a rating presents a real problem: as filmmaking it is very fine indeed and Spielberg is a filmmaker almost without peer. But unfortunately a film which sets out to do what he has attempted to do needs more, not least true honesty, so this one, Stevie, can only get a five, because five is halfway between zero and ten.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Slave Courtroom Drama.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Steven Spielberg directs this authentic looking film that tells the story of African tribal leader Cinque(Djimon Hounsou) who is sold into slavery by another tribe and is on a ship from Cuba to the U.S. when he leads a revolt against their cruel captors, killing them. The crew is later captured and put on trial as being murderous runaway slaves, when an abolitionist lawyer(played by Mathew McConaughey) comes to their defense, but, despite winning the case, is undermined by a presidential appeal, so turns to former president John Quincy Adams(played magnificently by Anthony Hopkins) to plead the case before the U.S Supreme Court. Good drama has fine acting by all, harrowing ship-board recreation of the slave revolt, though has its fair share of dramatic lulls as well, though does have a memorable end.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    'Amistad' is one of the most powerful movies I have ever seen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    janet-turpie-johnstone
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Stories such as this need to be continually told and retold - for every generation produces its great and awful people and circumstances. For me, Amistad gave me the most profound memory I can never lose "I will call to the past, to the beginning of time and beg them to come and help me. they will come, I will draw them into me. I am the whole reason they have existed at all." How many of us can acknowledge the reconditeness of this remarkable human strength, We know our past and our future, we are a continuous stream of life and each generational makes the past important and the past declares the present. As one with an Aboriginal heritage this for me is great truth.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Such a Potent History Lesson!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    g-bodyl
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Amistad is a surprisingly great movie that is a welcome addition into the filmography of Steven Spielberg. It has some courtroom clich&eacute;s and some typical Spielberg drama fluff, but it overcomes those minor obstacles to be a powerful, sometimes-disturbing film about a group of people who yearn for their freedom. The editing is also choppy and sometimes it is hard to pick up what's going on, but this story moved me so much, I didn't care if the editing was sub-par. Amistad, based on a true story, is about a group of African slaves who attempt to escape from their captors, but they are recaptured and sent to America for trial. Now these blacks will have to endure unfairness and racial hatred to find out their fates. The acting is powerful. This is the movie where Djimon Hounsou becomes a star and this movie shows why. His performance as the so-called "alpha male" nearly moved me to tears. Anthony Hopkins, who played John Quincy Adams, delivers one of the best speeches you'll ever hear in the movies. Matthew McConaughey, in one of his early non-romantic roles does a wonderful job. I really love Morgan Freeman, but I'm disappointed he didn't do much in the film. Overall, this is a powerhouse film that shows expert Spielberg direction and wonderful acting. The editing is questionable, but I'll let it slide for a film like this. I honestly didn't expect this to be good as it was so I'm quite happy. I rate this film 9/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Another Spielberg's Masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    denis888
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I haven't watched this movie till very recently and wow, what a movie it has been! This is a sheer work of a genius who is by all means Mr. Steven Spielberg. He does not do anything wrong again and again, and thus in this movie he did a great job, too. The very topic of slavery is so painful and disturbing that it would be wrong to make a sweetly home-video drama with no blood or brutality. Nay, sirs, Amistad did exactly the right job - the movie showed slavery as it is - brutal, bloody, bad, gory, evil, malicious, greedy, horrific and unpardonable. The casting is perfect and there are no bad actors in this movie at all. Even the small part of Anna Paquin as Isabella of Spain is a real gem, what say can we of bigger and even better parts by impeccable Morgan Freeman and Anthony Hopkins? The film is very heavy, full of really unpleasant violence scenes but this all is not for the violence's sake. Nay, again, this all served the ultimate goal - to depict the inhuman nature of human trade, and this excellent movie did that well
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    one of good Steven film forever
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    masanseemay20
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Yes! It is an amazing another great movie from my best director Steven Spielberg. It says story of some slaves who were brought by ship called Amistad. superb cast and crew! my best actor Morgan freeman acts well. I always like to watch to Steven film first off all. recently I watched his latest great movie War horse. after watching some of his great films I became fan of this director and do watch his films continually. He makes every thing beautifully as much as he can. Another great is its music. woww!! what a heartbreaking violin in last scenes. john William makes it perfect. finally, well directed and well acted film forever.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    All About African Slavery
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Amistad is a historical film directed by Steven Spielberg.The movie stars a talented cast that includes Morgan Freeman,Anthony Hopkins,Djimon Hounsou,Matthew McConaughey,Nigel Hawthorne,Stellan Skarsg&aring;rd,Harry Blackmun and Anna Paquin. It was based on the true story of an uprising in 1839 by newly captured African slaves that took place aboard the ship La Amistad off the coast of Cuba, the subsequent voyage to the Northeastern United States, and the legal battle that followed their capture by a United States revenue cutter. It shows how, even though the case was won at the federal district court level, it was appealed by President Martin Van Buren to the Supreme Court, and how former President John Quincy Adams took part in the proceedings. The movie opens showing Cinque and the other Africans in a violent takeover of the Amistad. Captured, they are imprisoned in New England where former slave Theodore Joadson, viewing the rebels as "freedom fighters," approaches property lawyer Baldwin, who attempts to prove the Africans were "stolen goods" because they were kidnapped. Running for re-election, President Martin Van Buren overturns the lower court's decision in favor of the Africans. Former President John Quincy Adams is reluctant to become involved, but when the case moves on to the Supreme Court, Adams stirs emotions with a powerful defense. The story line occasionally cuts away to Spain where the young Queen Isabella plays with dolls; she later debated the Amistad case with seven U.S. presidents. Amistad is worth seeing just for people to know about this important story, this moment in history.This is the most straightforward, understated, and powerful big-screen representation of the slavery in recent movie history. And for that, it should be recommended to everyone.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Masterful directing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bitesizemoviereview dotblogspotdotcom
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Combine an award-winning director, a talented cast, a poignant musical score and breathtaking cinematography with one of the darkest hours of world history, and you get Amistad, widely regarded as the definitive film about the trans-Atlantic slave trade. While the plot is focused on the Amistad case, the film itself reverberates with the broader issue of slavery, including anti-slavery figures such as John Quincy Adams. My favorite scene was when the African men enter a church and thumb through an illustrated Bible, able to identify with the sufferings of Christ, after which Spielberg ingeniously shows the masts of three ships, resembling the three crosses. Brilliant and heartbreaking, Amistad captures the struggle of these men and a very determined lawyer to win their freedom. With masterful directing, Spielberg draws upon the lessons of history to forge an acclaimed film that celebrates hope and freedom even in the darkest of times. http://bitesizemoviereview.blogspot.com/
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Extremely worthwhile for the historical perspective, IMO
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bob Pr.
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This tells the story of potential African slaves, the cargo on "Amistad," a Spanish sailing ship, who revolted (1839) and ended up in American jails and courts. -- Will they be hung for killing their captors? -- Or 'property' that will be returned to their purchasers? The film traces their journey from Africa through various US courts and their outcomes that often intermixed with the looming domestic political issue, a sleeping gorilla: that of 1840s pre-Civil War slavery in the U.S. south. The scenes in Africa and shipboard of the treatment of captured slaves have some unsettling ("R" rated) cruelty. But "Amistad" is largely a drama of historical courtroom events (IMO, grossly accurate with exceptions that will be minor to many, major to a few). Hopkins (as a lawyer, the former president, John Quincy Adams) got a deserved Oscar nomination for his supporting role. Freeman plays quite well a wholly invented, minor role (as a former slave & successful businessman in the 1840s North--who you trying to kid, Spielberg?!?!). McConaughey does a great job as the initial lawyer representing the Africans. Hounsu, as the captive African chief, is also very good. This film provides a fascinating U.S. history lesson brought very much alive. Wikipedia has several articles pertinent to this: see both "Amistad" (for the film, related places, writings, actual events, etc.) and also "Tecora" (the Portuguese slave ship which took the Africans to Cuba); these help those who are interested to distinguish much of who, where & when this film captures or distorts historical truths. See also the "Did You Know?" section on IMDb's "Amistad" main page; this covers some points not in the Wikipedia articles. I was extremely glad I saw this film for the knowledge gained despite its sometimes dramatized departures from utter truths.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Schindler's list for Amerika (cinematheque)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leplatypus
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As someone said it in the movie, the slaves had nothing to fear from their masters because as they work for them, they wouldn't be killed. So for me the only difference between slavery and holocaust is the lack of genocide. Besides this, it's the same oppression, the same racism: just see the way of how slaves were treated during the crossing and they are similar to the future extermination camps. But it's true that somewhere condemnation of slavery isn't as known as holocaust. Maybe the unfortunate explanation is that the masters are not beaten ones like Germany but as the movie shows the entire enlightened nations. As Tocqueville wrote, slavery was a shameful thorn in America democracy and Spielberg as a humanist American filmmaker couldn't avoid the subject. And he did in his own way, the same than in "Schindler's", that is to say showing that courage and hope are more powerful that the darkest time, the worst atrocities. Foretelling his later "Minority reports" or "Munich", he throws a very critic look at authorities and for the first apparition of POTUS in his work (a real plague in a lot of American movies) and whispers critics that could have pleased his colleague Stone. But his optimism is also visually contagious: compare the first terrifying look of Cinque and his latter appearances and you can see an happy hand. The only flaw of the movie is finally his title because it's doesn't tell very much what's about: "Amistad vs the people of America" would have been better... Pairing: "Schindler's list": before it, the allies were also evil forces...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Exquisitely made feelgood schlock which ultimately tells a big lie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    patrick powell
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As a film, as entertainment, as a night at the flicks, as a great way to spend well over two hours wallowing in non-stop feelgoodery Amistad is superb, and Steven Spielberg does quite brilliantly what only he and a few others can achieve. The acting is the finest, his actors are the finest, his script is the finest, his direction in which he balances action with reflection is the finest, and no doubt as for cinematography, sound design, editing and the rest a man of Spielberg's stature in the industry is able to employ the finest professionals working in film-making and he so obviously does so. So why do I feel that at the end of the day Spielberg's Amistad is simply nothing but 154 minutes of appalling sentimental schlock and, worse, appalling and dishonest sentimental schlock. I have no doubt that after watching Amistad Americans in their thousands have left the cinemas or turned off their DVD player and thought to themselves or even said out aloud: We are the finest nation on Earth and while we exist, the world is truly a better place. Well, perhaps all those who did and do so might care to pause a moment or two and ask themselves why the proportion of black and coloured inmates in U.S. jails compared to whites is still higher than the proportion of blacks and coloureds which make up the population of the U.S. They might care to ask themselves why a higher proportion of blacks and coloureds are unemployed, live in poverty and have a far lower standard of education. They might care to ask themselves why, almost 60 years after the hearing of the Amistad case before the Supreme Court the so-called Jim Crow laws were enacted denying blacks anything but equality with whites. But it's just a film, you might be saying, come on, don't be so uptight about it. Well, granted that it's not just the Americans but we Brits and the French, the Germans, the Russians, in fact every nation on earth who regularly chose to rewrite its history in films, novels, plays and poetry the calumny is not isolated or even unusual. We Brits like to bang on about what a civilising influence our glorious empire was and ignore completely the misery its establishment engendered and the huge number of deaths that were thought necessary for it to continue civilising 'savages'. And what after all, you might care to argue, is the 'truth'? One man's truth is another man's folly, perhaps, or one man's open mind is another man's gullibility. Well, I'll gracefully take the point but respond by pointing out the facts I cited above of the comparative freedoms and affluence of blacks and coloureds compared to whites in America. And I might ask why, when Hurricane Katrina devastated large parts of New Orleans, was hardly any assistance offered for several days? Why, it might be something to do with the fact that establishment America didn't and doesn't quite rate a black chocolate city like New Orleans has high as rather more top-drawer municipalities (although down-at-heel white communities aren't exactly privileged). And when we talk of 'establishment America', we might add that Hollywood and its filmmakers are one of its essential constituent parts. By all means enjoy Amistad as a film, a piece of fiction, but please don't run away with the idea that despite portraying historical incidents - although one larded with fictional characters: Morgan Freeman's dandified citizen is especially offensive, particularly since every other black face in the film is, if not an African from the Amistad, a servant or pauper. The incessant and remorseless feelgood soundtrack should serve as a warning: on and on and on it goes, all patriotic flutes, trumpets, syrupy strings. A good case could be made about accompanying some film soundtracks with the notice that 'this soundtrack can adversely influence your judgement'. When a 15-minute scene of a grand American figure such as John Quincy Adams grandly making grandly patriotic observations has a backdrop of such a patriotic melange of flutes, trumpets and strings, you just know something very rum is going on. Giving Amistad a rating presents a real problem: as filmmaking it is very fine indeed and Spielberg is a filmmaker almost without peer. But unfortunately a film which sets out to do what he has attempted to do needs more, not least true honesty, so this one, Stevie, can only get a five, because five is halfway between zero and ten.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Slave Courtroom Drama.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Steven Spielberg directs this authentic looking film that tells the story of African tribal leader Cinque(Djimon Hounsou) who is sold into slavery by another tribe and is on a ship from Cuba to the U.S. when he leads a revolt against their cruel captors, killing them. The crew is later captured and put on trial as being murderous runaway slaves, when an abolitionist lawyer(played by Mathew McConaughey) comes to their defense, but, despite winning the case, is undermined by a presidential appeal, so turns to former president John Quincy Adams(played magnificently by Anthony Hopkins) to plead the case before the U.S Supreme Court. Good drama has fine acting by all, harrowing ship-board recreation of the slave revolt, though has its fair share of dramatic lulls as well, though does have a memorable end.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    'Amistad' is one of the most powerful movies I have ever seen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    janet-turpie-johnstone
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Stories such as this need to be continually told and retold - for every generation produces its great and awful people and circumstances. For me, Amistad gave me the most profound memory I can never lose "I will call to the past, to the beginning of time and beg them to come and help me. they will come, I will draw them into me. I am the whole reason they have existed at all." How many of us can acknowledge the reconditeness of this remarkable human strength, We know our past and our future, we are a continuous stream of life and each generational makes the past important and the past declares the present. As one with an Aboriginal heritage this for me is great truth.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Such a Potent History Lesson!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    g-bodyl
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Amistad is a surprisingly great movie that is a welcome addition into the filmography of Steven Spielberg. It has some courtroom clich&eacute;s and some typical Spielberg drama fluff, but it overcomes those minor obstacles to be a powerful, sometimes-disturbing film about a group of people who yearn for their freedom. The editing is also choppy and sometimes it is hard to pick up what's going on, but this story moved me so much, I didn't care if the editing was sub-par. Amistad, based on a true story, is about a group of African slaves who attempt to escape from their captors, but they are recaptured and sent to America for trial. Now these blacks will have to endure unfairness and racial hatred to find out their fates. The acting is powerful. This is the movie where Djimon Hounsou becomes a star and this movie shows why. His performance as the so-called "alpha male" nearly moved me to tears. Anthony Hopkins, who played John Quincy Adams, delivers one of the best speeches you'll ever hear in the movies. Matthew McConaughey, in one of his early non-romantic roles does a wonderful job. I really love Morgan Freeman, but I'm disappointed he didn't do much in the film. Overall, this is a powerhouse film that shows expert Spielberg direction and wonderful acting. The editing is questionable, but I'll let it slide for a film like this. I honestly didn't expect this to be good as it was so I'm quite happy. I rate this film 9/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Another Spielberg's Masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    denis888
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I haven't watched this movie till very recently and wow, what a movie it has been! This is a sheer work of a genius who is by all means Mr. Steven Spielberg. He does not do anything wrong again and again, and thus in this movie he did a great job, too. The very topic of slavery is so painful and disturbing that it would be wrong to make a sweetly home-video drama with no blood or brutality. Nay, sirs, Amistad did exactly the right job - the movie showed slavery as it is - brutal, bloody, bad, gory, evil, malicious, greedy, horrific and unpardonable. The casting is perfect and there are no bad actors in this movie at all. Even the small part of Anna Paquin as Isabella of Spain is a real gem, what say can we of bigger and even better parts by impeccable Morgan Freeman and Anthony Hopkins? The film is very heavy, full of really unpleasant violence scenes but this all is not for the violence's sake. Nay, again, this all served the ultimate goal - to depict the inhuman nature of human trade, and this excellent movie did that well
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    one of good Steven film forever
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    masanseemay20
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Yes! It is an amazing another great movie from my best director Steven Spielberg. It says story of some slaves who were brought by ship called Amistad. superb cast and crew! my best actor Morgan freeman acts well. I always like to watch to Steven film first off all. recently I watched his latest great movie War horse. after watching some of his great films I became fan of this director and do watch his films continually. He makes every thing beautifully as much as he can. Another great is its music. woww!! what a heartbreaking violin in last scenes. john William makes it perfect. finally, well directed and well acted film forever.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    All About African Slavery
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Amistad is a historical film directed by Steven Spielberg.The movie stars a talented cast that includes Morgan Freeman,Anthony Hopkins,Djimon Hounsou,Matthew McConaughey,Nigel Hawthorne,Stellan Skarsg&aring;rd,Harry Blackmun and Anna Paquin. It was based on the true story of an uprising in 1839 by newly captured African slaves that took place aboard the ship La Amistad off the coast of Cuba, the subsequent voyage to the Northeastern United States, and the legal battle that followed their capture by a United States revenue cutter. It shows how, even though the case was won at the federal district court level, it was appealed by President Martin Van Buren to the Supreme Court, and how former President John Quincy Adams took part in the proceedings. The movie opens showing Cinque and the other Africans in a violent takeover of the Amistad. Captured, they are imprisoned in New England where former slave Theodore Joadson, viewing the rebels as "freedom fighters," approaches property lawyer Baldwin, who attempts to prove the Africans were "stolen goods" because they were kidnapped. Running for re-election, President Martin Van Buren overturns the lower court's decision in favor of the Africans. Former President John Quincy Adams is reluctant to become involved, but when the case moves on to the Supreme Court, Adams stirs emotions with a powerful defense. The story line occasionally cuts away to Spain where the young Queen Isabella plays with dolls; she later debated the Amistad case with seven U.S. presidents. Amistad is worth seeing just for people to know about this important story, this moment in history.This is the most straightforward, understated, and powerful big-screen representation of the slavery in recent movie history. And for that, it should be recommended to everyone.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Masterful directing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bitesizemoviereview dotblogspotdotcom
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Combine an award-winning director, a talented cast, a poignant musical score and breathtaking cinematography with one of the darkest hours of world history, and you get Amistad, widely regarded as the definitive film about the trans-Atlantic slave trade. While the plot is focused on the Amistad case, the film itself reverberates with the broader issue of slavery, including anti-slavery figures such as John Quincy Adams. My favorite scene was when the African men enter a church and thumb through an illustrated Bible, able to identify with the sufferings of Christ, after which Spielberg ingeniously shows the masts of three ships, resembling the three crosses. Brilliant and heartbreaking, Amistad captures the struggle of these men and a very determined lawyer to win their freedom. With masterful directing, Spielberg draws upon the lessons of history to forge an acclaimed film that celebrates hope and freedom even in the darkest of times. http://bitesizemoviereview.blogspot.com/
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Extremely worthwhile for the historical perspective, IMO
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bob Pr.
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This tells the story of potential African slaves, the cargo on "Amistad," a Spanish sailing ship, who revolted (1839) and ended up in American jails and courts. -- Will they be hung for killing their captors? -- Or 'property' that will be returned to their purchasers? The film traces their journey from Africa through various US courts and their outcomes that often intermixed with the looming domestic political issue, a sleeping gorilla: that of 1840s pre-Civil War slavery in the U.S. south. The scenes in Africa and shipboard of the treatment of captured slaves have some unsettling ("R" rated) cruelty. But "Amistad" is largely a drama of historical courtroom events (IMO, grossly accurate with exceptions that will be minor to many, major to a few). Hopkins (as a lawyer, the former president, John Quincy Adams) got a deserved Oscar nomination for his supporting role. Freeman plays quite well a wholly invented, minor role (as a former slave & successful businessman in the 1840s North--who you trying to kid, Spielberg?!?!). McConaughey does a great job as the initial lawyer representing the Africans. Hounsu, as the captive African chief, is also very good. This film provides a fascinating U.S. history lesson brought very much alive. Wikipedia has several articles pertinent to this: see both "Amistad" (for the film, related places, writings, actual events, etc.) and also "Tecora" (the Portuguese slave ship which took the Africans to Cuba); these help those who are interested to distinguish much of who, where & when this film captures or distorts historical truths. See also the "Did You Know?" section on IMDb's "Amistad" main page; this covers some points not in the Wikipedia articles. I was extremely glad I saw this film for the knowledge gained despite its sometimes dramatized departures from utter truths.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Schindler's list for Amerika (cinematheque)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leplatypus
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As someone said it in the movie, the slaves had nothing to fear from their masters because as they work for them, they wouldn't be killed. So for me the only difference between slavery and holocaust is the lack of genocide. Besides this, it's the same oppression, the same racism: just see the way of how slaves were treated during the crossing and they are similar to the future extermination camps. But it's true that somewhere condemnation of slavery isn't as known as holocaust. Maybe the unfortunate explanation is that the masters are not beaten ones like Germany but as the movie shows the entire enlightened nations. As Tocqueville wrote, slavery was a shameful thorn in America democracy and Spielberg as a humanist American filmmaker couldn't avoid the subject. And he did in his own way, the same than in "Schindler's", that is to say showing that courage and hope are more powerful that the darkest time, the worst atrocities. Foretelling his later "Minority reports" or "Munich", he throws a very critic look at authorities and for the first apparition of POTUS in his work (a real plague in a lot of American movies) and whispers critics that could have pleased his colleague Stone. But his optimism is also visually contagious: compare the first terrifying look of Cinque and his latter appearances and you can see an happy hand. The only flaw of the movie is finally his title because it's doesn't tell very much what's about: "Amistad vs the people of America" would have been better... Pairing: "Schindler's list": before it, the allies were also evil forces...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Exquisitely made feelgood schlock which ultimately tells a big lie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    patrick powell
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As a film, as entertainment, as a night at the flicks, as a great way to spend well over two hours wallowing in non-stop feelgoodery Amistad is superb, and Steven Spielberg does quite brilliantly what only he and a few others can achieve. The acting is the finest, his actors are the finest, his script is the finest, his direction in which he balances action with reflection is the finest, and no doubt as for cinematography, sound design, editing and the rest a man of Spielberg's stature in the industry is able to employ the finest professionals working in film-making and he so obviously does so. So why do I feel that at the end of the day Spielberg's Amistad is simply nothing but 154 minutes of appalling sentimental schlock and, worse, appalling and dishonest sentimental schlock. I have no doubt that after watching Amistad Americans in their thousands have left the cinemas or turned off their DVD player and thought to themselves or even said out aloud: We are the finest nation on Earth and while we exist, the world is truly a better place. Well, perhaps all those who did and do so might care to pause a moment or two and ask themselves why the proportion of black and coloured inmates in U.S. jails compared to whites is still higher than the proportion of blacks and coloureds which make up the population of the U.S. They might care to ask themselves why a higher proportion of blacks and coloureds are unemployed, live in poverty and have a far lower standard of education. They might care to ask themselves why, almost 60 years after the hearing of the Amistad case before the Supreme Court the so-called Jim Crow laws were enacted denying blacks anything but equality with whites. But it's just a film, you might be saying, come on, don't be so uptight about it. Well, granted that it's not just the Americans but we Brits and the French, the Germans, the Russians, in fact every nation on earth who regularly chose to rewrite its history in films, novels, plays and poetry the calumny is not isolated or even unusual. We Brits like to bang on about what a civilising influence our glorious empire was and ignore completely the misery its establishment engendered and the huge number of deaths that were thought necessary for it to continue civilising 'savages'. And what after all, you might care to argue, is the 'truth'? One man's truth is another man's folly, perhaps, or one man's open mind is another man's gullibility. Well, I'll gracefully take the point but respond by pointing out the facts I cited above of the comparative freedoms and affluence of blacks and coloureds compared to whites in America. And I might ask why, when Hurricane Katrina devastated large parts of New Orleans, was hardly any assistance offered for several days? Why, it might be something to do with the fact that establishment America didn't and doesn't quite rate a black chocolate city like New Orleans has high as rather more top-drawer municipalities (although down-at-heel white communities aren't exactly privileged). And when we talk of 'establishment America', we might add that Hollywood and its filmmakers are one of its essential constituent parts. By all means enjoy Amistad as a film, a piece of fiction, but please don't run away with the idea that despite portraying historical incidents - although one larded with fictional characters: Morgan Freeman's dandified citizen is especially offensive, particularly since every other black face in the film is, if not an African from the Amistad, a servant or pauper. The incessant and remorseless feelgood soundtrack should serve as a warning: on and on and on it goes, all patriotic flutes, trumpets, syrupy strings. A good case could be made about accompanying some film soundtracks with the notice that 'this soundtrack can adversely influence your judgement'. When a 15-minute scene of a grand American figure such as John Quincy Adams grandly making grandly patriotic observations has a backdrop of such a patriotic melange of flutes, trumpets and strings, you just know something very rum is going on. Giving Amistad a rating presents a real problem: as filmmaking it is very fine indeed and Spielberg is a filmmaker almost without peer. But unfortunately a film which sets out to do what he has attempted to do needs more, not least true honesty, so this one, Stevie, can only get a five, because five is halfway between zero and ten.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Slave Courtroom Drama.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Steven Spielberg directs this authentic looking film that tells the story of African tribal leader Cinque(Djimon Hounsou) who is sold into slavery by another tribe and is on a ship from Cuba to the U.S. when he leads a revolt against their cruel captors, killing them. The crew is later captured and put on trial as being murderous runaway slaves, when an abolitionist lawyer(played by Mathew McConaughey) comes to their defense, but, despite winning the case, is undermined by a presidential appeal, so turns to former president John Quincy Adams(played magnificently by Anthony Hopkins) to plead the case before the U.S Supreme Court. Good drama has fine acting by all, harrowing ship-board recreation of the slave revolt, though has its fair share of dramatic lulls as well, though does have a memorable end.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    'Amistad' is one of the most powerful movies I have ever seen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    janet-turpie-johnstone
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Stories such as this need to be continually told and retold - for every generation produces its great and awful people and circumstances. For me, Amistad gave me the most profound memory I can never lose "I will call to the past, to the beginning of time and beg them to come and help me. they will come, I will draw them into me. I am the whole reason they have existed at all." How many of us can acknowledge the reconditeness of this remarkable human strength, We know our past and our future, we are a continuous stream of life and each generational makes the past important and the past declares the present. As one with an Aboriginal heritage this for me is great truth.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Such a Potent History Lesson!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    g-bodyl
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Amistad is a surprisingly great movie that is a welcome addition into the filmography of Steven Spielberg. It has some courtroom clich&eacute;s and some typical Spielberg drama fluff, but it overcomes those minor obstacles to be a powerful, sometimes-disturbing film about a group of people who yearn for their freedom. The editing is also choppy and sometimes it is hard to pick up what's going on, but this story moved me so much, I didn't care if the editing was sub-par. Amistad, based on a true story, is about a group of African slaves who attempt to escape from their captors, but they are recaptured and sent to America for trial. Now these blacks will have to endure unfairness and racial hatred to find out their fates. The acting is powerful. This is the movie where Djimon Hounsou becomes a star and this movie shows why. His performance as the so-called "alpha male" nearly moved me to tears. Anthony Hopkins, who played John Quincy Adams, delivers one of the best speeches you'll ever hear in the movies. Matthew McConaughey, in one of his early non-romantic roles does a wonderful job. I really love Morgan Freeman, but I'm disappointed he didn't do much in the film. Overall, this is a powerhouse film that shows expert Spielberg direction and wonderful acting. The editing is questionable, but I'll let it slide for a film like this. I honestly didn't expect this to be good as it was so I'm quite happy. I rate this film 9/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Another Spielberg's Masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    denis888
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I haven't watched this movie till very recently and wow, what a movie it has been! This is a sheer work of a genius who is by all means Mr. Steven Spielberg. He does not do anything wrong again and again, and thus in this movie he did a great job, too. The very topic of slavery is so painful and disturbing that it would be wrong to make a sweetly home-video drama with no blood or brutality. Nay, sirs, Amistad did exactly the right job - the movie showed slavery as it is - brutal, bloody, bad, gory, evil, malicious, greedy, horrific and unpardonable. The casting is perfect and there are no bad actors in this movie at all. Even the small part of Anna Paquin as Isabella of Spain is a real gem, what say can we of bigger and even better parts by impeccable Morgan Freeman and Anthony Hopkins? The film is very heavy, full of really unpleasant violence scenes but this all is not for the violence's sake. Nay, again, this all served the ultimate goal - to depict the inhuman nature of human trade, and this excellent movie did that well
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    one of good Steven film forever
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    masanseemay20
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Yes! It is an amazing another great movie from my best director Steven Spielberg. It says story of some slaves who were brought by ship called Amistad. superb cast and crew! my best actor Morgan freeman acts well. I always like to watch to Steven film first off all. recently I watched his latest great movie War horse. after watching some of his great films I became fan of this director and do watch his films continually. He makes every thing beautifully as much as he can. Another great is its music. woww!! what a heartbreaking violin in last scenes. john William makes it perfect. finally, well directed and well acted film forever.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    All About African Slavery
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Amistad is a historical film directed by Steven Spielberg.The movie stars a talented cast that includes Morgan Freeman,Anthony Hopkins,Djimon Hounsou,Matthew McConaughey,Nigel Hawthorne,Stellan Skarsg&aring;rd,Harry Blackmun and Anna Paquin. It was based on the true story of an uprising in 1839 by newly captured African slaves that took place aboard the ship La Amistad off the coast of Cuba, the subsequent voyage to the Northeastern United States, and the legal battle that followed their capture by a United States revenue cutter. It shows how, even though the case was won at the federal district court level, it was appealed by President Martin Van Buren to the Supreme Court, and how former President John Quincy Adams took part in the proceedings. The movie opens showing Cinque and the other Africans in a violent takeover of the Amistad. Captured, they are imprisoned in New England where former slave Theodore Joadson, viewing the rebels as "freedom fighters," approaches property lawyer Baldwin, who attempts to prove the Africans were "stolen goods" because they were kidnapped. Running for re-election, President Martin Van Buren overturns the lower court's decision in favor of the Africans. Former President John Quincy Adams is reluctant to become involved, but when the case moves on to the Supreme Court, Adams stirs emotions with a powerful defense. The story line occasionally cuts away to Spain where the young Queen Isabella plays with dolls; she later debated the Amistad case with seven U.S. presidents. Amistad is worth seeing just for people to know about this important story, this moment in history.This is the most straightforward, understated, and powerful big-screen representation of the slavery in recent movie history. And for that, it should be recommended to everyone.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Masterful directing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bitesizemoviereview dotblogspotdotcom
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Combine an award-winning director, a talented cast, a poignant musical score and breathtaking cinematography with one of the darkest hours of world history, and you get Amistad, widely regarded as the definitive film about the trans-Atlantic slave trade. While the plot is focused on the Amistad case, the film itself reverberates with the broader issue of slavery, including anti-slavery figures such as John Quincy Adams. My favorite scene was when the African men enter a church and thumb through an illustrated Bible, able to identify with the sufferings of Christ, after which Spielberg ingeniously shows the masts of three ships, resembling the three crosses. Brilliant and heartbreaking, Amistad captures the struggle of these men and a very determined lawyer to win their freedom. With masterful directing, Spielberg draws upon the lessons of history to forge an acclaimed film that celebrates hope and freedom even in the darkest of times. http://bitesizemoviereview.blogspot.com/
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Extremely worthwhile for the historical perspective, IMO
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bob Pr.
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This tells the story of potential African slaves, the cargo on "Amistad," a Spanish sailing ship, who revolted (1839) and ended up in American jails and courts. -- Will they be hung for killing their captors? -- Or 'property' that will be returned to their purchasers? The film traces their journey from Africa through various US courts and their outcomes that often intermixed with the looming domestic political issue, a sleeping gorilla: that of 1840s pre-Civil War slavery in the U.S. south. The scenes in Africa and shipboard of the treatment of captured slaves have some unsettling ("R" rated) cruelty. But "Amistad" is largely a drama of historical courtroom events (IMO, grossly accurate with exceptions that will be minor to many, major to a few). Hopkins (as a lawyer, the former president, John Quincy Adams) got a deserved Oscar nomination for his supporting role. Freeman plays quite well a wholly invented, minor role (as a former slave & successful businessman in the 1840s North--who you trying to kid, Spielberg?!?!). McConaughey does a great job as the initial lawyer representing the Africans. Hounsu, as the captive African chief, is also very good. This film provides a fascinating U.S. history lesson brought very much alive. Wikipedia has several articles pertinent to this: see both "Amistad" (for the film, related places, writings, actual events, etc.) and also "Tecora" (the Portuguese slave ship which took the Africans to Cuba); these help those who are interested to distinguish much of who, where & when this film captures or distorts historical truths. See also the "Did You Know?" section on IMDb's "Amistad" main page; this covers some points not in the Wikipedia articles. I was extremely glad I saw this film for the knowledge gained despite its sometimes dramatized departures from utter truths.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Schindler's list for Amerika (cinematheque)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leplatypus
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As someone said it in the movie, the slaves had nothing to fear from their masters because as they work for them, they wouldn't be killed. So for me the only difference between slavery and holocaust is the lack of genocide. Besides this, it's the same oppression, the same racism: just see the way of how slaves were treated during the crossing and they are similar to the future extermination camps. But it's true that somewhere condemnation of slavery isn't as known as holocaust. Maybe the unfortunate explanation is that the masters are not beaten ones like Germany but as the movie shows the entire enlightened nations. As Tocqueville wrote, slavery was a shameful thorn in America democracy and Spielberg as a humanist American filmmaker couldn't avoid the subject. And he did in his own way, the same than in "Schindler's", that is to say showing that courage and hope are more powerful that the darkest time, the worst atrocities. Foretelling his later "Minority reports" or "Munich", he throws a very critic look at authorities and for the first apparition of POTUS in his work (a real plague in a lot of American movies) and whispers critics that could have pleased his colleague Stone. But his optimism is also visually contagious: compare the first terrifying look of Cinque and his latter appearances and you can see an happy hand. The only flaw of the movie is finally his title because it's doesn't tell very much what's about: "Amistad vs the people of America" would have been better... Pairing: "Schindler's list": before it, the allies were also evil forces...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Exquisitely made feelgood schlock which ultimately tells a big lie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    patrick powell
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As a film, as entertainment, as a night at the flicks, as a great way to spend well over two hours wallowing in non-stop feelgoodery Amistad is superb, and Steven Spielberg does quite brilliantly what only he and a few others can achieve. The acting is the finest, his actors are the finest, his script is the finest, his direction in which he balances action with reflection is the finest, and no doubt as for cinematography, sound design, editing and the rest a man of Spielberg's stature in the industry is able to employ the finest professionals working in film-making and he so obviously does so. So why do I feel that at the end of the day Spielberg's Amistad is simply nothing but 154 minutes of appalling sentimental schlock and, worse, appalling and dishonest sentimental schlock. I have no doubt that after watching Amistad Americans in their thousands have left the cinemas or turned off their DVD player and thought to themselves or even said out aloud: We are the finest nation on Earth and while we exist, the world is truly a better place. Well, perhaps all those who did and do so might care to pause a moment or two and ask themselves why the proportion of black and coloured inmates in U.S. jails compared to whites is still higher than the proportion of blacks and coloureds which make up the population of the U.S. They might care to ask themselves why a higher proportion of blacks and coloureds are unemployed, live in poverty and have a far lower standard of education. They might care to ask themselves why, almost 60 years after the hearing of the Amistad case before the Supreme Court the so-called Jim Crow laws were enacted denying blacks anything but equality with whites. But it's just a film, you might be saying, come on, don't be so uptight about it. Well, granted that it's not just the Americans but we Brits and the French, the Germans, the Russians, in fact every nation on earth who regularly chose to rewrite its history in films, novels, plays and poetry the calumny is not isolated or even unusual. We Brits like to bang on about what a civilising influence our glorious empire was and ignore completely the misery its establishment engendered and the huge number of deaths that were thought necessary for it to continue civilising 'savages'. And what after all, you might care to argue, is the 'truth'? One man's truth is another man's folly, perhaps, or one man's open mind is another man's gullibility. Well, I'll gracefully take the point but respond by pointing out the facts I cited above of the comparative freedoms and affluence of blacks and coloureds compared to whites in America. And I might ask why, when Hurricane Katrina devastated large parts of New Orleans, was hardly any assistance offered for several days? Why, it might be something to do with the fact that establishment America didn't and doesn't quite rate a black chocolate city like New Orleans has high as rather more top-drawer municipalities (although down-at-heel white communities aren't exactly privileged). And when we talk of 'establishment America', we might add that Hollywood and its filmmakers are one of its essential constituent parts. By all means enjoy Amistad as a film, a piece of fiction, but please don't run away with the idea that despite portraying historical incidents - although one larded with fictional characters: Morgan Freeman's dandified citizen is especially offensive, particularly since every other black face in the film is, if not an African from the Amistad, a servant or pauper. The incessant and remorseless feelgood soundtrack should serve as a warning: on and on and on it goes, all patriotic flutes, trumpets, syrupy strings. A good case could be made about accompanying some film soundtracks with the notice that 'this soundtrack can adversely influence your judgement'. When a 15-minute scene of a grand American figure such as John Quincy Adams grandly making grandly patriotic observations has a backdrop of such a patriotic melange of flutes, trumpets and strings, you just know something very rum is going on. Giving Amistad a rating presents a real problem: as filmmaking it is very fine indeed and Spielberg is a filmmaker almost without peer. But unfortunately a film which sets out to do what he has attempted to do needs more, not least true honesty, so this one, Stevie, can only get a five, because five is halfway between zero and ten.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Slave Courtroom Drama.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Steven Spielberg directs this authentic looking film that tells the story of African tribal leader Cinque(Djimon Hounsou) who is sold into slavery by another tribe and is on a ship from Cuba to the U.S. when he leads a revolt against their cruel captors, killing them. The crew is later captured and put on trial as being murderous runaway slaves, when an abolitionist lawyer(played by Mathew McConaughey) comes to their defense, but, despite winning the case, is undermined by a presidential appeal, so turns to former president John Quincy Adams(played magnificently by Anthony Hopkins) to plead the case before the U.S Supreme Court. Good drama has fine acting by all, harrowing ship-board recreation of the slave revolt, though has its fair share of dramatic lulls as well, though does have a memorable end.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    'Amistad' is one of the most powerful movies I have ever seen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    janet-turpie-johnstone
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Stories such as this need to be continually told and retold - for every generation produces its great and awful people and circumstances. For me, Amistad gave me the most profound memory I can never lose "I will call to the past, to the beginning of time and beg them to come and help me. they will come, I will draw them into me. I am the whole reason they have existed at all." How many of us can acknowledge the reconditeness of this remarkable human strength, We know our past and our future, we are a continuous stream of life and each generational makes the past important and the past declares the present. As one with an Aboriginal heritage this for me is great truth.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Such a Potent History Lesson!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    g-bodyl
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Amistad is a surprisingly great movie that is a welcome addition into the filmography of Steven Spielberg. It has some courtroom clich&eacute;s and some typical Spielberg drama fluff, but it overcomes those minor obstacles to be a powerful, sometimes-disturbing film about a group of people who yearn for their freedom. The editing is also choppy and sometimes it is hard to pick up what's going on, but this story moved me so much, I didn't care if the editing was sub-par. Amistad, based on a true story, is about a group of African slaves who attempt to escape from their captors, but they are recaptured and sent to America for trial. Now these blacks will have to endure unfairness and racial hatred to find out their fates. The acting is powerful. This is the movie where Djimon Hounsou becomes a star and this movie shows why. His performance as the so-called "alpha male" nearly moved me to tears. Anthony Hopkins, who played John Quincy Adams, delivers one of the best speeches you'll ever hear in the movies. Matthew McConaughey, in one of his early non-romantic roles does a wonderful job. I really love Morgan Freeman, but I'm disappointed he didn't do much in the film. Overall, this is a powerhouse film that shows expert Spielberg direction and wonderful acting. The editing is questionable, but I'll let it slide for a film like this. I honestly didn't expect this to be good as it was so I'm quite happy. I rate this film 9/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Another Spielberg's Masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    denis888
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I haven't watched this movie till very recently and wow, what a movie it has been! This is a sheer work of a genius who is by all means Mr. Steven Spielberg. He does not do anything wrong again and again, and thus in this movie he did a great job, too. The very topic of slavery is so painful and disturbing that it would be wrong to make a sweetly home-video drama with no blood or brutality. Nay, sirs, Amistad did exactly the right job - the movie showed slavery as it is - brutal, bloody, bad, gory, evil, malicious, greedy, horrific and unpardonable. The casting is perfect and there are no bad actors in this movie at all. Even the small part of Anna Paquin as Isabella of Spain is a real gem, what say can we of bigger and even better parts by impeccable Morgan Freeman and Anthony Hopkins? The film is very heavy, full of really unpleasant violence scenes but this all is not for the violence's sake. Nay, again, this all served the ultimate goal - to depict the inhuman nature of human trade, and this excellent movie did that well
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    one of good Steven film forever
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    masanseemay20
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Yes! It is an amazing another great movie from my best director Steven Spielberg. It says story of some slaves who were brought by ship called Amistad. superb cast and crew! my best actor Morgan freeman acts well. I always like to watch to Steven film first off all. recently I watched his latest great movie War horse. after watching some of his great films I became fan of this director and do watch his films continually. He makes every thing beautifully as much as he can. Another great is its music. woww!! what a heartbreaking violin in last scenes. john William makes it perfect. finally, well directed and well acted film forever.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    All About African Slavery
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Amistad is a historical film directed by Steven Spielberg.The movie stars a talented cast that includes Morgan Freeman,Anthony Hopkins,Djimon Hounsou,Matthew McConaughey,Nigel Hawthorne,Stellan Skarsg&aring;rd,Harry Blackmun and Anna Paquin. It was based on the true story of an uprising in 1839 by newly captured African slaves that took place aboard the ship La Amistad off the coast of Cuba, the subsequent voyage to the Northeastern United States, and the legal battle that followed their capture by a United States revenue cutter. It shows how, even though the case was won at the federal district court level, it was appealed by President Martin Van Buren to the Supreme Court, and how former President John Quincy Adams took part in the proceedings. The movie opens showing Cinque and the other Africans in a violent takeover of the Amistad. Captured, they are imprisoned in New England where former slave Theodore Joadson, viewing the rebels as "freedom fighters," approaches property lawyer Baldwin, who attempts to prove the Africans were "stolen goods" because they were kidnapped. Running for re-election, President Martin Van Buren overturns the lower court's decision in favor of the Africans. Former President John Quincy Adams is reluctant to become involved, but when the case moves on to the Supreme Court, Adams stirs emotions with a powerful defense. The story line occasionally cuts away to Spain where the young Queen Isabella plays with dolls; she later debated the Amistad case with seven U.S. presidents. Amistad is worth seeing just for people to know about this important story, this moment in history.This is the most straightforward, understated, and powerful big-screen representation of the slavery in recent movie history. And for that, it should be recommended to everyone.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Masterful directing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bitesizemoviereview dotblogspotdotcom
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Combine an award-winning director, a talented cast, a poignant musical score and breathtaking cinematography with one of the darkest hours of world history, and you get Amistad, widely regarded as the definitive film about the trans-Atlantic slave trade. While the plot is focused on the Amistad case, the film itself reverberates with the broader issue of slavery, including anti-slavery figures such as John Quincy Adams. My favorite scene was when the African men enter a church and thumb through an illustrated Bible, able to identify with the sufferings of Christ, after which Spielberg ingeniously shows the masts of three ships, resembling the three crosses. Brilliant and heartbreaking, Amistad captures the struggle of these men and a very determined lawyer to win their freedom. With masterful directing, Spielberg draws upon the lessons of history to forge an acclaimed film that celebrates hope and freedom even in the darkest of times. http://bitesizemoviereview.blogspot.com/
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Extremely worthwhile for the historical perspective, IMO
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bob Pr.
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This tells the story of potential African slaves, the cargo on "Amistad," a Spanish sailing ship, who revolted (1839) and ended up in American jails and courts. -- Will they be hung for killing their captors? -- Or 'property' that will be returned to their purchasers? The film traces their journey from Africa through various US courts and their outcomes that often intermixed with the looming domestic political issue, a sleeping gorilla: that of 1840s pre-Civil War slavery in the U.S. south. The scenes in Africa and shipboard of the treatment of captured slaves have some unsettling ("R" rated) cruelty. But "Amistad" is largely a drama of historical courtroom events (IMO, grossly accurate with exceptions that will be minor to many, major to a few). Hopkins (as a lawyer, the former president, John Quincy Adams) got a deserved Oscar nomination for his supporting role. Freeman plays quite well a wholly invented, minor role (as a former slave & successful businessman in the 1840s North--who you trying to kid, Spielberg?!?!). McConaughey does a great job as the initial lawyer representing the Africans. Hounsu, as the captive African chief, is also very good. This film provides a fascinating U.S. history lesson brought very much alive. Wikipedia has several articles pertinent to this: see both "Amistad" (for the film, related places, writings, actual events, etc.) and also "Tecora" (the Portuguese slave ship which took the Africans to Cuba); these help those who are interested to distinguish much of who, where & when this film captures or distorts historical truths. See also the "Did You Know?" section on IMDb's "Amistad" main page; this covers some points not in the Wikipedia articles. I was extremely glad I saw this film for the knowledge gained despite its sometimes dramatized departures from utter truths.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Schindler's list for Amerika (cinematheque)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leplatypus
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As someone said it in the movie, the slaves had nothing to fear from their masters because as they work for them, they wouldn't be killed. So for me the only difference between slavery and holocaust is the lack of genocide. Besides this, it's the same oppression, the same racism: just see the way of how slaves were treated during the crossing and they are similar to the future extermination camps. But it's true that somewhere condemnation of slavery isn't as known as holocaust. Maybe the unfortunate explanation is that the masters are not beaten ones like Germany but as the movie shows the entire enlightened nations. As Tocqueville wrote, slavery was a shameful thorn in America democracy and Spielberg as a humanist American filmmaker couldn't avoid the subject. And he did in his own way, the same than in "Schindler's", that is to say showing that courage and hope are more powerful that the darkest time, the worst atrocities. Foretelling his later "Minority reports" or "Munich", he throws a very critic look at authorities and for the first apparition of POTUS in his work (a real plague in a lot of American movies) and whispers critics that could have pleased his colleague Stone. But his optimism is also visually contagious: compare the first terrifying look of Cinque and his latter appearances and you can see an happy hand. The only flaw of the movie is finally his title because it's doesn't tell very much what's about: "Amistad vs the people of America" would have been better... Pairing: "Schindler's list": before it, the allies were also evil forces...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Exquisitely made feelgood schlock which ultimately tells a big lie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    patrick powell
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As a film, as entertainment, as a night at the flicks, as a great way to spend well over two hours wallowing in non-stop feelgoodery Amistad is superb, and Steven Spielberg does quite brilliantly what only he and a few others can achieve. The acting is the finest, his actors are the finest, his script is the finest, his direction in which he balances action with reflection is the finest, and no doubt as for cinematography, sound design, editing and the rest a man of Spielberg's stature in the industry is able to employ the finest professionals working in film-making and he so obviously does so. So why do I feel that at the end of the day Spielberg's Amistad is simply nothing but 154 minutes of appalling sentimental schlock and, worse, appalling and dishonest sentimental schlock. I have no doubt that after watching Amistad Americans in their thousands have left the cinemas or turned off their DVD player and thought to themselves or even said out aloud: We are the finest nation on Earth and while we exist, the world is truly a better place. Well, perhaps all those who did and do so might care to pause a moment or two and ask themselves why the proportion of black and coloured inmates in U.S. jails compared to whites is still higher than the proportion of blacks and coloureds which make up the population of the U.S. They might care to ask themselves why a higher proportion of blacks and coloureds are unemployed, live in poverty and have a far lower standard of education. They might care to ask themselves why, almost 60 years after the hearing of the Amistad case before the Supreme Court the so-called Jim Crow laws were enacted denying blacks anything but equality with whites. But it's just a film, you might be saying, come on, don't be so uptight about it. Well, granted that it's not just the Americans but we Brits and the French, the Germans, the Russians, in fact every nation on earth who regularly chose to rewrite its history in films, novels, plays and poetry the calumny is not isolated or even unusual. We Brits like to bang on about what a civilising influence our glorious empire was and ignore completely the misery its establishment engendered and the huge number of deaths that were thought necessary for it to continue civilising 'savages'. And what after all, you might care to argue, is the 'truth'? One man's truth is another man's folly, perhaps, or one man's open mind is another man's gullibility. Well, I'll gracefully take the point but respond by pointing out the facts I cited above of the comparative freedoms and affluence of blacks and coloureds compared to whites in America. And I might ask why, when Hurricane Katrina devastated large parts of New Orleans, was hardly any assistance offered for several days? Why, it might be something to do with the fact that establishment America didn't and doesn't quite rate a black chocolate city like New Orleans has high as rather more top-drawer municipalities (although down-at-heel white communities aren't exactly privileged). And when we talk of 'establishment America', we might add that Hollywood and its filmmakers are one of its essential constituent parts. By all means enjoy Amistad as a film, a piece of fiction, but please don't run away with the idea that despite portraying historical incidents - although one larded with fictional characters: Morgan Freeman's dandified citizen is especially offensive, particularly since every other black face in the film is, if not an African from the Amistad, a servant or pauper. The incessant and remorseless feelgood soundtrack should serve as a warning: on and on and on it goes, all patriotic flutes, trumpets, syrupy strings. A good case could be made about accompanying some film soundtracks with the notice that 'this soundtrack can adversely influence your judgement'. When a 15-minute scene of a grand American figure such as John Quincy Adams grandly making grandly patriotic observations has a backdrop of such a patriotic melange of flutes, trumpets and strings, you just know something very rum is going on. Giving Amistad a rating presents a real problem: as filmmaking it is very fine indeed and Spielberg is a filmmaker almost without peer. But unfortunately a film which sets out to do what he has attempted to do needs more, not least true honesty, so this one, Stevie, can only get a five, because five is halfway between zero and ten.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Slave Courtroom Drama.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Steven Spielberg directs this authentic looking film that tells the story of African tribal leader Cinque(Djimon Hounsou) who is sold into slavery by another tribe and is on a ship from Cuba to the U.S. when he leads a revolt against their cruel captors, killing them. The crew is later captured and put on trial as being murderous runaway slaves, when an abolitionist lawyer(played by Mathew McConaughey) comes to their defense, but, despite winning the case, is undermined by a presidential appeal, so turns to former president John Quincy Adams(played magnificently by Anthony Hopkins) to plead the case before the U.S Supreme Court. Good drama has fine acting by all, harrowing ship-board recreation of the slave revolt, though has its fair share of dramatic lulls as well, though does have a memorable end.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    'Amistad' is one of the most powerful movies I have ever seen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    janet-turpie-johnstone
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Stories such as this need to be continually told and retold - for every generation produces its great and awful people and circumstances. For me, Amistad gave me the most profound memory I can never lose "I will call to the past, to the beginning of time and beg them to come and help me. they will come, I will draw them into me. I am the whole reason they have existed at all." How many of us can acknowledge the reconditeness of this remarkable human strength, We know our past and our future, we are a continuous stream of life and each generational makes the past important and the past declares the present. As one with an Aboriginal heritage this for me is great truth.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Such a Potent History Lesson!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    g-bodyl
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Amistad is a surprisingly great movie that is a welcome addition into the filmography of Steven Spielberg. It has some courtroom clich&eacute;s and some typical Spielberg drama fluff, but it overcomes those minor obstacles to be a powerful, sometimes-disturbing film about a group of people who yearn for their freedom. The editing is also choppy and sometimes it is hard to pick up what's going on, but this story moved me so much, I didn't care if the editing was sub-par. Amistad, based on a true story, is about a group of African slaves who attempt to escape from their captors, but they are recaptured and sent to America for trial. Now these blacks will have to endure unfairness and racial hatred to find out their fates. The acting is powerful. This is the movie where Djimon Hounsou becomes a star and this movie shows why. His performance as the so-called "alpha male" nearly moved me to tears. Anthony Hopkins, who played John Quincy Adams, delivers one of the best speeches you'll ever hear in the movies. Matthew McConaughey, in one of his early non-romantic roles does a wonderful job. I really love Morgan Freeman, but I'm disappointed he didn't do much in the film. Overall, this is a powerhouse film that shows expert Spielberg direction and wonderful acting. The editing is questionable, but I'll let it slide for a film like this. I honestly didn't expect this to be good as it was so I'm quite happy. I rate this film 9/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Another Spielberg's Masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    denis888
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I haven't watched this movie till very recently and wow, what a movie it has been! This is a sheer work of a genius who is by all means Mr. Steven Spielberg. He does not do anything wrong again and again, and thus in this movie he did a great job, too. The very topic of slavery is so painful and disturbing that it would be wrong to make a sweetly home-video drama with no blood or brutality. Nay, sirs, Amistad did exactly the right job - the movie showed slavery as it is - brutal, bloody, bad, gory, evil, malicious, greedy, horrific and unpardonable. The casting is perfect and there are no bad actors in this movie at all. Even the small part of Anna Paquin as Isabella of Spain is a real gem, what say can we of bigger and even better parts by impeccable Morgan Freeman and Anthony Hopkins? The film is very heavy, full of really unpleasant violence scenes but this all is not for the violence's sake. Nay, again, this all served the ultimate goal - to depict the inhuman nature of human trade, and this excellent movie did that well
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    one of good Steven film forever
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    masanseemay20
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Yes! It is an amazing another great movie from my best director Steven Spielberg. It says story of some slaves who were brought by ship called Amistad. superb cast and crew! my best actor Morgan freeman acts well. I always like to watch to Steven film first off all. recently I watched his latest great movie War horse. after watching some of his great films I became fan of this director and do watch his films continually. He makes every thing beautifully as much as he can. Another great is its music. woww!! what a heartbreaking violin in last scenes. john William makes it perfect. finally, well directed and well acted film forever.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    All About African Slavery
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Amistad is a historical film directed by Steven Spielberg.The movie stars a talented cast that includes Morgan Freeman,Anthony Hopkins,Djimon Hounsou,Matthew McConaughey,Nigel Hawthorne,Stellan Skarsg&aring;rd,Harry Blackmun and Anna Paquin. It was based on the true story of an uprising in 1839 by newly captured African slaves that took place aboard the ship La Amistad off the coast of Cuba, the subsequent voyage to the Northeastern United States, and the legal battle that followed their capture by a United States revenue cutter. It shows how, even though the case was won at the federal district court level, it was appealed by President Martin Van Buren to the Supreme Court, and how former President John Quincy Adams took part in the proceedings. The movie opens showing Cinque and the other Africans in a violent takeover of the Amistad. Captured, they are imprisoned in New England where former slave Theodore Joadson, viewing the rebels as "freedom fighters," approaches property lawyer Baldwin, who attempts to prove the Africans were "stolen goods" because they were kidnapped. Running for re-election, President Martin Van Buren overturns the lower court's decision in favor of the Africans. Former President John Quincy Adams is reluctant to become involved, but when the case moves on to the Supreme Court, Adams stirs emotions with a powerful defense. The story line occasionally cuts away to Spain where the young Queen Isabella plays with dolls; she later debated the Amistad case with seven U.S. presidents. Amistad is worth seeing just for people to know about this important story, this moment in history.This is the most straightforward, understated, and powerful big-screen representation of the slavery in recent movie history. And for that, it should be recommended to everyone.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Masterful directing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bitesizemoviereview dotblogspotdotcom
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Combine an award-winning director, a talented cast, a poignant musical score and breathtaking cinematography with one of the darkest hours of world history, and you get Amistad, widely regarded as the definitive film about the trans-Atlantic slave trade. While the plot is focused on the Amistad case, the film itself reverberates with the broader issue of slavery, including anti-slavery figures such as John Quincy Adams. My favorite scene was when the African men enter a church and thumb through an illustrated Bible, able to identify with the sufferings of Christ, after which Spielberg ingeniously shows the masts of three ships, resembling the three crosses. Brilliant and heartbreaking, Amistad captures the struggle of these men and a very determined lawyer to win their freedom. With masterful directing, Spielberg draws upon the lessons of history to forge an acclaimed film that celebrates hope and freedom even in the darkest of times. http://bitesizemoviereview.blogspot.com/
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Extremely worthwhile for the historical perspective, IMO
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bob Pr.
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This tells the story of potential African slaves, the cargo on "Amistad," a Spanish sailing ship, who revolted (1839) and ended up in American jails and courts. -- Will they be hung for killing their captors? -- Or 'property' that will be returned to their purchasers? The film traces their journey from Africa through various US courts and their outcomes that often intermixed with the looming domestic political issue, a sleeping gorilla: that of 1840s pre-Civil War slavery in the U.S. south. The scenes in Africa and shipboard of the treatment of captured slaves have some unsettling ("R" rated) cruelty. But "Amistad" is largely a drama of historical courtroom events (IMO, grossly accurate with exceptions that will be minor to many, major to a few). Hopkins (as a lawyer, the former president, John Quincy Adams) got a deserved Oscar nomination for his supporting role. Freeman plays quite well a wholly invented, minor role (as a former slave & successful businessman in the 1840s North--who you trying to kid, Spielberg?!?!). McConaughey does a great job as the initial lawyer representing the Africans. Hounsu, as the captive African chief, is also very good. This film provides a fascinating U.S. history lesson brought very much alive. Wikipedia has several articles pertinent to this: see both "Amistad" (for the film, related places, writings, actual events, etc.) and also "Tecora" (the Portuguese slave ship which took the Africans to Cuba); these help those who are interested to distinguish much of who, where & when this film captures or distorts historical truths. See also the "Did You Know?" section on IMDb's "Amistad" main page; this covers some points not in the Wikipedia articles. I was extremely glad I saw this film for the knowledge gained despite its sometimes dramatized departures from utter truths.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Schindler's list for Amerika (cinematheque)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leplatypus
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As someone said it in the movie, the slaves had nothing to fear from their masters because as they work for them, they wouldn't be killed. So for me the only difference between slavery and holocaust is the lack of genocide. Besides this, it's the same oppression, the same racism: just see the way of how slaves were treated during the crossing and they are similar to the future extermination camps. But it's true that somewhere condemnation of slavery isn't as known as holocaust. Maybe the unfortunate explanation is that the masters are not beaten ones like Germany but as the movie shows the entire enlightened nations. As Tocqueville wrote, slavery was a shameful thorn in America democracy and Spielberg as a humanist American filmmaker couldn't avoid the subject. And he did in his own way, the same than in "Schindler's", that is to say showing that courage and hope are more powerful that the darkest time, the worst atrocities. Foretelling his later "Minority reports" or "Munich", he throws a very critic look at authorities and for the first apparition of POTUS in his work (a real plague in a lot of American movies) and whispers critics that could have pleased his colleague Stone. But his optimism is also visually contagious: compare the first terrifying look of Cinque and his latter appearances and you can see an happy hand. The only flaw of the movie is finally his title because it's doesn't tell very much what's about: "Amistad vs the people of America" would have been better... Pairing: "Schindler's list": before it, the allies were also evil forces...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Exquisitely made feelgood schlock which ultimately tells a big lie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    patrick powell
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As a film, as entertainment, as a night at the flicks, as a great way to spend well over two hours wallowing in non-stop feelgoodery Amistad is superb, and Steven Spielberg does quite brilliantly what only he and a few others can achieve. The acting is the finest, his actors are the finest, his script is the finest, his direction in which he balances action with reflection is the finest, and no doubt as for cinematography, sound design, editing and the rest a man of Spielberg's stature in the industry is able to employ the finest professionals working in film-making and he so obviously does so. So why do I feel that at the end of the day Spielberg's Amistad is simply nothing but 154 minutes of appalling sentimental schlock and, worse, appalling and dishonest sentimental schlock. I have no doubt that after watching Amistad Americans in their thousands have left the cinemas or turned off their DVD player and thought to themselves or even said out aloud: We are the finest nation on Earth and while we exist, the world is truly a better place. Well, perhaps all those who did and do so might care to pause a moment or two and ask themselves why the proportion of black and coloured inmates in U.S. jails compared to whites is still higher than the proportion of blacks and coloureds which make up the population of the U.S. They might care to ask themselves why a higher proportion of blacks and coloureds are unemployed, live in poverty and have a far lower standard of education. They might care to ask themselves why, almost 60 years after the hearing of the Amistad case before the Supreme Court the so-called Jim Crow laws were enacted denying blacks anything but equality with whites. But it's just a film, you might be saying, come on, don't be so uptight about it. Well, granted that it's not just the Americans but we Brits and the French, the Germans, the Russians, in fact every nation on earth who regularly chose to rewrite its history in films, novels, plays and poetry the calumny is not isolated or even unusual. We Brits like to bang on about what a civilising influence our glorious empire was and ignore completely the misery its establishment engendered and the huge number of deaths that were thought necessary for it to continue civilising 'savages'. And what after all, you might care to argue, is the 'truth'? One man's truth is another man's folly, perhaps, or one man's open mind is another man's gullibility. Well, I'll gracefully take the point but respond by pointing out the facts I cited above of the comparative freedoms and affluence of blacks and coloureds compared to whites in America. And I might ask why, when Hurricane Katrina devastated large parts of New Orleans, was hardly any assistance offered for several days? Why, it might be something to do with the fact that establishment America didn't and doesn't quite rate a black chocolate city like New Orleans has high as rather more top-drawer municipalities (although down-at-heel white communities aren't exactly privileged). And when we talk of 'establishment America', we might add that Hollywood and its filmmakers are one of its essential constituent parts. By all means enjoy Amistad as a film, a piece of fiction, but please don't run away with the idea that despite portraying historical incidents - although one larded with fictional characters: Morgan Freeman's dandified citizen is especially offensive, particularly since every other black face in the film is, if not an African from the Amistad, a servant or pauper. The incessant and remorseless feelgood soundtrack should serve as a warning: on and on and on it goes, all patriotic flutes, trumpets, syrupy strings. A good case could be made about accompanying some film soundtracks with the notice that 'this soundtrack can adversely influence your judgement'. When a 15-minute scene of a grand American figure such as John Quincy Adams grandly making grandly patriotic observations has a backdrop of such a patriotic melange of flutes, trumpets and strings, you just know something very rum is going on. Giving Amistad a rating presents a real problem: as filmmaking it is very fine indeed and Spielberg is a filmmaker almost without peer. But unfortunately a film which sets out to do what he has attempted to do needs more, not least true honesty, so this one, Stevie, can only get a five, because five is halfway between zero and ten.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Slave Courtroom Drama.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Steven Spielberg directs this authentic looking film that tells the story of African tribal leader Cinque(Djimon Hounsou) who is sold into slavery by another tribe and is on a ship from Cuba to the U.S. when he leads a revolt against their cruel captors, killing them. The crew is later captured and put on trial as being murderous runaway slaves, when an abolitionist lawyer(played by Mathew McConaughey) comes to their defense, but, despite winning the case, is undermined by a presidential appeal, so turns to former president John Quincy Adams(played magnificently by Anthony Hopkins) to plead the case before the U.S Supreme Court. Good drama has fine acting by all, harrowing ship-board recreation of the slave revolt, though has its fair share of dramatic lulls as well, though does have a memorable end.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    'Amistad' is one of the most powerful movies I have ever seen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    janet-turpie-johnstone
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Stories such as this need to be continually told and retold - for every generation produces its great and awful people and circumstances. For me, Amistad gave me the most profound memory I can never lose "I will call to the past, to the beginning of time and beg them to come and help me. they will come, I will draw them into me. I am the whole reason they have existed at all." How many of us can acknowledge the reconditeness of this remarkable human strength, We know our past and our future, we are a continuous stream of life and each generational makes the past important and the past declares the present. As one with an Aboriginal heritage this for me is great truth.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Such a Potent History Lesson!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    g-bodyl
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Amistad is a surprisingly great movie that is a welcome addition into the filmography of Steven Spielberg. It has some courtroom clich&eacute;s and some typical Spielberg drama fluff, but it overcomes those minor obstacles to be a powerful, sometimes-disturbing film about a group of people who yearn for their freedom. The editing is also choppy and sometimes it is hard to pick up what's going on, but this story moved me so much, I didn't care if the editing was sub-par. Amistad, based on a true story, is about a group of African slaves who attempt to escape from their captors, but they are recaptured and sent to America for trial. Now these blacks will have to endure unfairness and racial hatred to find out their fates. The acting is powerful. This is the movie where Djimon Hounsou becomes a star and this movie shows why. His performance as the so-called "alpha male" nearly moved me to tears. Anthony Hopkins, who played John Quincy Adams, delivers one of the best speeches you'll ever hear in the movies. Matthew McConaughey, in one of his early non-romantic roles does a wonderful job. I really love Morgan Freeman, but I'm disappointed he didn't do much in the film. Overall, this is a powerhouse film that shows expert Spielberg direction and wonderful acting. The editing is questionable, but I'll let it slide for a film like this. I honestly didn't expect this to be good as it was so I'm quite happy. I rate this film 9/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Another Spielberg's Masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    denis888
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I haven't watched this movie till very recently and wow, what a movie it has been! This is a sheer work of a genius who is by all means Mr. Steven Spielberg. He does not do anything wrong again and again, and thus in this movie he did a great job, too. The very topic of slavery is so painful and disturbing that it would be wrong to make a sweetly home-video drama with no blood or brutality. Nay, sirs, Amistad did exactly the right job - the movie showed slavery as it is - brutal, bloody, bad, gory, evil, malicious, greedy, horrific and unpardonable. The casting is perfect and there are no bad actors in this movie at all. Even the small part of Anna Paquin as Isabella of Spain is a real gem, what say can we of bigger and even better parts by impeccable Morgan Freeman and Anthony Hopkins? The film is very heavy, full of really unpleasant violence scenes but this all is not for the violence's sake. Nay, again, this all served the ultimate goal - to depict the inhuman nature of human trade, and this excellent movie did that well
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    one of good Steven film forever
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    masanseemay20
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Yes! It is an amazing another great movie from my best director Steven Spielberg. It says story of some slaves who were brought by ship called Amistad. superb cast and crew! my best actor Morgan freeman acts well. I always like to watch to Steven film first off all. recently I watched his latest great movie War horse. after watching some of his great films I became fan of this director and do watch his films continually. He makes every thing beautifully as much as he can. Another great is its music. woww!! what a heartbreaking violin in last scenes. john William makes it perfect. finally, well directed and well acted film forever.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    All About African Slavery
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Amistad is a historical film directed by Steven Spielberg.The movie stars a talented cast that includes Morgan Freeman,Anthony Hopkins,Djimon Hounsou,Matthew McConaughey,Nigel Hawthorne,Stellan Skarsg&aring;rd,Harry Blackmun and Anna Paquin. It was based on the true story of an uprising in 1839 by newly captured African slaves that took place aboard the ship La Amistad off the coast of Cuba, the subsequent voyage to the Northeastern United States, and the legal battle that followed their capture by a United States revenue cutter. It shows how, even though the case was won at the federal district court level, it was appealed by President Martin Van Buren to the Supreme Court, and how former President John Quincy Adams took part in the proceedings. The movie opens showing Cinque and the other Africans in a violent takeover of the Amistad. Captured, they are imprisoned in New England where former slave Theodore Joadson, viewing the rebels as "freedom fighters," approaches property lawyer Baldwin, who attempts to prove the Africans were "stolen goods" because they were kidnapped. Running for re-election, President Martin Van Buren overturns the lower court's decision in favor of the Africans. Former President John Quincy Adams is reluctant to become involved, but when the case moves on to the Supreme Court, Adams stirs emotions with a powerful defense. The story line occasionally cuts away to Spain where the young Queen Isabella plays with dolls; she later debated the Amistad case with seven U.S. presidents. Amistad is worth seeing just for people to know about this important story, this moment in history.This is the most straightforward, understated, and powerful big-screen representation of the slavery in recent movie history. And for that, it should be recommended to everyone.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Masterful directing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bitesizemoviereview dotblogspotdotcom
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Combine an award-winning director, a talented cast, a poignant musical score and breathtaking cinematography with one of the darkest hours of world history, and you get Amistad, widely regarded as the definitive film about the trans-Atlantic slave trade. While the plot is focused on the Amistad case, the film itself reverberates with the broader issue of slavery, including anti-slavery figures such as John Quincy Adams. My favorite scene was when the African men enter a church and thumb through an illustrated Bible, able to identify with the sufferings of Christ, after which Spielberg ingeniously shows the masts of three ships, resembling the three crosses. Brilliant and heartbreaking, Amistad captures the struggle of these men and a very determined lawyer to win their freedom. With masterful directing, Spielberg draws upon the lessons of history to forge an acclaimed film that celebrates hope and freedom even in the darkest of times. http://bitesizemoviereview.blogspot.com/
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Extremely worthwhile for the historical perspective, IMO
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bob Pr.
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This tells the story of potential African slaves, the cargo on "Amistad," a Spanish sailing ship, who revolted (1839) and ended up in American jails and courts. -- Will they be hung for killing their captors? -- Or 'property' that will be returned to their purchasers? The film traces their journey from Africa through various US courts and their outcomes that often intermixed with the looming domestic political issue, a sleeping gorilla: that of 1840s pre-Civil War slavery in the U.S. south. The scenes in Africa and shipboard of the treatment of captured slaves have some unsettling ("R" rated) cruelty. But "Amistad" is largely a drama of historical courtroom events (IMO, grossly accurate with exceptions that will be minor to many, major to a few). Hopkins (as a lawyer, the former president, John Quincy Adams) got a deserved Oscar nomination for his supporting role. Freeman plays quite well a wholly invented, minor role (as a former slave & successful businessman in the 1840s North--who you trying to kid, Spielberg?!?!). McConaughey does a great job as the initial lawyer representing the Africans. Hounsu, as the captive African chief, is also very good. This film provides a fascinating U.S. history lesson brought very much alive. Wikipedia has several articles pertinent to this: see both "Amistad" (for the film, related places, writings, actual events, etc.) and also "Tecora" (the Portuguese slave ship which took the Africans to Cuba); these help those who are interested to distinguish much of who, where & when this film captures or distorts historical truths. See also the "Did You Know?" section on IMDb's "Amistad" main page; this covers some points not in the Wikipedia articles. I was extremely glad I saw this film for the knowledge gained despite its sometimes dramatized departures from utter truths.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Schindler's list for Amerika (cinematheque)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leplatypus
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As someone said it in the movie, the slaves had nothing to fear from their masters because as they work for them, they wouldn't be killed. So for me the only difference between slavery and holocaust is the lack of genocide. Besides this, it's the same oppression, the same racism: just see the way of how slaves were treated during the crossing and they are similar to the future extermination camps. But it's true that somewhere condemnation of slavery isn't as known as holocaust. Maybe the unfortunate explanation is that the masters are not beaten ones like Germany but as the movie shows the entire enlightened nations. As Tocqueville wrote, slavery was a shameful thorn in America democracy and Spielberg as a humanist American filmmaker couldn't avoid the subject. And he did in his own way, the same than in "Schindler's", that is to say showing that courage and hope are more powerful that the darkest time, the worst atrocities. Foretelling his later "Minority reports" or "Munich", he throws a very critic look at authorities and for the first apparition of POTUS in his work (a real plague in a lot of American movies) and whispers critics that could have pleased his colleague Stone. But his optimism is also visually contagious: compare the first terrifying look of Cinque and his latter appearances and you can see an happy hand. The only flaw of the movie is finally his title because it's doesn't tell very much what's about: "Amistad vs the people of America" would have been better... Pairing: "Schindler's list": before it, the allies were also evil forces...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Exquisitely made feelgood schlock which ultimately tells a big lie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    patrick powell
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As a film, as entertainment, as a night at the flicks, as a great way to spend well over two hours wallowing in non-stop feelgoodery Amistad is superb, and Steven Spielberg does quite brilliantly what only he and a few others can achieve. The acting is the finest, his actors are the finest, his script is the finest, his direction in which he balances action with reflection is the finest, and no doubt as for cinematography, sound design, editing and the rest a man of Spielberg's stature in the industry is able to employ the finest professionals working in film-making and he so obviously does so. So why do I feel that at the end of the day Spielberg's Amistad is simply nothing but 154 minutes of appalling sentimental schlock and, worse, appalling and dishonest sentimental schlock. I have no doubt that after watching Amistad Americans in their thousands have left the cinemas or turned off their DVD player and thought to themselves or even said out aloud: We are the finest nation on Earth and while we exist, the world is truly a better place. Well, perhaps all those who did and do so might care to pause a moment or two and ask themselves why the proportion of black and coloured inmates in U.S. jails compared to whites is still higher than the proportion of blacks and coloureds which make up the population of the U.S. They might care to ask themselves why a higher proportion of blacks and coloureds are unemployed, live in poverty and have a far lower standard of education. They might care to ask themselves why, almost 60 years after the hearing of the Amistad case before the Supreme Court the so-called Jim Crow laws were enacted denying blacks anything but equality with whites. But it's just a film, you might be saying, come on, don't be so uptight about it. Well, granted that it's not just the Americans but we Brits and the French, the Germans, the Russians, in fact every nation on earth who regularly chose to rewrite its history in films, novels, plays and poetry the calumny is not isolated or even unusual. We Brits like to bang on about what a civilising influence our glorious empire was and ignore completely the misery its establishment engendered and the huge number of deaths that were thought necessary for it to continue civilising 'savages'. And what after all, you might care to argue, is the 'truth'? One man's truth is another man's folly, perhaps, or one man's open mind is another man's gullibility. Well, I'll gracefully take the point but respond by pointing out the facts I cited above of the comparative freedoms and affluence of blacks and coloureds compared to whites in America. And I might ask why, when Hurricane Katrina devastated large parts of New Orleans, was hardly any assistance offered for several days? Why, it might be something to do with the fact that establishment America didn't and doesn't quite rate a black chocolate city like New Orleans has high as rather more top-drawer municipalities (although down-at-heel white communities aren't exactly privileged). And when we talk of 'establishment America', we might add that Hollywood and its filmmakers are one of its essential constituent parts. By all means enjoy Amistad as a film, a piece of fiction, but please don't run away with the idea that despite portraying historical incidents - although one larded with fictional characters: Morgan Freeman's dandified citizen is especially offensive, particularly since every other black face in the film is, if not an African from the Amistad, a servant or pauper. The incessant and remorseless feelgood soundtrack should serve as a warning: on and on and on it goes, all patriotic flutes, trumpets, syrupy strings. A good case could be made about accompanying some film soundtracks with the notice that 'this soundtrack can adversely influence your judgement'. When a 15-minute scene of a grand American figure such as John Quincy Adams grandly making grandly patriotic observations has a backdrop of such a patriotic melange of flutes, trumpets and strings, you just know something very rum is going on. Giving Amistad a rating presents a real problem: as filmmaking it is very fine indeed and Spielberg is a filmmaker almost without peer. But unfortunately a film which sets out to do what he has attempted to do needs more, not least true honesty, so this one, Stevie, can only get a five, because five is halfway between zero and ten.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Slave Courtroom Drama.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Steven Spielberg directs this authentic looking film that tells the story of African tribal leader Cinque(Djimon Hounsou) who is sold into slavery by another tribe and is on a ship from Cuba to the U.S. when he leads a revolt against their cruel captors, killing them. The crew is later captured and put on trial as being murderous runaway slaves, when an abolitionist lawyer(played by Mathew McConaughey) comes to their defense, but, despite winning the case, is undermined by a presidential appeal, so turns to former president John Quincy Adams(played magnificently by Anthony Hopkins) to plead the case before the U.S Supreme Court. Good drama has fine acting by all, harrowing ship-board recreation of the slave revolt, though has its fair share of dramatic lulls as well, though does have a memorable end.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    'Amistad' is one of the most powerful movies I have ever seen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    janet-turpie-johnstone
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Stories such as this need to be continually told and retold - for every generation produces its great and awful people and circumstances. For me, Amistad gave me the most profound memory I can never lose "I will call to the past, to the beginning of time and beg them to come and help me. they will come, I will draw them into me. I am the whole reason they have existed at all." How many of us can acknowledge the reconditeness of this remarkable human strength, We know our past and our future, we are a continuous stream of life and each generational makes the past important and the past declares the present. As one with an Aboriginal heritage this for me is great truth.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Such a Potent History Lesson!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    g-bodyl
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Amistad is a surprisingly great movie that is a welcome addition into the filmography of Steven Spielberg. It has some courtroom clich&eacute;s and some typical Spielberg drama fluff, but it overcomes those minor obstacles to be a powerful, sometimes-disturbing film about a group of people who yearn for their freedom. The editing is also choppy and sometimes it is hard to pick up what's going on, but this story moved me so much, I didn't care if the editing was sub-par. Amistad, based on a true story, is about a group of African slaves who attempt to escape from their captors, but they are recaptured and sent to America for trial. Now these blacks will have to endure unfairness and racial hatred to find out their fates. The acting is powerful. This is the movie where Djimon Hounsou becomes a star and this movie shows why. His performance as the so-called "alpha male" nearly moved me to tears. Anthony Hopkins, who played John Quincy Adams, delivers one of the best speeches you'll ever hear in the movies. Matthew McConaughey, in one of his early non-romantic roles does a wonderful job. I really love Morgan Freeman, but I'm disappointed he didn't do much in the film. Overall, this is a powerhouse film that shows expert Spielberg direction and wonderful acting. The editing is questionable, but I'll let it slide for a film like this. I honestly didn't expect this to be good as it was so I'm quite happy. I rate this film 9/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Another Spielberg's Masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    denis888
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I haven't watched this movie till very recently and wow, what a movie it has been! This is a sheer work of a genius who is by all means Mr. Steven Spielberg. He does not do anything wrong again and again, and thus in this movie he did a great job, too. The very topic of slavery is so painful and disturbing that it would be wrong to make a sweetly home-video drama with no blood or brutality. Nay, sirs, Amistad did exactly the right job - the movie showed slavery as it is - brutal, bloody, bad, gory, evil, malicious, greedy, horrific and unpardonable. The casting is perfect and there are no bad actors in this movie at all. Even the small part of Anna Paquin as Isabella of Spain is a real gem, what say can we of bigger and even better parts by impeccable Morgan Freeman and Anthony Hopkins? The film is very heavy, full of really unpleasant violence scenes but this all is not for the violence's sake. Nay, again, this all served the ultimate goal - to depict the inhuman nature of human trade, and this excellent movie did that well
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    one of good Steven film forever
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    masanseemay20
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Yes! It is an amazing another great movie from my best director Steven Spielberg. It says story of some slaves who were brought by ship called Amistad. superb cast and crew! my best actor Morgan freeman acts well. I always like to watch to Steven film first off all. recently I watched his latest great movie War horse. after watching some of his great films I became fan of this director and do watch his films continually. He makes every thing beautifully as much as he can. Another great is its music. woww!! what a heartbreaking violin in last scenes. john William makes it perfect. finally, well directed and well acted film forever.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    All About African Slavery
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Amistad is a historical film directed by Steven Spielberg.The movie stars a talented cast that includes Morgan Freeman,Anthony Hopkins,Djimon Hounsou,Matthew McConaughey,Nigel Hawthorne,Stellan Skarsg&aring;rd,Harry Blackmun and Anna Paquin. It was based on the true story of an uprising in 1839 by newly captured African slaves that took place aboard the ship La Amistad off the coast of Cuba, the subsequent voyage to the Northeastern United States, and the legal battle that followed their capture by a United States revenue cutter. It shows how, even though the case was won at the federal district court level, it was appealed by President Martin Van Buren to the Supreme Court, and how former President John Quincy Adams took part in the proceedings. The movie opens showing Cinque and the other Africans in a violent takeover of the Amistad. Captured, they are imprisoned in New England where former slave Theodore Joadson, viewing the rebels as "freedom fighters," approaches property lawyer Baldwin, who attempts to prove the Africans were "stolen goods" because they were kidnapped. Running for re-election, President Martin Van Buren overturns the lower court's decision in favor of the Africans. Former President John Quincy Adams is reluctant to become involved, but when the case moves on to the Supreme Court, Adams stirs emotions with a powerful defense. The story line occasionally cuts away to Spain where the young Queen Isabella plays with dolls; she later debated the Amistad case with seven U.S. presidents. Amistad is worth seeing just for people to know about this important story, this moment in history.This is the most straightforward, understated, and powerful big-screen representation of the slavery in recent movie history. And for that, it should be recommended to everyone.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Masterful directing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bitesizemoviereview dotblogspotdotcom
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Combine an award-winning director, a talented cast, a poignant musical score and breathtaking cinematography with one of the darkest hours of world history, and you get Amistad, widely regarded as the definitive film about the trans-Atlantic slave trade. While the plot is focused on the Amistad case, the film itself reverberates with the broader issue of slavery, including anti-slavery figures such as John Quincy Adams. My favorite scene was when the African men enter a church and thumb through an illustrated Bible, able to identify with the sufferings of Christ, after which Spielberg ingeniously shows the masts of three ships, resembling the three crosses. Brilliant and heartbreaking, Amistad captures the struggle of these men and a very determined lawyer to win their freedom. With masterful directing, Spielberg draws upon the lessons of history to forge an acclaimed film that celebrates hope and freedom even in the darkest of times. http://bitesizemoviereview.blogspot.com/
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Extremely worthwhile for the historical perspective, IMO
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bob Pr.
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This tells the story of potential African slaves, the cargo on "Amistad," a Spanish sailing ship, who revolted (1839) and ended up in American jails and courts. -- Will they be hung for killing their captors? -- Or 'property' that will be returned to their purchasers? The film traces their journey from Africa through various US courts and their outcomes that often intermixed with the looming domestic political issue, a sleeping gorilla: that of 1840s pre-Civil War slavery in the U.S. south. The scenes in Africa and shipboard of the treatment of captured slaves have some unsettling ("R" rated) cruelty. But "Amistad" is largely a drama of historical courtroom events (IMO, grossly accurate with exceptions that will be minor to many, major to a few). Hopkins (as a lawyer, the former president, John Quincy Adams) got a deserved Oscar nomination for his supporting role. Freeman plays quite well a wholly invented, minor role (as a former slave & successful businessman in the 1840s North--who you trying to kid, Spielberg?!?!). McConaughey does a great job as the initial lawyer representing the Africans. Hounsu, as the captive African chief, is also very good. This film provides a fascinating U.S. history lesson brought very much alive. Wikipedia has several articles pertinent to this: see both "Amistad" (for the film, related places, writings, actual events, etc.) and also "Tecora" (the Portuguese slave ship which took the Africans to Cuba); these help those who are interested to distinguish much of who, where & when this film captures or distorts historical truths. See also the "Did You Know?" section on IMDb's "Amistad" main page; this covers some points not in the Wikipedia articles. I was extremely glad I saw this film for the knowledge gained despite its sometimes dramatized departures from utter truths.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Schindler's list for Amerika (cinematheque)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leplatypus
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As someone said it in the movie, the slaves had nothing to fear from their masters because as they work for them, they wouldn't be killed. So for me the only difference between slavery and holocaust is the lack of genocide. Besides this, it's the same oppression, the same racism: just see the way of how slaves were treated during the crossing and they are similar to the future extermination camps. But it's true that somewhere condemnation of slavery isn't as known as holocaust. Maybe the unfortunate explanation is that the masters are not beaten ones like Germany but as the movie shows the entire enlightened nations. As Tocqueville wrote, slavery was a shameful thorn in America democracy and Spielberg as a humanist American filmmaker couldn't avoid the subject. And he did in his own way, the same than in "Schindler's", that is to say showing that courage and hope are more powerful that the darkest time, the worst atrocities. Foretelling his later "Minority reports" or "Munich", he throws a very critic look at authorities and for the first apparition of POTUS in his work (a real plague in a lot of American movies) and whispers critics that could have pleased his colleague Stone. But his optimism is also visually contagious: compare the first terrifying look of Cinque and his latter appearances and you can see an happy hand. The only flaw of the movie is finally his title because it's doesn't tell very much what's about: "Amistad vs the people of America" would have been better... Pairing: "Schindler's list": before it, the allies were also evil forces...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Exquisitely made feelgood schlock which ultimately tells a big lie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    patrick powell
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As a film, as entertainment, as a night at the flicks, as a great way to spend well over two hours wallowing in non-stop feelgoodery Amistad is superb, and Steven Spielberg does quite brilliantly what only he and a few others can achieve. The acting is the finest, his actors are the finest, his script is the finest, his direction in which he balances action with reflection is the finest, and no doubt as for cinematography, sound design, editing and the rest a man of Spielberg's stature in the industry is able to employ the finest professionals working in film-making and he so obviously does so. So why do I feel that at the end of the day Spielberg's Amistad is simply nothing but 154 minutes of appalling sentimental schlock and, worse, appalling and dishonest sentimental schlock. I have no doubt that after watching Amistad Americans in their thousands have left the cinemas or turned off their DVD player and thought to themselves or even said out aloud: We are the finest nation on Earth and while we exist, the world is truly a better place. Well, perhaps all those who did and do so might care to pause a moment or two and ask themselves why the proportion of black and coloured inmates in U.S. jails compared to whites is still higher than the proportion of blacks and coloureds which make up the population of the U.S. They might care to ask themselves why a higher proportion of blacks and coloureds are unemployed, live in poverty and have a far lower standard of education. They might care to ask themselves why, almost 60 years after the hearing of the Amistad case before the Supreme Court the so-called Jim Crow laws were enacted denying blacks anything but equality with whites. But it's just a film, you might be saying, come on, don't be so uptight about it. Well, granted that it's not just the Americans but we Brits and the French, the Germans, the Russians, in fact every nation on earth who regularly chose to rewrite its history in films, novels, plays and poetry the calumny is not isolated or even unusual. We Brits like to bang on about what a civilising influence our glorious empire was and ignore completely the misery its establishment engendered and the huge number of deaths that were thought necessary for it to continue civilising 'savages'. And what after all, you might care to argue, is the 'truth'? One man's truth is another man's folly, perhaps, or one man's open mind is another man's gullibility. Well, I'll gracefully take the point but respond by pointing out the facts I cited above of the comparative freedoms and affluence of blacks and coloureds compared to whites in America. And I might ask why, when Hurricane Katrina devastated large parts of New Orleans, was hardly any assistance offered for several days? Why, it might be something to do with the fact that establishment America didn't and doesn't quite rate a black chocolate city like New Orleans has high as rather more top-drawer municipalities (although down-at-heel white communities aren't exactly privileged). And when we talk of 'establishment America', we might add that Hollywood and its filmmakers are one of its essential constituent parts. By all means enjoy Amistad as a film, a piece of fiction, but please don't run away with the idea that despite portraying historical incidents - although one larded with fictional characters: Morgan Freeman's dandified citizen is especially offensive, particularly since every other black face in the film is, if not an African from the Amistad, a servant or pauper. The incessant and remorseless feelgood soundtrack should serve as a warning: on and on and on it goes, all patriotic flutes, trumpets, syrupy strings. A good case could be made about accompanying some film soundtracks with the notice that 'this soundtrack can adversely influence your judgement'. When a 15-minute scene of a grand American figure such as John Quincy Adams grandly making grandly patriotic observations has a backdrop of such a patriotic melange of flutes, trumpets and strings, you just know something very rum is going on. Giving Amistad a rating presents a real problem: as filmmaking it is very fine indeed and Spielberg is a filmmaker almost without peer. But unfortunately a film which sets out to do what he has attempted to do needs more, not least true honesty, so this one, Stevie, can only get a five, because five is halfway between zero and ten.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Slave Courtroom Drama.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AaronCapenBanner
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Steven Spielberg directs this authentic looking film that tells the story of African tribal leader Cinque(Djimon Hounsou) who is sold into slavery by another tribe and is on a ship from Cuba to the U.S. when he leads a revolt against their cruel captors, killing them. The crew is later captured and put on trial as being murderous runaway slaves, when an abolitionist lawyer(played by Mathew McConaughey) comes to their defense, but, despite winning the case, is undermined by a presidential appeal, so turns to former president John Quincy Adams(played magnificently by Anthony Hopkins) to plead the case before the U.S Supreme Court. Good drama has fine acting by all, harrowing ship-board recreation of the slave revolt, though has its fair share of dramatic lulls as well, though does have a memorable end.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    'Amistad' is one of the most powerful movies I have ever seen
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    janet-turpie-johnstone
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Stories such as this need to be continually told and retold - for every generation produces its great and awful people and circumstances. For me, Amistad gave me the most profound memory I can never lose "I will call to the past, to the beginning of time and beg them to come and help me. they will come, I will draw them into me. I am the whole reason they have existed at all." How many of us can acknowledge the reconditeness of this remarkable human strength, We know our past and our future, we are a continuous stream of life and each generational makes the past important and the past declares the present. As one with an Aboriginal heritage this for me is great truth.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Such a Potent History Lesson!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    g-bodyl
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Amistad is a surprisingly great movie that is a welcome addition into the filmography of Steven Spielberg. It has some courtroom clich&eacute;s and some typical Spielberg drama fluff, but it overcomes those minor obstacles to be a powerful, sometimes-disturbing film about a group of people who yearn for their freedom. The editing is also choppy and sometimes it is hard to pick up what's going on, but this story moved me so much, I didn't care if the editing was sub-par. Amistad, based on a true story, is about a group of African slaves who attempt to escape from their captors, but they are recaptured and sent to America for trial. Now these blacks will have to endure unfairness and racial hatred to find out their fates. The acting is powerful. This is the movie where Djimon Hounsou becomes a star and this movie shows why. His performance as the so-called "alpha male" nearly moved me to tears. Anthony Hopkins, who played John Quincy Adams, delivers one of the best speeches you'll ever hear in the movies. Matthew McConaughey, in one of his early non-romantic roles does a wonderful job. I really love Morgan Freeman, but I'm disappointed he didn't do much in the film. Overall, this is a powerhouse film that shows expert Spielberg direction and wonderful acting. The editing is questionable, but I'll let it slide for a film like this. I honestly didn't expect this to be good as it was so I'm quite happy. I rate this film 9/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Another Spielberg's Masterpiece
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    denis888
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/2/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I haven't watched this movie till very recently and wow, what a movie it has been! This is a sheer work of a genius who is by all means Mr. Steven Spielberg. He does not do anything wrong again and again, and thus in this movie he did a great job, too. The very topic of slavery is so painful and disturbing that it would be wrong to make a sweetly home-video drama with no blood or brutality. Nay, sirs, Amistad did exactly the right job - the movie showed slavery as it is - brutal, bloody, bad, gory, evil, malicious, greedy, horrific and unpardonable. The casting is perfect and there are no bad actors in this movie at all. Even the small part of Anna Paquin as Isabella of Spain is a real gem, what say can we of bigger and even better parts by impeccable Morgan Freeman and Anthony Hopkins? The film is very heavy, full of really unpleasant violence scenes but this all is not for the violence's sake. Nay, again, this all served the ultimate goal - to depict the inhuman nature of human trade, and this excellent movie did that well
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    one of good Steven film forever
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    masanseemay20
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Yes! It is an amazing another great movie from my best director Steven Spielberg. It says story of some slaves who were brought by ship called Amistad. superb cast and crew! my best actor Morgan freeman acts well. I always like to watch to Steven film first off all. recently I watched his latest great movie War horse. after watching some of his great films I became fan of this director and do watch his films continually. He makes every thing beautifully as much as he can. Another great is its music. woww!! what a heartbreaking violin in last scenes. john William makes it perfect. finally, well directed and well acted film forever.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    All About African Slavery
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Amistad is a historical film directed by Steven Spielberg.The movie stars a talented cast that includes Morgan Freeman,Anthony Hopkins,Djimon Hounsou,Matthew McConaughey,Nigel Hawthorne,Stellan Skarsg&aring;rd,Harry Blackmun and Anna Paquin. It was based on the true story of an uprising in 1839 by newly captured African slaves that took place aboard the ship La Amistad off the coast of Cuba, the subsequent voyage to the Northeastern United States, and the legal battle that followed their capture by a United States revenue cutter. It shows how, even though the case was won at the federal district court level, it was appealed by President Martin Van Buren to the Supreme Court, and how former President John Quincy Adams took part in the proceedings. The movie opens showing Cinque and the other Africans in a violent takeover of the Amistad. Captured, they are imprisoned in New England where former slave Theodore Joadson, viewing the rebels as "freedom fighters," approaches property lawyer Baldwin, who attempts to prove the Africans were "stolen goods" because they were kidnapped. Running for re-election, President Martin Van Buren overturns the lower court's decision in favor of the Africans. Former President John Quincy Adams is reluctant to become involved, but when the case moves on to the Supreme Court, Adams stirs emotions with a powerful defense. The story line occasionally cuts away to Spain where the young Queen Isabella plays with dolls; she later debated the Amistad case with seven U.S. presidents. Amistad is worth seeing just for people to know about this important story, this moment in history.This is the most straightforward, understated, and powerful big-screen representation of the slavery in recent movie history. And for that, it should be recommended to everyone.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Masterful directing
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    bitesizemoviereview dotblogspotdotcom
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Combine an award-winning director, a talented cast, a poignant musical score and breathtaking cinematography with one of the darkest hours of world history, and you get Amistad, widely regarded as the definitive film about the trans-Atlantic slave trade. While the plot is focused on the Amistad case, the film itself reverberates with the broader issue of slavery, including anti-slavery figures such as John Quincy Adams. My favorite scene was when the African men enter a church and thumb through an illustrated Bible, able to identify with the sufferings of Christ, after which Spielberg ingeniously shows the masts of three ships, resembling the three crosses. Brilliant and heartbreaking, Amistad captures the struggle of these men and a very determined lawyer to win their freedom. With masterful directing, Spielberg draws upon the lessons of history to forge an acclaimed film that celebrates hope and freedom even in the darkest of times. http://bitesizemoviereview.blogspot.com/
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Extremely worthwhile for the historical perspective, IMO
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Bob Pr.
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This tells the story of potential African slaves, the cargo on "Amistad," a Spanish sailing ship, who revolted (1839) and ended up in American jails and courts. -- Will they be hung for killing their captors? -- Or 'property' that will be returned to their purchasers? The film traces their journey from Africa through various US courts and their outcomes that often intermixed with the looming domestic political issue, a sleeping gorilla: that of 1840s pre-Civil War slavery in the U.S. south. The scenes in Africa and shipboard of the treatment of captured slaves have some unsettling ("R" rated) cruelty. But "Amistad" is largely a drama of historical courtroom events (IMO, grossly accurate with exceptions that will be minor to many, major to a few). Hopkins (as a lawyer, the former president, John Quincy Adams) got a deserved Oscar nomination for his supporting role. Freeman plays quite well a wholly invented, minor role (as a former slave & successful businessman in the 1840s North--who you trying to kid, Spielberg?!?!). McConaughey does a great job as the initial lawyer representing the Africans. Hounsu, as the captive African chief, is also very good. This film provides a fascinating U.S. history lesson brought very much alive. Wikipedia has several articles pertinent to this: see both "Amistad" (for the film, related places, writings, actual events, etc.) and also "Tecora" (the Portuguese slave ship which took the Africans to Cuba); these help those who are interested to distinguish much of who, where & when this film captures or distorts historical truths. See also the "Did You Know?" section on IMDb's "Amistad" main page; this covers some points not in the Wikipedia articles. I was extremely glad I saw this film for the knowledge gained despite its sometimes dramatized departures from utter truths.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Schindler's list for Amerika (cinematheque)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leplatypus
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As someone said it in the movie, the slaves had nothing to fear from their masters because as they work for them, they wouldn't be killed. So for me the only difference between slavery and holocaust is the lack of genocide. Besides this, it's the same oppression, the same racism: just see the way of how slaves were treated during the crossing and they are similar to the future extermination camps. But it's true that somewhere condemnation of slavery isn't as known as holocaust. Maybe the unfortunate explanation is that the masters are not beaten ones like Germany but as the movie shows the entire enlightened nations. As Tocqueville wrote, slavery was a shameful thorn in America democracy and Spielberg as a humanist American filmmaker couldn't avoid the subject. And he did in his own way, the same than in "Schindler's", that is to say showing that courage and hope are more powerful that the darkest time, the worst atrocities. Foretelling his later "Minority reports" or "Munich", he throws a very critic look at authorities and for the first apparition of POTUS in his work (a real plague in a lot of American movies) and whispers critics that could have pleased his colleague Stone. But his optimism is also visually contagious: compare the first terrifying look of Cinque and his latter appearances and you can see an happy hand. The only flaw of the movie is finally his title because it's doesn't tell very much what's about: "Amistad vs the people of America" would have been better... Pairing: "Schindler's list": before it, the allies were also evil forces...
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Exquisitely made feelgood schlock which ultimately tells a big lie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    patrick powell
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As a film, as entertainment, as a night at the flicks, as a great way to spend well over two hours wallowing in non-stop feelgoodery Amistad is superb, and Steven Spielberg does quite brilliantly what only he and a few others can achieve. The acting is the finest, his actors are the finest, his script is the finest, his direction in which he balances action with reflection is the finest, and no doubt as for cinematography, sound design, editing and the rest a man of Spielberg's stature in the industry is able to employ the finest professionals working in film-making and he so obviously does so. So why do I feel that at the end of the day Spielberg's Amistad is simply nothing but 154 minutes of appalling sentimental schlock and, worse, appalling and dishonest sentimental schlock. I have no doubt that after watching Amistad Americans in their thousands have left the cinemas or turned off their DVD player and thought to themselves or even said out aloud: We are the finest nation on Earth and while we exist, the world is truly a better place. Well, perhaps all those who did and do so might care to pause a moment or two and ask themselves why the proportion of black and coloured inmates in U.S. jails compared to whites is still higher than the proportion of blacks and coloureds which make up the population of the U.S. They might care to ask themselves why a higher proportion of blacks and coloureds are unemployed, live in poverty and have a far lower standard of education. They might care to ask themselves why, almost 60 years after the hearing of the Amistad case before the Supreme Court the so-called Jim Crow laws were enacted denying blacks anything but equality with whites. But it's just a film, you might be saying, come on, don't be so uptight about it. Well, granted that it's not just the Americans but we Brits and the French, the Germans, the Russians, in fact every nation on earth who regularly chose to rewrite its history in films, novels, plays and poetry the calumny is not isolated or even unusual. We Brits like to bang on about what a civilising influence our glorious empire was and ignore completely the misery its establishment engendered and the huge number of deaths that were thought necessary for it to continue civilising 'savages'. And what after all, you might care to argue, is the 'truth'? One man's truth is another man's folly, perhaps, or one man's open mind is another man's gullibility. Well, I'll gracefully take the point but respond by pointing out the facts I cited above of the comparative freedoms and affluence of blacks and coloureds compared to whites in America. And I might ask why, when Hurricane Katrina devastated large parts of New Orleans, was hardly any assistance offered for several days? Why, it might be something to do with the fact that establishment America didn't and doesn't quite rate a black chocolate city like New Orleans has high as rather more top-drawer municipalities (although down-at-heel white communities aren't exactly privileged). And when we talk of 'establishment America', we might add that Hollywood and its filmmakers are one of its essential constituent parts. By all means enjoy Amistad as a film, a piece of fiction, but please don't run away with the idea that despite portraying historical incidents - although one larded with fictional characters: Morgan Freeman's dandified citizen is especially offensive, particularly since every other black face in the film is, if not an African from the Amistad, a servant or pauper. The incessant and remorseless feelgood soundtrack should serve as a warning: on and on and on it goes, all patriotic flutes, trumpets, syrupy strings. A good case could be made about accompanying some film soundtracks with the notice that 'this soundtrack can adversely influence your judgement'. When a 15-minute scene of a grand American figure such as John Quincy Adams grandly making grandly patriotic observations has a backdrop of such a patriotic melange of flutes, trumpets and strings, you just know something very rum is going on. Giving Amistad a rating presents a real problem: as filmmaking it is very fine indeed and Spielberg is a filmmaker almost without peer. But unfortunately a film which sets out to do what he has attempted to do needs more, not least true honesty, so this one, Stevie, can only get a five, because five is halfway between zero and ten.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
