<filme>
 <id>
  751
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0120347
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1997
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  007 - O Amanh&atilde; Nunca Morre
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.4
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  James Bond heads to stop a media mogul's plan to induce war between China and the UK in order to obtain exclusive global media coverage.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Agent James Bond 007 is on a mission which includes a media tycoon, his former lover and a Chinese agent. Elliot Carver wants to complete his global media empire, but in order for this to work, he must achieve broadcasting rights in China. Carver wants to start up World War III by starting a confrontation over British and Chinese waters. Bond gains the help of Wai Lin on his quest to stop him, but how will Bond feel when he meets up with his former lover, who is now Carver's wife.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Action
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Adventure
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Crime
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   media
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   british
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   china
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   missile
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   chase
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Roger Spottiswoode
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Bruce Feirstein
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Pierce Brosnan
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Jonathan Pryce
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Michelle Yeoh
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Silly but rather enjoyable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AllTomorrowsParties
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tomorrow Never Dies gets a bad rap. Not sure why. Really, there are only two things amiss. Firstly the villain is a bit 'soft' if you consider a news mogul a bit soft. Secondly the last act is really not as good as the rest of the film. Bits of it - Bond's fake death (or is that two fake deaths?) and Wei Lin getting access to the bridge stretch credulity a bit and the fist fight is rubbish - but that's about it for criticism - otherwise this is a really good Bond film and probably Brosnan's best. The action sequences are great - especially the helicopter / motorbike sequence - this is shot rather brilliantly. Then again, the driverless BMW is rather good as well. Its occasionally funny. Yeoh is masterful. Brosnan is on form and the inclusion of a British Navy is a bonus. Oh, and the funny CIA. You see, the list is quite long. Its not a 6.4 by any stretch of the imagination. Its not perfect, I grant you but it has a lot going for it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's kind of like a Fast Food Burger. You consume it, enjoy it, but forget all about it as soon you are finished
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    callanvass
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A far cry from Goldeneye, but It doesn't necessarily deserve all the hate it receives either. Tomorrow Never Dies is a fast paced affair, and an easily agreeable time-waster, but it's not the follow-up Goldeneye deserved, either. It's much too daft for the heavy plot that it has. The main reason this movie is entertaining is the spectacular stunts. It has some great action set pieces, which managed to make the time pass nicely. Michelle Yeoh makes for a refreshingly unique Bond Girl, due to her actual Martial Arts background. I dug the chemistry with her & Brosnan. Speaking of Brosnan He is very good as Bond. He has charisma and wit to spare. He's not quite as good as Timothy Dalton, but he is excellent nonetheless. Johnathan Pryce is decent as the villain. He is fitfully menacing and did the job overall. Teri Hatcher's character is a bit disposable, but she was good in her role. Desmond Llewelyn & Judi Dench are as classy as ever Final Thoughts: Instantly forgettable stuff, but it manages to be an effective time-waster. It's not a great Bond film, but it is an OK action film. I didn't mind it at all. 5.6/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Where Tomorrow Never Dies Stands
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    davorinlonac
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is Pierce Brosnans second performance as agent 007 and could have been better. It is a very big decline since his first film being Goldenye, one of my favorites. This Bond film is good but doesn't feel like a Bond film somehow. Bond pretty much murders Elliot Carver, the villain, like a serial killer would! But again Pierce Brosnan makes the Bond character feel cooler and smoother. This is a good Bond movie but if I compare it to my favorites, it isn't very good. After watching it once and then watching it again there are some scenes you can look forward to. Elliot Carver by far is the strangest, but OK Bond villain of all time. Tomorrow Never Dies stands 19th on a list of mine where the 007 Movies have been ranked from worst to greatest. The film itself is good but The Bond Girl lets it down, as well as some of the fake action.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the most exciting Bond films ever made
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rodrigo Amaro (rodrigo882008@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    By far, my favorite of Brosnan along with "Goldeneye". Might not be one of the best Bond movies but it's certainly one of the most memorable. But truth be told: its effectiveness now is a little ruined to the massive appeal of the award winning "Skyfall", which at the same time reinvented Bond yet brought back some of its most appreciable qualities - this merge was inexistent in "Casino Royale" and "Quantum of Solace", both are just new reboots with a theme song to show that it's faithful to its roots. Mr. Brosnan at the top of his game, so smooth, active and funny, returns as Bond with plenty of style in one of Bond's most down to earth missions: to stop a possible conflict between England and China about to emerge from the dephts of a creative and destructive mind, the egocentric Elliot Carver (the priceless Jonathan Pryce), a media mogul &agrave; la Citizen Kane/Rupert Murdoch with his own declaration of principals which is to provide the news before they happen. The big scoop is to broadcast (and cause!) the WWIII. 007 is helped by a Chinese agent, the handy Colonel Wai-Lin (Michelle Yeoh) who is more advanced in her spy/fight techniques; and the other Bond girl is a former affair of his, now married with Elliot, a femme fatale played by Teri Hatcher. And this wouldn't be a complete Bond movie without the gadgets carefully supplied by Q (Desmond Llewelyn); here, a fully equipped BMW car that can be guided with the cellphone which also has its deadly functions. It's quite obvious the merchant made by the already mention company - they also brought a fancy motorcycle used in one of the most thrilling sequences when James and Wai-Lin escape from Carver's henchmen and that includes the couple's fly over a helicopter. "Tomorrow Never Dies" is great because it doesn't commit any kind of excesses, the plot is very simple to follow (this can be viewed as a problem to some, specially those who are more accustomed with complex plots, Bourne style) and never absurd; all the action and adventure are not overplayed, prolonged or tiring, it's all in a good measure and it's very exciting. I dare say those sequences were quite inspired. High point: the building escape using Carver's poster as a way out; the incredible car chase; Wai-Lin effortless escape tactics against the dangerous ones faced by 007, who feel a little annoyed with her. Their pairing is one of the best in the series, but the great and fun spectacle is the buffoon Carver and his memorable lines and actions (his mimics of Wai-Lin fighting style kills me every time). Obviously, he cannot put up a fight against the secret agent, but he has the loyal and muscular Stamper (G&ouml;tz Otto), a frightening guy who likes to torture his victims, and that's his only form of pleasure. For me, the only downer of this movie was the theme song, that hurts the ears, completely oversung. Anyway, it's a fun entertainment, filled with adrenaline and we can't forget the marvelous cast (one of the finest in the series) with Judi Dench (M), Samantha Bond (Moneypenny), Geoffrey Palmer, Vincent Schiavelli, Ricky Jay, Joe Don Baker and Gerard Butler (but you get an award if you find him in the middle of all the action). 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Film without Bond feeling
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Simon Fredriksson
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Pierce Brosnan is tough, sexy and has a twinkle in his eye, the third-best 007 after Sean Connery and Daniel Craig. But this movie is much worse than "Goldeneye", his first Bond movie. Thin screenplay about a media moguls (Jonathan Pryce) attempts to control the world by creating a war between Britain and China so that his new TV channel have something spectacular to report. Michelle Yeoh is a colorful and cool Bond girl, but Teri Hatcher, from the TV series "Desperate Housewives", does not add much in the role as the media moguls wife. Most boring of all, James Bond is so little James Bond, he is like any action hero out there. But at the phone manufacturer Ericsson they will party hard. The film's best scene is a car chase where 007 steers his BMW with the help of a remote control built in... well, you can guess what kind of phone.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    So far... so good!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    orourkec-292-269155
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm still satisfied on Tomorrow Never Dies after the first successful Goldeneye movie. I loved the actions and stunts! Original scenes and good characters. It is an impressive piece of work. The gadgets are always so good and make you more entertained than ever. Pierce Brosnan for me makes part of the group of the three best bonds ever! There are smart fights included and women still beautiful! "James Bond doesn't stop to make love and love with women". The movie could have added more special effects and something more to entertain the audience. It still captured me into the story though. Good job! For those who like james bond and haven't seen this one, I hope it will make you happy. Out of 100%, I RECOMMEND IT at 70%! I rate it: 7.2/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Overwhelming and thrilling entry in which Bond/Brosnan goes after a powerful media mogul
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ma-cortes
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Elloit Carver (Jonathan Pryce) is a megalomaniac and selfish media baron. Carver has the power to reach every person on the planet through his Carver Media Group Network- except for the People's Republic of Chinese who refuse his presence in their nation . The mogul is tied to the disappearance of a British battleship in the South China Sea . James Bond (Pierce Brosnan) heads to stop the media mogul's plan to induce war between China and the UK in order to obtain exclusive global media coverage and whose tentacles reach around the world . Carver, whose spouse (Teri Hatcher) was a former flame of 007 , is supported by a computer genius (Ricky Jay) and a nasty hunk man (Gotz Otto) . Along the way Bond join forces with a Chinese secret agent (Michelle Yeoh) , expert on martial arts . In addition , there appears the usuals , such as M (Judi Dench), Q (Desmond Llewelin) , Lois Maxwell, &uml;MoneyPenny&uml; (Samantha Bond) , Minister of Defense (Julian Fellowes) and Jake Wade (Joe Don Baker) . But not counting the regular characters of Bond, Q, M and Moneypenny, this is the first Bond movie to contain absolutely no Ian Fleming references . Likable Pierce Brosnan in an amazing adventure set on wonderful outdoors located mostly on Vietnam , being actually shot in Thailand . The original title of the film was "Tomorrow Never Lies", which makes sense when you consider media mogul Elliot Carver was creating the next day's headlines in advance, then causing those events to happen , but a typo on an early script draft was adopted by the producers, and &uml;Tomorrow never dies&uml; was used instead . This is a Bond's good outing in which faces dangerous adventures around the globe . Brosnan's outing with overwhelming action and spectacular scenarios , the film teams Bond with Michelle Yeoh as endearing ally in an effort to stop a technological communication mogul . After his first introduction in &uml;Golden eye&uml; as tough and attractive James Bond of the Ian Fleming's famous creation , Pierce Brosnan went on playing various 007 , as &uml;Die Another Day &uml; and this &uml;Tomorrow never dies&uml; . The picture starts with an overblown opening and following other impressive action set pieces . This solid , slick thriller with magic mix of action-packed , dazzling stunts, gadgetry, and romance provided by sexy company as Teri Hatcher and Michelle Yeoh . Pierce Brosnan as James Bond is fine , he does remarkably well , he earns in irony, humor ,suavity and sympathy, however also has coldness ,cunning , intelligence and toughness . Here Bond is an efficient , relentless agent trying to chase obstinately the criminals , traveling around the world as always , as this globe-trotting story is set in Pucket, Bangkok, Thailand (Saigon, Vietnam) , Hamburg , London and many other places . Because the second half of the film is set in Vietnam, the production negotiated for some time for permission to film there ; although it appeared close, the Vietnamese Ministry of Culture and Information eventually refused to allow it , the production decided to use Thailand as Vietnam, with Bangkok substituting for Saigon . Bond to achieve his aims , along the way uses violent means even pulling off brutal killings against enemies who wreak all sorts of havoc . As always Bond will use fantastic gadgets and spectacular cars (here 15 BMW 750's were destroyed in the making of the film) provided by &uml;Q&uml; (Desmond Llewelyn) . The stealth ship is not a fictional invention , Lockheed secretly constructed and demonstrated one in the early 1980s, but the US Navy finally decided they didn't want any ; the prototype, called the Sea Shadow, was 160 feet long . The picture contains comic-strip adventure , sensational pursuits , silly set pieces , great stunts , tongue-in check humor, automovile chase, frantic unstopped action , a breathtaking tour around the world , amazing gimmicks and stimulating images like are the happenings on the spectacular pursuits on the motorcycle and helicopter . As is like a roller-coaster , as is fast-paced , light , excitement, funny and entertaining ; it's a winner for oo7 fans and non-fans alike . The chase and suspense formula wears strong in this entry . The film made particularly heavy use of gadgetry because some fans thought there was too little of it in GoldenEye . Enjoyable title song by Sheryl Crow and stirring musical score fitting to action by David Arnold , following the John Barry's classic style . Riveting and fancy main titles , furthermore eye-popping production design by Allan Cameron . It's brimming with colorful and fascinating cinematography by cameraman Robert Elswit . The motion picture produced by habitual producers, Barbara Broccoli and Michael G. Wilson and dedicated to the memory of long-time Bond-film producer Albert R. Broccoli ; being professionally made by Robert Spottiswoode who filmed other successes such as &uml;the 6th day&uml;, &uml;Turner and Hooch&uml;, &uml;Air America&uml; , Shoot to kill&uml;and Under fire&uml; . Robert keeps this moving at an incredibly fast pace and this story about every's favorite super-spy facing off dangerous mogul . The film will appeal to James Bond series's buffs but good for fans only ; because this one goes on far too long and has provoked so much debate among 007 followers . Rating : 6'5 , well worth watching .
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Decent Bond flick.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Blueghost
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There's a couple of things I liked about classic Sean Connery Bond. A) he was smart. B) he let you know it. The other thing I liked about the classic Bond films was that there was a kind of credibility to them. You knew it was all comic book fun, but they were grounded. Pierce Brosnan could have been one of the great Bonds, but he's given precious little dialogue. We're essentially seeing a well crafted action flick from frame one. Bond films always had action, but this film seemed heavy on action, and little of what Bond knew, what he was all about, and how we knew he was capable of doing the things he did. That's pretty much my critique. A lot of money went into making this film a big blockbuster smash, and it delivers for what it is, but I didn't get a sense of Bondness, so much as I got a sense of a film wanting to be a James Bond film. Still, it's decent enough for what it is, an action film, but isn't Bond more than just an action hero? I think the technical stuff has gotten a lot better over the years of the Bond franchise's existence. But when you went to see a Bond film in the 60s and 70s, you didn't just go to see bullets flying, nor the Bond hotties adorning the screen, you went for the story and character. There's a fine plot driven film in here, but little else. And, true to big budget blockbusters needing bad-guys, we have a hint of Nazis in working for the evil boss that Bond must confront (although he himself may be one). I don't have much else to say about it other than I think that there's a better film in here. Yes, you heard me right. With all of the money dumped into this thing I'm still not satisfied that I saw a James Bond film. But, that's neither here nor there, I suppose. If I had shot it I would have cut back on some of the pyrotechnics, asked the Royal Navy to spare a frigate and a destroyer or two to fire real rounds instead of relying on my SFX team to drag a model through the water tank on the back lot while shooting it in slow mo. There's a lot of superficial adornments in this film to make it a Bond flick, but there isn't much Bond in it. I would have directed a different film. But again, that's all Monday morning quarterbacking. Still, it's a film, and a kind of popcorn fun film with some cross international romance involved, and maybe a bit of social engineering going on, but otherwise a decent watch. Give it a shot.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    007 Classy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    willrasmussen-617-992319
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is what I call a fun Bond movie to watch over again. I really like Pierce Brosnan as him playing Bond. The movie is enjoyable to watch and the action sequences are fun also. What seems to make this as a unique Bond film is the different types of weapons and gadgets that are shown in the movie. The story line is also makes the movie fun. I think this Bond movie is probably one the best Pierce Brosnan 007 movies. The movie is not so long and the scenes move at a fair pace. Prior to Goldeneye, this sets off a new type of Bond formula. I think this 007 movie is probably better than the Bond movies with Daniel Craig. I wish Pierce Brosnan was still playing James Bond.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Action packed but nothing extraordinary
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    varghesejunior
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If it's action you want then this Bond film will suit you. But it has nothing different to offer apart from conventional Bond stuff. In TND,Bond goes on a mission to expose a psychic media tycoon who wants to incite fire between UK and China and start World war 3 for his own selfish ends, and whose wife also happens to be Bond's ex girlfriend. The film is made well  Good story, direction, fast paced action with plenty of stunts, cool gadgets, dialogue delivery. It sure is enjoyable. There are a few unwanted scenes which is what I did not like. But there is nothing different in the film, unlike Daniel Craig's Bond films.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Silly but rather enjoyable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AllTomorrowsParties
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tomorrow Never Dies gets a bad rap. Not sure why. Really, there are only two things amiss. Firstly the villain is a bit 'soft' if you consider a news mogul a bit soft. Secondly the last act is really not as good as the rest of the film. Bits of it - Bond's fake death (or is that two fake deaths?) and Wei Lin getting access to the bridge stretch credulity a bit and the fist fight is rubbish - but that's about it for criticism - otherwise this is a really good Bond film and probably Brosnan's best. The action sequences are great - especially the helicopter / motorbike sequence - this is shot rather brilliantly. Then again, the driverless BMW is rather good as well. Its occasionally funny. Yeoh is masterful. Brosnan is on form and the inclusion of a British Navy is a bonus. Oh, and the funny CIA. You see, the list is quite long. Its not a 6.4 by any stretch of the imagination. Its not perfect, I grant you but it has a lot going for it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's kind of like a Fast Food Burger. You consume it, enjoy it, but forget all about it as soon you are finished
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    callanvass
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A far cry from Goldeneye, but It doesn't necessarily deserve all the hate it receives either. Tomorrow Never Dies is a fast paced affair, and an easily agreeable time-waster, but it's not the follow-up Goldeneye deserved, either. It's much too daft for the heavy plot that it has. The main reason this movie is entertaining is the spectacular stunts. It has some great action set pieces, which managed to make the time pass nicely. Michelle Yeoh makes for a refreshingly unique Bond Girl, due to her actual Martial Arts background. I dug the chemistry with her & Brosnan. Speaking of Brosnan He is very good as Bond. He has charisma and wit to spare. He's not quite as good as Timothy Dalton, but he is excellent nonetheless. Johnathan Pryce is decent as the villain. He is fitfully menacing and did the job overall. Teri Hatcher's character is a bit disposable, but she was good in her role. Desmond Llewelyn & Judi Dench are as classy as ever Final Thoughts: Instantly forgettable stuff, but it manages to be an effective time-waster. It's not a great Bond film, but it is an OK action film. I didn't mind it at all. 5.6/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Where Tomorrow Never Dies Stands
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    davorinlonac
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is Pierce Brosnans second performance as agent 007 and could have been better. It is a very big decline since his first film being Goldenye, one of my favorites. This Bond film is good but doesn't feel like a Bond film somehow. Bond pretty much murders Elliot Carver, the villain, like a serial killer would! But again Pierce Brosnan makes the Bond character feel cooler and smoother. This is a good Bond movie but if I compare it to my favorites, it isn't very good. After watching it once and then watching it again there are some scenes you can look forward to. Elliot Carver by far is the strangest, but OK Bond villain of all time. Tomorrow Never Dies stands 19th on a list of mine where the 007 Movies have been ranked from worst to greatest. The film itself is good but The Bond Girl lets it down, as well as some of the fake action.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the most exciting Bond films ever made
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rodrigo Amaro (rodrigo882008@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    By far, my favorite of Brosnan along with "Goldeneye". Might not be one of the best Bond movies but it's certainly one of the most memorable. But truth be told: its effectiveness now is a little ruined to the massive appeal of the award winning "Skyfall", which at the same time reinvented Bond yet brought back some of its most appreciable qualities - this merge was inexistent in "Casino Royale" and "Quantum of Solace", both are just new reboots with a theme song to show that it's faithful to its roots. Mr. Brosnan at the top of his game, so smooth, active and funny, returns as Bond with plenty of style in one of Bond's most down to earth missions: to stop a possible conflict between England and China about to emerge from the dephts of a creative and destructive mind, the egocentric Elliot Carver (the priceless Jonathan Pryce), a media mogul &agrave; la Citizen Kane/Rupert Murdoch with his own declaration of principals which is to provide the news before they happen. The big scoop is to broadcast (and cause!) the WWIII. 007 is helped by a Chinese agent, the handy Colonel Wai-Lin (Michelle Yeoh) who is more advanced in her spy/fight techniques; and the other Bond girl is a former affair of his, now married with Elliot, a femme fatale played by Teri Hatcher. And this wouldn't be a complete Bond movie without the gadgets carefully supplied by Q (Desmond Llewelyn); here, a fully equipped BMW car that can be guided with the cellphone which also has its deadly functions. It's quite obvious the merchant made by the already mention company - they also brought a fancy motorcycle used in one of the most thrilling sequences when James and Wai-Lin escape from Carver's henchmen and that includes the couple's fly over a helicopter. "Tomorrow Never Dies" is great because it doesn't commit any kind of excesses, the plot is very simple to follow (this can be viewed as a problem to some, specially those who are more accustomed with complex plots, Bourne style) and never absurd; all the action and adventure are not overplayed, prolonged or tiring, it's all in a good measure and it's very exciting. I dare say those sequences were quite inspired. High point: the building escape using Carver's poster as a way out; the incredible car chase; Wai-Lin effortless escape tactics against the dangerous ones faced by 007, who feel a little annoyed with her. Their pairing is one of the best in the series, but the great and fun spectacle is the buffoon Carver and his memorable lines and actions (his mimics of Wai-Lin fighting style kills me every time). Obviously, he cannot put up a fight against the secret agent, but he has the loyal and muscular Stamper (G&ouml;tz Otto), a frightening guy who likes to torture his victims, and that's his only form of pleasure. For me, the only downer of this movie was the theme song, that hurts the ears, completely oversung. Anyway, it's a fun entertainment, filled with adrenaline and we can't forget the marvelous cast (one of the finest in the series) with Judi Dench (M), Samantha Bond (Moneypenny), Geoffrey Palmer, Vincent Schiavelli, Ricky Jay, Joe Don Baker and Gerard Butler (but you get an award if you find him in the middle of all the action). 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Film without Bond feeling
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Simon Fredriksson
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Pierce Brosnan is tough, sexy and has a twinkle in his eye, the third-best 007 after Sean Connery and Daniel Craig. But this movie is much worse than "Goldeneye", his first Bond movie. Thin screenplay about a media moguls (Jonathan Pryce) attempts to control the world by creating a war between Britain and China so that his new TV channel have something spectacular to report. Michelle Yeoh is a colorful and cool Bond girl, but Teri Hatcher, from the TV series "Desperate Housewives", does not add much in the role as the media moguls wife. Most boring of all, James Bond is so little James Bond, he is like any action hero out there. But at the phone manufacturer Ericsson they will party hard. The film's best scene is a car chase where 007 steers his BMW with the help of a remote control built in... well, you can guess what kind of phone.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    So far... so good!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    orourkec-292-269155
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm still satisfied on Tomorrow Never Dies after the first successful Goldeneye movie. I loved the actions and stunts! Original scenes and good characters. It is an impressive piece of work. The gadgets are always so good and make you more entertained than ever. Pierce Brosnan for me makes part of the group of the three best bonds ever! There are smart fights included and women still beautiful! "James Bond doesn't stop to make love and love with women". The movie could have added more special effects and something more to entertain the audience. It still captured me into the story though. Good job! For those who like james bond and haven't seen this one, I hope it will make you happy. Out of 100%, I RECOMMEND IT at 70%! I rate it: 7.2/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Overwhelming and thrilling entry in which Bond/Brosnan goes after a powerful media mogul
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ma-cortes
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Elloit Carver (Jonathan Pryce) is a megalomaniac and selfish media baron. Carver has the power to reach every person on the planet through his Carver Media Group Network- except for the People's Republic of Chinese who refuse his presence in their nation . The mogul is tied to the disappearance of a British battleship in the South China Sea . James Bond (Pierce Brosnan) heads to stop the media mogul's plan to induce war between China and the UK in order to obtain exclusive global media coverage and whose tentacles reach around the world . Carver, whose spouse (Teri Hatcher) was a former flame of 007 , is supported by a computer genius (Ricky Jay) and a nasty hunk man (Gotz Otto) . Along the way Bond join forces with a Chinese secret agent (Michelle Yeoh) , expert on martial arts . In addition , there appears the usuals , such as M (Judi Dench), Q (Desmond Llewelin) , Lois Maxwell, &uml;MoneyPenny&uml; (Samantha Bond) , Minister of Defense (Julian Fellowes) and Jake Wade (Joe Don Baker) . But not counting the regular characters of Bond, Q, M and Moneypenny, this is the first Bond movie to contain absolutely no Ian Fleming references . Likable Pierce Brosnan in an amazing adventure set on wonderful outdoors located mostly on Vietnam , being actually shot in Thailand . The original title of the film was "Tomorrow Never Lies", which makes sense when you consider media mogul Elliot Carver was creating the next day's headlines in advance, then causing those events to happen , but a typo on an early script draft was adopted by the producers, and &uml;Tomorrow never dies&uml; was used instead . This is a Bond's good outing in which faces dangerous adventures around the globe . Brosnan's outing with overwhelming action and spectacular scenarios , the film teams Bond with Michelle Yeoh as endearing ally in an effort to stop a technological communication mogul . After his first introduction in &uml;Golden eye&uml; as tough and attractive James Bond of the Ian Fleming's famous creation , Pierce Brosnan went on playing various 007 , as &uml;Die Another Day &uml; and this &uml;Tomorrow never dies&uml; . The picture starts with an overblown opening and following other impressive action set pieces . This solid , slick thriller with magic mix of action-packed , dazzling stunts, gadgetry, and romance provided by sexy company as Teri Hatcher and Michelle Yeoh . Pierce Brosnan as James Bond is fine , he does remarkably well , he earns in irony, humor ,suavity and sympathy, however also has coldness ,cunning , intelligence and toughness . Here Bond is an efficient , relentless agent trying to chase obstinately the criminals , traveling around the world as always , as this globe-trotting story is set in Pucket, Bangkok, Thailand (Saigon, Vietnam) , Hamburg , London and many other places . Because the second half of the film is set in Vietnam, the production negotiated for some time for permission to film there ; although it appeared close, the Vietnamese Ministry of Culture and Information eventually refused to allow it , the production decided to use Thailand as Vietnam, with Bangkok substituting for Saigon . Bond to achieve his aims , along the way uses violent means even pulling off brutal killings against enemies who wreak all sorts of havoc . As always Bond will use fantastic gadgets and spectacular cars (here 15 BMW 750's were destroyed in the making of the film) provided by &uml;Q&uml; (Desmond Llewelyn) . The stealth ship is not a fictional invention , Lockheed secretly constructed and demonstrated one in the early 1980s, but the US Navy finally decided they didn't want any ; the prototype, called the Sea Shadow, was 160 feet long . The picture contains comic-strip adventure , sensational pursuits , silly set pieces , great stunts , tongue-in check humor, automovile chase, frantic unstopped action , a breathtaking tour around the world , amazing gimmicks and stimulating images like are the happenings on the spectacular pursuits on the motorcycle and helicopter . As is like a roller-coaster , as is fast-paced , light , excitement, funny and entertaining ; it's a winner for oo7 fans and non-fans alike . The chase and suspense formula wears strong in this entry . The film made particularly heavy use of gadgetry because some fans thought there was too little of it in GoldenEye . Enjoyable title song by Sheryl Crow and stirring musical score fitting to action by David Arnold , following the John Barry's classic style . Riveting and fancy main titles , furthermore eye-popping production design by Allan Cameron . It's brimming with colorful and fascinating cinematography by cameraman Robert Elswit . The motion picture produced by habitual producers, Barbara Broccoli and Michael G. Wilson and dedicated to the memory of long-time Bond-film producer Albert R. Broccoli ; being professionally made by Robert Spottiswoode who filmed other successes such as &uml;the 6th day&uml;, &uml;Turner and Hooch&uml;, &uml;Air America&uml; , Shoot to kill&uml;and Under fire&uml; . Robert keeps this moving at an incredibly fast pace and this story about every's favorite super-spy facing off dangerous mogul . The film will appeal to James Bond series's buffs but good for fans only ; because this one goes on far too long and has provoked so much debate among 007 followers . Rating : 6'5 , well worth watching .
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Decent Bond flick.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Blueghost
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There's a couple of things I liked about classic Sean Connery Bond. A) he was smart. B) he let you know it. The other thing I liked about the classic Bond films was that there was a kind of credibility to them. You knew it was all comic book fun, but they were grounded. Pierce Brosnan could have been one of the great Bonds, but he's given precious little dialogue. We're essentially seeing a well crafted action flick from frame one. Bond films always had action, but this film seemed heavy on action, and little of what Bond knew, what he was all about, and how we knew he was capable of doing the things he did. That's pretty much my critique. A lot of money went into making this film a big blockbuster smash, and it delivers for what it is, but I didn't get a sense of Bondness, so much as I got a sense of a film wanting to be a James Bond film. Still, it's decent enough for what it is, an action film, but isn't Bond more than just an action hero? I think the technical stuff has gotten a lot better over the years of the Bond franchise's existence. But when you went to see a Bond film in the 60s and 70s, you didn't just go to see bullets flying, nor the Bond hotties adorning the screen, you went for the story and character. There's a fine plot driven film in here, but little else. And, true to big budget blockbusters needing bad-guys, we have a hint of Nazis in working for the evil boss that Bond must confront (although he himself may be one). I don't have much else to say about it other than I think that there's a better film in here. Yes, you heard me right. With all of the money dumped into this thing I'm still not satisfied that I saw a James Bond film. But, that's neither here nor there, I suppose. If I had shot it I would have cut back on some of the pyrotechnics, asked the Royal Navy to spare a frigate and a destroyer or two to fire real rounds instead of relying on my SFX team to drag a model through the water tank on the back lot while shooting it in slow mo. There's a lot of superficial adornments in this film to make it a Bond flick, but there isn't much Bond in it. I would have directed a different film. But again, that's all Monday morning quarterbacking. Still, it's a film, and a kind of popcorn fun film with some cross international romance involved, and maybe a bit of social engineering going on, but otherwise a decent watch. Give it a shot.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    007 Classy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    willrasmussen-617-992319
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is what I call a fun Bond movie to watch over again. I really like Pierce Brosnan as him playing Bond. The movie is enjoyable to watch and the action sequences are fun also. What seems to make this as a unique Bond film is the different types of weapons and gadgets that are shown in the movie. The story line is also makes the movie fun. I think this Bond movie is probably one the best Pierce Brosnan 007 movies. The movie is not so long and the scenes move at a fair pace. Prior to Goldeneye, this sets off a new type of Bond formula. I think this 007 movie is probably better than the Bond movies with Daniel Craig. I wish Pierce Brosnan was still playing James Bond.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Action packed but nothing extraordinary
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    varghesejunior
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If it's action you want then this Bond film will suit you. But it has nothing different to offer apart from conventional Bond stuff. In TND,Bond goes on a mission to expose a psychic media tycoon who wants to incite fire between UK and China and start World war 3 for his own selfish ends, and whose wife also happens to be Bond's ex girlfriend. The film is made well  Good story, direction, fast paced action with plenty of stunts, cool gadgets, dialogue delivery. It sure is enjoyable. There are a few unwanted scenes which is what I did not like. But there is nothing different in the film, unlike Daniel Craig's Bond films.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Silly but rather enjoyable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AllTomorrowsParties
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tomorrow Never Dies gets a bad rap. Not sure why. Really, there are only two things amiss. Firstly the villain is a bit 'soft' if you consider a news mogul a bit soft. Secondly the last act is really not as good as the rest of the film. Bits of it - Bond's fake death (or is that two fake deaths?) and Wei Lin getting access to the bridge stretch credulity a bit and the fist fight is rubbish - but that's about it for criticism - otherwise this is a really good Bond film and probably Brosnan's best. The action sequences are great - especially the helicopter / motorbike sequence - this is shot rather brilliantly. Then again, the driverless BMW is rather good as well. Its occasionally funny. Yeoh is masterful. Brosnan is on form and the inclusion of a British Navy is a bonus. Oh, and the funny CIA. You see, the list is quite long. Its not a 6.4 by any stretch of the imagination. Its not perfect, I grant you but it has a lot going for it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's kind of like a Fast Food Burger. You consume it, enjoy it, but forget all about it as soon you are finished
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    callanvass
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A far cry from Goldeneye, but It doesn't necessarily deserve all the hate it receives either. Tomorrow Never Dies is a fast paced affair, and an easily agreeable time-waster, but it's not the follow-up Goldeneye deserved, either. It's much too daft for the heavy plot that it has. The main reason this movie is entertaining is the spectacular stunts. It has some great action set pieces, which managed to make the time pass nicely. Michelle Yeoh makes for a refreshingly unique Bond Girl, due to her actual Martial Arts background. I dug the chemistry with her & Brosnan. Speaking of Brosnan He is very good as Bond. He has charisma and wit to spare. He's not quite as good as Timothy Dalton, but he is excellent nonetheless. Johnathan Pryce is decent as the villain. He is fitfully menacing and did the job overall. Teri Hatcher's character is a bit disposable, but she was good in her role. Desmond Llewelyn & Judi Dench are as classy as ever Final Thoughts: Instantly forgettable stuff, but it manages to be an effective time-waster. It's not a great Bond film, but it is an OK action film. I didn't mind it at all. 5.6/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Where Tomorrow Never Dies Stands
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    davorinlonac
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is Pierce Brosnans second performance as agent 007 and could have been better. It is a very big decline since his first film being Goldenye, one of my favorites. This Bond film is good but doesn't feel like a Bond film somehow. Bond pretty much murders Elliot Carver, the villain, like a serial killer would! But again Pierce Brosnan makes the Bond character feel cooler and smoother. This is a good Bond movie but if I compare it to my favorites, it isn't very good. After watching it once and then watching it again there are some scenes you can look forward to. Elliot Carver by far is the strangest, but OK Bond villain of all time. Tomorrow Never Dies stands 19th on a list of mine where the 007 Movies have been ranked from worst to greatest. The film itself is good but The Bond Girl lets it down, as well as some of the fake action.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the most exciting Bond films ever made
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rodrigo Amaro (rodrigo882008@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    By far, my favorite of Brosnan along with "Goldeneye". Might not be one of the best Bond movies but it's certainly one of the most memorable. But truth be told: its effectiveness now is a little ruined to the massive appeal of the award winning "Skyfall", which at the same time reinvented Bond yet brought back some of its most appreciable qualities - this merge was inexistent in "Casino Royale" and "Quantum of Solace", both are just new reboots with a theme song to show that it's faithful to its roots. Mr. Brosnan at the top of his game, so smooth, active and funny, returns as Bond with plenty of style in one of Bond's most down to earth missions: to stop a possible conflict between England and China about to emerge from the dephts of a creative and destructive mind, the egocentric Elliot Carver (the priceless Jonathan Pryce), a media mogul &agrave; la Citizen Kane/Rupert Murdoch with his own declaration of principals which is to provide the news before they happen. The big scoop is to broadcast (and cause!) the WWIII. 007 is helped by a Chinese agent, the handy Colonel Wai-Lin (Michelle Yeoh) who is more advanced in her spy/fight techniques; and the other Bond girl is a former affair of his, now married with Elliot, a femme fatale played by Teri Hatcher. And this wouldn't be a complete Bond movie without the gadgets carefully supplied by Q (Desmond Llewelyn); here, a fully equipped BMW car that can be guided with the cellphone which also has its deadly functions. It's quite obvious the merchant made by the already mention company - they also brought a fancy motorcycle used in one of the most thrilling sequences when James and Wai-Lin escape from Carver's henchmen and that includes the couple's fly over a helicopter. "Tomorrow Never Dies" is great because it doesn't commit any kind of excesses, the plot is very simple to follow (this can be viewed as a problem to some, specially those who are more accustomed with complex plots, Bourne style) and never absurd; all the action and adventure are not overplayed, prolonged or tiring, it's all in a good measure and it's very exciting. I dare say those sequences were quite inspired. High point: the building escape using Carver's poster as a way out; the incredible car chase; Wai-Lin effortless escape tactics against the dangerous ones faced by 007, who feel a little annoyed with her. Their pairing is one of the best in the series, but the great and fun spectacle is the buffoon Carver and his memorable lines and actions (his mimics of Wai-Lin fighting style kills me every time). Obviously, he cannot put up a fight against the secret agent, but he has the loyal and muscular Stamper (G&ouml;tz Otto), a frightening guy who likes to torture his victims, and that's his only form of pleasure. For me, the only downer of this movie was the theme song, that hurts the ears, completely oversung. Anyway, it's a fun entertainment, filled with adrenaline and we can't forget the marvelous cast (one of the finest in the series) with Judi Dench (M), Samantha Bond (Moneypenny), Geoffrey Palmer, Vincent Schiavelli, Ricky Jay, Joe Don Baker and Gerard Butler (but you get an award if you find him in the middle of all the action). 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Film without Bond feeling
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Simon Fredriksson
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Pierce Brosnan is tough, sexy and has a twinkle in his eye, the third-best 007 after Sean Connery and Daniel Craig. But this movie is much worse than "Goldeneye", his first Bond movie. Thin screenplay about a media moguls (Jonathan Pryce) attempts to control the world by creating a war between Britain and China so that his new TV channel have something spectacular to report. Michelle Yeoh is a colorful and cool Bond girl, but Teri Hatcher, from the TV series "Desperate Housewives", does not add much in the role as the media moguls wife. Most boring of all, James Bond is so little James Bond, he is like any action hero out there. But at the phone manufacturer Ericsson they will party hard. The film's best scene is a car chase where 007 steers his BMW with the help of a remote control built in... well, you can guess what kind of phone.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    So far... so good!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    orourkec-292-269155
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm still satisfied on Tomorrow Never Dies after the first successful Goldeneye movie. I loved the actions and stunts! Original scenes and good characters. It is an impressive piece of work. The gadgets are always so good and make you more entertained than ever. Pierce Brosnan for me makes part of the group of the three best bonds ever! There are smart fights included and women still beautiful! "James Bond doesn't stop to make love and love with women". The movie could have added more special effects and something more to entertain the audience. It still captured me into the story though. Good job! For those who like james bond and haven't seen this one, I hope it will make you happy. Out of 100%, I RECOMMEND IT at 70%! I rate it: 7.2/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Overwhelming and thrilling entry in which Bond/Brosnan goes after a powerful media mogul
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ma-cortes
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Elloit Carver (Jonathan Pryce) is a megalomaniac and selfish media baron. Carver has the power to reach every person on the planet through his Carver Media Group Network- except for the People's Republic of Chinese who refuse his presence in their nation . The mogul is tied to the disappearance of a British battleship in the South China Sea . James Bond (Pierce Brosnan) heads to stop the media mogul's plan to induce war between China and the UK in order to obtain exclusive global media coverage and whose tentacles reach around the world . Carver, whose spouse (Teri Hatcher) was a former flame of 007 , is supported by a computer genius (Ricky Jay) and a nasty hunk man (Gotz Otto) . Along the way Bond join forces with a Chinese secret agent (Michelle Yeoh) , expert on martial arts . In addition , there appears the usuals , such as M (Judi Dench), Q (Desmond Llewelin) , Lois Maxwell, &uml;MoneyPenny&uml; (Samantha Bond) , Minister of Defense (Julian Fellowes) and Jake Wade (Joe Don Baker) . But not counting the regular characters of Bond, Q, M and Moneypenny, this is the first Bond movie to contain absolutely no Ian Fleming references . Likable Pierce Brosnan in an amazing adventure set on wonderful outdoors located mostly on Vietnam , being actually shot in Thailand . The original title of the film was "Tomorrow Never Lies", which makes sense when you consider media mogul Elliot Carver was creating the next day's headlines in advance, then causing those events to happen , but a typo on an early script draft was adopted by the producers, and &uml;Tomorrow never dies&uml; was used instead . This is a Bond's good outing in which faces dangerous adventures around the globe . Brosnan's outing with overwhelming action and spectacular scenarios , the film teams Bond with Michelle Yeoh as endearing ally in an effort to stop a technological communication mogul . After his first introduction in &uml;Golden eye&uml; as tough and attractive James Bond of the Ian Fleming's famous creation , Pierce Brosnan went on playing various 007 , as &uml;Die Another Day &uml; and this &uml;Tomorrow never dies&uml; . The picture starts with an overblown opening and following other impressive action set pieces . This solid , slick thriller with magic mix of action-packed , dazzling stunts, gadgetry, and romance provided by sexy company as Teri Hatcher and Michelle Yeoh . Pierce Brosnan as James Bond is fine , he does remarkably well , he earns in irony, humor ,suavity and sympathy, however also has coldness ,cunning , intelligence and toughness . Here Bond is an efficient , relentless agent trying to chase obstinately the criminals , traveling around the world as always , as this globe-trotting story is set in Pucket, Bangkok, Thailand (Saigon, Vietnam) , Hamburg , London and many other places . Because the second half of the film is set in Vietnam, the production negotiated for some time for permission to film there ; although it appeared close, the Vietnamese Ministry of Culture and Information eventually refused to allow it , the production decided to use Thailand as Vietnam, with Bangkok substituting for Saigon . Bond to achieve his aims , along the way uses violent means even pulling off brutal killings against enemies who wreak all sorts of havoc . As always Bond will use fantastic gadgets and spectacular cars (here 15 BMW 750's were destroyed in the making of the film) provided by &uml;Q&uml; (Desmond Llewelyn) . The stealth ship is not a fictional invention , Lockheed secretly constructed and demonstrated one in the early 1980s, but the US Navy finally decided they didn't want any ; the prototype, called the Sea Shadow, was 160 feet long . The picture contains comic-strip adventure , sensational pursuits , silly set pieces , great stunts , tongue-in check humor, automovile chase, frantic unstopped action , a breathtaking tour around the world , amazing gimmicks and stimulating images like are the happenings on the spectacular pursuits on the motorcycle and helicopter . As is like a roller-coaster , as is fast-paced , light , excitement, funny and entertaining ; it's a winner for oo7 fans and non-fans alike . The chase and suspense formula wears strong in this entry . The film made particularly heavy use of gadgetry because some fans thought there was too little of it in GoldenEye . Enjoyable title song by Sheryl Crow and stirring musical score fitting to action by David Arnold , following the John Barry's classic style . Riveting and fancy main titles , furthermore eye-popping production design by Allan Cameron . It's brimming with colorful and fascinating cinematography by cameraman Robert Elswit . The motion picture produced by habitual producers, Barbara Broccoli and Michael G. Wilson and dedicated to the memory of long-time Bond-film producer Albert R. Broccoli ; being professionally made by Robert Spottiswoode who filmed other successes such as &uml;the 6th day&uml;, &uml;Turner and Hooch&uml;, &uml;Air America&uml; , Shoot to kill&uml;and Under fire&uml; . Robert keeps this moving at an incredibly fast pace and this story about every's favorite super-spy facing off dangerous mogul . The film will appeal to James Bond series's buffs but good for fans only ; because this one goes on far too long and has provoked so much debate among 007 followers . Rating : 6'5 , well worth watching .
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Decent Bond flick.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Blueghost
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There's a couple of things I liked about classic Sean Connery Bond. A) he was smart. B) he let you know it. The other thing I liked about the classic Bond films was that there was a kind of credibility to them. You knew it was all comic book fun, but they were grounded. Pierce Brosnan could have been one of the great Bonds, but he's given precious little dialogue. We're essentially seeing a well crafted action flick from frame one. Bond films always had action, but this film seemed heavy on action, and little of what Bond knew, what he was all about, and how we knew he was capable of doing the things he did. That's pretty much my critique. A lot of money went into making this film a big blockbuster smash, and it delivers for what it is, but I didn't get a sense of Bondness, so much as I got a sense of a film wanting to be a James Bond film. Still, it's decent enough for what it is, an action film, but isn't Bond more than just an action hero? I think the technical stuff has gotten a lot better over the years of the Bond franchise's existence. But when you went to see a Bond film in the 60s and 70s, you didn't just go to see bullets flying, nor the Bond hotties adorning the screen, you went for the story and character. There's a fine plot driven film in here, but little else. And, true to big budget blockbusters needing bad-guys, we have a hint of Nazis in working for the evil boss that Bond must confront (although he himself may be one). I don't have much else to say about it other than I think that there's a better film in here. Yes, you heard me right. With all of the money dumped into this thing I'm still not satisfied that I saw a James Bond film. But, that's neither here nor there, I suppose. If I had shot it I would have cut back on some of the pyrotechnics, asked the Royal Navy to spare a frigate and a destroyer or two to fire real rounds instead of relying on my SFX team to drag a model through the water tank on the back lot while shooting it in slow mo. There's a lot of superficial adornments in this film to make it a Bond flick, but there isn't much Bond in it. I would have directed a different film. But again, that's all Monday morning quarterbacking. Still, it's a film, and a kind of popcorn fun film with some cross international romance involved, and maybe a bit of social engineering going on, but otherwise a decent watch. Give it a shot.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    007 Classy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    willrasmussen-617-992319
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is what I call a fun Bond movie to watch over again. I really like Pierce Brosnan as him playing Bond. The movie is enjoyable to watch and the action sequences are fun also. What seems to make this as a unique Bond film is the different types of weapons and gadgets that are shown in the movie. The story line is also makes the movie fun. I think this Bond movie is probably one the best Pierce Brosnan 007 movies. The movie is not so long and the scenes move at a fair pace. Prior to Goldeneye, this sets off a new type of Bond formula. I think this 007 movie is probably better than the Bond movies with Daniel Craig. I wish Pierce Brosnan was still playing James Bond.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Action packed but nothing extraordinary
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    varghesejunior
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If it's action you want then this Bond film will suit you. But it has nothing different to offer apart from conventional Bond stuff. In TND,Bond goes on a mission to expose a psychic media tycoon who wants to incite fire between UK and China and start World war 3 for his own selfish ends, and whose wife also happens to be Bond's ex girlfriend. The film is made well  Good story, direction, fast paced action with plenty of stunts, cool gadgets, dialogue delivery. It sure is enjoyable. There are a few unwanted scenes which is what I did not like. But there is nothing different in the film, unlike Daniel Craig's Bond films.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Silly but rather enjoyable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AllTomorrowsParties
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tomorrow Never Dies gets a bad rap. Not sure why. Really, there are only two things amiss. Firstly the villain is a bit 'soft' if you consider a news mogul a bit soft. Secondly the last act is really not as good as the rest of the film. Bits of it - Bond's fake death (or is that two fake deaths?) and Wei Lin getting access to the bridge stretch credulity a bit and the fist fight is rubbish - but that's about it for criticism - otherwise this is a really good Bond film and probably Brosnan's best. The action sequences are great - especially the helicopter / motorbike sequence - this is shot rather brilliantly. Then again, the driverless BMW is rather good as well. Its occasionally funny. Yeoh is masterful. Brosnan is on form and the inclusion of a British Navy is a bonus. Oh, and the funny CIA. You see, the list is quite long. Its not a 6.4 by any stretch of the imagination. Its not perfect, I grant you but it has a lot going for it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's kind of like a Fast Food Burger. You consume it, enjoy it, but forget all about it as soon you are finished
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    callanvass
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A far cry from Goldeneye, but It doesn't necessarily deserve all the hate it receives either. Tomorrow Never Dies is a fast paced affair, and an easily agreeable time-waster, but it's not the follow-up Goldeneye deserved, either. It's much too daft for the heavy plot that it has. The main reason this movie is entertaining is the spectacular stunts. It has some great action set pieces, which managed to make the time pass nicely. Michelle Yeoh makes for a refreshingly unique Bond Girl, due to her actual Martial Arts background. I dug the chemistry with her & Brosnan. Speaking of Brosnan He is very good as Bond. He has charisma and wit to spare. He's not quite as good as Timothy Dalton, but he is excellent nonetheless. Johnathan Pryce is decent as the villain. He is fitfully menacing and did the job overall. Teri Hatcher's character is a bit disposable, but she was good in her role. Desmond Llewelyn & Judi Dench are as classy as ever Final Thoughts: Instantly forgettable stuff, but it manages to be an effective time-waster. It's not a great Bond film, but it is an OK action film. I didn't mind it at all. 5.6/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Where Tomorrow Never Dies Stands
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    davorinlonac
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is Pierce Brosnans second performance as agent 007 and could have been better. It is a very big decline since his first film being Goldenye, one of my favorites. This Bond film is good but doesn't feel like a Bond film somehow. Bond pretty much murders Elliot Carver, the villain, like a serial killer would! But again Pierce Brosnan makes the Bond character feel cooler and smoother. This is a good Bond movie but if I compare it to my favorites, it isn't very good. After watching it once and then watching it again there are some scenes you can look forward to. Elliot Carver by far is the strangest, but OK Bond villain of all time. Tomorrow Never Dies stands 19th on a list of mine where the 007 Movies have been ranked from worst to greatest. The film itself is good but The Bond Girl lets it down, as well as some of the fake action.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the most exciting Bond films ever made
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rodrigo Amaro (rodrigo882008@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    By far, my favorite of Brosnan along with "Goldeneye". Might not be one of the best Bond movies but it's certainly one of the most memorable. But truth be told: its effectiveness now is a little ruined to the massive appeal of the award winning "Skyfall", which at the same time reinvented Bond yet brought back some of its most appreciable qualities - this merge was inexistent in "Casino Royale" and "Quantum of Solace", both are just new reboots with a theme song to show that it's faithful to its roots. Mr. Brosnan at the top of his game, so smooth, active and funny, returns as Bond with plenty of style in one of Bond's most down to earth missions: to stop a possible conflict between England and China about to emerge from the dephts of a creative and destructive mind, the egocentric Elliot Carver (the priceless Jonathan Pryce), a media mogul &agrave; la Citizen Kane/Rupert Murdoch with his own declaration of principals which is to provide the news before they happen. The big scoop is to broadcast (and cause!) the WWIII. 007 is helped by a Chinese agent, the handy Colonel Wai-Lin (Michelle Yeoh) who is more advanced in her spy/fight techniques; and the other Bond girl is a former affair of his, now married with Elliot, a femme fatale played by Teri Hatcher. And this wouldn't be a complete Bond movie without the gadgets carefully supplied by Q (Desmond Llewelyn); here, a fully equipped BMW car that can be guided with the cellphone which also has its deadly functions. It's quite obvious the merchant made by the already mention company - they also brought a fancy motorcycle used in one of the most thrilling sequences when James and Wai-Lin escape from Carver's henchmen and that includes the couple's fly over a helicopter. "Tomorrow Never Dies" is great because it doesn't commit any kind of excesses, the plot is very simple to follow (this can be viewed as a problem to some, specially those who are more accustomed with complex plots, Bourne style) and never absurd; all the action and adventure are not overplayed, prolonged or tiring, it's all in a good measure and it's very exciting. I dare say those sequences were quite inspired. High point: the building escape using Carver's poster as a way out; the incredible car chase; Wai-Lin effortless escape tactics against the dangerous ones faced by 007, who feel a little annoyed with her. Their pairing is one of the best in the series, but the great and fun spectacle is the buffoon Carver and his memorable lines and actions (his mimics of Wai-Lin fighting style kills me every time). Obviously, he cannot put up a fight against the secret agent, but he has the loyal and muscular Stamper (G&ouml;tz Otto), a frightening guy who likes to torture his victims, and that's his only form of pleasure. For me, the only downer of this movie was the theme song, that hurts the ears, completely oversung. Anyway, it's a fun entertainment, filled with adrenaline and we can't forget the marvelous cast (one of the finest in the series) with Judi Dench (M), Samantha Bond (Moneypenny), Geoffrey Palmer, Vincent Schiavelli, Ricky Jay, Joe Don Baker and Gerard Butler (but you get an award if you find him in the middle of all the action). 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Film without Bond feeling
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Simon Fredriksson
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Pierce Brosnan is tough, sexy and has a twinkle in his eye, the third-best 007 after Sean Connery and Daniel Craig. But this movie is much worse than "Goldeneye", his first Bond movie. Thin screenplay about a media moguls (Jonathan Pryce) attempts to control the world by creating a war between Britain and China so that his new TV channel have something spectacular to report. Michelle Yeoh is a colorful and cool Bond girl, but Teri Hatcher, from the TV series "Desperate Housewives", does not add much in the role as the media moguls wife. Most boring of all, James Bond is so little James Bond, he is like any action hero out there. But at the phone manufacturer Ericsson they will party hard. The film's best scene is a car chase where 007 steers his BMW with the help of a remote control built in... well, you can guess what kind of phone.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    So far... so good!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    orourkec-292-269155
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm still satisfied on Tomorrow Never Dies after the first successful Goldeneye movie. I loved the actions and stunts! Original scenes and good characters. It is an impressive piece of work. The gadgets are always so good and make you more entertained than ever. Pierce Brosnan for me makes part of the group of the three best bonds ever! There are smart fights included and women still beautiful! "James Bond doesn't stop to make love and love with women". The movie could have added more special effects and something more to entertain the audience. It still captured me into the story though. Good job! For those who like james bond and haven't seen this one, I hope it will make you happy. Out of 100%, I RECOMMEND IT at 70%! I rate it: 7.2/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Overwhelming and thrilling entry in which Bond/Brosnan goes after a powerful media mogul
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ma-cortes
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Elloit Carver (Jonathan Pryce) is a megalomaniac and selfish media baron. Carver has the power to reach every person on the planet through his Carver Media Group Network- except for the People's Republic of Chinese who refuse his presence in their nation . The mogul is tied to the disappearance of a British battleship in the South China Sea . James Bond (Pierce Brosnan) heads to stop the media mogul's plan to induce war between China and the UK in order to obtain exclusive global media coverage and whose tentacles reach around the world . Carver, whose spouse (Teri Hatcher) was a former flame of 007 , is supported by a computer genius (Ricky Jay) and a nasty hunk man (Gotz Otto) . Along the way Bond join forces with a Chinese secret agent (Michelle Yeoh) , expert on martial arts . In addition , there appears the usuals , such as M (Judi Dench), Q (Desmond Llewelin) , Lois Maxwell, &uml;MoneyPenny&uml; (Samantha Bond) , Minister of Defense (Julian Fellowes) and Jake Wade (Joe Don Baker) . But not counting the regular characters of Bond, Q, M and Moneypenny, this is the first Bond movie to contain absolutely no Ian Fleming references . Likable Pierce Brosnan in an amazing adventure set on wonderful outdoors located mostly on Vietnam , being actually shot in Thailand . The original title of the film was "Tomorrow Never Lies", which makes sense when you consider media mogul Elliot Carver was creating the next day's headlines in advance, then causing those events to happen , but a typo on an early script draft was adopted by the producers, and &uml;Tomorrow never dies&uml; was used instead . This is a Bond's good outing in which faces dangerous adventures around the globe . Brosnan's outing with overwhelming action and spectacular scenarios , the film teams Bond with Michelle Yeoh as endearing ally in an effort to stop a technological communication mogul . After his first introduction in &uml;Golden eye&uml; as tough and attractive James Bond of the Ian Fleming's famous creation , Pierce Brosnan went on playing various 007 , as &uml;Die Another Day &uml; and this &uml;Tomorrow never dies&uml; . The picture starts with an overblown opening and following other impressive action set pieces . This solid , slick thriller with magic mix of action-packed , dazzling stunts, gadgetry, and romance provided by sexy company as Teri Hatcher and Michelle Yeoh . Pierce Brosnan as James Bond is fine , he does remarkably well , he earns in irony, humor ,suavity and sympathy, however also has coldness ,cunning , intelligence and toughness . Here Bond is an efficient , relentless agent trying to chase obstinately the criminals , traveling around the world as always , as this globe-trotting story is set in Pucket, Bangkok, Thailand (Saigon, Vietnam) , Hamburg , London and many other places . Because the second half of the film is set in Vietnam, the production negotiated for some time for permission to film there ; although it appeared close, the Vietnamese Ministry of Culture and Information eventually refused to allow it , the production decided to use Thailand as Vietnam, with Bangkok substituting for Saigon . Bond to achieve his aims , along the way uses violent means even pulling off brutal killings against enemies who wreak all sorts of havoc . As always Bond will use fantastic gadgets and spectacular cars (here 15 BMW 750's were destroyed in the making of the film) provided by &uml;Q&uml; (Desmond Llewelyn) . The stealth ship is not a fictional invention , Lockheed secretly constructed and demonstrated one in the early 1980s, but the US Navy finally decided they didn't want any ; the prototype, called the Sea Shadow, was 160 feet long . The picture contains comic-strip adventure , sensational pursuits , silly set pieces , great stunts , tongue-in check humor, automovile chase, frantic unstopped action , a breathtaking tour around the world , amazing gimmicks and stimulating images like are the happenings on the spectacular pursuits on the motorcycle and helicopter . As is like a roller-coaster , as is fast-paced , light , excitement, funny and entertaining ; it's a winner for oo7 fans and non-fans alike . The chase and suspense formula wears strong in this entry . The film made particularly heavy use of gadgetry because some fans thought there was too little of it in GoldenEye . Enjoyable title song by Sheryl Crow and stirring musical score fitting to action by David Arnold , following the John Barry's classic style . Riveting and fancy main titles , furthermore eye-popping production design by Allan Cameron . It's brimming with colorful and fascinating cinematography by cameraman Robert Elswit . The motion picture produced by habitual producers, Barbara Broccoli and Michael G. Wilson and dedicated to the memory of long-time Bond-film producer Albert R. Broccoli ; being professionally made by Robert Spottiswoode who filmed other successes such as &uml;the 6th day&uml;, &uml;Turner and Hooch&uml;, &uml;Air America&uml; , Shoot to kill&uml;and Under fire&uml; . Robert keeps this moving at an incredibly fast pace and this story about every's favorite super-spy facing off dangerous mogul . The film will appeal to James Bond series's buffs but good for fans only ; because this one goes on far too long and has provoked so much debate among 007 followers . Rating : 6'5 , well worth watching .
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Decent Bond flick.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Blueghost
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There's a couple of things I liked about classic Sean Connery Bond. A) he was smart. B) he let you know it. The other thing I liked about the classic Bond films was that there was a kind of credibility to them. You knew it was all comic book fun, but they were grounded. Pierce Brosnan could have been one of the great Bonds, but he's given precious little dialogue. We're essentially seeing a well crafted action flick from frame one. Bond films always had action, but this film seemed heavy on action, and little of what Bond knew, what he was all about, and how we knew he was capable of doing the things he did. That's pretty much my critique. A lot of money went into making this film a big blockbuster smash, and it delivers for what it is, but I didn't get a sense of Bondness, so much as I got a sense of a film wanting to be a James Bond film. Still, it's decent enough for what it is, an action film, but isn't Bond more than just an action hero? I think the technical stuff has gotten a lot better over the years of the Bond franchise's existence. But when you went to see a Bond film in the 60s and 70s, you didn't just go to see bullets flying, nor the Bond hotties adorning the screen, you went for the story and character. There's a fine plot driven film in here, but little else. And, true to big budget blockbusters needing bad-guys, we have a hint of Nazis in working for the evil boss that Bond must confront (although he himself may be one). I don't have much else to say about it other than I think that there's a better film in here. Yes, you heard me right. With all of the money dumped into this thing I'm still not satisfied that I saw a James Bond film. But, that's neither here nor there, I suppose. If I had shot it I would have cut back on some of the pyrotechnics, asked the Royal Navy to spare a frigate and a destroyer or two to fire real rounds instead of relying on my SFX team to drag a model through the water tank on the back lot while shooting it in slow mo. There's a lot of superficial adornments in this film to make it a Bond flick, but there isn't much Bond in it. I would have directed a different film. But again, that's all Monday morning quarterbacking. Still, it's a film, and a kind of popcorn fun film with some cross international romance involved, and maybe a bit of social engineering going on, but otherwise a decent watch. Give it a shot.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    007 Classy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    willrasmussen-617-992319
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is what I call a fun Bond movie to watch over again. I really like Pierce Brosnan as him playing Bond. The movie is enjoyable to watch and the action sequences are fun also. What seems to make this as a unique Bond film is the different types of weapons and gadgets that are shown in the movie. The story line is also makes the movie fun. I think this Bond movie is probably one the best Pierce Brosnan 007 movies. The movie is not so long and the scenes move at a fair pace. Prior to Goldeneye, this sets off a new type of Bond formula. I think this 007 movie is probably better than the Bond movies with Daniel Craig. I wish Pierce Brosnan was still playing James Bond.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Action packed but nothing extraordinary
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    varghesejunior
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If it's action you want then this Bond film will suit you. But it has nothing different to offer apart from conventional Bond stuff. In TND,Bond goes on a mission to expose a psychic media tycoon who wants to incite fire between UK and China and start World war 3 for his own selfish ends, and whose wife also happens to be Bond's ex girlfriend. The film is made well  Good story, direction, fast paced action with plenty of stunts, cool gadgets, dialogue delivery. It sure is enjoyable. There are a few unwanted scenes which is what I did not like. But there is nothing different in the film, unlike Daniel Craig's Bond films.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Silly but rather enjoyable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AllTomorrowsParties
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tomorrow Never Dies gets a bad rap. Not sure why. Really, there are only two things amiss. Firstly the villain is a bit 'soft' if you consider a news mogul a bit soft. Secondly the last act is really not as good as the rest of the film. Bits of it - Bond's fake death (or is that two fake deaths?) and Wei Lin getting access to the bridge stretch credulity a bit and the fist fight is rubbish - but that's about it for criticism - otherwise this is a really good Bond film and probably Brosnan's best. The action sequences are great - especially the helicopter / motorbike sequence - this is shot rather brilliantly. Then again, the driverless BMW is rather good as well. Its occasionally funny. Yeoh is masterful. Brosnan is on form and the inclusion of a British Navy is a bonus. Oh, and the funny CIA. You see, the list is quite long. Its not a 6.4 by any stretch of the imagination. Its not perfect, I grant you but it has a lot going for it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's kind of like a Fast Food Burger. You consume it, enjoy it, but forget all about it as soon you are finished
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    callanvass
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A far cry from Goldeneye, but It doesn't necessarily deserve all the hate it receives either. Tomorrow Never Dies is a fast paced affair, and an easily agreeable time-waster, but it's not the follow-up Goldeneye deserved, either. It's much too daft for the heavy plot that it has. The main reason this movie is entertaining is the spectacular stunts. It has some great action set pieces, which managed to make the time pass nicely. Michelle Yeoh makes for a refreshingly unique Bond Girl, due to her actual Martial Arts background. I dug the chemistry with her & Brosnan. Speaking of Brosnan He is very good as Bond. He has charisma and wit to spare. He's not quite as good as Timothy Dalton, but he is excellent nonetheless. Johnathan Pryce is decent as the villain. He is fitfully menacing and did the job overall. Teri Hatcher's character is a bit disposable, but she was good in her role. Desmond Llewelyn & Judi Dench are as classy as ever Final Thoughts: Instantly forgettable stuff, but it manages to be an effective time-waster. It's not a great Bond film, but it is an OK action film. I didn't mind it at all. 5.6/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Where Tomorrow Never Dies Stands
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    davorinlonac
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is Pierce Brosnans second performance as agent 007 and could have been better. It is a very big decline since his first film being Goldenye, one of my favorites. This Bond film is good but doesn't feel like a Bond film somehow. Bond pretty much murders Elliot Carver, the villain, like a serial killer would! But again Pierce Brosnan makes the Bond character feel cooler and smoother. This is a good Bond movie but if I compare it to my favorites, it isn't very good. After watching it once and then watching it again there are some scenes you can look forward to. Elliot Carver by far is the strangest, but OK Bond villain of all time. Tomorrow Never Dies stands 19th on a list of mine where the 007 Movies have been ranked from worst to greatest. The film itself is good but The Bond Girl lets it down, as well as some of the fake action.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the most exciting Bond films ever made
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rodrigo Amaro (rodrigo882008@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    By far, my favorite of Brosnan along with "Goldeneye". Might not be one of the best Bond movies but it's certainly one of the most memorable. But truth be told: its effectiveness now is a little ruined to the massive appeal of the award winning "Skyfall", which at the same time reinvented Bond yet brought back some of its most appreciable qualities - this merge was inexistent in "Casino Royale" and "Quantum of Solace", both are just new reboots with a theme song to show that it's faithful to its roots. Mr. Brosnan at the top of his game, so smooth, active and funny, returns as Bond with plenty of style in one of Bond's most down to earth missions: to stop a possible conflict between England and China about to emerge from the dephts of a creative and destructive mind, the egocentric Elliot Carver (the priceless Jonathan Pryce), a media mogul &agrave; la Citizen Kane/Rupert Murdoch with his own declaration of principals which is to provide the news before they happen. The big scoop is to broadcast (and cause!) the WWIII. 007 is helped by a Chinese agent, the handy Colonel Wai-Lin (Michelle Yeoh) who is more advanced in her spy/fight techniques; and the other Bond girl is a former affair of his, now married with Elliot, a femme fatale played by Teri Hatcher. And this wouldn't be a complete Bond movie without the gadgets carefully supplied by Q (Desmond Llewelyn); here, a fully equipped BMW car that can be guided with the cellphone which also has its deadly functions. It's quite obvious the merchant made by the already mention company - they also brought a fancy motorcycle used in one of the most thrilling sequences when James and Wai-Lin escape from Carver's henchmen and that includes the couple's fly over a helicopter. "Tomorrow Never Dies" is great because it doesn't commit any kind of excesses, the plot is very simple to follow (this can be viewed as a problem to some, specially those who are more accustomed with complex plots, Bourne style) and never absurd; all the action and adventure are not overplayed, prolonged or tiring, it's all in a good measure and it's very exciting. I dare say those sequences were quite inspired. High point: the building escape using Carver's poster as a way out; the incredible car chase; Wai-Lin effortless escape tactics against the dangerous ones faced by 007, who feel a little annoyed with her. Their pairing is one of the best in the series, but the great and fun spectacle is the buffoon Carver and his memorable lines and actions (his mimics of Wai-Lin fighting style kills me every time). Obviously, he cannot put up a fight against the secret agent, but he has the loyal and muscular Stamper (G&ouml;tz Otto), a frightening guy who likes to torture his victims, and that's his only form of pleasure. For me, the only downer of this movie was the theme song, that hurts the ears, completely oversung. Anyway, it's a fun entertainment, filled with adrenaline and we can't forget the marvelous cast (one of the finest in the series) with Judi Dench (M), Samantha Bond (Moneypenny), Geoffrey Palmer, Vincent Schiavelli, Ricky Jay, Joe Don Baker and Gerard Butler (but you get an award if you find him in the middle of all the action). 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Film without Bond feeling
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Simon Fredriksson
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Pierce Brosnan is tough, sexy and has a twinkle in his eye, the third-best 007 after Sean Connery and Daniel Craig. But this movie is much worse than "Goldeneye", his first Bond movie. Thin screenplay about a media moguls (Jonathan Pryce) attempts to control the world by creating a war between Britain and China so that his new TV channel have something spectacular to report. Michelle Yeoh is a colorful and cool Bond girl, but Teri Hatcher, from the TV series "Desperate Housewives", does not add much in the role as the media moguls wife. Most boring of all, James Bond is so little James Bond, he is like any action hero out there. But at the phone manufacturer Ericsson they will party hard. The film's best scene is a car chase where 007 steers his BMW with the help of a remote control built in... well, you can guess what kind of phone.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    So far... so good!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    orourkec-292-269155
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm still satisfied on Tomorrow Never Dies after the first successful Goldeneye movie. I loved the actions and stunts! Original scenes and good characters. It is an impressive piece of work. The gadgets are always so good and make you more entertained than ever. Pierce Brosnan for me makes part of the group of the three best bonds ever! There are smart fights included and women still beautiful! "James Bond doesn't stop to make love and love with women". The movie could have added more special effects and something more to entertain the audience. It still captured me into the story though. Good job! For those who like james bond and haven't seen this one, I hope it will make you happy. Out of 100%, I RECOMMEND IT at 70%! I rate it: 7.2/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Overwhelming and thrilling entry in which Bond/Brosnan goes after a powerful media mogul
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ma-cortes
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Elloit Carver (Jonathan Pryce) is a megalomaniac and selfish media baron. Carver has the power to reach every person on the planet through his Carver Media Group Network- except for the People's Republic of Chinese who refuse his presence in their nation . The mogul is tied to the disappearance of a British battleship in the South China Sea . James Bond (Pierce Brosnan) heads to stop the media mogul's plan to induce war between China and the UK in order to obtain exclusive global media coverage and whose tentacles reach around the world . Carver, whose spouse (Teri Hatcher) was a former flame of 007 , is supported by a computer genius (Ricky Jay) and a nasty hunk man (Gotz Otto) . Along the way Bond join forces with a Chinese secret agent (Michelle Yeoh) , expert on martial arts . In addition , there appears the usuals , such as M (Judi Dench), Q (Desmond Llewelin) , Lois Maxwell, &uml;MoneyPenny&uml; (Samantha Bond) , Minister of Defense (Julian Fellowes) and Jake Wade (Joe Don Baker) . But not counting the regular characters of Bond, Q, M and Moneypenny, this is the first Bond movie to contain absolutely no Ian Fleming references . Likable Pierce Brosnan in an amazing adventure set on wonderful outdoors located mostly on Vietnam , being actually shot in Thailand . The original title of the film was "Tomorrow Never Lies", which makes sense when you consider media mogul Elliot Carver was creating the next day's headlines in advance, then causing those events to happen , but a typo on an early script draft was adopted by the producers, and &uml;Tomorrow never dies&uml; was used instead . This is a Bond's good outing in which faces dangerous adventures around the globe . Brosnan's outing with overwhelming action and spectacular scenarios , the film teams Bond with Michelle Yeoh as endearing ally in an effort to stop a technological communication mogul . After his first introduction in &uml;Golden eye&uml; as tough and attractive James Bond of the Ian Fleming's famous creation , Pierce Brosnan went on playing various 007 , as &uml;Die Another Day &uml; and this &uml;Tomorrow never dies&uml; . The picture starts with an overblown opening and following other impressive action set pieces . This solid , slick thriller with magic mix of action-packed , dazzling stunts, gadgetry, and romance provided by sexy company as Teri Hatcher and Michelle Yeoh . Pierce Brosnan as James Bond is fine , he does remarkably well , he earns in irony, humor ,suavity and sympathy, however also has coldness ,cunning , intelligence and toughness . Here Bond is an efficient , relentless agent trying to chase obstinately the criminals , traveling around the world as always , as this globe-trotting story is set in Pucket, Bangkok, Thailand (Saigon, Vietnam) , Hamburg , London and many other places . Because the second half of the film is set in Vietnam, the production negotiated for some time for permission to film there ; although it appeared close, the Vietnamese Ministry of Culture and Information eventually refused to allow it , the production decided to use Thailand as Vietnam, with Bangkok substituting for Saigon . Bond to achieve his aims , along the way uses violent means even pulling off brutal killings against enemies who wreak all sorts of havoc . As always Bond will use fantastic gadgets and spectacular cars (here 15 BMW 750's were destroyed in the making of the film) provided by &uml;Q&uml; (Desmond Llewelyn) . The stealth ship is not a fictional invention , Lockheed secretly constructed and demonstrated one in the early 1980s, but the US Navy finally decided they didn't want any ; the prototype, called the Sea Shadow, was 160 feet long . The picture contains comic-strip adventure , sensational pursuits , silly set pieces , great stunts , tongue-in check humor, automovile chase, frantic unstopped action , a breathtaking tour around the world , amazing gimmicks and stimulating images like are the happenings on the spectacular pursuits on the motorcycle and helicopter . As is like a roller-coaster , as is fast-paced , light , excitement, funny and entertaining ; it's a winner for oo7 fans and non-fans alike . The chase and suspense formula wears strong in this entry . The film made particularly heavy use of gadgetry because some fans thought there was too little of it in GoldenEye . Enjoyable title song by Sheryl Crow and stirring musical score fitting to action by David Arnold , following the John Barry's classic style . Riveting and fancy main titles , furthermore eye-popping production design by Allan Cameron . It's brimming with colorful and fascinating cinematography by cameraman Robert Elswit . The motion picture produced by habitual producers, Barbara Broccoli and Michael G. Wilson and dedicated to the memory of long-time Bond-film producer Albert R. Broccoli ; being professionally made by Robert Spottiswoode who filmed other successes such as &uml;the 6th day&uml;, &uml;Turner and Hooch&uml;, &uml;Air America&uml; , Shoot to kill&uml;and Under fire&uml; . Robert keeps this moving at an incredibly fast pace and this story about every's favorite super-spy facing off dangerous mogul . The film will appeal to James Bond series's buffs but good for fans only ; because this one goes on far too long and has provoked so much debate among 007 followers . Rating : 6'5 , well worth watching .
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Decent Bond flick.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Blueghost
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There's a couple of things I liked about classic Sean Connery Bond. A) he was smart. B) he let you know it. The other thing I liked about the classic Bond films was that there was a kind of credibility to them. You knew it was all comic book fun, but they were grounded. Pierce Brosnan could have been one of the great Bonds, but he's given precious little dialogue. We're essentially seeing a well crafted action flick from frame one. Bond films always had action, but this film seemed heavy on action, and little of what Bond knew, what he was all about, and how we knew he was capable of doing the things he did. That's pretty much my critique. A lot of money went into making this film a big blockbuster smash, and it delivers for what it is, but I didn't get a sense of Bondness, so much as I got a sense of a film wanting to be a James Bond film. Still, it's decent enough for what it is, an action film, but isn't Bond more than just an action hero? I think the technical stuff has gotten a lot better over the years of the Bond franchise's existence. But when you went to see a Bond film in the 60s and 70s, you didn't just go to see bullets flying, nor the Bond hotties adorning the screen, you went for the story and character. There's a fine plot driven film in here, but little else. And, true to big budget blockbusters needing bad-guys, we have a hint of Nazis in working for the evil boss that Bond must confront (although he himself may be one). I don't have much else to say about it other than I think that there's a better film in here. Yes, you heard me right. With all of the money dumped into this thing I'm still not satisfied that I saw a James Bond film. But, that's neither here nor there, I suppose. If I had shot it I would have cut back on some of the pyrotechnics, asked the Royal Navy to spare a frigate and a destroyer or two to fire real rounds instead of relying on my SFX team to drag a model through the water tank on the back lot while shooting it in slow mo. There's a lot of superficial adornments in this film to make it a Bond flick, but there isn't much Bond in it. I would have directed a different film. But again, that's all Monday morning quarterbacking. Still, it's a film, and a kind of popcorn fun film with some cross international romance involved, and maybe a bit of social engineering going on, but otherwise a decent watch. Give it a shot.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    007 Classy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    willrasmussen-617-992319
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is what I call a fun Bond movie to watch over again. I really like Pierce Brosnan as him playing Bond. The movie is enjoyable to watch and the action sequences are fun also. What seems to make this as a unique Bond film is the different types of weapons and gadgets that are shown in the movie. The story line is also makes the movie fun. I think this Bond movie is probably one the best Pierce Brosnan 007 movies. The movie is not so long and the scenes move at a fair pace. Prior to Goldeneye, this sets off a new type of Bond formula. I think this 007 movie is probably better than the Bond movies with Daniel Craig. I wish Pierce Brosnan was still playing James Bond.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Action packed but nothing extraordinary
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    varghesejunior
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If it's action you want then this Bond film will suit you. But it has nothing different to offer apart from conventional Bond stuff. In TND,Bond goes on a mission to expose a psychic media tycoon who wants to incite fire between UK and China and start World war 3 for his own selfish ends, and whose wife also happens to be Bond's ex girlfriend. The film is made well  Good story, direction, fast paced action with plenty of stunts, cool gadgets, dialogue delivery. It sure is enjoyable. There are a few unwanted scenes which is what I did not like. But there is nothing different in the film, unlike Daniel Craig's Bond films.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Silly but rather enjoyable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AllTomorrowsParties
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tomorrow Never Dies gets a bad rap. Not sure why. Really, there are only two things amiss. Firstly the villain is a bit 'soft' if you consider a news mogul a bit soft. Secondly the last act is really not as good as the rest of the film. Bits of it - Bond's fake death (or is that two fake deaths?) and Wei Lin getting access to the bridge stretch credulity a bit and the fist fight is rubbish - but that's about it for criticism - otherwise this is a really good Bond film and probably Brosnan's best. The action sequences are great - especially the helicopter / motorbike sequence - this is shot rather brilliantly. Then again, the driverless BMW is rather good as well. Its occasionally funny. Yeoh is masterful. Brosnan is on form and the inclusion of a British Navy is a bonus. Oh, and the funny CIA. You see, the list is quite long. Its not a 6.4 by any stretch of the imagination. Its not perfect, I grant you but it has a lot going for it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's kind of like a Fast Food Burger. You consume it, enjoy it, but forget all about it as soon you are finished
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    callanvass
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A far cry from Goldeneye, but It doesn't necessarily deserve all the hate it receives either. Tomorrow Never Dies is a fast paced affair, and an easily agreeable time-waster, but it's not the follow-up Goldeneye deserved, either. It's much too daft for the heavy plot that it has. The main reason this movie is entertaining is the spectacular stunts. It has some great action set pieces, which managed to make the time pass nicely. Michelle Yeoh makes for a refreshingly unique Bond Girl, due to her actual Martial Arts background. I dug the chemistry with her & Brosnan. Speaking of Brosnan He is very good as Bond. He has charisma and wit to spare. He's not quite as good as Timothy Dalton, but he is excellent nonetheless. Johnathan Pryce is decent as the villain. He is fitfully menacing and did the job overall. Teri Hatcher's character is a bit disposable, but she was good in her role. Desmond Llewelyn & Judi Dench are as classy as ever Final Thoughts: Instantly forgettable stuff, but it manages to be an effective time-waster. It's not a great Bond film, but it is an OK action film. I didn't mind it at all. 5.6/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Where Tomorrow Never Dies Stands
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    davorinlonac
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is Pierce Brosnans second performance as agent 007 and could have been better. It is a very big decline since his first film being Goldenye, one of my favorites. This Bond film is good but doesn't feel like a Bond film somehow. Bond pretty much murders Elliot Carver, the villain, like a serial killer would! But again Pierce Brosnan makes the Bond character feel cooler and smoother. This is a good Bond movie but if I compare it to my favorites, it isn't very good. After watching it once and then watching it again there are some scenes you can look forward to. Elliot Carver by far is the strangest, but OK Bond villain of all time. Tomorrow Never Dies stands 19th on a list of mine where the 007 Movies have been ranked from worst to greatest. The film itself is good but The Bond Girl lets it down, as well as some of the fake action.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the most exciting Bond films ever made
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rodrigo Amaro (rodrigo882008@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    By far, my favorite of Brosnan along with "Goldeneye". Might not be one of the best Bond movies but it's certainly one of the most memorable. But truth be told: its effectiveness now is a little ruined to the massive appeal of the award winning "Skyfall", which at the same time reinvented Bond yet brought back some of its most appreciable qualities - this merge was inexistent in "Casino Royale" and "Quantum of Solace", both are just new reboots with a theme song to show that it's faithful to its roots. Mr. Brosnan at the top of his game, so smooth, active and funny, returns as Bond with plenty of style in one of Bond's most down to earth missions: to stop a possible conflict between England and China about to emerge from the dephts of a creative and destructive mind, the egocentric Elliot Carver (the priceless Jonathan Pryce), a media mogul &agrave; la Citizen Kane/Rupert Murdoch with his own declaration of principals which is to provide the news before they happen. The big scoop is to broadcast (and cause!) the WWIII. 007 is helped by a Chinese agent, the handy Colonel Wai-Lin (Michelle Yeoh) who is more advanced in her spy/fight techniques; and the other Bond girl is a former affair of his, now married with Elliot, a femme fatale played by Teri Hatcher. And this wouldn't be a complete Bond movie without the gadgets carefully supplied by Q (Desmond Llewelyn); here, a fully equipped BMW car that can be guided with the cellphone which also has its deadly functions. It's quite obvious the merchant made by the already mention company - they also brought a fancy motorcycle used in one of the most thrilling sequences when James and Wai-Lin escape from Carver's henchmen and that includes the couple's fly over a helicopter. "Tomorrow Never Dies" is great because it doesn't commit any kind of excesses, the plot is very simple to follow (this can be viewed as a problem to some, specially those who are more accustomed with complex plots, Bourne style) and never absurd; all the action and adventure are not overplayed, prolonged or tiring, it's all in a good measure and it's very exciting. I dare say those sequences were quite inspired. High point: the building escape using Carver's poster as a way out; the incredible car chase; Wai-Lin effortless escape tactics against the dangerous ones faced by 007, who feel a little annoyed with her. Their pairing is one of the best in the series, but the great and fun spectacle is the buffoon Carver and his memorable lines and actions (his mimics of Wai-Lin fighting style kills me every time). Obviously, he cannot put up a fight against the secret agent, but he has the loyal and muscular Stamper (G&ouml;tz Otto), a frightening guy who likes to torture his victims, and that's his only form of pleasure. For me, the only downer of this movie was the theme song, that hurts the ears, completely oversung. Anyway, it's a fun entertainment, filled with adrenaline and we can't forget the marvelous cast (one of the finest in the series) with Judi Dench (M), Samantha Bond (Moneypenny), Geoffrey Palmer, Vincent Schiavelli, Ricky Jay, Joe Don Baker and Gerard Butler (but you get an award if you find him in the middle of all the action). 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Film without Bond feeling
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Simon Fredriksson
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Pierce Brosnan is tough, sexy and has a twinkle in his eye, the third-best 007 after Sean Connery and Daniel Craig. But this movie is much worse than "Goldeneye", his first Bond movie. Thin screenplay about a media moguls (Jonathan Pryce) attempts to control the world by creating a war between Britain and China so that his new TV channel have something spectacular to report. Michelle Yeoh is a colorful and cool Bond girl, but Teri Hatcher, from the TV series "Desperate Housewives", does not add much in the role as the media moguls wife. Most boring of all, James Bond is so little James Bond, he is like any action hero out there. But at the phone manufacturer Ericsson they will party hard. The film's best scene is a car chase where 007 steers his BMW with the help of a remote control built in... well, you can guess what kind of phone.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    So far... so good!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    orourkec-292-269155
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm still satisfied on Tomorrow Never Dies after the first successful Goldeneye movie. I loved the actions and stunts! Original scenes and good characters. It is an impressive piece of work. The gadgets are always so good and make you more entertained than ever. Pierce Brosnan for me makes part of the group of the three best bonds ever! There are smart fights included and women still beautiful! "James Bond doesn't stop to make love and love with women". The movie could have added more special effects and something more to entertain the audience. It still captured me into the story though. Good job! For those who like james bond and haven't seen this one, I hope it will make you happy. Out of 100%, I RECOMMEND IT at 70%! I rate it: 7.2/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Overwhelming and thrilling entry in which Bond/Brosnan goes after a powerful media mogul
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ma-cortes
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Elloit Carver (Jonathan Pryce) is a megalomaniac and selfish media baron. Carver has the power to reach every person on the planet through his Carver Media Group Network- except for the People's Republic of Chinese who refuse his presence in their nation . The mogul is tied to the disappearance of a British battleship in the South China Sea . James Bond (Pierce Brosnan) heads to stop the media mogul's plan to induce war between China and the UK in order to obtain exclusive global media coverage and whose tentacles reach around the world . Carver, whose spouse (Teri Hatcher) was a former flame of 007 , is supported by a computer genius (Ricky Jay) and a nasty hunk man (Gotz Otto) . Along the way Bond join forces with a Chinese secret agent (Michelle Yeoh) , expert on martial arts . In addition , there appears the usuals , such as M (Judi Dench), Q (Desmond Llewelin) , Lois Maxwell, &uml;MoneyPenny&uml; (Samantha Bond) , Minister of Defense (Julian Fellowes) and Jake Wade (Joe Don Baker) . But not counting the regular characters of Bond, Q, M and Moneypenny, this is the first Bond movie to contain absolutely no Ian Fleming references . Likable Pierce Brosnan in an amazing adventure set on wonderful outdoors located mostly on Vietnam , being actually shot in Thailand . The original title of the film was "Tomorrow Never Lies", which makes sense when you consider media mogul Elliot Carver was creating the next day's headlines in advance, then causing those events to happen , but a typo on an early script draft was adopted by the producers, and &uml;Tomorrow never dies&uml; was used instead . This is a Bond's good outing in which faces dangerous adventures around the globe . Brosnan's outing with overwhelming action and spectacular scenarios , the film teams Bond with Michelle Yeoh as endearing ally in an effort to stop a technological communication mogul . After his first introduction in &uml;Golden eye&uml; as tough and attractive James Bond of the Ian Fleming's famous creation , Pierce Brosnan went on playing various 007 , as &uml;Die Another Day &uml; and this &uml;Tomorrow never dies&uml; . The picture starts with an overblown opening and following other impressive action set pieces . This solid , slick thriller with magic mix of action-packed , dazzling stunts, gadgetry, and romance provided by sexy company as Teri Hatcher and Michelle Yeoh . Pierce Brosnan as James Bond is fine , he does remarkably well , he earns in irony, humor ,suavity and sympathy, however also has coldness ,cunning , intelligence and toughness . Here Bond is an efficient , relentless agent trying to chase obstinately the criminals , traveling around the world as always , as this globe-trotting story is set in Pucket, Bangkok, Thailand (Saigon, Vietnam) , Hamburg , London and many other places . Because the second half of the film is set in Vietnam, the production negotiated for some time for permission to film there ; although it appeared close, the Vietnamese Ministry of Culture and Information eventually refused to allow it , the production decided to use Thailand as Vietnam, with Bangkok substituting for Saigon . Bond to achieve his aims , along the way uses violent means even pulling off brutal killings against enemies who wreak all sorts of havoc . As always Bond will use fantastic gadgets and spectacular cars (here 15 BMW 750's were destroyed in the making of the film) provided by &uml;Q&uml; (Desmond Llewelyn) . The stealth ship is not a fictional invention , Lockheed secretly constructed and demonstrated one in the early 1980s, but the US Navy finally decided they didn't want any ; the prototype, called the Sea Shadow, was 160 feet long . The picture contains comic-strip adventure , sensational pursuits , silly set pieces , great stunts , tongue-in check humor, automovile chase, frantic unstopped action , a breathtaking tour around the world , amazing gimmicks and stimulating images like are the happenings on the spectacular pursuits on the motorcycle and helicopter . As is like a roller-coaster , as is fast-paced , light , excitement, funny and entertaining ; it's a winner for oo7 fans and non-fans alike . The chase and suspense formula wears strong in this entry . The film made particularly heavy use of gadgetry because some fans thought there was too little of it in GoldenEye . Enjoyable title song by Sheryl Crow and stirring musical score fitting to action by David Arnold , following the John Barry's classic style . Riveting and fancy main titles , furthermore eye-popping production design by Allan Cameron . It's brimming with colorful and fascinating cinematography by cameraman Robert Elswit . The motion picture produced by habitual producers, Barbara Broccoli and Michael G. Wilson and dedicated to the memory of long-time Bond-film producer Albert R. Broccoli ; being professionally made by Robert Spottiswoode who filmed other successes such as &uml;the 6th day&uml;, &uml;Turner and Hooch&uml;, &uml;Air America&uml; , Shoot to kill&uml;and Under fire&uml; . Robert keeps this moving at an incredibly fast pace and this story about every's favorite super-spy facing off dangerous mogul . The film will appeal to James Bond series's buffs but good for fans only ; because this one goes on far too long and has provoked so much debate among 007 followers . Rating : 6'5 , well worth watching .
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Decent Bond flick.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Blueghost
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There's a couple of things I liked about classic Sean Connery Bond. A) he was smart. B) he let you know it. The other thing I liked about the classic Bond films was that there was a kind of credibility to them. You knew it was all comic book fun, but they were grounded. Pierce Brosnan could have been one of the great Bonds, but he's given precious little dialogue. We're essentially seeing a well crafted action flick from frame one. Bond films always had action, but this film seemed heavy on action, and little of what Bond knew, what he was all about, and how we knew he was capable of doing the things he did. That's pretty much my critique. A lot of money went into making this film a big blockbuster smash, and it delivers for what it is, but I didn't get a sense of Bondness, so much as I got a sense of a film wanting to be a James Bond film. Still, it's decent enough for what it is, an action film, but isn't Bond more than just an action hero? I think the technical stuff has gotten a lot better over the years of the Bond franchise's existence. But when you went to see a Bond film in the 60s and 70s, you didn't just go to see bullets flying, nor the Bond hotties adorning the screen, you went for the story and character. There's a fine plot driven film in here, but little else. And, true to big budget blockbusters needing bad-guys, we have a hint of Nazis in working for the evil boss that Bond must confront (although he himself may be one). I don't have much else to say about it other than I think that there's a better film in here. Yes, you heard me right. With all of the money dumped into this thing I'm still not satisfied that I saw a James Bond film. But, that's neither here nor there, I suppose. If I had shot it I would have cut back on some of the pyrotechnics, asked the Royal Navy to spare a frigate and a destroyer or two to fire real rounds instead of relying on my SFX team to drag a model through the water tank on the back lot while shooting it in slow mo. There's a lot of superficial adornments in this film to make it a Bond flick, but there isn't much Bond in it. I would have directed a different film. But again, that's all Monday morning quarterbacking. Still, it's a film, and a kind of popcorn fun film with some cross international romance involved, and maybe a bit of social engineering going on, but otherwise a decent watch. Give it a shot.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    007 Classy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    willrasmussen-617-992319
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is what I call a fun Bond movie to watch over again. I really like Pierce Brosnan as him playing Bond. The movie is enjoyable to watch and the action sequences are fun also. What seems to make this as a unique Bond film is the different types of weapons and gadgets that are shown in the movie. The story line is also makes the movie fun. I think this Bond movie is probably one the best Pierce Brosnan 007 movies. The movie is not so long and the scenes move at a fair pace. Prior to Goldeneye, this sets off a new type of Bond formula. I think this 007 movie is probably better than the Bond movies with Daniel Craig. I wish Pierce Brosnan was still playing James Bond.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Action packed but nothing extraordinary
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    varghesejunior
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If it's action you want then this Bond film will suit you. But it has nothing different to offer apart from conventional Bond stuff. In TND,Bond goes on a mission to expose a psychic media tycoon who wants to incite fire between UK and China and start World war 3 for his own selfish ends, and whose wife also happens to be Bond's ex girlfriend. The film is made well  Good story, direction, fast paced action with plenty of stunts, cool gadgets, dialogue delivery. It sure is enjoyable. There are a few unwanted scenes which is what I did not like. But there is nothing different in the film, unlike Daniel Craig's Bond films.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Silly but rather enjoyable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AllTomorrowsParties
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tomorrow Never Dies gets a bad rap. Not sure why. Really, there are only two things amiss. Firstly the villain is a bit 'soft' if you consider a news mogul a bit soft. Secondly the last act is really not as good as the rest of the film. Bits of it - Bond's fake death (or is that two fake deaths?) and Wei Lin getting access to the bridge stretch credulity a bit and the fist fight is rubbish - but that's about it for criticism - otherwise this is a really good Bond film and probably Brosnan's best. The action sequences are great - especially the helicopter / motorbike sequence - this is shot rather brilliantly. Then again, the driverless BMW is rather good as well. Its occasionally funny. Yeoh is masterful. Brosnan is on form and the inclusion of a British Navy is a bonus. Oh, and the funny CIA. You see, the list is quite long. Its not a 6.4 by any stretch of the imagination. Its not perfect, I grant you but it has a lot going for it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's kind of like a Fast Food Burger. You consume it, enjoy it, but forget all about it as soon you are finished
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    callanvass
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A far cry from Goldeneye, but It doesn't necessarily deserve all the hate it receives either. Tomorrow Never Dies is a fast paced affair, and an easily agreeable time-waster, but it's not the follow-up Goldeneye deserved, either. It's much too daft for the heavy plot that it has. The main reason this movie is entertaining is the spectacular stunts. It has some great action set pieces, which managed to make the time pass nicely. Michelle Yeoh makes for a refreshingly unique Bond Girl, due to her actual Martial Arts background. I dug the chemistry with her & Brosnan. Speaking of Brosnan He is very good as Bond. He has charisma and wit to spare. He's not quite as good as Timothy Dalton, but he is excellent nonetheless. Johnathan Pryce is decent as the villain. He is fitfully menacing and did the job overall. Teri Hatcher's character is a bit disposable, but she was good in her role. Desmond Llewelyn & Judi Dench are as classy as ever Final Thoughts: Instantly forgettable stuff, but it manages to be an effective time-waster. It's not a great Bond film, but it is an OK action film. I didn't mind it at all. 5.6/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Where Tomorrow Never Dies Stands
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    davorinlonac
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is Pierce Brosnans second performance as agent 007 and could have been better. It is a very big decline since his first film being Goldenye, one of my favorites. This Bond film is good but doesn't feel like a Bond film somehow. Bond pretty much murders Elliot Carver, the villain, like a serial killer would! But again Pierce Brosnan makes the Bond character feel cooler and smoother. This is a good Bond movie but if I compare it to my favorites, it isn't very good. After watching it once and then watching it again there are some scenes you can look forward to. Elliot Carver by far is the strangest, but OK Bond villain of all time. Tomorrow Never Dies stands 19th on a list of mine where the 007 Movies have been ranked from worst to greatest. The film itself is good but The Bond Girl lets it down, as well as some of the fake action.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the most exciting Bond films ever made
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rodrigo Amaro (rodrigo882008@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    By far, my favorite of Brosnan along with "Goldeneye". Might not be one of the best Bond movies but it's certainly one of the most memorable. But truth be told: its effectiveness now is a little ruined to the massive appeal of the award winning "Skyfall", which at the same time reinvented Bond yet brought back some of its most appreciable qualities - this merge was inexistent in "Casino Royale" and "Quantum of Solace", both are just new reboots with a theme song to show that it's faithful to its roots. Mr. Brosnan at the top of his game, so smooth, active and funny, returns as Bond with plenty of style in one of Bond's most down to earth missions: to stop a possible conflict between England and China about to emerge from the dephts of a creative and destructive mind, the egocentric Elliot Carver (the priceless Jonathan Pryce), a media mogul &agrave; la Citizen Kane/Rupert Murdoch with his own declaration of principals which is to provide the news before they happen. The big scoop is to broadcast (and cause!) the WWIII. 007 is helped by a Chinese agent, the handy Colonel Wai-Lin (Michelle Yeoh) who is more advanced in her spy/fight techniques; and the other Bond girl is a former affair of his, now married with Elliot, a femme fatale played by Teri Hatcher. And this wouldn't be a complete Bond movie without the gadgets carefully supplied by Q (Desmond Llewelyn); here, a fully equipped BMW car that can be guided with the cellphone which also has its deadly functions. It's quite obvious the merchant made by the already mention company - they also brought a fancy motorcycle used in one of the most thrilling sequences when James and Wai-Lin escape from Carver's henchmen and that includes the couple's fly over a helicopter. "Tomorrow Never Dies" is great because it doesn't commit any kind of excesses, the plot is very simple to follow (this can be viewed as a problem to some, specially those who are more accustomed with complex plots, Bourne style) and never absurd; all the action and adventure are not overplayed, prolonged or tiring, it's all in a good measure and it's very exciting. I dare say those sequences were quite inspired. High point: the building escape using Carver's poster as a way out; the incredible car chase; Wai-Lin effortless escape tactics against the dangerous ones faced by 007, who feel a little annoyed with her. Their pairing is one of the best in the series, but the great and fun spectacle is the buffoon Carver and his memorable lines and actions (his mimics of Wai-Lin fighting style kills me every time). Obviously, he cannot put up a fight against the secret agent, but he has the loyal and muscular Stamper (G&ouml;tz Otto), a frightening guy who likes to torture his victims, and that's his only form of pleasure. For me, the only downer of this movie was the theme song, that hurts the ears, completely oversung. Anyway, it's a fun entertainment, filled with adrenaline and we can't forget the marvelous cast (one of the finest in the series) with Judi Dench (M), Samantha Bond (Moneypenny), Geoffrey Palmer, Vincent Schiavelli, Ricky Jay, Joe Don Baker and Gerard Butler (but you get an award if you find him in the middle of all the action). 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Film without Bond feeling
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Simon Fredriksson
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Pierce Brosnan is tough, sexy and has a twinkle in his eye, the third-best 007 after Sean Connery and Daniel Craig. But this movie is much worse than "Goldeneye", his first Bond movie. Thin screenplay about a media moguls (Jonathan Pryce) attempts to control the world by creating a war between Britain and China so that his new TV channel have something spectacular to report. Michelle Yeoh is a colorful and cool Bond girl, but Teri Hatcher, from the TV series "Desperate Housewives", does not add much in the role as the media moguls wife. Most boring of all, James Bond is so little James Bond, he is like any action hero out there. But at the phone manufacturer Ericsson they will party hard. The film's best scene is a car chase where 007 steers his BMW with the help of a remote control built in... well, you can guess what kind of phone.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    So far... so good!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    orourkec-292-269155
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm still satisfied on Tomorrow Never Dies after the first successful Goldeneye movie. I loved the actions and stunts! Original scenes and good characters. It is an impressive piece of work. The gadgets are always so good and make you more entertained than ever. Pierce Brosnan for me makes part of the group of the three best bonds ever! There are smart fights included and women still beautiful! "James Bond doesn't stop to make love and love with women". The movie could have added more special effects and something more to entertain the audience. It still captured me into the story though. Good job! For those who like james bond and haven't seen this one, I hope it will make you happy. Out of 100%, I RECOMMEND IT at 70%! I rate it: 7.2/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Overwhelming and thrilling entry in which Bond/Brosnan goes after a powerful media mogul
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ma-cortes
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Elloit Carver (Jonathan Pryce) is a megalomaniac and selfish media baron. Carver has the power to reach every person on the planet through his Carver Media Group Network- except for the People's Republic of Chinese who refuse his presence in their nation . The mogul is tied to the disappearance of a British battleship in the South China Sea . James Bond (Pierce Brosnan) heads to stop the media mogul's plan to induce war between China and the UK in order to obtain exclusive global media coverage and whose tentacles reach around the world . Carver, whose spouse (Teri Hatcher) was a former flame of 007 , is supported by a computer genius (Ricky Jay) and a nasty hunk man (Gotz Otto) . Along the way Bond join forces with a Chinese secret agent (Michelle Yeoh) , expert on martial arts . In addition , there appears the usuals , such as M (Judi Dench), Q (Desmond Llewelin) , Lois Maxwell, &uml;MoneyPenny&uml; (Samantha Bond) , Minister of Defense (Julian Fellowes) and Jake Wade (Joe Don Baker) . But not counting the regular characters of Bond, Q, M and Moneypenny, this is the first Bond movie to contain absolutely no Ian Fleming references . Likable Pierce Brosnan in an amazing adventure set on wonderful outdoors located mostly on Vietnam , being actually shot in Thailand . The original title of the film was "Tomorrow Never Lies", which makes sense when you consider media mogul Elliot Carver was creating the next day's headlines in advance, then causing those events to happen , but a typo on an early script draft was adopted by the producers, and &uml;Tomorrow never dies&uml; was used instead . This is a Bond's good outing in which faces dangerous adventures around the globe . Brosnan's outing with overwhelming action and spectacular scenarios , the film teams Bond with Michelle Yeoh as endearing ally in an effort to stop a technological communication mogul . After his first introduction in &uml;Golden eye&uml; as tough and attractive James Bond of the Ian Fleming's famous creation , Pierce Brosnan went on playing various 007 , as &uml;Die Another Day &uml; and this &uml;Tomorrow never dies&uml; . The picture starts with an overblown opening and following other impressive action set pieces . This solid , slick thriller with magic mix of action-packed , dazzling stunts, gadgetry, and romance provided by sexy company as Teri Hatcher and Michelle Yeoh . Pierce Brosnan as James Bond is fine , he does remarkably well , he earns in irony, humor ,suavity and sympathy, however also has coldness ,cunning , intelligence and toughness . Here Bond is an efficient , relentless agent trying to chase obstinately the criminals , traveling around the world as always , as this globe-trotting story is set in Pucket, Bangkok, Thailand (Saigon, Vietnam) , Hamburg , London and many other places . Because the second half of the film is set in Vietnam, the production negotiated for some time for permission to film there ; although it appeared close, the Vietnamese Ministry of Culture and Information eventually refused to allow it , the production decided to use Thailand as Vietnam, with Bangkok substituting for Saigon . Bond to achieve his aims , along the way uses violent means even pulling off brutal killings against enemies who wreak all sorts of havoc . As always Bond will use fantastic gadgets and spectacular cars (here 15 BMW 750's were destroyed in the making of the film) provided by &uml;Q&uml; (Desmond Llewelyn) . The stealth ship is not a fictional invention , Lockheed secretly constructed and demonstrated one in the early 1980s, but the US Navy finally decided they didn't want any ; the prototype, called the Sea Shadow, was 160 feet long . The picture contains comic-strip adventure , sensational pursuits , silly set pieces , great stunts , tongue-in check humor, automovile chase, frantic unstopped action , a breathtaking tour around the world , amazing gimmicks and stimulating images like are the happenings on the spectacular pursuits on the motorcycle and helicopter . As is like a roller-coaster , as is fast-paced , light , excitement, funny and entertaining ; it's a winner for oo7 fans and non-fans alike . The chase and suspense formula wears strong in this entry . The film made particularly heavy use of gadgetry because some fans thought there was too little of it in GoldenEye . Enjoyable title song by Sheryl Crow and stirring musical score fitting to action by David Arnold , following the John Barry's classic style . Riveting and fancy main titles , furthermore eye-popping production design by Allan Cameron . It's brimming with colorful and fascinating cinematography by cameraman Robert Elswit . The motion picture produced by habitual producers, Barbara Broccoli and Michael G. Wilson and dedicated to the memory of long-time Bond-film producer Albert R. Broccoli ; being professionally made by Robert Spottiswoode who filmed other successes such as &uml;the 6th day&uml;, &uml;Turner and Hooch&uml;, &uml;Air America&uml; , Shoot to kill&uml;and Under fire&uml; . Robert keeps this moving at an incredibly fast pace and this story about every's favorite super-spy facing off dangerous mogul . The film will appeal to James Bond series's buffs but good for fans only ; because this one goes on far too long and has provoked so much debate among 007 followers . Rating : 6'5 , well worth watching .
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Decent Bond flick.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Blueghost
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There's a couple of things I liked about classic Sean Connery Bond. A) he was smart. B) he let you know it. The other thing I liked about the classic Bond films was that there was a kind of credibility to them. You knew it was all comic book fun, but they were grounded. Pierce Brosnan could have been one of the great Bonds, but he's given precious little dialogue. We're essentially seeing a well crafted action flick from frame one. Bond films always had action, but this film seemed heavy on action, and little of what Bond knew, what he was all about, and how we knew he was capable of doing the things he did. That's pretty much my critique. A lot of money went into making this film a big blockbuster smash, and it delivers for what it is, but I didn't get a sense of Bondness, so much as I got a sense of a film wanting to be a James Bond film. Still, it's decent enough for what it is, an action film, but isn't Bond more than just an action hero? I think the technical stuff has gotten a lot better over the years of the Bond franchise's existence. But when you went to see a Bond film in the 60s and 70s, you didn't just go to see bullets flying, nor the Bond hotties adorning the screen, you went for the story and character. There's a fine plot driven film in here, but little else. And, true to big budget blockbusters needing bad-guys, we have a hint of Nazis in working for the evil boss that Bond must confront (although he himself may be one). I don't have much else to say about it other than I think that there's a better film in here. Yes, you heard me right. With all of the money dumped into this thing I'm still not satisfied that I saw a James Bond film. But, that's neither here nor there, I suppose. If I had shot it I would have cut back on some of the pyrotechnics, asked the Royal Navy to spare a frigate and a destroyer or two to fire real rounds instead of relying on my SFX team to drag a model through the water tank on the back lot while shooting it in slow mo. There's a lot of superficial adornments in this film to make it a Bond flick, but there isn't much Bond in it. I would have directed a different film. But again, that's all Monday morning quarterbacking. Still, it's a film, and a kind of popcorn fun film with some cross international romance involved, and maybe a bit of social engineering going on, but otherwise a decent watch. Give it a shot.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    007 Classy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    willrasmussen-617-992319
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is what I call a fun Bond movie to watch over again. I really like Pierce Brosnan as him playing Bond. The movie is enjoyable to watch and the action sequences are fun also. What seems to make this as a unique Bond film is the different types of weapons and gadgets that are shown in the movie. The story line is also makes the movie fun. I think this Bond movie is probably one the best Pierce Brosnan 007 movies. The movie is not so long and the scenes move at a fair pace. Prior to Goldeneye, this sets off a new type of Bond formula. I think this 007 movie is probably better than the Bond movies with Daniel Craig. I wish Pierce Brosnan was still playing James Bond.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Action packed but nothing extraordinary
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    varghesejunior
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If it's action you want then this Bond film will suit you. But it has nothing different to offer apart from conventional Bond stuff. In TND,Bond goes on a mission to expose a psychic media tycoon who wants to incite fire between UK and China and start World war 3 for his own selfish ends, and whose wife also happens to be Bond's ex girlfriend. The film is made well  Good story, direction, fast paced action with plenty of stunts, cool gadgets, dialogue delivery. It sure is enjoyable. There are a few unwanted scenes which is what I did not like. But there is nothing different in the film, unlike Daniel Craig's Bond films.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Silly but rather enjoyable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AllTomorrowsParties
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tomorrow Never Dies gets a bad rap. Not sure why. Really, there are only two things amiss. Firstly the villain is a bit 'soft' if you consider a news mogul a bit soft. Secondly the last act is really not as good as the rest of the film. Bits of it - Bond's fake death (or is that two fake deaths?) and Wei Lin getting access to the bridge stretch credulity a bit and the fist fight is rubbish - but that's about it for criticism - otherwise this is a really good Bond film and probably Brosnan's best. The action sequences are great - especially the helicopter / motorbike sequence - this is shot rather brilliantly. Then again, the driverless BMW is rather good as well. Its occasionally funny. Yeoh is masterful. Brosnan is on form and the inclusion of a British Navy is a bonus. Oh, and the funny CIA. You see, the list is quite long. Its not a 6.4 by any stretch of the imagination. Its not perfect, I grant you but it has a lot going for it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's kind of like a Fast Food Burger. You consume it, enjoy it, but forget all about it as soon you are finished
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    callanvass
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A far cry from Goldeneye, but It doesn't necessarily deserve all the hate it receives either. Tomorrow Never Dies is a fast paced affair, and an easily agreeable time-waster, but it's not the follow-up Goldeneye deserved, either. It's much too daft for the heavy plot that it has. The main reason this movie is entertaining is the spectacular stunts. It has some great action set pieces, which managed to make the time pass nicely. Michelle Yeoh makes for a refreshingly unique Bond Girl, due to her actual Martial Arts background. I dug the chemistry with her & Brosnan. Speaking of Brosnan He is very good as Bond. He has charisma and wit to spare. He's not quite as good as Timothy Dalton, but he is excellent nonetheless. Johnathan Pryce is decent as the villain. He is fitfully menacing and did the job overall. Teri Hatcher's character is a bit disposable, but she was good in her role. Desmond Llewelyn & Judi Dench are as classy as ever Final Thoughts: Instantly forgettable stuff, but it manages to be an effective time-waster. It's not a great Bond film, but it is an OK action film. I didn't mind it at all. 5.6/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Where Tomorrow Never Dies Stands
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    davorinlonac
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is Pierce Brosnans second performance as agent 007 and could have been better. It is a very big decline since his first film being Goldenye, one of my favorites. This Bond film is good but doesn't feel like a Bond film somehow. Bond pretty much murders Elliot Carver, the villain, like a serial killer would! But again Pierce Brosnan makes the Bond character feel cooler and smoother. This is a good Bond movie but if I compare it to my favorites, it isn't very good. After watching it once and then watching it again there are some scenes you can look forward to. Elliot Carver by far is the strangest, but OK Bond villain of all time. Tomorrow Never Dies stands 19th on a list of mine where the 007 Movies have been ranked from worst to greatest. The film itself is good but The Bond Girl lets it down, as well as some of the fake action.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the most exciting Bond films ever made
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rodrigo Amaro (rodrigo882008@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    By far, my favorite of Brosnan along with "Goldeneye". Might not be one of the best Bond movies but it's certainly one of the most memorable. But truth be told: its effectiveness now is a little ruined to the massive appeal of the award winning "Skyfall", which at the same time reinvented Bond yet brought back some of its most appreciable qualities - this merge was inexistent in "Casino Royale" and "Quantum of Solace", both are just new reboots with a theme song to show that it's faithful to its roots. Mr. Brosnan at the top of his game, so smooth, active and funny, returns as Bond with plenty of style in one of Bond's most down to earth missions: to stop a possible conflict between England and China about to emerge from the dephts of a creative and destructive mind, the egocentric Elliot Carver (the priceless Jonathan Pryce), a media mogul &agrave; la Citizen Kane/Rupert Murdoch with his own declaration of principals which is to provide the news before they happen. The big scoop is to broadcast (and cause!) the WWIII. 007 is helped by a Chinese agent, the handy Colonel Wai-Lin (Michelle Yeoh) who is more advanced in her spy/fight techniques; and the other Bond girl is a former affair of his, now married with Elliot, a femme fatale played by Teri Hatcher. And this wouldn't be a complete Bond movie without the gadgets carefully supplied by Q (Desmond Llewelyn); here, a fully equipped BMW car that can be guided with the cellphone which also has its deadly functions. It's quite obvious the merchant made by the already mention company - they also brought a fancy motorcycle used in one of the most thrilling sequences when James and Wai-Lin escape from Carver's henchmen and that includes the couple's fly over a helicopter. "Tomorrow Never Dies" is great because it doesn't commit any kind of excesses, the plot is very simple to follow (this can be viewed as a problem to some, specially those who are more accustomed with complex plots, Bourne style) and never absurd; all the action and adventure are not overplayed, prolonged or tiring, it's all in a good measure and it's very exciting. I dare say those sequences were quite inspired. High point: the building escape using Carver's poster as a way out; the incredible car chase; Wai-Lin effortless escape tactics against the dangerous ones faced by 007, who feel a little annoyed with her. Their pairing is one of the best in the series, but the great and fun spectacle is the buffoon Carver and his memorable lines and actions (his mimics of Wai-Lin fighting style kills me every time). Obviously, he cannot put up a fight against the secret agent, but he has the loyal and muscular Stamper (G&ouml;tz Otto), a frightening guy who likes to torture his victims, and that's his only form of pleasure. For me, the only downer of this movie was the theme song, that hurts the ears, completely oversung. Anyway, it's a fun entertainment, filled with adrenaline and we can't forget the marvelous cast (one of the finest in the series) with Judi Dench (M), Samantha Bond (Moneypenny), Geoffrey Palmer, Vincent Schiavelli, Ricky Jay, Joe Don Baker and Gerard Butler (but you get an award if you find him in the middle of all the action). 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Film without Bond feeling
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Simon Fredriksson
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Pierce Brosnan is tough, sexy and has a twinkle in his eye, the third-best 007 after Sean Connery and Daniel Craig. But this movie is much worse than "Goldeneye", his first Bond movie. Thin screenplay about a media moguls (Jonathan Pryce) attempts to control the world by creating a war between Britain and China so that his new TV channel have something spectacular to report. Michelle Yeoh is a colorful and cool Bond girl, but Teri Hatcher, from the TV series "Desperate Housewives", does not add much in the role as the media moguls wife. Most boring of all, James Bond is so little James Bond, he is like any action hero out there. But at the phone manufacturer Ericsson they will party hard. The film's best scene is a car chase where 007 steers his BMW with the help of a remote control built in... well, you can guess what kind of phone.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    So far... so good!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    orourkec-292-269155
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm still satisfied on Tomorrow Never Dies after the first successful Goldeneye movie. I loved the actions and stunts! Original scenes and good characters. It is an impressive piece of work. The gadgets are always so good and make you more entertained than ever. Pierce Brosnan for me makes part of the group of the three best bonds ever! There are smart fights included and women still beautiful! "James Bond doesn't stop to make love and love with women". The movie could have added more special effects and something more to entertain the audience. It still captured me into the story though. Good job! For those who like james bond and haven't seen this one, I hope it will make you happy. Out of 100%, I RECOMMEND IT at 70%! I rate it: 7.2/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Overwhelming and thrilling entry in which Bond/Brosnan goes after a powerful media mogul
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ma-cortes
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Elloit Carver (Jonathan Pryce) is a megalomaniac and selfish media baron. Carver has the power to reach every person on the planet through his Carver Media Group Network- except for the People's Republic of Chinese who refuse his presence in their nation . The mogul is tied to the disappearance of a British battleship in the South China Sea . James Bond (Pierce Brosnan) heads to stop the media mogul's plan to induce war between China and the UK in order to obtain exclusive global media coverage and whose tentacles reach around the world . Carver, whose spouse (Teri Hatcher) was a former flame of 007 , is supported by a computer genius (Ricky Jay) and a nasty hunk man (Gotz Otto) . Along the way Bond join forces with a Chinese secret agent (Michelle Yeoh) , expert on martial arts . In addition , there appears the usuals , such as M (Judi Dench), Q (Desmond Llewelin) , Lois Maxwell, &uml;MoneyPenny&uml; (Samantha Bond) , Minister of Defense (Julian Fellowes) and Jake Wade (Joe Don Baker) . But not counting the regular characters of Bond, Q, M and Moneypenny, this is the first Bond movie to contain absolutely no Ian Fleming references . Likable Pierce Brosnan in an amazing adventure set on wonderful outdoors located mostly on Vietnam , being actually shot in Thailand . The original title of the film was "Tomorrow Never Lies", which makes sense when you consider media mogul Elliot Carver was creating the next day's headlines in advance, then causing those events to happen , but a typo on an early script draft was adopted by the producers, and &uml;Tomorrow never dies&uml; was used instead . This is a Bond's good outing in which faces dangerous adventures around the globe . Brosnan's outing with overwhelming action and spectacular scenarios , the film teams Bond with Michelle Yeoh as endearing ally in an effort to stop a technological communication mogul . After his first introduction in &uml;Golden eye&uml; as tough and attractive James Bond of the Ian Fleming's famous creation , Pierce Brosnan went on playing various 007 , as &uml;Die Another Day &uml; and this &uml;Tomorrow never dies&uml; . The picture starts with an overblown opening and following other impressive action set pieces . This solid , slick thriller with magic mix of action-packed , dazzling stunts, gadgetry, and romance provided by sexy company as Teri Hatcher and Michelle Yeoh . Pierce Brosnan as James Bond is fine , he does remarkably well , he earns in irony, humor ,suavity and sympathy, however also has coldness ,cunning , intelligence and toughness . Here Bond is an efficient , relentless agent trying to chase obstinately the criminals , traveling around the world as always , as this globe-trotting story is set in Pucket, Bangkok, Thailand (Saigon, Vietnam) , Hamburg , London and many other places . Because the second half of the film is set in Vietnam, the production negotiated for some time for permission to film there ; although it appeared close, the Vietnamese Ministry of Culture and Information eventually refused to allow it , the production decided to use Thailand as Vietnam, with Bangkok substituting for Saigon . Bond to achieve his aims , along the way uses violent means even pulling off brutal killings against enemies who wreak all sorts of havoc . As always Bond will use fantastic gadgets and spectacular cars (here 15 BMW 750's were destroyed in the making of the film) provided by &uml;Q&uml; (Desmond Llewelyn) . The stealth ship is not a fictional invention , Lockheed secretly constructed and demonstrated one in the early 1980s, but the US Navy finally decided they didn't want any ; the prototype, called the Sea Shadow, was 160 feet long . The picture contains comic-strip adventure , sensational pursuits , silly set pieces , great stunts , tongue-in check humor, automovile chase, frantic unstopped action , a breathtaking tour around the world , amazing gimmicks and stimulating images like are the happenings on the spectacular pursuits on the motorcycle and helicopter . As is like a roller-coaster , as is fast-paced , light , excitement, funny and entertaining ; it's a winner for oo7 fans and non-fans alike . The chase and suspense formula wears strong in this entry . The film made particularly heavy use of gadgetry because some fans thought there was too little of it in GoldenEye . Enjoyable title song by Sheryl Crow and stirring musical score fitting to action by David Arnold , following the John Barry's classic style . Riveting and fancy main titles , furthermore eye-popping production design by Allan Cameron . It's brimming with colorful and fascinating cinematography by cameraman Robert Elswit . The motion picture produced by habitual producers, Barbara Broccoli and Michael G. Wilson and dedicated to the memory of long-time Bond-film producer Albert R. Broccoli ; being professionally made by Robert Spottiswoode who filmed other successes such as &uml;the 6th day&uml;, &uml;Turner and Hooch&uml;, &uml;Air America&uml; , Shoot to kill&uml;and Under fire&uml; . Robert keeps this moving at an incredibly fast pace and this story about every's favorite super-spy facing off dangerous mogul . The film will appeal to James Bond series's buffs but good for fans only ; because this one goes on far too long and has provoked so much debate among 007 followers . Rating : 6'5 , well worth watching .
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Decent Bond flick.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Blueghost
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There's a couple of things I liked about classic Sean Connery Bond. A) he was smart. B) he let you know it. The other thing I liked about the classic Bond films was that there was a kind of credibility to them. You knew it was all comic book fun, but they were grounded. Pierce Brosnan could have been one of the great Bonds, but he's given precious little dialogue. We're essentially seeing a well crafted action flick from frame one. Bond films always had action, but this film seemed heavy on action, and little of what Bond knew, what he was all about, and how we knew he was capable of doing the things he did. That's pretty much my critique. A lot of money went into making this film a big blockbuster smash, and it delivers for what it is, but I didn't get a sense of Bondness, so much as I got a sense of a film wanting to be a James Bond film. Still, it's decent enough for what it is, an action film, but isn't Bond more than just an action hero? I think the technical stuff has gotten a lot better over the years of the Bond franchise's existence. But when you went to see a Bond film in the 60s and 70s, you didn't just go to see bullets flying, nor the Bond hotties adorning the screen, you went for the story and character. There's a fine plot driven film in here, but little else. And, true to big budget blockbusters needing bad-guys, we have a hint of Nazis in working for the evil boss that Bond must confront (although he himself may be one). I don't have much else to say about it other than I think that there's a better film in here. Yes, you heard me right. With all of the money dumped into this thing I'm still not satisfied that I saw a James Bond film. But, that's neither here nor there, I suppose. If I had shot it I would have cut back on some of the pyrotechnics, asked the Royal Navy to spare a frigate and a destroyer or two to fire real rounds instead of relying on my SFX team to drag a model through the water tank on the back lot while shooting it in slow mo. There's a lot of superficial adornments in this film to make it a Bond flick, but there isn't much Bond in it. I would have directed a different film. But again, that's all Monday morning quarterbacking. Still, it's a film, and a kind of popcorn fun film with some cross international romance involved, and maybe a bit of social engineering going on, but otherwise a decent watch. Give it a shot.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    007 Classy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    willrasmussen-617-992319
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is what I call a fun Bond movie to watch over again. I really like Pierce Brosnan as him playing Bond. The movie is enjoyable to watch and the action sequences are fun also. What seems to make this as a unique Bond film is the different types of weapons and gadgets that are shown in the movie. The story line is also makes the movie fun. I think this Bond movie is probably one the best Pierce Brosnan 007 movies. The movie is not so long and the scenes move at a fair pace. Prior to Goldeneye, this sets off a new type of Bond formula. I think this 007 movie is probably better than the Bond movies with Daniel Craig. I wish Pierce Brosnan was still playing James Bond.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Action packed but nothing extraordinary
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    varghesejunior
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If it's action you want then this Bond film will suit you. But it has nothing different to offer apart from conventional Bond stuff. In TND,Bond goes on a mission to expose a psychic media tycoon who wants to incite fire between UK and China and start World war 3 for his own selfish ends, and whose wife also happens to be Bond's ex girlfriend. The film is made well  Good story, direction, fast paced action with plenty of stunts, cool gadgets, dialogue delivery. It sure is enjoyable. There are a few unwanted scenes which is what I did not like. But there is nothing different in the film, unlike Daniel Craig's Bond films.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Silly but rather enjoyable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AllTomorrowsParties
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tomorrow Never Dies gets a bad rap. Not sure why. Really, there are only two things amiss. Firstly the villain is a bit 'soft' if you consider a news mogul a bit soft. Secondly the last act is really not as good as the rest of the film. Bits of it - Bond's fake death (or is that two fake deaths?) and Wei Lin getting access to the bridge stretch credulity a bit and the fist fight is rubbish - but that's about it for criticism - otherwise this is a really good Bond film and probably Brosnan's best. The action sequences are great - especially the helicopter / motorbike sequence - this is shot rather brilliantly. Then again, the driverless BMW is rather good as well. Its occasionally funny. Yeoh is masterful. Brosnan is on form and the inclusion of a British Navy is a bonus. Oh, and the funny CIA. You see, the list is quite long. Its not a 6.4 by any stretch of the imagination. Its not perfect, I grant you but it has a lot going for it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's kind of like a Fast Food Burger. You consume it, enjoy it, but forget all about it as soon you are finished
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    callanvass
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A far cry from Goldeneye, but It doesn't necessarily deserve all the hate it receives either. Tomorrow Never Dies is a fast paced affair, and an easily agreeable time-waster, but it's not the follow-up Goldeneye deserved, either. It's much too daft for the heavy plot that it has. The main reason this movie is entertaining is the spectacular stunts. It has some great action set pieces, which managed to make the time pass nicely. Michelle Yeoh makes for a refreshingly unique Bond Girl, due to her actual Martial Arts background. I dug the chemistry with her & Brosnan. Speaking of Brosnan He is very good as Bond. He has charisma and wit to spare. He's not quite as good as Timothy Dalton, but he is excellent nonetheless. Johnathan Pryce is decent as the villain. He is fitfully menacing and did the job overall. Teri Hatcher's character is a bit disposable, but she was good in her role. Desmond Llewelyn & Judi Dench are as classy as ever Final Thoughts: Instantly forgettable stuff, but it manages to be an effective time-waster. It's not a great Bond film, but it is an OK action film. I didn't mind it at all. 5.6/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Where Tomorrow Never Dies Stands
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    davorinlonac
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is Pierce Brosnans second performance as agent 007 and could have been better. It is a very big decline since his first film being Goldenye, one of my favorites. This Bond film is good but doesn't feel like a Bond film somehow. Bond pretty much murders Elliot Carver, the villain, like a serial killer would! But again Pierce Brosnan makes the Bond character feel cooler and smoother. This is a good Bond movie but if I compare it to my favorites, it isn't very good. After watching it once and then watching it again there are some scenes you can look forward to. Elliot Carver by far is the strangest, but OK Bond villain of all time. Tomorrow Never Dies stands 19th on a list of mine where the 007 Movies have been ranked from worst to greatest. The film itself is good but The Bond Girl lets it down, as well as some of the fake action.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the most exciting Bond films ever made
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rodrigo Amaro (rodrigo882008@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    By far, my favorite of Brosnan along with "Goldeneye". Might not be one of the best Bond movies but it's certainly one of the most memorable. But truth be told: its effectiveness now is a little ruined to the massive appeal of the award winning "Skyfall", which at the same time reinvented Bond yet brought back some of its most appreciable qualities - this merge was inexistent in "Casino Royale" and "Quantum of Solace", both are just new reboots with a theme song to show that it's faithful to its roots. Mr. Brosnan at the top of his game, so smooth, active and funny, returns as Bond with plenty of style in one of Bond's most down to earth missions: to stop a possible conflict between England and China about to emerge from the dephts of a creative and destructive mind, the egocentric Elliot Carver (the priceless Jonathan Pryce), a media mogul &agrave; la Citizen Kane/Rupert Murdoch with his own declaration of principals which is to provide the news before they happen. The big scoop is to broadcast (and cause!) the WWIII. 007 is helped by a Chinese agent, the handy Colonel Wai-Lin (Michelle Yeoh) who is more advanced in her spy/fight techniques; and the other Bond girl is a former affair of his, now married with Elliot, a femme fatale played by Teri Hatcher. And this wouldn't be a complete Bond movie without the gadgets carefully supplied by Q (Desmond Llewelyn); here, a fully equipped BMW car that can be guided with the cellphone which also has its deadly functions. It's quite obvious the merchant made by the already mention company - they also brought a fancy motorcycle used in one of the most thrilling sequences when James and Wai-Lin escape from Carver's henchmen and that includes the couple's fly over a helicopter. "Tomorrow Never Dies" is great because it doesn't commit any kind of excesses, the plot is very simple to follow (this can be viewed as a problem to some, specially those who are more accustomed with complex plots, Bourne style) and never absurd; all the action and adventure are not overplayed, prolonged or tiring, it's all in a good measure and it's very exciting. I dare say those sequences were quite inspired. High point: the building escape using Carver's poster as a way out; the incredible car chase; Wai-Lin effortless escape tactics against the dangerous ones faced by 007, who feel a little annoyed with her. Their pairing is one of the best in the series, but the great and fun spectacle is the buffoon Carver and his memorable lines and actions (his mimics of Wai-Lin fighting style kills me every time). Obviously, he cannot put up a fight against the secret agent, but he has the loyal and muscular Stamper (G&ouml;tz Otto), a frightening guy who likes to torture his victims, and that's his only form of pleasure. For me, the only downer of this movie was the theme song, that hurts the ears, completely oversung. Anyway, it's a fun entertainment, filled with adrenaline and we can't forget the marvelous cast (one of the finest in the series) with Judi Dench (M), Samantha Bond (Moneypenny), Geoffrey Palmer, Vincent Schiavelli, Ricky Jay, Joe Don Baker and Gerard Butler (but you get an award if you find him in the middle of all the action). 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Film without Bond feeling
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Simon Fredriksson
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Pierce Brosnan is tough, sexy and has a twinkle in his eye, the third-best 007 after Sean Connery and Daniel Craig. But this movie is much worse than "Goldeneye", his first Bond movie. Thin screenplay about a media moguls (Jonathan Pryce) attempts to control the world by creating a war between Britain and China so that his new TV channel have something spectacular to report. Michelle Yeoh is a colorful and cool Bond girl, but Teri Hatcher, from the TV series "Desperate Housewives", does not add much in the role as the media moguls wife. Most boring of all, James Bond is so little James Bond, he is like any action hero out there. But at the phone manufacturer Ericsson they will party hard. The film's best scene is a car chase where 007 steers his BMW with the help of a remote control built in... well, you can guess what kind of phone.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    So far... so good!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    orourkec-292-269155
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm still satisfied on Tomorrow Never Dies after the first successful Goldeneye movie. I loved the actions and stunts! Original scenes and good characters. It is an impressive piece of work. The gadgets are always so good and make you more entertained than ever. Pierce Brosnan for me makes part of the group of the three best bonds ever! There are smart fights included and women still beautiful! "James Bond doesn't stop to make love and love with women". The movie could have added more special effects and something more to entertain the audience. It still captured me into the story though. Good job! For those who like james bond and haven't seen this one, I hope it will make you happy. Out of 100%, I RECOMMEND IT at 70%! I rate it: 7.2/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Overwhelming and thrilling entry in which Bond/Brosnan goes after a powerful media mogul
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ma-cortes
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Elloit Carver (Jonathan Pryce) is a megalomaniac and selfish media baron. Carver has the power to reach every person on the planet through his Carver Media Group Network- except for the People's Republic of Chinese who refuse his presence in their nation . The mogul is tied to the disappearance of a British battleship in the South China Sea . James Bond (Pierce Brosnan) heads to stop the media mogul's plan to induce war between China and the UK in order to obtain exclusive global media coverage and whose tentacles reach around the world . Carver, whose spouse (Teri Hatcher) was a former flame of 007 , is supported by a computer genius (Ricky Jay) and a nasty hunk man (Gotz Otto) . Along the way Bond join forces with a Chinese secret agent (Michelle Yeoh) , expert on martial arts . In addition , there appears the usuals , such as M (Judi Dench), Q (Desmond Llewelin) , Lois Maxwell, &uml;MoneyPenny&uml; (Samantha Bond) , Minister of Defense (Julian Fellowes) and Jake Wade (Joe Don Baker) . But not counting the regular characters of Bond, Q, M and Moneypenny, this is the first Bond movie to contain absolutely no Ian Fleming references . Likable Pierce Brosnan in an amazing adventure set on wonderful outdoors located mostly on Vietnam , being actually shot in Thailand . The original title of the film was "Tomorrow Never Lies", which makes sense when you consider media mogul Elliot Carver was creating the next day's headlines in advance, then causing those events to happen , but a typo on an early script draft was adopted by the producers, and &uml;Tomorrow never dies&uml; was used instead . This is a Bond's good outing in which faces dangerous adventures around the globe . Brosnan's outing with overwhelming action and spectacular scenarios , the film teams Bond with Michelle Yeoh as endearing ally in an effort to stop a technological communication mogul . After his first introduction in &uml;Golden eye&uml; as tough and attractive James Bond of the Ian Fleming's famous creation , Pierce Brosnan went on playing various 007 , as &uml;Die Another Day &uml; and this &uml;Tomorrow never dies&uml; . The picture starts with an overblown opening and following other impressive action set pieces . This solid , slick thriller with magic mix of action-packed , dazzling stunts, gadgetry, and romance provided by sexy company as Teri Hatcher and Michelle Yeoh . Pierce Brosnan as James Bond is fine , he does remarkably well , he earns in irony, humor ,suavity and sympathy, however also has coldness ,cunning , intelligence and toughness . Here Bond is an efficient , relentless agent trying to chase obstinately the criminals , traveling around the world as always , as this globe-trotting story is set in Pucket, Bangkok, Thailand (Saigon, Vietnam) , Hamburg , London and many other places . Because the second half of the film is set in Vietnam, the production negotiated for some time for permission to film there ; although it appeared close, the Vietnamese Ministry of Culture and Information eventually refused to allow it , the production decided to use Thailand as Vietnam, with Bangkok substituting for Saigon . Bond to achieve his aims , along the way uses violent means even pulling off brutal killings against enemies who wreak all sorts of havoc . As always Bond will use fantastic gadgets and spectacular cars (here 15 BMW 750's were destroyed in the making of the film) provided by &uml;Q&uml; (Desmond Llewelyn) . The stealth ship is not a fictional invention , Lockheed secretly constructed and demonstrated one in the early 1980s, but the US Navy finally decided they didn't want any ; the prototype, called the Sea Shadow, was 160 feet long . The picture contains comic-strip adventure , sensational pursuits , silly set pieces , great stunts , tongue-in check humor, automovile chase, frantic unstopped action , a breathtaking tour around the world , amazing gimmicks and stimulating images like are the happenings on the spectacular pursuits on the motorcycle and helicopter . As is like a roller-coaster , as is fast-paced , light , excitement, funny and entertaining ; it's a winner for oo7 fans and non-fans alike . The chase and suspense formula wears strong in this entry . The film made particularly heavy use of gadgetry because some fans thought there was too little of it in GoldenEye . Enjoyable title song by Sheryl Crow and stirring musical score fitting to action by David Arnold , following the John Barry's classic style . Riveting and fancy main titles , furthermore eye-popping production design by Allan Cameron . It's brimming with colorful and fascinating cinematography by cameraman Robert Elswit . The motion picture produced by habitual producers, Barbara Broccoli and Michael G. Wilson and dedicated to the memory of long-time Bond-film producer Albert R. Broccoli ; being professionally made by Robert Spottiswoode who filmed other successes such as &uml;the 6th day&uml;, &uml;Turner and Hooch&uml;, &uml;Air America&uml; , Shoot to kill&uml;and Under fire&uml; . Robert keeps this moving at an incredibly fast pace and this story about every's favorite super-spy facing off dangerous mogul . The film will appeal to James Bond series's buffs but good for fans only ; because this one goes on far too long and has provoked so much debate among 007 followers . Rating : 6'5 , well worth watching .
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Decent Bond flick.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Blueghost
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There's a couple of things I liked about classic Sean Connery Bond. A) he was smart. B) he let you know it. The other thing I liked about the classic Bond films was that there was a kind of credibility to them. You knew it was all comic book fun, but they were grounded. Pierce Brosnan could have been one of the great Bonds, but he's given precious little dialogue. We're essentially seeing a well crafted action flick from frame one. Bond films always had action, but this film seemed heavy on action, and little of what Bond knew, what he was all about, and how we knew he was capable of doing the things he did. That's pretty much my critique. A lot of money went into making this film a big blockbuster smash, and it delivers for what it is, but I didn't get a sense of Bondness, so much as I got a sense of a film wanting to be a James Bond film. Still, it's decent enough for what it is, an action film, but isn't Bond more than just an action hero? I think the technical stuff has gotten a lot better over the years of the Bond franchise's existence. But when you went to see a Bond film in the 60s and 70s, you didn't just go to see bullets flying, nor the Bond hotties adorning the screen, you went for the story and character. There's a fine plot driven film in here, but little else. And, true to big budget blockbusters needing bad-guys, we have a hint of Nazis in working for the evil boss that Bond must confront (although he himself may be one). I don't have much else to say about it other than I think that there's a better film in here. Yes, you heard me right. With all of the money dumped into this thing I'm still not satisfied that I saw a James Bond film. But, that's neither here nor there, I suppose. If I had shot it I would have cut back on some of the pyrotechnics, asked the Royal Navy to spare a frigate and a destroyer or two to fire real rounds instead of relying on my SFX team to drag a model through the water tank on the back lot while shooting it in slow mo. There's a lot of superficial adornments in this film to make it a Bond flick, but there isn't much Bond in it. I would have directed a different film. But again, that's all Monday morning quarterbacking. Still, it's a film, and a kind of popcorn fun film with some cross international romance involved, and maybe a bit of social engineering going on, but otherwise a decent watch. Give it a shot.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    007 Classy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    willrasmussen-617-992319
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is what I call a fun Bond movie to watch over again. I really like Pierce Brosnan as him playing Bond. The movie is enjoyable to watch and the action sequences are fun also. What seems to make this as a unique Bond film is the different types of weapons and gadgets that are shown in the movie. The story line is also makes the movie fun. I think this Bond movie is probably one the best Pierce Brosnan 007 movies. The movie is not so long and the scenes move at a fair pace. Prior to Goldeneye, this sets off a new type of Bond formula. I think this 007 movie is probably better than the Bond movies with Daniel Craig. I wish Pierce Brosnan was still playing James Bond.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Action packed but nothing extraordinary
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    varghesejunior
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If it's action you want then this Bond film will suit you. But it has nothing different to offer apart from conventional Bond stuff. In TND,Bond goes on a mission to expose a psychic media tycoon who wants to incite fire between UK and China and start World war 3 for his own selfish ends, and whose wife also happens to be Bond's ex girlfriend. The film is made well  Good story, direction, fast paced action with plenty of stunts, cool gadgets, dialogue delivery. It sure is enjoyable. There are a few unwanted scenes which is what I did not like. But there is nothing different in the film, unlike Daniel Craig's Bond films.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Silly but rather enjoyable
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    AllTomorrowsParties
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Tomorrow Never Dies gets a bad rap. Not sure why. Really, there are only two things amiss. Firstly the villain is a bit 'soft' if you consider a news mogul a bit soft. Secondly the last act is really not as good as the rest of the film. Bits of it - Bond's fake death (or is that two fake deaths?) and Wei Lin getting access to the bridge stretch credulity a bit and the fist fight is rubbish - but that's about it for criticism - otherwise this is a really good Bond film and probably Brosnan's best. The action sequences are great - especially the helicopter / motorbike sequence - this is shot rather brilliantly. Then again, the driverless BMW is rather good as well. Its occasionally funny. Yeoh is masterful. Brosnan is on form and the inclusion of a British Navy is a bonus. Oh, and the funny CIA. You see, the list is quite long. Its not a 6.4 by any stretch of the imagination. Its not perfect, I grant you but it has a lot going for it.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It's kind of like a Fast Food Burger. You consume it, enjoy it, but forget all about it as soon you are finished
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    callanvass
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    A far cry from Goldeneye, but It doesn't necessarily deserve all the hate it receives either. Tomorrow Never Dies is a fast paced affair, and an easily agreeable time-waster, but it's not the follow-up Goldeneye deserved, either. It's much too daft for the heavy plot that it has. The main reason this movie is entertaining is the spectacular stunts. It has some great action set pieces, which managed to make the time pass nicely. Michelle Yeoh makes for a refreshingly unique Bond Girl, due to her actual Martial Arts background. I dug the chemistry with her & Brosnan. Speaking of Brosnan He is very good as Bond. He has charisma and wit to spare. He's not quite as good as Timothy Dalton, but he is excellent nonetheless. Johnathan Pryce is decent as the villain. He is fitfully menacing and did the job overall. Teri Hatcher's character is a bit disposable, but she was good in her role. Desmond Llewelyn & Judi Dench are as classy as ever Final Thoughts: Instantly forgettable stuff, but it manages to be an effective time-waster. It's not a great Bond film, but it is an OK action film. I didn't mind it at all. 5.6/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Where Tomorrow Never Dies Stands
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    davorinlonac
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is Pierce Brosnans second performance as agent 007 and could have been better. It is a very big decline since his first film being Goldenye, one of my favorites. This Bond film is good but doesn't feel like a Bond film somehow. Bond pretty much murders Elliot Carver, the villain, like a serial killer would! But again Pierce Brosnan makes the Bond character feel cooler and smoother. This is a good Bond movie but if I compare it to my favorites, it isn't very good. After watching it once and then watching it again there are some scenes you can look forward to. Elliot Carver by far is the strangest, but OK Bond villain of all time. Tomorrow Never Dies stands 19th on a list of mine where the 007 Movies have been ranked from worst to greatest. The film itself is good but The Bond Girl lets it down, as well as some of the fake action.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of the most exciting Bond films ever made
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Rodrigo Amaro (rodrigo882008@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    By far, my favorite of Brosnan along with "Goldeneye". Might not be one of the best Bond movies but it's certainly one of the most memorable. But truth be told: its effectiveness now is a little ruined to the massive appeal of the award winning "Skyfall", which at the same time reinvented Bond yet brought back some of its most appreciable qualities - this merge was inexistent in "Casino Royale" and "Quantum of Solace", both are just new reboots with a theme song to show that it's faithful to its roots. Mr. Brosnan at the top of his game, so smooth, active and funny, returns as Bond with plenty of style in one of Bond's most down to earth missions: to stop a possible conflict between England and China about to emerge from the dephts of a creative and destructive mind, the egocentric Elliot Carver (the priceless Jonathan Pryce), a media mogul &agrave; la Citizen Kane/Rupert Murdoch with his own declaration of principals which is to provide the news before they happen. The big scoop is to broadcast (and cause!) the WWIII. 007 is helped by a Chinese agent, the handy Colonel Wai-Lin (Michelle Yeoh) who is more advanced in her spy/fight techniques; and the other Bond girl is a former affair of his, now married with Elliot, a femme fatale played by Teri Hatcher. And this wouldn't be a complete Bond movie without the gadgets carefully supplied by Q (Desmond Llewelyn); here, a fully equipped BMW car that can be guided with the cellphone which also has its deadly functions. It's quite obvious the merchant made by the already mention company - they also brought a fancy motorcycle used in one of the most thrilling sequences when James and Wai-Lin escape from Carver's henchmen and that includes the couple's fly over a helicopter. "Tomorrow Never Dies" is great because it doesn't commit any kind of excesses, the plot is very simple to follow (this can be viewed as a problem to some, specially those who are more accustomed with complex plots, Bourne style) and never absurd; all the action and adventure are not overplayed, prolonged or tiring, it's all in a good measure and it's very exciting. I dare say those sequences were quite inspired. High point: the building escape using Carver's poster as a way out; the incredible car chase; Wai-Lin effortless escape tactics against the dangerous ones faced by 007, who feel a little annoyed with her. Their pairing is one of the best in the series, but the great and fun spectacle is the buffoon Carver and his memorable lines and actions (his mimics of Wai-Lin fighting style kills me every time). Obviously, he cannot put up a fight against the secret agent, but he has the loyal and muscular Stamper (G&ouml;tz Otto), a frightening guy who likes to torture his victims, and that's his only form of pleasure. For me, the only downer of this movie was the theme song, that hurts the ears, completely oversung. Anyway, it's a fun entertainment, filled with adrenaline and we can't forget the marvelous cast (one of the finest in the series) with Judi Dench (M), Samantha Bond (Moneypenny), Geoffrey Palmer, Vincent Schiavelli, Ricky Jay, Joe Don Baker and Gerard Butler (but you get an award if you find him in the middle of all the action). 10/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Film without Bond feeling
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Simon Fredriksson
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Pierce Brosnan is tough, sexy and has a twinkle in his eye, the third-best 007 after Sean Connery and Daniel Craig. But this movie is much worse than "Goldeneye", his first Bond movie. Thin screenplay about a media moguls (Jonathan Pryce) attempts to control the world by creating a war between Britain and China so that his new TV channel have something spectacular to report. Michelle Yeoh is a colorful and cool Bond girl, but Teri Hatcher, from the TV series "Desperate Housewives", does not add much in the role as the media moguls wife. Most boring of all, James Bond is so little James Bond, he is like any action hero out there. But at the phone manufacturer Ericsson they will party hard. The film's best scene is a car chase where 007 steers his BMW with the help of a remote control built in... well, you can guess what kind of phone.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    So far... so good!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    orourkec-292-269155
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I'm still satisfied on Tomorrow Never Dies after the first successful Goldeneye movie. I loved the actions and stunts! Original scenes and good characters. It is an impressive piece of work. The gadgets are always so good and make you more entertained than ever. Pierce Brosnan for me makes part of the group of the three best bonds ever! There are smart fights included and women still beautiful! "James Bond doesn't stop to make love and love with women". The movie could have added more special effects and something more to entertain the audience. It still captured me into the story though. Good job! For those who like james bond and haven't seen this one, I hope it will make you happy. Out of 100%, I RECOMMEND IT at 70%! I rate it: 7.2/10.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Overwhelming and thrilling entry in which Bond/Brosnan goes after a powerful media mogul
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ma-cortes
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Elloit Carver (Jonathan Pryce) is a megalomaniac and selfish media baron. Carver has the power to reach every person on the planet through his Carver Media Group Network- except for the People's Republic of Chinese who refuse his presence in their nation . The mogul is tied to the disappearance of a British battleship in the South China Sea . James Bond (Pierce Brosnan) heads to stop the media mogul's plan to induce war between China and the UK in order to obtain exclusive global media coverage and whose tentacles reach around the world . Carver, whose spouse (Teri Hatcher) was a former flame of 007 , is supported by a computer genius (Ricky Jay) and a nasty hunk man (Gotz Otto) . Along the way Bond join forces with a Chinese secret agent (Michelle Yeoh) , expert on martial arts . In addition , there appears the usuals , such as M (Judi Dench), Q (Desmond Llewelin) , Lois Maxwell, &uml;MoneyPenny&uml; (Samantha Bond) , Minister of Defense (Julian Fellowes) and Jake Wade (Joe Don Baker) . But not counting the regular characters of Bond, Q, M and Moneypenny, this is the first Bond movie to contain absolutely no Ian Fleming references . Likable Pierce Brosnan in an amazing adventure set on wonderful outdoors located mostly on Vietnam , being actually shot in Thailand . The original title of the film was "Tomorrow Never Lies", which makes sense when you consider media mogul Elliot Carver was creating the next day's headlines in advance, then causing those events to happen , but a typo on an early script draft was adopted by the producers, and &uml;Tomorrow never dies&uml; was used instead . This is a Bond's good outing in which faces dangerous adventures around the globe . Brosnan's outing with overwhelming action and spectacular scenarios , the film teams Bond with Michelle Yeoh as endearing ally in an effort to stop a technological communication mogul . After his first introduction in &uml;Golden eye&uml; as tough and attractive James Bond of the Ian Fleming's famous creation , Pierce Brosnan went on playing various 007 , as &uml;Die Another Day &uml; and this &uml;Tomorrow never dies&uml; . The picture starts with an overblown opening and following other impressive action set pieces . This solid , slick thriller with magic mix of action-packed , dazzling stunts, gadgetry, and romance provided by sexy company as Teri Hatcher and Michelle Yeoh . Pierce Brosnan as James Bond is fine , he does remarkably well , he earns in irony, humor ,suavity and sympathy, however also has coldness ,cunning , intelligence and toughness . Here Bond is an efficient , relentless agent trying to chase obstinately the criminals , traveling around the world as always , as this globe-trotting story is set in Pucket, Bangkok, Thailand (Saigon, Vietnam) , Hamburg , London and many other places . Because the second half of the film is set in Vietnam, the production negotiated for some time for permission to film there ; although it appeared close, the Vietnamese Ministry of Culture and Information eventually refused to allow it , the production decided to use Thailand as Vietnam, with Bangkok substituting for Saigon . Bond to achieve his aims , along the way uses violent means even pulling off brutal killings against enemies who wreak all sorts of havoc . As always Bond will use fantastic gadgets and spectacular cars (here 15 BMW 750's were destroyed in the making of the film) provided by &uml;Q&uml; (Desmond Llewelyn) . The stealth ship is not a fictional invention , Lockheed secretly constructed and demonstrated one in the early 1980s, but the US Navy finally decided they didn't want any ; the prototype, called the Sea Shadow, was 160 feet long . The picture contains comic-strip adventure , sensational pursuits , silly set pieces , great stunts , tongue-in check humor, automovile chase, frantic unstopped action , a breathtaking tour around the world , amazing gimmicks and stimulating images like are the happenings on the spectacular pursuits on the motorcycle and helicopter . As is like a roller-coaster , as is fast-paced , light , excitement, funny and entertaining ; it's a winner for oo7 fans and non-fans alike . The chase and suspense formula wears strong in this entry . The film made particularly heavy use of gadgetry because some fans thought there was too little of it in GoldenEye . Enjoyable title song by Sheryl Crow and stirring musical score fitting to action by David Arnold , following the John Barry's classic style . Riveting and fancy main titles , furthermore eye-popping production design by Allan Cameron . It's brimming with colorful and fascinating cinematography by cameraman Robert Elswit . The motion picture produced by habitual producers, Barbara Broccoli and Michael G. Wilson and dedicated to the memory of long-time Bond-film producer Albert R. Broccoli ; being professionally made by Robert Spottiswoode who filmed other successes such as &uml;the 6th day&uml;, &uml;Turner and Hooch&uml;, &uml;Air America&uml; , Shoot to kill&uml;and Under fire&uml; . Robert keeps this moving at an incredibly fast pace and this story about every's favorite super-spy facing off dangerous mogul . The film will appeal to James Bond series's buffs but good for fans only ; because this one goes on far too long and has provoked so much debate among 007 followers . Rating : 6'5 , well worth watching .
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Decent Bond flick.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Blueghost
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There's a couple of things I liked about classic Sean Connery Bond. A) he was smart. B) he let you know it. The other thing I liked about the classic Bond films was that there was a kind of credibility to them. You knew it was all comic book fun, but they were grounded. Pierce Brosnan could have been one of the great Bonds, but he's given precious little dialogue. We're essentially seeing a well crafted action flick from frame one. Bond films always had action, but this film seemed heavy on action, and little of what Bond knew, what he was all about, and how we knew he was capable of doing the things he did. That's pretty much my critique. A lot of money went into making this film a big blockbuster smash, and it delivers for what it is, but I didn't get a sense of Bondness, so much as I got a sense of a film wanting to be a James Bond film. Still, it's decent enough for what it is, an action film, but isn't Bond more than just an action hero? I think the technical stuff has gotten a lot better over the years of the Bond franchise's existence. But when you went to see a Bond film in the 60s and 70s, you didn't just go to see bullets flying, nor the Bond hotties adorning the screen, you went for the story and character. There's a fine plot driven film in here, but little else. And, true to big budget blockbusters needing bad-guys, we have a hint of Nazis in working for the evil boss that Bond must confront (although he himself may be one). I don't have much else to say about it other than I think that there's a better film in here. Yes, you heard me right. With all of the money dumped into this thing I'm still not satisfied that I saw a James Bond film. But, that's neither here nor there, I suppose. If I had shot it I would have cut back on some of the pyrotechnics, asked the Royal Navy to spare a frigate and a destroyer or two to fire real rounds instead of relying on my SFX team to drag a model through the water tank on the back lot while shooting it in slow mo. There's a lot of superficial adornments in this film to make it a Bond flick, but there isn't much Bond in it. I would have directed a different film. But again, that's all Monday morning quarterbacking. Still, it's a film, and a kind of popcorn fun film with some cross international romance involved, and maybe a bit of social engineering going on, but otherwise a decent watch. Give it a shot.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    007 Classy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    willrasmussen-617-992319
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/4/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is what I call a fun Bond movie to watch over again. I really like Pierce Brosnan as him playing Bond. The movie is enjoyable to watch and the action sequences are fun also. What seems to make this as a unique Bond film is the different types of weapons and gadgets that are shown in the movie. The story line is also makes the movie fun. I think this Bond movie is probably one the best Pierce Brosnan 007 movies. The movie is not so long and the scenes move at a fair pace. Prior to Goldeneye, this sets off a new type of Bond formula. I think this 007 movie is probably better than the Bond movies with Daniel Craig. I wish Pierce Brosnan was still playing James Bond.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Action packed but nothing extraordinary
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    varghesejunior
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If it's action you want then this Bond film will suit you. But it has nothing different to offer apart from conventional Bond stuff. In TND,Bond goes on a mission to expose a psychic media tycoon who wants to incite fire between UK and China and start World war 3 for his own selfish ends, and whose wife also happens to be Bond's ex girlfriend. The film is made well  Good story, direction, fast paced action with plenty of stunts, cool gadgets, dialogue delivery. It sure is enjoyable. There are a few unwanted scenes which is what I did not like. But there is nothing different in the film, unlike Daniel Craig's Bond films.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
