<filme>
 <id>
  76
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0106519
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1993
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  O Pagamento Final
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  7.9
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  A Puerto-Rican ex-con, just released from prison, pledges to stay away from drugs and violence despite the pressure around him and lead on to a better life outside of NYC.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  A Puerto Rican ex-con pledges to stay away from his former drug dealing ways but finds himself being dragged back by his past connections and the naive machinations of his lawyer and best friend. Hoping to raise enough money to get away from New York, Carlito Brigante takes on the job of running a nightclub, renews an affair with a dancer but old associates and old instincts suck him back into a world of violence and mistrust.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Crime
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Thriller
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   prison
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   drugs
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   puerto rican
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   violence
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   dancer
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Brian De Palma
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Edwin Torres
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   David Koepp
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Al Pacino
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Sean Penn
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Penelope Ann Miller
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    10 years after Scarface
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Pusztai Norbi (noresz999)
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sorry for my bad English, I'm still learning the language. 10 years after Scarface, its director, and actor, made a gangster movie again, and its outcome isn't so far from the mentioned. They made it based on 2 books (by Edwin Torres), in 144 minutes, if we see on book adaptations, then it's a good time from 1 book, but not from 2. 2 books are compacted in 144 min. It's hard to do it well, but the creators made it very well. I could say without any overstatement, that it's in the top 10 all-time best gangster movies, I cannot see any problem with the movie. It has a lot of memorable scenes, it has some jokes, it's end very exciting, and heartbreaking, and it's not boring, for a minute, either. Furthermore, it's very strong in performances (Al Pacino, Sean Penn), directing (Brian De Palma), and screen writing (David Koepp), i think that it's the key of success. Who has seen this movie, that'll never forget it, simply brilliant. 9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Carlito the Pragmatic Gangster!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Stray Pez
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    DePalma's film is a masterpiece on many levels. For one, it is historically accurate to the letter. Carlito, a former smack peddler, is released from prison after a few years. When released, the drug business has changed. Cocaine, rather than heroine, is the drug of choice for most New Yorkers. It is more expensive and much more widely used than heroine. Before Cocaine, drug dealers were guys who operated on the fringes of society and catered to artists and musicians. In addition, Heroine was relatively cheap compared to Coke. This was the world Carlito was used to in the 50's and 60's. Yet he was somehow able to make a name for himself in this parched landscape through toughness, street smarts and pragmatism. Now released from prison, he finds out that the dope business changed while he was on the inside. Cocaine is easily available and in high demand. Drug users are now part of mainstream society. They include young professionals, politicians and athletes. As a result, drug dealers are not only able to make more money, they also become celebrities in their own right. This was so true about New York in the 1970's. Guys like Nikki Barnes made the cover of magazines because of Coke. It was ridiculous. Another important issue to point out is the escalating violence that results as well. Because Coke is more expensive, dealers are able to buy more guns from the windfall profits. DePalma does an excellent job incorporating this into a generation gap issue between Carlito and the newer criminals. Carlito is a killer and a thug. But he killed for survival. Perhaps his mothers death when he was young gave him more respect for human life or his generation as a whole valued life more than the new generation of gangsters. Carlito was born in a time when many people did not survive childhood. Some women still died during childbirth. World Wars also took the lives of many men. Since the new generation didn't experience death like he did, they value human life less. More guns in circulation feeds the beast of indifference. Pachanga said it best: "They shotgun you just to see you fly up in the air". Overall, a great movie with a tragic ending. The movie incorporates many themes about living a life of crime, changing social attitudes and capitalism. Highly recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    All About Carlito Brigante
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Carlito's Way is a crime drama based on the novels Carlito's Way and After Hours by Judge Edwin Torres. The film adaptation was written by David Koepp. It stars Al Pacino and Sean Penn,together with Penelope Ann Miller, Luis Guzm&aacute;n, John Leguizamo, and Viggo Mortensen in supporting roles. The story follows the life of Carlito Brigante after he is released from prison and vows to go straight and retire from criminal activities. However, unable to escape his past, he ends up being dragged into actions that got him imprisoned in the first place.The movie is narrated by Carlito himself, who explains his hopes, his strategies, and especially his mistakes. Brian De Palma directed the film. Carlito, a fabled heroin dealer, is released from prison after serving 5 years of a 30-year sentence. Tired and middle-aged, he wants out of the business as he has lost the juice for itfor the risks, the killing. It's the mid-'70s, the era of cocaine, fast sex, and disco glitz, and he takes a job running a dance club partially owned by his oldest and most trusted comrade, the coke-addled mob lawyer David Kleinfeld. Carlito's plan is to make some quick cash and move out of the country. But he is dragged down by his rootsby his hair-trigger survivor's instincts, honed while he was still a switchblade-wielding street kid, and by his loyalty to Kleinfeld, who tricks Carlito into helping him execute a mob hit. This film is one of the truly underrated films in the Brian De Palma and/or Al Pacino filmographies. It may have been unjustly derided and dismissed upon its theatrical debut during its year of release, but the it has received a cult following for many years now.The acting is great as the viewers are tickled by Sean Penn's weasely performance, Al Pacino's electric lead, or that crazy-cool chase through the NYC train station. Aside from its excellent performances,it has memorable moments, and some serious action and violent scenes. Overall,Carlito's Way is a smoother piece of filmmaking than Scarface, the only other picture De Palma has made with Pacino.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good classic Brian De Palma
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Panapaok
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Back to the gangster genre for Brian De Palma with Carlito's Way. After Scarface and The Untouchables he gives another pure example of his filmmaking and proves that he is a very strong and underrated master. Al Pacino gives another strong performance as Carlito Brigante and this is not unusual for him because he is in a well known field. But this time he is not another greedy and violent guy like Michael Corleone or Tony Montana but he is wise and clever and his goal is to retire from the business. Furthermore Sean Penn shows again his enormous talent by giving a strong performance as Carlto's rogue lawyer whose motives are not what they seem. He is rotten and cocaine addict and Penn pulls of this role brilliantly. This is a very good film both entertaining and touching and it is a must see for all De Palma's fans. Pacino's narration is an important key for the audience to realize who Carlito is. And, like a lot of gangster films, Carlito's Way proves that once a gangster means always a gangster no matter what.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A very good film... one of Pacinos best.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    richieandsam
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    CARLITO'S WAY I thought this was really good. The movie is about an ex con who gets released from prison and is determined to go straight. He is not interested in crime anymore. The problem is, he has got such a big reputation, that all the gangsters and criminals find him for advice, deals and help... some even want to kill him. The film stars Al Pacino, Sean Penn, Penelope Ann Miller, John Leguizamo, Ingrid Rogers & Luis Guzman. Everyone did a great job. Al is an amazing actor. He is over the top in some of his movies and there are scenes in this film where he is over the top too, but his performances always brings intensity. He is such an intense person and he can be a very scary person. But i think he is great! Sean Penn plays his lawyer... and at the beginning of the movie I felt he was a geek. Big curly hair, geeky glasses and he looks like he doesn't belong in the company of these gangsters... but as the film goes on he changes. The pressures of life gets to him and he can't handle it. His character has a hard time and i felt sorry for him towards the end of the film. I loved the action sequences. The gun fights and make-up were great. There was one scene where a guy gets shot in the face, it was so well shot. The way it was filmed made it look so real. It was a good crime drama/thriller... and I was pleasantly surprised at how good it is. I will give this film 7 out of 10. Al Pacino knows how to play a great gangster... and you can't help but feel sorry for him in this film because all he wants it to get out, but no matter what he does he just gets dragged back in. For more reviews, please like my Facebook page: https://www.facebook.com/pages/Ordinary-Person-Movie- Reviews/456572047728204?ref=hl
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pacino works his magic yet again!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pinturicchio_juve
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I just love Brian De Palma films. They're just so good to watch and have the right mix of good dialogues and an appealing storyline to get the viewer hooked. Scarface and The Untouchables would serve as worthy examples to this fact, and now that I've watched it, I guess Carlito's Way does too. The film is an adaptation of Edwin Torres' novel "After Hours" which follows the story of ex-con/gangster/drug peddler Carlito Brigante (played by Al Pacino), who tries to shun away from a life of crime after being released from prison. Brigante had in actuality been serving a thirty-to-life sentence, which had gotten reduced to five years, owing to the influence his lawyer, David Kleinfeld (Sean Penn) had with the jury. Once out on the streets, Carlito pledges to live life the right way and reluctantly agrees to co-own a nightclub so that he can save just enough money to leave New York and start a car rental business. But inevitably, he's lured into crime once again, and how he fights the odds forms the rest of the plot. One thing that struck me as I watched the film was that everything was very direct. There is not really much for the audience to interpret. Each character is sketched out quite well at the beginning itself, and one kind of knows what he/she would tend to do under the given circumstances. For example, Sean Penn's character, David Kleinfeld is exposed as a corrupt lawyer, and subsequent events throughout the film show him as one, with all his shady dealings and money laundering activities coming back to haunt him. I liked this about the movie, because one is not left wondering what a particular scene means, or what that character was trying to say. Its all said and done. There. Take it or leave it. Of course, this kind of storytelling will not work in all situations, but here, it feels just right. Then there's that aura of the gangster about Carlito. In the beginning, he accompanies his cousin to a drug dealer's hangout for a transaction. As the scene develops, one can feel Carlito sensing that there's something amiss about the place. The tension is brilliantly captured by De Palma here and you can just feel Pacino getting into the skin of the gangster he's portraying. He knows exactly what's going to happen, he's prepared for it, and when it does happen, he knows what to do. This gut instinct comes to the fore in the latter half of the film as well and is part of the reason why this films works for me. There are a lot of scenes and characters which contribute to making the film what it is, such as John Leguizamo as "Benny Blanco" the young upstart who tries to get chummy with Carlito but fails, Gail, Carlito's former lover, with whom he rekindles his relationship and Luiz Guzman as "Pachanga", Carlito's right hand man. But to me, this one is Pacino all the way. He carries the film on his shoulders and commands respect in almost every frame. You can see that he's always in control and this again points to the direct nature of the storyline. The De Palma-Pacino-gangster plot combine gives rise to obvious comparisons with Scarface. But the two are so different. While Tony Montana is just a drug dealer, Carlito Brigante is much more than that. He's a larger than life personality with a heart, remorse, and a conscience. He believes he has a shot at redemption. Montana has none of this. He's arrogant, ruthless and has absolutely no feelings of guilt or regret. The differing nature of their characters make the two films widely different, thus making a comparison would just be a wasteful exercise. The climax sequence, shot at a railway station does bring back scenes reminiscent of The Untouchables, though the events that unfold in the two films are entirely different. Carlito's Way might have its share of flaws which may not put it in the league of gangster flicks such as Goodfellas or The Godfather movies, but it is still a classic, and a highly underrated one at that. De Palma himself is a hugely underrated director (It is a surprise to me how he hasn't won an Oscar yet), and this film just underlines his capability. This one's a must watch for all fans of mob films, but I think that at its very basic level, it's just a story about a man with a heart.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a good movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Hooman Moeen (che-hooman)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    this film have a very good story.AL PACINO have a very good film i ever see.this film show the good guy why have a bad life this movie is a very good romance and crime\gangster i see.good drama i really like that.HAS A A LITTLE SCARFACE REUNION IN IT. SEAN PENN WUZ GREAT AS THE CORRUPT LAWYER. THE ENDING WUZ GREAT BUT TRAGIC BECAUSE YOU END UP PULLING FOR MR BRIGANTE (AL PACINO) DESPITE HIS CRIMINAL PAST.a lot of action is in this movie.Sean Penn plays a good part as a lawyer who got in too deep with the bad guys.he ends up getting shot in the hospital. i just wish there was a different end to this movie.....i wont give it away.if you like Al pacino and Sean Penn,then this movie is a must see.....
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A great story and film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    evas428
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of my favorite movies of all time! Amazing performance by Sean Penn, who really carries the film forward despite the powerhouse presence of the great Al Pacino. The characters were very well written and performed beautifully, especially from the less know (at the time) Vigo Mortensen and John Leguizamo. While this can be considered a "gangster movie", the love story of Carlito and Gale serve as the perfect motivation for the title character to escape the street life. This is much different than The Godfather. Overall, I highly recommend this film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Carlito Goes All The Way-Carlito's Way ****
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Simply put, an outrageously great gangster film with Al Pacino, as usual, turning in still another phenomenal performance as a Puerto Rican gangster who wants to grow straight, but is eventually pulled into a situation which causes tragedy for him. He is equally matched by Sean Penn as a cocaine addicted lawyer who draws him in and Penelope Ann Miller, the girl he loved but tragically could not have. It's basically a well-crafted story of environment having its hold on people and trapping them once they have committed crimes. The music at the club that Pacino owns is absolutely fabulous with an array of popular songs for the period.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The "so-called" sequel to Scarface
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    aaronalmarez
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just like "Casino" has been considered the "so-called" sequel to "Goodfellas", in my opinion, "Carlito's Way" is basically the "so-called" sequel to "Scarface." The reasons for that explanation is because of the stars and similar story lines of each movie. With "Goodfellas" and "Casino", both movies starred Robert De Niro and Joe Pesci and were directed by Martin Scorsese. When it comes to both "Scarface" and "Carlito's Way", both movies star Al Pacino and were directed by Brian De Palma. And even actors that played minor roles in one movie appear in some capacity in their counterparts. Also in the past, there were weekends were I would watch both sets of movies together but on separate days from each other. But of course, there are differences between "Tony Montana" and "Carlito Brigante." "Tony Montana" was basically a Cuban refugee hoodlum who along with other Cuban refugees, arrives in Miami, Florida during the "Mariel Boat Lift" in 1980 and within a few years becomes the top drug lord in Miami and uses cocaine as a source of power. But that particular drug also contributes to his downfall in the end. With "Carlito Brigante", he's a Nuyorican(Puerto Rican New Yorker) ex drug lord who returns to the streets of New York City in 1975 after serving 5 years of a 30 year prison sentence. Now planning to live a legitimate crime free life, he also tries to rekindle his relationship with Gail(Penelope Ann Miller) that he had before his imprisonment. But there are two causes to Carlito's downfall. The first is his lawyer, David Kleinfeld(Sean Penn)who not only has a very bad cocaine addiction but is corrupt and is also a retaliatory target of incarcerated Italian mob boss, Tony "Tony T" Taglialucci(Frank Minucci), another one of his clients. Carlito's second downfall is "Benny Blanco" who is a young, inexperienced punk who is trying to rise up in the drug trade by trying to surpass Carlito and is played by actor/comedian John Leguizamo, respectively. But in the end, is it Carlito himself that contributes to his downfall just for having a loyal trust in Kleinfeld and Pachanga(Luis Guzman), an old friend from his past. "Carlito's Way" was released in 1993 for which it was 10 years apart from "Scarface"(which was released in 1983). And another difference between each movie is the musical score. With "Scarface", the score was conducted by Giorgio Moroder and was synthesizer based. With "Carlito's Way", the score was conducted by Patrick Doyle and was more symphonic/orchestra based. But the soundtrack also consisted of songs from 1970's Disco groups such as KC and the Sunshine Band, The O Jays, The Hues Corporation, The Bee Gees, LaBelle, etc. that fit the time period of the movie(1975). And the soundtrack also consisted of songs from Latin music artists such as Celia Cruz, Hector Lavoe, Willie Colon, and Santana as well. And besides the other aforementioned actors, the other actors that comprised the cast such as James Rebhorn, Viggo Mortensen, Adrian Pasdar, Joseph Siravo, Richard Foronjy, John Ortiz, Ingrid Rogers and the late Argentinian comedic actor, Jorge Porcel(in his only American acting appearance) also put in good performances in this movie. And besides Al Pacino, other "Scarface" alumni such as Al Israel(Hector), Angel Salazar(Chi Chi), Cesar Cordova(Cuban cook), and Mike Moran(Nick the Pig)also make brief cameos in "Carlito's Way." Just like he perfected the Cuban accent for "Tony Montana" in "Scarface", Pacino perfects the Nuyorican accent for "Carlito Brigante" in "Carlito's Way", even if he is an Italian-American actor. Although "Carlito's Way: Rise to Power" was, in my opinion, a good prequel starring Jay Hernandez as a young "Carlito" in his early years, it will never compare to the original film from 1993. "Carlito's Way", in my opinion, is another great gangster film that should be included in the ranks with "The Godfather" trilogy, "Once Upon a Time in America", "Goodfellas", "Casino", "A Bronx Tale", and of course, "Scarface"(both versions from 1932 and 1983/Al Pacino respectively). Also, look out for a director's trademark that director Brian De Palma left in both movies that involves a gun that includes a silencer and an arm in a sling. Of course, both "Scarface" and "Carlito's Way" have to be watched together side by side to find that director's trademark along with its symbolism.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    10 years after Scarface
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Pusztai Norbi (noresz999)
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sorry for my bad English, I'm still learning the language. 10 years after Scarface, its director, and actor, made a gangster movie again, and its outcome isn't so far from the mentioned. They made it based on 2 books (by Edwin Torres), in 144 minutes, if we see on book adaptations, then it's a good time from 1 book, but not from 2. 2 books are compacted in 144 min. It's hard to do it well, but the creators made it very well. I could say without any overstatement, that it's in the top 10 all-time best gangster movies, I cannot see any problem with the movie. It has a lot of memorable scenes, it has some jokes, it's end very exciting, and heartbreaking, and it's not boring, for a minute, either. Furthermore, it's very strong in performances (Al Pacino, Sean Penn), directing (Brian De Palma), and screen writing (David Koepp), i think that it's the key of success. Who has seen this movie, that'll never forget it, simply brilliant. 9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Carlito the Pragmatic Gangster!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Stray Pez
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    DePalma's film is a masterpiece on many levels. For one, it is historically accurate to the letter. Carlito, a former smack peddler, is released from prison after a few years. When released, the drug business has changed. Cocaine, rather than heroine, is the drug of choice for most New Yorkers. It is more expensive and much more widely used than heroine. Before Cocaine, drug dealers were guys who operated on the fringes of society and catered to artists and musicians. In addition, Heroine was relatively cheap compared to Coke. This was the world Carlito was used to in the 50's and 60's. Yet he was somehow able to make a name for himself in this parched landscape through toughness, street smarts and pragmatism. Now released from prison, he finds out that the dope business changed while he was on the inside. Cocaine is easily available and in high demand. Drug users are now part of mainstream society. They include young professionals, politicians and athletes. As a result, drug dealers are not only able to make more money, they also become celebrities in their own right. This was so true about New York in the 1970's. Guys like Nikki Barnes made the cover of magazines because of Coke. It was ridiculous. Another important issue to point out is the escalating violence that results as well. Because Coke is more expensive, dealers are able to buy more guns from the windfall profits. DePalma does an excellent job incorporating this into a generation gap issue between Carlito and the newer criminals. Carlito is a killer and a thug. But he killed for survival. Perhaps his mothers death when he was young gave him more respect for human life or his generation as a whole valued life more than the new generation of gangsters. Carlito was born in a time when many people did not survive childhood. Some women still died during childbirth. World Wars also took the lives of many men. Since the new generation didn't experience death like he did, they value human life less. More guns in circulation feeds the beast of indifference. Pachanga said it best: "They shotgun you just to see you fly up in the air". Overall, a great movie with a tragic ending. The movie incorporates many themes about living a life of crime, changing social attitudes and capitalism. Highly recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    All About Carlito Brigante
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Carlito's Way is a crime drama based on the novels Carlito's Way and After Hours by Judge Edwin Torres. The film adaptation was written by David Koepp. It stars Al Pacino and Sean Penn,together with Penelope Ann Miller, Luis Guzm&aacute;n, John Leguizamo, and Viggo Mortensen in supporting roles. The story follows the life of Carlito Brigante after he is released from prison and vows to go straight and retire from criminal activities. However, unable to escape his past, he ends up being dragged into actions that got him imprisoned in the first place.The movie is narrated by Carlito himself, who explains his hopes, his strategies, and especially his mistakes. Brian De Palma directed the film. Carlito, a fabled heroin dealer, is released from prison after serving 5 years of a 30-year sentence. Tired and middle-aged, he wants out of the business as he has lost the juice for itfor the risks, the killing. It's the mid-'70s, the era of cocaine, fast sex, and disco glitz, and he takes a job running a dance club partially owned by his oldest and most trusted comrade, the coke-addled mob lawyer David Kleinfeld. Carlito's plan is to make some quick cash and move out of the country. But he is dragged down by his rootsby his hair-trigger survivor's instincts, honed while he was still a switchblade-wielding street kid, and by his loyalty to Kleinfeld, who tricks Carlito into helping him execute a mob hit. This film is one of the truly underrated films in the Brian De Palma and/or Al Pacino filmographies. It may have been unjustly derided and dismissed upon its theatrical debut during its year of release, but the it has received a cult following for many years now.The acting is great as the viewers are tickled by Sean Penn's weasely performance, Al Pacino's electric lead, or that crazy-cool chase through the NYC train station. Aside from its excellent performances,it has memorable moments, and some serious action and violent scenes. Overall,Carlito's Way is a smoother piece of filmmaking than Scarface, the only other picture De Palma has made with Pacino.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good classic Brian De Palma
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Panapaok
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Back to the gangster genre for Brian De Palma with Carlito's Way. After Scarface and The Untouchables he gives another pure example of his filmmaking and proves that he is a very strong and underrated master. Al Pacino gives another strong performance as Carlito Brigante and this is not unusual for him because he is in a well known field. But this time he is not another greedy and violent guy like Michael Corleone or Tony Montana but he is wise and clever and his goal is to retire from the business. Furthermore Sean Penn shows again his enormous talent by giving a strong performance as Carlto's rogue lawyer whose motives are not what they seem. He is rotten and cocaine addict and Penn pulls of this role brilliantly. This is a very good film both entertaining and touching and it is a must see for all De Palma's fans. Pacino's narration is an important key for the audience to realize who Carlito is. And, like a lot of gangster films, Carlito's Way proves that once a gangster means always a gangster no matter what.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A very good film... one of Pacinos best.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    richieandsam
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    CARLITO'S WAY I thought this was really good. The movie is about an ex con who gets released from prison and is determined to go straight. He is not interested in crime anymore. The problem is, he has got such a big reputation, that all the gangsters and criminals find him for advice, deals and help... some even want to kill him. The film stars Al Pacino, Sean Penn, Penelope Ann Miller, John Leguizamo, Ingrid Rogers & Luis Guzman. Everyone did a great job. Al is an amazing actor. He is over the top in some of his movies and there are scenes in this film where he is over the top too, but his performances always brings intensity. He is such an intense person and he can be a very scary person. But i think he is great! Sean Penn plays his lawyer... and at the beginning of the movie I felt he was a geek. Big curly hair, geeky glasses and he looks like he doesn't belong in the company of these gangsters... but as the film goes on he changes. The pressures of life gets to him and he can't handle it. His character has a hard time and i felt sorry for him towards the end of the film. I loved the action sequences. The gun fights and make-up were great. There was one scene where a guy gets shot in the face, it was so well shot. The way it was filmed made it look so real. It was a good crime drama/thriller... and I was pleasantly surprised at how good it is. I will give this film 7 out of 10. Al Pacino knows how to play a great gangster... and you can't help but feel sorry for him in this film because all he wants it to get out, but no matter what he does he just gets dragged back in. For more reviews, please like my Facebook page: https://www.facebook.com/pages/Ordinary-Person-Movie- Reviews/456572047728204?ref=hl
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pacino works his magic yet again!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pinturicchio_juve
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I just love Brian De Palma films. They're just so good to watch and have the right mix of good dialogues and an appealing storyline to get the viewer hooked. Scarface and The Untouchables would serve as worthy examples to this fact, and now that I've watched it, I guess Carlito's Way does too. The film is an adaptation of Edwin Torres' novel "After Hours" which follows the story of ex-con/gangster/drug peddler Carlito Brigante (played by Al Pacino), who tries to shun away from a life of crime after being released from prison. Brigante had in actuality been serving a thirty-to-life sentence, which had gotten reduced to five years, owing to the influence his lawyer, David Kleinfeld (Sean Penn) had with the jury. Once out on the streets, Carlito pledges to live life the right way and reluctantly agrees to co-own a nightclub so that he can save just enough money to leave New York and start a car rental business. But inevitably, he's lured into crime once again, and how he fights the odds forms the rest of the plot. One thing that struck me as I watched the film was that everything was very direct. There is not really much for the audience to interpret. Each character is sketched out quite well at the beginning itself, and one kind of knows what he/she would tend to do under the given circumstances. For example, Sean Penn's character, David Kleinfeld is exposed as a corrupt lawyer, and subsequent events throughout the film show him as one, with all his shady dealings and money laundering activities coming back to haunt him. I liked this about the movie, because one is not left wondering what a particular scene means, or what that character was trying to say. Its all said and done. There. Take it or leave it. Of course, this kind of storytelling will not work in all situations, but here, it feels just right. Then there's that aura of the gangster about Carlito. In the beginning, he accompanies his cousin to a drug dealer's hangout for a transaction. As the scene develops, one can feel Carlito sensing that there's something amiss about the place. The tension is brilliantly captured by De Palma here and you can just feel Pacino getting into the skin of the gangster he's portraying. He knows exactly what's going to happen, he's prepared for it, and when it does happen, he knows what to do. This gut instinct comes to the fore in the latter half of the film as well and is part of the reason why this films works for me. There are a lot of scenes and characters which contribute to making the film what it is, such as John Leguizamo as "Benny Blanco" the young upstart who tries to get chummy with Carlito but fails, Gail, Carlito's former lover, with whom he rekindles his relationship and Luiz Guzman as "Pachanga", Carlito's right hand man. But to me, this one is Pacino all the way. He carries the film on his shoulders and commands respect in almost every frame. You can see that he's always in control and this again points to the direct nature of the storyline. The De Palma-Pacino-gangster plot combine gives rise to obvious comparisons with Scarface. But the two are so different. While Tony Montana is just a drug dealer, Carlito Brigante is much more than that. He's a larger than life personality with a heart, remorse, and a conscience. He believes he has a shot at redemption. Montana has none of this. He's arrogant, ruthless and has absolutely no feelings of guilt or regret. The differing nature of their characters make the two films widely different, thus making a comparison would just be a wasteful exercise. The climax sequence, shot at a railway station does bring back scenes reminiscent of The Untouchables, though the events that unfold in the two films are entirely different. Carlito's Way might have its share of flaws which may not put it in the league of gangster flicks such as Goodfellas or The Godfather movies, but it is still a classic, and a highly underrated one at that. De Palma himself is a hugely underrated director (It is a surprise to me how he hasn't won an Oscar yet), and this film just underlines his capability. This one's a must watch for all fans of mob films, but I think that at its very basic level, it's just a story about a man with a heart.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a good movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Hooman Moeen (che-hooman)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    this film have a very good story.AL PACINO have a very good film i ever see.this film show the good guy why have a bad life this movie is a very good romance and crime\gangster i see.good drama i really like that.HAS A A LITTLE SCARFACE REUNION IN IT. SEAN PENN WUZ GREAT AS THE CORRUPT LAWYER. THE ENDING WUZ GREAT BUT TRAGIC BECAUSE YOU END UP PULLING FOR MR BRIGANTE (AL PACINO) DESPITE HIS CRIMINAL PAST.a lot of action is in this movie.Sean Penn plays a good part as a lawyer who got in too deep with the bad guys.he ends up getting shot in the hospital. i just wish there was a different end to this movie.....i wont give it away.if you like Al pacino and Sean Penn,then this movie is a must see.....
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A great story and film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    evas428
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of my favorite movies of all time! Amazing performance by Sean Penn, who really carries the film forward despite the powerhouse presence of the great Al Pacino. The characters were very well written and performed beautifully, especially from the less know (at the time) Vigo Mortensen and John Leguizamo. While this can be considered a "gangster movie", the love story of Carlito and Gale serve as the perfect motivation for the title character to escape the street life. This is much different than The Godfather. Overall, I highly recommend this film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Carlito Goes All The Way-Carlito's Way ****
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Simply put, an outrageously great gangster film with Al Pacino, as usual, turning in still another phenomenal performance as a Puerto Rican gangster who wants to grow straight, but is eventually pulled into a situation which causes tragedy for him. He is equally matched by Sean Penn as a cocaine addicted lawyer who draws him in and Penelope Ann Miller, the girl he loved but tragically could not have. It's basically a well-crafted story of environment having its hold on people and trapping them once they have committed crimes. The music at the club that Pacino owns is absolutely fabulous with an array of popular songs for the period.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The "so-called" sequel to Scarface
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    aaronalmarez
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just like "Casino" has been considered the "so-called" sequel to "Goodfellas", in my opinion, "Carlito's Way" is basically the "so-called" sequel to "Scarface." The reasons for that explanation is because of the stars and similar story lines of each movie. With "Goodfellas" and "Casino", both movies starred Robert De Niro and Joe Pesci and were directed by Martin Scorsese. When it comes to both "Scarface" and "Carlito's Way", both movies star Al Pacino and were directed by Brian De Palma. And even actors that played minor roles in one movie appear in some capacity in their counterparts. Also in the past, there were weekends were I would watch both sets of movies together but on separate days from each other. But of course, there are differences between "Tony Montana" and "Carlito Brigante." "Tony Montana" was basically a Cuban refugee hoodlum who along with other Cuban refugees, arrives in Miami, Florida during the "Mariel Boat Lift" in 1980 and within a few years becomes the top drug lord in Miami and uses cocaine as a source of power. But that particular drug also contributes to his downfall in the end. With "Carlito Brigante", he's a Nuyorican(Puerto Rican New Yorker) ex drug lord who returns to the streets of New York City in 1975 after serving 5 years of a 30 year prison sentence. Now planning to live a legitimate crime free life, he also tries to rekindle his relationship with Gail(Penelope Ann Miller) that he had before his imprisonment. But there are two causes to Carlito's downfall. The first is his lawyer, David Kleinfeld(Sean Penn)who not only has a very bad cocaine addiction but is corrupt and is also a retaliatory target of incarcerated Italian mob boss, Tony "Tony T" Taglialucci(Frank Minucci), another one of his clients. Carlito's second downfall is "Benny Blanco" who is a young, inexperienced punk who is trying to rise up in the drug trade by trying to surpass Carlito and is played by actor/comedian John Leguizamo, respectively. But in the end, is it Carlito himself that contributes to his downfall just for having a loyal trust in Kleinfeld and Pachanga(Luis Guzman), an old friend from his past. "Carlito's Way" was released in 1993 for which it was 10 years apart from "Scarface"(which was released in 1983). And another difference between each movie is the musical score. With "Scarface", the score was conducted by Giorgio Moroder and was synthesizer based. With "Carlito's Way", the score was conducted by Patrick Doyle and was more symphonic/orchestra based. But the soundtrack also consisted of songs from 1970's Disco groups such as KC and the Sunshine Band, The O Jays, The Hues Corporation, The Bee Gees, LaBelle, etc. that fit the time period of the movie(1975). And the soundtrack also consisted of songs from Latin music artists such as Celia Cruz, Hector Lavoe, Willie Colon, and Santana as well. And besides the other aforementioned actors, the other actors that comprised the cast such as James Rebhorn, Viggo Mortensen, Adrian Pasdar, Joseph Siravo, Richard Foronjy, John Ortiz, Ingrid Rogers and the late Argentinian comedic actor, Jorge Porcel(in his only American acting appearance) also put in good performances in this movie. And besides Al Pacino, other "Scarface" alumni such as Al Israel(Hector), Angel Salazar(Chi Chi), Cesar Cordova(Cuban cook), and Mike Moran(Nick the Pig)also make brief cameos in "Carlito's Way." Just like he perfected the Cuban accent for "Tony Montana" in "Scarface", Pacino perfects the Nuyorican accent for "Carlito Brigante" in "Carlito's Way", even if he is an Italian-American actor. Although "Carlito's Way: Rise to Power" was, in my opinion, a good prequel starring Jay Hernandez as a young "Carlito" in his early years, it will never compare to the original film from 1993. "Carlito's Way", in my opinion, is another great gangster film that should be included in the ranks with "The Godfather" trilogy, "Once Upon a Time in America", "Goodfellas", "Casino", "A Bronx Tale", and of course, "Scarface"(both versions from 1932 and 1983/Al Pacino respectively). Also, look out for a director's trademark that director Brian De Palma left in both movies that involves a gun that includes a silencer and an arm in a sling. Of course, both "Scarface" and "Carlito's Way" have to be watched together side by side to find that director's trademark along with its symbolism.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    10 years after Scarface
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Pusztai Norbi (noresz999)
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sorry for my bad English, I'm still learning the language. 10 years after Scarface, its director, and actor, made a gangster movie again, and its outcome isn't so far from the mentioned. They made it based on 2 books (by Edwin Torres), in 144 minutes, if we see on book adaptations, then it's a good time from 1 book, but not from 2. 2 books are compacted in 144 min. It's hard to do it well, but the creators made it very well. I could say without any overstatement, that it's in the top 10 all-time best gangster movies, I cannot see any problem with the movie. It has a lot of memorable scenes, it has some jokes, it's end very exciting, and heartbreaking, and it's not boring, for a minute, either. Furthermore, it's very strong in performances (Al Pacino, Sean Penn), directing (Brian De Palma), and screen writing (David Koepp), i think that it's the key of success. Who has seen this movie, that'll never forget it, simply brilliant. 9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Carlito the Pragmatic Gangster!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Stray Pez
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    DePalma's film is a masterpiece on many levels. For one, it is historically accurate to the letter. Carlito, a former smack peddler, is released from prison after a few years. When released, the drug business has changed. Cocaine, rather than heroine, is the drug of choice for most New Yorkers. It is more expensive and much more widely used than heroine. Before Cocaine, drug dealers were guys who operated on the fringes of society and catered to artists and musicians. In addition, Heroine was relatively cheap compared to Coke. This was the world Carlito was used to in the 50's and 60's. Yet he was somehow able to make a name for himself in this parched landscape through toughness, street smarts and pragmatism. Now released from prison, he finds out that the dope business changed while he was on the inside. Cocaine is easily available and in high demand. Drug users are now part of mainstream society. They include young professionals, politicians and athletes. As a result, drug dealers are not only able to make more money, they also become celebrities in their own right. This was so true about New York in the 1970's. Guys like Nikki Barnes made the cover of magazines because of Coke. It was ridiculous. Another important issue to point out is the escalating violence that results as well. Because Coke is more expensive, dealers are able to buy more guns from the windfall profits. DePalma does an excellent job incorporating this into a generation gap issue between Carlito and the newer criminals. Carlito is a killer and a thug. But he killed for survival. Perhaps his mothers death when he was young gave him more respect for human life or his generation as a whole valued life more than the new generation of gangsters. Carlito was born in a time when many people did not survive childhood. Some women still died during childbirth. World Wars also took the lives of many men. Since the new generation didn't experience death like he did, they value human life less. More guns in circulation feeds the beast of indifference. Pachanga said it best: "They shotgun you just to see you fly up in the air". Overall, a great movie with a tragic ending. The movie incorporates many themes about living a life of crime, changing social attitudes and capitalism. Highly recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    All About Carlito Brigante
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Carlito's Way is a crime drama based on the novels Carlito's Way and After Hours by Judge Edwin Torres. The film adaptation was written by David Koepp. It stars Al Pacino and Sean Penn,together with Penelope Ann Miller, Luis Guzm&aacute;n, John Leguizamo, and Viggo Mortensen in supporting roles. The story follows the life of Carlito Brigante after he is released from prison and vows to go straight and retire from criminal activities. However, unable to escape his past, he ends up being dragged into actions that got him imprisoned in the first place.The movie is narrated by Carlito himself, who explains his hopes, his strategies, and especially his mistakes. Brian De Palma directed the film. Carlito, a fabled heroin dealer, is released from prison after serving 5 years of a 30-year sentence. Tired and middle-aged, he wants out of the business as he has lost the juice for itfor the risks, the killing. It's the mid-'70s, the era of cocaine, fast sex, and disco glitz, and he takes a job running a dance club partially owned by his oldest and most trusted comrade, the coke-addled mob lawyer David Kleinfeld. Carlito's plan is to make some quick cash and move out of the country. But he is dragged down by his rootsby his hair-trigger survivor's instincts, honed while he was still a switchblade-wielding street kid, and by his loyalty to Kleinfeld, who tricks Carlito into helping him execute a mob hit. This film is one of the truly underrated films in the Brian De Palma and/or Al Pacino filmographies. It may have been unjustly derided and dismissed upon its theatrical debut during its year of release, but the it has received a cult following for many years now.The acting is great as the viewers are tickled by Sean Penn's weasely performance, Al Pacino's electric lead, or that crazy-cool chase through the NYC train station. Aside from its excellent performances,it has memorable moments, and some serious action and violent scenes. Overall,Carlito's Way is a smoother piece of filmmaking than Scarface, the only other picture De Palma has made with Pacino.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good classic Brian De Palma
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Panapaok
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Back to the gangster genre for Brian De Palma with Carlito's Way. After Scarface and The Untouchables he gives another pure example of his filmmaking and proves that he is a very strong and underrated master. Al Pacino gives another strong performance as Carlito Brigante and this is not unusual for him because he is in a well known field. But this time he is not another greedy and violent guy like Michael Corleone or Tony Montana but he is wise and clever and his goal is to retire from the business. Furthermore Sean Penn shows again his enormous talent by giving a strong performance as Carlto's rogue lawyer whose motives are not what they seem. He is rotten and cocaine addict and Penn pulls of this role brilliantly. This is a very good film both entertaining and touching and it is a must see for all De Palma's fans. Pacino's narration is an important key for the audience to realize who Carlito is. And, like a lot of gangster films, Carlito's Way proves that once a gangster means always a gangster no matter what.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A very good film... one of Pacinos best.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    richieandsam
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    CARLITO'S WAY I thought this was really good. The movie is about an ex con who gets released from prison and is determined to go straight. He is not interested in crime anymore. The problem is, he has got such a big reputation, that all the gangsters and criminals find him for advice, deals and help... some even want to kill him. The film stars Al Pacino, Sean Penn, Penelope Ann Miller, John Leguizamo, Ingrid Rogers & Luis Guzman. Everyone did a great job. Al is an amazing actor. He is over the top in some of his movies and there are scenes in this film where he is over the top too, but his performances always brings intensity. He is such an intense person and he can be a very scary person. But i think he is great! Sean Penn plays his lawyer... and at the beginning of the movie I felt he was a geek. Big curly hair, geeky glasses and he looks like he doesn't belong in the company of these gangsters... but as the film goes on he changes. The pressures of life gets to him and he can't handle it. His character has a hard time and i felt sorry for him towards the end of the film. I loved the action sequences. The gun fights and make-up were great. There was one scene where a guy gets shot in the face, it was so well shot. The way it was filmed made it look so real. It was a good crime drama/thriller... and I was pleasantly surprised at how good it is. I will give this film 7 out of 10. Al Pacino knows how to play a great gangster... and you can't help but feel sorry for him in this film because all he wants it to get out, but no matter what he does he just gets dragged back in. For more reviews, please like my Facebook page: https://www.facebook.com/pages/Ordinary-Person-Movie- Reviews/456572047728204?ref=hl
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pacino works his magic yet again!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pinturicchio_juve
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I just love Brian De Palma films. They're just so good to watch and have the right mix of good dialogues and an appealing storyline to get the viewer hooked. Scarface and The Untouchables would serve as worthy examples to this fact, and now that I've watched it, I guess Carlito's Way does too. The film is an adaptation of Edwin Torres' novel "After Hours" which follows the story of ex-con/gangster/drug peddler Carlito Brigante (played by Al Pacino), who tries to shun away from a life of crime after being released from prison. Brigante had in actuality been serving a thirty-to-life sentence, which had gotten reduced to five years, owing to the influence his lawyer, David Kleinfeld (Sean Penn) had with the jury. Once out on the streets, Carlito pledges to live life the right way and reluctantly agrees to co-own a nightclub so that he can save just enough money to leave New York and start a car rental business. But inevitably, he's lured into crime once again, and how he fights the odds forms the rest of the plot. One thing that struck me as I watched the film was that everything was very direct. There is not really much for the audience to interpret. Each character is sketched out quite well at the beginning itself, and one kind of knows what he/she would tend to do under the given circumstances. For example, Sean Penn's character, David Kleinfeld is exposed as a corrupt lawyer, and subsequent events throughout the film show him as one, with all his shady dealings and money laundering activities coming back to haunt him. I liked this about the movie, because one is not left wondering what a particular scene means, or what that character was trying to say. Its all said and done. There. Take it or leave it. Of course, this kind of storytelling will not work in all situations, but here, it feels just right. Then there's that aura of the gangster about Carlito. In the beginning, he accompanies his cousin to a drug dealer's hangout for a transaction. As the scene develops, one can feel Carlito sensing that there's something amiss about the place. The tension is brilliantly captured by De Palma here and you can just feel Pacino getting into the skin of the gangster he's portraying. He knows exactly what's going to happen, he's prepared for it, and when it does happen, he knows what to do. This gut instinct comes to the fore in the latter half of the film as well and is part of the reason why this films works for me. There are a lot of scenes and characters which contribute to making the film what it is, such as John Leguizamo as "Benny Blanco" the young upstart who tries to get chummy with Carlito but fails, Gail, Carlito's former lover, with whom he rekindles his relationship and Luiz Guzman as "Pachanga", Carlito's right hand man. But to me, this one is Pacino all the way. He carries the film on his shoulders and commands respect in almost every frame. You can see that he's always in control and this again points to the direct nature of the storyline. The De Palma-Pacino-gangster plot combine gives rise to obvious comparisons with Scarface. But the two are so different. While Tony Montana is just a drug dealer, Carlito Brigante is much more than that. He's a larger than life personality with a heart, remorse, and a conscience. He believes he has a shot at redemption. Montana has none of this. He's arrogant, ruthless and has absolutely no feelings of guilt or regret. The differing nature of their characters make the two films widely different, thus making a comparison would just be a wasteful exercise. The climax sequence, shot at a railway station does bring back scenes reminiscent of The Untouchables, though the events that unfold in the two films are entirely different. Carlito's Way might have its share of flaws which may not put it in the league of gangster flicks such as Goodfellas or The Godfather movies, but it is still a classic, and a highly underrated one at that. De Palma himself is a hugely underrated director (It is a surprise to me how he hasn't won an Oscar yet), and this film just underlines his capability. This one's a must watch for all fans of mob films, but I think that at its very basic level, it's just a story about a man with a heart.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a good movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Hooman Moeen (che-hooman)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    this film have a very good story.AL PACINO have a very good film i ever see.this film show the good guy why have a bad life this movie is a very good romance and crime\gangster i see.good drama i really like that.HAS A A LITTLE SCARFACE REUNION IN IT. SEAN PENN WUZ GREAT AS THE CORRUPT LAWYER. THE ENDING WUZ GREAT BUT TRAGIC BECAUSE YOU END UP PULLING FOR MR BRIGANTE (AL PACINO) DESPITE HIS CRIMINAL PAST.a lot of action is in this movie.Sean Penn plays a good part as a lawyer who got in too deep with the bad guys.he ends up getting shot in the hospital. i just wish there was a different end to this movie.....i wont give it away.if you like Al pacino and Sean Penn,then this movie is a must see.....
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A great story and film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    evas428
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of my favorite movies of all time! Amazing performance by Sean Penn, who really carries the film forward despite the powerhouse presence of the great Al Pacino. The characters were very well written and performed beautifully, especially from the less know (at the time) Vigo Mortensen and John Leguizamo. While this can be considered a "gangster movie", the love story of Carlito and Gale serve as the perfect motivation for the title character to escape the street life. This is much different than The Godfather. Overall, I highly recommend this film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Carlito Goes All The Way-Carlito's Way ****
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Simply put, an outrageously great gangster film with Al Pacino, as usual, turning in still another phenomenal performance as a Puerto Rican gangster who wants to grow straight, but is eventually pulled into a situation which causes tragedy for him. He is equally matched by Sean Penn as a cocaine addicted lawyer who draws him in and Penelope Ann Miller, the girl he loved but tragically could not have. It's basically a well-crafted story of environment having its hold on people and trapping them once they have committed crimes. The music at the club that Pacino owns is absolutely fabulous with an array of popular songs for the period.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The "so-called" sequel to Scarface
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    aaronalmarez
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just like "Casino" has been considered the "so-called" sequel to "Goodfellas", in my opinion, "Carlito's Way" is basically the "so-called" sequel to "Scarface." The reasons for that explanation is because of the stars and similar story lines of each movie. With "Goodfellas" and "Casino", both movies starred Robert De Niro and Joe Pesci and were directed by Martin Scorsese. When it comes to both "Scarface" and "Carlito's Way", both movies star Al Pacino and were directed by Brian De Palma. And even actors that played minor roles in one movie appear in some capacity in their counterparts. Also in the past, there were weekends were I would watch both sets of movies together but on separate days from each other. But of course, there are differences between "Tony Montana" and "Carlito Brigante." "Tony Montana" was basically a Cuban refugee hoodlum who along with other Cuban refugees, arrives in Miami, Florida during the "Mariel Boat Lift" in 1980 and within a few years becomes the top drug lord in Miami and uses cocaine as a source of power. But that particular drug also contributes to his downfall in the end. With "Carlito Brigante", he's a Nuyorican(Puerto Rican New Yorker) ex drug lord who returns to the streets of New York City in 1975 after serving 5 years of a 30 year prison sentence. Now planning to live a legitimate crime free life, he also tries to rekindle his relationship with Gail(Penelope Ann Miller) that he had before his imprisonment. But there are two causes to Carlito's downfall. The first is his lawyer, David Kleinfeld(Sean Penn)who not only has a very bad cocaine addiction but is corrupt and is also a retaliatory target of incarcerated Italian mob boss, Tony "Tony T" Taglialucci(Frank Minucci), another one of his clients. Carlito's second downfall is "Benny Blanco" who is a young, inexperienced punk who is trying to rise up in the drug trade by trying to surpass Carlito and is played by actor/comedian John Leguizamo, respectively. But in the end, is it Carlito himself that contributes to his downfall just for having a loyal trust in Kleinfeld and Pachanga(Luis Guzman), an old friend from his past. "Carlito's Way" was released in 1993 for which it was 10 years apart from "Scarface"(which was released in 1983). And another difference between each movie is the musical score. With "Scarface", the score was conducted by Giorgio Moroder and was synthesizer based. With "Carlito's Way", the score was conducted by Patrick Doyle and was more symphonic/orchestra based. But the soundtrack also consisted of songs from 1970's Disco groups such as KC and the Sunshine Band, The O Jays, The Hues Corporation, The Bee Gees, LaBelle, etc. that fit the time period of the movie(1975). And the soundtrack also consisted of songs from Latin music artists such as Celia Cruz, Hector Lavoe, Willie Colon, and Santana as well. And besides the other aforementioned actors, the other actors that comprised the cast such as James Rebhorn, Viggo Mortensen, Adrian Pasdar, Joseph Siravo, Richard Foronjy, John Ortiz, Ingrid Rogers and the late Argentinian comedic actor, Jorge Porcel(in his only American acting appearance) also put in good performances in this movie. And besides Al Pacino, other "Scarface" alumni such as Al Israel(Hector), Angel Salazar(Chi Chi), Cesar Cordova(Cuban cook), and Mike Moran(Nick the Pig)also make brief cameos in "Carlito's Way." Just like he perfected the Cuban accent for "Tony Montana" in "Scarface", Pacino perfects the Nuyorican accent for "Carlito Brigante" in "Carlito's Way", even if he is an Italian-American actor. Although "Carlito's Way: Rise to Power" was, in my opinion, a good prequel starring Jay Hernandez as a young "Carlito" in his early years, it will never compare to the original film from 1993. "Carlito's Way", in my opinion, is another great gangster film that should be included in the ranks with "The Godfather" trilogy, "Once Upon a Time in America", "Goodfellas", "Casino", "A Bronx Tale", and of course, "Scarface"(both versions from 1932 and 1983/Al Pacino respectively). Also, look out for a director's trademark that director Brian De Palma left in both movies that involves a gun that includes a silencer and an arm in a sling. Of course, both "Scarface" and "Carlito's Way" have to be watched together side by side to find that director's trademark along with its symbolism.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    10 years after Scarface
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Pusztai Norbi (noresz999)
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sorry for my bad English, I'm still learning the language. 10 years after Scarface, its director, and actor, made a gangster movie again, and its outcome isn't so far from the mentioned. They made it based on 2 books (by Edwin Torres), in 144 minutes, if we see on book adaptations, then it's a good time from 1 book, but not from 2. 2 books are compacted in 144 min. It's hard to do it well, but the creators made it very well. I could say without any overstatement, that it's in the top 10 all-time best gangster movies, I cannot see any problem with the movie. It has a lot of memorable scenes, it has some jokes, it's end very exciting, and heartbreaking, and it's not boring, for a minute, either. Furthermore, it's very strong in performances (Al Pacino, Sean Penn), directing (Brian De Palma), and screen writing (David Koepp), i think that it's the key of success. Who has seen this movie, that'll never forget it, simply brilliant. 9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Carlito the Pragmatic Gangster!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Stray Pez
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    DePalma's film is a masterpiece on many levels. For one, it is historically accurate to the letter. Carlito, a former smack peddler, is released from prison after a few years. When released, the drug business has changed. Cocaine, rather than heroine, is the drug of choice for most New Yorkers. It is more expensive and much more widely used than heroine. Before Cocaine, drug dealers were guys who operated on the fringes of society and catered to artists and musicians. In addition, Heroine was relatively cheap compared to Coke. This was the world Carlito was used to in the 50's and 60's. Yet he was somehow able to make a name for himself in this parched landscape through toughness, street smarts and pragmatism. Now released from prison, he finds out that the dope business changed while he was on the inside. Cocaine is easily available and in high demand. Drug users are now part of mainstream society. They include young professionals, politicians and athletes. As a result, drug dealers are not only able to make more money, they also become celebrities in their own right. This was so true about New York in the 1970's. Guys like Nikki Barnes made the cover of magazines because of Coke. It was ridiculous. Another important issue to point out is the escalating violence that results as well. Because Coke is more expensive, dealers are able to buy more guns from the windfall profits. DePalma does an excellent job incorporating this into a generation gap issue between Carlito and the newer criminals. Carlito is a killer and a thug. But he killed for survival. Perhaps his mothers death when he was young gave him more respect for human life or his generation as a whole valued life more than the new generation of gangsters. Carlito was born in a time when many people did not survive childhood. Some women still died during childbirth. World Wars also took the lives of many men. Since the new generation didn't experience death like he did, they value human life less. More guns in circulation feeds the beast of indifference. Pachanga said it best: "They shotgun you just to see you fly up in the air". Overall, a great movie with a tragic ending. The movie incorporates many themes about living a life of crime, changing social attitudes and capitalism. Highly recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    All About Carlito Brigante
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Carlito's Way is a crime drama based on the novels Carlito's Way and After Hours by Judge Edwin Torres. The film adaptation was written by David Koepp. It stars Al Pacino and Sean Penn,together with Penelope Ann Miller, Luis Guzm&aacute;n, John Leguizamo, and Viggo Mortensen in supporting roles. The story follows the life of Carlito Brigante after he is released from prison and vows to go straight and retire from criminal activities. However, unable to escape his past, he ends up being dragged into actions that got him imprisoned in the first place.The movie is narrated by Carlito himself, who explains his hopes, his strategies, and especially his mistakes. Brian De Palma directed the film. Carlito, a fabled heroin dealer, is released from prison after serving 5 years of a 30-year sentence. Tired and middle-aged, he wants out of the business as he has lost the juice for itfor the risks, the killing. It's the mid-'70s, the era of cocaine, fast sex, and disco glitz, and he takes a job running a dance club partially owned by his oldest and most trusted comrade, the coke-addled mob lawyer David Kleinfeld. Carlito's plan is to make some quick cash and move out of the country. But he is dragged down by his rootsby his hair-trigger survivor's instincts, honed while he was still a switchblade-wielding street kid, and by his loyalty to Kleinfeld, who tricks Carlito into helping him execute a mob hit. This film is one of the truly underrated films in the Brian De Palma and/or Al Pacino filmographies. It may have been unjustly derided and dismissed upon its theatrical debut during its year of release, but the it has received a cult following for many years now.The acting is great as the viewers are tickled by Sean Penn's weasely performance, Al Pacino's electric lead, or that crazy-cool chase through the NYC train station. Aside from its excellent performances,it has memorable moments, and some serious action and violent scenes. Overall,Carlito's Way is a smoother piece of filmmaking than Scarface, the only other picture De Palma has made with Pacino.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good classic Brian De Palma
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Panapaok
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Back to the gangster genre for Brian De Palma with Carlito's Way. After Scarface and The Untouchables he gives another pure example of his filmmaking and proves that he is a very strong and underrated master. Al Pacino gives another strong performance as Carlito Brigante and this is not unusual for him because he is in a well known field. But this time he is not another greedy and violent guy like Michael Corleone or Tony Montana but he is wise and clever and his goal is to retire from the business. Furthermore Sean Penn shows again his enormous talent by giving a strong performance as Carlto's rogue lawyer whose motives are not what they seem. He is rotten and cocaine addict and Penn pulls of this role brilliantly. This is a very good film both entertaining and touching and it is a must see for all De Palma's fans. Pacino's narration is an important key for the audience to realize who Carlito is. And, like a lot of gangster films, Carlito's Way proves that once a gangster means always a gangster no matter what.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A very good film... one of Pacinos best.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    richieandsam
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    CARLITO'S WAY I thought this was really good. The movie is about an ex con who gets released from prison and is determined to go straight. He is not interested in crime anymore. The problem is, he has got such a big reputation, that all the gangsters and criminals find him for advice, deals and help... some even want to kill him. The film stars Al Pacino, Sean Penn, Penelope Ann Miller, John Leguizamo, Ingrid Rogers & Luis Guzman. Everyone did a great job. Al is an amazing actor. He is over the top in some of his movies and there are scenes in this film where he is over the top too, but his performances always brings intensity. He is such an intense person and he can be a very scary person. But i think he is great! Sean Penn plays his lawyer... and at the beginning of the movie I felt he was a geek. Big curly hair, geeky glasses and he looks like he doesn't belong in the company of these gangsters... but as the film goes on he changes. The pressures of life gets to him and he can't handle it. His character has a hard time and i felt sorry for him towards the end of the film. I loved the action sequences. The gun fights and make-up were great. There was one scene where a guy gets shot in the face, it was so well shot. The way it was filmed made it look so real. It was a good crime drama/thriller... and I was pleasantly surprised at how good it is. I will give this film 7 out of 10. Al Pacino knows how to play a great gangster... and you can't help but feel sorry for him in this film because all he wants it to get out, but no matter what he does he just gets dragged back in. For more reviews, please like my Facebook page: https://www.facebook.com/pages/Ordinary-Person-Movie- Reviews/456572047728204?ref=hl
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pacino works his magic yet again!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pinturicchio_juve
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I just love Brian De Palma films. They're just so good to watch and have the right mix of good dialogues and an appealing storyline to get the viewer hooked. Scarface and The Untouchables would serve as worthy examples to this fact, and now that I've watched it, I guess Carlito's Way does too. The film is an adaptation of Edwin Torres' novel "After Hours" which follows the story of ex-con/gangster/drug peddler Carlito Brigante (played by Al Pacino), who tries to shun away from a life of crime after being released from prison. Brigante had in actuality been serving a thirty-to-life sentence, which had gotten reduced to five years, owing to the influence his lawyer, David Kleinfeld (Sean Penn) had with the jury. Once out on the streets, Carlito pledges to live life the right way and reluctantly agrees to co-own a nightclub so that he can save just enough money to leave New York and start a car rental business. But inevitably, he's lured into crime once again, and how he fights the odds forms the rest of the plot. One thing that struck me as I watched the film was that everything was very direct. There is not really much for the audience to interpret. Each character is sketched out quite well at the beginning itself, and one kind of knows what he/she would tend to do under the given circumstances. For example, Sean Penn's character, David Kleinfeld is exposed as a corrupt lawyer, and subsequent events throughout the film show him as one, with all his shady dealings and money laundering activities coming back to haunt him. I liked this about the movie, because one is not left wondering what a particular scene means, or what that character was trying to say. Its all said and done. There. Take it or leave it. Of course, this kind of storytelling will not work in all situations, but here, it feels just right. Then there's that aura of the gangster about Carlito. In the beginning, he accompanies his cousin to a drug dealer's hangout for a transaction. As the scene develops, one can feel Carlito sensing that there's something amiss about the place. The tension is brilliantly captured by De Palma here and you can just feel Pacino getting into the skin of the gangster he's portraying. He knows exactly what's going to happen, he's prepared for it, and when it does happen, he knows what to do. This gut instinct comes to the fore in the latter half of the film as well and is part of the reason why this films works for me. There are a lot of scenes and characters which contribute to making the film what it is, such as John Leguizamo as "Benny Blanco" the young upstart who tries to get chummy with Carlito but fails, Gail, Carlito's former lover, with whom he rekindles his relationship and Luiz Guzman as "Pachanga", Carlito's right hand man. But to me, this one is Pacino all the way. He carries the film on his shoulders and commands respect in almost every frame. You can see that he's always in control and this again points to the direct nature of the storyline. The De Palma-Pacino-gangster plot combine gives rise to obvious comparisons with Scarface. But the two are so different. While Tony Montana is just a drug dealer, Carlito Brigante is much more than that. He's a larger than life personality with a heart, remorse, and a conscience. He believes he has a shot at redemption. Montana has none of this. He's arrogant, ruthless and has absolutely no feelings of guilt or regret. The differing nature of their characters make the two films widely different, thus making a comparison would just be a wasteful exercise. The climax sequence, shot at a railway station does bring back scenes reminiscent of The Untouchables, though the events that unfold in the two films are entirely different. Carlito's Way might have its share of flaws which may not put it in the league of gangster flicks such as Goodfellas or The Godfather movies, but it is still a classic, and a highly underrated one at that. De Palma himself is a hugely underrated director (It is a surprise to me how he hasn't won an Oscar yet), and this film just underlines his capability. This one's a must watch for all fans of mob films, but I think that at its very basic level, it's just a story about a man with a heart.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a good movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Hooman Moeen (che-hooman)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    this film have a very good story.AL PACINO have a very good film i ever see.this film show the good guy why have a bad life this movie is a very good romance and crime\gangster i see.good drama i really like that.HAS A A LITTLE SCARFACE REUNION IN IT. SEAN PENN WUZ GREAT AS THE CORRUPT LAWYER. THE ENDING WUZ GREAT BUT TRAGIC BECAUSE YOU END UP PULLING FOR MR BRIGANTE (AL PACINO) DESPITE HIS CRIMINAL PAST.a lot of action is in this movie.Sean Penn plays a good part as a lawyer who got in too deep with the bad guys.he ends up getting shot in the hospital. i just wish there was a different end to this movie.....i wont give it away.if you like Al pacino and Sean Penn,then this movie is a must see.....
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A great story and film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    evas428
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of my favorite movies of all time! Amazing performance by Sean Penn, who really carries the film forward despite the powerhouse presence of the great Al Pacino. The characters were very well written and performed beautifully, especially from the less know (at the time) Vigo Mortensen and John Leguizamo. While this can be considered a "gangster movie", the love story of Carlito and Gale serve as the perfect motivation for the title character to escape the street life. This is much different than The Godfather. Overall, I highly recommend this film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Carlito Goes All The Way-Carlito's Way ****
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Simply put, an outrageously great gangster film with Al Pacino, as usual, turning in still another phenomenal performance as a Puerto Rican gangster who wants to grow straight, but is eventually pulled into a situation which causes tragedy for him. He is equally matched by Sean Penn as a cocaine addicted lawyer who draws him in and Penelope Ann Miller, the girl he loved but tragically could not have. It's basically a well-crafted story of environment having its hold on people and trapping them once they have committed crimes. The music at the club that Pacino owns is absolutely fabulous with an array of popular songs for the period.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The "so-called" sequel to Scarface
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    aaronalmarez
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just like "Casino" has been considered the "so-called" sequel to "Goodfellas", in my opinion, "Carlito's Way" is basically the "so-called" sequel to "Scarface." The reasons for that explanation is because of the stars and similar story lines of each movie. With "Goodfellas" and "Casino", both movies starred Robert De Niro and Joe Pesci and were directed by Martin Scorsese. When it comes to both "Scarface" and "Carlito's Way", both movies star Al Pacino and were directed by Brian De Palma. And even actors that played minor roles in one movie appear in some capacity in their counterparts. Also in the past, there were weekends were I would watch both sets of movies together but on separate days from each other. But of course, there are differences between "Tony Montana" and "Carlito Brigante." "Tony Montana" was basically a Cuban refugee hoodlum who along with other Cuban refugees, arrives in Miami, Florida during the "Mariel Boat Lift" in 1980 and within a few years becomes the top drug lord in Miami and uses cocaine as a source of power. But that particular drug also contributes to his downfall in the end. With "Carlito Brigante", he's a Nuyorican(Puerto Rican New Yorker) ex drug lord who returns to the streets of New York City in 1975 after serving 5 years of a 30 year prison sentence. Now planning to live a legitimate crime free life, he also tries to rekindle his relationship with Gail(Penelope Ann Miller) that he had before his imprisonment. But there are two causes to Carlito's downfall. The first is his lawyer, David Kleinfeld(Sean Penn)who not only has a very bad cocaine addiction but is corrupt and is also a retaliatory target of incarcerated Italian mob boss, Tony "Tony T" Taglialucci(Frank Minucci), another one of his clients. Carlito's second downfall is "Benny Blanco" who is a young, inexperienced punk who is trying to rise up in the drug trade by trying to surpass Carlito and is played by actor/comedian John Leguizamo, respectively. But in the end, is it Carlito himself that contributes to his downfall just for having a loyal trust in Kleinfeld and Pachanga(Luis Guzman), an old friend from his past. "Carlito's Way" was released in 1993 for which it was 10 years apart from "Scarface"(which was released in 1983). And another difference between each movie is the musical score. With "Scarface", the score was conducted by Giorgio Moroder and was synthesizer based. With "Carlito's Way", the score was conducted by Patrick Doyle and was more symphonic/orchestra based. But the soundtrack also consisted of songs from 1970's Disco groups such as KC and the Sunshine Band, The O Jays, The Hues Corporation, The Bee Gees, LaBelle, etc. that fit the time period of the movie(1975). And the soundtrack also consisted of songs from Latin music artists such as Celia Cruz, Hector Lavoe, Willie Colon, and Santana as well. And besides the other aforementioned actors, the other actors that comprised the cast such as James Rebhorn, Viggo Mortensen, Adrian Pasdar, Joseph Siravo, Richard Foronjy, John Ortiz, Ingrid Rogers and the late Argentinian comedic actor, Jorge Porcel(in his only American acting appearance) also put in good performances in this movie. And besides Al Pacino, other "Scarface" alumni such as Al Israel(Hector), Angel Salazar(Chi Chi), Cesar Cordova(Cuban cook), and Mike Moran(Nick the Pig)also make brief cameos in "Carlito's Way." Just like he perfected the Cuban accent for "Tony Montana" in "Scarface", Pacino perfects the Nuyorican accent for "Carlito Brigante" in "Carlito's Way", even if he is an Italian-American actor. Although "Carlito's Way: Rise to Power" was, in my opinion, a good prequel starring Jay Hernandez as a young "Carlito" in his early years, it will never compare to the original film from 1993. "Carlito's Way", in my opinion, is another great gangster film that should be included in the ranks with "The Godfather" trilogy, "Once Upon a Time in America", "Goodfellas", "Casino", "A Bronx Tale", and of course, "Scarface"(both versions from 1932 and 1983/Al Pacino respectively). Also, look out for a director's trademark that director Brian De Palma left in both movies that involves a gun that includes a silencer and an arm in a sling. Of course, both "Scarface" and "Carlito's Way" have to be watched together side by side to find that director's trademark along with its symbolism.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    10 years after Scarface
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Pusztai Norbi (noresz999)
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sorry for my bad English, I'm still learning the language. 10 years after Scarface, its director, and actor, made a gangster movie again, and its outcome isn't so far from the mentioned. They made it based on 2 books (by Edwin Torres), in 144 minutes, if we see on book adaptations, then it's a good time from 1 book, but not from 2. 2 books are compacted in 144 min. It's hard to do it well, but the creators made it very well. I could say without any overstatement, that it's in the top 10 all-time best gangster movies, I cannot see any problem with the movie. It has a lot of memorable scenes, it has some jokes, it's end very exciting, and heartbreaking, and it's not boring, for a minute, either. Furthermore, it's very strong in performances (Al Pacino, Sean Penn), directing (Brian De Palma), and screen writing (David Koepp), i think that it's the key of success. Who has seen this movie, that'll never forget it, simply brilliant. 9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Carlito the Pragmatic Gangster!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Stray Pez
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    DePalma's film is a masterpiece on many levels. For one, it is historically accurate to the letter. Carlito, a former smack peddler, is released from prison after a few years. When released, the drug business has changed. Cocaine, rather than heroine, is the drug of choice for most New Yorkers. It is more expensive and much more widely used than heroine. Before Cocaine, drug dealers were guys who operated on the fringes of society and catered to artists and musicians. In addition, Heroine was relatively cheap compared to Coke. This was the world Carlito was used to in the 50's and 60's. Yet he was somehow able to make a name for himself in this parched landscape through toughness, street smarts and pragmatism. Now released from prison, he finds out that the dope business changed while he was on the inside. Cocaine is easily available and in high demand. Drug users are now part of mainstream society. They include young professionals, politicians and athletes. As a result, drug dealers are not only able to make more money, they also become celebrities in their own right. This was so true about New York in the 1970's. Guys like Nikki Barnes made the cover of magazines because of Coke. It was ridiculous. Another important issue to point out is the escalating violence that results as well. Because Coke is more expensive, dealers are able to buy more guns from the windfall profits. DePalma does an excellent job incorporating this into a generation gap issue between Carlito and the newer criminals. Carlito is a killer and a thug. But he killed for survival. Perhaps his mothers death when he was young gave him more respect for human life or his generation as a whole valued life more than the new generation of gangsters. Carlito was born in a time when many people did not survive childhood. Some women still died during childbirth. World Wars also took the lives of many men. Since the new generation didn't experience death like he did, they value human life less. More guns in circulation feeds the beast of indifference. Pachanga said it best: "They shotgun you just to see you fly up in the air". Overall, a great movie with a tragic ending. The movie incorporates many themes about living a life of crime, changing social attitudes and capitalism. Highly recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    All About Carlito Brigante
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Carlito's Way is a crime drama based on the novels Carlito's Way and After Hours by Judge Edwin Torres. The film adaptation was written by David Koepp. It stars Al Pacino and Sean Penn,together with Penelope Ann Miller, Luis Guzm&aacute;n, John Leguizamo, and Viggo Mortensen in supporting roles. The story follows the life of Carlito Brigante after he is released from prison and vows to go straight and retire from criminal activities. However, unable to escape his past, he ends up being dragged into actions that got him imprisoned in the first place.The movie is narrated by Carlito himself, who explains his hopes, his strategies, and especially his mistakes. Brian De Palma directed the film. Carlito, a fabled heroin dealer, is released from prison after serving 5 years of a 30-year sentence. Tired and middle-aged, he wants out of the business as he has lost the juice for itfor the risks, the killing. It's the mid-'70s, the era of cocaine, fast sex, and disco glitz, and he takes a job running a dance club partially owned by his oldest and most trusted comrade, the coke-addled mob lawyer David Kleinfeld. Carlito's plan is to make some quick cash and move out of the country. But he is dragged down by his rootsby his hair-trigger survivor's instincts, honed while he was still a switchblade-wielding street kid, and by his loyalty to Kleinfeld, who tricks Carlito into helping him execute a mob hit. This film is one of the truly underrated films in the Brian De Palma and/or Al Pacino filmographies. It may have been unjustly derided and dismissed upon its theatrical debut during its year of release, but the it has received a cult following for many years now.The acting is great as the viewers are tickled by Sean Penn's weasely performance, Al Pacino's electric lead, or that crazy-cool chase through the NYC train station. Aside from its excellent performances,it has memorable moments, and some serious action and violent scenes. Overall,Carlito's Way is a smoother piece of filmmaking than Scarface, the only other picture De Palma has made with Pacino.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good classic Brian De Palma
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Panapaok
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Back to the gangster genre for Brian De Palma with Carlito's Way. After Scarface and The Untouchables he gives another pure example of his filmmaking and proves that he is a very strong and underrated master. Al Pacino gives another strong performance as Carlito Brigante and this is not unusual for him because he is in a well known field. But this time he is not another greedy and violent guy like Michael Corleone or Tony Montana but he is wise and clever and his goal is to retire from the business. Furthermore Sean Penn shows again his enormous talent by giving a strong performance as Carlto's rogue lawyer whose motives are not what they seem. He is rotten and cocaine addict and Penn pulls of this role brilliantly. This is a very good film both entertaining and touching and it is a must see for all De Palma's fans. Pacino's narration is an important key for the audience to realize who Carlito is. And, like a lot of gangster films, Carlito's Way proves that once a gangster means always a gangster no matter what.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A very good film... one of Pacinos best.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    richieandsam
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    CARLITO'S WAY I thought this was really good. The movie is about an ex con who gets released from prison and is determined to go straight. He is not interested in crime anymore. The problem is, he has got such a big reputation, that all the gangsters and criminals find him for advice, deals and help... some even want to kill him. The film stars Al Pacino, Sean Penn, Penelope Ann Miller, John Leguizamo, Ingrid Rogers & Luis Guzman. Everyone did a great job. Al is an amazing actor. He is over the top in some of his movies and there are scenes in this film where he is over the top too, but his performances always brings intensity. He is such an intense person and he can be a very scary person. But i think he is great! Sean Penn plays his lawyer... and at the beginning of the movie I felt he was a geek. Big curly hair, geeky glasses and he looks like he doesn't belong in the company of these gangsters... but as the film goes on he changes. The pressures of life gets to him and he can't handle it. His character has a hard time and i felt sorry for him towards the end of the film. I loved the action sequences. The gun fights and make-up were great. There was one scene where a guy gets shot in the face, it was so well shot. The way it was filmed made it look so real. It was a good crime drama/thriller... and I was pleasantly surprised at how good it is. I will give this film 7 out of 10. Al Pacino knows how to play a great gangster... and you can't help but feel sorry for him in this film because all he wants it to get out, but no matter what he does he just gets dragged back in. For more reviews, please like my Facebook page: https://www.facebook.com/pages/Ordinary-Person-Movie- Reviews/456572047728204?ref=hl
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pacino works his magic yet again!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pinturicchio_juve
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I just love Brian De Palma films. They're just so good to watch and have the right mix of good dialogues and an appealing storyline to get the viewer hooked. Scarface and The Untouchables would serve as worthy examples to this fact, and now that I've watched it, I guess Carlito's Way does too. The film is an adaptation of Edwin Torres' novel "After Hours" which follows the story of ex-con/gangster/drug peddler Carlito Brigante (played by Al Pacino), who tries to shun away from a life of crime after being released from prison. Brigante had in actuality been serving a thirty-to-life sentence, which had gotten reduced to five years, owing to the influence his lawyer, David Kleinfeld (Sean Penn) had with the jury. Once out on the streets, Carlito pledges to live life the right way and reluctantly agrees to co-own a nightclub so that he can save just enough money to leave New York and start a car rental business. But inevitably, he's lured into crime once again, and how he fights the odds forms the rest of the plot. One thing that struck me as I watched the film was that everything was very direct. There is not really much for the audience to interpret. Each character is sketched out quite well at the beginning itself, and one kind of knows what he/she would tend to do under the given circumstances. For example, Sean Penn's character, David Kleinfeld is exposed as a corrupt lawyer, and subsequent events throughout the film show him as one, with all his shady dealings and money laundering activities coming back to haunt him. I liked this about the movie, because one is not left wondering what a particular scene means, or what that character was trying to say. Its all said and done. There. Take it or leave it. Of course, this kind of storytelling will not work in all situations, but here, it feels just right. Then there's that aura of the gangster about Carlito. In the beginning, he accompanies his cousin to a drug dealer's hangout for a transaction. As the scene develops, one can feel Carlito sensing that there's something amiss about the place. The tension is brilliantly captured by De Palma here and you can just feel Pacino getting into the skin of the gangster he's portraying. He knows exactly what's going to happen, he's prepared for it, and when it does happen, he knows what to do. This gut instinct comes to the fore in the latter half of the film as well and is part of the reason why this films works for me. There are a lot of scenes and characters which contribute to making the film what it is, such as John Leguizamo as "Benny Blanco" the young upstart who tries to get chummy with Carlito but fails, Gail, Carlito's former lover, with whom he rekindles his relationship and Luiz Guzman as "Pachanga", Carlito's right hand man. But to me, this one is Pacino all the way. He carries the film on his shoulders and commands respect in almost every frame. You can see that he's always in control and this again points to the direct nature of the storyline. The De Palma-Pacino-gangster plot combine gives rise to obvious comparisons with Scarface. But the two are so different. While Tony Montana is just a drug dealer, Carlito Brigante is much more than that. He's a larger than life personality with a heart, remorse, and a conscience. He believes he has a shot at redemption. Montana has none of this. He's arrogant, ruthless and has absolutely no feelings of guilt or regret. The differing nature of their characters make the two films widely different, thus making a comparison would just be a wasteful exercise. The climax sequence, shot at a railway station does bring back scenes reminiscent of The Untouchables, though the events that unfold in the two films are entirely different. Carlito's Way might have its share of flaws which may not put it in the league of gangster flicks such as Goodfellas or The Godfather movies, but it is still a classic, and a highly underrated one at that. De Palma himself is a hugely underrated director (It is a surprise to me how he hasn't won an Oscar yet), and this film just underlines his capability. This one's a must watch for all fans of mob films, but I think that at its very basic level, it's just a story about a man with a heart.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a good movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Hooman Moeen (che-hooman)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    this film have a very good story.AL PACINO have a very good film i ever see.this film show the good guy why have a bad life this movie is a very good romance and crime\gangster i see.good drama i really like that.HAS A A LITTLE SCARFACE REUNION IN IT. SEAN PENN WUZ GREAT AS THE CORRUPT LAWYER. THE ENDING WUZ GREAT BUT TRAGIC BECAUSE YOU END UP PULLING FOR MR BRIGANTE (AL PACINO) DESPITE HIS CRIMINAL PAST.a lot of action is in this movie.Sean Penn plays a good part as a lawyer who got in too deep with the bad guys.he ends up getting shot in the hospital. i just wish there was a different end to this movie.....i wont give it away.if you like Al pacino and Sean Penn,then this movie is a must see.....
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A great story and film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    evas428
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of my favorite movies of all time! Amazing performance by Sean Penn, who really carries the film forward despite the powerhouse presence of the great Al Pacino. The characters were very well written and performed beautifully, especially from the less know (at the time) Vigo Mortensen and John Leguizamo. While this can be considered a "gangster movie", the love story of Carlito and Gale serve as the perfect motivation for the title character to escape the street life. This is much different than The Godfather. Overall, I highly recommend this film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Carlito Goes All The Way-Carlito's Way ****
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Simply put, an outrageously great gangster film with Al Pacino, as usual, turning in still another phenomenal performance as a Puerto Rican gangster who wants to grow straight, but is eventually pulled into a situation which causes tragedy for him. He is equally matched by Sean Penn as a cocaine addicted lawyer who draws him in and Penelope Ann Miller, the girl he loved but tragically could not have. It's basically a well-crafted story of environment having its hold on people and trapping them once they have committed crimes. The music at the club that Pacino owns is absolutely fabulous with an array of popular songs for the period.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The "so-called" sequel to Scarface
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    aaronalmarez
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just like "Casino" has been considered the "so-called" sequel to "Goodfellas", in my opinion, "Carlito's Way" is basically the "so-called" sequel to "Scarface." The reasons for that explanation is because of the stars and similar story lines of each movie. With "Goodfellas" and "Casino", both movies starred Robert De Niro and Joe Pesci and were directed by Martin Scorsese. When it comes to both "Scarface" and "Carlito's Way", both movies star Al Pacino and were directed by Brian De Palma. And even actors that played minor roles in one movie appear in some capacity in their counterparts. Also in the past, there were weekends were I would watch both sets of movies together but on separate days from each other. But of course, there are differences between "Tony Montana" and "Carlito Brigante." "Tony Montana" was basically a Cuban refugee hoodlum who along with other Cuban refugees, arrives in Miami, Florida during the "Mariel Boat Lift" in 1980 and within a few years becomes the top drug lord in Miami and uses cocaine as a source of power. But that particular drug also contributes to his downfall in the end. With "Carlito Brigante", he's a Nuyorican(Puerto Rican New Yorker) ex drug lord who returns to the streets of New York City in 1975 after serving 5 years of a 30 year prison sentence. Now planning to live a legitimate crime free life, he also tries to rekindle his relationship with Gail(Penelope Ann Miller) that he had before his imprisonment. But there are two causes to Carlito's downfall. The first is his lawyer, David Kleinfeld(Sean Penn)who not only has a very bad cocaine addiction but is corrupt and is also a retaliatory target of incarcerated Italian mob boss, Tony "Tony T" Taglialucci(Frank Minucci), another one of his clients. Carlito's second downfall is "Benny Blanco" who is a young, inexperienced punk who is trying to rise up in the drug trade by trying to surpass Carlito and is played by actor/comedian John Leguizamo, respectively. But in the end, is it Carlito himself that contributes to his downfall just for having a loyal trust in Kleinfeld and Pachanga(Luis Guzman), an old friend from his past. "Carlito's Way" was released in 1993 for which it was 10 years apart from "Scarface"(which was released in 1983). And another difference between each movie is the musical score. With "Scarface", the score was conducted by Giorgio Moroder and was synthesizer based. With "Carlito's Way", the score was conducted by Patrick Doyle and was more symphonic/orchestra based. But the soundtrack also consisted of songs from 1970's Disco groups such as KC and the Sunshine Band, The O Jays, The Hues Corporation, The Bee Gees, LaBelle, etc. that fit the time period of the movie(1975). And the soundtrack also consisted of songs from Latin music artists such as Celia Cruz, Hector Lavoe, Willie Colon, and Santana as well. And besides the other aforementioned actors, the other actors that comprised the cast such as James Rebhorn, Viggo Mortensen, Adrian Pasdar, Joseph Siravo, Richard Foronjy, John Ortiz, Ingrid Rogers and the late Argentinian comedic actor, Jorge Porcel(in his only American acting appearance) also put in good performances in this movie. And besides Al Pacino, other "Scarface" alumni such as Al Israel(Hector), Angel Salazar(Chi Chi), Cesar Cordova(Cuban cook), and Mike Moran(Nick the Pig)also make brief cameos in "Carlito's Way." Just like he perfected the Cuban accent for "Tony Montana" in "Scarface", Pacino perfects the Nuyorican accent for "Carlito Brigante" in "Carlito's Way", even if he is an Italian-American actor. Although "Carlito's Way: Rise to Power" was, in my opinion, a good prequel starring Jay Hernandez as a young "Carlito" in his early years, it will never compare to the original film from 1993. "Carlito's Way", in my opinion, is another great gangster film that should be included in the ranks with "The Godfather" trilogy, "Once Upon a Time in America", "Goodfellas", "Casino", "A Bronx Tale", and of course, "Scarface"(both versions from 1932 and 1983/Al Pacino respectively). Also, look out for a director's trademark that director Brian De Palma left in both movies that involves a gun that includes a silencer and an arm in a sling. Of course, both "Scarface" and "Carlito's Way" have to be watched together side by side to find that director's trademark along with its symbolism.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    10 years after Scarface
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Pusztai Norbi (noresz999)
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sorry for my bad English, I'm still learning the language. 10 years after Scarface, its director, and actor, made a gangster movie again, and its outcome isn't so far from the mentioned. They made it based on 2 books (by Edwin Torres), in 144 minutes, if we see on book adaptations, then it's a good time from 1 book, but not from 2. 2 books are compacted in 144 min. It's hard to do it well, but the creators made it very well. I could say without any overstatement, that it's in the top 10 all-time best gangster movies, I cannot see any problem with the movie. It has a lot of memorable scenes, it has some jokes, it's end very exciting, and heartbreaking, and it's not boring, for a minute, either. Furthermore, it's very strong in performances (Al Pacino, Sean Penn), directing (Brian De Palma), and screen writing (David Koepp), i think that it's the key of success. Who has seen this movie, that'll never forget it, simply brilliant. 9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Carlito the Pragmatic Gangster!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Stray Pez
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    DePalma's film is a masterpiece on many levels. For one, it is historically accurate to the letter. Carlito, a former smack peddler, is released from prison after a few years. When released, the drug business has changed. Cocaine, rather than heroine, is the drug of choice for most New Yorkers. It is more expensive and much more widely used than heroine. Before Cocaine, drug dealers were guys who operated on the fringes of society and catered to artists and musicians. In addition, Heroine was relatively cheap compared to Coke. This was the world Carlito was used to in the 50's and 60's. Yet he was somehow able to make a name for himself in this parched landscape through toughness, street smarts and pragmatism. Now released from prison, he finds out that the dope business changed while he was on the inside. Cocaine is easily available and in high demand. Drug users are now part of mainstream society. They include young professionals, politicians and athletes. As a result, drug dealers are not only able to make more money, they also become celebrities in their own right. This was so true about New York in the 1970's. Guys like Nikki Barnes made the cover of magazines because of Coke. It was ridiculous. Another important issue to point out is the escalating violence that results as well. Because Coke is more expensive, dealers are able to buy more guns from the windfall profits. DePalma does an excellent job incorporating this into a generation gap issue between Carlito and the newer criminals. Carlito is a killer and a thug. But he killed for survival. Perhaps his mothers death when he was young gave him more respect for human life or his generation as a whole valued life more than the new generation of gangsters. Carlito was born in a time when many people did not survive childhood. Some women still died during childbirth. World Wars also took the lives of many men. Since the new generation didn't experience death like he did, they value human life less. More guns in circulation feeds the beast of indifference. Pachanga said it best: "They shotgun you just to see you fly up in the air". Overall, a great movie with a tragic ending. The movie incorporates many themes about living a life of crime, changing social attitudes and capitalism. Highly recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    All About Carlito Brigante
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Carlito's Way is a crime drama based on the novels Carlito's Way and After Hours by Judge Edwin Torres. The film adaptation was written by David Koepp. It stars Al Pacino and Sean Penn,together with Penelope Ann Miller, Luis Guzm&aacute;n, John Leguizamo, and Viggo Mortensen in supporting roles. The story follows the life of Carlito Brigante after he is released from prison and vows to go straight and retire from criminal activities. However, unable to escape his past, he ends up being dragged into actions that got him imprisoned in the first place.The movie is narrated by Carlito himself, who explains his hopes, his strategies, and especially his mistakes. Brian De Palma directed the film. Carlito, a fabled heroin dealer, is released from prison after serving 5 years of a 30-year sentence. Tired and middle-aged, he wants out of the business as he has lost the juice for itfor the risks, the killing. It's the mid-'70s, the era of cocaine, fast sex, and disco glitz, and he takes a job running a dance club partially owned by his oldest and most trusted comrade, the coke-addled mob lawyer David Kleinfeld. Carlito's plan is to make some quick cash and move out of the country. But he is dragged down by his rootsby his hair-trigger survivor's instincts, honed while he was still a switchblade-wielding street kid, and by his loyalty to Kleinfeld, who tricks Carlito into helping him execute a mob hit. This film is one of the truly underrated films in the Brian De Palma and/or Al Pacino filmographies. It may have been unjustly derided and dismissed upon its theatrical debut during its year of release, but the it has received a cult following for many years now.The acting is great as the viewers are tickled by Sean Penn's weasely performance, Al Pacino's electric lead, or that crazy-cool chase through the NYC train station. Aside from its excellent performances,it has memorable moments, and some serious action and violent scenes. Overall,Carlito's Way is a smoother piece of filmmaking than Scarface, the only other picture De Palma has made with Pacino.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good classic Brian De Palma
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Panapaok
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Back to the gangster genre for Brian De Palma with Carlito's Way. After Scarface and The Untouchables he gives another pure example of his filmmaking and proves that he is a very strong and underrated master. Al Pacino gives another strong performance as Carlito Brigante and this is not unusual for him because he is in a well known field. But this time he is not another greedy and violent guy like Michael Corleone or Tony Montana but he is wise and clever and his goal is to retire from the business. Furthermore Sean Penn shows again his enormous talent by giving a strong performance as Carlto's rogue lawyer whose motives are not what they seem. He is rotten and cocaine addict and Penn pulls of this role brilliantly. This is a very good film both entertaining and touching and it is a must see for all De Palma's fans. Pacino's narration is an important key for the audience to realize who Carlito is. And, like a lot of gangster films, Carlito's Way proves that once a gangster means always a gangster no matter what.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A very good film... one of Pacinos best.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    richieandsam
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    CARLITO'S WAY I thought this was really good. The movie is about an ex con who gets released from prison and is determined to go straight. He is not interested in crime anymore. The problem is, he has got such a big reputation, that all the gangsters and criminals find him for advice, deals and help... some even want to kill him. The film stars Al Pacino, Sean Penn, Penelope Ann Miller, John Leguizamo, Ingrid Rogers & Luis Guzman. Everyone did a great job. Al is an amazing actor. He is over the top in some of his movies and there are scenes in this film where he is over the top too, but his performances always brings intensity. He is such an intense person and he can be a very scary person. But i think he is great! Sean Penn plays his lawyer... and at the beginning of the movie I felt he was a geek. Big curly hair, geeky glasses and he looks like he doesn't belong in the company of these gangsters... but as the film goes on he changes. The pressures of life gets to him and he can't handle it. His character has a hard time and i felt sorry for him towards the end of the film. I loved the action sequences. The gun fights and make-up were great. There was one scene where a guy gets shot in the face, it was so well shot. The way it was filmed made it look so real. It was a good crime drama/thriller... and I was pleasantly surprised at how good it is. I will give this film 7 out of 10. Al Pacino knows how to play a great gangster... and you can't help but feel sorry for him in this film because all he wants it to get out, but no matter what he does he just gets dragged back in. For more reviews, please like my Facebook page: https://www.facebook.com/pages/Ordinary-Person-Movie- Reviews/456572047728204?ref=hl
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pacino works his magic yet again!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pinturicchio_juve
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I just love Brian De Palma films. They're just so good to watch and have the right mix of good dialogues and an appealing storyline to get the viewer hooked. Scarface and The Untouchables would serve as worthy examples to this fact, and now that I've watched it, I guess Carlito's Way does too. The film is an adaptation of Edwin Torres' novel "After Hours" which follows the story of ex-con/gangster/drug peddler Carlito Brigante (played by Al Pacino), who tries to shun away from a life of crime after being released from prison. Brigante had in actuality been serving a thirty-to-life sentence, which had gotten reduced to five years, owing to the influence his lawyer, David Kleinfeld (Sean Penn) had with the jury. Once out on the streets, Carlito pledges to live life the right way and reluctantly agrees to co-own a nightclub so that he can save just enough money to leave New York and start a car rental business. But inevitably, he's lured into crime once again, and how he fights the odds forms the rest of the plot. One thing that struck me as I watched the film was that everything was very direct. There is not really much for the audience to interpret. Each character is sketched out quite well at the beginning itself, and one kind of knows what he/she would tend to do under the given circumstances. For example, Sean Penn's character, David Kleinfeld is exposed as a corrupt lawyer, and subsequent events throughout the film show him as one, with all his shady dealings and money laundering activities coming back to haunt him. I liked this about the movie, because one is not left wondering what a particular scene means, or what that character was trying to say. Its all said and done. There. Take it or leave it. Of course, this kind of storytelling will not work in all situations, but here, it feels just right. Then there's that aura of the gangster about Carlito. In the beginning, he accompanies his cousin to a drug dealer's hangout for a transaction. As the scene develops, one can feel Carlito sensing that there's something amiss about the place. The tension is brilliantly captured by De Palma here and you can just feel Pacino getting into the skin of the gangster he's portraying. He knows exactly what's going to happen, he's prepared for it, and when it does happen, he knows what to do. This gut instinct comes to the fore in the latter half of the film as well and is part of the reason why this films works for me. There are a lot of scenes and characters which contribute to making the film what it is, such as John Leguizamo as "Benny Blanco" the young upstart who tries to get chummy with Carlito but fails, Gail, Carlito's former lover, with whom he rekindles his relationship and Luiz Guzman as "Pachanga", Carlito's right hand man. But to me, this one is Pacino all the way. He carries the film on his shoulders and commands respect in almost every frame. You can see that he's always in control and this again points to the direct nature of the storyline. The De Palma-Pacino-gangster plot combine gives rise to obvious comparisons with Scarface. But the two are so different. While Tony Montana is just a drug dealer, Carlito Brigante is much more than that. He's a larger than life personality with a heart, remorse, and a conscience. He believes he has a shot at redemption. Montana has none of this. He's arrogant, ruthless and has absolutely no feelings of guilt or regret. The differing nature of their characters make the two films widely different, thus making a comparison would just be a wasteful exercise. The climax sequence, shot at a railway station does bring back scenes reminiscent of The Untouchables, though the events that unfold in the two films are entirely different. Carlito's Way might have its share of flaws which may not put it in the league of gangster flicks such as Goodfellas or The Godfather movies, but it is still a classic, and a highly underrated one at that. De Palma himself is a hugely underrated director (It is a surprise to me how he hasn't won an Oscar yet), and this film just underlines his capability. This one's a must watch for all fans of mob films, but I think that at its very basic level, it's just a story about a man with a heart.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a good movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Hooman Moeen (che-hooman)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    this film have a very good story.AL PACINO have a very good film i ever see.this film show the good guy why have a bad life this movie is a very good romance and crime\gangster i see.good drama i really like that.HAS A A LITTLE SCARFACE REUNION IN IT. SEAN PENN WUZ GREAT AS THE CORRUPT LAWYER. THE ENDING WUZ GREAT BUT TRAGIC BECAUSE YOU END UP PULLING FOR MR BRIGANTE (AL PACINO) DESPITE HIS CRIMINAL PAST.a lot of action is in this movie.Sean Penn plays a good part as a lawyer who got in too deep with the bad guys.he ends up getting shot in the hospital. i just wish there was a different end to this movie.....i wont give it away.if you like Al pacino and Sean Penn,then this movie is a must see.....
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A great story and film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    evas428
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of my favorite movies of all time! Amazing performance by Sean Penn, who really carries the film forward despite the powerhouse presence of the great Al Pacino. The characters were very well written and performed beautifully, especially from the less know (at the time) Vigo Mortensen and John Leguizamo. While this can be considered a "gangster movie", the love story of Carlito and Gale serve as the perfect motivation for the title character to escape the street life. This is much different than The Godfather. Overall, I highly recommend this film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Carlito Goes All The Way-Carlito's Way ****
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Simply put, an outrageously great gangster film with Al Pacino, as usual, turning in still another phenomenal performance as a Puerto Rican gangster who wants to grow straight, but is eventually pulled into a situation which causes tragedy for him. He is equally matched by Sean Penn as a cocaine addicted lawyer who draws him in and Penelope Ann Miller, the girl he loved but tragically could not have. It's basically a well-crafted story of environment having its hold on people and trapping them once they have committed crimes. The music at the club that Pacino owns is absolutely fabulous with an array of popular songs for the period.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The "so-called" sequel to Scarface
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    aaronalmarez
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just like "Casino" has been considered the "so-called" sequel to "Goodfellas", in my opinion, "Carlito's Way" is basically the "so-called" sequel to "Scarface." The reasons for that explanation is because of the stars and similar story lines of each movie. With "Goodfellas" and "Casino", both movies starred Robert De Niro and Joe Pesci and were directed by Martin Scorsese. When it comes to both "Scarface" and "Carlito's Way", both movies star Al Pacino and were directed by Brian De Palma. And even actors that played minor roles in one movie appear in some capacity in their counterparts. Also in the past, there were weekends were I would watch both sets of movies together but on separate days from each other. But of course, there are differences between "Tony Montana" and "Carlito Brigante." "Tony Montana" was basically a Cuban refugee hoodlum who along with other Cuban refugees, arrives in Miami, Florida during the "Mariel Boat Lift" in 1980 and within a few years becomes the top drug lord in Miami and uses cocaine as a source of power. But that particular drug also contributes to his downfall in the end. With "Carlito Brigante", he's a Nuyorican(Puerto Rican New Yorker) ex drug lord who returns to the streets of New York City in 1975 after serving 5 years of a 30 year prison sentence. Now planning to live a legitimate crime free life, he also tries to rekindle his relationship with Gail(Penelope Ann Miller) that he had before his imprisonment. But there are two causes to Carlito's downfall. The first is his lawyer, David Kleinfeld(Sean Penn)who not only has a very bad cocaine addiction but is corrupt and is also a retaliatory target of incarcerated Italian mob boss, Tony "Tony T" Taglialucci(Frank Minucci), another one of his clients. Carlito's second downfall is "Benny Blanco" who is a young, inexperienced punk who is trying to rise up in the drug trade by trying to surpass Carlito and is played by actor/comedian John Leguizamo, respectively. But in the end, is it Carlito himself that contributes to his downfall just for having a loyal trust in Kleinfeld and Pachanga(Luis Guzman), an old friend from his past. "Carlito's Way" was released in 1993 for which it was 10 years apart from "Scarface"(which was released in 1983). And another difference between each movie is the musical score. With "Scarface", the score was conducted by Giorgio Moroder and was synthesizer based. With "Carlito's Way", the score was conducted by Patrick Doyle and was more symphonic/orchestra based. But the soundtrack also consisted of songs from 1970's Disco groups such as KC and the Sunshine Band, The O Jays, The Hues Corporation, The Bee Gees, LaBelle, etc. that fit the time period of the movie(1975). And the soundtrack also consisted of songs from Latin music artists such as Celia Cruz, Hector Lavoe, Willie Colon, and Santana as well. And besides the other aforementioned actors, the other actors that comprised the cast such as James Rebhorn, Viggo Mortensen, Adrian Pasdar, Joseph Siravo, Richard Foronjy, John Ortiz, Ingrid Rogers and the late Argentinian comedic actor, Jorge Porcel(in his only American acting appearance) also put in good performances in this movie. And besides Al Pacino, other "Scarface" alumni such as Al Israel(Hector), Angel Salazar(Chi Chi), Cesar Cordova(Cuban cook), and Mike Moran(Nick the Pig)also make brief cameos in "Carlito's Way." Just like he perfected the Cuban accent for "Tony Montana" in "Scarface", Pacino perfects the Nuyorican accent for "Carlito Brigante" in "Carlito's Way", even if he is an Italian-American actor. Although "Carlito's Way: Rise to Power" was, in my opinion, a good prequel starring Jay Hernandez as a young "Carlito" in his early years, it will never compare to the original film from 1993. "Carlito's Way", in my opinion, is another great gangster film that should be included in the ranks with "The Godfather" trilogy, "Once Upon a Time in America", "Goodfellas", "Casino", "A Bronx Tale", and of course, "Scarface"(both versions from 1932 and 1983/Al Pacino respectively). Also, look out for a director's trademark that director Brian De Palma left in both movies that involves a gun that includes a silencer and an arm in a sling. Of course, both "Scarface" and "Carlito's Way" have to be watched together side by side to find that director's trademark along with its symbolism.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    10 years after Scarface
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Pusztai Norbi (noresz999)
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sorry for my bad English, I'm still learning the language. 10 years after Scarface, its director, and actor, made a gangster movie again, and its outcome isn't so far from the mentioned. They made it based on 2 books (by Edwin Torres), in 144 minutes, if we see on book adaptations, then it's a good time from 1 book, but not from 2. 2 books are compacted in 144 min. It's hard to do it well, but the creators made it very well. I could say without any overstatement, that it's in the top 10 all-time best gangster movies, I cannot see any problem with the movie. It has a lot of memorable scenes, it has some jokes, it's end very exciting, and heartbreaking, and it's not boring, for a minute, either. Furthermore, it's very strong in performances (Al Pacino, Sean Penn), directing (Brian De Palma), and screen writing (David Koepp), i think that it's the key of success. Who has seen this movie, that'll never forget it, simply brilliant. 9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Carlito the Pragmatic Gangster!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Stray Pez
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    DePalma's film is a masterpiece on many levels. For one, it is historically accurate to the letter. Carlito, a former smack peddler, is released from prison after a few years. When released, the drug business has changed. Cocaine, rather than heroine, is the drug of choice for most New Yorkers. It is more expensive and much more widely used than heroine. Before Cocaine, drug dealers were guys who operated on the fringes of society and catered to artists and musicians. In addition, Heroine was relatively cheap compared to Coke. This was the world Carlito was used to in the 50's and 60's. Yet he was somehow able to make a name for himself in this parched landscape through toughness, street smarts and pragmatism. Now released from prison, he finds out that the dope business changed while he was on the inside. Cocaine is easily available and in high demand. Drug users are now part of mainstream society. They include young professionals, politicians and athletes. As a result, drug dealers are not only able to make more money, they also become celebrities in their own right. This was so true about New York in the 1970's. Guys like Nikki Barnes made the cover of magazines because of Coke. It was ridiculous. Another important issue to point out is the escalating violence that results as well. Because Coke is more expensive, dealers are able to buy more guns from the windfall profits. DePalma does an excellent job incorporating this into a generation gap issue between Carlito and the newer criminals. Carlito is a killer and a thug. But he killed for survival. Perhaps his mothers death when he was young gave him more respect for human life or his generation as a whole valued life more than the new generation of gangsters. Carlito was born in a time when many people did not survive childhood. Some women still died during childbirth. World Wars also took the lives of many men. Since the new generation didn't experience death like he did, they value human life less. More guns in circulation feeds the beast of indifference. Pachanga said it best: "They shotgun you just to see you fly up in the air". Overall, a great movie with a tragic ending. The movie incorporates many themes about living a life of crime, changing social attitudes and capitalism. Highly recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    All About Carlito Brigante
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Carlito's Way is a crime drama based on the novels Carlito's Way and After Hours by Judge Edwin Torres. The film adaptation was written by David Koepp. It stars Al Pacino and Sean Penn,together with Penelope Ann Miller, Luis Guzm&aacute;n, John Leguizamo, and Viggo Mortensen in supporting roles. The story follows the life of Carlito Brigante after he is released from prison and vows to go straight and retire from criminal activities. However, unable to escape his past, he ends up being dragged into actions that got him imprisoned in the first place.The movie is narrated by Carlito himself, who explains his hopes, his strategies, and especially his mistakes. Brian De Palma directed the film. Carlito, a fabled heroin dealer, is released from prison after serving 5 years of a 30-year sentence. Tired and middle-aged, he wants out of the business as he has lost the juice for itfor the risks, the killing. It's the mid-'70s, the era of cocaine, fast sex, and disco glitz, and he takes a job running a dance club partially owned by his oldest and most trusted comrade, the coke-addled mob lawyer David Kleinfeld. Carlito's plan is to make some quick cash and move out of the country. But he is dragged down by his rootsby his hair-trigger survivor's instincts, honed while he was still a switchblade-wielding street kid, and by his loyalty to Kleinfeld, who tricks Carlito into helping him execute a mob hit. This film is one of the truly underrated films in the Brian De Palma and/or Al Pacino filmographies. It may have been unjustly derided and dismissed upon its theatrical debut during its year of release, but the it has received a cult following for many years now.The acting is great as the viewers are tickled by Sean Penn's weasely performance, Al Pacino's electric lead, or that crazy-cool chase through the NYC train station. Aside from its excellent performances,it has memorable moments, and some serious action and violent scenes. Overall,Carlito's Way is a smoother piece of filmmaking than Scarface, the only other picture De Palma has made with Pacino.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good classic Brian De Palma
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Panapaok
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Back to the gangster genre for Brian De Palma with Carlito's Way. After Scarface and The Untouchables he gives another pure example of his filmmaking and proves that he is a very strong and underrated master. Al Pacino gives another strong performance as Carlito Brigante and this is not unusual for him because he is in a well known field. But this time he is not another greedy and violent guy like Michael Corleone or Tony Montana but he is wise and clever and his goal is to retire from the business. Furthermore Sean Penn shows again his enormous talent by giving a strong performance as Carlto's rogue lawyer whose motives are not what they seem. He is rotten and cocaine addict and Penn pulls of this role brilliantly. This is a very good film both entertaining and touching and it is a must see for all De Palma's fans. Pacino's narration is an important key for the audience to realize who Carlito is. And, like a lot of gangster films, Carlito's Way proves that once a gangster means always a gangster no matter what.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A very good film... one of Pacinos best.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    richieandsam
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    CARLITO'S WAY I thought this was really good. The movie is about an ex con who gets released from prison and is determined to go straight. He is not interested in crime anymore. The problem is, he has got such a big reputation, that all the gangsters and criminals find him for advice, deals and help... some even want to kill him. The film stars Al Pacino, Sean Penn, Penelope Ann Miller, John Leguizamo, Ingrid Rogers & Luis Guzman. Everyone did a great job. Al is an amazing actor. He is over the top in some of his movies and there are scenes in this film where he is over the top too, but his performances always brings intensity. He is such an intense person and he can be a very scary person. But i think he is great! Sean Penn plays his lawyer... and at the beginning of the movie I felt he was a geek. Big curly hair, geeky glasses and he looks like he doesn't belong in the company of these gangsters... but as the film goes on he changes. The pressures of life gets to him and he can't handle it. His character has a hard time and i felt sorry for him towards the end of the film. I loved the action sequences. The gun fights and make-up were great. There was one scene where a guy gets shot in the face, it was so well shot. The way it was filmed made it look so real. It was a good crime drama/thriller... and I was pleasantly surprised at how good it is. I will give this film 7 out of 10. Al Pacino knows how to play a great gangster... and you can't help but feel sorry for him in this film because all he wants it to get out, but no matter what he does he just gets dragged back in. For more reviews, please like my Facebook page: https://www.facebook.com/pages/Ordinary-Person-Movie- Reviews/456572047728204?ref=hl
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pacino works his magic yet again!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pinturicchio_juve
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I just love Brian De Palma films. They're just so good to watch and have the right mix of good dialogues and an appealing storyline to get the viewer hooked. Scarface and The Untouchables would serve as worthy examples to this fact, and now that I've watched it, I guess Carlito's Way does too. The film is an adaptation of Edwin Torres' novel "After Hours" which follows the story of ex-con/gangster/drug peddler Carlito Brigante (played by Al Pacino), who tries to shun away from a life of crime after being released from prison. Brigante had in actuality been serving a thirty-to-life sentence, which had gotten reduced to five years, owing to the influence his lawyer, David Kleinfeld (Sean Penn) had with the jury. Once out on the streets, Carlito pledges to live life the right way and reluctantly agrees to co-own a nightclub so that he can save just enough money to leave New York and start a car rental business. But inevitably, he's lured into crime once again, and how he fights the odds forms the rest of the plot. One thing that struck me as I watched the film was that everything was very direct. There is not really much for the audience to interpret. Each character is sketched out quite well at the beginning itself, and one kind of knows what he/she would tend to do under the given circumstances. For example, Sean Penn's character, David Kleinfeld is exposed as a corrupt lawyer, and subsequent events throughout the film show him as one, with all his shady dealings and money laundering activities coming back to haunt him. I liked this about the movie, because one is not left wondering what a particular scene means, or what that character was trying to say. Its all said and done. There. Take it or leave it. Of course, this kind of storytelling will not work in all situations, but here, it feels just right. Then there's that aura of the gangster about Carlito. In the beginning, he accompanies his cousin to a drug dealer's hangout for a transaction. As the scene develops, one can feel Carlito sensing that there's something amiss about the place. The tension is brilliantly captured by De Palma here and you can just feel Pacino getting into the skin of the gangster he's portraying. He knows exactly what's going to happen, he's prepared for it, and when it does happen, he knows what to do. This gut instinct comes to the fore in the latter half of the film as well and is part of the reason why this films works for me. There are a lot of scenes and characters which contribute to making the film what it is, such as John Leguizamo as "Benny Blanco" the young upstart who tries to get chummy with Carlito but fails, Gail, Carlito's former lover, with whom he rekindles his relationship and Luiz Guzman as "Pachanga", Carlito's right hand man. But to me, this one is Pacino all the way. He carries the film on his shoulders and commands respect in almost every frame. You can see that he's always in control and this again points to the direct nature of the storyline. The De Palma-Pacino-gangster plot combine gives rise to obvious comparisons with Scarface. But the two are so different. While Tony Montana is just a drug dealer, Carlito Brigante is much more than that. He's a larger than life personality with a heart, remorse, and a conscience. He believes he has a shot at redemption. Montana has none of this. He's arrogant, ruthless and has absolutely no feelings of guilt or regret. The differing nature of their characters make the two films widely different, thus making a comparison would just be a wasteful exercise. The climax sequence, shot at a railway station does bring back scenes reminiscent of The Untouchables, though the events that unfold in the two films are entirely different. Carlito's Way might have its share of flaws which may not put it in the league of gangster flicks such as Goodfellas or The Godfather movies, but it is still a classic, and a highly underrated one at that. De Palma himself is a hugely underrated director (It is a surprise to me how he hasn't won an Oscar yet), and this film just underlines his capability. This one's a must watch for all fans of mob films, but I think that at its very basic level, it's just a story about a man with a heart.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a good movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Hooman Moeen (che-hooman)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    this film have a very good story.AL PACINO have a very good film i ever see.this film show the good guy why have a bad life this movie is a very good romance and crime\gangster i see.good drama i really like that.HAS A A LITTLE SCARFACE REUNION IN IT. SEAN PENN WUZ GREAT AS THE CORRUPT LAWYER. THE ENDING WUZ GREAT BUT TRAGIC BECAUSE YOU END UP PULLING FOR MR BRIGANTE (AL PACINO) DESPITE HIS CRIMINAL PAST.a lot of action is in this movie.Sean Penn plays a good part as a lawyer who got in too deep with the bad guys.he ends up getting shot in the hospital. i just wish there was a different end to this movie.....i wont give it away.if you like Al pacino and Sean Penn,then this movie is a must see.....
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A great story and film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    evas428
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of my favorite movies of all time! Amazing performance by Sean Penn, who really carries the film forward despite the powerhouse presence of the great Al Pacino. The characters were very well written and performed beautifully, especially from the less know (at the time) Vigo Mortensen and John Leguizamo. While this can be considered a "gangster movie", the love story of Carlito and Gale serve as the perfect motivation for the title character to escape the street life. This is much different than The Godfather. Overall, I highly recommend this film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Carlito Goes All The Way-Carlito's Way ****
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Simply put, an outrageously great gangster film with Al Pacino, as usual, turning in still another phenomenal performance as a Puerto Rican gangster who wants to grow straight, but is eventually pulled into a situation which causes tragedy for him. He is equally matched by Sean Penn as a cocaine addicted lawyer who draws him in and Penelope Ann Miller, the girl he loved but tragically could not have. It's basically a well-crafted story of environment having its hold on people and trapping them once they have committed crimes. The music at the club that Pacino owns is absolutely fabulous with an array of popular songs for the period.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The "so-called" sequel to Scarface
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    aaronalmarez
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just like "Casino" has been considered the "so-called" sequel to "Goodfellas", in my opinion, "Carlito's Way" is basically the "so-called" sequel to "Scarface." The reasons for that explanation is because of the stars and similar story lines of each movie. With "Goodfellas" and "Casino", both movies starred Robert De Niro and Joe Pesci and were directed by Martin Scorsese. When it comes to both "Scarface" and "Carlito's Way", both movies star Al Pacino and were directed by Brian De Palma. And even actors that played minor roles in one movie appear in some capacity in their counterparts. Also in the past, there were weekends were I would watch both sets of movies together but on separate days from each other. But of course, there are differences between "Tony Montana" and "Carlito Brigante." "Tony Montana" was basically a Cuban refugee hoodlum who along with other Cuban refugees, arrives in Miami, Florida during the "Mariel Boat Lift" in 1980 and within a few years becomes the top drug lord in Miami and uses cocaine as a source of power. But that particular drug also contributes to his downfall in the end. With "Carlito Brigante", he's a Nuyorican(Puerto Rican New Yorker) ex drug lord who returns to the streets of New York City in 1975 after serving 5 years of a 30 year prison sentence. Now planning to live a legitimate crime free life, he also tries to rekindle his relationship with Gail(Penelope Ann Miller) that he had before his imprisonment. But there are two causes to Carlito's downfall. The first is his lawyer, David Kleinfeld(Sean Penn)who not only has a very bad cocaine addiction but is corrupt and is also a retaliatory target of incarcerated Italian mob boss, Tony "Tony T" Taglialucci(Frank Minucci), another one of his clients. Carlito's second downfall is "Benny Blanco" who is a young, inexperienced punk who is trying to rise up in the drug trade by trying to surpass Carlito and is played by actor/comedian John Leguizamo, respectively. But in the end, is it Carlito himself that contributes to his downfall just for having a loyal trust in Kleinfeld and Pachanga(Luis Guzman), an old friend from his past. "Carlito's Way" was released in 1993 for which it was 10 years apart from "Scarface"(which was released in 1983). And another difference between each movie is the musical score. With "Scarface", the score was conducted by Giorgio Moroder and was synthesizer based. With "Carlito's Way", the score was conducted by Patrick Doyle and was more symphonic/orchestra based. But the soundtrack also consisted of songs from 1970's Disco groups such as KC and the Sunshine Band, The O Jays, The Hues Corporation, The Bee Gees, LaBelle, etc. that fit the time period of the movie(1975). And the soundtrack also consisted of songs from Latin music artists such as Celia Cruz, Hector Lavoe, Willie Colon, and Santana as well. And besides the other aforementioned actors, the other actors that comprised the cast such as James Rebhorn, Viggo Mortensen, Adrian Pasdar, Joseph Siravo, Richard Foronjy, John Ortiz, Ingrid Rogers and the late Argentinian comedic actor, Jorge Porcel(in his only American acting appearance) also put in good performances in this movie. And besides Al Pacino, other "Scarface" alumni such as Al Israel(Hector), Angel Salazar(Chi Chi), Cesar Cordova(Cuban cook), and Mike Moran(Nick the Pig)also make brief cameos in "Carlito's Way." Just like he perfected the Cuban accent for "Tony Montana" in "Scarface", Pacino perfects the Nuyorican accent for "Carlito Brigante" in "Carlito's Way", even if he is an Italian-American actor. Although "Carlito's Way: Rise to Power" was, in my opinion, a good prequel starring Jay Hernandez as a young "Carlito" in his early years, it will never compare to the original film from 1993. "Carlito's Way", in my opinion, is another great gangster film that should be included in the ranks with "The Godfather" trilogy, "Once Upon a Time in America", "Goodfellas", "Casino", "A Bronx Tale", and of course, "Scarface"(both versions from 1932 and 1983/Al Pacino respectively). Also, look out for a director's trademark that director Brian De Palma left in both movies that involves a gun that includes a silencer and an arm in a sling. Of course, both "Scarface" and "Carlito's Way" have to be watched together side by side to find that director's trademark along with its symbolism.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    10 years after Scarface
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Pusztai Norbi (noresz999)
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sorry for my bad English, I'm still learning the language. 10 years after Scarface, its director, and actor, made a gangster movie again, and its outcome isn't so far from the mentioned. They made it based on 2 books (by Edwin Torres), in 144 minutes, if we see on book adaptations, then it's a good time from 1 book, but not from 2. 2 books are compacted in 144 min. It's hard to do it well, but the creators made it very well. I could say without any overstatement, that it's in the top 10 all-time best gangster movies, I cannot see any problem with the movie. It has a lot of memorable scenes, it has some jokes, it's end very exciting, and heartbreaking, and it's not boring, for a minute, either. Furthermore, it's very strong in performances (Al Pacino, Sean Penn), directing (Brian De Palma), and screen writing (David Koepp), i think that it's the key of success. Who has seen this movie, that'll never forget it, simply brilliant. 9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Carlito the Pragmatic Gangster!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Stray Pez
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    DePalma's film is a masterpiece on many levels. For one, it is historically accurate to the letter. Carlito, a former smack peddler, is released from prison after a few years. When released, the drug business has changed. Cocaine, rather than heroine, is the drug of choice for most New Yorkers. It is more expensive and much more widely used than heroine. Before Cocaine, drug dealers were guys who operated on the fringes of society and catered to artists and musicians. In addition, Heroine was relatively cheap compared to Coke. This was the world Carlito was used to in the 50's and 60's. Yet he was somehow able to make a name for himself in this parched landscape through toughness, street smarts and pragmatism. Now released from prison, he finds out that the dope business changed while he was on the inside. Cocaine is easily available and in high demand. Drug users are now part of mainstream society. They include young professionals, politicians and athletes. As a result, drug dealers are not only able to make more money, they also become celebrities in their own right. This was so true about New York in the 1970's. Guys like Nikki Barnes made the cover of magazines because of Coke. It was ridiculous. Another important issue to point out is the escalating violence that results as well. Because Coke is more expensive, dealers are able to buy more guns from the windfall profits. DePalma does an excellent job incorporating this into a generation gap issue between Carlito and the newer criminals. Carlito is a killer and a thug. But he killed for survival. Perhaps his mothers death when he was young gave him more respect for human life or his generation as a whole valued life more than the new generation of gangsters. Carlito was born in a time when many people did not survive childhood. Some women still died during childbirth. World Wars also took the lives of many men. Since the new generation didn't experience death like he did, they value human life less. More guns in circulation feeds the beast of indifference. Pachanga said it best: "They shotgun you just to see you fly up in the air". Overall, a great movie with a tragic ending. The movie incorporates many themes about living a life of crime, changing social attitudes and capitalism. Highly recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    All About Carlito Brigante
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Carlito's Way is a crime drama based on the novels Carlito's Way and After Hours by Judge Edwin Torres. The film adaptation was written by David Koepp. It stars Al Pacino and Sean Penn,together with Penelope Ann Miller, Luis Guzm&aacute;n, John Leguizamo, and Viggo Mortensen in supporting roles. The story follows the life of Carlito Brigante after he is released from prison and vows to go straight and retire from criminal activities. However, unable to escape his past, he ends up being dragged into actions that got him imprisoned in the first place.The movie is narrated by Carlito himself, who explains his hopes, his strategies, and especially his mistakes. Brian De Palma directed the film. Carlito, a fabled heroin dealer, is released from prison after serving 5 years of a 30-year sentence. Tired and middle-aged, he wants out of the business as he has lost the juice for itfor the risks, the killing. It's the mid-'70s, the era of cocaine, fast sex, and disco glitz, and he takes a job running a dance club partially owned by his oldest and most trusted comrade, the coke-addled mob lawyer David Kleinfeld. Carlito's plan is to make some quick cash and move out of the country. But he is dragged down by his rootsby his hair-trigger survivor's instincts, honed while he was still a switchblade-wielding street kid, and by his loyalty to Kleinfeld, who tricks Carlito into helping him execute a mob hit. This film is one of the truly underrated films in the Brian De Palma and/or Al Pacino filmographies. It may have been unjustly derided and dismissed upon its theatrical debut during its year of release, but the it has received a cult following for many years now.The acting is great as the viewers are tickled by Sean Penn's weasely performance, Al Pacino's electric lead, or that crazy-cool chase through the NYC train station. Aside from its excellent performances,it has memorable moments, and some serious action and violent scenes. Overall,Carlito's Way is a smoother piece of filmmaking than Scarface, the only other picture De Palma has made with Pacino.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good classic Brian De Palma
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Panapaok
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Back to the gangster genre for Brian De Palma with Carlito's Way. After Scarface and The Untouchables he gives another pure example of his filmmaking and proves that he is a very strong and underrated master. Al Pacino gives another strong performance as Carlito Brigante and this is not unusual for him because he is in a well known field. But this time he is not another greedy and violent guy like Michael Corleone or Tony Montana but he is wise and clever and his goal is to retire from the business. Furthermore Sean Penn shows again his enormous talent by giving a strong performance as Carlto's rogue lawyer whose motives are not what they seem. He is rotten and cocaine addict and Penn pulls of this role brilliantly. This is a very good film both entertaining and touching and it is a must see for all De Palma's fans. Pacino's narration is an important key for the audience to realize who Carlito is. And, like a lot of gangster films, Carlito's Way proves that once a gangster means always a gangster no matter what.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A very good film... one of Pacinos best.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    richieandsam
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    CARLITO'S WAY I thought this was really good. The movie is about an ex con who gets released from prison and is determined to go straight. He is not interested in crime anymore. The problem is, he has got such a big reputation, that all the gangsters and criminals find him for advice, deals and help... some even want to kill him. The film stars Al Pacino, Sean Penn, Penelope Ann Miller, John Leguizamo, Ingrid Rogers & Luis Guzman. Everyone did a great job. Al is an amazing actor. He is over the top in some of his movies and there are scenes in this film where he is over the top too, but his performances always brings intensity. He is such an intense person and he can be a very scary person. But i think he is great! Sean Penn plays his lawyer... and at the beginning of the movie I felt he was a geek. Big curly hair, geeky glasses and he looks like he doesn't belong in the company of these gangsters... but as the film goes on he changes. The pressures of life gets to him and he can't handle it. His character has a hard time and i felt sorry for him towards the end of the film. I loved the action sequences. The gun fights and make-up were great. There was one scene where a guy gets shot in the face, it was so well shot. The way it was filmed made it look so real. It was a good crime drama/thriller... and I was pleasantly surprised at how good it is. I will give this film 7 out of 10. Al Pacino knows how to play a great gangster... and you can't help but feel sorry for him in this film because all he wants it to get out, but no matter what he does he just gets dragged back in. For more reviews, please like my Facebook page: https://www.facebook.com/pages/Ordinary-Person-Movie- Reviews/456572047728204?ref=hl
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pacino works his magic yet again!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pinturicchio_juve
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I just love Brian De Palma films. They're just so good to watch and have the right mix of good dialogues and an appealing storyline to get the viewer hooked. Scarface and The Untouchables would serve as worthy examples to this fact, and now that I've watched it, I guess Carlito's Way does too. The film is an adaptation of Edwin Torres' novel "After Hours" which follows the story of ex-con/gangster/drug peddler Carlito Brigante (played by Al Pacino), who tries to shun away from a life of crime after being released from prison. Brigante had in actuality been serving a thirty-to-life sentence, which had gotten reduced to five years, owing to the influence his lawyer, David Kleinfeld (Sean Penn) had with the jury. Once out on the streets, Carlito pledges to live life the right way and reluctantly agrees to co-own a nightclub so that he can save just enough money to leave New York and start a car rental business. But inevitably, he's lured into crime once again, and how he fights the odds forms the rest of the plot. One thing that struck me as I watched the film was that everything was very direct. There is not really much for the audience to interpret. Each character is sketched out quite well at the beginning itself, and one kind of knows what he/she would tend to do under the given circumstances. For example, Sean Penn's character, David Kleinfeld is exposed as a corrupt lawyer, and subsequent events throughout the film show him as one, with all his shady dealings and money laundering activities coming back to haunt him. I liked this about the movie, because one is not left wondering what a particular scene means, or what that character was trying to say. Its all said and done. There. Take it or leave it. Of course, this kind of storytelling will not work in all situations, but here, it feels just right. Then there's that aura of the gangster about Carlito. In the beginning, he accompanies his cousin to a drug dealer's hangout for a transaction. As the scene develops, one can feel Carlito sensing that there's something amiss about the place. The tension is brilliantly captured by De Palma here and you can just feel Pacino getting into the skin of the gangster he's portraying. He knows exactly what's going to happen, he's prepared for it, and when it does happen, he knows what to do. This gut instinct comes to the fore in the latter half of the film as well and is part of the reason why this films works for me. There are a lot of scenes and characters which contribute to making the film what it is, such as John Leguizamo as "Benny Blanco" the young upstart who tries to get chummy with Carlito but fails, Gail, Carlito's former lover, with whom he rekindles his relationship and Luiz Guzman as "Pachanga", Carlito's right hand man. But to me, this one is Pacino all the way. He carries the film on his shoulders and commands respect in almost every frame. You can see that he's always in control and this again points to the direct nature of the storyline. The De Palma-Pacino-gangster plot combine gives rise to obvious comparisons with Scarface. But the two are so different. While Tony Montana is just a drug dealer, Carlito Brigante is much more than that. He's a larger than life personality with a heart, remorse, and a conscience. He believes he has a shot at redemption. Montana has none of this. He's arrogant, ruthless and has absolutely no feelings of guilt or regret. The differing nature of their characters make the two films widely different, thus making a comparison would just be a wasteful exercise. The climax sequence, shot at a railway station does bring back scenes reminiscent of The Untouchables, though the events that unfold in the two films are entirely different. Carlito's Way might have its share of flaws which may not put it in the league of gangster flicks such as Goodfellas or The Godfather movies, but it is still a classic, and a highly underrated one at that. De Palma himself is a hugely underrated director (It is a surprise to me how he hasn't won an Oscar yet), and this film just underlines his capability. This one's a must watch for all fans of mob films, but I think that at its very basic level, it's just a story about a man with a heart.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a good movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Hooman Moeen (che-hooman)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    this film have a very good story.AL PACINO have a very good film i ever see.this film show the good guy why have a bad life this movie is a very good romance and crime\gangster i see.good drama i really like that.HAS A A LITTLE SCARFACE REUNION IN IT. SEAN PENN WUZ GREAT AS THE CORRUPT LAWYER. THE ENDING WUZ GREAT BUT TRAGIC BECAUSE YOU END UP PULLING FOR MR BRIGANTE (AL PACINO) DESPITE HIS CRIMINAL PAST.a lot of action is in this movie.Sean Penn plays a good part as a lawyer who got in too deep with the bad guys.he ends up getting shot in the hospital. i just wish there was a different end to this movie.....i wont give it away.if you like Al pacino and Sean Penn,then this movie is a must see.....
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A great story and film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    evas428
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of my favorite movies of all time! Amazing performance by Sean Penn, who really carries the film forward despite the powerhouse presence of the great Al Pacino. The characters were very well written and performed beautifully, especially from the less know (at the time) Vigo Mortensen and John Leguizamo. While this can be considered a "gangster movie", the love story of Carlito and Gale serve as the perfect motivation for the title character to escape the street life. This is much different than The Godfather. Overall, I highly recommend this film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Carlito Goes All The Way-Carlito's Way ****
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Simply put, an outrageously great gangster film with Al Pacino, as usual, turning in still another phenomenal performance as a Puerto Rican gangster who wants to grow straight, but is eventually pulled into a situation which causes tragedy for him. He is equally matched by Sean Penn as a cocaine addicted lawyer who draws him in and Penelope Ann Miller, the girl he loved but tragically could not have. It's basically a well-crafted story of environment having its hold on people and trapping them once they have committed crimes. The music at the club that Pacino owns is absolutely fabulous with an array of popular songs for the period.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The "so-called" sequel to Scarface
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    aaronalmarez
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just like "Casino" has been considered the "so-called" sequel to "Goodfellas", in my opinion, "Carlito's Way" is basically the "so-called" sequel to "Scarface." The reasons for that explanation is because of the stars and similar story lines of each movie. With "Goodfellas" and "Casino", both movies starred Robert De Niro and Joe Pesci and were directed by Martin Scorsese. When it comes to both "Scarface" and "Carlito's Way", both movies star Al Pacino and were directed by Brian De Palma. And even actors that played minor roles in one movie appear in some capacity in their counterparts. Also in the past, there were weekends were I would watch both sets of movies together but on separate days from each other. But of course, there are differences between "Tony Montana" and "Carlito Brigante." "Tony Montana" was basically a Cuban refugee hoodlum who along with other Cuban refugees, arrives in Miami, Florida during the "Mariel Boat Lift" in 1980 and within a few years becomes the top drug lord in Miami and uses cocaine as a source of power. But that particular drug also contributes to his downfall in the end. With "Carlito Brigante", he's a Nuyorican(Puerto Rican New Yorker) ex drug lord who returns to the streets of New York City in 1975 after serving 5 years of a 30 year prison sentence. Now planning to live a legitimate crime free life, he also tries to rekindle his relationship with Gail(Penelope Ann Miller) that he had before his imprisonment. But there are two causes to Carlito's downfall. The first is his lawyer, David Kleinfeld(Sean Penn)who not only has a very bad cocaine addiction but is corrupt and is also a retaliatory target of incarcerated Italian mob boss, Tony "Tony T" Taglialucci(Frank Minucci), another one of his clients. Carlito's second downfall is "Benny Blanco" who is a young, inexperienced punk who is trying to rise up in the drug trade by trying to surpass Carlito and is played by actor/comedian John Leguizamo, respectively. But in the end, is it Carlito himself that contributes to his downfall just for having a loyal trust in Kleinfeld and Pachanga(Luis Guzman), an old friend from his past. "Carlito's Way" was released in 1993 for which it was 10 years apart from "Scarface"(which was released in 1983). And another difference between each movie is the musical score. With "Scarface", the score was conducted by Giorgio Moroder and was synthesizer based. With "Carlito's Way", the score was conducted by Patrick Doyle and was more symphonic/orchestra based. But the soundtrack also consisted of songs from 1970's Disco groups such as KC and the Sunshine Band, The O Jays, The Hues Corporation, The Bee Gees, LaBelle, etc. that fit the time period of the movie(1975). And the soundtrack also consisted of songs from Latin music artists such as Celia Cruz, Hector Lavoe, Willie Colon, and Santana as well. And besides the other aforementioned actors, the other actors that comprised the cast such as James Rebhorn, Viggo Mortensen, Adrian Pasdar, Joseph Siravo, Richard Foronjy, John Ortiz, Ingrid Rogers and the late Argentinian comedic actor, Jorge Porcel(in his only American acting appearance) also put in good performances in this movie. And besides Al Pacino, other "Scarface" alumni such as Al Israel(Hector), Angel Salazar(Chi Chi), Cesar Cordova(Cuban cook), and Mike Moran(Nick the Pig)also make brief cameos in "Carlito's Way." Just like he perfected the Cuban accent for "Tony Montana" in "Scarface", Pacino perfects the Nuyorican accent for "Carlito Brigante" in "Carlito's Way", even if he is an Italian-American actor. Although "Carlito's Way: Rise to Power" was, in my opinion, a good prequel starring Jay Hernandez as a young "Carlito" in his early years, it will never compare to the original film from 1993. "Carlito's Way", in my opinion, is another great gangster film that should be included in the ranks with "The Godfather" trilogy, "Once Upon a Time in America", "Goodfellas", "Casino", "A Bronx Tale", and of course, "Scarface"(both versions from 1932 and 1983/Al Pacino respectively). Also, look out for a director's trademark that director Brian De Palma left in both movies that involves a gun that includes a silencer and an arm in a sling. Of course, both "Scarface" and "Carlito's Way" have to be watched together side by side to find that director's trademark along with its symbolism.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    10 years after Scarface
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Pusztai Norbi (noresz999)
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sorry for my bad English, I'm still learning the language. 10 years after Scarface, its director, and actor, made a gangster movie again, and its outcome isn't so far from the mentioned. They made it based on 2 books (by Edwin Torres), in 144 minutes, if we see on book adaptations, then it's a good time from 1 book, but not from 2. 2 books are compacted in 144 min. It's hard to do it well, but the creators made it very well. I could say without any overstatement, that it's in the top 10 all-time best gangster movies, I cannot see any problem with the movie. It has a lot of memorable scenes, it has some jokes, it's end very exciting, and heartbreaking, and it's not boring, for a minute, either. Furthermore, it's very strong in performances (Al Pacino, Sean Penn), directing (Brian De Palma), and screen writing (David Koepp), i think that it's the key of success. Who has seen this movie, that'll never forget it, simply brilliant. 9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Carlito the Pragmatic Gangster!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Stray Pez
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    DePalma's film is a masterpiece on many levels. For one, it is historically accurate to the letter. Carlito, a former smack peddler, is released from prison after a few years. When released, the drug business has changed. Cocaine, rather than heroine, is the drug of choice for most New Yorkers. It is more expensive and much more widely used than heroine. Before Cocaine, drug dealers were guys who operated on the fringes of society and catered to artists and musicians. In addition, Heroine was relatively cheap compared to Coke. This was the world Carlito was used to in the 50's and 60's. Yet he was somehow able to make a name for himself in this parched landscape through toughness, street smarts and pragmatism. Now released from prison, he finds out that the dope business changed while he was on the inside. Cocaine is easily available and in high demand. Drug users are now part of mainstream society. They include young professionals, politicians and athletes. As a result, drug dealers are not only able to make more money, they also become celebrities in their own right. This was so true about New York in the 1970's. Guys like Nikki Barnes made the cover of magazines because of Coke. It was ridiculous. Another important issue to point out is the escalating violence that results as well. Because Coke is more expensive, dealers are able to buy more guns from the windfall profits. DePalma does an excellent job incorporating this into a generation gap issue between Carlito and the newer criminals. Carlito is a killer and a thug. But he killed for survival. Perhaps his mothers death when he was young gave him more respect for human life or his generation as a whole valued life more than the new generation of gangsters. Carlito was born in a time when many people did not survive childhood. Some women still died during childbirth. World Wars also took the lives of many men. Since the new generation didn't experience death like he did, they value human life less. More guns in circulation feeds the beast of indifference. Pachanga said it best: "They shotgun you just to see you fly up in the air". Overall, a great movie with a tragic ending. The movie incorporates many themes about living a life of crime, changing social attitudes and capitalism. Highly recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    All About Carlito Brigante
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Carlito's Way is a crime drama based on the novels Carlito's Way and After Hours by Judge Edwin Torres. The film adaptation was written by David Koepp. It stars Al Pacino and Sean Penn,together with Penelope Ann Miller, Luis Guzm&aacute;n, John Leguizamo, and Viggo Mortensen in supporting roles. The story follows the life of Carlito Brigante after he is released from prison and vows to go straight and retire from criminal activities. However, unable to escape his past, he ends up being dragged into actions that got him imprisoned in the first place.The movie is narrated by Carlito himself, who explains his hopes, his strategies, and especially his mistakes. Brian De Palma directed the film. Carlito, a fabled heroin dealer, is released from prison after serving 5 years of a 30-year sentence. Tired and middle-aged, he wants out of the business as he has lost the juice for itfor the risks, the killing. It's the mid-'70s, the era of cocaine, fast sex, and disco glitz, and he takes a job running a dance club partially owned by his oldest and most trusted comrade, the coke-addled mob lawyer David Kleinfeld. Carlito's plan is to make some quick cash and move out of the country. But he is dragged down by his rootsby his hair-trigger survivor's instincts, honed while he was still a switchblade-wielding street kid, and by his loyalty to Kleinfeld, who tricks Carlito into helping him execute a mob hit. This film is one of the truly underrated films in the Brian De Palma and/or Al Pacino filmographies. It may have been unjustly derided and dismissed upon its theatrical debut during its year of release, but the it has received a cult following for many years now.The acting is great as the viewers are tickled by Sean Penn's weasely performance, Al Pacino's electric lead, or that crazy-cool chase through the NYC train station. Aside from its excellent performances,it has memorable moments, and some serious action and violent scenes. Overall,Carlito's Way is a smoother piece of filmmaking than Scarface, the only other picture De Palma has made with Pacino.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good classic Brian De Palma
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Panapaok
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Back to the gangster genre for Brian De Palma with Carlito's Way. After Scarface and The Untouchables he gives another pure example of his filmmaking and proves that he is a very strong and underrated master. Al Pacino gives another strong performance as Carlito Brigante and this is not unusual for him because he is in a well known field. But this time he is not another greedy and violent guy like Michael Corleone or Tony Montana but he is wise and clever and his goal is to retire from the business. Furthermore Sean Penn shows again his enormous talent by giving a strong performance as Carlto's rogue lawyer whose motives are not what they seem. He is rotten and cocaine addict and Penn pulls of this role brilliantly. This is a very good film both entertaining and touching and it is a must see for all De Palma's fans. Pacino's narration is an important key for the audience to realize who Carlito is. And, like a lot of gangster films, Carlito's Way proves that once a gangster means always a gangster no matter what.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A very good film... one of Pacinos best.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    richieandsam
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    CARLITO'S WAY I thought this was really good. The movie is about an ex con who gets released from prison and is determined to go straight. He is not interested in crime anymore. The problem is, he has got such a big reputation, that all the gangsters and criminals find him for advice, deals and help... some even want to kill him. The film stars Al Pacino, Sean Penn, Penelope Ann Miller, John Leguizamo, Ingrid Rogers & Luis Guzman. Everyone did a great job. Al is an amazing actor. He is over the top in some of his movies and there are scenes in this film where he is over the top too, but his performances always brings intensity. He is such an intense person and he can be a very scary person. But i think he is great! Sean Penn plays his lawyer... and at the beginning of the movie I felt he was a geek. Big curly hair, geeky glasses and he looks like he doesn't belong in the company of these gangsters... but as the film goes on he changes. The pressures of life gets to him and he can't handle it. His character has a hard time and i felt sorry for him towards the end of the film. I loved the action sequences. The gun fights and make-up were great. There was one scene where a guy gets shot in the face, it was so well shot. The way it was filmed made it look so real. It was a good crime drama/thriller... and I was pleasantly surprised at how good it is. I will give this film 7 out of 10. Al Pacino knows how to play a great gangster... and you can't help but feel sorry for him in this film because all he wants it to get out, but no matter what he does he just gets dragged back in. For more reviews, please like my Facebook page: https://www.facebook.com/pages/Ordinary-Person-Movie- Reviews/456572047728204?ref=hl
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pacino works his magic yet again!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pinturicchio_juve
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I just love Brian De Palma films. They're just so good to watch and have the right mix of good dialogues and an appealing storyline to get the viewer hooked. Scarface and The Untouchables would serve as worthy examples to this fact, and now that I've watched it, I guess Carlito's Way does too. The film is an adaptation of Edwin Torres' novel "After Hours" which follows the story of ex-con/gangster/drug peddler Carlito Brigante (played by Al Pacino), who tries to shun away from a life of crime after being released from prison. Brigante had in actuality been serving a thirty-to-life sentence, which had gotten reduced to five years, owing to the influence his lawyer, David Kleinfeld (Sean Penn) had with the jury. Once out on the streets, Carlito pledges to live life the right way and reluctantly agrees to co-own a nightclub so that he can save just enough money to leave New York and start a car rental business. But inevitably, he's lured into crime once again, and how he fights the odds forms the rest of the plot. One thing that struck me as I watched the film was that everything was very direct. There is not really much for the audience to interpret. Each character is sketched out quite well at the beginning itself, and one kind of knows what he/she would tend to do under the given circumstances. For example, Sean Penn's character, David Kleinfeld is exposed as a corrupt lawyer, and subsequent events throughout the film show him as one, with all his shady dealings and money laundering activities coming back to haunt him. I liked this about the movie, because one is not left wondering what a particular scene means, or what that character was trying to say. Its all said and done. There. Take it or leave it. Of course, this kind of storytelling will not work in all situations, but here, it feels just right. Then there's that aura of the gangster about Carlito. In the beginning, he accompanies his cousin to a drug dealer's hangout for a transaction. As the scene develops, one can feel Carlito sensing that there's something amiss about the place. The tension is brilliantly captured by De Palma here and you can just feel Pacino getting into the skin of the gangster he's portraying. He knows exactly what's going to happen, he's prepared for it, and when it does happen, he knows what to do. This gut instinct comes to the fore in the latter half of the film as well and is part of the reason why this films works for me. There are a lot of scenes and characters which contribute to making the film what it is, such as John Leguizamo as "Benny Blanco" the young upstart who tries to get chummy with Carlito but fails, Gail, Carlito's former lover, with whom he rekindles his relationship and Luiz Guzman as "Pachanga", Carlito's right hand man. But to me, this one is Pacino all the way. He carries the film on his shoulders and commands respect in almost every frame. You can see that he's always in control and this again points to the direct nature of the storyline. The De Palma-Pacino-gangster plot combine gives rise to obvious comparisons with Scarface. But the two are so different. While Tony Montana is just a drug dealer, Carlito Brigante is much more than that. He's a larger than life personality with a heart, remorse, and a conscience. He believes he has a shot at redemption. Montana has none of this. He's arrogant, ruthless and has absolutely no feelings of guilt or regret. The differing nature of their characters make the two films widely different, thus making a comparison would just be a wasteful exercise. The climax sequence, shot at a railway station does bring back scenes reminiscent of The Untouchables, though the events that unfold in the two films are entirely different. Carlito's Way might have its share of flaws which may not put it in the league of gangster flicks such as Goodfellas or The Godfather movies, but it is still a classic, and a highly underrated one at that. De Palma himself is a hugely underrated director (It is a surprise to me how he hasn't won an Oscar yet), and this film just underlines his capability. This one's a must watch for all fans of mob films, but I think that at its very basic level, it's just a story about a man with a heart.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a good movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Hooman Moeen (che-hooman)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    this film have a very good story.AL PACINO have a very good film i ever see.this film show the good guy why have a bad life this movie is a very good romance and crime\gangster i see.good drama i really like that.HAS A A LITTLE SCARFACE REUNION IN IT. SEAN PENN WUZ GREAT AS THE CORRUPT LAWYER. THE ENDING WUZ GREAT BUT TRAGIC BECAUSE YOU END UP PULLING FOR MR BRIGANTE (AL PACINO) DESPITE HIS CRIMINAL PAST.a lot of action is in this movie.Sean Penn plays a good part as a lawyer who got in too deep with the bad guys.he ends up getting shot in the hospital. i just wish there was a different end to this movie.....i wont give it away.if you like Al pacino and Sean Penn,then this movie is a must see.....
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A great story and film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    evas428
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of my favorite movies of all time! Amazing performance by Sean Penn, who really carries the film forward despite the powerhouse presence of the great Al Pacino. The characters were very well written and performed beautifully, especially from the less know (at the time) Vigo Mortensen and John Leguizamo. While this can be considered a "gangster movie", the love story of Carlito and Gale serve as the perfect motivation for the title character to escape the street life. This is much different than The Godfather. Overall, I highly recommend this film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Carlito Goes All The Way-Carlito's Way ****
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Simply put, an outrageously great gangster film with Al Pacino, as usual, turning in still another phenomenal performance as a Puerto Rican gangster who wants to grow straight, but is eventually pulled into a situation which causes tragedy for him. He is equally matched by Sean Penn as a cocaine addicted lawyer who draws him in and Penelope Ann Miller, the girl he loved but tragically could not have. It's basically a well-crafted story of environment having its hold on people and trapping them once they have committed crimes. The music at the club that Pacino owns is absolutely fabulous with an array of popular songs for the period.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The "so-called" sequel to Scarface
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    aaronalmarez
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just like "Casino" has been considered the "so-called" sequel to "Goodfellas", in my opinion, "Carlito's Way" is basically the "so-called" sequel to "Scarface." The reasons for that explanation is because of the stars and similar story lines of each movie. With "Goodfellas" and "Casino", both movies starred Robert De Niro and Joe Pesci and were directed by Martin Scorsese. When it comes to both "Scarface" and "Carlito's Way", both movies star Al Pacino and were directed by Brian De Palma. And even actors that played minor roles in one movie appear in some capacity in their counterparts. Also in the past, there were weekends were I would watch both sets of movies together but on separate days from each other. But of course, there are differences between "Tony Montana" and "Carlito Brigante." "Tony Montana" was basically a Cuban refugee hoodlum who along with other Cuban refugees, arrives in Miami, Florida during the "Mariel Boat Lift" in 1980 and within a few years becomes the top drug lord in Miami and uses cocaine as a source of power. But that particular drug also contributes to his downfall in the end. With "Carlito Brigante", he's a Nuyorican(Puerto Rican New Yorker) ex drug lord who returns to the streets of New York City in 1975 after serving 5 years of a 30 year prison sentence. Now planning to live a legitimate crime free life, he also tries to rekindle his relationship with Gail(Penelope Ann Miller) that he had before his imprisonment. But there are two causes to Carlito's downfall. The first is his lawyer, David Kleinfeld(Sean Penn)who not only has a very bad cocaine addiction but is corrupt and is also a retaliatory target of incarcerated Italian mob boss, Tony "Tony T" Taglialucci(Frank Minucci), another one of his clients. Carlito's second downfall is "Benny Blanco" who is a young, inexperienced punk who is trying to rise up in the drug trade by trying to surpass Carlito and is played by actor/comedian John Leguizamo, respectively. But in the end, is it Carlito himself that contributes to his downfall just for having a loyal trust in Kleinfeld and Pachanga(Luis Guzman), an old friend from his past. "Carlito's Way" was released in 1993 for which it was 10 years apart from "Scarface"(which was released in 1983). And another difference between each movie is the musical score. With "Scarface", the score was conducted by Giorgio Moroder and was synthesizer based. With "Carlito's Way", the score was conducted by Patrick Doyle and was more symphonic/orchestra based. But the soundtrack also consisted of songs from 1970's Disco groups such as KC and the Sunshine Band, The O Jays, The Hues Corporation, The Bee Gees, LaBelle, etc. that fit the time period of the movie(1975). And the soundtrack also consisted of songs from Latin music artists such as Celia Cruz, Hector Lavoe, Willie Colon, and Santana as well. And besides the other aforementioned actors, the other actors that comprised the cast such as James Rebhorn, Viggo Mortensen, Adrian Pasdar, Joseph Siravo, Richard Foronjy, John Ortiz, Ingrid Rogers and the late Argentinian comedic actor, Jorge Porcel(in his only American acting appearance) also put in good performances in this movie. And besides Al Pacino, other "Scarface" alumni such as Al Israel(Hector), Angel Salazar(Chi Chi), Cesar Cordova(Cuban cook), and Mike Moran(Nick the Pig)also make brief cameos in "Carlito's Way." Just like he perfected the Cuban accent for "Tony Montana" in "Scarface", Pacino perfects the Nuyorican accent for "Carlito Brigante" in "Carlito's Way", even if he is an Italian-American actor. Although "Carlito's Way: Rise to Power" was, in my opinion, a good prequel starring Jay Hernandez as a young "Carlito" in his early years, it will never compare to the original film from 1993. "Carlito's Way", in my opinion, is another great gangster film that should be included in the ranks with "The Godfather" trilogy, "Once Upon a Time in America", "Goodfellas", "Casino", "A Bronx Tale", and of course, "Scarface"(both versions from 1932 and 1983/Al Pacino respectively). Also, look out for a director's trademark that director Brian De Palma left in both movies that involves a gun that includes a silencer and an arm in a sling. Of course, both "Scarface" and "Carlito's Way" have to be watched together side by side to find that director's trademark along with its symbolism.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    10 years after Scarface
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Pusztai Norbi (noresz999)
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sorry for my bad English, I'm still learning the language. 10 years after Scarface, its director, and actor, made a gangster movie again, and its outcome isn't so far from the mentioned. They made it based on 2 books (by Edwin Torres), in 144 minutes, if we see on book adaptations, then it's a good time from 1 book, but not from 2. 2 books are compacted in 144 min. It's hard to do it well, but the creators made it very well. I could say without any overstatement, that it's in the top 10 all-time best gangster movies, I cannot see any problem with the movie. It has a lot of memorable scenes, it has some jokes, it's end very exciting, and heartbreaking, and it's not boring, for a minute, either. Furthermore, it's very strong in performances (Al Pacino, Sean Penn), directing (Brian De Palma), and screen writing (David Koepp), i think that it's the key of success. Who has seen this movie, that'll never forget it, simply brilliant. 9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Carlito the Pragmatic Gangster!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Stray Pez
   </autor>
   <data>
    10/9/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    DePalma's film is a masterpiece on many levels. For one, it is historically accurate to the letter. Carlito, a former smack peddler, is released from prison after a few years. When released, the drug business has changed. Cocaine, rather than heroine, is the drug of choice for most New Yorkers. It is more expensive and much more widely used than heroine. Before Cocaine, drug dealers were guys who operated on the fringes of society and catered to artists and musicians. In addition, Heroine was relatively cheap compared to Coke. This was the world Carlito was used to in the 50's and 60's. Yet he was somehow able to make a name for himself in this parched landscape through toughness, street smarts and pragmatism. Now released from prison, he finds out that the dope business changed while he was on the inside. Cocaine is easily available and in high demand. Drug users are now part of mainstream society. They include young professionals, politicians and athletes. As a result, drug dealers are not only able to make more money, they also become celebrities in their own right. This was so true about New York in the 1970's. Guys like Nikki Barnes made the cover of magazines because of Coke. It was ridiculous. Another important issue to point out is the escalating violence that results as well. Because Coke is more expensive, dealers are able to buy more guns from the windfall profits. DePalma does an excellent job incorporating this into a generation gap issue between Carlito and the newer criminals. Carlito is a killer and a thug. But he killed for survival. Perhaps his mothers death when he was young gave him more respect for human life or his generation as a whole valued life more than the new generation of gangsters. Carlito was born in a time when many people did not survive childhood. Some women still died during childbirth. World Wars also took the lives of many men. Since the new generation didn't experience death like he did, they value human life less. More guns in circulation feeds the beast of indifference. Pachanga said it best: "They shotgun you just to see you fly up in the air". Overall, a great movie with a tragic ending. The movie incorporates many themes about living a life of crime, changing social attitudes and capitalism. Highly recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    All About Carlito Brigante
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Carlito's Way is a crime drama based on the novels Carlito's Way and After Hours by Judge Edwin Torres. The film adaptation was written by David Koepp. It stars Al Pacino and Sean Penn,together with Penelope Ann Miller, Luis Guzm&aacute;n, John Leguizamo, and Viggo Mortensen in supporting roles. The story follows the life of Carlito Brigante after he is released from prison and vows to go straight and retire from criminal activities. However, unable to escape his past, he ends up being dragged into actions that got him imprisoned in the first place.The movie is narrated by Carlito himself, who explains his hopes, his strategies, and especially his mistakes. Brian De Palma directed the film. Carlito, a fabled heroin dealer, is released from prison after serving 5 years of a 30-year sentence. Tired and middle-aged, he wants out of the business as he has lost the juice for itfor the risks, the killing. It's the mid-'70s, the era of cocaine, fast sex, and disco glitz, and he takes a job running a dance club partially owned by his oldest and most trusted comrade, the coke-addled mob lawyer David Kleinfeld. Carlito's plan is to make some quick cash and move out of the country. But he is dragged down by his rootsby his hair-trigger survivor's instincts, honed while he was still a switchblade-wielding street kid, and by his loyalty to Kleinfeld, who tricks Carlito into helping him execute a mob hit. This film is one of the truly underrated films in the Brian De Palma and/or Al Pacino filmographies. It may have been unjustly derided and dismissed upon its theatrical debut during its year of release, but the it has received a cult following for many years now.The acting is great as the viewers are tickled by Sean Penn's weasely performance, Al Pacino's electric lead, or that crazy-cool chase through the NYC train station. Aside from its excellent performances,it has memorable moments, and some serious action and violent scenes. Overall,Carlito's Way is a smoother piece of filmmaking than Scarface, the only other picture De Palma has made with Pacino.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Good classic Brian De Palma
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Panapaok
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Back to the gangster genre for Brian De Palma with Carlito's Way. After Scarface and The Untouchables he gives another pure example of his filmmaking and proves that he is a very strong and underrated master. Al Pacino gives another strong performance as Carlito Brigante and this is not unusual for him because he is in a well known field. But this time he is not another greedy and violent guy like Michael Corleone or Tony Montana but he is wise and clever and his goal is to retire from the business. Furthermore Sean Penn shows again his enormous talent by giving a strong performance as Carlto's rogue lawyer whose motives are not what they seem. He is rotten and cocaine addict and Penn pulls of this role brilliantly. This is a very good film both entertaining and touching and it is a must see for all De Palma's fans. Pacino's narration is an important key for the audience to realize who Carlito is. And, like a lot of gangster films, Carlito's Way proves that once a gangster means always a gangster no matter what.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A very good film... one of Pacinos best.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    richieandsam
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    CARLITO'S WAY I thought this was really good. The movie is about an ex con who gets released from prison and is determined to go straight. He is not interested in crime anymore. The problem is, he has got such a big reputation, that all the gangsters and criminals find him for advice, deals and help... some even want to kill him. The film stars Al Pacino, Sean Penn, Penelope Ann Miller, John Leguizamo, Ingrid Rogers & Luis Guzman. Everyone did a great job. Al is an amazing actor. He is over the top in some of his movies and there are scenes in this film where he is over the top too, but his performances always brings intensity. He is such an intense person and he can be a very scary person. But i think he is great! Sean Penn plays his lawyer... and at the beginning of the movie I felt he was a geek. Big curly hair, geeky glasses and he looks like he doesn't belong in the company of these gangsters... but as the film goes on he changes. The pressures of life gets to him and he can't handle it. His character has a hard time and i felt sorry for him towards the end of the film. I loved the action sequences. The gun fights and make-up were great. There was one scene where a guy gets shot in the face, it was so well shot. The way it was filmed made it look so real. It was a good crime drama/thriller... and I was pleasantly surprised at how good it is. I will give this film 7 out of 10. Al Pacino knows how to play a great gangster... and you can't help but feel sorry for him in this film because all he wants it to get out, but no matter what he does he just gets dragged back in. For more reviews, please like my Facebook page: https://www.facebook.com/pages/Ordinary-Person-Movie- Reviews/456572047728204?ref=hl
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pacino works his magic yet again!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    pinturicchio_juve
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I just love Brian De Palma films. They're just so good to watch and have the right mix of good dialogues and an appealing storyline to get the viewer hooked. Scarface and The Untouchables would serve as worthy examples to this fact, and now that I've watched it, I guess Carlito's Way does too. The film is an adaptation of Edwin Torres' novel "After Hours" which follows the story of ex-con/gangster/drug peddler Carlito Brigante (played by Al Pacino), who tries to shun away from a life of crime after being released from prison. Brigante had in actuality been serving a thirty-to-life sentence, which had gotten reduced to five years, owing to the influence his lawyer, David Kleinfeld (Sean Penn) had with the jury. Once out on the streets, Carlito pledges to live life the right way and reluctantly agrees to co-own a nightclub so that he can save just enough money to leave New York and start a car rental business. But inevitably, he's lured into crime once again, and how he fights the odds forms the rest of the plot. One thing that struck me as I watched the film was that everything was very direct. There is not really much for the audience to interpret. Each character is sketched out quite well at the beginning itself, and one kind of knows what he/she would tend to do under the given circumstances. For example, Sean Penn's character, David Kleinfeld is exposed as a corrupt lawyer, and subsequent events throughout the film show him as one, with all his shady dealings and money laundering activities coming back to haunt him. I liked this about the movie, because one is not left wondering what a particular scene means, or what that character was trying to say. Its all said and done. There. Take it or leave it. Of course, this kind of storytelling will not work in all situations, but here, it feels just right. Then there's that aura of the gangster about Carlito. In the beginning, he accompanies his cousin to a drug dealer's hangout for a transaction. As the scene develops, one can feel Carlito sensing that there's something amiss about the place. The tension is brilliantly captured by De Palma here and you can just feel Pacino getting into the skin of the gangster he's portraying. He knows exactly what's going to happen, he's prepared for it, and when it does happen, he knows what to do. This gut instinct comes to the fore in the latter half of the film as well and is part of the reason why this films works for me. There are a lot of scenes and characters which contribute to making the film what it is, such as John Leguizamo as "Benny Blanco" the young upstart who tries to get chummy with Carlito but fails, Gail, Carlito's former lover, with whom he rekindles his relationship and Luiz Guzman as "Pachanga", Carlito's right hand man. But to me, this one is Pacino all the way. He carries the film on his shoulders and commands respect in almost every frame. You can see that he's always in control and this again points to the direct nature of the storyline. The De Palma-Pacino-gangster plot combine gives rise to obvious comparisons with Scarface. But the two are so different. While Tony Montana is just a drug dealer, Carlito Brigante is much more than that. He's a larger than life personality with a heart, remorse, and a conscience. He believes he has a shot at redemption. Montana has none of this. He's arrogant, ruthless and has absolutely no feelings of guilt or regret. The differing nature of their characters make the two films widely different, thus making a comparison would just be a wasteful exercise. The climax sequence, shot at a railway station does bring back scenes reminiscent of The Untouchables, though the events that unfold in the two films are entirely different. Carlito's Way might have its share of flaws which may not put it in the league of gangster flicks such as Goodfellas or The Godfather movies, but it is still a classic, and a highly underrated one at that. De Palma himself is a hugely underrated director (It is a surprise to me how he hasn't won an Oscar yet), and this film just underlines his capability. This one's a must watch for all fans of mob films, but I think that at its very basic level, it's just a story about a man with a heart.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a good movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Hooman Moeen (che-hooman)
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/3/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    this film have a very good story.AL PACINO have a very good film i ever see.this film show the good guy why have a bad life this movie is a very good romance and crime\gangster i see.good drama i really like that.HAS A A LITTLE SCARFACE REUNION IN IT. SEAN PENN WUZ GREAT AS THE CORRUPT LAWYER. THE ENDING WUZ GREAT BUT TRAGIC BECAUSE YOU END UP PULLING FOR MR BRIGANTE (AL PACINO) DESPITE HIS CRIMINAL PAST.a lot of action is in this movie.Sean Penn plays a good part as a lawyer who got in too deep with the bad guys.he ends up getting shot in the hospital. i just wish there was a different end to this movie.....i wont give it away.if you like Al pacino and Sean Penn,then this movie is a must see.....
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A great story and film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    evas428
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    One of my favorite movies of all time! Amazing performance by Sean Penn, who really carries the film forward despite the powerhouse presence of the great Al Pacino. The characters were very well written and performed beautifully, especially from the less know (at the time) Vigo Mortensen and John Leguizamo. While this can be considered a "gangster movie", the love story of Carlito and Gale serve as the perfect motivation for the title character to escape the street life. This is much different than The Godfather. Overall, I highly recommend this film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Carlito Goes All The Way-Carlito's Way ****
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Simply put, an outrageously great gangster film with Al Pacino, as usual, turning in still another phenomenal performance as a Puerto Rican gangster who wants to grow straight, but is eventually pulled into a situation which causes tragedy for him. He is equally matched by Sean Penn as a cocaine addicted lawyer who draws him in and Penelope Ann Miller, the girl he loved but tragically could not have. It's basically a well-crafted story of environment having its hold on people and trapping them once they have committed crimes. The music at the club that Pacino owns is absolutely fabulous with an array of popular songs for the period.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The "so-called" sequel to Scarface
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    aaronalmarez
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just like "Casino" has been considered the "so-called" sequel to "Goodfellas", in my opinion, "Carlito's Way" is basically the "so-called" sequel to "Scarface." The reasons for that explanation is because of the stars and similar story lines of each movie. With "Goodfellas" and "Casino", both movies starred Robert De Niro and Joe Pesci and were directed by Martin Scorsese. When it comes to both "Scarface" and "Carlito's Way", both movies star Al Pacino and were directed by Brian De Palma. And even actors that played minor roles in one movie appear in some capacity in their counterparts. Also in the past, there were weekends were I would watch both sets of movies together but on separate days from each other. But of course, there are differences between "Tony Montana" and "Carlito Brigante." "Tony Montana" was basically a Cuban refugee hoodlum who along with other Cuban refugees, arrives in Miami, Florida during the "Mariel Boat Lift" in 1980 and within a few years becomes the top drug lord in Miami and uses cocaine as a source of power. But that particular drug also contributes to his downfall in the end. With "Carlito Brigante", he's a Nuyorican(Puerto Rican New Yorker) ex drug lord who returns to the streets of New York City in 1975 after serving 5 years of a 30 year prison sentence. Now planning to live a legitimate crime free life, he also tries to rekindle his relationship with Gail(Penelope Ann Miller) that he had before his imprisonment. But there are two causes to Carlito's downfall. The first is his lawyer, David Kleinfeld(Sean Penn)who not only has a very bad cocaine addiction but is corrupt and is also a retaliatory target of incarcerated Italian mob boss, Tony "Tony T" Taglialucci(Frank Minucci), another one of his clients. Carlito's second downfall is "Benny Blanco" who is a young, inexperienced punk who is trying to rise up in the drug trade by trying to surpass Carlito and is played by actor/comedian John Leguizamo, respectively. But in the end, is it Carlito himself that contributes to his downfall just for having a loyal trust in Kleinfeld and Pachanga(Luis Guzman), an old friend from his past. "Carlito's Way" was released in 1993 for which it was 10 years apart from "Scarface"(which was released in 1983). And another difference between each movie is the musical score. With "Scarface", the score was conducted by Giorgio Moroder and was synthesizer based. With "Carlito's Way", the score was conducted by Patrick Doyle and was more symphonic/orchestra based. But the soundtrack also consisted of songs from 1970's Disco groups such as KC and the Sunshine Band, The O Jays, The Hues Corporation, The Bee Gees, LaBelle, etc. that fit the time period of the movie(1975). And the soundtrack also consisted of songs from Latin music artists such as Celia Cruz, Hector Lavoe, Willie Colon, and Santana as well. And besides the other aforementioned actors, the other actors that comprised the cast such as James Rebhorn, Viggo Mortensen, Adrian Pasdar, Joseph Siravo, Richard Foronjy, John Ortiz, Ingrid Rogers and the late Argentinian comedic actor, Jorge Porcel(in his only American acting appearance) also put in good performances in this movie. And besides Al Pacino, other "Scarface" alumni such as Al Israel(Hector), Angel Salazar(Chi Chi), Cesar Cordova(Cuban cook), and Mike Moran(Nick the Pig)also make brief cameos in "Carlito's Way." Just like he perfected the Cuban accent for "Tony Montana" in "Scarface", Pacino perfects the Nuyorican accent for "Carlito Brigante" in "Carlito's Way", even if he is an Italian-American actor. Although "Carlito's Way: Rise to Power" was, in my opinion, a good prequel starring Jay Hernandez as a young "Carlito" in his early years, it will never compare to the original film from 1993. "Carlito's Way", in my opinion, is another great gangster film that should be included in the ranks with "The Godfather" trilogy, "Once Upon a Time in America", "Goodfellas", "Casino", "A Bronx Tale", and of course, "Scarface"(both versions from 1932 and 1983/Al Pacino respectively). Also, look out for a director's trademark that director Brian De Palma left in both movies that involves a gun that includes a silencer and an arm in a sling. Of course, both "Scarface" and "Carlito's Way" have to be watched together side by side to find that director's trademark along with its symbolism.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
