<filme>
 <id>
  760
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0114367
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1995
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Assassinos Cibern&eacute;ticos
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.2
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  (SIRIUS 6B, Year 2078) On a distant mining planet ravaged by a decade of war, scientists have created the perfect weapon: a blade-wielding, self-replicating race of killing devices known as... &nbsp;&raquo;
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  (SIRIUS 6B, Year 2078) On a distant mining planet ravaged by a decade of war, scientists have created the perfect weapon: a blade-wielding, self-replicating race of killing devices known as Screamers designed for one purpose only -- to hunt down and destroy all enemy life forms But man's greatest weapon has continued to evolve without any human guidance, and now it has devised a new mission: to obliterate all life. Col. Hendricksson (Peter Weller) is commander of a handful of Alliance soldiers still alive on Sirius 6B. Betrayed by his own political leaders and disgusted by the atrocities of this never-ending war, Hendricksson decides he must negotiate a separate peace with the New Economic Bloc's decimated forces. But to do so, he will have to cross a treacherous wasteland where the deadliest threat comes from the very weapons he helped to create.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Action
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Adventure
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Horror
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   soldier
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   future
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   cut into pieces
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   combat
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   future war
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Christian Duguay
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Philip K. Dick
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Dan O'Bannon
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Peter Weller
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Roy Dupuis
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Jennifer Rubin
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Noisy, Too Generic for Its Own Good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jmillerdp
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film sounds really cool in concept. But, it is permeated by lots of yelling and (yes!) screaming. The film follows acclaimed Science Fiction writer Philip K. Dick's original short story fairly closely, except for its difference in tone and ending. The direction is fairly routine, as is the script. The showdown upon showdown upon showdown gets tiring at the end, and undoes the paranoia of what came before. The acting gets pretty hammy, adding to the melodrama. The visual and practical effects are very good for a lower-budget film. The film score is fairly routine. Philip K. Dick was one of the most visionary Science-Fiction writers. And, few of his stories have been made into good films, which is too bad. "Screamers" is one of those misses. ***** (5 Out of 10 Stars)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Close Deception
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    hellraiser7
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Trust has always been a fundamental problem throughout the years because by it's nature it's never been a solid foundation to begin with. Despite the length of time we spend with a person we never truly know them, from his/her past to even what they do when were not around them. This film is an under the radar sci-fi gem which is based on a short story by my favorite sci-fi author Philp K. Dick. I like the production value despite a low budget they were able to use it well. We see a post apocalyptic world that is just dirty, grimy, and desolate. There is no vegetation, it is always cold, there is hardly any sun, and the worst part is the radioactive winds that blow every once in a while. It really adds to the suspense because it gives it a feeling of isolation, the fact there is hardly any life stirring means there is no help that will come when you need it the most. I also like the effects, most to all are practical so there's no CGI, at least none I know about, though some effects are a tad dated but not bad in my book. I really like the designs of the Moble Sword/Screamer robots, whom are menacing from their capabilities not just in killing but in learning and the different types they were able to produce which unfortunately give them an edge. The music is good, action is decent liked the hill battle, but most importantly I really like the suspense where you are on constant edge and has a steady build because you're never sure of what you'll discover, and when you do it might be too late. Like one sequence which is my favorite is when Hendrickson is using a computer in the bunker to discover all the different types of Screamers, it was suspenseful on two counts; one the fact that he has only a limited amount of time to use it and second what information is left in the dark afterward which puts us a step behind and makes the stakes of survival even higher. The story is very good, I wouldn't say the concepts are entirely new but everything done right. I like how despite post apocalyptic conditions they still have high technology that still works. And certain aspects of the story somewhat acknowledges or are even prolific on our war for oil as well as terrorism. Characters are solid, Joe Hendrickson played by one of my favorite actors Peter Weller. I like that Joe is a person whom is layed back, has a sense of humor, tired of the war and just wants to go home. Same with Jessica Hansen play well by Jennifer Rubin whom despite someone on the shady end of things, is capable of being selfless, doesn't give her trust to just anyone. I like that both have a decent dynamic together, I bought it. I really like how the film gets at the issue of paranoia as well as the philosophical issue on what is a human. One of the best things about Philp's stories is how our perception of humanity can be blurred. We discover how far the robots come not just in replicating human's physically but even in feelings and thoughts, which makes you wonder if that constitutes them as human and not just machines. The only problems I really have are the pacing can be slow at some points. And also there isn't enough action, but then again this is more of a suspense thriller so I can't complain much. Overall, I think is a very good sci-fi that I think is worth checking out. Be careful of who you trust, it could be the last person you give it to. Rating: 3 and a half stars.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Doesn't compare to other PKD adaptations
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Zazwaz
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The story is about a war on a mining colony between two rivaling human factions. One of the factions has developed a new weapon: an army of robotic drones, nicknamed 'screamers', that hide underground and attack anything that they don't recognize. However, as the war is starting to draw to a close, the screamers refuse to work for the human faction that created them and it soon becomes clear that they have evolved on their own and now pose a threat to both sides. It's a neat idea and there are a lot of twists along the way, albeit very predictable ones. The writing could have taken a little more effort, the characters are shallow and the dialogue is very cheesy. The acting is also not that fantastic. Neither is the direction. It's all very average. Screamers is entertaining, but it doesn't stand out like other PKD adaptations such as Bladerunner or Minority Report. If you are looking for a fun sci-fi action flick, you might consider checking this one out, but if you are looking for depth then you're looking in the wrong place.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    False movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Shamek Stepien
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    By 2070 a galactic war has erupted between corporate and state powers fighting over resources on a Syrius 6B. After nuclear attacks by the NEB corporation the opposing Alliance employs automated robotics called Screamers to turn the tide of the war. Deep in the bowels of the planet the machines fabricate robot warfare, which in time evolve and start building bigger better products. Facing annihilation after the lengthened war captain Joe Hendricksson (Peter Weller) responds to a seize fire and embarks on a journey to the enemy bunker to undertake peace proceedings. Unfortunately for him the path may have been chosen too late... Post-mortem Philip K. Dick doesn't get much love from scriptwriters and the story "Second Variety" is no exception. For someone so cerebrally metaphysical movies based on his novels tend to take a action turn for the worse, dissolving the underlying essence of his stories and frontally assaulting with visual high-octane spectacles. "Screamers" is a low-budget take on the latter, albeit with some undeniable atmosphere to back it up. Nonetheless based on a clich&eacute;d ridden script with thinly developed characters spewing out tirades of one-liners occasionally interrupted by Shakespeare quotes, "Screamers" is an undeniable work in progress having some wider appeal, but lacking substance to stand the test of time. Budget and technological limitations to the movie decrease the overall quality, but the underpinning problem is one of limited tension, surprise and a multitude of scenes, which essentially lack sense or reason. Somewhere within this world lies potential much in the vein of "Bladerunner", but inept direction overly focused on churning out action brings Weller and the remaining cast down with its undertow. Plastic people with plastic morality ultimately divert attention from possibilities making us focus on the superficiality of the effort.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A mix of previous ideas but still entertaining
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moviefanman76-blogspot-com
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's hard for filmmakers to adapt stories to the screen, especially when they resemble stories that have been previously told. Turns out though director Christian Duguay evens out the story and though it still recalls other movies before its time, it still has elements in it that make it have a quality worth watching. The story of Screamers is loosely based off of Second Variety, a short story written by Philip K. Dick, the novelist of Blade Runner (1982) and Total Recall (1990). Dick is a very prestigious science fiction writer. His work has multiple twists and it always was a pleasant read. I also read Second Variety and much of it was fairly close to this movie. I actually enjoyed the film adaptation more than the story itself. Peter Weller is Joseph A. Hendricksson, an eccentric commander of an alliance bunker located on a planet known as Sirius 6B. Years before on Earth, there was nuclear fallout between two major groups; the N.E.B. (New Economic Block) and alliance workers over a special mineral that could change energy usage for transportation. So the fighting was moved to Sirius 6B where there has been a "Cold War" ever since. For the alliance to defend themselves, they created the Autonomous Mobile Sword or better known as, the screamer. The screamer is a mechanical life form that was equipped with a razor sharp blade so it could kill its enemy. But like all man made robots, they become self-aware and are now deciding for themselves who they should kill. Strangely enough, they are always updating their software, even making screamers that look like humans. So from there, audiences might make the connection of these traits between Skynet from The Terminator (1984), and characters not knowing who's real and who isn't from the novel Who Goes There, by John W. Campbell Jr. But for those few relations, Screamers can hold it's own as an entertaining sci-fi horror movie. It does not contain a lot of blood but it can be very suspenseful. Weller's performances are always a welcome to the screen. His ability to make his character sarcastic as is serious is a great touch. Andrew Lauer plays a innocent rookie named Ace Jefferson who tags along Hendricksson to meet with the N.E.B. command. The N.E.B. group these two visit is lead by the lovely Jennifer Ruben as Jessica Hanson. And with her is Roy Dupuis, who looks like Matthew McConaughey's distant cousin, who likes bugging another soldier who has some serious patience issues. The special effects are definitely dated. And it's really obvious when the camera is focused on the screamer itself but hey, the creature looks cool enough to look at. I think the most baffling part is how the machine keep upgrading their models. It makes you wonder, "What's going on down there". The set design is also something to see. A lot of does have the same color like from the movie Soldier (1998) but it at least looks real. The backgrounds actually resemble Chernobyl; which is eerie. Normand Corbeil composed the soundtrack and it also another strong point. When Hedricksson runs into a homeless child, the music makes the scene so heartbreaking. It's emotional and soft on the ears. The film variation of Second Variety does borough ideas from previous movies, but it's put together in such a way that it won't matter to the audience. The music is good and so is Weller's performance as a tired out war veteran.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A quite impressive but obviously flawed film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ozoneocean
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are two sides at war, but the war is winding down, it looks like one side has won, and the other side wants a truce... The trouble is that the autonomous weapons systems that the winning side deployed (called "screamers") and which helped them win, have other ideas. It stars Peter Weller, from Robocop. On the face of it, this looks like it'll be a by the numbers crappy scifi thriller horror with paper thin characters and wooden acting, and at best some testosterone fueled action movie sequences... That's what I thought anyway. I was very wrong. The acting was all extremely well done, especially by Weller. I was very impressed. Very good performances by all. The filming was atmospheric and well shot. Sets were great, props and costumes too. The story was full of emotion, it was thought provoking and well acted. This was an intelligent film! It was let down in two areas: 1. For most of the film the effects were very cheap, contrasting with the quality of the rest of it. 2. They lent a little too much on the cheap thriller aspect in parts of it, especially at the very end. It detracted a little from the intelligent themes and great acting. It's almost as if there were two competing forces at work: Highly competent, professional, pro, A-list film makers VS some strange incompetent cretin who BADLY wanted it to be a B-film. So it was flawed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sci-fi the way it was meant to be
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dragonsouls
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I decided to watch Screamers because I'm a big Phillip K. Dick fan, and this was a film based on one of his stories I never read yet. I had realized I overlooked the movie for way too long. I originally thought the movie was outdated, since I have experienced the human/robot social films for a while now, mostly with Battle Star Galactica, Blade Runner, i, Robot, and even Terminator. However, this is one of the first and original stories to convey the human/robot social conflicts and was glad to find the film on my video on demand lists. Worth mentioning first is the fine acting by Peter Weller, and I can't help but wonder why he never became more than a cult film actor, he truly could have been a big time action star on par with the other heavyweights of the 90s. And he really is convincing in this film, as a man who was on the brink of madness from desolation and hardship. As for the supporting cast, excellent performances for a low budget film. It reminded me of a time when all Science Fiction films were B-movies, before the Star Wars and Star Trek's came along. Come to think of it, the film had a decent sized budget for a 90s film. Nothing like other adapted Phillip K. Dick novels had gotten, such as Blade Runner, Minority Report, or Total Recall, but still, Screamers is a story that needed a bigger budget and if it had gotten one, this film would be a classic to be mentioned in the same breath as Dick's other masterpieces. The story reminded me of Blade Runner in some ways, and another short by Dick called "The Defenders" In a sense, Dick re-tells his themes over and over again, but nevertheless, Screamers is well written and unique in its own way. It's just perplexing why this film didn't come out in the 70s, or even early 80s, before the original Battle Star Galactica, and before Terminator, etc. This story would have made for a very pioneering film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sci-fi doing a great job to entertain
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (Richie@RanRightRealty.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a surprise movie meaning that turns out to be a great movie when you were expecting just a good one. The story has to be respected and understood. Then, what happens after that falls into place nicely. I am totally disappointed that they did not make a sequel to this winner. It was certainly set-up to do so. It has what I call genuine and satisfying scary moments brought to you via intelligence, not shock. Anytime you can engage the viewers imagination in a quality way after a movie viewing (as well as during) means you got a success on your hands. This is certainly one of those movies. The concept presented of something man has done that has mutated into something else is a good one. Now, if that something else wants to compete and then eliminate man, well you got my full attention thus this movie. Science Fiction treads a fine line of being believable or not when introducing a story. It doesn't have to be perfect to make its point. It has to be respectful and this movie respects the viewer. You will not have any trouble getting into this movie after the first few minutes. Then, all the dots start to connect and cause a viewing pleasure. It will suck you right in and when the ducks line up, scare you good and proper..Enjoy with a favorite snack so you don't bite your nails
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I would LOVE to see this movie remade with a good director and a large movie budget!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    picturetaker
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I originally saw this movie in the theatre. Many reviewers comment saying it should have gone straight to video but I don't think so. As this movie for its time was not that bad. I have seen this movie about 6 times since 1995 and every time I have enjoyed it. Could this movie have been better? Of course! But for what it cost and for what kind of movie it is, it is alright! Its such an interesting premise I would LOVE to see this movie remade with a good director and a large movie budget! As that would be GREAT! Screamers did have a OK script, it had a great story, OK character and storyline development. All in all it was an OK 1995 film. As most sci-fi goes it is not the worst at all! Screamers was an original movie and it is entertaining so if you get the opportunity to see it, I recommend you check it out if you like sci-fi movies.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Once it gets inside, that's when the killin' starts
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tieman64
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "We are now in a new form of schizophrenia. No more hysteria, no more projective paranoia, but this state of terror proper to the schizophrenic. [] The schizophrenic can no longer produce the limits of its own being. [] He is only a pure screen." - Baudrillard "That's right - Pinnochio's not a real little boy!" - Becker ("Screamers") Scifi author Harlan Ellison once took James Cameron to court, alleging that the director's 1984 film, "The Terminator", plagiarised "Demon With A Glass Hand" and "Soldier", two tales written by Ellison in the 1950s. But Cameron, a scifi nut, seems to have also borrowed heavily from Philip K Dick's "Second Variety", a 1953 short story which finds the world ravaged by war and mankind locked in combat with a race of machines. These machines were created for defence purposes, but eventually became "self aware", started evolving, making armies, factories and hunting down humans, whom they sought to completely eradicate. The machines then began creating terminator-like infiltration units; cyborgs which convincingly resemble humans and which are programmed to penetrate human bases. Dick's hero, a resourceful soldier, even resembles Cameron's Kyle Reese, and much of Dick's dialogue, desperate, fast and apocalyptic, recalls the frenetic banter in Cameron's "Terminator". While "Screamers", Christian Duguay's adaptation of Dick's "Second Variety", barely captures the tone and urgency of Dick's short story, Cameron's "Terminator" films do, though all these "adaptations" are more interesting in the way they demonstrate how Dick's approach to scifi changed from the 1950s onwards. All of Dick's novels are ontological conundrums, taking place in a landscape in which all "reality" seems to be constantly shifting, and in which worlds and selves constantly seem to fall apart. For Dick, there is no definitive reality, human identity itself is uncertain, nothing exists as it seems, and everything is simply a perception of pure information. In "Second Variety" these themes are approached in a fairly simple manner ("Is it an undercover killer robot or is it a human?", "What constitutes a robot?", "What constitutes a human?", "Aren't humans already cyborgs?", "How do I know what is real?", "How do I know what is machine?", "How do I know what I think I know?"), which is largely why it, and Dick's early work, remain his most popular. As Dick turned to drugs, stopped proof-reading, stopped perfecting and re-writing his stories, abandoned conventional narrative structures and started churning out novels quickly in a desperate attempt to pay his bills, his books, like his heroes and his own state of mind, became increasingly schizophrenic, paranoid and shapeless. Many deride Dick for this, but such a stance was the logical continuation of his early 1950s work. Today, Dick's later writing bare a striking similarity to postmodernist theories by thinkers such as Jameson, Baudrillard and Brian McHale. Dick anticipated the twenty-first century network society, a fragmented, culturally overloaded, media saturated world characterised by rapid technological change, constant movement and a dizzying, excessive and sometimes surreal aesthetic. For Dick, the future, our postmodern present, would morph into a sort of virtual reality game. A "consensual hallucination" in which all traditional demarcations or distinctions are erased. It is no longer an issue of there being a split between man and robot, but of man and technology constantly co-mingling, of both servicing the other, of all being technology, of man himself already being cybernetic, of the world already being cyberspacial, representational, all emotions faked, all behaviour play-acting, every object in quotes, everything grounded on the illusory. Whereas in an explicitly modernist film such as "Metropolis" the dichotomy between the original copy or experience (man) and the replication (machine) is very clear, in later Dickian films ("Blade Runner", Total Recall", "A Scanner Darkly", "Matrix", Cronenberg, Assayas etc - note how comparatively conservative Spielberg's version of Dick's "Minority Report" is) a crisis of representation occurs, as the signifier is now alienated from the object it signifies, a Deleuzian "schizoid existence" brought about by a breakdown "in the signifying chain". Unlike the apocalyptic, cosily hopeful rubble of "Terminator" and "Second Variety", later Dick also posits a urban, networked and mechanical landscape which engenders a consequential decline in organic feeling and sensibility. Men then become "consumers of illusion", an illusion of "belonging and participation" covering up massive industrial alienation. But every connection seems to lead back to corporations, a "soft fascism" whose grid it is impossible to escape. Here, everything is organised by the constant flow of money, all landscapes are advertising-saturated and the "goal" of commerce is to destroy history itself, to put its customers in the eternal Now, the big happy theme park of desires. No surprise then that one of Dick's last stories, "Stability", takes place in a world in which mankind doesn't progress anymore, despite the illusion of constant, hyper-motion. The story's solution? The invention of a Terminator-like time machine. If Dick got one thing wrong, it was in his assumption that this "schizoid existence" would trouble or traumatise man. Today, the opposite is true. Man's adapted. He loves his cage, even as he fantasises about Judgement Day. So postmodernist theory has itself has become what Brian McHale calls the "sister genre" of science fiction, both revolving around similar themes (What is reality? What constitutes the authentic human being?) and issues of technology and its effects on society and the individual subject. And while modernism was mainly interested in epistemology, the condition of knowledge, both Dick's scifi and postmodernism are governed by ontology and the basic conditions of existence. But "Screamers" and "The Terminator" films represent a kind of outdated, 1950s Philip K Dick, with nice easy, clear demarcations best suited for action cinema. Latter Dick is perhaps unsuited to the medium of cinema itself, though some of Olivier Assayas' more trashy films capture well his style ("Boarding Gate", "Demonlover"). 7.9/10  Worth one viewing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Noisy, Too Generic for Its Own Good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jmillerdp
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film sounds really cool in concept. But, it is permeated by lots of yelling and (yes!) screaming. The film follows acclaimed Science Fiction writer Philip K. Dick's original short story fairly closely, except for its difference in tone and ending. The direction is fairly routine, as is the script. The showdown upon showdown upon showdown gets tiring at the end, and undoes the paranoia of what came before. The acting gets pretty hammy, adding to the melodrama. The visual and practical effects are very good for a lower-budget film. The film score is fairly routine. Philip K. Dick was one of the most visionary Science-Fiction writers. And, few of his stories have been made into good films, which is too bad. "Screamers" is one of those misses. ***** (5 Out of 10 Stars)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Close Deception
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    hellraiser7
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Trust has always been a fundamental problem throughout the years because by it's nature it's never been a solid foundation to begin with. Despite the length of time we spend with a person we never truly know them, from his/her past to even what they do when were not around them. This film is an under the radar sci-fi gem which is based on a short story by my favorite sci-fi author Philp K. Dick. I like the production value despite a low budget they were able to use it well. We see a post apocalyptic world that is just dirty, grimy, and desolate. There is no vegetation, it is always cold, there is hardly any sun, and the worst part is the radioactive winds that blow every once in a while. It really adds to the suspense because it gives it a feeling of isolation, the fact there is hardly any life stirring means there is no help that will come when you need it the most. I also like the effects, most to all are practical so there's no CGI, at least none I know about, though some effects are a tad dated but not bad in my book. I really like the designs of the Moble Sword/Screamer robots, whom are menacing from their capabilities not just in killing but in learning and the different types they were able to produce which unfortunately give them an edge. The music is good, action is decent liked the hill battle, but most importantly I really like the suspense where you are on constant edge and has a steady build because you're never sure of what you'll discover, and when you do it might be too late. Like one sequence which is my favorite is when Hendrickson is using a computer in the bunker to discover all the different types of Screamers, it was suspenseful on two counts; one the fact that he has only a limited amount of time to use it and second what information is left in the dark afterward which puts us a step behind and makes the stakes of survival even higher. The story is very good, I wouldn't say the concepts are entirely new but everything done right. I like how despite post apocalyptic conditions they still have high technology that still works. And certain aspects of the story somewhat acknowledges or are even prolific on our war for oil as well as terrorism. Characters are solid, Joe Hendrickson played by one of my favorite actors Peter Weller. I like that Joe is a person whom is layed back, has a sense of humor, tired of the war and just wants to go home. Same with Jessica Hansen play well by Jennifer Rubin whom despite someone on the shady end of things, is capable of being selfless, doesn't give her trust to just anyone. I like that both have a decent dynamic together, I bought it. I really like how the film gets at the issue of paranoia as well as the philosophical issue on what is a human. One of the best things about Philp's stories is how our perception of humanity can be blurred. We discover how far the robots come not just in replicating human's physically but even in feelings and thoughts, which makes you wonder if that constitutes them as human and not just machines. The only problems I really have are the pacing can be slow at some points. And also there isn't enough action, but then again this is more of a suspense thriller so I can't complain much. Overall, I think is a very good sci-fi that I think is worth checking out. Be careful of who you trust, it could be the last person you give it to. Rating: 3 and a half stars.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Doesn't compare to other PKD adaptations
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Zazwaz
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The story is about a war on a mining colony between two rivaling human factions. One of the factions has developed a new weapon: an army of robotic drones, nicknamed 'screamers', that hide underground and attack anything that they don't recognize. However, as the war is starting to draw to a close, the screamers refuse to work for the human faction that created them and it soon becomes clear that they have evolved on their own and now pose a threat to both sides. It's a neat idea and there are a lot of twists along the way, albeit very predictable ones. The writing could have taken a little more effort, the characters are shallow and the dialogue is very cheesy. The acting is also not that fantastic. Neither is the direction. It's all very average. Screamers is entertaining, but it doesn't stand out like other PKD adaptations such as Bladerunner or Minority Report. If you are looking for a fun sci-fi action flick, you might consider checking this one out, but if you are looking for depth then you're looking in the wrong place.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    False movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Shamek Stepien
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    By 2070 a galactic war has erupted between corporate and state powers fighting over resources on a Syrius 6B. After nuclear attacks by the NEB corporation the opposing Alliance employs automated robotics called Screamers to turn the tide of the war. Deep in the bowels of the planet the machines fabricate robot warfare, which in time evolve and start building bigger better products. Facing annihilation after the lengthened war captain Joe Hendricksson (Peter Weller) responds to a seize fire and embarks on a journey to the enemy bunker to undertake peace proceedings. Unfortunately for him the path may have been chosen too late... Post-mortem Philip K. Dick doesn't get much love from scriptwriters and the story "Second Variety" is no exception. For someone so cerebrally metaphysical movies based on his novels tend to take a action turn for the worse, dissolving the underlying essence of his stories and frontally assaulting with visual high-octane spectacles. "Screamers" is a low-budget take on the latter, albeit with some undeniable atmosphere to back it up. Nonetheless based on a clich&eacute;d ridden script with thinly developed characters spewing out tirades of one-liners occasionally interrupted by Shakespeare quotes, "Screamers" is an undeniable work in progress having some wider appeal, but lacking substance to stand the test of time. Budget and technological limitations to the movie decrease the overall quality, but the underpinning problem is one of limited tension, surprise and a multitude of scenes, which essentially lack sense or reason. Somewhere within this world lies potential much in the vein of "Bladerunner", but inept direction overly focused on churning out action brings Weller and the remaining cast down with its undertow. Plastic people with plastic morality ultimately divert attention from possibilities making us focus on the superficiality of the effort.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A mix of previous ideas but still entertaining
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moviefanman76-blogspot-com
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's hard for filmmakers to adapt stories to the screen, especially when they resemble stories that have been previously told. Turns out though director Christian Duguay evens out the story and though it still recalls other movies before its time, it still has elements in it that make it have a quality worth watching. The story of Screamers is loosely based off of Second Variety, a short story written by Philip K. Dick, the novelist of Blade Runner (1982) and Total Recall (1990). Dick is a very prestigious science fiction writer. His work has multiple twists and it always was a pleasant read. I also read Second Variety and much of it was fairly close to this movie. I actually enjoyed the film adaptation more than the story itself. Peter Weller is Joseph A. Hendricksson, an eccentric commander of an alliance bunker located on a planet known as Sirius 6B. Years before on Earth, there was nuclear fallout between two major groups; the N.E.B. (New Economic Block) and alliance workers over a special mineral that could change energy usage for transportation. So the fighting was moved to Sirius 6B where there has been a "Cold War" ever since. For the alliance to defend themselves, they created the Autonomous Mobile Sword or better known as, the screamer. The screamer is a mechanical life form that was equipped with a razor sharp blade so it could kill its enemy. But like all man made robots, they become self-aware and are now deciding for themselves who they should kill. Strangely enough, they are always updating their software, even making screamers that look like humans. So from there, audiences might make the connection of these traits between Skynet from The Terminator (1984), and characters not knowing who's real and who isn't from the novel Who Goes There, by John W. Campbell Jr. But for those few relations, Screamers can hold it's own as an entertaining sci-fi horror movie. It does not contain a lot of blood but it can be very suspenseful. Weller's performances are always a welcome to the screen. His ability to make his character sarcastic as is serious is a great touch. Andrew Lauer plays a innocent rookie named Ace Jefferson who tags along Hendricksson to meet with the N.E.B. command. The N.E.B. group these two visit is lead by the lovely Jennifer Ruben as Jessica Hanson. And with her is Roy Dupuis, who looks like Matthew McConaughey's distant cousin, who likes bugging another soldier who has some serious patience issues. The special effects are definitely dated. And it's really obvious when the camera is focused on the screamer itself but hey, the creature looks cool enough to look at. I think the most baffling part is how the machine keep upgrading their models. It makes you wonder, "What's going on down there". The set design is also something to see. A lot of does have the same color like from the movie Soldier (1998) but it at least looks real. The backgrounds actually resemble Chernobyl; which is eerie. Normand Corbeil composed the soundtrack and it also another strong point. When Hedricksson runs into a homeless child, the music makes the scene so heartbreaking. It's emotional and soft on the ears. The film variation of Second Variety does borough ideas from previous movies, but it's put together in such a way that it won't matter to the audience. The music is good and so is Weller's performance as a tired out war veteran.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A quite impressive but obviously flawed film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ozoneocean
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are two sides at war, but the war is winding down, it looks like one side has won, and the other side wants a truce... The trouble is that the autonomous weapons systems that the winning side deployed (called "screamers") and which helped them win, have other ideas. It stars Peter Weller, from Robocop. On the face of it, this looks like it'll be a by the numbers crappy scifi thriller horror with paper thin characters and wooden acting, and at best some testosterone fueled action movie sequences... That's what I thought anyway. I was very wrong. The acting was all extremely well done, especially by Weller. I was very impressed. Very good performances by all. The filming was atmospheric and well shot. Sets were great, props and costumes too. The story was full of emotion, it was thought provoking and well acted. This was an intelligent film! It was let down in two areas: 1. For most of the film the effects were very cheap, contrasting with the quality of the rest of it. 2. They lent a little too much on the cheap thriller aspect in parts of it, especially at the very end. It detracted a little from the intelligent themes and great acting. It's almost as if there were two competing forces at work: Highly competent, professional, pro, A-list film makers VS some strange incompetent cretin who BADLY wanted it to be a B-film. So it was flawed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sci-fi the way it was meant to be
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dragonsouls
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I decided to watch Screamers because I'm a big Phillip K. Dick fan, and this was a film based on one of his stories I never read yet. I had realized I overlooked the movie for way too long. I originally thought the movie was outdated, since I have experienced the human/robot social films for a while now, mostly with Battle Star Galactica, Blade Runner, i, Robot, and even Terminator. However, this is one of the first and original stories to convey the human/robot social conflicts and was glad to find the film on my video on demand lists. Worth mentioning first is the fine acting by Peter Weller, and I can't help but wonder why he never became more than a cult film actor, he truly could have been a big time action star on par with the other heavyweights of the 90s. And he really is convincing in this film, as a man who was on the brink of madness from desolation and hardship. As for the supporting cast, excellent performances for a low budget film. It reminded me of a time when all Science Fiction films were B-movies, before the Star Wars and Star Trek's came along. Come to think of it, the film had a decent sized budget for a 90s film. Nothing like other adapted Phillip K. Dick novels had gotten, such as Blade Runner, Minority Report, or Total Recall, but still, Screamers is a story that needed a bigger budget and if it had gotten one, this film would be a classic to be mentioned in the same breath as Dick's other masterpieces. The story reminded me of Blade Runner in some ways, and another short by Dick called "The Defenders" In a sense, Dick re-tells his themes over and over again, but nevertheless, Screamers is well written and unique in its own way. It's just perplexing why this film didn't come out in the 70s, or even early 80s, before the original Battle Star Galactica, and before Terminator, etc. This story would have made for a very pioneering film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sci-fi doing a great job to entertain
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (Richie@RanRightRealty.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a surprise movie meaning that turns out to be a great movie when you were expecting just a good one. The story has to be respected and understood. Then, what happens after that falls into place nicely. I am totally disappointed that they did not make a sequel to this winner. It was certainly set-up to do so. It has what I call genuine and satisfying scary moments brought to you via intelligence, not shock. Anytime you can engage the viewers imagination in a quality way after a movie viewing (as well as during) means you got a success on your hands. This is certainly one of those movies. The concept presented of something man has done that has mutated into something else is a good one. Now, if that something else wants to compete and then eliminate man, well you got my full attention thus this movie. Science Fiction treads a fine line of being believable or not when introducing a story. It doesn't have to be perfect to make its point. It has to be respectful and this movie respects the viewer. You will not have any trouble getting into this movie after the first few minutes. Then, all the dots start to connect and cause a viewing pleasure. It will suck you right in and when the ducks line up, scare you good and proper..Enjoy with a favorite snack so you don't bite your nails
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I would LOVE to see this movie remade with a good director and a large movie budget!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    picturetaker
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I originally saw this movie in the theatre. Many reviewers comment saying it should have gone straight to video but I don't think so. As this movie for its time was not that bad. I have seen this movie about 6 times since 1995 and every time I have enjoyed it. Could this movie have been better? Of course! But for what it cost and for what kind of movie it is, it is alright! Its such an interesting premise I would LOVE to see this movie remade with a good director and a large movie budget! As that would be GREAT! Screamers did have a OK script, it had a great story, OK character and storyline development. All in all it was an OK 1995 film. As most sci-fi goes it is not the worst at all! Screamers was an original movie and it is entertaining so if you get the opportunity to see it, I recommend you check it out if you like sci-fi movies.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Once it gets inside, that's when the killin' starts
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tieman64
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "We are now in a new form of schizophrenia. No more hysteria, no more projective paranoia, but this state of terror proper to the schizophrenic. [] The schizophrenic can no longer produce the limits of its own being. [] He is only a pure screen." - Baudrillard "That's right - Pinnochio's not a real little boy!" - Becker ("Screamers") Scifi author Harlan Ellison once took James Cameron to court, alleging that the director's 1984 film, "The Terminator", plagiarised "Demon With A Glass Hand" and "Soldier", two tales written by Ellison in the 1950s. But Cameron, a scifi nut, seems to have also borrowed heavily from Philip K Dick's "Second Variety", a 1953 short story which finds the world ravaged by war and mankind locked in combat with a race of machines. These machines were created for defence purposes, but eventually became "self aware", started evolving, making armies, factories and hunting down humans, whom they sought to completely eradicate. The machines then began creating terminator-like infiltration units; cyborgs which convincingly resemble humans and which are programmed to penetrate human bases. Dick's hero, a resourceful soldier, even resembles Cameron's Kyle Reese, and much of Dick's dialogue, desperate, fast and apocalyptic, recalls the frenetic banter in Cameron's "Terminator". While "Screamers", Christian Duguay's adaptation of Dick's "Second Variety", barely captures the tone and urgency of Dick's short story, Cameron's "Terminator" films do, though all these "adaptations" are more interesting in the way they demonstrate how Dick's approach to scifi changed from the 1950s onwards. All of Dick's novels are ontological conundrums, taking place in a landscape in which all "reality" seems to be constantly shifting, and in which worlds and selves constantly seem to fall apart. For Dick, there is no definitive reality, human identity itself is uncertain, nothing exists as it seems, and everything is simply a perception of pure information. In "Second Variety" these themes are approached in a fairly simple manner ("Is it an undercover killer robot or is it a human?", "What constitutes a robot?", "What constitutes a human?", "Aren't humans already cyborgs?", "How do I know what is real?", "How do I know what is machine?", "How do I know what I think I know?"), which is largely why it, and Dick's early work, remain his most popular. As Dick turned to drugs, stopped proof-reading, stopped perfecting and re-writing his stories, abandoned conventional narrative structures and started churning out novels quickly in a desperate attempt to pay his bills, his books, like his heroes and his own state of mind, became increasingly schizophrenic, paranoid and shapeless. Many deride Dick for this, but such a stance was the logical continuation of his early 1950s work. Today, Dick's later writing bare a striking similarity to postmodernist theories by thinkers such as Jameson, Baudrillard and Brian McHale. Dick anticipated the twenty-first century network society, a fragmented, culturally overloaded, media saturated world characterised by rapid technological change, constant movement and a dizzying, excessive and sometimes surreal aesthetic. For Dick, the future, our postmodern present, would morph into a sort of virtual reality game. A "consensual hallucination" in which all traditional demarcations or distinctions are erased. It is no longer an issue of there being a split between man and robot, but of man and technology constantly co-mingling, of both servicing the other, of all being technology, of man himself already being cybernetic, of the world already being cyberspacial, representational, all emotions faked, all behaviour play-acting, every object in quotes, everything grounded on the illusory. Whereas in an explicitly modernist film such as "Metropolis" the dichotomy between the original copy or experience (man) and the replication (machine) is very clear, in later Dickian films ("Blade Runner", Total Recall", "A Scanner Darkly", "Matrix", Cronenberg, Assayas etc - note how comparatively conservative Spielberg's version of Dick's "Minority Report" is) a crisis of representation occurs, as the signifier is now alienated from the object it signifies, a Deleuzian "schizoid existence" brought about by a breakdown "in the signifying chain". Unlike the apocalyptic, cosily hopeful rubble of "Terminator" and "Second Variety", later Dick also posits a urban, networked and mechanical landscape which engenders a consequential decline in organic feeling and sensibility. Men then become "consumers of illusion", an illusion of "belonging and participation" covering up massive industrial alienation. But every connection seems to lead back to corporations, a "soft fascism" whose grid it is impossible to escape. Here, everything is organised by the constant flow of money, all landscapes are advertising-saturated and the "goal" of commerce is to destroy history itself, to put its customers in the eternal Now, the big happy theme park of desires. No surprise then that one of Dick's last stories, "Stability", takes place in a world in which mankind doesn't progress anymore, despite the illusion of constant, hyper-motion. The story's solution? The invention of a Terminator-like time machine. If Dick got one thing wrong, it was in his assumption that this "schizoid existence" would trouble or traumatise man. Today, the opposite is true. Man's adapted. He loves his cage, even as he fantasises about Judgement Day. So postmodernist theory has itself has become what Brian McHale calls the "sister genre" of science fiction, both revolving around similar themes (What is reality? What constitutes the authentic human being?) and issues of technology and its effects on society and the individual subject. And while modernism was mainly interested in epistemology, the condition of knowledge, both Dick's scifi and postmodernism are governed by ontology and the basic conditions of existence. But "Screamers" and "The Terminator" films represent a kind of outdated, 1950s Philip K Dick, with nice easy, clear demarcations best suited for action cinema. Latter Dick is perhaps unsuited to the medium of cinema itself, though some of Olivier Assayas' more trashy films capture well his style ("Boarding Gate", "Demonlover"). 7.9/10  Worth one viewing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Noisy, Too Generic for Its Own Good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jmillerdp
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film sounds really cool in concept. But, it is permeated by lots of yelling and (yes!) screaming. The film follows acclaimed Science Fiction writer Philip K. Dick's original short story fairly closely, except for its difference in tone and ending. The direction is fairly routine, as is the script. The showdown upon showdown upon showdown gets tiring at the end, and undoes the paranoia of what came before. The acting gets pretty hammy, adding to the melodrama. The visual and practical effects are very good for a lower-budget film. The film score is fairly routine. Philip K. Dick was one of the most visionary Science-Fiction writers. And, few of his stories have been made into good films, which is too bad. "Screamers" is one of those misses. ***** (5 Out of 10 Stars)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Close Deception
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    hellraiser7
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Trust has always been a fundamental problem throughout the years because by it's nature it's never been a solid foundation to begin with. Despite the length of time we spend with a person we never truly know them, from his/her past to even what they do when were not around them. This film is an under the radar sci-fi gem which is based on a short story by my favorite sci-fi author Philp K. Dick. I like the production value despite a low budget they were able to use it well. We see a post apocalyptic world that is just dirty, grimy, and desolate. There is no vegetation, it is always cold, there is hardly any sun, and the worst part is the radioactive winds that blow every once in a while. It really adds to the suspense because it gives it a feeling of isolation, the fact there is hardly any life stirring means there is no help that will come when you need it the most. I also like the effects, most to all are practical so there's no CGI, at least none I know about, though some effects are a tad dated but not bad in my book. I really like the designs of the Moble Sword/Screamer robots, whom are menacing from their capabilities not just in killing but in learning and the different types they were able to produce which unfortunately give them an edge. The music is good, action is decent liked the hill battle, but most importantly I really like the suspense where you are on constant edge and has a steady build because you're never sure of what you'll discover, and when you do it might be too late. Like one sequence which is my favorite is when Hendrickson is using a computer in the bunker to discover all the different types of Screamers, it was suspenseful on two counts; one the fact that he has only a limited amount of time to use it and second what information is left in the dark afterward which puts us a step behind and makes the stakes of survival even higher. The story is very good, I wouldn't say the concepts are entirely new but everything done right. I like how despite post apocalyptic conditions they still have high technology that still works. And certain aspects of the story somewhat acknowledges or are even prolific on our war for oil as well as terrorism. Characters are solid, Joe Hendrickson played by one of my favorite actors Peter Weller. I like that Joe is a person whom is layed back, has a sense of humor, tired of the war and just wants to go home. Same with Jessica Hansen play well by Jennifer Rubin whom despite someone on the shady end of things, is capable of being selfless, doesn't give her trust to just anyone. I like that both have a decent dynamic together, I bought it. I really like how the film gets at the issue of paranoia as well as the philosophical issue on what is a human. One of the best things about Philp's stories is how our perception of humanity can be blurred. We discover how far the robots come not just in replicating human's physically but even in feelings and thoughts, which makes you wonder if that constitutes them as human and not just machines. The only problems I really have are the pacing can be slow at some points. And also there isn't enough action, but then again this is more of a suspense thriller so I can't complain much. Overall, I think is a very good sci-fi that I think is worth checking out. Be careful of who you trust, it could be the last person you give it to. Rating: 3 and a half stars.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Doesn't compare to other PKD adaptations
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Zazwaz
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The story is about a war on a mining colony between two rivaling human factions. One of the factions has developed a new weapon: an army of robotic drones, nicknamed 'screamers', that hide underground and attack anything that they don't recognize. However, as the war is starting to draw to a close, the screamers refuse to work for the human faction that created them and it soon becomes clear that they have evolved on their own and now pose a threat to both sides. It's a neat idea and there are a lot of twists along the way, albeit very predictable ones. The writing could have taken a little more effort, the characters are shallow and the dialogue is very cheesy. The acting is also not that fantastic. Neither is the direction. It's all very average. Screamers is entertaining, but it doesn't stand out like other PKD adaptations such as Bladerunner or Minority Report. If you are looking for a fun sci-fi action flick, you might consider checking this one out, but if you are looking for depth then you're looking in the wrong place.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    False movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Shamek Stepien
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    By 2070 a galactic war has erupted between corporate and state powers fighting over resources on a Syrius 6B. After nuclear attacks by the NEB corporation the opposing Alliance employs automated robotics called Screamers to turn the tide of the war. Deep in the bowels of the planet the machines fabricate robot warfare, which in time evolve and start building bigger better products. Facing annihilation after the lengthened war captain Joe Hendricksson (Peter Weller) responds to a seize fire and embarks on a journey to the enemy bunker to undertake peace proceedings. Unfortunately for him the path may have been chosen too late... Post-mortem Philip K. Dick doesn't get much love from scriptwriters and the story "Second Variety" is no exception. For someone so cerebrally metaphysical movies based on his novels tend to take a action turn for the worse, dissolving the underlying essence of his stories and frontally assaulting with visual high-octane spectacles. "Screamers" is a low-budget take on the latter, albeit with some undeniable atmosphere to back it up. Nonetheless based on a clich&eacute;d ridden script with thinly developed characters spewing out tirades of one-liners occasionally interrupted by Shakespeare quotes, "Screamers" is an undeniable work in progress having some wider appeal, but lacking substance to stand the test of time. Budget and technological limitations to the movie decrease the overall quality, but the underpinning problem is one of limited tension, surprise and a multitude of scenes, which essentially lack sense or reason. Somewhere within this world lies potential much in the vein of "Bladerunner", but inept direction overly focused on churning out action brings Weller and the remaining cast down with its undertow. Plastic people with plastic morality ultimately divert attention from possibilities making us focus on the superficiality of the effort.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A mix of previous ideas but still entertaining
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moviefanman76-blogspot-com
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's hard for filmmakers to adapt stories to the screen, especially when they resemble stories that have been previously told. Turns out though director Christian Duguay evens out the story and though it still recalls other movies before its time, it still has elements in it that make it have a quality worth watching. The story of Screamers is loosely based off of Second Variety, a short story written by Philip K. Dick, the novelist of Blade Runner (1982) and Total Recall (1990). Dick is a very prestigious science fiction writer. His work has multiple twists and it always was a pleasant read. I also read Second Variety and much of it was fairly close to this movie. I actually enjoyed the film adaptation more than the story itself. Peter Weller is Joseph A. Hendricksson, an eccentric commander of an alliance bunker located on a planet known as Sirius 6B. Years before on Earth, there was nuclear fallout between two major groups; the N.E.B. (New Economic Block) and alliance workers over a special mineral that could change energy usage for transportation. So the fighting was moved to Sirius 6B where there has been a "Cold War" ever since. For the alliance to defend themselves, they created the Autonomous Mobile Sword or better known as, the screamer. The screamer is a mechanical life form that was equipped with a razor sharp blade so it could kill its enemy. But like all man made robots, they become self-aware and are now deciding for themselves who they should kill. Strangely enough, they are always updating their software, even making screamers that look like humans. So from there, audiences might make the connection of these traits between Skynet from The Terminator (1984), and characters not knowing who's real and who isn't from the novel Who Goes There, by John W. Campbell Jr. But for those few relations, Screamers can hold it's own as an entertaining sci-fi horror movie. It does not contain a lot of blood but it can be very suspenseful. Weller's performances are always a welcome to the screen. His ability to make his character sarcastic as is serious is a great touch. Andrew Lauer plays a innocent rookie named Ace Jefferson who tags along Hendricksson to meet with the N.E.B. command. The N.E.B. group these two visit is lead by the lovely Jennifer Ruben as Jessica Hanson. And with her is Roy Dupuis, who looks like Matthew McConaughey's distant cousin, who likes bugging another soldier who has some serious patience issues. The special effects are definitely dated. And it's really obvious when the camera is focused on the screamer itself but hey, the creature looks cool enough to look at. I think the most baffling part is how the machine keep upgrading their models. It makes you wonder, "What's going on down there". The set design is also something to see. A lot of does have the same color like from the movie Soldier (1998) but it at least looks real. The backgrounds actually resemble Chernobyl; which is eerie. Normand Corbeil composed the soundtrack and it also another strong point. When Hedricksson runs into a homeless child, the music makes the scene so heartbreaking. It's emotional and soft on the ears. The film variation of Second Variety does borough ideas from previous movies, but it's put together in such a way that it won't matter to the audience. The music is good and so is Weller's performance as a tired out war veteran.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A quite impressive but obviously flawed film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ozoneocean
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are two sides at war, but the war is winding down, it looks like one side has won, and the other side wants a truce... The trouble is that the autonomous weapons systems that the winning side deployed (called "screamers") and which helped them win, have other ideas. It stars Peter Weller, from Robocop. On the face of it, this looks like it'll be a by the numbers crappy scifi thriller horror with paper thin characters and wooden acting, and at best some testosterone fueled action movie sequences... That's what I thought anyway. I was very wrong. The acting was all extremely well done, especially by Weller. I was very impressed. Very good performances by all. The filming was atmospheric and well shot. Sets were great, props and costumes too. The story was full of emotion, it was thought provoking and well acted. This was an intelligent film! It was let down in two areas: 1. For most of the film the effects were very cheap, contrasting with the quality of the rest of it. 2. They lent a little too much on the cheap thriller aspect in parts of it, especially at the very end. It detracted a little from the intelligent themes and great acting. It's almost as if there were two competing forces at work: Highly competent, professional, pro, A-list film makers VS some strange incompetent cretin who BADLY wanted it to be a B-film. So it was flawed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sci-fi the way it was meant to be
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dragonsouls
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I decided to watch Screamers because I'm a big Phillip K. Dick fan, and this was a film based on one of his stories I never read yet. I had realized I overlooked the movie for way too long. I originally thought the movie was outdated, since I have experienced the human/robot social films for a while now, mostly with Battle Star Galactica, Blade Runner, i, Robot, and even Terminator. However, this is one of the first and original stories to convey the human/robot social conflicts and was glad to find the film on my video on demand lists. Worth mentioning first is the fine acting by Peter Weller, and I can't help but wonder why he never became more than a cult film actor, he truly could have been a big time action star on par with the other heavyweights of the 90s. And he really is convincing in this film, as a man who was on the brink of madness from desolation and hardship. As for the supporting cast, excellent performances for a low budget film. It reminded me of a time when all Science Fiction films were B-movies, before the Star Wars and Star Trek's came along. Come to think of it, the film had a decent sized budget for a 90s film. Nothing like other adapted Phillip K. Dick novels had gotten, such as Blade Runner, Minority Report, or Total Recall, but still, Screamers is a story that needed a bigger budget and if it had gotten one, this film would be a classic to be mentioned in the same breath as Dick's other masterpieces. The story reminded me of Blade Runner in some ways, and another short by Dick called "The Defenders" In a sense, Dick re-tells his themes over and over again, but nevertheless, Screamers is well written and unique in its own way. It's just perplexing why this film didn't come out in the 70s, or even early 80s, before the original Battle Star Galactica, and before Terminator, etc. This story would have made for a very pioneering film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sci-fi doing a great job to entertain
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (Richie@RanRightRealty.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a surprise movie meaning that turns out to be a great movie when you were expecting just a good one. The story has to be respected and understood. Then, what happens after that falls into place nicely. I am totally disappointed that they did not make a sequel to this winner. It was certainly set-up to do so. It has what I call genuine and satisfying scary moments brought to you via intelligence, not shock. Anytime you can engage the viewers imagination in a quality way after a movie viewing (as well as during) means you got a success on your hands. This is certainly one of those movies. The concept presented of something man has done that has mutated into something else is a good one. Now, if that something else wants to compete and then eliminate man, well you got my full attention thus this movie. Science Fiction treads a fine line of being believable or not when introducing a story. It doesn't have to be perfect to make its point. It has to be respectful and this movie respects the viewer. You will not have any trouble getting into this movie after the first few minutes. Then, all the dots start to connect and cause a viewing pleasure. It will suck you right in and when the ducks line up, scare you good and proper..Enjoy with a favorite snack so you don't bite your nails
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I would LOVE to see this movie remade with a good director and a large movie budget!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    picturetaker
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I originally saw this movie in the theatre. Many reviewers comment saying it should have gone straight to video but I don't think so. As this movie for its time was not that bad. I have seen this movie about 6 times since 1995 and every time I have enjoyed it. Could this movie have been better? Of course! But for what it cost and for what kind of movie it is, it is alright! Its such an interesting premise I would LOVE to see this movie remade with a good director and a large movie budget! As that would be GREAT! Screamers did have a OK script, it had a great story, OK character and storyline development. All in all it was an OK 1995 film. As most sci-fi goes it is not the worst at all! Screamers was an original movie and it is entertaining so if you get the opportunity to see it, I recommend you check it out if you like sci-fi movies.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Once it gets inside, that's when the killin' starts
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tieman64
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "We are now in a new form of schizophrenia. No more hysteria, no more projective paranoia, but this state of terror proper to the schizophrenic. [] The schizophrenic can no longer produce the limits of its own being. [] He is only a pure screen." - Baudrillard "That's right - Pinnochio's not a real little boy!" - Becker ("Screamers") Scifi author Harlan Ellison once took James Cameron to court, alleging that the director's 1984 film, "The Terminator", plagiarised "Demon With A Glass Hand" and "Soldier", two tales written by Ellison in the 1950s. But Cameron, a scifi nut, seems to have also borrowed heavily from Philip K Dick's "Second Variety", a 1953 short story which finds the world ravaged by war and mankind locked in combat with a race of machines. These machines were created for defence purposes, but eventually became "self aware", started evolving, making armies, factories and hunting down humans, whom they sought to completely eradicate. The machines then began creating terminator-like infiltration units; cyborgs which convincingly resemble humans and which are programmed to penetrate human bases. Dick's hero, a resourceful soldier, even resembles Cameron's Kyle Reese, and much of Dick's dialogue, desperate, fast and apocalyptic, recalls the frenetic banter in Cameron's "Terminator". While "Screamers", Christian Duguay's adaptation of Dick's "Second Variety", barely captures the tone and urgency of Dick's short story, Cameron's "Terminator" films do, though all these "adaptations" are more interesting in the way they demonstrate how Dick's approach to scifi changed from the 1950s onwards. All of Dick's novels are ontological conundrums, taking place in a landscape in which all "reality" seems to be constantly shifting, and in which worlds and selves constantly seem to fall apart. For Dick, there is no definitive reality, human identity itself is uncertain, nothing exists as it seems, and everything is simply a perception of pure information. In "Second Variety" these themes are approached in a fairly simple manner ("Is it an undercover killer robot or is it a human?", "What constitutes a robot?", "What constitutes a human?", "Aren't humans already cyborgs?", "How do I know what is real?", "How do I know what is machine?", "How do I know what I think I know?"), which is largely why it, and Dick's early work, remain his most popular. As Dick turned to drugs, stopped proof-reading, stopped perfecting and re-writing his stories, abandoned conventional narrative structures and started churning out novels quickly in a desperate attempt to pay his bills, his books, like his heroes and his own state of mind, became increasingly schizophrenic, paranoid and shapeless. Many deride Dick for this, but such a stance was the logical continuation of his early 1950s work. Today, Dick's later writing bare a striking similarity to postmodernist theories by thinkers such as Jameson, Baudrillard and Brian McHale. Dick anticipated the twenty-first century network society, a fragmented, culturally overloaded, media saturated world characterised by rapid technological change, constant movement and a dizzying, excessive and sometimes surreal aesthetic. For Dick, the future, our postmodern present, would morph into a sort of virtual reality game. A "consensual hallucination" in which all traditional demarcations or distinctions are erased. It is no longer an issue of there being a split between man and robot, but of man and technology constantly co-mingling, of both servicing the other, of all being technology, of man himself already being cybernetic, of the world already being cyberspacial, representational, all emotions faked, all behaviour play-acting, every object in quotes, everything grounded on the illusory. Whereas in an explicitly modernist film such as "Metropolis" the dichotomy between the original copy or experience (man) and the replication (machine) is very clear, in later Dickian films ("Blade Runner", Total Recall", "A Scanner Darkly", "Matrix", Cronenberg, Assayas etc - note how comparatively conservative Spielberg's version of Dick's "Minority Report" is) a crisis of representation occurs, as the signifier is now alienated from the object it signifies, a Deleuzian "schizoid existence" brought about by a breakdown "in the signifying chain". Unlike the apocalyptic, cosily hopeful rubble of "Terminator" and "Second Variety", later Dick also posits a urban, networked and mechanical landscape which engenders a consequential decline in organic feeling and sensibility. Men then become "consumers of illusion", an illusion of "belonging and participation" covering up massive industrial alienation. But every connection seems to lead back to corporations, a "soft fascism" whose grid it is impossible to escape. Here, everything is organised by the constant flow of money, all landscapes are advertising-saturated and the "goal" of commerce is to destroy history itself, to put its customers in the eternal Now, the big happy theme park of desires. No surprise then that one of Dick's last stories, "Stability", takes place in a world in which mankind doesn't progress anymore, despite the illusion of constant, hyper-motion. The story's solution? The invention of a Terminator-like time machine. If Dick got one thing wrong, it was in his assumption that this "schizoid existence" would trouble or traumatise man. Today, the opposite is true. Man's adapted. He loves his cage, even as he fantasises about Judgement Day. So postmodernist theory has itself has become what Brian McHale calls the "sister genre" of science fiction, both revolving around similar themes (What is reality? What constitutes the authentic human being?) and issues of technology and its effects on society and the individual subject. And while modernism was mainly interested in epistemology, the condition of knowledge, both Dick's scifi and postmodernism are governed by ontology and the basic conditions of existence. But "Screamers" and "The Terminator" films represent a kind of outdated, 1950s Philip K Dick, with nice easy, clear demarcations best suited for action cinema. Latter Dick is perhaps unsuited to the medium of cinema itself, though some of Olivier Assayas' more trashy films capture well his style ("Boarding Gate", "Demonlover"). 7.9/10  Worth one viewing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Noisy, Too Generic for Its Own Good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jmillerdp
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film sounds really cool in concept. But, it is permeated by lots of yelling and (yes!) screaming. The film follows acclaimed Science Fiction writer Philip K. Dick's original short story fairly closely, except for its difference in tone and ending. The direction is fairly routine, as is the script. The showdown upon showdown upon showdown gets tiring at the end, and undoes the paranoia of what came before. The acting gets pretty hammy, adding to the melodrama. The visual and practical effects are very good for a lower-budget film. The film score is fairly routine. Philip K. Dick was one of the most visionary Science-Fiction writers. And, few of his stories have been made into good films, which is too bad. "Screamers" is one of those misses. ***** (5 Out of 10 Stars)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Close Deception
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    hellraiser7
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Trust has always been a fundamental problem throughout the years because by it's nature it's never been a solid foundation to begin with. Despite the length of time we spend with a person we never truly know them, from his/her past to even what they do when were not around them. This film is an under the radar sci-fi gem which is based on a short story by my favorite sci-fi author Philp K. Dick. I like the production value despite a low budget they were able to use it well. We see a post apocalyptic world that is just dirty, grimy, and desolate. There is no vegetation, it is always cold, there is hardly any sun, and the worst part is the radioactive winds that blow every once in a while. It really adds to the suspense because it gives it a feeling of isolation, the fact there is hardly any life stirring means there is no help that will come when you need it the most. I also like the effects, most to all are practical so there's no CGI, at least none I know about, though some effects are a tad dated but not bad in my book. I really like the designs of the Moble Sword/Screamer robots, whom are menacing from their capabilities not just in killing but in learning and the different types they were able to produce which unfortunately give them an edge. The music is good, action is decent liked the hill battle, but most importantly I really like the suspense where you are on constant edge and has a steady build because you're never sure of what you'll discover, and when you do it might be too late. Like one sequence which is my favorite is when Hendrickson is using a computer in the bunker to discover all the different types of Screamers, it was suspenseful on two counts; one the fact that he has only a limited amount of time to use it and second what information is left in the dark afterward which puts us a step behind and makes the stakes of survival even higher. The story is very good, I wouldn't say the concepts are entirely new but everything done right. I like how despite post apocalyptic conditions they still have high technology that still works. And certain aspects of the story somewhat acknowledges or are even prolific on our war for oil as well as terrorism. Characters are solid, Joe Hendrickson played by one of my favorite actors Peter Weller. I like that Joe is a person whom is layed back, has a sense of humor, tired of the war and just wants to go home. Same with Jessica Hansen play well by Jennifer Rubin whom despite someone on the shady end of things, is capable of being selfless, doesn't give her trust to just anyone. I like that both have a decent dynamic together, I bought it. I really like how the film gets at the issue of paranoia as well as the philosophical issue on what is a human. One of the best things about Philp's stories is how our perception of humanity can be blurred. We discover how far the robots come not just in replicating human's physically but even in feelings and thoughts, which makes you wonder if that constitutes them as human and not just machines. The only problems I really have are the pacing can be slow at some points. And also there isn't enough action, but then again this is more of a suspense thriller so I can't complain much. Overall, I think is a very good sci-fi that I think is worth checking out. Be careful of who you trust, it could be the last person you give it to. Rating: 3 and a half stars.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Doesn't compare to other PKD adaptations
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Zazwaz
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The story is about a war on a mining colony between two rivaling human factions. One of the factions has developed a new weapon: an army of robotic drones, nicknamed 'screamers', that hide underground and attack anything that they don't recognize. However, as the war is starting to draw to a close, the screamers refuse to work for the human faction that created them and it soon becomes clear that they have evolved on their own and now pose a threat to both sides. It's a neat idea and there are a lot of twists along the way, albeit very predictable ones. The writing could have taken a little more effort, the characters are shallow and the dialogue is very cheesy. The acting is also not that fantastic. Neither is the direction. It's all very average. Screamers is entertaining, but it doesn't stand out like other PKD adaptations such as Bladerunner or Minority Report. If you are looking for a fun sci-fi action flick, you might consider checking this one out, but if you are looking for depth then you're looking in the wrong place.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    False movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Shamek Stepien
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    By 2070 a galactic war has erupted between corporate and state powers fighting over resources on a Syrius 6B. After nuclear attacks by the NEB corporation the opposing Alliance employs automated robotics called Screamers to turn the tide of the war. Deep in the bowels of the planet the machines fabricate robot warfare, which in time evolve and start building bigger better products. Facing annihilation after the lengthened war captain Joe Hendricksson (Peter Weller) responds to a seize fire and embarks on a journey to the enemy bunker to undertake peace proceedings. Unfortunately for him the path may have been chosen too late... Post-mortem Philip K. Dick doesn't get much love from scriptwriters and the story "Second Variety" is no exception. For someone so cerebrally metaphysical movies based on his novels tend to take a action turn for the worse, dissolving the underlying essence of his stories and frontally assaulting with visual high-octane spectacles. "Screamers" is a low-budget take on the latter, albeit with some undeniable atmosphere to back it up. Nonetheless based on a clich&eacute;d ridden script with thinly developed characters spewing out tirades of one-liners occasionally interrupted by Shakespeare quotes, "Screamers" is an undeniable work in progress having some wider appeal, but lacking substance to stand the test of time. Budget and technological limitations to the movie decrease the overall quality, but the underpinning problem is one of limited tension, surprise and a multitude of scenes, which essentially lack sense or reason. Somewhere within this world lies potential much in the vein of "Bladerunner", but inept direction overly focused on churning out action brings Weller and the remaining cast down with its undertow. Plastic people with plastic morality ultimately divert attention from possibilities making us focus on the superficiality of the effort.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A mix of previous ideas but still entertaining
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moviefanman76-blogspot-com
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's hard for filmmakers to adapt stories to the screen, especially when they resemble stories that have been previously told. Turns out though director Christian Duguay evens out the story and though it still recalls other movies before its time, it still has elements in it that make it have a quality worth watching. The story of Screamers is loosely based off of Second Variety, a short story written by Philip K. Dick, the novelist of Blade Runner (1982) and Total Recall (1990). Dick is a very prestigious science fiction writer. His work has multiple twists and it always was a pleasant read. I also read Second Variety and much of it was fairly close to this movie. I actually enjoyed the film adaptation more than the story itself. Peter Weller is Joseph A. Hendricksson, an eccentric commander of an alliance bunker located on a planet known as Sirius 6B. Years before on Earth, there was nuclear fallout between two major groups; the N.E.B. (New Economic Block) and alliance workers over a special mineral that could change energy usage for transportation. So the fighting was moved to Sirius 6B where there has been a "Cold War" ever since. For the alliance to defend themselves, they created the Autonomous Mobile Sword or better known as, the screamer. The screamer is a mechanical life form that was equipped with a razor sharp blade so it could kill its enemy. But like all man made robots, they become self-aware and are now deciding for themselves who they should kill. Strangely enough, they are always updating their software, even making screamers that look like humans. So from there, audiences might make the connection of these traits between Skynet from The Terminator (1984), and characters not knowing who's real and who isn't from the novel Who Goes There, by John W. Campbell Jr. But for those few relations, Screamers can hold it's own as an entertaining sci-fi horror movie. It does not contain a lot of blood but it can be very suspenseful. Weller's performances are always a welcome to the screen. His ability to make his character sarcastic as is serious is a great touch. Andrew Lauer plays a innocent rookie named Ace Jefferson who tags along Hendricksson to meet with the N.E.B. command. The N.E.B. group these two visit is lead by the lovely Jennifer Ruben as Jessica Hanson. And with her is Roy Dupuis, who looks like Matthew McConaughey's distant cousin, who likes bugging another soldier who has some serious patience issues. The special effects are definitely dated. And it's really obvious when the camera is focused on the screamer itself but hey, the creature looks cool enough to look at. I think the most baffling part is how the machine keep upgrading their models. It makes you wonder, "What's going on down there". The set design is also something to see. A lot of does have the same color like from the movie Soldier (1998) but it at least looks real. The backgrounds actually resemble Chernobyl; which is eerie. Normand Corbeil composed the soundtrack and it also another strong point. When Hedricksson runs into a homeless child, the music makes the scene so heartbreaking. It's emotional and soft on the ears. The film variation of Second Variety does borough ideas from previous movies, but it's put together in such a way that it won't matter to the audience. The music is good and so is Weller's performance as a tired out war veteran.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A quite impressive but obviously flawed film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ozoneocean
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are two sides at war, but the war is winding down, it looks like one side has won, and the other side wants a truce... The trouble is that the autonomous weapons systems that the winning side deployed (called "screamers") and which helped them win, have other ideas. It stars Peter Weller, from Robocop. On the face of it, this looks like it'll be a by the numbers crappy scifi thriller horror with paper thin characters and wooden acting, and at best some testosterone fueled action movie sequences... That's what I thought anyway. I was very wrong. The acting was all extremely well done, especially by Weller. I was very impressed. Very good performances by all. The filming was atmospheric and well shot. Sets were great, props and costumes too. The story was full of emotion, it was thought provoking and well acted. This was an intelligent film! It was let down in two areas: 1. For most of the film the effects were very cheap, contrasting with the quality of the rest of it. 2. They lent a little too much on the cheap thriller aspect in parts of it, especially at the very end. It detracted a little from the intelligent themes and great acting. It's almost as if there were two competing forces at work: Highly competent, professional, pro, A-list film makers VS some strange incompetent cretin who BADLY wanted it to be a B-film. So it was flawed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sci-fi the way it was meant to be
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dragonsouls
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I decided to watch Screamers because I'm a big Phillip K. Dick fan, and this was a film based on one of his stories I never read yet. I had realized I overlooked the movie for way too long. I originally thought the movie was outdated, since I have experienced the human/robot social films for a while now, mostly with Battle Star Galactica, Blade Runner, i, Robot, and even Terminator. However, this is one of the first and original stories to convey the human/robot social conflicts and was glad to find the film on my video on demand lists. Worth mentioning first is the fine acting by Peter Weller, and I can't help but wonder why he never became more than a cult film actor, he truly could have been a big time action star on par with the other heavyweights of the 90s. And he really is convincing in this film, as a man who was on the brink of madness from desolation and hardship. As for the supporting cast, excellent performances for a low budget film. It reminded me of a time when all Science Fiction films were B-movies, before the Star Wars and Star Trek's came along. Come to think of it, the film had a decent sized budget for a 90s film. Nothing like other adapted Phillip K. Dick novels had gotten, such as Blade Runner, Minority Report, or Total Recall, but still, Screamers is a story that needed a bigger budget and if it had gotten one, this film would be a classic to be mentioned in the same breath as Dick's other masterpieces. The story reminded me of Blade Runner in some ways, and another short by Dick called "The Defenders" In a sense, Dick re-tells his themes over and over again, but nevertheless, Screamers is well written and unique in its own way. It's just perplexing why this film didn't come out in the 70s, or even early 80s, before the original Battle Star Galactica, and before Terminator, etc. This story would have made for a very pioneering film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sci-fi doing a great job to entertain
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (Richie@RanRightRealty.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a surprise movie meaning that turns out to be a great movie when you were expecting just a good one. The story has to be respected and understood. Then, what happens after that falls into place nicely. I am totally disappointed that they did not make a sequel to this winner. It was certainly set-up to do so. It has what I call genuine and satisfying scary moments brought to you via intelligence, not shock. Anytime you can engage the viewers imagination in a quality way after a movie viewing (as well as during) means you got a success on your hands. This is certainly one of those movies. The concept presented of something man has done that has mutated into something else is a good one. Now, if that something else wants to compete and then eliminate man, well you got my full attention thus this movie. Science Fiction treads a fine line of being believable or not when introducing a story. It doesn't have to be perfect to make its point. It has to be respectful and this movie respects the viewer. You will not have any trouble getting into this movie after the first few minutes. Then, all the dots start to connect and cause a viewing pleasure. It will suck you right in and when the ducks line up, scare you good and proper..Enjoy with a favorite snack so you don't bite your nails
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I would LOVE to see this movie remade with a good director and a large movie budget!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    picturetaker
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I originally saw this movie in the theatre. Many reviewers comment saying it should have gone straight to video but I don't think so. As this movie for its time was not that bad. I have seen this movie about 6 times since 1995 and every time I have enjoyed it. Could this movie have been better? Of course! But for what it cost and for what kind of movie it is, it is alright! Its such an interesting premise I would LOVE to see this movie remade with a good director and a large movie budget! As that would be GREAT! Screamers did have a OK script, it had a great story, OK character and storyline development. All in all it was an OK 1995 film. As most sci-fi goes it is not the worst at all! Screamers was an original movie and it is entertaining so if you get the opportunity to see it, I recommend you check it out if you like sci-fi movies.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Once it gets inside, that's when the killin' starts
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tieman64
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "We are now in a new form of schizophrenia. No more hysteria, no more projective paranoia, but this state of terror proper to the schizophrenic. [] The schizophrenic can no longer produce the limits of its own being. [] He is only a pure screen." - Baudrillard "That's right - Pinnochio's not a real little boy!" - Becker ("Screamers") Scifi author Harlan Ellison once took James Cameron to court, alleging that the director's 1984 film, "The Terminator", plagiarised "Demon With A Glass Hand" and "Soldier", two tales written by Ellison in the 1950s. But Cameron, a scifi nut, seems to have also borrowed heavily from Philip K Dick's "Second Variety", a 1953 short story which finds the world ravaged by war and mankind locked in combat with a race of machines. These machines were created for defence purposes, but eventually became "self aware", started evolving, making armies, factories and hunting down humans, whom they sought to completely eradicate. The machines then began creating terminator-like infiltration units; cyborgs which convincingly resemble humans and which are programmed to penetrate human bases. Dick's hero, a resourceful soldier, even resembles Cameron's Kyle Reese, and much of Dick's dialogue, desperate, fast and apocalyptic, recalls the frenetic banter in Cameron's "Terminator". While "Screamers", Christian Duguay's adaptation of Dick's "Second Variety", barely captures the tone and urgency of Dick's short story, Cameron's "Terminator" films do, though all these "adaptations" are more interesting in the way they demonstrate how Dick's approach to scifi changed from the 1950s onwards. All of Dick's novels are ontological conundrums, taking place in a landscape in which all "reality" seems to be constantly shifting, and in which worlds and selves constantly seem to fall apart. For Dick, there is no definitive reality, human identity itself is uncertain, nothing exists as it seems, and everything is simply a perception of pure information. In "Second Variety" these themes are approached in a fairly simple manner ("Is it an undercover killer robot or is it a human?", "What constitutes a robot?", "What constitutes a human?", "Aren't humans already cyborgs?", "How do I know what is real?", "How do I know what is machine?", "How do I know what I think I know?"), which is largely why it, and Dick's early work, remain his most popular. As Dick turned to drugs, stopped proof-reading, stopped perfecting and re-writing his stories, abandoned conventional narrative structures and started churning out novels quickly in a desperate attempt to pay his bills, his books, like his heroes and his own state of mind, became increasingly schizophrenic, paranoid and shapeless. Many deride Dick for this, but such a stance was the logical continuation of his early 1950s work. Today, Dick's later writing bare a striking similarity to postmodernist theories by thinkers such as Jameson, Baudrillard and Brian McHale. Dick anticipated the twenty-first century network society, a fragmented, culturally overloaded, media saturated world characterised by rapid technological change, constant movement and a dizzying, excessive and sometimes surreal aesthetic. For Dick, the future, our postmodern present, would morph into a sort of virtual reality game. A "consensual hallucination" in which all traditional demarcations or distinctions are erased. It is no longer an issue of there being a split between man and robot, but of man and technology constantly co-mingling, of both servicing the other, of all being technology, of man himself already being cybernetic, of the world already being cyberspacial, representational, all emotions faked, all behaviour play-acting, every object in quotes, everything grounded on the illusory. Whereas in an explicitly modernist film such as "Metropolis" the dichotomy between the original copy or experience (man) and the replication (machine) is very clear, in later Dickian films ("Blade Runner", Total Recall", "A Scanner Darkly", "Matrix", Cronenberg, Assayas etc - note how comparatively conservative Spielberg's version of Dick's "Minority Report" is) a crisis of representation occurs, as the signifier is now alienated from the object it signifies, a Deleuzian "schizoid existence" brought about by a breakdown "in the signifying chain". Unlike the apocalyptic, cosily hopeful rubble of "Terminator" and "Second Variety", later Dick also posits a urban, networked and mechanical landscape which engenders a consequential decline in organic feeling and sensibility. Men then become "consumers of illusion", an illusion of "belonging and participation" covering up massive industrial alienation. But every connection seems to lead back to corporations, a "soft fascism" whose grid it is impossible to escape. Here, everything is organised by the constant flow of money, all landscapes are advertising-saturated and the "goal" of commerce is to destroy history itself, to put its customers in the eternal Now, the big happy theme park of desires. No surprise then that one of Dick's last stories, "Stability", takes place in a world in which mankind doesn't progress anymore, despite the illusion of constant, hyper-motion. The story's solution? The invention of a Terminator-like time machine. If Dick got one thing wrong, it was in his assumption that this "schizoid existence" would trouble or traumatise man. Today, the opposite is true. Man's adapted. He loves his cage, even as he fantasises about Judgement Day. So postmodernist theory has itself has become what Brian McHale calls the "sister genre" of science fiction, both revolving around similar themes (What is reality? What constitutes the authentic human being?) and issues of technology and its effects on society and the individual subject. And while modernism was mainly interested in epistemology, the condition of knowledge, both Dick's scifi and postmodernism are governed by ontology and the basic conditions of existence. But "Screamers" and "The Terminator" films represent a kind of outdated, 1950s Philip K Dick, with nice easy, clear demarcations best suited for action cinema. Latter Dick is perhaps unsuited to the medium of cinema itself, though some of Olivier Assayas' more trashy films capture well his style ("Boarding Gate", "Demonlover"). 7.9/10  Worth one viewing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Noisy, Too Generic for Its Own Good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jmillerdp
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film sounds really cool in concept. But, it is permeated by lots of yelling and (yes!) screaming. The film follows acclaimed Science Fiction writer Philip K. Dick's original short story fairly closely, except for its difference in tone and ending. The direction is fairly routine, as is the script. The showdown upon showdown upon showdown gets tiring at the end, and undoes the paranoia of what came before. The acting gets pretty hammy, adding to the melodrama. The visual and practical effects are very good for a lower-budget film. The film score is fairly routine. Philip K. Dick was one of the most visionary Science-Fiction writers. And, few of his stories have been made into good films, which is too bad. "Screamers" is one of those misses. ***** (5 Out of 10 Stars)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Close Deception
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    hellraiser7
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Trust has always been a fundamental problem throughout the years because by it's nature it's never been a solid foundation to begin with. Despite the length of time we spend with a person we never truly know them, from his/her past to even what they do when were not around them. This film is an under the radar sci-fi gem which is based on a short story by my favorite sci-fi author Philp K. Dick. I like the production value despite a low budget they were able to use it well. We see a post apocalyptic world that is just dirty, grimy, and desolate. There is no vegetation, it is always cold, there is hardly any sun, and the worst part is the radioactive winds that blow every once in a while. It really adds to the suspense because it gives it a feeling of isolation, the fact there is hardly any life stirring means there is no help that will come when you need it the most. I also like the effects, most to all are practical so there's no CGI, at least none I know about, though some effects are a tad dated but not bad in my book. I really like the designs of the Moble Sword/Screamer robots, whom are menacing from their capabilities not just in killing but in learning and the different types they were able to produce which unfortunately give them an edge. The music is good, action is decent liked the hill battle, but most importantly I really like the suspense where you are on constant edge and has a steady build because you're never sure of what you'll discover, and when you do it might be too late. Like one sequence which is my favorite is when Hendrickson is using a computer in the bunker to discover all the different types of Screamers, it was suspenseful on two counts; one the fact that he has only a limited amount of time to use it and second what information is left in the dark afterward which puts us a step behind and makes the stakes of survival even higher. The story is very good, I wouldn't say the concepts are entirely new but everything done right. I like how despite post apocalyptic conditions they still have high technology that still works. And certain aspects of the story somewhat acknowledges or are even prolific on our war for oil as well as terrorism. Characters are solid, Joe Hendrickson played by one of my favorite actors Peter Weller. I like that Joe is a person whom is layed back, has a sense of humor, tired of the war and just wants to go home. Same with Jessica Hansen play well by Jennifer Rubin whom despite someone on the shady end of things, is capable of being selfless, doesn't give her trust to just anyone. I like that both have a decent dynamic together, I bought it. I really like how the film gets at the issue of paranoia as well as the philosophical issue on what is a human. One of the best things about Philp's stories is how our perception of humanity can be blurred. We discover how far the robots come not just in replicating human's physically but even in feelings and thoughts, which makes you wonder if that constitutes them as human and not just machines. The only problems I really have are the pacing can be slow at some points. And also there isn't enough action, but then again this is more of a suspense thriller so I can't complain much. Overall, I think is a very good sci-fi that I think is worth checking out. Be careful of who you trust, it could be the last person you give it to. Rating: 3 and a half stars.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Doesn't compare to other PKD adaptations
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Zazwaz
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The story is about a war on a mining colony between two rivaling human factions. One of the factions has developed a new weapon: an army of robotic drones, nicknamed 'screamers', that hide underground and attack anything that they don't recognize. However, as the war is starting to draw to a close, the screamers refuse to work for the human faction that created them and it soon becomes clear that they have evolved on their own and now pose a threat to both sides. It's a neat idea and there are a lot of twists along the way, albeit very predictable ones. The writing could have taken a little more effort, the characters are shallow and the dialogue is very cheesy. The acting is also not that fantastic. Neither is the direction. It's all very average. Screamers is entertaining, but it doesn't stand out like other PKD adaptations such as Bladerunner or Minority Report. If you are looking for a fun sci-fi action flick, you might consider checking this one out, but if you are looking for depth then you're looking in the wrong place.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    False movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Shamek Stepien
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    By 2070 a galactic war has erupted between corporate and state powers fighting over resources on a Syrius 6B. After nuclear attacks by the NEB corporation the opposing Alliance employs automated robotics called Screamers to turn the tide of the war. Deep in the bowels of the planet the machines fabricate robot warfare, which in time evolve and start building bigger better products. Facing annihilation after the lengthened war captain Joe Hendricksson (Peter Weller) responds to a seize fire and embarks on a journey to the enemy bunker to undertake peace proceedings. Unfortunately for him the path may have been chosen too late... Post-mortem Philip K. Dick doesn't get much love from scriptwriters and the story "Second Variety" is no exception. For someone so cerebrally metaphysical movies based on his novels tend to take a action turn for the worse, dissolving the underlying essence of his stories and frontally assaulting with visual high-octane spectacles. "Screamers" is a low-budget take on the latter, albeit with some undeniable atmosphere to back it up. Nonetheless based on a clich&eacute;d ridden script with thinly developed characters spewing out tirades of one-liners occasionally interrupted by Shakespeare quotes, "Screamers" is an undeniable work in progress having some wider appeal, but lacking substance to stand the test of time. Budget and technological limitations to the movie decrease the overall quality, but the underpinning problem is one of limited tension, surprise and a multitude of scenes, which essentially lack sense or reason. Somewhere within this world lies potential much in the vein of "Bladerunner", but inept direction overly focused on churning out action brings Weller and the remaining cast down with its undertow. Plastic people with plastic morality ultimately divert attention from possibilities making us focus on the superficiality of the effort.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A mix of previous ideas but still entertaining
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moviefanman76-blogspot-com
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's hard for filmmakers to adapt stories to the screen, especially when they resemble stories that have been previously told. Turns out though director Christian Duguay evens out the story and though it still recalls other movies before its time, it still has elements in it that make it have a quality worth watching. The story of Screamers is loosely based off of Second Variety, a short story written by Philip K. Dick, the novelist of Blade Runner (1982) and Total Recall (1990). Dick is a very prestigious science fiction writer. His work has multiple twists and it always was a pleasant read. I also read Second Variety and much of it was fairly close to this movie. I actually enjoyed the film adaptation more than the story itself. Peter Weller is Joseph A. Hendricksson, an eccentric commander of an alliance bunker located on a planet known as Sirius 6B. Years before on Earth, there was nuclear fallout between two major groups; the N.E.B. (New Economic Block) and alliance workers over a special mineral that could change energy usage for transportation. So the fighting was moved to Sirius 6B where there has been a "Cold War" ever since. For the alliance to defend themselves, they created the Autonomous Mobile Sword or better known as, the screamer. The screamer is a mechanical life form that was equipped with a razor sharp blade so it could kill its enemy. But like all man made robots, they become self-aware and are now deciding for themselves who they should kill. Strangely enough, they are always updating their software, even making screamers that look like humans. So from there, audiences might make the connection of these traits between Skynet from The Terminator (1984), and characters not knowing who's real and who isn't from the novel Who Goes There, by John W. Campbell Jr. But for those few relations, Screamers can hold it's own as an entertaining sci-fi horror movie. It does not contain a lot of blood but it can be very suspenseful. Weller's performances are always a welcome to the screen. His ability to make his character sarcastic as is serious is a great touch. Andrew Lauer plays a innocent rookie named Ace Jefferson who tags along Hendricksson to meet with the N.E.B. command. The N.E.B. group these two visit is lead by the lovely Jennifer Ruben as Jessica Hanson. And with her is Roy Dupuis, who looks like Matthew McConaughey's distant cousin, who likes bugging another soldier who has some serious patience issues. The special effects are definitely dated. And it's really obvious when the camera is focused on the screamer itself but hey, the creature looks cool enough to look at. I think the most baffling part is how the machine keep upgrading their models. It makes you wonder, "What's going on down there". The set design is also something to see. A lot of does have the same color like from the movie Soldier (1998) but it at least looks real. The backgrounds actually resemble Chernobyl; which is eerie. Normand Corbeil composed the soundtrack and it also another strong point. When Hedricksson runs into a homeless child, the music makes the scene so heartbreaking. It's emotional and soft on the ears. The film variation of Second Variety does borough ideas from previous movies, but it's put together in such a way that it won't matter to the audience. The music is good and so is Weller's performance as a tired out war veteran.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A quite impressive but obviously flawed film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ozoneocean
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are two sides at war, but the war is winding down, it looks like one side has won, and the other side wants a truce... The trouble is that the autonomous weapons systems that the winning side deployed (called "screamers") and which helped them win, have other ideas. It stars Peter Weller, from Robocop. On the face of it, this looks like it'll be a by the numbers crappy scifi thriller horror with paper thin characters and wooden acting, and at best some testosterone fueled action movie sequences... That's what I thought anyway. I was very wrong. The acting was all extremely well done, especially by Weller. I was very impressed. Very good performances by all. The filming was atmospheric and well shot. Sets were great, props and costumes too. The story was full of emotion, it was thought provoking and well acted. This was an intelligent film! It was let down in two areas: 1. For most of the film the effects were very cheap, contrasting with the quality of the rest of it. 2. They lent a little too much on the cheap thriller aspect in parts of it, especially at the very end. It detracted a little from the intelligent themes and great acting. It's almost as if there were two competing forces at work: Highly competent, professional, pro, A-list film makers VS some strange incompetent cretin who BADLY wanted it to be a B-film. So it was flawed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sci-fi the way it was meant to be
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dragonsouls
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I decided to watch Screamers because I'm a big Phillip K. Dick fan, and this was a film based on one of his stories I never read yet. I had realized I overlooked the movie for way too long. I originally thought the movie was outdated, since I have experienced the human/robot social films for a while now, mostly with Battle Star Galactica, Blade Runner, i, Robot, and even Terminator. However, this is one of the first and original stories to convey the human/robot social conflicts and was glad to find the film on my video on demand lists. Worth mentioning first is the fine acting by Peter Weller, and I can't help but wonder why he never became more than a cult film actor, he truly could have been a big time action star on par with the other heavyweights of the 90s. And he really is convincing in this film, as a man who was on the brink of madness from desolation and hardship. As for the supporting cast, excellent performances for a low budget film. It reminded me of a time when all Science Fiction films were B-movies, before the Star Wars and Star Trek's came along. Come to think of it, the film had a decent sized budget for a 90s film. Nothing like other adapted Phillip K. Dick novels had gotten, such as Blade Runner, Minority Report, or Total Recall, but still, Screamers is a story that needed a bigger budget and if it had gotten one, this film would be a classic to be mentioned in the same breath as Dick's other masterpieces. The story reminded me of Blade Runner in some ways, and another short by Dick called "The Defenders" In a sense, Dick re-tells his themes over and over again, but nevertheless, Screamers is well written and unique in its own way. It's just perplexing why this film didn't come out in the 70s, or even early 80s, before the original Battle Star Galactica, and before Terminator, etc. This story would have made for a very pioneering film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sci-fi doing a great job to entertain
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (Richie@RanRightRealty.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a surprise movie meaning that turns out to be a great movie when you were expecting just a good one. The story has to be respected and understood. Then, what happens after that falls into place nicely. I am totally disappointed that they did not make a sequel to this winner. It was certainly set-up to do so. It has what I call genuine and satisfying scary moments brought to you via intelligence, not shock. Anytime you can engage the viewers imagination in a quality way after a movie viewing (as well as during) means you got a success on your hands. This is certainly one of those movies. The concept presented of something man has done that has mutated into something else is a good one. Now, if that something else wants to compete and then eliminate man, well you got my full attention thus this movie. Science Fiction treads a fine line of being believable or not when introducing a story. It doesn't have to be perfect to make its point. It has to be respectful and this movie respects the viewer. You will not have any trouble getting into this movie after the first few minutes. Then, all the dots start to connect and cause a viewing pleasure. It will suck you right in and when the ducks line up, scare you good and proper..Enjoy with a favorite snack so you don't bite your nails
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I would LOVE to see this movie remade with a good director and a large movie budget!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    picturetaker
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I originally saw this movie in the theatre. Many reviewers comment saying it should have gone straight to video but I don't think so. As this movie for its time was not that bad. I have seen this movie about 6 times since 1995 and every time I have enjoyed it. Could this movie have been better? Of course! But for what it cost and for what kind of movie it is, it is alright! Its such an interesting premise I would LOVE to see this movie remade with a good director and a large movie budget! As that would be GREAT! Screamers did have a OK script, it had a great story, OK character and storyline development. All in all it was an OK 1995 film. As most sci-fi goes it is not the worst at all! Screamers was an original movie and it is entertaining so if you get the opportunity to see it, I recommend you check it out if you like sci-fi movies.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Once it gets inside, that's when the killin' starts
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tieman64
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "We are now in a new form of schizophrenia. No more hysteria, no more projective paranoia, but this state of terror proper to the schizophrenic. [] The schizophrenic can no longer produce the limits of its own being. [] He is only a pure screen." - Baudrillard "That's right - Pinnochio's not a real little boy!" - Becker ("Screamers") Scifi author Harlan Ellison once took James Cameron to court, alleging that the director's 1984 film, "The Terminator", plagiarised "Demon With A Glass Hand" and "Soldier", two tales written by Ellison in the 1950s. But Cameron, a scifi nut, seems to have also borrowed heavily from Philip K Dick's "Second Variety", a 1953 short story which finds the world ravaged by war and mankind locked in combat with a race of machines. These machines were created for defence purposes, but eventually became "self aware", started evolving, making armies, factories and hunting down humans, whom they sought to completely eradicate. The machines then began creating terminator-like infiltration units; cyborgs which convincingly resemble humans and which are programmed to penetrate human bases. Dick's hero, a resourceful soldier, even resembles Cameron's Kyle Reese, and much of Dick's dialogue, desperate, fast and apocalyptic, recalls the frenetic banter in Cameron's "Terminator". While "Screamers", Christian Duguay's adaptation of Dick's "Second Variety", barely captures the tone and urgency of Dick's short story, Cameron's "Terminator" films do, though all these "adaptations" are more interesting in the way they demonstrate how Dick's approach to scifi changed from the 1950s onwards. All of Dick's novels are ontological conundrums, taking place in a landscape in which all "reality" seems to be constantly shifting, and in which worlds and selves constantly seem to fall apart. For Dick, there is no definitive reality, human identity itself is uncertain, nothing exists as it seems, and everything is simply a perception of pure information. In "Second Variety" these themes are approached in a fairly simple manner ("Is it an undercover killer robot or is it a human?", "What constitutes a robot?", "What constitutes a human?", "Aren't humans already cyborgs?", "How do I know what is real?", "How do I know what is machine?", "How do I know what I think I know?"), which is largely why it, and Dick's early work, remain his most popular. As Dick turned to drugs, stopped proof-reading, stopped perfecting and re-writing his stories, abandoned conventional narrative structures and started churning out novels quickly in a desperate attempt to pay his bills, his books, like his heroes and his own state of mind, became increasingly schizophrenic, paranoid and shapeless. Many deride Dick for this, but such a stance was the logical continuation of his early 1950s work. Today, Dick's later writing bare a striking similarity to postmodernist theories by thinkers such as Jameson, Baudrillard and Brian McHale. Dick anticipated the twenty-first century network society, a fragmented, culturally overloaded, media saturated world characterised by rapid technological change, constant movement and a dizzying, excessive and sometimes surreal aesthetic. For Dick, the future, our postmodern present, would morph into a sort of virtual reality game. A "consensual hallucination" in which all traditional demarcations or distinctions are erased. It is no longer an issue of there being a split between man and robot, but of man and technology constantly co-mingling, of both servicing the other, of all being technology, of man himself already being cybernetic, of the world already being cyberspacial, representational, all emotions faked, all behaviour play-acting, every object in quotes, everything grounded on the illusory. Whereas in an explicitly modernist film such as "Metropolis" the dichotomy between the original copy or experience (man) and the replication (machine) is very clear, in later Dickian films ("Blade Runner", Total Recall", "A Scanner Darkly", "Matrix", Cronenberg, Assayas etc - note how comparatively conservative Spielberg's version of Dick's "Minority Report" is) a crisis of representation occurs, as the signifier is now alienated from the object it signifies, a Deleuzian "schizoid existence" brought about by a breakdown "in the signifying chain". Unlike the apocalyptic, cosily hopeful rubble of "Terminator" and "Second Variety", later Dick also posits a urban, networked and mechanical landscape which engenders a consequential decline in organic feeling and sensibility. Men then become "consumers of illusion", an illusion of "belonging and participation" covering up massive industrial alienation. But every connection seems to lead back to corporations, a "soft fascism" whose grid it is impossible to escape. Here, everything is organised by the constant flow of money, all landscapes are advertising-saturated and the "goal" of commerce is to destroy history itself, to put its customers in the eternal Now, the big happy theme park of desires. No surprise then that one of Dick's last stories, "Stability", takes place in a world in which mankind doesn't progress anymore, despite the illusion of constant, hyper-motion. The story's solution? The invention of a Terminator-like time machine. If Dick got one thing wrong, it was in his assumption that this "schizoid existence" would trouble or traumatise man. Today, the opposite is true. Man's adapted. He loves his cage, even as he fantasises about Judgement Day. So postmodernist theory has itself has become what Brian McHale calls the "sister genre" of science fiction, both revolving around similar themes (What is reality? What constitutes the authentic human being?) and issues of technology and its effects on society and the individual subject. And while modernism was mainly interested in epistemology, the condition of knowledge, both Dick's scifi and postmodernism are governed by ontology and the basic conditions of existence. But "Screamers" and "The Terminator" films represent a kind of outdated, 1950s Philip K Dick, with nice easy, clear demarcations best suited for action cinema. Latter Dick is perhaps unsuited to the medium of cinema itself, though some of Olivier Assayas' more trashy films capture well his style ("Boarding Gate", "Demonlover"). 7.9/10  Worth one viewing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Noisy, Too Generic for Its Own Good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jmillerdp
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film sounds really cool in concept. But, it is permeated by lots of yelling and (yes!) screaming. The film follows acclaimed Science Fiction writer Philip K. Dick's original short story fairly closely, except for its difference in tone and ending. The direction is fairly routine, as is the script. The showdown upon showdown upon showdown gets tiring at the end, and undoes the paranoia of what came before. The acting gets pretty hammy, adding to the melodrama. The visual and practical effects are very good for a lower-budget film. The film score is fairly routine. Philip K. Dick was one of the most visionary Science-Fiction writers. And, few of his stories have been made into good films, which is too bad. "Screamers" is one of those misses. ***** (5 Out of 10 Stars)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Close Deception
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    hellraiser7
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Trust has always been a fundamental problem throughout the years because by it's nature it's never been a solid foundation to begin with. Despite the length of time we spend with a person we never truly know them, from his/her past to even what they do when were not around them. This film is an under the radar sci-fi gem which is based on a short story by my favorite sci-fi author Philp K. Dick. I like the production value despite a low budget they were able to use it well. We see a post apocalyptic world that is just dirty, grimy, and desolate. There is no vegetation, it is always cold, there is hardly any sun, and the worst part is the radioactive winds that blow every once in a while. It really adds to the suspense because it gives it a feeling of isolation, the fact there is hardly any life stirring means there is no help that will come when you need it the most. I also like the effects, most to all are practical so there's no CGI, at least none I know about, though some effects are a tad dated but not bad in my book. I really like the designs of the Moble Sword/Screamer robots, whom are menacing from their capabilities not just in killing but in learning and the different types they were able to produce which unfortunately give them an edge. The music is good, action is decent liked the hill battle, but most importantly I really like the suspense where you are on constant edge and has a steady build because you're never sure of what you'll discover, and when you do it might be too late. Like one sequence which is my favorite is when Hendrickson is using a computer in the bunker to discover all the different types of Screamers, it was suspenseful on two counts; one the fact that he has only a limited amount of time to use it and second what information is left in the dark afterward which puts us a step behind and makes the stakes of survival even higher. The story is very good, I wouldn't say the concepts are entirely new but everything done right. I like how despite post apocalyptic conditions they still have high technology that still works. And certain aspects of the story somewhat acknowledges or are even prolific on our war for oil as well as terrorism. Characters are solid, Joe Hendrickson played by one of my favorite actors Peter Weller. I like that Joe is a person whom is layed back, has a sense of humor, tired of the war and just wants to go home. Same with Jessica Hansen play well by Jennifer Rubin whom despite someone on the shady end of things, is capable of being selfless, doesn't give her trust to just anyone. I like that both have a decent dynamic together, I bought it. I really like how the film gets at the issue of paranoia as well as the philosophical issue on what is a human. One of the best things about Philp's stories is how our perception of humanity can be blurred. We discover how far the robots come not just in replicating human's physically but even in feelings and thoughts, which makes you wonder if that constitutes them as human and not just machines. The only problems I really have are the pacing can be slow at some points. And also there isn't enough action, but then again this is more of a suspense thriller so I can't complain much. Overall, I think is a very good sci-fi that I think is worth checking out. Be careful of who you trust, it could be the last person you give it to. Rating: 3 and a half stars.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Doesn't compare to other PKD adaptations
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Zazwaz
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The story is about a war on a mining colony between two rivaling human factions. One of the factions has developed a new weapon: an army of robotic drones, nicknamed 'screamers', that hide underground and attack anything that they don't recognize. However, as the war is starting to draw to a close, the screamers refuse to work for the human faction that created them and it soon becomes clear that they have evolved on their own and now pose a threat to both sides. It's a neat idea and there are a lot of twists along the way, albeit very predictable ones. The writing could have taken a little more effort, the characters are shallow and the dialogue is very cheesy. The acting is also not that fantastic. Neither is the direction. It's all very average. Screamers is entertaining, but it doesn't stand out like other PKD adaptations such as Bladerunner or Minority Report. If you are looking for a fun sci-fi action flick, you might consider checking this one out, but if you are looking for depth then you're looking in the wrong place.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    False movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Shamek Stepien
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    By 2070 a galactic war has erupted between corporate and state powers fighting over resources on a Syrius 6B. After nuclear attacks by the NEB corporation the opposing Alliance employs automated robotics called Screamers to turn the tide of the war. Deep in the bowels of the planet the machines fabricate robot warfare, which in time evolve and start building bigger better products. Facing annihilation after the lengthened war captain Joe Hendricksson (Peter Weller) responds to a seize fire and embarks on a journey to the enemy bunker to undertake peace proceedings. Unfortunately for him the path may have been chosen too late... Post-mortem Philip K. Dick doesn't get much love from scriptwriters and the story "Second Variety" is no exception. For someone so cerebrally metaphysical movies based on his novels tend to take a action turn for the worse, dissolving the underlying essence of his stories and frontally assaulting with visual high-octane spectacles. "Screamers" is a low-budget take on the latter, albeit with some undeniable atmosphere to back it up. Nonetheless based on a clich&eacute;d ridden script with thinly developed characters spewing out tirades of one-liners occasionally interrupted by Shakespeare quotes, "Screamers" is an undeniable work in progress having some wider appeal, but lacking substance to stand the test of time. Budget and technological limitations to the movie decrease the overall quality, but the underpinning problem is one of limited tension, surprise and a multitude of scenes, which essentially lack sense or reason. Somewhere within this world lies potential much in the vein of "Bladerunner", but inept direction overly focused on churning out action brings Weller and the remaining cast down with its undertow. Plastic people with plastic morality ultimately divert attention from possibilities making us focus on the superficiality of the effort.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A mix of previous ideas but still entertaining
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moviefanman76-blogspot-com
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's hard for filmmakers to adapt stories to the screen, especially when they resemble stories that have been previously told. Turns out though director Christian Duguay evens out the story and though it still recalls other movies before its time, it still has elements in it that make it have a quality worth watching. The story of Screamers is loosely based off of Second Variety, a short story written by Philip K. Dick, the novelist of Blade Runner (1982) and Total Recall (1990). Dick is a very prestigious science fiction writer. His work has multiple twists and it always was a pleasant read. I also read Second Variety and much of it was fairly close to this movie. I actually enjoyed the film adaptation more than the story itself. Peter Weller is Joseph A. Hendricksson, an eccentric commander of an alliance bunker located on a planet known as Sirius 6B. Years before on Earth, there was nuclear fallout between two major groups; the N.E.B. (New Economic Block) and alliance workers over a special mineral that could change energy usage for transportation. So the fighting was moved to Sirius 6B where there has been a "Cold War" ever since. For the alliance to defend themselves, they created the Autonomous Mobile Sword or better known as, the screamer. The screamer is a mechanical life form that was equipped with a razor sharp blade so it could kill its enemy. But like all man made robots, they become self-aware and are now deciding for themselves who they should kill. Strangely enough, they are always updating their software, even making screamers that look like humans. So from there, audiences might make the connection of these traits between Skynet from The Terminator (1984), and characters not knowing who's real and who isn't from the novel Who Goes There, by John W. Campbell Jr. But for those few relations, Screamers can hold it's own as an entertaining sci-fi horror movie. It does not contain a lot of blood but it can be very suspenseful. Weller's performances are always a welcome to the screen. His ability to make his character sarcastic as is serious is a great touch. Andrew Lauer plays a innocent rookie named Ace Jefferson who tags along Hendricksson to meet with the N.E.B. command. The N.E.B. group these two visit is lead by the lovely Jennifer Ruben as Jessica Hanson. And with her is Roy Dupuis, who looks like Matthew McConaughey's distant cousin, who likes bugging another soldier who has some serious patience issues. The special effects are definitely dated. And it's really obvious when the camera is focused on the screamer itself but hey, the creature looks cool enough to look at. I think the most baffling part is how the machine keep upgrading their models. It makes you wonder, "What's going on down there". The set design is also something to see. A lot of does have the same color like from the movie Soldier (1998) but it at least looks real. The backgrounds actually resemble Chernobyl; which is eerie. Normand Corbeil composed the soundtrack and it also another strong point. When Hedricksson runs into a homeless child, the music makes the scene so heartbreaking. It's emotional and soft on the ears. The film variation of Second Variety does borough ideas from previous movies, but it's put together in such a way that it won't matter to the audience. The music is good and so is Weller's performance as a tired out war veteran.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A quite impressive but obviously flawed film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ozoneocean
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are two sides at war, but the war is winding down, it looks like one side has won, and the other side wants a truce... The trouble is that the autonomous weapons systems that the winning side deployed (called "screamers") and which helped them win, have other ideas. It stars Peter Weller, from Robocop. On the face of it, this looks like it'll be a by the numbers crappy scifi thriller horror with paper thin characters and wooden acting, and at best some testosterone fueled action movie sequences... That's what I thought anyway. I was very wrong. The acting was all extremely well done, especially by Weller. I was very impressed. Very good performances by all. The filming was atmospheric and well shot. Sets were great, props and costumes too. The story was full of emotion, it was thought provoking and well acted. This was an intelligent film! It was let down in two areas: 1. For most of the film the effects were very cheap, contrasting with the quality of the rest of it. 2. They lent a little too much on the cheap thriller aspect in parts of it, especially at the very end. It detracted a little from the intelligent themes and great acting. It's almost as if there were two competing forces at work: Highly competent, professional, pro, A-list film makers VS some strange incompetent cretin who BADLY wanted it to be a B-film. So it was flawed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sci-fi the way it was meant to be
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dragonsouls
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I decided to watch Screamers because I'm a big Phillip K. Dick fan, and this was a film based on one of his stories I never read yet. I had realized I overlooked the movie for way too long. I originally thought the movie was outdated, since I have experienced the human/robot social films for a while now, mostly with Battle Star Galactica, Blade Runner, i, Robot, and even Terminator. However, this is one of the first and original stories to convey the human/robot social conflicts and was glad to find the film on my video on demand lists. Worth mentioning first is the fine acting by Peter Weller, and I can't help but wonder why he never became more than a cult film actor, he truly could have been a big time action star on par with the other heavyweights of the 90s. And he really is convincing in this film, as a man who was on the brink of madness from desolation and hardship. As for the supporting cast, excellent performances for a low budget film. It reminded me of a time when all Science Fiction films were B-movies, before the Star Wars and Star Trek's came along. Come to think of it, the film had a decent sized budget for a 90s film. Nothing like other adapted Phillip K. Dick novels had gotten, such as Blade Runner, Minority Report, or Total Recall, but still, Screamers is a story that needed a bigger budget and if it had gotten one, this film would be a classic to be mentioned in the same breath as Dick's other masterpieces. The story reminded me of Blade Runner in some ways, and another short by Dick called "The Defenders" In a sense, Dick re-tells his themes over and over again, but nevertheless, Screamers is well written and unique in its own way. It's just perplexing why this film didn't come out in the 70s, or even early 80s, before the original Battle Star Galactica, and before Terminator, etc. This story would have made for a very pioneering film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sci-fi doing a great job to entertain
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (Richie@RanRightRealty.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a surprise movie meaning that turns out to be a great movie when you were expecting just a good one. The story has to be respected and understood. Then, what happens after that falls into place nicely. I am totally disappointed that they did not make a sequel to this winner. It was certainly set-up to do so. It has what I call genuine and satisfying scary moments brought to you via intelligence, not shock. Anytime you can engage the viewers imagination in a quality way after a movie viewing (as well as during) means you got a success on your hands. This is certainly one of those movies. The concept presented of something man has done that has mutated into something else is a good one. Now, if that something else wants to compete and then eliminate man, well you got my full attention thus this movie. Science Fiction treads a fine line of being believable or not when introducing a story. It doesn't have to be perfect to make its point. It has to be respectful and this movie respects the viewer. You will not have any trouble getting into this movie after the first few minutes. Then, all the dots start to connect and cause a viewing pleasure. It will suck you right in and when the ducks line up, scare you good and proper..Enjoy with a favorite snack so you don't bite your nails
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I would LOVE to see this movie remade with a good director and a large movie budget!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    picturetaker
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I originally saw this movie in the theatre. Many reviewers comment saying it should have gone straight to video but I don't think so. As this movie for its time was not that bad. I have seen this movie about 6 times since 1995 and every time I have enjoyed it. Could this movie have been better? Of course! But for what it cost and for what kind of movie it is, it is alright! Its such an interesting premise I would LOVE to see this movie remade with a good director and a large movie budget! As that would be GREAT! Screamers did have a OK script, it had a great story, OK character and storyline development. All in all it was an OK 1995 film. As most sci-fi goes it is not the worst at all! Screamers was an original movie and it is entertaining so if you get the opportunity to see it, I recommend you check it out if you like sci-fi movies.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Once it gets inside, that's when the killin' starts
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tieman64
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "We are now in a new form of schizophrenia. No more hysteria, no more projective paranoia, but this state of terror proper to the schizophrenic. [] The schizophrenic can no longer produce the limits of its own being. [] He is only a pure screen." - Baudrillard "That's right - Pinnochio's not a real little boy!" - Becker ("Screamers") Scifi author Harlan Ellison once took James Cameron to court, alleging that the director's 1984 film, "The Terminator", plagiarised "Demon With A Glass Hand" and "Soldier", two tales written by Ellison in the 1950s. But Cameron, a scifi nut, seems to have also borrowed heavily from Philip K Dick's "Second Variety", a 1953 short story which finds the world ravaged by war and mankind locked in combat with a race of machines. These machines were created for defence purposes, but eventually became "self aware", started evolving, making armies, factories and hunting down humans, whom they sought to completely eradicate. The machines then began creating terminator-like infiltration units; cyborgs which convincingly resemble humans and which are programmed to penetrate human bases. Dick's hero, a resourceful soldier, even resembles Cameron's Kyle Reese, and much of Dick's dialogue, desperate, fast and apocalyptic, recalls the frenetic banter in Cameron's "Terminator". While "Screamers", Christian Duguay's adaptation of Dick's "Second Variety", barely captures the tone and urgency of Dick's short story, Cameron's "Terminator" films do, though all these "adaptations" are more interesting in the way they demonstrate how Dick's approach to scifi changed from the 1950s onwards. All of Dick's novels are ontological conundrums, taking place in a landscape in which all "reality" seems to be constantly shifting, and in which worlds and selves constantly seem to fall apart. For Dick, there is no definitive reality, human identity itself is uncertain, nothing exists as it seems, and everything is simply a perception of pure information. In "Second Variety" these themes are approached in a fairly simple manner ("Is it an undercover killer robot or is it a human?", "What constitutes a robot?", "What constitutes a human?", "Aren't humans already cyborgs?", "How do I know what is real?", "How do I know what is machine?", "How do I know what I think I know?"), which is largely why it, and Dick's early work, remain his most popular. As Dick turned to drugs, stopped proof-reading, stopped perfecting and re-writing his stories, abandoned conventional narrative structures and started churning out novels quickly in a desperate attempt to pay his bills, his books, like his heroes and his own state of mind, became increasingly schizophrenic, paranoid and shapeless. Many deride Dick for this, but such a stance was the logical continuation of his early 1950s work. Today, Dick's later writing bare a striking similarity to postmodernist theories by thinkers such as Jameson, Baudrillard and Brian McHale. Dick anticipated the twenty-first century network society, a fragmented, culturally overloaded, media saturated world characterised by rapid technological change, constant movement and a dizzying, excessive and sometimes surreal aesthetic. For Dick, the future, our postmodern present, would morph into a sort of virtual reality game. A "consensual hallucination" in which all traditional demarcations or distinctions are erased. It is no longer an issue of there being a split between man and robot, but of man and technology constantly co-mingling, of both servicing the other, of all being technology, of man himself already being cybernetic, of the world already being cyberspacial, representational, all emotions faked, all behaviour play-acting, every object in quotes, everything grounded on the illusory. Whereas in an explicitly modernist film such as "Metropolis" the dichotomy between the original copy or experience (man) and the replication (machine) is very clear, in later Dickian films ("Blade Runner", Total Recall", "A Scanner Darkly", "Matrix", Cronenberg, Assayas etc - note how comparatively conservative Spielberg's version of Dick's "Minority Report" is) a crisis of representation occurs, as the signifier is now alienated from the object it signifies, a Deleuzian "schizoid existence" brought about by a breakdown "in the signifying chain". Unlike the apocalyptic, cosily hopeful rubble of "Terminator" and "Second Variety", later Dick also posits a urban, networked and mechanical landscape which engenders a consequential decline in organic feeling and sensibility. Men then become "consumers of illusion", an illusion of "belonging and participation" covering up massive industrial alienation. But every connection seems to lead back to corporations, a "soft fascism" whose grid it is impossible to escape. Here, everything is organised by the constant flow of money, all landscapes are advertising-saturated and the "goal" of commerce is to destroy history itself, to put its customers in the eternal Now, the big happy theme park of desires. No surprise then that one of Dick's last stories, "Stability", takes place in a world in which mankind doesn't progress anymore, despite the illusion of constant, hyper-motion. The story's solution? The invention of a Terminator-like time machine. If Dick got one thing wrong, it was in his assumption that this "schizoid existence" would trouble or traumatise man. Today, the opposite is true. Man's adapted. He loves his cage, even as he fantasises about Judgement Day. So postmodernist theory has itself has become what Brian McHale calls the "sister genre" of science fiction, both revolving around similar themes (What is reality? What constitutes the authentic human being?) and issues of technology and its effects on society and the individual subject. And while modernism was mainly interested in epistemology, the condition of knowledge, both Dick's scifi and postmodernism are governed by ontology and the basic conditions of existence. But "Screamers" and "The Terminator" films represent a kind of outdated, 1950s Philip K Dick, with nice easy, clear demarcations best suited for action cinema. Latter Dick is perhaps unsuited to the medium of cinema itself, though some of Olivier Assayas' more trashy films capture well his style ("Boarding Gate", "Demonlover"). 7.9/10  Worth one viewing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Noisy, Too Generic for Its Own Good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jmillerdp
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film sounds really cool in concept. But, it is permeated by lots of yelling and (yes!) screaming. The film follows acclaimed Science Fiction writer Philip K. Dick's original short story fairly closely, except for its difference in tone and ending. The direction is fairly routine, as is the script. The showdown upon showdown upon showdown gets tiring at the end, and undoes the paranoia of what came before. The acting gets pretty hammy, adding to the melodrama. The visual and practical effects are very good for a lower-budget film. The film score is fairly routine. Philip K. Dick was one of the most visionary Science-Fiction writers. And, few of his stories have been made into good films, which is too bad. "Screamers" is one of those misses. ***** (5 Out of 10 Stars)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Close Deception
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    hellraiser7
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Trust has always been a fundamental problem throughout the years because by it's nature it's never been a solid foundation to begin with. Despite the length of time we spend with a person we never truly know them, from his/her past to even what they do when were not around them. This film is an under the radar sci-fi gem which is based on a short story by my favorite sci-fi author Philp K. Dick. I like the production value despite a low budget they were able to use it well. We see a post apocalyptic world that is just dirty, grimy, and desolate. There is no vegetation, it is always cold, there is hardly any sun, and the worst part is the radioactive winds that blow every once in a while. It really adds to the suspense because it gives it a feeling of isolation, the fact there is hardly any life stirring means there is no help that will come when you need it the most. I also like the effects, most to all are practical so there's no CGI, at least none I know about, though some effects are a tad dated but not bad in my book. I really like the designs of the Moble Sword/Screamer robots, whom are menacing from their capabilities not just in killing but in learning and the different types they were able to produce which unfortunately give them an edge. The music is good, action is decent liked the hill battle, but most importantly I really like the suspense where you are on constant edge and has a steady build because you're never sure of what you'll discover, and when you do it might be too late. Like one sequence which is my favorite is when Hendrickson is using a computer in the bunker to discover all the different types of Screamers, it was suspenseful on two counts; one the fact that he has only a limited amount of time to use it and second what information is left in the dark afterward which puts us a step behind and makes the stakes of survival even higher. The story is very good, I wouldn't say the concepts are entirely new but everything done right. I like how despite post apocalyptic conditions they still have high technology that still works. And certain aspects of the story somewhat acknowledges or are even prolific on our war for oil as well as terrorism. Characters are solid, Joe Hendrickson played by one of my favorite actors Peter Weller. I like that Joe is a person whom is layed back, has a sense of humor, tired of the war and just wants to go home. Same with Jessica Hansen play well by Jennifer Rubin whom despite someone on the shady end of things, is capable of being selfless, doesn't give her trust to just anyone. I like that both have a decent dynamic together, I bought it. I really like how the film gets at the issue of paranoia as well as the philosophical issue on what is a human. One of the best things about Philp's stories is how our perception of humanity can be blurred. We discover how far the robots come not just in replicating human's physically but even in feelings and thoughts, which makes you wonder if that constitutes them as human and not just machines. The only problems I really have are the pacing can be slow at some points. And also there isn't enough action, but then again this is more of a suspense thriller so I can't complain much. Overall, I think is a very good sci-fi that I think is worth checking out. Be careful of who you trust, it could be the last person you give it to. Rating: 3 and a half stars.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Doesn't compare to other PKD adaptations
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Zazwaz
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The story is about a war on a mining colony between two rivaling human factions. One of the factions has developed a new weapon: an army of robotic drones, nicknamed 'screamers', that hide underground and attack anything that they don't recognize. However, as the war is starting to draw to a close, the screamers refuse to work for the human faction that created them and it soon becomes clear that they have evolved on their own and now pose a threat to both sides. It's a neat idea and there are a lot of twists along the way, albeit very predictable ones. The writing could have taken a little more effort, the characters are shallow and the dialogue is very cheesy. The acting is also not that fantastic. Neither is the direction. It's all very average. Screamers is entertaining, but it doesn't stand out like other PKD adaptations such as Bladerunner or Minority Report. If you are looking for a fun sci-fi action flick, you might consider checking this one out, but if you are looking for depth then you're looking in the wrong place.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    False movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Shamek Stepien
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    By 2070 a galactic war has erupted between corporate and state powers fighting over resources on a Syrius 6B. After nuclear attacks by the NEB corporation the opposing Alliance employs automated robotics called Screamers to turn the tide of the war. Deep in the bowels of the planet the machines fabricate robot warfare, which in time evolve and start building bigger better products. Facing annihilation after the lengthened war captain Joe Hendricksson (Peter Weller) responds to a seize fire and embarks on a journey to the enemy bunker to undertake peace proceedings. Unfortunately for him the path may have been chosen too late... Post-mortem Philip K. Dick doesn't get much love from scriptwriters and the story "Second Variety" is no exception. For someone so cerebrally metaphysical movies based on his novels tend to take a action turn for the worse, dissolving the underlying essence of his stories and frontally assaulting with visual high-octane spectacles. "Screamers" is a low-budget take on the latter, albeit with some undeniable atmosphere to back it up. Nonetheless based on a clich&eacute;d ridden script with thinly developed characters spewing out tirades of one-liners occasionally interrupted by Shakespeare quotes, "Screamers" is an undeniable work in progress having some wider appeal, but lacking substance to stand the test of time. Budget and technological limitations to the movie decrease the overall quality, but the underpinning problem is one of limited tension, surprise and a multitude of scenes, which essentially lack sense or reason. Somewhere within this world lies potential much in the vein of "Bladerunner", but inept direction overly focused on churning out action brings Weller and the remaining cast down with its undertow. Plastic people with plastic morality ultimately divert attention from possibilities making us focus on the superficiality of the effort.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A mix of previous ideas but still entertaining
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moviefanman76-blogspot-com
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's hard for filmmakers to adapt stories to the screen, especially when they resemble stories that have been previously told. Turns out though director Christian Duguay evens out the story and though it still recalls other movies before its time, it still has elements in it that make it have a quality worth watching. The story of Screamers is loosely based off of Second Variety, a short story written by Philip K. Dick, the novelist of Blade Runner (1982) and Total Recall (1990). Dick is a very prestigious science fiction writer. His work has multiple twists and it always was a pleasant read. I also read Second Variety and much of it was fairly close to this movie. I actually enjoyed the film adaptation more than the story itself. Peter Weller is Joseph A. Hendricksson, an eccentric commander of an alliance bunker located on a planet known as Sirius 6B. Years before on Earth, there was nuclear fallout between two major groups; the N.E.B. (New Economic Block) and alliance workers over a special mineral that could change energy usage for transportation. So the fighting was moved to Sirius 6B where there has been a "Cold War" ever since. For the alliance to defend themselves, they created the Autonomous Mobile Sword or better known as, the screamer. The screamer is a mechanical life form that was equipped with a razor sharp blade so it could kill its enemy. But like all man made robots, they become self-aware and are now deciding for themselves who they should kill. Strangely enough, they are always updating their software, even making screamers that look like humans. So from there, audiences might make the connection of these traits between Skynet from The Terminator (1984), and characters not knowing who's real and who isn't from the novel Who Goes There, by John W. Campbell Jr. But for those few relations, Screamers can hold it's own as an entertaining sci-fi horror movie. It does not contain a lot of blood but it can be very suspenseful. Weller's performances are always a welcome to the screen. His ability to make his character sarcastic as is serious is a great touch. Andrew Lauer plays a innocent rookie named Ace Jefferson who tags along Hendricksson to meet with the N.E.B. command. The N.E.B. group these two visit is lead by the lovely Jennifer Ruben as Jessica Hanson. And with her is Roy Dupuis, who looks like Matthew McConaughey's distant cousin, who likes bugging another soldier who has some serious patience issues. The special effects are definitely dated. And it's really obvious when the camera is focused on the screamer itself but hey, the creature looks cool enough to look at. I think the most baffling part is how the machine keep upgrading their models. It makes you wonder, "What's going on down there". The set design is also something to see. A lot of does have the same color like from the movie Soldier (1998) but it at least looks real. The backgrounds actually resemble Chernobyl; which is eerie. Normand Corbeil composed the soundtrack and it also another strong point. When Hedricksson runs into a homeless child, the music makes the scene so heartbreaking. It's emotional and soft on the ears. The film variation of Second Variety does borough ideas from previous movies, but it's put together in such a way that it won't matter to the audience. The music is good and so is Weller's performance as a tired out war veteran.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A quite impressive but obviously flawed film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ozoneocean
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are two sides at war, but the war is winding down, it looks like one side has won, and the other side wants a truce... The trouble is that the autonomous weapons systems that the winning side deployed (called "screamers") and which helped them win, have other ideas. It stars Peter Weller, from Robocop. On the face of it, this looks like it'll be a by the numbers crappy scifi thriller horror with paper thin characters and wooden acting, and at best some testosterone fueled action movie sequences... That's what I thought anyway. I was very wrong. The acting was all extremely well done, especially by Weller. I was very impressed. Very good performances by all. The filming was atmospheric and well shot. Sets were great, props and costumes too. The story was full of emotion, it was thought provoking and well acted. This was an intelligent film! It was let down in two areas: 1. For most of the film the effects were very cheap, contrasting with the quality of the rest of it. 2. They lent a little too much on the cheap thriller aspect in parts of it, especially at the very end. It detracted a little from the intelligent themes and great acting. It's almost as if there were two competing forces at work: Highly competent, professional, pro, A-list film makers VS some strange incompetent cretin who BADLY wanted it to be a B-film. So it was flawed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sci-fi the way it was meant to be
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dragonsouls
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I decided to watch Screamers because I'm a big Phillip K. Dick fan, and this was a film based on one of his stories I never read yet. I had realized I overlooked the movie for way too long. I originally thought the movie was outdated, since I have experienced the human/robot social films for a while now, mostly with Battle Star Galactica, Blade Runner, i, Robot, and even Terminator. However, this is one of the first and original stories to convey the human/robot social conflicts and was glad to find the film on my video on demand lists. Worth mentioning first is the fine acting by Peter Weller, and I can't help but wonder why he never became more than a cult film actor, he truly could have been a big time action star on par with the other heavyweights of the 90s. And he really is convincing in this film, as a man who was on the brink of madness from desolation and hardship. As for the supporting cast, excellent performances for a low budget film. It reminded me of a time when all Science Fiction films were B-movies, before the Star Wars and Star Trek's came along. Come to think of it, the film had a decent sized budget for a 90s film. Nothing like other adapted Phillip K. Dick novels had gotten, such as Blade Runner, Minority Report, or Total Recall, but still, Screamers is a story that needed a bigger budget and if it had gotten one, this film would be a classic to be mentioned in the same breath as Dick's other masterpieces. The story reminded me of Blade Runner in some ways, and another short by Dick called "The Defenders" In a sense, Dick re-tells his themes over and over again, but nevertheless, Screamers is well written and unique in its own way. It's just perplexing why this film didn't come out in the 70s, or even early 80s, before the original Battle Star Galactica, and before Terminator, etc. This story would have made for a very pioneering film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sci-fi doing a great job to entertain
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (Richie@RanRightRealty.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a surprise movie meaning that turns out to be a great movie when you were expecting just a good one. The story has to be respected and understood. Then, what happens after that falls into place nicely. I am totally disappointed that they did not make a sequel to this winner. It was certainly set-up to do so. It has what I call genuine and satisfying scary moments brought to you via intelligence, not shock. Anytime you can engage the viewers imagination in a quality way after a movie viewing (as well as during) means you got a success on your hands. This is certainly one of those movies. The concept presented of something man has done that has mutated into something else is a good one. Now, if that something else wants to compete and then eliminate man, well you got my full attention thus this movie. Science Fiction treads a fine line of being believable or not when introducing a story. It doesn't have to be perfect to make its point. It has to be respectful and this movie respects the viewer. You will not have any trouble getting into this movie after the first few minutes. Then, all the dots start to connect and cause a viewing pleasure. It will suck you right in and when the ducks line up, scare you good and proper..Enjoy with a favorite snack so you don't bite your nails
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I would LOVE to see this movie remade with a good director and a large movie budget!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    picturetaker
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I originally saw this movie in the theatre. Many reviewers comment saying it should have gone straight to video but I don't think so. As this movie for its time was not that bad. I have seen this movie about 6 times since 1995 and every time I have enjoyed it. Could this movie have been better? Of course! But for what it cost and for what kind of movie it is, it is alright! Its such an interesting premise I would LOVE to see this movie remade with a good director and a large movie budget! As that would be GREAT! Screamers did have a OK script, it had a great story, OK character and storyline development. All in all it was an OK 1995 film. As most sci-fi goes it is not the worst at all! Screamers was an original movie and it is entertaining so if you get the opportunity to see it, I recommend you check it out if you like sci-fi movies.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Once it gets inside, that's when the killin' starts
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tieman64
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "We are now in a new form of schizophrenia. No more hysteria, no more projective paranoia, but this state of terror proper to the schizophrenic. [] The schizophrenic can no longer produce the limits of its own being. [] He is only a pure screen." - Baudrillard "That's right - Pinnochio's not a real little boy!" - Becker ("Screamers") Scifi author Harlan Ellison once took James Cameron to court, alleging that the director's 1984 film, "The Terminator", plagiarised "Demon With A Glass Hand" and "Soldier", two tales written by Ellison in the 1950s. But Cameron, a scifi nut, seems to have also borrowed heavily from Philip K Dick's "Second Variety", a 1953 short story which finds the world ravaged by war and mankind locked in combat with a race of machines. These machines were created for defence purposes, but eventually became "self aware", started evolving, making armies, factories and hunting down humans, whom they sought to completely eradicate. The machines then began creating terminator-like infiltration units; cyborgs which convincingly resemble humans and which are programmed to penetrate human bases. Dick's hero, a resourceful soldier, even resembles Cameron's Kyle Reese, and much of Dick's dialogue, desperate, fast and apocalyptic, recalls the frenetic banter in Cameron's "Terminator". While "Screamers", Christian Duguay's adaptation of Dick's "Second Variety", barely captures the tone and urgency of Dick's short story, Cameron's "Terminator" films do, though all these "adaptations" are more interesting in the way they demonstrate how Dick's approach to scifi changed from the 1950s onwards. All of Dick's novels are ontological conundrums, taking place in a landscape in which all "reality" seems to be constantly shifting, and in which worlds and selves constantly seem to fall apart. For Dick, there is no definitive reality, human identity itself is uncertain, nothing exists as it seems, and everything is simply a perception of pure information. In "Second Variety" these themes are approached in a fairly simple manner ("Is it an undercover killer robot or is it a human?", "What constitutes a robot?", "What constitutes a human?", "Aren't humans already cyborgs?", "How do I know what is real?", "How do I know what is machine?", "How do I know what I think I know?"), which is largely why it, and Dick's early work, remain his most popular. As Dick turned to drugs, stopped proof-reading, stopped perfecting and re-writing his stories, abandoned conventional narrative structures and started churning out novels quickly in a desperate attempt to pay his bills, his books, like his heroes and his own state of mind, became increasingly schizophrenic, paranoid and shapeless. Many deride Dick for this, but such a stance was the logical continuation of his early 1950s work. Today, Dick's later writing bare a striking similarity to postmodernist theories by thinkers such as Jameson, Baudrillard and Brian McHale. Dick anticipated the twenty-first century network society, a fragmented, culturally overloaded, media saturated world characterised by rapid technological change, constant movement and a dizzying, excessive and sometimes surreal aesthetic. For Dick, the future, our postmodern present, would morph into a sort of virtual reality game. A "consensual hallucination" in which all traditional demarcations or distinctions are erased. It is no longer an issue of there being a split between man and robot, but of man and technology constantly co-mingling, of both servicing the other, of all being technology, of man himself already being cybernetic, of the world already being cyberspacial, representational, all emotions faked, all behaviour play-acting, every object in quotes, everything grounded on the illusory. Whereas in an explicitly modernist film such as "Metropolis" the dichotomy between the original copy or experience (man) and the replication (machine) is very clear, in later Dickian films ("Blade Runner", Total Recall", "A Scanner Darkly", "Matrix", Cronenberg, Assayas etc - note how comparatively conservative Spielberg's version of Dick's "Minority Report" is) a crisis of representation occurs, as the signifier is now alienated from the object it signifies, a Deleuzian "schizoid existence" brought about by a breakdown "in the signifying chain". Unlike the apocalyptic, cosily hopeful rubble of "Terminator" and "Second Variety", later Dick also posits a urban, networked and mechanical landscape which engenders a consequential decline in organic feeling and sensibility. Men then become "consumers of illusion", an illusion of "belonging and participation" covering up massive industrial alienation. But every connection seems to lead back to corporations, a "soft fascism" whose grid it is impossible to escape. Here, everything is organised by the constant flow of money, all landscapes are advertising-saturated and the "goal" of commerce is to destroy history itself, to put its customers in the eternal Now, the big happy theme park of desires. No surprise then that one of Dick's last stories, "Stability", takes place in a world in which mankind doesn't progress anymore, despite the illusion of constant, hyper-motion. The story's solution? The invention of a Terminator-like time machine. If Dick got one thing wrong, it was in his assumption that this "schizoid existence" would trouble or traumatise man. Today, the opposite is true. Man's adapted. He loves his cage, even as he fantasises about Judgement Day. So postmodernist theory has itself has become what Brian McHale calls the "sister genre" of science fiction, both revolving around similar themes (What is reality? What constitutes the authentic human being?) and issues of technology and its effects on society and the individual subject. And while modernism was mainly interested in epistemology, the condition of knowledge, both Dick's scifi and postmodernism are governed by ontology and the basic conditions of existence. But "Screamers" and "The Terminator" films represent a kind of outdated, 1950s Philip K Dick, with nice easy, clear demarcations best suited for action cinema. Latter Dick is perhaps unsuited to the medium of cinema itself, though some of Olivier Assayas' more trashy films capture well his style ("Boarding Gate", "Demonlover"). 7.9/10  Worth one viewing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Noisy, Too Generic for Its Own Good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jmillerdp
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film sounds really cool in concept. But, it is permeated by lots of yelling and (yes!) screaming. The film follows acclaimed Science Fiction writer Philip K. Dick's original short story fairly closely, except for its difference in tone and ending. The direction is fairly routine, as is the script. The showdown upon showdown upon showdown gets tiring at the end, and undoes the paranoia of what came before. The acting gets pretty hammy, adding to the melodrama. The visual and practical effects are very good for a lower-budget film. The film score is fairly routine. Philip K. Dick was one of the most visionary Science-Fiction writers. And, few of his stories have been made into good films, which is too bad. "Screamers" is one of those misses. ***** (5 Out of 10 Stars)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Close Deception
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    hellraiser7
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Trust has always been a fundamental problem throughout the years because by it's nature it's never been a solid foundation to begin with. Despite the length of time we spend with a person we never truly know them, from his/her past to even what they do when were not around them. This film is an under the radar sci-fi gem which is based on a short story by my favorite sci-fi author Philp K. Dick. I like the production value despite a low budget they were able to use it well. We see a post apocalyptic world that is just dirty, grimy, and desolate. There is no vegetation, it is always cold, there is hardly any sun, and the worst part is the radioactive winds that blow every once in a while. It really adds to the suspense because it gives it a feeling of isolation, the fact there is hardly any life stirring means there is no help that will come when you need it the most. I also like the effects, most to all are practical so there's no CGI, at least none I know about, though some effects are a tad dated but not bad in my book. I really like the designs of the Moble Sword/Screamer robots, whom are menacing from their capabilities not just in killing but in learning and the different types they were able to produce which unfortunately give them an edge. The music is good, action is decent liked the hill battle, but most importantly I really like the suspense where you are on constant edge and has a steady build because you're never sure of what you'll discover, and when you do it might be too late. Like one sequence which is my favorite is when Hendrickson is using a computer in the bunker to discover all the different types of Screamers, it was suspenseful on two counts; one the fact that he has only a limited amount of time to use it and second what information is left in the dark afterward which puts us a step behind and makes the stakes of survival even higher. The story is very good, I wouldn't say the concepts are entirely new but everything done right. I like how despite post apocalyptic conditions they still have high technology that still works. And certain aspects of the story somewhat acknowledges or are even prolific on our war for oil as well as terrorism. Characters are solid, Joe Hendrickson played by one of my favorite actors Peter Weller. I like that Joe is a person whom is layed back, has a sense of humor, tired of the war and just wants to go home. Same with Jessica Hansen play well by Jennifer Rubin whom despite someone on the shady end of things, is capable of being selfless, doesn't give her trust to just anyone. I like that both have a decent dynamic together, I bought it. I really like how the film gets at the issue of paranoia as well as the philosophical issue on what is a human. One of the best things about Philp's stories is how our perception of humanity can be blurred. We discover how far the robots come not just in replicating human's physically but even in feelings and thoughts, which makes you wonder if that constitutes them as human and not just machines. The only problems I really have are the pacing can be slow at some points. And also there isn't enough action, but then again this is more of a suspense thriller so I can't complain much. Overall, I think is a very good sci-fi that I think is worth checking out. Be careful of who you trust, it could be the last person you give it to. Rating: 3 and a half stars.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Doesn't compare to other PKD adaptations
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Zazwaz
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The story is about a war on a mining colony between two rivaling human factions. One of the factions has developed a new weapon: an army of robotic drones, nicknamed 'screamers', that hide underground and attack anything that they don't recognize. However, as the war is starting to draw to a close, the screamers refuse to work for the human faction that created them and it soon becomes clear that they have evolved on their own and now pose a threat to both sides. It's a neat idea and there are a lot of twists along the way, albeit very predictable ones. The writing could have taken a little more effort, the characters are shallow and the dialogue is very cheesy. The acting is also not that fantastic. Neither is the direction. It's all very average. Screamers is entertaining, but it doesn't stand out like other PKD adaptations such as Bladerunner or Minority Report. If you are looking for a fun sci-fi action flick, you might consider checking this one out, but if you are looking for depth then you're looking in the wrong place.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    False movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Shamek Stepien
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    By 2070 a galactic war has erupted between corporate and state powers fighting over resources on a Syrius 6B. After nuclear attacks by the NEB corporation the opposing Alliance employs automated robotics called Screamers to turn the tide of the war. Deep in the bowels of the planet the machines fabricate robot warfare, which in time evolve and start building bigger better products. Facing annihilation after the lengthened war captain Joe Hendricksson (Peter Weller) responds to a seize fire and embarks on a journey to the enemy bunker to undertake peace proceedings. Unfortunately for him the path may have been chosen too late... Post-mortem Philip K. Dick doesn't get much love from scriptwriters and the story "Second Variety" is no exception. For someone so cerebrally metaphysical movies based on his novels tend to take a action turn for the worse, dissolving the underlying essence of his stories and frontally assaulting with visual high-octane spectacles. "Screamers" is a low-budget take on the latter, albeit with some undeniable atmosphere to back it up. Nonetheless based on a clich&eacute;d ridden script with thinly developed characters spewing out tirades of one-liners occasionally interrupted by Shakespeare quotes, "Screamers" is an undeniable work in progress having some wider appeal, but lacking substance to stand the test of time. Budget and technological limitations to the movie decrease the overall quality, but the underpinning problem is one of limited tension, surprise and a multitude of scenes, which essentially lack sense or reason. Somewhere within this world lies potential much in the vein of "Bladerunner", but inept direction overly focused on churning out action brings Weller and the remaining cast down with its undertow. Plastic people with plastic morality ultimately divert attention from possibilities making us focus on the superficiality of the effort.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A mix of previous ideas but still entertaining
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moviefanman76-blogspot-com
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's hard for filmmakers to adapt stories to the screen, especially when they resemble stories that have been previously told. Turns out though director Christian Duguay evens out the story and though it still recalls other movies before its time, it still has elements in it that make it have a quality worth watching. The story of Screamers is loosely based off of Second Variety, a short story written by Philip K. Dick, the novelist of Blade Runner (1982) and Total Recall (1990). Dick is a very prestigious science fiction writer. His work has multiple twists and it always was a pleasant read. I also read Second Variety and much of it was fairly close to this movie. I actually enjoyed the film adaptation more than the story itself. Peter Weller is Joseph A. Hendricksson, an eccentric commander of an alliance bunker located on a planet known as Sirius 6B. Years before on Earth, there was nuclear fallout between two major groups; the N.E.B. (New Economic Block) and alliance workers over a special mineral that could change energy usage for transportation. So the fighting was moved to Sirius 6B where there has been a "Cold War" ever since. For the alliance to defend themselves, they created the Autonomous Mobile Sword or better known as, the screamer. The screamer is a mechanical life form that was equipped with a razor sharp blade so it could kill its enemy. But like all man made robots, they become self-aware and are now deciding for themselves who they should kill. Strangely enough, they are always updating their software, even making screamers that look like humans. So from there, audiences might make the connection of these traits between Skynet from The Terminator (1984), and characters not knowing who's real and who isn't from the novel Who Goes There, by John W. Campbell Jr. But for those few relations, Screamers can hold it's own as an entertaining sci-fi horror movie. It does not contain a lot of blood but it can be very suspenseful. Weller's performances are always a welcome to the screen. His ability to make his character sarcastic as is serious is a great touch. Andrew Lauer plays a innocent rookie named Ace Jefferson who tags along Hendricksson to meet with the N.E.B. command. The N.E.B. group these two visit is lead by the lovely Jennifer Ruben as Jessica Hanson. And with her is Roy Dupuis, who looks like Matthew McConaughey's distant cousin, who likes bugging another soldier who has some serious patience issues. The special effects are definitely dated. And it's really obvious when the camera is focused on the screamer itself but hey, the creature looks cool enough to look at. I think the most baffling part is how the machine keep upgrading their models. It makes you wonder, "What's going on down there". The set design is also something to see. A lot of does have the same color like from the movie Soldier (1998) but it at least looks real. The backgrounds actually resemble Chernobyl; which is eerie. Normand Corbeil composed the soundtrack and it also another strong point. When Hedricksson runs into a homeless child, the music makes the scene so heartbreaking. It's emotional and soft on the ears. The film variation of Second Variety does borough ideas from previous movies, but it's put together in such a way that it won't matter to the audience. The music is good and so is Weller's performance as a tired out war veteran.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A quite impressive but obviously flawed film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ozoneocean
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are two sides at war, but the war is winding down, it looks like one side has won, and the other side wants a truce... The trouble is that the autonomous weapons systems that the winning side deployed (called "screamers") and which helped them win, have other ideas. It stars Peter Weller, from Robocop. On the face of it, this looks like it'll be a by the numbers crappy scifi thriller horror with paper thin characters and wooden acting, and at best some testosterone fueled action movie sequences... That's what I thought anyway. I was very wrong. The acting was all extremely well done, especially by Weller. I was very impressed. Very good performances by all. The filming was atmospheric and well shot. Sets were great, props and costumes too. The story was full of emotion, it was thought provoking and well acted. This was an intelligent film! It was let down in two areas: 1. For most of the film the effects were very cheap, contrasting with the quality of the rest of it. 2. They lent a little too much on the cheap thriller aspect in parts of it, especially at the very end. It detracted a little from the intelligent themes and great acting. It's almost as if there were two competing forces at work: Highly competent, professional, pro, A-list film makers VS some strange incompetent cretin who BADLY wanted it to be a B-film. So it was flawed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sci-fi the way it was meant to be
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dragonsouls
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I decided to watch Screamers because I'm a big Phillip K. Dick fan, and this was a film based on one of his stories I never read yet. I had realized I overlooked the movie for way too long. I originally thought the movie was outdated, since I have experienced the human/robot social films for a while now, mostly with Battle Star Galactica, Blade Runner, i, Robot, and even Terminator. However, this is one of the first and original stories to convey the human/robot social conflicts and was glad to find the film on my video on demand lists. Worth mentioning first is the fine acting by Peter Weller, and I can't help but wonder why he never became more than a cult film actor, he truly could have been a big time action star on par with the other heavyweights of the 90s. And he really is convincing in this film, as a man who was on the brink of madness from desolation and hardship. As for the supporting cast, excellent performances for a low budget film. It reminded me of a time when all Science Fiction films were B-movies, before the Star Wars and Star Trek's came along. Come to think of it, the film had a decent sized budget for a 90s film. Nothing like other adapted Phillip K. Dick novels had gotten, such as Blade Runner, Minority Report, or Total Recall, but still, Screamers is a story that needed a bigger budget and if it had gotten one, this film would be a classic to be mentioned in the same breath as Dick's other masterpieces. The story reminded me of Blade Runner in some ways, and another short by Dick called "The Defenders" In a sense, Dick re-tells his themes over and over again, but nevertheless, Screamers is well written and unique in its own way. It's just perplexing why this film didn't come out in the 70s, or even early 80s, before the original Battle Star Galactica, and before Terminator, etc. This story would have made for a very pioneering film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sci-fi doing a great job to entertain
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (Richie@RanRightRealty.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a surprise movie meaning that turns out to be a great movie when you were expecting just a good one. The story has to be respected and understood. Then, what happens after that falls into place nicely. I am totally disappointed that they did not make a sequel to this winner. It was certainly set-up to do so. It has what I call genuine and satisfying scary moments brought to you via intelligence, not shock. Anytime you can engage the viewers imagination in a quality way after a movie viewing (as well as during) means you got a success on your hands. This is certainly one of those movies. The concept presented of something man has done that has mutated into something else is a good one. Now, if that something else wants to compete and then eliminate man, well you got my full attention thus this movie. Science Fiction treads a fine line of being believable or not when introducing a story. It doesn't have to be perfect to make its point. It has to be respectful and this movie respects the viewer. You will not have any trouble getting into this movie after the first few minutes. Then, all the dots start to connect and cause a viewing pleasure. It will suck you right in and when the ducks line up, scare you good and proper..Enjoy with a favorite snack so you don't bite your nails
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I would LOVE to see this movie remade with a good director and a large movie budget!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    picturetaker
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I originally saw this movie in the theatre. Many reviewers comment saying it should have gone straight to video but I don't think so. As this movie for its time was not that bad. I have seen this movie about 6 times since 1995 and every time I have enjoyed it. Could this movie have been better? Of course! But for what it cost and for what kind of movie it is, it is alright! Its such an interesting premise I would LOVE to see this movie remade with a good director and a large movie budget! As that would be GREAT! Screamers did have a OK script, it had a great story, OK character and storyline development. All in all it was an OK 1995 film. As most sci-fi goes it is not the worst at all! Screamers was an original movie and it is entertaining so if you get the opportunity to see it, I recommend you check it out if you like sci-fi movies.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Once it gets inside, that's when the killin' starts
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tieman64
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "We are now in a new form of schizophrenia. No more hysteria, no more projective paranoia, but this state of terror proper to the schizophrenic. [] The schizophrenic can no longer produce the limits of its own being. [] He is only a pure screen." - Baudrillard "That's right - Pinnochio's not a real little boy!" - Becker ("Screamers") Scifi author Harlan Ellison once took James Cameron to court, alleging that the director's 1984 film, "The Terminator", plagiarised "Demon With A Glass Hand" and "Soldier", two tales written by Ellison in the 1950s. But Cameron, a scifi nut, seems to have also borrowed heavily from Philip K Dick's "Second Variety", a 1953 short story which finds the world ravaged by war and mankind locked in combat with a race of machines. These machines were created for defence purposes, but eventually became "self aware", started evolving, making armies, factories and hunting down humans, whom they sought to completely eradicate. The machines then began creating terminator-like infiltration units; cyborgs which convincingly resemble humans and which are programmed to penetrate human bases. Dick's hero, a resourceful soldier, even resembles Cameron's Kyle Reese, and much of Dick's dialogue, desperate, fast and apocalyptic, recalls the frenetic banter in Cameron's "Terminator". While "Screamers", Christian Duguay's adaptation of Dick's "Second Variety", barely captures the tone and urgency of Dick's short story, Cameron's "Terminator" films do, though all these "adaptations" are more interesting in the way they demonstrate how Dick's approach to scifi changed from the 1950s onwards. All of Dick's novels are ontological conundrums, taking place in a landscape in which all "reality" seems to be constantly shifting, and in which worlds and selves constantly seem to fall apart. For Dick, there is no definitive reality, human identity itself is uncertain, nothing exists as it seems, and everything is simply a perception of pure information. In "Second Variety" these themes are approached in a fairly simple manner ("Is it an undercover killer robot or is it a human?", "What constitutes a robot?", "What constitutes a human?", "Aren't humans already cyborgs?", "How do I know what is real?", "How do I know what is machine?", "How do I know what I think I know?"), which is largely why it, and Dick's early work, remain his most popular. As Dick turned to drugs, stopped proof-reading, stopped perfecting and re-writing his stories, abandoned conventional narrative structures and started churning out novels quickly in a desperate attempt to pay his bills, his books, like his heroes and his own state of mind, became increasingly schizophrenic, paranoid and shapeless. Many deride Dick for this, but such a stance was the logical continuation of his early 1950s work. Today, Dick's later writing bare a striking similarity to postmodernist theories by thinkers such as Jameson, Baudrillard and Brian McHale. Dick anticipated the twenty-first century network society, a fragmented, culturally overloaded, media saturated world characterised by rapid technological change, constant movement and a dizzying, excessive and sometimes surreal aesthetic. For Dick, the future, our postmodern present, would morph into a sort of virtual reality game. A "consensual hallucination" in which all traditional demarcations or distinctions are erased. It is no longer an issue of there being a split between man and robot, but of man and technology constantly co-mingling, of both servicing the other, of all being technology, of man himself already being cybernetic, of the world already being cyberspacial, representational, all emotions faked, all behaviour play-acting, every object in quotes, everything grounded on the illusory. Whereas in an explicitly modernist film such as "Metropolis" the dichotomy between the original copy or experience (man) and the replication (machine) is very clear, in later Dickian films ("Blade Runner", Total Recall", "A Scanner Darkly", "Matrix", Cronenberg, Assayas etc - note how comparatively conservative Spielberg's version of Dick's "Minority Report" is) a crisis of representation occurs, as the signifier is now alienated from the object it signifies, a Deleuzian "schizoid existence" brought about by a breakdown "in the signifying chain". Unlike the apocalyptic, cosily hopeful rubble of "Terminator" and "Second Variety", later Dick also posits a urban, networked and mechanical landscape which engenders a consequential decline in organic feeling and sensibility. Men then become "consumers of illusion", an illusion of "belonging and participation" covering up massive industrial alienation. But every connection seems to lead back to corporations, a "soft fascism" whose grid it is impossible to escape. Here, everything is organised by the constant flow of money, all landscapes are advertising-saturated and the "goal" of commerce is to destroy history itself, to put its customers in the eternal Now, the big happy theme park of desires. No surprise then that one of Dick's last stories, "Stability", takes place in a world in which mankind doesn't progress anymore, despite the illusion of constant, hyper-motion. The story's solution? The invention of a Terminator-like time machine. If Dick got one thing wrong, it was in his assumption that this "schizoid existence" would trouble or traumatise man. Today, the opposite is true. Man's adapted. He loves his cage, even as he fantasises about Judgement Day. So postmodernist theory has itself has become what Brian McHale calls the "sister genre" of science fiction, both revolving around similar themes (What is reality? What constitutes the authentic human being?) and issues of technology and its effects on society and the individual subject. And while modernism was mainly interested in epistemology, the condition of knowledge, both Dick's scifi and postmodernism are governed by ontology and the basic conditions of existence. But "Screamers" and "The Terminator" films represent a kind of outdated, 1950s Philip K Dick, with nice easy, clear demarcations best suited for action cinema. Latter Dick is perhaps unsuited to the medium of cinema itself, though some of Olivier Assayas' more trashy films capture well his style ("Boarding Gate", "Demonlover"). 7.9/10  Worth one viewing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Noisy, Too Generic for Its Own Good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jmillerdp
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film sounds really cool in concept. But, it is permeated by lots of yelling and (yes!) screaming. The film follows acclaimed Science Fiction writer Philip K. Dick's original short story fairly closely, except for its difference in tone and ending. The direction is fairly routine, as is the script. The showdown upon showdown upon showdown gets tiring at the end, and undoes the paranoia of what came before. The acting gets pretty hammy, adding to the melodrama. The visual and practical effects are very good for a lower-budget film. The film score is fairly routine. Philip K. Dick was one of the most visionary Science-Fiction writers. And, few of his stories have been made into good films, which is too bad. "Screamers" is one of those misses. ***** (5 Out of 10 Stars)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Close Deception
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    hellraiser7
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Trust has always been a fundamental problem throughout the years because by it's nature it's never been a solid foundation to begin with. Despite the length of time we spend with a person we never truly know them, from his/her past to even what they do when were not around them. This film is an under the radar sci-fi gem which is based on a short story by my favorite sci-fi author Philp K. Dick. I like the production value despite a low budget they were able to use it well. We see a post apocalyptic world that is just dirty, grimy, and desolate. There is no vegetation, it is always cold, there is hardly any sun, and the worst part is the radioactive winds that blow every once in a while. It really adds to the suspense because it gives it a feeling of isolation, the fact there is hardly any life stirring means there is no help that will come when you need it the most. I also like the effects, most to all are practical so there's no CGI, at least none I know about, though some effects are a tad dated but not bad in my book. I really like the designs of the Moble Sword/Screamer robots, whom are menacing from their capabilities not just in killing but in learning and the different types they were able to produce which unfortunately give them an edge. The music is good, action is decent liked the hill battle, but most importantly I really like the suspense where you are on constant edge and has a steady build because you're never sure of what you'll discover, and when you do it might be too late. Like one sequence which is my favorite is when Hendrickson is using a computer in the bunker to discover all the different types of Screamers, it was suspenseful on two counts; one the fact that he has only a limited amount of time to use it and second what information is left in the dark afterward which puts us a step behind and makes the stakes of survival even higher. The story is very good, I wouldn't say the concepts are entirely new but everything done right. I like how despite post apocalyptic conditions they still have high technology that still works. And certain aspects of the story somewhat acknowledges or are even prolific on our war for oil as well as terrorism. Characters are solid, Joe Hendrickson played by one of my favorite actors Peter Weller. I like that Joe is a person whom is layed back, has a sense of humor, tired of the war and just wants to go home. Same with Jessica Hansen play well by Jennifer Rubin whom despite someone on the shady end of things, is capable of being selfless, doesn't give her trust to just anyone. I like that both have a decent dynamic together, I bought it. I really like how the film gets at the issue of paranoia as well as the philosophical issue on what is a human. One of the best things about Philp's stories is how our perception of humanity can be blurred. We discover how far the robots come not just in replicating human's physically but even in feelings and thoughts, which makes you wonder if that constitutes them as human and not just machines. The only problems I really have are the pacing can be slow at some points. And also there isn't enough action, but then again this is more of a suspense thriller so I can't complain much. Overall, I think is a very good sci-fi that I think is worth checking out. Be careful of who you trust, it could be the last person you give it to. Rating: 3 and a half stars.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Doesn't compare to other PKD adaptations
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Zazwaz
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The story is about a war on a mining colony between two rivaling human factions. One of the factions has developed a new weapon: an army of robotic drones, nicknamed 'screamers', that hide underground and attack anything that they don't recognize. However, as the war is starting to draw to a close, the screamers refuse to work for the human faction that created them and it soon becomes clear that they have evolved on their own and now pose a threat to both sides. It's a neat idea and there are a lot of twists along the way, albeit very predictable ones. The writing could have taken a little more effort, the characters are shallow and the dialogue is very cheesy. The acting is also not that fantastic. Neither is the direction. It's all very average. Screamers is entertaining, but it doesn't stand out like other PKD adaptations such as Bladerunner or Minority Report. If you are looking for a fun sci-fi action flick, you might consider checking this one out, but if you are looking for depth then you're looking in the wrong place.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    False movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Shamek Stepien
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    By 2070 a galactic war has erupted between corporate and state powers fighting over resources on a Syrius 6B. After nuclear attacks by the NEB corporation the opposing Alliance employs automated robotics called Screamers to turn the tide of the war. Deep in the bowels of the planet the machines fabricate robot warfare, which in time evolve and start building bigger better products. Facing annihilation after the lengthened war captain Joe Hendricksson (Peter Weller) responds to a seize fire and embarks on a journey to the enemy bunker to undertake peace proceedings. Unfortunately for him the path may have been chosen too late... Post-mortem Philip K. Dick doesn't get much love from scriptwriters and the story "Second Variety" is no exception. For someone so cerebrally metaphysical movies based on his novels tend to take a action turn for the worse, dissolving the underlying essence of his stories and frontally assaulting with visual high-octane spectacles. "Screamers" is a low-budget take on the latter, albeit with some undeniable atmosphere to back it up. Nonetheless based on a clich&eacute;d ridden script with thinly developed characters spewing out tirades of one-liners occasionally interrupted by Shakespeare quotes, "Screamers" is an undeniable work in progress having some wider appeal, but lacking substance to stand the test of time. Budget and technological limitations to the movie decrease the overall quality, but the underpinning problem is one of limited tension, surprise and a multitude of scenes, which essentially lack sense or reason. Somewhere within this world lies potential much in the vein of "Bladerunner", but inept direction overly focused on churning out action brings Weller and the remaining cast down with its undertow. Plastic people with plastic morality ultimately divert attention from possibilities making us focus on the superficiality of the effort.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A mix of previous ideas but still entertaining
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moviefanman76-blogspot-com
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's hard for filmmakers to adapt stories to the screen, especially when they resemble stories that have been previously told. Turns out though director Christian Duguay evens out the story and though it still recalls other movies before its time, it still has elements in it that make it have a quality worth watching. The story of Screamers is loosely based off of Second Variety, a short story written by Philip K. Dick, the novelist of Blade Runner (1982) and Total Recall (1990). Dick is a very prestigious science fiction writer. His work has multiple twists and it always was a pleasant read. I also read Second Variety and much of it was fairly close to this movie. I actually enjoyed the film adaptation more than the story itself. Peter Weller is Joseph A. Hendricksson, an eccentric commander of an alliance bunker located on a planet known as Sirius 6B. Years before on Earth, there was nuclear fallout between two major groups; the N.E.B. (New Economic Block) and alliance workers over a special mineral that could change energy usage for transportation. So the fighting was moved to Sirius 6B where there has been a "Cold War" ever since. For the alliance to defend themselves, they created the Autonomous Mobile Sword or better known as, the screamer. The screamer is a mechanical life form that was equipped with a razor sharp blade so it could kill its enemy. But like all man made robots, they become self-aware and are now deciding for themselves who they should kill. Strangely enough, they are always updating their software, even making screamers that look like humans. So from there, audiences might make the connection of these traits between Skynet from The Terminator (1984), and characters not knowing who's real and who isn't from the novel Who Goes There, by John W. Campbell Jr. But for those few relations, Screamers can hold it's own as an entertaining sci-fi horror movie. It does not contain a lot of blood but it can be very suspenseful. Weller's performances are always a welcome to the screen. His ability to make his character sarcastic as is serious is a great touch. Andrew Lauer plays a innocent rookie named Ace Jefferson who tags along Hendricksson to meet with the N.E.B. command. The N.E.B. group these two visit is lead by the lovely Jennifer Ruben as Jessica Hanson. And with her is Roy Dupuis, who looks like Matthew McConaughey's distant cousin, who likes bugging another soldier who has some serious patience issues. The special effects are definitely dated. And it's really obvious when the camera is focused on the screamer itself but hey, the creature looks cool enough to look at. I think the most baffling part is how the machine keep upgrading their models. It makes you wonder, "What's going on down there". The set design is also something to see. A lot of does have the same color like from the movie Soldier (1998) but it at least looks real. The backgrounds actually resemble Chernobyl; which is eerie. Normand Corbeil composed the soundtrack and it also another strong point. When Hedricksson runs into a homeless child, the music makes the scene so heartbreaking. It's emotional and soft on the ears. The film variation of Second Variety does borough ideas from previous movies, but it's put together in such a way that it won't matter to the audience. The music is good and so is Weller's performance as a tired out war veteran.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A quite impressive but obviously flawed film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ozoneocean
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are two sides at war, but the war is winding down, it looks like one side has won, and the other side wants a truce... The trouble is that the autonomous weapons systems that the winning side deployed (called "screamers") and which helped them win, have other ideas. It stars Peter Weller, from Robocop. On the face of it, this looks like it'll be a by the numbers crappy scifi thriller horror with paper thin characters and wooden acting, and at best some testosterone fueled action movie sequences... That's what I thought anyway. I was very wrong. The acting was all extremely well done, especially by Weller. I was very impressed. Very good performances by all. The filming was atmospheric and well shot. Sets were great, props and costumes too. The story was full of emotion, it was thought provoking and well acted. This was an intelligent film! It was let down in two areas: 1. For most of the film the effects were very cheap, contrasting with the quality of the rest of it. 2. They lent a little too much on the cheap thriller aspect in parts of it, especially at the very end. It detracted a little from the intelligent themes and great acting. It's almost as if there were two competing forces at work: Highly competent, professional, pro, A-list film makers VS some strange incompetent cretin who BADLY wanted it to be a B-film. So it was flawed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sci-fi the way it was meant to be
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dragonsouls
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I decided to watch Screamers because I'm a big Phillip K. Dick fan, and this was a film based on one of his stories I never read yet. I had realized I overlooked the movie for way too long. I originally thought the movie was outdated, since I have experienced the human/robot social films for a while now, mostly with Battle Star Galactica, Blade Runner, i, Robot, and even Terminator. However, this is one of the first and original stories to convey the human/robot social conflicts and was glad to find the film on my video on demand lists. Worth mentioning first is the fine acting by Peter Weller, and I can't help but wonder why he never became more than a cult film actor, he truly could have been a big time action star on par with the other heavyweights of the 90s. And he really is convincing in this film, as a man who was on the brink of madness from desolation and hardship. As for the supporting cast, excellent performances for a low budget film. It reminded me of a time when all Science Fiction films were B-movies, before the Star Wars and Star Trek's came along. Come to think of it, the film had a decent sized budget for a 90s film. Nothing like other adapted Phillip K. Dick novels had gotten, such as Blade Runner, Minority Report, or Total Recall, but still, Screamers is a story that needed a bigger budget and if it had gotten one, this film would be a classic to be mentioned in the same breath as Dick's other masterpieces. The story reminded me of Blade Runner in some ways, and another short by Dick called "The Defenders" In a sense, Dick re-tells his themes over and over again, but nevertheless, Screamers is well written and unique in its own way. It's just perplexing why this film didn't come out in the 70s, or even early 80s, before the original Battle Star Galactica, and before Terminator, etc. This story would have made for a very pioneering film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sci-fi doing a great job to entertain
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (Richie@RanRightRealty.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a surprise movie meaning that turns out to be a great movie when you were expecting just a good one. The story has to be respected and understood. Then, what happens after that falls into place nicely. I am totally disappointed that they did not make a sequel to this winner. It was certainly set-up to do so. It has what I call genuine and satisfying scary moments brought to you via intelligence, not shock. Anytime you can engage the viewers imagination in a quality way after a movie viewing (as well as during) means you got a success on your hands. This is certainly one of those movies. The concept presented of something man has done that has mutated into something else is a good one. Now, if that something else wants to compete and then eliminate man, well you got my full attention thus this movie. Science Fiction treads a fine line of being believable or not when introducing a story. It doesn't have to be perfect to make its point. It has to be respectful and this movie respects the viewer. You will not have any trouble getting into this movie after the first few minutes. Then, all the dots start to connect and cause a viewing pleasure. It will suck you right in and when the ducks line up, scare you good and proper..Enjoy with a favorite snack so you don't bite your nails
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I would LOVE to see this movie remade with a good director and a large movie budget!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    picturetaker
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I originally saw this movie in the theatre. Many reviewers comment saying it should have gone straight to video but I don't think so. As this movie for its time was not that bad. I have seen this movie about 6 times since 1995 and every time I have enjoyed it. Could this movie have been better? Of course! But for what it cost and for what kind of movie it is, it is alright! Its such an interesting premise I would LOVE to see this movie remade with a good director and a large movie budget! As that would be GREAT! Screamers did have a OK script, it had a great story, OK character and storyline development. All in all it was an OK 1995 film. As most sci-fi goes it is not the worst at all! Screamers was an original movie and it is entertaining so if you get the opportunity to see it, I recommend you check it out if you like sci-fi movies.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Once it gets inside, that's when the killin' starts
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tieman64
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "We are now in a new form of schizophrenia. No more hysteria, no more projective paranoia, but this state of terror proper to the schizophrenic. [] The schizophrenic can no longer produce the limits of its own being. [] He is only a pure screen." - Baudrillard "That's right - Pinnochio's not a real little boy!" - Becker ("Screamers") Scifi author Harlan Ellison once took James Cameron to court, alleging that the director's 1984 film, "The Terminator", plagiarised "Demon With A Glass Hand" and "Soldier", two tales written by Ellison in the 1950s. But Cameron, a scifi nut, seems to have also borrowed heavily from Philip K Dick's "Second Variety", a 1953 short story which finds the world ravaged by war and mankind locked in combat with a race of machines. These machines were created for defence purposes, but eventually became "self aware", started evolving, making armies, factories and hunting down humans, whom they sought to completely eradicate. The machines then began creating terminator-like infiltration units; cyborgs which convincingly resemble humans and which are programmed to penetrate human bases. Dick's hero, a resourceful soldier, even resembles Cameron's Kyle Reese, and much of Dick's dialogue, desperate, fast and apocalyptic, recalls the frenetic banter in Cameron's "Terminator". While "Screamers", Christian Duguay's adaptation of Dick's "Second Variety", barely captures the tone and urgency of Dick's short story, Cameron's "Terminator" films do, though all these "adaptations" are more interesting in the way they demonstrate how Dick's approach to scifi changed from the 1950s onwards. All of Dick's novels are ontological conundrums, taking place in a landscape in which all "reality" seems to be constantly shifting, and in which worlds and selves constantly seem to fall apart. For Dick, there is no definitive reality, human identity itself is uncertain, nothing exists as it seems, and everything is simply a perception of pure information. In "Second Variety" these themes are approached in a fairly simple manner ("Is it an undercover killer robot or is it a human?", "What constitutes a robot?", "What constitutes a human?", "Aren't humans already cyborgs?", "How do I know what is real?", "How do I know what is machine?", "How do I know what I think I know?"), which is largely why it, and Dick's early work, remain his most popular. As Dick turned to drugs, stopped proof-reading, stopped perfecting and re-writing his stories, abandoned conventional narrative structures and started churning out novels quickly in a desperate attempt to pay his bills, his books, like his heroes and his own state of mind, became increasingly schizophrenic, paranoid and shapeless. Many deride Dick for this, but such a stance was the logical continuation of his early 1950s work. Today, Dick's later writing bare a striking similarity to postmodernist theories by thinkers such as Jameson, Baudrillard and Brian McHale. Dick anticipated the twenty-first century network society, a fragmented, culturally overloaded, media saturated world characterised by rapid technological change, constant movement and a dizzying, excessive and sometimes surreal aesthetic. For Dick, the future, our postmodern present, would morph into a sort of virtual reality game. A "consensual hallucination" in which all traditional demarcations or distinctions are erased. It is no longer an issue of there being a split between man and robot, but of man and technology constantly co-mingling, of both servicing the other, of all being technology, of man himself already being cybernetic, of the world already being cyberspacial, representational, all emotions faked, all behaviour play-acting, every object in quotes, everything grounded on the illusory. Whereas in an explicitly modernist film such as "Metropolis" the dichotomy between the original copy or experience (man) and the replication (machine) is very clear, in later Dickian films ("Blade Runner", Total Recall", "A Scanner Darkly", "Matrix", Cronenberg, Assayas etc - note how comparatively conservative Spielberg's version of Dick's "Minority Report" is) a crisis of representation occurs, as the signifier is now alienated from the object it signifies, a Deleuzian "schizoid existence" brought about by a breakdown "in the signifying chain". Unlike the apocalyptic, cosily hopeful rubble of "Terminator" and "Second Variety", later Dick also posits a urban, networked and mechanical landscape which engenders a consequential decline in organic feeling and sensibility. Men then become "consumers of illusion", an illusion of "belonging and participation" covering up massive industrial alienation. But every connection seems to lead back to corporations, a "soft fascism" whose grid it is impossible to escape. Here, everything is organised by the constant flow of money, all landscapes are advertising-saturated and the "goal" of commerce is to destroy history itself, to put its customers in the eternal Now, the big happy theme park of desires. No surprise then that one of Dick's last stories, "Stability", takes place in a world in which mankind doesn't progress anymore, despite the illusion of constant, hyper-motion. The story's solution? The invention of a Terminator-like time machine. If Dick got one thing wrong, it was in his assumption that this "schizoid existence" would trouble or traumatise man. Today, the opposite is true. Man's adapted. He loves his cage, even as he fantasises about Judgement Day. So postmodernist theory has itself has become what Brian McHale calls the "sister genre" of science fiction, both revolving around similar themes (What is reality? What constitutes the authentic human being?) and issues of technology and its effects on society and the individual subject. And while modernism was mainly interested in epistemology, the condition of knowledge, both Dick's scifi and postmodernism are governed by ontology and the basic conditions of existence. But "Screamers" and "The Terminator" films represent a kind of outdated, 1950s Philip K Dick, with nice easy, clear demarcations best suited for action cinema. Latter Dick is perhaps unsuited to the medium of cinema itself, though some of Olivier Assayas' more trashy films capture well his style ("Boarding Gate", "Demonlover"). 7.9/10  Worth one viewing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Noisy, Too Generic for Its Own Good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jmillerdp
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This film sounds really cool in concept. But, it is permeated by lots of yelling and (yes!) screaming. The film follows acclaimed Science Fiction writer Philip K. Dick's original short story fairly closely, except for its difference in tone and ending. The direction is fairly routine, as is the script. The showdown upon showdown upon showdown gets tiring at the end, and undoes the paranoia of what came before. The acting gets pretty hammy, adding to the melodrama. The visual and practical effects are very good for a lower-budget film. The film score is fairly routine. Philip K. Dick was one of the most visionary Science-Fiction writers. And, few of his stories have been made into good films, which is too bad. "Screamers" is one of those misses. ***** (5 Out of 10 Stars)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Close Deception
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    hellraiser7
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Trust has always been a fundamental problem throughout the years because by it's nature it's never been a solid foundation to begin with. Despite the length of time we spend with a person we never truly know them, from his/her past to even what they do when were not around them. This film is an under the radar sci-fi gem which is based on a short story by my favorite sci-fi author Philp K. Dick. I like the production value despite a low budget they were able to use it well. We see a post apocalyptic world that is just dirty, grimy, and desolate. There is no vegetation, it is always cold, there is hardly any sun, and the worst part is the radioactive winds that blow every once in a while. It really adds to the suspense because it gives it a feeling of isolation, the fact there is hardly any life stirring means there is no help that will come when you need it the most. I also like the effects, most to all are practical so there's no CGI, at least none I know about, though some effects are a tad dated but not bad in my book. I really like the designs of the Moble Sword/Screamer robots, whom are menacing from their capabilities not just in killing but in learning and the different types they were able to produce which unfortunately give them an edge. The music is good, action is decent liked the hill battle, but most importantly I really like the suspense where you are on constant edge and has a steady build because you're never sure of what you'll discover, and when you do it might be too late. Like one sequence which is my favorite is when Hendrickson is using a computer in the bunker to discover all the different types of Screamers, it was suspenseful on two counts; one the fact that he has only a limited amount of time to use it and second what information is left in the dark afterward which puts us a step behind and makes the stakes of survival even higher. The story is very good, I wouldn't say the concepts are entirely new but everything done right. I like how despite post apocalyptic conditions they still have high technology that still works. And certain aspects of the story somewhat acknowledges or are even prolific on our war for oil as well as terrorism. Characters are solid, Joe Hendrickson played by one of my favorite actors Peter Weller. I like that Joe is a person whom is layed back, has a sense of humor, tired of the war and just wants to go home. Same with Jessica Hansen play well by Jennifer Rubin whom despite someone on the shady end of things, is capable of being selfless, doesn't give her trust to just anyone. I like that both have a decent dynamic together, I bought it. I really like how the film gets at the issue of paranoia as well as the philosophical issue on what is a human. One of the best things about Philp's stories is how our perception of humanity can be blurred. We discover how far the robots come not just in replicating human's physically but even in feelings and thoughts, which makes you wonder if that constitutes them as human and not just machines. The only problems I really have are the pacing can be slow at some points. And also there isn't enough action, but then again this is more of a suspense thriller so I can't complain much. Overall, I think is a very good sci-fi that I think is worth checking out. Be careful of who you trust, it could be the last person you give it to. Rating: 3 and a half stars.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Doesn't compare to other PKD adaptations
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Zazwaz
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/6/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The story is about a war on a mining colony between two rivaling human factions. One of the factions has developed a new weapon: an army of robotic drones, nicknamed 'screamers', that hide underground and attack anything that they don't recognize. However, as the war is starting to draw to a close, the screamers refuse to work for the human faction that created them and it soon becomes clear that they have evolved on their own and now pose a threat to both sides. It's a neat idea and there are a lot of twists along the way, albeit very predictable ones. The writing could have taken a little more effort, the characters are shallow and the dialogue is very cheesy. The acting is also not that fantastic. Neither is the direction. It's all very average. Screamers is entertaining, but it doesn't stand out like other PKD adaptations such as Bladerunner or Minority Report. If you are looking for a fun sci-fi action flick, you might consider checking this one out, but if you are looking for depth then you're looking in the wrong place.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    False movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Shamek Stepien
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    By 2070 a galactic war has erupted between corporate and state powers fighting over resources on a Syrius 6B. After nuclear attacks by the NEB corporation the opposing Alliance employs automated robotics called Screamers to turn the tide of the war. Deep in the bowels of the planet the machines fabricate robot warfare, which in time evolve and start building bigger better products. Facing annihilation after the lengthened war captain Joe Hendricksson (Peter Weller) responds to a seize fire and embarks on a journey to the enemy bunker to undertake peace proceedings. Unfortunately for him the path may have been chosen too late... Post-mortem Philip K. Dick doesn't get much love from scriptwriters and the story "Second Variety" is no exception. For someone so cerebrally metaphysical movies based on his novels tend to take a action turn for the worse, dissolving the underlying essence of his stories and frontally assaulting with visual high-octane spectacles. "Screamers" is a low-budget take on the latter, albeit with some undeniable atmosphere to back it up. Nonetheless based on a clich&eacute;d ridden script with thinly developed characters spewing out tirades of one-liners occasionally interrupted by Shakespeare quotes, "Screamers" is an undeniable work in progress having some wider appeal, but lacking substance to stand the test of time. Budget and technological limitations to the movie decrease the overall quality, but the underpinning problem is one of limited tension, surprise and a multitude of scenes, which essentially lack sense or reason. Somewhere within this world lies potential much in the vein of "Bladerunner", but inept direction overly focused on churning out action brings Weller and the remaining cast down with its undertow. Plastic people with plastic morality ultimately divert attention from possibilities making us focus on the superficiality of the effort.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A mix of previous ideas but still entertaining
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    moviefanman76-blogspot-com
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/6/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It's hard for filmmakers to adapt stories to the screen, especially when they resemble stories that have been previously told. Turns out though director Christian Duguay evens out the story and though it still recalls other movies before its time, it still has elements in it that make it have a quality worth watching. The story of Screamers is loosely based off of Second Variety, a short story written by Philip K. Dick, the novelist of Blade Runner (1982) and Total Recall (1990). Dick is a very prestigious science fiction writer. His work has multiple twists and it always was a pleasant read. I also read Second Variety and much of it was fairly close to this movie. I actually enjoyed the film adaptation more than the story itself. Peter Weller is Joseph A. Hendricksson, an eccentric commander of an alliance bunker located on a planet known as Sirius 6B. Years before on Earth, there was nuclear fallout between two major groups; the N.E.B. (New Economic Block) and alliance workers over a special mineral that could change energy usage for transportation. So the fighting was moved to Sirius 6B where there has been a "Cold War" ever since. For the alliance to defend themselves, they created the Autonomous Mobile Sword or better known as, the screamer. The screamer is a mechanical life form that was equipped with a razor sharp blade so it could kill its enemy. But like all man made robots, they become self-aware and are now deciding for themselves who they should kill. Strangely enough, they are always updating their software, even making screamers that look like humans. So from there, audiences might make the connection of these traits between Skynet from The Terminator (1984), and characters not knowing who's real and who isn't from the novel Who Goes There, by John W. Campbell Jr. But for those few relations, Screamers can hold it's own as an entertaining sci-fi horror movie. It does not contain a lot of blood but it can be very suspenseful. Weller's performances are always a welcome to the screen. His ability to make his character sarcastic as is serious is a great touch. Andrew Lauer plays a innocent rookie named Ace Jefferson who tags along Hendricksson to meet with the N.E.B. command. The N.E.B. group these two visit is lead by the lovely Jennifer Ruben as Jessica Hanson. And with her is Roy Dupuis, who looks like Matthew McConaughey's distant cousin, who likes bugging another soldier who has some serious patience issues. The special effects are definitely dated. And it's really obvious when the camera is focused on the screamer itself but hey, the creature looks cool enough to look at. I think the most baffling part is how the machine keep upgrading their models. It makes you wonder, "What's going on down there". The set design is also something to see. A lot of does have the same color like from the movie Soldier (1998) but it at least looks real. The backgrounds actually resemble Chernobyl; which is eerie. Normand Corbeil composed the soundtrack and it also another strong point. When Hedricksson runs into a homeless child, the music makes the scene so heartbreaking. It's emotional and soft on the ears. The film variation of Second Variety does borough ideas from previous movies, but it's put together in such a way that it won't matter to the audience. The music is good and so is Weller's performance as a tired out war veteran.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A quite impressive but obviously flawed film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ozoneocean
   </autor>
   <data>
    13/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There are two sides at war, but the war is winding down, it looks like one side has won, and the other side wants a truce... The trouble is that the autonomous weapons systems that the winning side deployed (called "screamers") and which helped them win, have other ideas. It stars Peter Weller, from Robocop. On the face of it, this looks like it'll be a by the numbers crappy scifi thriller horror with paper thin characters and wooden acting, and at best some testosterone fueled action movie sequences... That's what I thought anyway. I was very wrong. The acting was all extremely well done, especially by Weller. I was very impressed. Very good performances by all. The filming was atmospheric and well shot. Sets were great, props and costumes too. The story was full of emotion, it was thought provoking and well acted. This was an intelligent film! It was let down in two areas: 1. For most of the film the effects were very cheap, contrasting with the quality of the rest of it. 2. They lent a little too much on the cheap thriller aspect in parts of it, especially at the very end. It detracted a little from the intelligent themes and great acting. It's almost as if there were two competing forces at work: Highly competent, professional, pro, A-list film makers VS some strange incompetent cretin who BADLY wanted it to be a B-film. So it was flawed.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sci-fi the way it was meant to be
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Dragonsouls
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I decided to watch Screamers because I'm a big Phillip K. Dick fan, and this was a film based on one of his stories I never read yet. I had realized I overlooked the movie for way too long. I originally thought the movie was outdated, since I have experienced the human/robot social films for a while now, mostly with Battle Star Galactica, Blade Runner, i, Robot, and even Terminator. However, this is one of the first and original stories to convey the human/robot social conflicts and was glad to find the film on my video on demand lists. Worth mentioning first is the fine acting by Peter Weller, and I can't help but wonder why he never became more than a cult film actor, he truly could have been a big time action star on par with the other heavyweights of the 90s. And he really is convincing in this film, as a man who was on the brink of madness from desolation and hardship. As for the supporting cast, excellent performances for a low budget film. It reminded me of a time when all Science Fiction films were B-movies, before the Star Wars and Star Trek's came along. Come to think of it, the film had a decent sized budget for a 90s film. Nothing like other adapted Phillip K. Dick novels had gotten, such as Blade Runner, Minority Report, or Total Recall, but still, Screamers is a story that needed a bigger budget and if it had gotten one, this film would be a classic to be mentioned in the same breath as Dick's other masterpieces. The story reminded me of Blade Runner in some ways, and another short by Dick called "The Defenders" In a sense, Dick re-tells his themes over and over again, but nevertheless, Screamers is well written and unique in its own way. It's just perplexing why this film didn't come out in the 70s, or even early 80s, before the original Battle Star Galactica, and before Terminator, etc. This story would have made for a very pioneering film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Sci-fi doing a great job to entertain
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (Richie@RanRightRealty.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/10/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is a surprise movie meaning that turns out to be a great movie when you were expecting just a good one. The story has to be respected and understood. Then, what happens after that falls into place nicely. I am totally disappointed that they did not make a sequel to this winner. It was certainly set-up to do so. It has what I call genuine and satisfying scary moments brought to you via intelligence, not shock. Anytime you can engage the viewers imagination in a quality way after a movie viewing (as well as during) means you got a success on your hands. This is certainly one of those movies. The concept presented of something man has done that has mutated into something else is a good one. Now, if that something else wants to compete and then eliminate man, well you got my full attention thus this movie. Science Fiction treads a fine line of being believable or not when introducing a story. It doesn't have to be perfect to make its point. It has to be respectful and this movie respects the viewer. You will not have any trouble getting into this movie after the first few minutes. Then, all the dots start to connect and cause a viewing pleasure. It will suck you right in and when the ducks line up, scare you good and proper..Enjoy with a favorite snack so you don't bite your nails
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    I would LOVE to see this movie remade with a good director and a large movie budget!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    picturetaker
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/9/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I originally saw this movie in the theatre. Many reviewers comment saying it should have gone straight to video but I don't think so. As this movie for its time was not that bad. I have seen this movie about 6 times since 1995 and every time I have enjoyed it. Could this movie have been better? Of course! But for what it cost and for what kind of movie it is, it is alright! Its such an interesting premise I would LOVE to see this movie remade with a good director and a large movie budget! As that would be GREAT! Screamers did have a OK script, it had a great story, OK character and storyline development. All in all it was an OK 1995 film. As most sci-fi goes it is not the worst at all! Screamers was an original movie and it is entertaining so if you get the opportunity to see it, I recommend you check it out if you like sci-fi movies.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Once it gets inside, that's when the killin' starts
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tieman64
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "We are now in a new form of schizophrenia. No more hysteria, no more projective paranoia, but this state of terror proper to the schizophrenic. [] The schizophrenic can no longer produce the limits of its own being. [] He is only a pure screen." - Baudrillard "That's right - Pinnochio's not a real little boy!" - Becker ("Screamers") Scifi author Harlan Ellison once took James Cameron to court, alleging that the director's 1984 film, "The Terminator", plagiarised "Demon With A Glass Hand" and "Soldier", two tales written by Ellison in the 1950s. But Cameron, a scifi nut, seems to have also borrowed heavily from Philip K Dick's "Second Variety", a 1953 short story which finds the world ravaged by war and mankind locked in combat with a race of machines. These machines were created for defence purposes, but eventually became "self aware", started evolving, making armies, factories and hunting down humans, whom they sought to completely eradicate. The machines then began creating terminator-like infiltration units; cyborgs which convincingly resemble humans and which are programmed to penetrate human bases. Dick's hero, a resourceful soldier, even resembles Cameron's Kyle Reese, and much of Dick's dialogue, desperate, fast and apocalyptic, recalls the frenetic banter in Cameron's "Terminator". While "Screamers", Christian Duguay's adaptation of Dick's "Second Variety", barely captures the tone and urgency of Dick's short story, Cameron's "Terminator" films do, though all these "adaptations" are more interesting in the way they demonstrate how Dick's approach to scifi changed from the 1950s onwards. All of Dick's novels are ontological conundrums, taking place in a landscape in which all "reality" seems to be constantly shifting, and in which worlds and selves constantly seem to fall apart. For Dick, there is no definitive reality, human identity itself is uncertain, nothing exists as it seems, and everything is simply a perception of pure information. In "Second Variety" these themes are approached in a fairly simple manner ("Is it an undercover killer robot or is it a human?", "What constitutes a robot?", "What constitutes a human?", "Aren't humans already cyborgs?", "How do I know what is real?", "How do I know what is machine?", "How do I know what I think I know?"), which is largely why it, and Dick's early work, remain his most popular. As Dick turned to drugs, stopped proof-reading, stopped perfecting and re-writing his stories, abandoned conventional narrative structures and started churning out novels quickly in a desperate attempt to pay his bills, his books, like his heroes and his own state of mind, became increasingly schizophrenic, paranoid and shapeless. Many deride Dick for this, but such a stance was the logical continuation of his early 1950s work. Today, Dick's later writing bare a striking similarity to postmodernist theories by thinkers such as Jameson, Baudrillard and Brian McHale. Dick anticipated the twenty-first century network society, a fragmented, culturally overloaded, media saturated world characterised by rapid technological change, constant movement and a dizzying, excessive and sometimes surreal aesthetic. For Dick, the future, our postmodern present, would morph into a sort of virtual reality game. A "consensual hallucination" in which all traditional demarcations or distinctions are erased. It is no longer an issue of there being a split between man and robot, but of man and technology constantly co-mingling, of both servicing the other, of all being technology, of man himself already being cybernetic, of the world already being cyberspacial, representational, all emotions faked, all behaviour play-acting, every object in quotes, everything grounded on the illusory. Whereas in an explicitly modernist film such as "Metropolis" the dichotomy between the original copy or experience (man) and the replication (machine) is very clear, in later Dickian films ("Blade Runner", Total Recall", "A Scanner Darkly", "Matrix", Cronenberg, Assayas etc - note how comparatively conservative Spielberg's version of Dick's "Minority Report" is) a crisis of representation occurs, as the signifier is now alienated from the object it signifies, a Deleuzian "schizoid existence" brought about by a breakdown "in the signifying chain". Unlike the apocalyptic, cosily hopeful rubble of "Terminator" and "Second Variety", later Dick also posits a urban, networked and mechanical landscape which engenders a consequential decline in organic feeling and sensibility. Men then become "consumers of illusion", an illusion of "belonging and participation" covering up massive industrial alienation. But every connection seems to lead back to corporations, a "soft fascism" whose grid it is impossible to escape. Here, everything is organised by the constant flow of money, all landscapes are advertising-saturated and the "goal" of commerce is to destroy history itself, to put its customers in the eternal Now, the big happy theme park of desires. No surprise then that one of Dick's last stories, "Stability", takes place in a world in which mankind doesn't progress anymore, despite the illusion of constant, hyper-motion. The story's solution? The invention of a Terminator-like time machine. If Dick got one thing wrong, it was in his assumption that this "schizoid existence" would trouble or traumatise man. Today, the opposite is true. Man's adapted. He loves his cage, even as he fantasises about Judgement Day. So postmodernist theory has itself has become what Brian McHale calls the "sister genre" of science fiction, both revolving around similar themes (What is reality? What constitutes the authentic human being?) and issues of technology and its effects on society and the individual subject. And while modernism was mainly interested in epistemology, the condition of knowledge, both Dick's scifi and postmodernism are governed by ontology and the basic conditions of existence. But "Screamers" and "The Terminator" films represent a kind of outdated, 1950s Philip K Dick, with nice easy, clear demarcations best suited for action cinema. Latter Dick is perhaps unsuited to the medium of cinema itself, though some of Olivier Assayas' more trashy films capture well his style ("Boarding Gate", "Demonlover"). 7.9/10  Worth one viewing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
