<filme>
 <id>
  765
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0103859
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1992
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  O Pr&iacute;ncipe das Mulheres
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  5.1
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  A successful executive and womanizer finds his lifestyle choices have turned back on him when his new female boss turns out to be an even bigger deviant then he is.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Marcus is a successful advertising executive who woos and beds women almost at will. After a company merger, he finds that his new boss, the ravishing Jacqueline, is treating him in exactly the same way. Completely traumatized by this, his work goes badly downhill. But then Jacqueline's more quietly attractive assistant, Angela, who has been dating Marcus' best friend, shows herself more than a little concerned by his parlous state.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Romance
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   advertising
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   womanizer
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   dating
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   african american
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   girl next door
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Reginald Hudlin
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Eddie Murphy
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Barry W. Blaustein
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Eddie Murphy
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Robin Givens
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Halle Berry
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Boomerang's a Romantic Comedy Classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tbills2
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Boomerang is one of the best examples of a movie that while watching it, it's to some extent ultimately unsatisfying, though nearly intentionally so for bettering the viewing, as it never fully fulfills your desirability towards the story or toward the characters, but it keeps you invested, and the movie ultimately sticks with you, leaving you yearning for more, kinda like, the characters themselves know that they're on the very verge of something greater in their lives and right now they're just messing around having some fun in the moment and you're there enjoying their experiences with them but you want to head to that better place too. Boomerang remains really appealing for its stylish, sophisticated, sexy, down-to-earth, kick-back vibe. It has just enough comedy with just enough romance. It's hip, it's smart, it's sweet, it's funny, it's freaky, and it's an original piece of film. Boomerang teaches you the way of a gentleman player, and as you enjoy it, it really pushes you to fantasize about your own love life. There's no pressing plot line, there's just a strong emotional attachment to the characters who all kinda kick it through the whole movie, making it very relatable. Eddie Murphy knew the vision he had in mind. Eddie came up with the story, saying he'd wanted to do that type of character; Murphy played a similar role in The Distinguished Gentlemen that same year, 1992. Murphy makes the movie as Marcus. In playing Marcus, Murphy tones down his comedic talents and timing in an interpret understanding that the character, Marcus, isn't as funny as he is. This is brilliant for the movie. If Murphy had went out on a high note on all of his funnier moments, which he could have easily done, Boomerang would have had a too cheesy comedic element, and it would have lost its smooth and suave attractiveness. Robin Givens is great, really great for the viewing. Do you understand that Givens is great for the viewing? David Alan Grier and Martin Lawrence are both so hilarious, if you don't know, and their characters are a lot of funny too. Halle Berry is amazing, so really sweet. She seems most at ease as Angela, a fine part for her, as Angela may be Halle's one character closest to her real live self. Halle Berry is the finest woman ever. Chris Rock and Tisha Campbell are good and funny and strengthen the movie with their small supporting parts. Boomerang is a good movie to just let go and enjoy it. It's sexy and it's real. Boomerang has a strong cultural click. Boomerang, Boomerang, Boomerang, Boom-Boomerang, Boomerang, Boomerang, I really love this movie. Can't you tell?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unsure Of Itself
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Errington_92
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This romantic comedy/drama never found its feet thematically. The essence of the narrative is Marcus Graham, the leading role played by Eddie Murphy, who is known for his slickness with the ladies when he meets his match in colleague Jacqueline, starting the morality play regarding relationships which is severely undermined and contradicted. Since the morality play forms Boomerang's primary theme it should have been handed better. Once Jacqueline began to reject Marcus Boomerang solicits sympathy towards him as being emotionally abused. Considering Marcus' previous actions had been satisfying his needs at the expense of women, it was very hard to feel sympathy towards him and produced nothing for character development. Especially as he betrayed Gerard, one of his best friends by sleeping with Gerard's love interest. It contradicts Boomerang's intentions as to some extent Marcus never changed his ways and as a result Gerard, who was the most honourable character and the type of personality Boomerang vainly strived Marcus to be, to the wayside. It churns itself out into an overdrawn story trying to keep hold of the audiences' attention but only highlighted Boomerang as a flawed film. When Boomerang was not focusing on its primary theme, it was mostly filled with characters whose sole aim seemed to be acting out situations for nothing more than comedy. Eartha Kitt as randy Lady Eloise whose blatant attempts to seduce Marcus came across as more repelling than funny, Chris Rock as assistant Bony T whose personality traits offered nothing more than a few laughs and Yvonne (Tisha Campbell - Martin), Marcus' former flame and coincidently next door neighbour who spent her time insulting him and warning potential suitors about his womanising. In spite of the screen time these characters had, it felt they were only filling void spaces to keep viewers entertained when Boomerang was meant to be dealing with relationship issues. Even Helen Strange, played with direct ferociousness by Grace Jones and offered a great critique on the ridiculous personalities of the advertising/fashion industry, came across as style of substance increasing Boomerang's superficialness in trying to present in depth the complications between men and women. Overall it's not surprising reflecting over Boomerang's theme and narrative that the conclusion is one of imbalance. If a different, more serious approach was taken without the starling contradictions and aiming for entertainment value rather than being earnest, Boomerang may have been a better film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Eddie Murphy once again shines in a romantic role while still being funny in Boomerang
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tavm
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Having only heard and seen clips of this movie for the last 20 years, I finally watched Boomerang on Netflix Streaming just now. Once again, Eddie Murphy got together with his writers from "Saturday Night Live"-Barry W. Blaustein and David Sheffield-and made another romantic comedy that turned out to be a success like their previous one in Coming to America. And once again, they got a fine supporting cast accompanying them like Lela Rochon (having previously appeared in Murphy's Harlem Nights), Robin Givens, Martin Lawrence, David Alan Grier, Chris Rock, Grace Jones, Eartha Kitt and a newcomer named Halle Berry. Oh, and Tisha Campbell also appeared before her teaming with Lawrence in his upcomimg series "Martin". This time the director picked was Reginald Hudlin with his brother Warrington as co-producer after their success with their debut feature House Party. Like Coming to America, this was a nice change of pace for Murphy from his previous wise-ass characters but with both funny and touching scenes. Really, I had a good time watching this. So on that note, I highly recommend Boomerang. Oh, and the person who played a commercial editor looked familiar so I looked at the cast list and found out he was played by the one and only Melvin Van Peebles!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Robin Givens is the highlight of a very funny and sexy film.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brooksduane54
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Eddie Murphy romantic/sex comedy "Boomerang" is, quite simply, a thorough and total joy. Murphy portrays longtime womanizer Marcus Graham with his usual charm and poise. Halle Berry is absolutely appealing and absolutely warm as the girl who prompts Marcus to clean up his horny act. Martin Lawrence and David Alan Grier provide ingratiating and stylish buddy-support. Lela Rochon and Eartha Kitt are, respectively, magnificently kittenish and magnificently cougar-ish as women with whom Marcus scores. Yet the film's greatest asset, its leading lure is Robin Givens's portrayal of Marcus's boss/female counterpart Jacqueline Broyer. She is by turns sexy and stylish, sultry and commanding, seductive and polished. We immediately see why Marcus falls under her spell and, when she dumps him, not only do we not turn against her, we admire her independent spirit and her no-bullshit attitude. Really and truly, by and of itself "Boomerang" is a sexy, charming, absolutely joyous romantic/sex farce; with Robin Givens on board, however, it achieves genuine cinematic greatness.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Some humor, though mostly boring
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    truwarier
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The scenes with the male actors (Murphy, Greer, Lawrence) have some humor. The jokes are OK, the actors are good, and they have very nice chemistry together. The love scenes, which there are several of, are very lame. Adrian Lyne should have brought in to direct them. The scenes of Murphy with the female characters are boring and repetitive. It becomes a struggle to get through them after awhile, which is a problem as they make up most of the movie. Score and soundtrack are nice, very early-90s. Some of the details are neat, such as the advertising spots. Most importantly, Eddie Murphy is portrayed as a huge stud. And quite effectively so.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Underdeveloped Romance !
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ahmed elshikh (ahmed_abd_elreheem@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What this movie is about? The story of a liar who lives a lying world then finds truth finally? A lover man who's torn between 2 different women? The friendship of 3 guys? Actually the movie itself doesn't know otherwise it could've been more coherent, enjoyable and complete. OK, it's a story of a man who sells everything until he himself becomes a merchandise to be sold. And as a romance, supposedly romance !, the movie pushes this lead to learn about himself as lost person without real love in his life. BUT this movie so lousily sinks itself in a lot of details, un-comic characters, many conversations before hitting the right nerve. It was too late for (Halle Berry) to discover that she loves (Eddie Murphy) or that he loves her; it seemed a desperate attempt for making a third act more than being the movie's main core for god's sake! Not to mention, the matter of so ugly (Robin Givens) on screen, portraying a femme fatale as well ??!! The inhumanly dreadful sight of (Grace Jones) who's one of a few emetic people I've watched in my entire life. The long conversations scenes which with the tepid, nearly dead, direction so the truly dull pace the whole thing looked close to pointless for most of the time. Many characters like (the mail-boy "Chris Rock", the mad model, the French artistic director, the old-deceived neighbor, the friend's parents, or even the annoying employee of the clothes store) all of them took more time on the screen than what the original story, any original story, did take or should've taken. I pitied the charming and talented young (Berry). Although, she was a perfect princess of innocence, but this dumb script and that endless digressions wasted her utterly. The movie didn't give her space to appear right, or to appear right as someone would love the lead (she advised him how to seduce her boss by Jazz !?). I think that it must've been clear to her, so somehow us, how she got something for him from the very start, and how she must take over the screen at least since the second half. Instead of that they threw some real naive stuff to her (like the clueless first dialog between her and Murphy), and treated her like minor character (the heroine's sidekick) all along to suddenly remember her just before the very end! Although the intense performance that she delivered at the scene of her emotional explosion was the best, most strong anything, of this movie.. still one of the worst movies she was in! After many hits in the field of action and comedy, why not (Eddie Murphy) takes on romance. It was a bold attempt. Yes, he's a good actor along with being big star, but the movie wasn't that good (the word is : broken up). I think it got something with (Murphy) himself as the story's writer, and maybe his fear that the movie could be just romance without comedy, to end up as jammed comedy with not-real-laughs that belated the romance if not suffocated it. I loved a few of his moments here; on their top of course is the shot in which he finds the money for his "fatigue" besides the bed from his female version who's now treating him like a whore, notice how Murphy  silently  pulls the sheets on his chest, sad with weak feminine look in his eyes; actually with wicked little reactions he mastered like these, he's one of few comedians who can make comedy brilliantly with or without talking. Anyhow, it seemed like many incomplete movies in one, or boring stray comedy. I know that it could've been nice romantic comedy but what I've watched was an ideal example for underdeveloped one or a movie with dysfunctional personality. I read opinions about (Boomerang) as "smart movie" please, it's anything but smart! P.S : at one scene (when the lead was being dumped) we see the lights go off at the top of one skyscraper. At later scene (when the lead hugs his friends) we see the lights go on at the same skyscraper !??... Naaa.. Don't bother, it's part of this movie's naivety !
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Players get played too
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Newsense
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/1/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Man has this movie aged well. Boomerang was crass, raunchy, vulgar and funny as hell to boot. It was Eddie Murphy in top form just the way we like him. Plot/story: Marcus Graham(Eddie Murphy) is a marketing executive with a player mentality who meets his match with a gorgeous boss by the name of Jacqueline(Robin Givens). Marcus eventually tries to cope after getting p-whipped and played by Jacqueline. Opinion: Boomerang was funny as hell back then as it is funny now. The interactions between Eddie Murphy, David Alan Grier and Martin Lawrence characters are funny as hell. Grace Jones's character Strange' is a riot. I still lmao at the restaurant scene where Strange' loudly proclaims her favorite part of the female anatomy 20 times in front of everybody. Eartha Kitt's Lady Eloise is a hoot also. John Weatherspoon is just as funny as David Alan Grier's character's father. Boomerang works because it doesn't just rely on the comics being funny alone(like most comedies do). Its material is funny in its raunchiness and the chemistry between everybody works. I would strongly recommend this movie any day over the recent busts that Eddie Murphy has starred in. 5 stars. Rest In Peace Eartha Kitt.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Boomerang
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/2/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I don't understand the meaning of the title (probably relating to throwing something away, and getting it back), but I recognised many of the African American stars in this film, and I enjoyed the fair amount. Basically Marcus Graham (Eddie Murphy) is a successful advertising executive, and also a hit with the ladies (womaniser). After a company merger he finds that his new boss, ravishing Jacqueline 'Jackie'/'Jack' Broyer (Robin Givens, former wife of Mike Tyson), she is treating him the same way he would. He thought he was in love with her, and for a while he was (presumably), and his work is going downhill, but then later he starts dating her more quietly attractive assistant Angela (Halle Berry), who was dating one of his best friends. In the end, after some negative turns and rejection, the eventually get back together, and they (supposedly) live happily ever after. I can definitely agree with the critics that Grace Jones as Helen Strang&eacute; and The Emperor's New Groove's Eartha Kitt as Lady Eloise give the film a buzz. Jones being, well, herself (putting on a French accent) is funny taking her knickers off in public, and demanding sex with Murphy, and saying "pussy" a lot, and Kitt with her funny nymphomaniac (desperate for sex) character, really husky voice, and sexy legs and body (even here 65, she's still foxy). Also starring Jumanji's David Alan Grier as Gerard Jackson, Martin Lawrence (just before his breakthrough in Bad Boys) as Tyler, Live and Let Die's Geoffrey Holder as Nelson, young Chris Rock (not long before he started stand-up comedy) as Bony T, Tisha Campbell as Yvonne and Lela Rochon as Christie. Sure, it's slightly long, but don't let that sway you. Worth watching!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A pretty good movie overall
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Valkyrie-8
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/2/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Typically I don't like Eddie Murphy since his range is so limited and his humor wasn't funny in 1980 and hasn't changed much since then however.... he breaks that mold and does a pretty decent job. He pulls off suave without being smarmy and except for the middle part of the script where he fails to see he's being played it works. It doesn't hurt that the movie has some gorgeous ladies (Halle, Robin Givens, Grace Jones). As a player Eddie shows some great style as not seen since the Tao of Steve. An underrated movie and worth the time to watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of my favorite comedies...Period
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Oatmeal-n-Bisquick77
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/2/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Where do I start? Wow. It is rare that a movie can make me smile but at the same make me really laugh. No fake laughs but real laughs I seen this movie a number of times and it never gets old. The cast is so superb... I mean come on Martin( who is actually funny in this movie... okay he was funny in blue streak also) David Allen Grier ( Very underrated talent...funniest cast member on "in living color") and of Course Eddie Murphy. Then the other supporting cast was hilarious. How can anyone not love this movie... and my god I can quote it all day long. This movie is a perfect example of relying on the surrounding cast members and not one star to bring in the funny. Worth the view..
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Boomerang's a Romantic Comedy Classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tbills2
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Boomerang is one of the best examples of a movie that while watching it, it's to some extent ultimately unsatisfying, though nearly intentionally so for bettering the viewing, as it never fully fulfills your desirability towards the story or toward the characters, but it keeps you invested, and the movie ultimately sticks with you, leaving you yearning for more, kinda like, the characters themselves know that they're on the very verge of something greater in their lives and right now they're just messing around having some fun in the moment and you're there enjoying their experiences with them but you want to head to that better place too. Boomerang remains really appealing for its stylish, sophisticated, sexy, down-to-earth, kick-back vibe. It has just enough comedy with just enough romance. It's hip, it's smart, it's sweet, it's funny, it's freaky, and it's an original piece of film. Boomerang teaches you the way of a gentleman player, and as you enjoy it, it really pushes you to fantasize about your own love life. There's no pressing plot line, there's just a strong emotional attachment to the characters who all kinda kick it through the whole movie, making it very relatable. Eddie Murphy knew the vision he had in mind. Eddie came up with the story, saying he'd wanted to do that type of character; Murphy played a similar role in The Distinguished Gentlemen that same year, 1992. Murphy makes the movie as Marcus. In playing Marcus, Murphy tones down his comedic talents and timing in an interpret understanding that the character, Marcus, isn't as funny as he is. This is brilliant for the movie. If Murphy had went out on a high note on all of his funnier moments, which he could have easily done, Boomerang would have had a too cheesy comedic element, and it would have lost its smooth and suave attractiveness. Robin Givens is great, really great for the viewing. Do you understand that Givens is great for the viewing? David Alan Grier and Martin Lawrence are both so hilarious, if you don't know, and their characters are a lot of funny too. Halle Berry is amazing, so really sweet. She seems most at ease as Angela, a fine part for her, as Angela may be Halle's one character closest to her real live self. Halle Berry is the finest woman ever. Chris Rock and Tisha Campbell are good and funny and strengthen the movie with their small supporting parts. Boomerang is a good movie to just let go and enjoy it. It's sexy and it's real. Boomerang has a strong cultural click. Boomerang, Boomerang, Boomerang, Boom-Boomerang, Boomerang, Boomerang, I really love this movie. Can't you tell?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unsure Of Itself
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Errington_92
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This romantic comedy/drama never found its feet thematically. The essence of the narrative is Marcus Graham, the leading role played by Eddie Murphy, who is known for his slickness with the ladies when he meets his match in colleague Jacqueline, starting the morality play regarding relationships which is severely undermined and contradicted. Since the morality play forms Boomerang's primary theme it should have been handed better. Once Jacqueline began to reject Marcus Boomerang solicits sympathy towards him as being emotionally abused. Considering Marcus' previous actions had been satisfying his needs at the expense of women, it was very hard to feel sympathy towards him and produced nothing for character development. Especially as he betrayed Gerard, one of his best friends by sleeping with Gerard's love interest. It contradicts Boomerang's intentions as to some extent Marcus never changed his ways and as a result Gerard, who was the most honourable character and the type of personality Boomerang vainly strived Marcus to be, to the wayside. It churns itself out into an overdrawn story trying to keep hold of the audiences' attention but only highlighted Boomerang as a flawed film. When Boomerang was not focusing on its primary theme, it was mostly filled with characters whose sole aim seemed to be acting out situations for nothing more than comedy. Eartha Kitt as randy Lady Eloise whose blatant attempts to seduce Marcus came across as more repelling than funny, Chris Rock as assistant Bony T whose personality traits offered nothing more than a few laughs and Yvonne (Tisha Campbell - Martin), Marcus' former flame and coincidently next door neighbour who spent her time insulting him and warning potential suitors about his womanising. In spite of the screen time these characters had, it felt they were only filling void spaces to keep viewers entertained when Boomerang was meant to be dealing with relationship issues. Even Helen Strange, played with direct ferociousness by Grace Jones and offered a great critique on the ridiculous personalities of the advertising/fashion industry, came across as style of substance increasing Boomerang's superficialness in trying to present in depth the complications between men and women. Overall it's not surprising reflecting over Boomerang's theme and narrative that the conclusion is one of imbalance. If a different, more serious approach was taken without the starling contradictions and aiming for entertainment value rather than being earnest, Boomerang may have been a better film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Eddie Murphy once again shines in a romantic role while still being funny in Boomerang
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tavm
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Having only heard and seen clips of this movie for the last 20 years, I finally watched Boomerang on Netflix Streaming just now. Once again, Eddie Murphy got together with his writers from "Saturday Night Live"-Barry W. Blaustein and David Sheffield-and made another romantic comedy that turned out to be a success like their previous one in Coming to America. And once again, they got a fine supporting cast accompanying them like Lela Rochon (having previously appeared in Murphy's Harlem Nights), Robin Givens, Martin Lawrence, David Alan Grier, Chris Rock, Grace Jones, Eartha Kitt and a newcomer named Halle Berry. Oh, and Tisha Campbell also appeared before her teaming with Lawrence in his upcomimg series "Martin". This time the director picked was Reginald Hudlin with his brother Warrington as co-producer after their success with their debut feature House Party. Like Coming to America, this was a nice change of pace for Murphy from his previous wise-ass characters but with both funny and touching scenes. Really, I had a good time watching this. So on that note, I highly recommend Boomerang. Oh, and the person who played a commercial editor looked familiar so I looked at the cast list and found out he was played by the one and only Melvin Van Peebles!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Robin Givens is the highlight of a very funny and sexy film.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brooksduane54
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Eddie Murphy romantic/sex comedy "Boomerang" is, quite simply, a thorough and total joy. Murphy portrays longtime womanizer Marcus Graham with his usual charm and poise. Halle Berry is absolutely appealing and absolutely warm as the girl who prompts Marcus to clean up his horny act. Martin Lawrence and David Alan Grier provide ingratiating and stylish buddy-support. Lela Rochon and Eartha Kitt are, respectively, magnificently kittenish and magnificently cougar-ish as women with whom Marcus scores. Yet the film's greatest asset, its leading lure is Robin Givens's portrayal of Marcus's boss/female counterpart Jacqueline Broyer. She is by turns sexy and stylish, sultry and commanding, seductive and polished. We immediately see why Marcus falls under her spell and, when she dumps him, not only do we not turn against her, we admire her independent spirit and her no-bullshit attitude. Really and truly, by and of itself "Boomerang" is a sexy, charming, absolutely joyous romantic/sex farce; with Robin Givens on board, however, it achieves genuine cinematic greatness.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Some humor, though mostly boring
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    truwarier
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The scenes with the male actors (Murphy, Greer, Lawrence) have some humor. The jokes are OK, the actors are good, and they have very nice chemistry together. The love scenes, which there are several of, are very lame. Adrian Lyne should have brought in to direct them. The scenes of Murphy with the female characters are boring and repetitive. It becomes a struggle to get through them after awhile, which is a problem as they make up most of the movie. Score and soundtrack are nice, very early-90s. Some of the details are neat, such as the advertising spots. Most importantly, Eddie Murphy is portrayed as a huge stud. And quite effectively so.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Underdeveloped Romance !
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ahmed elshikh (ahmed_abd_elreheem@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What this movie is about? The story of a liar who lives a lying world then finds truth finally? A lover man who's torn between 2 different women? The friendship of 3 guys? Actually the movie itself doesn't know otherwise it could've been more coherent, enjoyable and complete. OK, it's a story of a man who sells everything until he himself becomes a merchandise to be sold. And as a romance, supposedly romance !, the movie pushes this lead to learn about himself as lost person without real love in his life. BUT this movie so lousily sinks itself in a lot of details, un-comic characters, many conversations before hitting the right nerve. It was too late for (Halle Berry) to discover that she loves (Eddie Murphy) or that he loves her; it seemed a desperate attempt for making a third act more than being the movie's main core for god's sake! Not to mention, the matter of so ugly (Robin Givens) on screen, portraying a femme fatale as well ??!! The inhumanly dreadful sight of (Grace Jones) who's one of a few emetic people I've watched in my entire life. The long conversations scenes which with the tepid, nearly dead, direction so the truly dull pace the whole thing looked close to pointless for most of the time. Many characters like (the mail-boy "Chris Rock", the mad model, the French artistic director, the old-deceived neighbor, the friend's parents, or even the annoying employee of the clothes store) all of them took more time on the screen than what the original story, any original story, did take or should've taken. I pitied the charming and talented young (Berry). Although, she was a perfect princess of innocence, but this dumb script and that endless digressions wasted her utterly. The movie didn't give her space to appear right, or to appear right as someone would love the lead (she advised him how to seduce her boss by Jazz !?). I think that it must've been clear to her, so somehow us, how she got something for him from the very start, and how she must take over the screen at least since the second half. Instead of that they threw some real naive stuff to her (like the clueless first dialog between her and Murphy), and treated her like minor character (the heroine's sidekick) all along to suddenly remember her just before the very end! Although the intense performance that she delivered at the scene of her emotional explosion was the best, most strong anything, of this movie.. still one of the worst movies she was in! After many hits in the field of action and comedy, why not (Eddie Murphy) takes on romance. It was a bold attempt. Yes, he's a good actor along with being big star, but the movie wasn't that good (the word is : broken up). I think it got something with (Murphy) himself as the story's writer, and maybe his fear that the movie could be just romance without comedy, to end up as jammed comedy with not-real-laughs that belated the romance if not suffocated it. I loved a few of his moments here; on their top of course is the shot in which he finds the money for his "fatigue" besides the bed from his female version who's now treating him like a whore, notice how Murphy  silently  pulls the sheets on his chest, sad with weak feminine look in his eyes; actually with wicked little reactions he mastered like these, he's one of few comedians who can make comedy brilliantly with or without talking. Anyhow, it seemed like many incomplete movies in one, or boring stray comedy. I know that it could've been nice romantic comedy but what I've watched was an ideal example for underdeveloped one or a movie with dysfunctional personality. I read opinions about (Boomerang) as "smart movie" please, it's anything but smart! P.S : at one scene (when the lead was being dumped) we see the lights go off at the top of one skyscraper. At later scene (when the lead hugs his friends) we see the lights go on at the same skyscraper !??... Naaa.. Don't bother, it's part of this movie's naivety !
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Players get played too
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Newsense
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/1/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Man has this movie aged well. Boomerang was crass, raunchy, vulgar and funny as hell to boot. It was Eddie Murphy in top form just the way we like him. Plot/story: Marcus Graham(Eddie Murphy) is a marketing executive with a player mentality who meets his match with a gorgeous boss by the name of Jacqueline(Robin Givens). Marcus eventually tries to cope after getting p-whipped and played by Jacqueline. Opinion: Boomerang was funny as hell back then as it is funny now. The interactions between Eddie Murphy, David Alan Grier and Martin Lawrence characters are funny as hell. Grace Jones's character Strange' is a riot. I still lmao at the restaurant scene where Strange' loudly proclaims her favorite part of the female anatomy 20 times in front of everybody. Eartha Kitt's Lady Eloise is a hoot also. John Weatherspoon is just as funny as David Alan Grier's character's father. Boomerang works because it doesn't just rely on the comics being funny alone(like most comedies do). Its material is funny in its raunchiness and the chemistry between everybody works. I would strongly recommend this movie any day over the recent busts that Eddie Murphy has starred in. 5 stars. Rest In Peace Eartha Kitt.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Boomerang
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/2/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I don't understand the meaning of the title (probably relating to throwing something away, and getting it back), but I recognised many of the African American stars in this film, and I enjoyed the fair amount. Basically Marcus Graham (Eddie Murphy) is a successful advertising executive, and also a hit with the ladies (womaniser). After a company merger he finds that his new boss, ravishing Jacqueline 'Jackie'/'Jack' Broyer (Robin Givens, former wife of Mike Tyson), she is treating him the same way he would. He thought he was in love with her, and for a while he was (presumably), and his work is going downhill, but then later he starts dating her more quietly attractive assistant Angela (Halle Berry), who was dating one of his best friends. In the end, after some negative turns and rejection, the eventually get back together, and they (supposedly) live happily ever after. I can definitely agree with the critics that Grace Jones as Helen Strang&eacute; and The Emperor's New Groove's Eartha Kitt as Lady Eloise give the film a buzz. Jones being, well, herself (putting on a French accent) is funny taking her knickers off in public, and demanding sex with Murphy, and saying "pussy" a lot, and Kitt with her funny nymphomaniac (desperate for sex) character, really husky voice, and sexy legs and body (even here 65, she's still foxy). Also starring Jumanji's David Alan Grier as Gerard Jackson, Martin Lawrence (just before his breakthrough in Bad Boys) as Tyler, Live and Let Die's Geoffrey Holder as Nelson, young Chris Rock (not long before he started stand-up comedy) as Bony T, Tisha Campbell as Yvonne and Lela Rochon as Christie. Sure, it's slightly long, but don't let that sway you. Worth watching!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A pretty good movie overall
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Valkyrie-8
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/2/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Typically I don't like Eddie Murphy since his range is so limited and his humor wasn't funny in 1980 and hasn't changed much since then however.... he breaks that mold and does a pretty decent job. He pulls off suave without being smarmy and except for the middle part of the script where he fails to see he's being played it works. It doesn't hurt that the movie has some gorgeous ladies (Halle, Robin Givens, Grace Jones). As a player Eddie shows some great style as not seen since the Tao of Steve. An underrated movie and worth the time to watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of my favorite comedies...Period
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Oatmeal-n-Bisquick77
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/2/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Where do I start? Wow. It is rare that a movie can make me smile but at the same make me really laugh. No fake laughs but real laughs I seen this movie a number of times and it never gets old. The cast is so superb... I mean come on Martin( who is actually funny in this movie... okay he was funny in blue streak also) David Allen Grier ( Very underrated talent...funniest cast member on "in living color") and of Course Eddie Murphy. Then the other supporting cast was hilarious. How can anyone not love this movie... and my god I can quote it all day long. This movie is a perfect example of relying on the surrounding cast members and not one star to bring in the funny. Worth the view..
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Boomerang's a Romantic Comedy Classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tbills2
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Boomerang is one of the best examples of a movie that while watching it, it's to some extent ultimately unsatisfying, though nearly intentionally so for bettering the viewing, as it never fully fulfills your desirability towards the story or toward the characters, but it keeps you invested, and the movie ultimately sticks with you, leaving you yearning for more, kinda like, the characters themselves know that they're on the very verge of something greater in their lives and right now they're just messing around having some fun in the moment and you're there enjoying their experiences with them but you want to head to that better place too. Boomerang remains really appealing for its stylish, sophisticated, sexy, down-to-earth, kick-back vibe. It has just enough comedy with just enough romance. It's hip, it's smart, it's sweet, it's funny, it's freaky, and it's an original piece of film. Boomerang teaches you the way of a gentleman player, and as you enjoy it, it really pushes you to fantasize about your own love life. There's no pressing plot line, there's just a strong emotional attachment to the characters who all kinda kick it through the whole movie, making it very relatable. Eddie Murphy knew the vision he had in mind. Eddie came up with the story, saying he'd wanted to do that type of character; Murphy played a similar role in The Distinguished Gentlemen that same year, 1992. Murphy makes the movie as Marcus. In playing Marcus, Murphy tones down his comedic talents and timing in an interpret understanding that the character, Marcus, isn't as funny as he is. This is brilliant for the movie. If Murphy had went out on a high note on all of his funnier moments, which he could have easily done, Boomerang would have had a too cheesy comedic element, and it would have lost its smooth and suave attractiveness. Robin Givens is great, really great for the viewing. Do you understand that Givens is great for the viewing? David Alan Grier and Martin Lawrence are both so hilarious, if you don't know, and their characters are a lot of funny too. Halle Berry is amazing, so really sweet. She seems most at ease as Angela, a fine part for her, as Angela may be Halle's one character closest to her real live self. Halle Berry is the finest woman ever. Chris Rock and Tisha Campbell are good and funny and strengthen the movie with their small supporting parts. Boomerang is a good movie to just let go and enjoy it. It's sexy and it's real. Boomerang has a strong cultural click. Boomerang, Boomerang, Boomerang, Boom-Boomerang, Boomerang, Boomerang, I really love this movie. Can't you tell?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unsure Of Itself
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Errington_92
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This romantic comedy/drama never found its feet thematically. The essence of the narrative is Marcus Graham, the leading role played by Eddie Murphy, who is known for his slickness with the ladies when he meets his match in colleague Jacqueline, starting the morality play regarding relationships which is severely undermined and contradicted. Since the morality play forms Boomerang's primary theme it should have been handed better. Once Jacqueline began to reject Marcus Boomerang solicits sympathy towards him as being emotionally abused. Considering Marcus' previous actions had been satisfying his needs at the expense of women, it was very hard to feel sympathy towards him and produced nothing for character development. Especially as he betrayed Gerard, one of his best friends by sleeping with Gerard's love interest. It contradicts Boomerang's intentions as to some extent Marcus never changed his ways and as a result Gerard, who was the most honourable character and the type of personality Boomerang vainly strived Marcus to be, to the wayside. It churns itself out into an overdrawn story trying to keep hold of the audiences' attention but only highlighted Boomerang as a flawed film. When Boomerang was not focusing on its primary theme, it was mostly filled with characters whose sole aim seemed to be acting out situations for nothing more than comedy. Eartha Kitt as randy Lady Eloise whose blatant attempts to seduce Marcus came across as more repelling than funny, Chris Rock as assistant Bony T whose personality traits offered nothing more than a few laughs and Yvonne (Tisha Campbell - Martin), Marcus' former flame and coincidently next door neighbour who spent her time insulting him and warning potential suitors about his womanising. In spite of the screen time these characters had, it felt they were only filling void spaces to keep viewers entertained when Boomerang was meant to be dealing with relationship issues. Even Helen Strange, played with direct ferociousness by Grace Jones and offered a great critique on the ridiculous personalities of the advertising/fashion industry, came across as style of substance increasing Boomerang's superficialness in trying to present in depth the complications between men and women. Overall it's not surprising reflecting over Boomerang's theme and narrative that the conclusion is one of imbalance. If a different, more serious approach was taken without the starling contradictions and aiming for entertainment value rather than being earnest, Boomerang may have been a better film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Eddie Murphy once again shines in a romantic role while still being funny in Boomerang
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tavm
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Having only heard and seen clips of this movie for the last 20 years, I finally watched Boomerang on Netflix Streaming just now. Once again, Eddie Murphy got together with his writers from "Saturday Night Live"-Barry W. Blaustein and David Sheffield-and made another romantic comedy that turned out to be a success like their previous one in Coming to America. And once again, they got a fine supporting cast accompanying them like Lela Rochon (having previously appeared in Murphy's Harlem Nights), Robin Givens, Martin Lawrence, David Alan Grier, Chris Rock, Grace Jones, Eartha Kitt and a newcomer named Halle Berry. Oh, and Tisha Campbell also appeared before her teaming with Lawrence in his upcomimg series "Martin". This time the director picked was Reginald Hudlin with his brother Warrington as co-producer after their success with their debut feature House Party. Like Coming to America, this was a nice change of pace for Murphy from his previous wise-ass characters but with both funny and touching scenes. Really, I had a good time watching this. So on that note, I highly recommend Boomerang. Oh, and the person who played a commercial editor looked familiar so I looked at the cast list and found out he was played by the one and only Melvin Van Peebles!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Robin Givens is the highlight of a very funny and sexy film.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brooksduane54
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Eddie Murphy romantic/sex comedy "Boomerang" is, quite simply, a thorough and total joy. Murphy portrays longtime womanizer Marcus Graham with his usual charm and poise. Halle Berry is absolutely appealing and absolutely warm as the girl who prompts Marcus to clean up his horny act. Martin Lawrence and David Alan Grier provide ingratiating and stylish buddy-support. Lela Rochon and Eartha Kitt are, respectively, magnificently kittenish and magnificently cougar-ish as women with whom Marcus scores. Yet the film's greatest asset, its leading lure is Robin Givens's portrayal of Marcus's boss/female counterpart Jacqueline Broyer. She is by turns sexy and stylish, sultry and commanding, seductive and polished. We immediately see why Marcus falls under her spell and, when she dumps him, not only do we not turn against her, we admire her independent spirit and her no-bullshit attitude. Really and truly, by and of itself "Boomerang" is a sexy, charming, absolutely joyous romantic/sex farce; with Robin Givens on board, however, it achieves genuine cinematic greatness.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Some humor, though mostly boring
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    truwarier
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The scenes with the male actors (Murphy, Greer, Lawrence) have some humor. The jokes are OK, the actors are good, and they have very nice chemistry together. The love scenes, which there are several of, are very lame. Adrian Lyne should have brought in to direct them. The scenes of Murphy with the female characters are boring and repetitive. It becomes a struggle to get through them after awhile, which is a problem as they make up most of the movie. Score and soundtrack are nice, very early-90s. Some of the details are neat, such as the advertising spots. Most importantly, Eddie Murphy is portrayed as a huge stud. And quite effectively so.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Underdeveloped Romance !
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ahmed elshikh (ahmed_abd_elreheem@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What this movie is about? The story of a liar who lives a lying world then finds truth finally? A lover man who's torn between 2 different women? The friendship of 3 guys? Actually the movie itself doesn't know otherwise it could've been more coherent, enjoyable and complete. OK, it's a story of a man who sells everything until he himself becomes a merchandise to be sold. And as a romance, supposedly romance !, the movie pushes this lead to learn about himself as lost person without real love in his life. BUT this movie so lousily sinks itself in a lot of details, un-comic characters, many conversations before hitting the right nerve. It was too late for (Halle Berry) to discover that she loves (Eddie Murphy) or that he loves her; it seemed a desperate attempt for making a third act more than being the movie's main core for god's sake! Not to mention, the matter of so ugly (Robin Givens) on screen, portraying a femme fatale as well ??!! The inhumanly dreadful sight of (Grace Jones) who's one of a few emetic people I've watched in my entire life. The long conversations scenes which with the tepid, nearly dead, direction so the truly dull pace the whole thing looked close to pointless for most of the time. Many characters like (the mail-boy "Chris Rock", the mad model, the French artistic director, the old-deceived neighbor, the friend's parents, or even the annoying employee of the clothes store) all of them took more time on the screen than what the original story, any original story, did take or should've taken. I pitied the charming and talented young (Berry). Although, she was a perfect princess of innocence, but this dumb script and that endless digressions wasted her utterly. The movie didn't give her space to appear right, or to appear right as someone would love the lead (she advised him how to seduce her boss by Jazz !?). I think that it must've been clear to her, so somehow us, how she got something for him from the very start, and how she must take over the screen at least since the second half. Instead of that they threw some real naive stuff to her (like the clueless first dialog between her and Murphy), and treated her like minor character (the heroine's sidekick) all along to suddenly remember her just before the very end! Although the intense performance that she delivered at the scene of her emotional explosion was the best, most strong anything, of this movie.. still one of the worst movies she was in! After many hits in the field of action and comedy, why not (Eddie Murphy) takes on romance. It was a bold attempt. Yes, he's a good actor along with being big star, but the movie wasn't that good (the word is : broken up). I think it got something with (Murphy) himself as the story's writer, and maybe his fear that the movie could be just romance without comedy, to end up as jammed comedy with not-real-laughs that belated the romance if not suffocated it. I loved a few of his moments here; on their top of course is the shot in which he finds the money for his "fatigue" besides the bed from his female version who's now treating him like a whore, notice how Murphy  silently  pulls the sheets on his chest, sad with weak feminine look in his eyes; actually with wicked little reactions he mastered like these, he's one of few comedians who can make comedy brilliantly with or without talking. Anyhow, it seemed like many incomplete movies in one, or boring stray comedy. I know that it could've been nice romantic comedy but what I've watched was an ideal example for underdeveloped one or a movie with dysfunctional personality. I read opinions about (Boomerang) as "smart movie" please, it's anything but smart! P.S : at one scene (when the lead was being dumped) we see the lights go off at the top of one skyscraper. At later scene (when the lead hugs his friends) we see the lights go on at the same skyscraper !??... Naaa.. Don't bother, it's part of this movie's naivety !
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Players get played too
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Newsense
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/1/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Man has this movie aged well. Boomerang was crass, raunchy, vulgar and funny as hell to boot. It was Eddie Murphy in top form just the way we like him. Plot/story: Marcus Graham(Eddie Murphy) is a marketing executive with a player mentality who meets his match with a gorgeous boss by the name of Jacqueline(Robin Givens). Marcus eventually tries to cope after getting p-whipped and played by Jacqueline. Opinion: Boomerang was funny as hell back then as it is funny now. The interactions between Eddie Murphy, David Alan Grier and Martin Lawrence characters are funny as hell. Grace Jones's character Strange' is a riot. I still lmao at the restaurant scene where Strange' loudly proclaims her favorite part of the female anatomy 20 times in front of everybody. Eartha Kitt's Lady Eloise is a hoot also. John Weatherspoon is just as funny as David Alan Grier's character's father. Boomerang works because it doesn't just rely on the comics being funny alone(like most comedies do). Its material is funny in its raunchiness and the chemistry between everybody works. I would strongly recommend this movie any day over the recent busts that Eddie Murphy has starred in. 5 stars. Rest In Peace Eartha Kitt.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Boomerang
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/2/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I don't understand the meaning of the title (probably relating to throwing something away, and getting it back), but I recognised many of the African American stars in this film, and I enjoyed the fair amount. Basically Marcus Graham (Eddie Murphy) is a successful advertising executive, and also a hit with the ladies (womaniser). After a company merger he finds that his new boss, ravishing Jacqueline 'Jackie'/'Jack' Broyer (Robin Givens, former wife of Mike Tyson), she is treating him the same way he would. He thought he was in love with her, and for a while he was (presumably), and his work is going downhill, but then later he starts dating her more quietly attractive assistant Angela (Halle Berry), who was dating one of his best friends. In the end, after some negative turns and rejection, the eventually get back together, and they (supposedly) live happily ever after. I can definitely agree with the critics that Grace Jones as Helen Strang&eacute; and The Emperor's New Groove's Eartha Kitt as Lady Eloise give the film a buzz. Jones being, well, herself (putting on a French accent) is funny taking her knickers off in public, and demanding sex with Murphy, and saying "pussy" a lot, and Kitt with her funny nymphomaniac (desperate for sex) character, really husky voice, and sexy legs and body (even here 65, she's still foxy). Also starring Jumanji's David Alan Grier as Gerard Jackson, Martin Lawrence (just before his breakthrough in Bad Boys) as Tyler, Live and Let Die's Geoffrey Holder as Nelson, young Chris Rock (not long before he started stand-up comedy) as Bony T, Tisha Campbell as Yvonne and Lela Rochon as Christie. Sure, it's slightly long, but don't let that sway you. Worth watching!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A pretty good movie overall
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Valkyrie-8
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/2/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Typically I don't like Eddie Murphy since his range is so limited and his humor wasn't funny in 1980 and hasn't changed much since then however.... he breaks that mold and does a pretty decent job. He pulls off suave without being smarmy and except for the middle part of the script where he fails to see he's being played it works. It doesn't hurt that the movie has some gorgeous ladies (Halle, Robin Givens, Grace Jones). As a player Eddie shows some great style as not seen since the Tao of Steve. An underrated movie and worth the time to watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of my favorite comedies...Period
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Oatmeal-n-Bisquick77
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/2/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Where do I start? Wow. It is rare that a movie can make me smile but at the same make me really laugh. No fake laughs but real laughs I seen this movie a number of times and it never gets old. The cast is so superb... I mean come on Martin( who is actually funny in this movie... okay he was funny in blue streak also) David Allen Grier ( Very underrated talent...funniest cast member on "in living color") and of Course Eddie Murphy. Then the other supporting cast was hilarious. How can anyone not love this movie... and my god I can quote it all day long. This movie is a perfect example of relying on the surrounding cast members and not one star to bring in the funny. Worth the view..
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Boomerang's a Romantic Comedy Classic
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tbills2
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Boomerang is one of the best examples of a movie that while watching it, it's to some extent ultimately unsatisfying, though nearly intentionally so for bettering the viewing, as it never fully fulfills your desirability towards the story or toward the characters, but it keeps you invested, and the movie ultimately sticks with you, leaving you yearning for more, kinda like, the characters themselves know that they're on the very verge of something greater in their lives and right now they're just messing around having some fun in the moment and you're there enjoying their experiences with them but you want to head to that better place too. Boomerang remains really appealing for its stylish, sophisticated, sexy, down-to-earth, kick-back vibe. It has just enough comedy with just enough romance. It's hip, it's smart, it's sweet, it's funny, it's freaky, and it's an original piece of film. Boomerang teaches you the way of a gentleman player, and as you enjoy it, it really pushes you to fantasize about your own love life. There's no pressing plot line, there's just a strong emotional attachment to the characters who all kinda kick it through the whole movie, making it very relatable. Eddie Murphy knew the vision he had in mind. Eddie came up with the story, saying he'd wanted to do that type of character; Murphy played a similar role in The Distinguished Gentlemen that same year, 1992. Murphy makes the movie as Marcus. In playing Marcus, Murphy tones down his comedic talents and timing in an interpret understanding that the character, Marcus, isn't as funny as he is. This is brilliant for the movie. If Murphy had went out on a high note on all of his funnier moments, which he could have easily done, Boomerang would have had a too cheesy comedic element, and it would have lost its smooth and suave attractiveness. Robin Givens is great, really great for the viewing. Do you understand that Givens is great for the viewing? David Alan Grier and Martin Lawrence are both so hilarious, if you don't know, and their characters are a lot of funny too. Halle Berry is amazing, so really sweet. She seems most at ease as Angela, a fine part for her, as Angela may be Halle's one character closest to her real live self. Halle Berry is the finest woman ever. Chris Rock and Tisha Campbell are good and funny and strengthen the movie with their small supporting parts. Boomerang is a good movie to just let go and enjoy it. It's sexy and it's real. Boomerang has a strong cultural click. Boomerang, Boomerang, Boomerang, Boom-Boomerang, Boomerang, Boomerang, I really love this movie. Can't you tell?
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Unsure Of Itself
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Errington_92
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/12/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This romantic comedy/drama never found its feet thematically. The essence of the narrative is Marcus Graham, the leading role played by Eddie Murphy, who is known for his slickness with the ladies when he meets his match in colleague Jacqueline, starting the morality play regarding relationships which is severely undermined and contradicted. Since the morality play forms Boomerang's primary theme it should have been handed better. Once Jacqueline began to reject Marcus Boomerang solicits sympathy towards him as being emotionally abused. Considering Marcus' previous actions had been satisfying his needs at the expense of women, it was very hard to feel sympathy towards him and produced nothing for character development. Especially as he betrayed Gerard, one of his best friends by sleeping with Gerard's love interest. It contradicts Boomerang's intentions as to some extent Marcus never changed his ways and as a result Gerard, who was the most honourable character and the type of personality Boomerang vainly strived Marcus to be, to the wayside. It churns itself out into an overdrawn story trying to keep hold of the audiences' attention but only highlighted Boomerang as a flawed film. When Boomerang was not focusing on its primary theme, it was mostly filled with characters whose sole aim seemed to be acting out situations for nothing more than comedy. Eartha Kitt as randy Lady Eloise whose blatant attempts to seduce Marcus came across as more repelling than funny, Chris Rock as assistant Bony T whose personality traits offered nothing more than a few laughs and Yvonne (Tisha Campbell - Martin), Marcus' former flame and coincidently next door neighbour who spent her time insulting him and warning potential suitors about his womanising. In spite of the screen time these characters had, it felt they were only filling void spaces to keep viewers entertained when Boomerang was meant to be dealing with relationship issues. Even Helen Strange, played with direct ferociousness by Grace Jones and offered a great critique on the ridiculous personalities of the advertising/fashion industry, came across as style of substance increasing Boomerang's superficialness in trying to present in depth the complications between men and women. Overall it's not surprising reflecting over Boomerang's theme and narrative that the conclusion is one of imbalance. If a different, more serious approach was taken without the starling contradictions and aiming for entertainment value rather than being earnest, Boomerang may have been a better film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Eddie Murphy once again shines in a romantic role while still being funny in Boomerang
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tavm
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Having only heard and seen clips of this movie for the last 20 years, I finally watched Boomerang on Netflix Streaming just now. Once again, Eddie Murphy got together with his writers from "Saturday Night Live"-Barry W. Blaustein and David Sheffield-and made another romantic comedy that turned out to be a success like their previous one in Coming to America. And once again, they got a fine supporting cast accompanying them like Lela Rochon (having previously appeared in Murphy's Harlem Nights), Robin Givens, Martin Lawrence, David Alan Grier, Chris Rock, Grace Jones, Eartha Kitt and a newcomer named Halle Berry. Oh, and Tisha Campbell also appeared before her teaming with Lawrence in his upcomimg series "Martin". This time the director picked was Reginald Hudlin with his brother Warrington as co-producer after their success with their debut feature House Party. Like Coming to America, this was a nice change of pace for Murphy from his previous wise-ass characters but with both funny and touching scenes. Really, I had a good time watching this. So on that note, I highly recommend Boomerang. Oh, and the person who played a commercial editor looked familiar so I looked at the cast list and found out he was played by the one and only Melvin Van Peebles!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Robin Givens is the highlight of a very funny and sexy film.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    brooksduane54
   </autor>
   <data>
    11/8/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The Eddie Murphy romantic/sex comedy "Boomerang" is, quite simply, a thorough and total joy. Murphy portrays longtime womanizer Marcus Graham with his usual charm and poise. Halle Berry is absolutely appealing and absolutely warm as the girl who prompts Marcus to clean up his horny act. Martin Lawrence and David Alan Grier provide ingratiating and stylish buddy-support. Lela Rochon and Eartha Kitt are, respectively, magnificently kittenish and magnificently cougar-ish as women with whom Marcus scores. Yet the film's greatest asset, its leading lure is Robin Givens's portrayal of Marcus's boss/female counterpart Jacqueline Broyer. She is by turns sexy and stylish, sultry and commanding, seductive and polished. We immediately see why Marcus falls under her spell and, when she dumps him, not only do we not turn against her, we admire her independent spirit and her no-bullshit attitude. Really and truly, by and of itself "Boomerang" is a sexy, charming, absolutely joyous romantic/sex farce; with Robin Givens on board, however, it achieves genuine cinematic greatness.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Some humor, though mostly boring
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    truwarier
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The scenes with the male actors (Murphy, Greer, Lawrence) have some humor. The jokes are OK, the actors are good, and they have very nice chemistry together. The love scenes, which there are several of, are very lame. Adrian Lyne should have brought in to direct them. The scenes of Murphy with the female characters are boring and repetitive. It becomes a struggle to get through them after awhile, which is a problem as they make up most of the movie. Score and soundtrack are nice, very early-90s. Some of the details are neat, such as the advertising spots. Most importantly, Eddie Murphy is portrayed as a huge stud. And quite effectively so.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Underdeveloped Romance !
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ahmed elshikh (ahmed_abd_elreheem@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/4/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What this movie is about? The story of a liar who lives a lying world then finds truth finally? A lover man who's torn between 2 different women? The friendship of 3 guys? Actually the movie itself doesn't know otherwise it could've been more coherent, enjoyable and complete. OK, it's a story of a man who sells everything until he himself becomes a merchandise to be sold. And as a romance, supposedly romance !, the movie pushes this lead to learn about himself as lost person without real love in his life. BUT this movie so lousily sinks itself in a lot of details, un-comic characters, many conversations before hitting the right nerve. It was too late for (Halle Berry) to discover that she loves (Eddie Murphy) or that he loves her; it seemed a desperate attempt for making a third act more than being the movie's main core for god's sake! Not to mention, the matter of so ugly (Robin Givens) on screen, portraying a femme fatale as well ??!! The inhumanly dreadful sight of (Grace Jones) who's one of a few emetic people I've watched in my entire life. The long conversations scenes which with the tepid, nearly dead, direction so the truly dull pace the whole thing looked close to pointless for most of the time. Many characters like (the mail-boy "Chris Rock", the mad model, the French artistic director, the old-deceived neighbor, the friend's parents, or even the annoying employee of the clothes store) all of them took more time on the screen than what the original story, any original story, did take or should've taken. I pitied the charming and talented young (Berry). Although, she was a perfect princess of innocence, but this dumb script and that endless digressions wasted her utterly. The movie didn't give her space to appear right, or to appear right as someone would love the lead (she advised him how to seduce her boss by Jazz !?). I think that it must've been clear to her, so somehow us, how she got something for him from the very start, and how she must take over the screen at least since the second half. Instead of that they threw some real naive stuff to her (like the clueless first dialog between her and Murphy), and treated her like minor character (the heroine's sidekick) all along to suddenly remember her just before the very end! Although the intense performance that she delivered at the scene of her emotional explosion was the best, most strong anything, of this movie.. still one of the worst movies she was in! After many hits in the field of action and comedy, why not (Eddie Murphy) takes on romance. It was a bold attempt. Yes, he's a good actor along with being big star, but the movie wasn't that good (the word is : broken up). I think it got something with (Murphy) himself as the story's writer, and maybe his fear that the movie could be just romance without comedy, to end up as jammed comedy with not-real-laughs that belated the romance if not suffocated it. I loved a few of his moments here; on their top of course is the shot in which he finds the money for his "fatigue" besides the bed from his female version who's now treating him like a whore, notice how Murphy  silently  pulls the sheets on his chest, sad with weak feminine look in his eyes; actually with wicked little reactions he mastered like these, he's one of few comedians who can make comedy brilliantly with or without talking. Anyhow, it seemed like many incomplete movies in one, or boring stray comedy. I know that it could've been nice romantic comedy but what I've watched was an ideal example for underdeveloped one or a movie with dysfunctional personality. I read opinions about (Boomerang) as "smart movie" please, it's anything but smart! P.S : at one scene (when the lead was being dumped) we see the lights go off at the top of one skyscraper. At later scene (when the lead hugs his friends) we see the lights go on at the same skyscraper !??... Naaa.. Don't bother, it's part of this movie's naivety !
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Players get played too
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Newsense
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/1/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Man has this movie aged well. Boomerang was crass, raunchy, vulgar and funny as hell to boot. It was Eddie Murphy in top form just the way we like him. Plot/story: Marcus Graham(Eddie Murphy) is a marketing executive with a player mentality who meets his match with a gorgeous boss by the name of Jacqueline(Robin Givens). Marcus eventually tries to cope after getting p-whipped and played by Jacqueline. Opinion: Boomerang was funny as hell back then as it is funny now. The interactions between Eddie Murphy, David Alan Grier and Martin Lawrence characters are funny as hell. Grace Jones's character Strange' is a riot. I still lmao at the restaurant scene where Strange' loudly proclaims her favorite part of the female anatomy 20 times in front of everybody. Eartha Kitt's Lady Eloise is a hoot also. John Weatherspoon is just as funny as David Alan Grier's character's father. Boomerang works because it doesn't just rely on the comics being funny alone(like most comedies do). Its material is funny in its raunchiness and the chemistry between everybody works. I would strongly recommend this movie any day over the recent busts that Eddie Murphy has starred in. 5 stars. Rest In Peace Eartha Kitt.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Boomerang
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Jackson Booth-Millard
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/2/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I don't understand the meaning of the title (probably relating to throwing something away, and getting it back), but I recognised many of the African American stars in this film, and I enjoyed the fair amount. Basically Marcus Graham (Eddie Murphy) is a successful advertising executive, and also a hit with the ladies (womaniser). After a company merger he finds that his new boss, ravishing Jacqueline 'Jackie'/'Jack' Broyer (Robin Givens, former wife of Mike Tyson), she is treating him the same way he would. He thought he was in love with her, and for a while he was (presumably), and his work is going downhill, but then later he starts dating her more quietly attractive assistant Angela (Halle Berry), who was dating one of his best friends. In the end, after some negative turns and rejection, the eventually get back together, and they (supposedly) live happily ever after. I can definitely agree with the critics that Grace Jones as Helen Strang&eacute; and The Emperor's New Groove's Eartha Kitt as Lady Eloise give the film a buzz. Jones being, well, herself (putting on a French accent) is funny taking her knickers off in public, and demanding sex with Murphy, and saying "pussy" a lot, and Kitt with her funny nymphomaniac (desperate for sex) character, really husky voice, and sexy legs and body (even here 65, she's still foxy). Also starring Jumanji's David Alan Grier as Gerard Jackson, Martin Lawrence (just before his breakthrough in Bad Boys) as Tyler, Live and Let Die's Geoffrey Holder as Nelson, young Chris Rock (not long before he started stand-up comedy) as Bony T, Tisha Campbell as Yvonne and Lela Rochon as Christie. Sure, it's slightly long, but don't let that sway you. Worth watching!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A pretty good movie overall
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Valkyrie-8
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/2/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Typically I don't like Eddie Murphy since his range is so limited and his humor wasn't funny in 1980 and hasn't changed much since then however.... he breaks that mold and does a pretty decent job. He pulls off suave without being smarmy and except for the middle part of the script where he fails to see he's being played it works. It doesn't hurt that the movie has some gorgeous ladies (Halle, Robin Givens, Grace Jones). As a player Eddie shows some great style as not seen since the Tao of Steve. An underrated movie and worth the time to watch.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of my favorite comedies...Period
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Oatmeal-n-Bisquick77
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/2/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Where do I start? Wow. It is rare that a movie can make me smile but at the same make me really laugh. No fake laughs but real laughs I seen this movie a number of times and it never gets old. The cast is so superb... I mean come on Martin( who is actually funny in this movie... okay he was funny in blue streak also) David Allen Grier ( Very underrated talent...funniest cast member on "in living color") and of Course Eddie Murphy. Then the other supporting cast was hilarious. How can anyone not love this movie... and my god I can quote it all day long. This movie is a perfect example of relying on the surrounding cast members and not one star to bring in the funny. Worth the view..
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
