<filme>
 <id>
  773
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0110604
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1994
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Testemunha Muda
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.7
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Billy Hughes, a mute makeup artist working on a slasher film being shot in Moscow, is locked in the studio after hours. While there she witnesses a brutal murder, and must first escape ... &nbsp;&raquo;
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Billy Hughes, a mute makeup artist working on a slasher film being shot in Moscow, is locked in the studio after hours. While there she witnesses a brutal murder, and must first escape capture at that time, then keep from being killed before convincing authorities of what she's seen. Plot twists galore follow as Billy tries to stay alive.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Horror
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Thriller
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   mute
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   murder
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   nudity
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   sign language
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   home invasion
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Anthony Waller
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Anthony Waller
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Marina Zudina
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Fay Ripley
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Evan Richards
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Highly recommended despite some silliness towards the end
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    coachjacki
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The first half to 3/4 of this movie are top quality suspense with a fine smattering of dark humor. The director uses camera angles and location beautifully and the screenplay makes a brilliant job of using the lead characters vulnerabilities (her inability to speak and being in a foreign country)as a major plot device. The chase through the building sequence is one of the most thrilling chase scenes I've witnessed - and all without special effects or big explosions! The movie had me on the edge of my seat and I lost several nails due to biting them, which no movie has managed in quite some time!! It reminded me of Wait Until Dark & The Spiral Staircase (original) and was every bit as beautifully directed as those awesome classics of old. I particularly loved the use of some very well thought-out close-ups and slo-mo camera sequences that added a unique style to the movie and enhanced it's sense of dread and danger. BUT I have to agree with other reviewers that unfortunately things fall apart a bit in the last half hour. Not enough to completely ruin the movie but certainly enough to pull the viewer out of the suspense and involvement that we'd been enjoying until then. (for some viewers this might actually be a good thing tho!!) I liked the ambiguity of the character that was introduced, I thought that worked well because we could not tell where he stood. But the other "surprises" and strange plot twists became a bit over the top and the movie lost a lot of it's very well developed feeling of reality. As for the sister/husband act in that last bit, they could easily have been left out (they were not important to the plot) and the movie would have been far better off for it. It really does feel like someone else took over and put together the ending because it's so different to the rest of it. But in the end this still rates as one of the best thrillers I've seen in recent times - as long as you don't count the ending. I highly recommend it. (I gave it a 7 but with a few adjustments to the screenplay it could easily have been a 9 & a new classic)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Still Great after Eighteen Years
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Claudio Carvalho
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In Moscow, the clumsy director Andy Clarke (Evan Richards) is making a slasher movie in a studio set with Russian and American cast and crew. The responsible for the makeup is the mute Billy Hughes (Marina Sudina), who is the sister of Andy's girlfriend Karen Hughes (Fay Ripley). One day, Billy needs to find a mask for the shot on the next day and she stays after hours in the studio set seeking out the object. However, the janitor locks her in the studio alone and Billy cannot find a way out. When Billy sees light in the studio, she accidentally witnesses the Russians Arkadi (Igor Volkov) and Lyosha (Sergej Karlenkov) making a porn snuff movie and brutally killing a woman. Billy succeeds to escape, but the police officers do not trust on her. Further, the powerful Russian mafia chases her believing that Billy has a diskette with evidences against the mobsters. I saw "Mute Witness" eighteen years ago and I loved this film. Yesterday I saw it again, now on DVD, and it still is a great film that combines thriller and horror with black humor in a plot with many twists. The director Anthony Waller masterly raises tension and relieves with black humor, startling the viewer and then making him or her laugh. Unfortunately the conclusion is a little disappointing but it is worthwhile watching this wonderful little film. My vote is eight. Title (Brazil): "Testemunha Muda" ("Mute Witness")
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    superb action-comedy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nose_smasher
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/8/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Man, I never laughed so much this year, and it's quite hard to make me laugh. While I expected some Hostel-style movie, the smile came to my face even from the beginning. This film-inside-film start with a female stabbed "victim" messing the whole set until she finally "die". Her overacting drive the director nuts and his funny reaction tell us, the viewers, that Mute Witness is not a typically horror movie. The main character, the mute American make-up artist Billy Hughes, is played by the beautiful yet talented Russian actress Marina Zudina. Her performance is top-notch; her character can't speak, so the body language and the emotions on her face must compensate.And, oh boy, she did a wonderful job. Her sister (Fay Ripley) is the girlfriend or the fianc&eacute;e or the wife of the "in-film director" (Evan Richards). They were both very funny most of the time. I won't spoil more, but the scenes following the bathtub moment, with them both, the fake policemen and later the angry neighbor were plain brilliant black comedy. The plot got twisted near the end, possibly misleading at one particular moment. But don't worry. Such a delicious movie can be viewed in family or with your boy-/girl-/friend.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gripping and Tense Thriller !!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    prabanand-c
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/5/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I don't know how this film went unnoticed for so long. I saw this film on TV, i was flipping through the channels and came across this unexpectedly well made film. i missed the first, probably , 10 minutes, but that does not matter..this film literally gripped me, it is a real spine chiller. The absence of well known actors in the film adds on to the effect,u do not know what to expect from the actors because they are new. U never know when they will get killed or what they are up to. so it is all the more tense.Even though there are many new faces their performances were top class. The filmmakers play with your mind, just revealing enough gore to make imagine the rest. The shock, fear, horror and helplessness are also brought out well by characters in the film. The well written situations n twists,fast camera movements, slick editing and superb direction makes it an excellent suspense thriller. This film actually switches between the genres - horror and suspense thriller leaving the viewer clueless and tensed. Undoubtedly comparable to Hitchcock. I could not even move from the TV even during the commercial breaks .. i was the helpless MUTE WITNESS to this superb film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The first hour was really good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sashank_kini-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/11/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The first half of the Mute Witness was really understandable and thrilling- it made sense. The start of the movie, which takes us into a studio where a murder is being rehearsed, is really shot well. Then, we are introduced to a mute make-up artist, her sister and her sister's husband, who is the director of the film. It has quirky moments in the beginning, which is actually funny and witty, and you know that these things must be occurring during a film's shooting. Side-actors thinking they are the prime actors and trying to lengthen the screen to show their presence to the audience, even though their role is miserly, many a times, happens in cinemas. So you could relate the plot. Then, at night, the mute lady, is mistakenly locked at the studio- what could she do, she couldn't shout as she was dumb. She calls her sister, then witnesses a murder taking place in the studio by two of the people working in the film and decides to fled. The murderers search for her and find her when her sister and her husband arrive at the spot and she explains to them with gestures and hand movements about the murder. But no one except her sister pays any heed to her as the accused have eradicated all their evidence. Then, we are shown that the accused are working for someone who tells them to kill the witness. They attack her at her house but she outwits them and while her sister, worried, and her husband arrive at her place. Till here, the story is perfectly clear. I loved everyone's acting and found their performances strong. The way they show the lady being murdered is quiet brutal and intense, though not scary in my opinion. The way they show the mute girl escaping is shot really well. The camera effects, the sudden silence, the heavy breathing, all are taken in such a way that the audience is glued to the film. There is some dark humor in this film but in the first hour only, it gels with the film pretty well. The agitated sister, who is so worried about her sister, gives a power-packed performance, while her husband, who takes the matter lightly, too, gives a real good role. As the film is shot in Russia, many of the people speak in foreign language, but you can cope up with them because there is a translator in the beginning and well, you can understand. The scene where the girl is lying in the tub is taken pretty well, in slow-motion and I loved the camera-effects, the 'plopping' of the water. Really strong. But after that, we are introduced to a person who is from the police and rescues the girl. Then, there is a mish-mash where the story turns way too stupid and confusing that I was perplexed at the end, not with the story at all. The 'Reaper' thing was all c**p and the film became more sleazy. The sister and the husband's role became quite unnecessary and stupid as from a powerful role, their role turn absolutely stupid, and they were more kept as the funny guys. The mute-girl too became childish and a side-kick while the police-man became the hero of the film all of a sudden. I reckon that there would have been different script writers for the first and the second part, because after about an hour, the film became the complete opposite. Its reputation tumbled down and that's the main reason I am giving it a six out of ten. THe first have surely deserved an eight.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Another Hitchcock wannabe...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JoeytheBrit
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/9/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Mute Witness begins strongly with a simple but intense set-up that has a mute American make-up girl accidentally getting locked in the decrepit Russian film studio in which she is working on a US film being directed by her brother-in-law. While trying to find her way out she inadvertently witnesses the filming of a snuff movie and subsequently finds herself hunted through the deserted studio's dimly-lit corridors. All of this is well paced and filmed  the murder scene, like Hitchcock's famous shower scene, cleverly uses the viewer's imagination to provide the gory details  and the film manages to create an increasingly claustrophobic atmosphere as the heroine's avenues of escape are systematically reduced. Unfortunately, it can't sustain this level of tension for long, and once the plot is opened out things start to unravel. For some unfathomable reason, writer/director Anthony Waller decides to introduce a 'comedy' element in the guise of the heroine's film director brother-in-law, and the whole thing nearly falls apart completely as he and his wife (the heroine's sister) are given increasingly larger amounts of screen time. The story grows a little confused as it widens from a lady-in-peril thriller to more of a conspiracy plot involving a shadowy figure called The Reaper (Alec Guinness in a cameo he filmed about nine years before the rest of the film was shot!) and police complicity in the snuff trade, and by its climax, Waller has thrown in so many twists and red herrings to try and disguise some glaring plot holes that you're left deflated by thinking about what could have been.. Waller was obviously trying to deliver a Hitchcock homage, but this is all the evidence you need that aiming for Hitch on your debut effort is aiming way too high.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Well worth watching
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    shornby-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/3/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you enjoy suspense this movie has it. The fact that Marina Zudina portrays a mute adds to her haplessness and increases the suspense. Alec Guiness's appearance was nice, but didn't really add to the movie. I'm not sure if Evan Richard's part as Andy Clarke was an attempt to add a little humor or if he was supposed to just be a bumbling idiot. I thought the cinematography was excellent. This added not just to the quality of the production but to the suspense as well. The bathtub seen with the water droplets in slow motion was wonderful. Also the scene where the knife comes down and then it switches to Andy Clarke cutting an extremely rare piece of meat was very well done. I would call it overall good entertainment
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Tense and gritty little thriller!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    The_Void
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/2/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I went into this film expecting a slasher, and while Mute Witness does take influence from said style of film-making, this is much more than just your average slash flick. There are a number of thrillers that focus on a certain disability - blindness is more common (Blind Terror, Wait Until Dark, Cat o'Nine Tails to name a handful), but the implications of having a mute lead in a thriller such as this are well portrayed, and actually integral to the plot as the fact that the lead character can't speak is often the reason why she finds herself in dangerous situations that would be easy for anyone else to get out of. Our mute witness is Billy Hughes, a make-up artist working on a horror film production at a studio in Moscow. She finds herself locked in after hours one night, and after attempting to phone her sister for help, she stumbles upon what at first appears to be the making of an illicit sex flick, but soon turns out to be a snuff movie! She tries to convince the authorities of what she's seen, but finds that no one believes her story... Recently Hostel made the headlines for showing snuff movie making in a foreign country, but this film did it first and actually does a better job. It's maybe not quite as nasty as Eli Roth's opus, but the gore is more effective, and since director Anthony Waller (who went on to direct one of my favourite modern thrillers with 'The Guilty') implements a good sense of humour into the proceedings, Mute Witness is both sufficiently gory and fun to watch. The director certainly has a talent for crafting suspenseful thrill rides, as this one never stands still. The plot is put into action quickly, and Waller constantly introduces plot twists which give a big helping hand to the overall entertainment value of the film. The acting isn't bad for a B-movie, with young performers Marina Zudina, Fay Ripley and Evan Richards delivering good performances. The atmosphere is gritty, and the Russian locations are suitably unfriendly, which helps the film to retain a foreboding atmosphere. Overall, Mute Witness is a much better film than you might expect it to be. The plot flows well, and the atmosphere and tension are spot on.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A great, fun and effective (if sadly overlooked) thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Trelloskilos
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/10/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It is always a well-known, and important directorial device to set up the atmosphere of a film within the first 5 minutes. In the crucial opening scenes, the film should assert itself and make the viewers take notice and get interested in the rest of the film. Here, in "Mute Witness", we find a prime example of this. *Scene spoiler* In the first 5-10 minutes, the film opens to a very Hitchcockian scene of a pretty blonde lady in her apartment, with the radio on. She's wandering around, applying lipstick, dolling herself up, and ignoring the news report of a serial killer on the loose. Of course, the serial killer is in her house, and monitoring her moves, knife in hand. She hears a noise, looks in a room, and there is her partner in a pool of blood. At the very point of her screams, she turns around to be faced with the knife-wielding maniac, who stabs her repeatedly in a brutal and horrifying act.... ...then something odd happens. As the woman convulses in her death throes, the killer sits down and takes out a cigarette to watch his victim perish. Before he finds his lighter, his cigarette is lit...from someone else in the room! The camera pans out, and we realise that there are more and more people in the room, some taking notes, some filming, some recording the death, and that the lady is taking an awfully long time to die, and making a very hammy job of it too. When the audience realises what's going on, and the whole scene is part of a film, the suspenseful and horrific scene takes on an element of humour. *End Scene Spoiler* I have highlighted this opening scene for several reasons. Firstly, it portrays the atmosphere of the whole movie perfectly. A thriller in the style of Hitchcock or De Palma, with some very disorientating, and even blackly humorous moments. - It conveys a central subject matter (that of the difference between a 'movie screen death' and a 'snuff film death', an issue which is elaborated on later in the film), and finally, it introduces the viewer to the characters, all as silently as possible. The plot of Mute Witness centres around Billy Hughes, an American special effects make-up artist who is working on the set of the film, being shot in a large warehouse in Moscow. Billy cannot speak, but she communicates in sign language through her sister. After the end of an evening's filming, Billy inadvertently finds herself locked in the warehouse by accident, and in her attempt to escape, is witness to two of the crew making what first appears to be a porno film, but turns out to be a snuff movie. Suddenly, her escape from the warehouse is a matter of life and death. Without doubt, the first half of the film is powerful and absolutely gripping. Billy's saving grace, and her handicap is the fact that she isn't able to utter a sound. (In fact, in my opinion, one of the best aspects of the film is the fact that it isn't chock-full of women screaming). There are some utterly disturbing moments, and some superb set-pieces of real suspense (The corridoor, and the elevator shaft are perfect examples). The timing is fluid, and the whole first half is an incredibly satisfying experience in itself. The second half of the film introduces new concepts. While there are still several suspenseful moments, the focus is on plot twists. New characters are introduced, and it is ambiguous as to whose side they are on. While there is nothing wrong per se with the second half of the film, it just doesn't quite measure up to the first half. There are some neat moments of black humour that perfectly juxtapose and punctuate some very dramatic scenes, but there are also some very lame comedy moments (coming specifically from Billy's sister and her fianc&eacute;e, who happens to be the director of the movie Billy is working on), that almost ruin the film, just because they are badly misplaced and/or mistimed and ruin the pace. - At the end, the twists keep coming at a rapid-fire speed, and the climax of the film is, appropriately, as tense as the first half. There are several things that really make the movie work. The barriers of communication that Billy must face, both as a mute, and as an American in Moscow, mean that even an emergency call for help becomes a dangerous situation. The actress that plays Billy, Natasha Zudina, does a wonderful job in the film, with an engaging on-screen prescence, and a brilliant performance, and finally, the direction as a whole, but most particularly in the first half of the film, which truly is a study in Alfred Hitchcock's suspense/thriller film techniques. As I have already said, though, the let-downs in the film are from some terrible comic relief moments that really do not need to be added. There is already a consistent and effective streak of dark humour that appears in the film without the need for the characters of Karen Hughes and Andy Clarke (The sister and the moviemaker) to turn their scenes into some unusual sit-com. However, despite these shortcomings, the film is a thoroughly enjoyable thriller, and ideal for a group viewing at halloween. (Certainly better than the usual slasher horror film...!)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Words cannot express the horror.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lost-in-limbo
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Billy Hughes is a mute young lady working for make-up on a cheap horror picture being filmed in Moscow by an American director. One night Billy gets locked in the movie studio. Later that night she hears that someone might be in the building and goes to check it out. That's when she stumbles across a woman being brutally murdered, while being filmed. After escaping the clutches of the murderers, Billy informs the authorities, only to be red-faced when the men show it was an act. Billy knows what she saw and soon her life is in turmoil again from underground figures that believe she has something of importance. I don't know how this heart-pounding sleeper passed me by, but I thought it was a much older flick. There's one thing though, it's got to be one of the most jarringly, and intense thrillers I've seen in quite a while. It's just a great suspense builder and mostly everything clicks into place! The first half of the feature is surprisingly gripping with taut sequences that have your heart in your throat and clouds us with an atmospherically foreboding environment of alienation. Underling this is a humorously wicked black streak. Faults do pop up in the story, as it does lose that furious grip it held so early and goofy humour (or better putter comic relief) between Fay Ripley and Evan Richard's characters is a hit and miss affair by being too forceful. In the long run, it probably could have done without. Despite some cringe moments, this aspect didn't hinder my enjoyment of it. For me, the soft ending they decided to go with just didn't feel right. The interestingly mysterious premise was eerie to the bone and packed some unsettling goods. So multi-facet was the context and its thrills, there was something fresh to how this all plays out and the nervy jolts and unbearable tension are weaved into a range of sudden plot turns and twists. Really, they made superb use of the novel idea of this disability and to handicap the situation, by staging it in a foreign place where not too many spoke English and so we are caught up in the confusion too. The delicate Marina Zudina gives a harrowing portrayal of the American mute girl Billy. The way she able to display the erratic emotions through her eyes and actions gave it some gruff and believability. Director Anthony Waller shoots the flick in a rather stylish, well-timed and skillful manner, without loosing that grimy look that eventuates from its rigid surroundings and a powerfully airy music score persistently nags at you. The only real name to make an appearance was small cameo part by Alec Guinness. The performances by the cast were all fine, especially the nail biting turns by Oleg Yankovsky and Igor Volkov as the Russian murderers. This riveting feature that's mostly made up of unknowns, is way better than your average dark thriller. Highly Recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Highly recommended despite some silliness towards the end
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    coachjacki
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The first half to 3/4 of this movie are top quality suspense with a fine smattering of dark humor. The director uses camera angles and location beautifully and the screenplay makes a brilliant job of using the lead characters vulnerabilities (her inability to speak and being in a foreign country)as a major plot device. The chase through the building sequence is one of the most thrilling chase scenes I've witnessed - and all without special effects or big explosions! The movie had me on the edge of my seat and I lost several nails due to biting them, which no movie has managed in quite some time!! It reminded me of Wait Until Dark & The Spiral Staircase (original) and was every bit as beautifully directed as those awesome classics of old. I particularly loved the use of some very well thought-out close-ups and slo-mo camera sequences that added a unique style to the movie and enhanced it's sense of dread and danger. BUT I have to agree with other reviewers that unfortunately things fall apart a bit in the last half hour. Not enough to completely ruin the movie but certainly enough to pull the viewer out of the suspense and involvement that we'd been enjoying until then. (for some viewers this might actually be a good thing tho!!) I liked the ambiguity of the character that was introduced, I thought that worked well because we could not tell where he stood. But the other "surprises" and strange plot twists became a bit over the top and the movie lost a lot of it's very well developed feeling of reality. As for the sister/husband act in that last bit, they could easily have been left out (they were not important to the plot) and the movie would have been far better off for it. It really does feel like someone else took over and put together the ending because it's so different to the rest of it. But in the end this still rates as one of the best thrillers I've seen in recent times - as long as you don't count the ending. I highly recommend it. (I gave it a 7 but with a few adjustments to the screenplay it could easily have been a 9 & a new classic)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Still Great after Eighteen Years
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Claudio Carvalho
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In Moscow, the clumsy director Andy Clarke (Evan Richards) is making a slasher movie in a studio set with Russian and American cast and crew. The responsible for the makeup is the mute Billy Hughes (Marina Sudina), who is the sister of Andy's girlfriend Karen Hughes (Fay Ripley). One day, Billy needs to find a mask for the shot on the next day and she stays after hours in the studio set seeking out the object. However, the janitor locks her in the studio alone and Billy cannot find a way out. When Billy sees light in the studio, she accidentally witnesses the Russians Arkadi (Igor Volkov) and Lyosha (Sergej Karlenkov) making a porn snuff movie and brutally killing a woman. Billy succeeds to escape, but the police officers do not trust on her. Further, the powerful Russian mafia chases her believing that Billy has a diskette with evidences against the mobsters. I saw "Mute Witness" eighteen years ago and I loved this film. Yesterday I saw it again, now on DVD, and it still is a great film that combines thriller and horror with black humor in a plot with many twists. The director Anthony Waller masterly raises tension and relieves with black humor, startling the viewer and then making him or her laugh. Unfortunately the conclusion is a little disappointing but it is worthwhile watching this wonderful little film. My vote is eight. Title (Brazil): "Testemunha Muda" ("Mute Witness")
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    superb action-comedy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nose_smasher
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/8/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Man, I never laughed so much this year, and it's quite hard to make me laugh. While I expected some Hostel-style movie, the smile came to my face even from the beginning. This film-inside-film start with a female stabbed "victim" messing the whole set until she finally "die". Her overacting drive the director nuts and his funny reaction tell us, the viewers, that Mute Witness is not a typically horror movie. The main character, the mute American make-up artist Billy Hughes, is played by the beautiful yet talented Russian actress Marina Zudina. Her performance is top-notch; her character can't speak, so the body language and the emotions on her face must compensate.And, oh boy, she did a wonderful job. Her sister (Fay Ripley) is the girlfriend or the fianc&eacute;e or the wife of the "in-film director" (Evan Richards). They were both very funny most of the time. I won't spoil more, but the scenes following the bathtub moment, with them both, the fake policemen and later the angry neighbor were plain brilliant black comedy. The plot got twisted near the end, possibly misleading at one particular moment. But don't worry. Such a delicious movie can be viewed in family or with your boy-/girl-/friend.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gripping and Tense Thriller !!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    prabanand-c
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/5/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I don't know how this film went unnoticed for so long. I saw this film on TV, i was flipping through the channels and came across this unexpectedly well made film. i missed the first, probably , 10 minutes, but that does not matter..this film literally gripped me, it is a real spine chiller. The absence of well known actors in the film adds on to the effect,u do not know what to expect from the actors because they are new. U never know when they will get killed or what they are up to. so it is all the more tense.Even though there are many new faces their performances were top class. The filmmakers play with your mind, just revealing enough gore to make imagine the rest. The shock, fear, horror and helplessness are also brought out well by characters in the film. The well written situations n twists,fast camera movements, slick editing and superb direction makes it an excellent suspense thriller. This film actually switches between the genres - horror and suspense thriller leaving the viewer clueless and tensed. Undoubtedly comparable to Hitchcock. I could not even move from the TV even during the commercial breaks .. i was the helpless MUTE WITNESS to this superb film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The first hour was really good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sashank_kini-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/11/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The first half of the Mute Witness was really understandable and thrilling- it made sense. The start of the movie, which takes us into a studio where a murder is being rehearsed, is really shot well. Then, we are introduced to a mute make-up artist, her sister and her sister's husband, who is the director of the film. It has quirky moments in the beginning, which is actually funny and witty, and you know that these things must be occurring during a film's shooting. Side-actors thinking they are the prime actors and trying to lengthen the screen to show their presence to the audience, even though their role is miserly, many a times, happens in cinemas. So you could relate the plot. Then, at night, the mute lady, is mistakenly locked at the studio- what could she do, she couldn't shout as she was dumb. She calls her sister, then witnesses a murder taking place in the studio by two of the people working in the film and decides to fled. The murderers search for her and find her when her sister and her husband arrive at the spot and she explains to them with gestures and hand movements about the murder. But no one except her sister pays any heed to her as the accused have eradicated all their evidence. Then, we are shown that the accused are working for someone who tells them to kill the witness. They attack her at her house but she outwits them and while her sister, worried, and her husband arrive at her place. Till here, the story is perfectly clear. I loved everyone's acting and found their performances strong. The way they show the lady being murdered is quiet brutal and intense, though not scary in my opinion. The way they show the mute girl escaping is shot really well. The camera effects, the sudden silence, the heavy breathing, all are taken in such a way that the audience is glued to the film. There is some dark humor in this film but in the first hour only, it gels with the film pretty well. The agitated sister, who is so worried about her sister, gives a power-packed performance, while her husband, who takes the matter lightly, too, gives a real good role. As the film is shot in Russia, many of the people speak in foreign language, but you can cope up with them because there is a translator in the beginning and well, you can understand. The scene where the girl is lying in the tub is taken pretty well, in slow-motion and I loved the camera-effects, the 'plopping' of the water. Really strong. But after that, we are introduced to a person who is from the police and rescues the girl. Then, there is a mish-mash where the story turns way too stupid and confusing that I was perplexed at the end, not with the story at all. The 'Reaper' thing was all c**p and the film became more sleazy. The sister and the husband's role became quite unnecessary and stupid as from a powerful role, their role turn absolutely stupid, and they were more kept as the funny guys. The mute-girl too became childish and a side-kick while the police-man became the hero of the film all of a sudden. I reckon that there would have been different script writers for the first and the second part, because after about an hour, the film became the complete opposite. Its reputation tumbled down and that's the main reason I am giving it a six out of ten. THe first have surely deserved an eight.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Another Hitchcock wannabe...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JoeytheBrit
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/9/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Mute Witness begins strongly with a simple but intense set-up that has a mute American make-up girl accidentally getting locked in the decrepit Russian film studio in which she is working on a US film being directed by her brother-in-law. While trying to find her way out she inadvertently witnesses the filming of a snuff movie and subsequently finds herself hunted through the deserted studio's dimly-lit corridors. All of this is well paced and filmed  the murder scene, like Hitchcock's famous shower scene, cleverly uses the viewer's imagination to provide the gory details  and the film manages to create an increasingly claustrophobic atmosphere as the heroine's avenues of escape are systematically reduced. Unfortunately, it can't sustain this level of tension for long, and once the plot is opened out things start to unravel. For some unfathomable reason, writer/director Anthony Waller decides to introduce a 'comedy' element in the guise of the heroine's film director brother-in-law, and the whole thing nearly falls apart completely as he and his wife (the heroine's sister) are given increasingly larger amounts of screen time. The story grows a little confused as it widens from a lady-in-peril thriller to more of a conspiracy plot involving a shadowy figure called The Reaper (Alec Guinness in a cameo he filmed about nine years before the rest of the film was shot!) and police complicity in the snuff trade, and by its climax, Waller has thrown in so many twists and red herrings to try and disguise some glaring plot holes that you're left deflated by thinking about what could have been.. Waller was obviously trying to deliver a Hitchcock homage, but this is all the evidence you need that aiming for Hitch on your debut effort is aiming way too high.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Well worth watching
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    shornby-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/3/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you enjoy suspense this movie has it. The fact that Marina Zudina portrays a mute adds to her haplessness and increases the suspense. Alec Guiness's appearance was nice, but didn't really add to the movie. I'm not sure if Evan Richard's part as Andy Clarke was an attempt to add a little humor or if he was supposed to just be a bumbling idiot. I thought the cinematography was excellent. This added not just to the quality of the production but to the suspense as well. The bathtub seen with the water droplets in slow motion was wonderful. Also the scene where the knife comes down and then it switches to Andy Clarke cutting an extremely rare piece of meat was very well done. I would call it overall good entertainment
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Tense and gritty little thriller!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    The_Void
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/2/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I went into this film expecting a slasher, and while Mute Witness does take influence from said style of film-making, this is much more than just your average slash flick. There are a number of thrillers that focus on a certain disability - blindness is more common (Blind Terror, Wait Until Dark, Cat o'Nine Tails to name a handful), but the implications of having a mute lead in a thriller such as this are well portrayed, and actually integral to the plot as the fact that the lead character can't speak is often the reason why she finds herself in dangerous situations that would be easy for anyone else to get out of. Our mute witness is Billy Hughes, a make-up artist working on a horror film production at a studio in Moscow. She finds herself locked in after hours one night, and after attempting to phone her sister for help, she stumbles upon what at first appears to be the making of an illicit sex flick, but soon turns out to be a snuff movie! She tries to convince the authorities of what she's seen, but finds that no one believes her story... Recently Hostel made the headlines for showing snuff movie making in a foreign country, but this film did it first and actually does a better job. It's maybe not quite as nasty as Eli Roth's opus, but the gore is more effective, and since director Anthony Waller (who went on to direct one of my favourite modern thrillers with 'The Guilty') implements a good sense of humour into the proceedings, Mute Witness is both sufficiently gory and fun to watch. The director certainly has a talent for crafting suspenseful thrill rides, as this one never stands still. The plot is put into action quickly, and Waller constantly introduces plot twists which give a big helping hand to the overall entertainment value of the film. The acting isn't bad for a B-movie, with young performers Marina Zudina, Fay Ripley and Evan Richards delivering good performances. The atmosphere is gritty, and the Russian locations are suitably unfriendly, which helps the film to retain a foreboding atmosphere. Overall, Mute Witness is a much better film than you might expect it to be. The plot flows well, and the atmosphere and tension are spot on.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A great, fun and effective (if sadly overlooked) thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Trelloskilos
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/10/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It is always a well-known, and important directorial device to set up the atmosphere of a film within the first 5 minutes. In the crucial opening scenes, the film should assert itself and make the viewers take notice and get interested in the rest of the film. Here, in "Mute Witness", we find a prime example of this. *Scene spoiler* In the first 5-10 minutes, the film opens to a very Hitchcockian scene of a pretty blonde lady in her apartment, with the radio on. She's wandering around, applying lipstick, dolling herself up, and ignoring the news report of a serial killer on the loose. Of course, the serial killer is in her house, and monitoring her moves, knife in hand. She hears a noise, looks in a room, and there is her partner in a pool of blood. At the very point of her screams, she turns around to be faced with the knife-wielding maniac, who stabs her repeatedly in a brutal and horrifying act.... ...then something odd happens. As the woman convulses in her death throes, the killer sits down and takes out a cigarette to watch his victim perish. Before he finds his lighter, his cigarette is lit...from someone else in the room! The camera pans out, and we realise that there are more and more people in the room, some taking notes, some filming, some recording the death, and that the lady is taking an awfully long time to die, and making a very hammy job of it too. When the audience realises what's going on, and the whole scene is part of a film, the suspenseful and horrific scene takes on an element of humour. *End Scene Spoiler* I have highlighted this opening scene for several reasons. Firstly, it portrays the atmosphere of the whole movie perfectly. A thriller in the style of Hitchcock or De Palma, with some very disorientating, and even blackly humorous moments. - It conveys a central subject matter (that of the difference between a 'movie screen death' and a 'snuff film death', an issue which is elaborated on later in the film), and finally, it introduces the viewer to the characters, all as silently as possible. The plot of Mute Witness centres around Billy Hughes, an American special effects make-up artist who is working on the set of the film, being shot in a large warehouse in Moscow. Billy cannot speak, but she communicates in sign language through her sister. After the end of an evening's filming, Billy inadvertently finds herself locked in the warehouse by accident, and in her attempt to escape, is witness to two of the crew making what first appears to be a porno film, but turns out to be a snuff movie. Suddenly, her escape from the warehouse is a matter of life and death. Without doubt, the first half of the film is powerful and absolutely gripping. Billy's saving grace, and her handicap is the fact that she isn't able to utter a sound. (In fact, in my opinion, one of the best aspects of the film is the fact that it isn't chock-full of women screaming). There are some utterly disturbing moments, and some superb set-pieces of real suspense (The corridoor, and the elevator shaft are perfect examples). The timing is fluid, and the whole first half is an incredibly satisfying experience in itself. The second half of the film introduces new concepts. While there are still several suspenseful moments, the focus is on plot twists. New characters are introduced, and it is ambiguous as to whose side they are on. While there is nothing wrong per se with the second half of the film, it just doesn't quite measure up to the first half. There are some neat moments of black humour that perfectly juxtapose and punctuate some very dramatic scenes, but there are also some very lame comedy moments (coming specifically from Billy's sister and her fianc&eacute;e, who happens to be the director of the movie Billy is working on), that almost ruin the film, just because they are badly misplaced and/or mistimed and ruin the pace. - At the end, the twists keep coming at a rapid-fire speed, and the climax of the film is, appropriately, as tense as the first half. There are several things that really make the movie work. The barriers of communication that Billy must face, both as a mute, and as an American in Moscow, mean that even an emergency call for help becomes a dangerous situation. The actress that plays Billy, Natasha Zudina, does a wonderful job in the film, with an engaging on-screen prescence, and a brilliant performance, and finally, the direction as a whole, but most particularly in the first half of the film, which truly is a study in Alfred Hitchcock's suspense/thriller film techniques. As I have already said, though, the let-downs in the film are from some terrible comic relief moments that really do not need to be added. There is already a consistent and effective streak of dark humour that appears in the film without the need for the characters of Karen Hughes and Andy Clarke (The sister and the moviemaker) to turn their scenes into some unusual sit-com. However, despite these shortcomings, the film is a thoroughly enjoyable thriller, and ideal for a group viewing at halloween. (Certainly better than the usual slasher horror film...!)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Words cannot express the horror.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lost-in-limbo
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Billy Hughes is a mute young lady working for make-up on a cheap horror picture being filmed in Moscow by an American director. One night Billy gets locked in the movie studio. Later that night she hears that someone might be in the building and goes to check it out. That's when she stumbles across a woman being brutally murdered, while being filmed. After escaping the clutches of the murderers, Billy informs the authorities, only to be red-faced when the men show it was an act. Billy knows what she saw and soon her life is in turmoil again from underground figures that believe she has something of importance. I don't know how this heart-pounding sleeper passed me by, but I thought it was a much older flick. There's one thing though, it's got to be one of the most jarringly, and intense thrillers I've seen in quite a while. It's just a great suspense builder and mostly everything clicks into place! The first half of the feature is surprisingly gripping with taut sequences that have your heart in your throat and clouds us with an atmospherically foreboding environment of alienation. Underling this is a humorously wicked black streak. Faults do pop up in the story, as it does lose that furious grip it held so early and goofy humour (or better putter comic relief) between Fay Ripley and Evan Richard's characters is a hit and miss affair by being too forceful. In the long run, it probably could have done without. Despite some cringe moments, this aspect didn't hinder my enjoyment of it. For me, the soft ending they decided to go with just didn't feel right. The interestingly mysterious premise was eerie to the bone and packed some unsettling goods. So multi-facet was the context and its thrills, there was something fresh to how this all plays out and the nervy jolts and unbearable tension are weaved into a range of sudden plot turns and twists. Really, they made superb use of the novel idea of this disability and to handicap the situation, by staging it in a foreign place where not too many spoke English and so we are caught up in the confusion too. The delicate Marina Zudina gives a harrowing portrayal of the American mute girl Billy. The way she able to display the erratic emotions through her eyes and actions gave it some gruff and believability. Director Anthony Waller shoots the flick in a rather stylish, well-timed and skillful manner, without loosing that grimy look that eventuates from its rigid surroundings and a powerfully airy music score persistently nags at you. The only real name to make an appearance was small cameo part by Alec Guinness. The performances by the cast were all fine, especially the nail biting turns by Oleg Yankovsky and Igor Volkov as the Russian murderers. This riveting feature that's mostly made up of unknowns, is way better than your average dark thriller. Highly Recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Highly recommended despite some silliness towards the end
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    coachjacki
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The first half to 3/4 of this movie are top quality suspense with a fine smattering of dark humor. The director uses camera angles and location beautifully and the screenplay makes a brilliant job of using the lead characters vulnerabilities (her inability to speak and being in a foreign country)as a major plot device. The chase through the building sequence is one of the most thrilling chase scenes I've witnessed - and all without special effects or big explosions! The movie had me on the edge of my seat and I lost several nails due to biting them, which no movie has managed in quite some time!! It reminded me of Wait Until Dark & The Spiral Staircase (original) and was every bit as beautifully directed as those awesome classics of old. I particularly loved the use of some very well thought-out close-ups and slo-mo camera sequences that added a unique style to the movie and enhanced it's sense of dread and danger. BUT I have to agree with other reviewers that unfortunately things fall apart a bit in the last half hour. Not enough to completely ruin the movie but certainly enough to pull the viewer out of the suspense and involvement that we'd been enjoying until then. (for some viewers this might actually be a good thing tho!!) I liked the ambiguity of the character that was introduced, I thought that worked well because we could not tell where he stood. But the other "surprises" and strange plot twists became a bit over the top and the movie lost a lot of it's very well developed feeling of reality. As for the sister/husband act in that last bit, they could easily have been left out (they were not important to the plot) and the movie would have been far better off for it. It really does feel like someone else took over and put together the ending because it's so different to the rest of it. But in the end this still rates as one of the best thrillers I've seen in recent times - as long as you don't count the ending. I highly recommend it. (I gave it a 7 but with a few adjustments to the screenplay it could easily have been a 9 & a new classic)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Still Great after Eighteen Years
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Claudio Carvalho
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In Moscow, the clumsy director Andy Clarke (Evan Richards) is making a slasher movie in a studio set with Russian and American cast and crew. The responsible for the makeup is the mute Billy Hughes (Marina Sudina), who is the sister of Andy's girlfriend Karen Hughes (Fay Ripley). One day, Billy needs to find a mask for the shot on the next day and she stays after hours in the studio set seeking out the object. However, the janitor locks her in the studio alone and Billy cannot find a way out. When Billy sees light in the studio, she accidentally witnesses the Russians Arkadi (Igor Volkov) and Lyosha (Sergej Karlenkov) making a porn snuff movie and brutally killing a woman. Billy succeeds to escape, but the police officers do not trust on her. Further, the powerful Russian mafia chases her believing that Billy has a diskette with evidences against the mobsters. I saw "Mute Witness" eighteen years ago and I loved this film. Yesterday I saw it again, now on DVD, and it still is a great film that combines thriller and horror with black humor in a plot with many twists. The director Anthony Waller masterly raises tension and relieves with black humor, startling the viewer and then making him or her laugh. Unfortunately the conclusion is a little disappointing but it is worthwhile watching this wonderful little film. My vote is eight. Title (Brazil): "Testemunha Muda" ("Mute Witness")
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    superb action-comedy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nose_smasher
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/8/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Man, I never laughed so much this year, and it's quite hard to make me laugh. While I expected some Hostel-style movie, the smile came to my face even from the beginning. This film-inside-film start with a female stabbed "victim" messing the whole set until she finally "die". Her overacting drive the director nuts and his funny reaction tell us, the viewers, that Mute Witness is not a typically horror movie. The main character, the mute American make-up artist Billy Hughes, is played by the beautiful yet talented Russian actress Marina Zudina. Her performance is top-notch; her character can't speak, so the body language and the emotions on her face must compensate.And, oh boy, she did a wonderful job. Her sister (Fay Ripley) is the girlfriend or the fianc&eacute;e or the wife of the "in-film director" (Evan Richards). They were both very funny most of the time. I won't spoil more, but the scenes following the bathtub moment, with them both, the fake policemen and later the angry neighbor were plain brilliant black comedy. The plot got twisted near the end, possibly misleading at one particular moment. But don't worry. Such a delicious movie can be viewed in family or with your boy-/girl-/friend.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gripping and Tense Thriller !!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    prabanand-c
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/5/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I don't know how this film went unnoticed for so long. I saw this film on TV, i was flipping through the channels and came across this unexpectedly well made film. i missed the first, probably , 10 minutes, but that does not matter..this film literally gripped me, it is a real spine chiller. The absence of well known actors in the film adds on to the effect,u do not know what to expect from the actors because they are new. U never know when they will get killed or what they are up to. so it is all the more tense.Even though there are many new faces their performances were top class. The filmmakers play with your mind, just revealing enough gore to make imagine the rest. The shock, fear, horror and helplessness are also brought out well by characters in the film. The well written situations n twists,fast camera movements, slick editing and superb direction makes it an excellent suspense thriller. This film actually switches between the genres - horror and suspense thriller leaving the viewer clueless and tensed. Undoubtedly comparable to Hitchcock. I could not even move from the TV even during the commercial breaks .. i was the helpless MUTE WITNESS to this superb film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The first hour was really good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sashank_kini-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/11/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The first half of the Mute Witness was really understandable and thrilling- it made sense. The start of the movie, which takes us into a studio where a murder is being rehearsed, is really shot well. Then, we are introduced to a mute make-up artist, her sister and her sister's husband, who is the director of the film. It has quirky moments in the beginning, which is actually funny and witty, and you know that these things must be occurring during a film's shooting. Side-actors thinking they are the prime actors and trying to lengthen the screen to show their presence to the audience, even though their role is miserly, many a times, happens in cinemas. So you could relate the plot. Then, at night, the mute lady, is mistakenly locked at the studio- what could she do, she couldn't shout as she was dumb. She calls her sister, then witnesses a murder taking place in the studio by two of the people working in the film and decides to fled. The murderers search for her and find her when her sister and her husband arrive at the spot and she explains to them with gestures and hand movements about the murder. But no one except her sister pays any heed to her as the accused have eradicated all their evidence. Then, we are shown that the accused are working for someone who tells them to kill the witness. They attack her at her house but she outwits them and while her sister, worried, and her husband arrive at her place. Till here, the story is perfectly clear. I loved everyone's acting and found their performances strong. The way they show the lady being murdered is quiet brutal and intense, though not scary in my opinion. The way they show the mute girl escaping is shot really well. The camera effects, the sudden silence, the heavy breathing, all are taken in such a way that the audience is glued to the film. There is some dark humor in this film but in the first hour only, it gels with the film pretty well. The agitated sister, who is so worried about her sister, gives a power-packed performance, while her husband, who takes the matter lightly, too, gives a real good role. As the film is shot in Russia, many of the people speak in foreign language, but you can cope up with them because there is a translator in the beginning and well, you can understand. The scene where the girl is lying in the tub is taken pretty well, in slow-motion and I loved the camera-effects, the 'plopping' of the water. Really strong. But after that, we are introduced to a person who is from the police and rescues the girl. Then, there is a mish-mash where the story turns way too stupid and confusing that I was perplexed at the end, not with the story at all. The 'Reaper' thing was all c**p and the film became more sleazy. The sister and the husband's role became quite unnecessary and stupid as from a powerful role, their role turn absolutely stupid, and they were more kept as the funny guys. The mute-girl too became childish and a side-kick while the police-man became the hero of the film all of a sudden. I reckon that there would have been different script writers for the first and the second part, because after about an hour, the film became the complete opposite. Its reputation tumbled down and that's the main reason I am giving it a six out of ten. THe first have surely deserved an eight.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Another Hitchcock wannabe...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JoeytheBrit
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/9/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Mute Witness begins strongly with a simple but intense set-up that has a mute American make-up girl accidentally getting locked in the decrepit Russian film studio in which she is working on a US film being directed by her brother-in-law. While trying to find her way out she inadvertently witnesses the filming of a snuff movie and subsequently finds herself hunted through the deserted studio's dimly-lit corridors. All of this is well paced and filmed  the murder scene, like Hitchcock's famous shower scene, cleverly uses the viewer's imagination to provide the gory details  and the film manages to create an increasingly claustrophobic atmosphere as the heroine's avenues of escape are systematically reduced. Unfortunately, it can't sustain this level of tension for long, and once the plot is opened out things start to unravel. For some unfathomable reason, writer/director Anthony Waller decides to introduce a 'comedy' element in the guise of the heroine's film director brother-in-law, and the whole thing nearly falls apart completely as he and his wife (the heroine's sister) are given increasingly larger amounts of screen time. The story grows a little confused as it widens from a lady-in-peril thriller to more of a conspiracy plot involving a shadowy figure called The Reaper (Alec Guinness in a cameo he filmed about nine years before the rest of the film was shot!) and police complicity in the snuff trade, and by its climax, Waller has thrown in so many twists and red herrings to try and disguise some glaring plot holes that you're left deflated by thinking about what could have been.. Waller was obviously trying to deliver a Hitchcock homage, but this is all the evidence you need that aiming for Hitch on your debut effort is aiming way too high.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Well worth watching
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    shornby-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/3/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you enjoy suspense this movie has it. The fact that Marina Zudina portrays a mute adds to her haplessness and increases the suspense. Alec Guiness's appearance was nice, but didn't really add to the movie. I'm not sure if Evan Richard's part as Andy Clarke was an attempt to add a little humor or if he was supposed to just be a bumbling idiot. I thought the cinematography was excellent. This added not just to the quality of the production but to the suspense as well. The bathtub seen with the water droplets in slow motion was wonderful. Also the scene where the knife comes down and then it switches to Andy Clarke cutting an extremely rare piece of meat was very well done. I would call it overall good entertainment
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Tense and gritty little thriller!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    The_Void
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/2/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I went into this film expecting a slasher, and while Mute Witness does take influence from said style of film-making, this is much more than just your average slash flick. There are a number of thrillers that focus on a certain disability - blindness is more common (Blind Terror, Wait Until Dark, Cat o'Nine Tails to name a handful), but the implications of having a mute lead in a thriller such as this are well portrayed, and actually integral to the plot as the fact that the lead character can't speak is often the reason why she finds herself in dangerous situations that would be easy for anyone else to get out of. Our mute witness is Billy Hughes, a make-up artist working on a horror film production at a studio in Moscow. She finds herself locked in after hours one night, and after attempting to phone her sister for help, she stumbles upon what at first appears to be the making of an illicit sex flick, but soon turns out to be a snuff movie! She tries to convince the authorities of what she's seen, but finds that no one believes her story... Recently Hostel made the headlines for showing snuff movie making in a foreign country, but this film did it first and actually does a better job. It's maybe not quite as nasty as Eli Roth's opus, but the gore is more effective, and since director Anthony Waller (who went on to direct one of my favourite modern thrillers with 'The Guilty') implements a good sense of humour into the proceedings, Mute Witness is both sufficiently gory and fun to watch. The director certainly has a talent for crafting suspenseful thrill rides, as this one never stands still. The plot is put into action quickly, and Waller constantly introduces plot twists which give a big helping hand to the overall entertainment value of the film. The acting isn't bad for a B-movie, with young performers Marina Zudina, Fay Ripley and Evan Richards delivering good performances. The atmosphere is gritty, and the Russian locations are suitably unfriendly, which helps the film to retain a foreboding atmosphere. Overall, Mute Witness is a much better film than you might expect it to be. The plot flows well, and the atmosphere and tension are spot on.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A great, fun and effective (if sadly overlooked) thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Trelloskilos
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/10/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It is always a well-known, and important directorial device to set up the atmosphere of a film within the first 5 minutes. In the crucial opening scenes, the film should assert itself and make the viewers take notice and get interested in the rest of the film. Here, in "Mute Witness", we find a prime example of this. *Scene spoiler* In the first 5-10 minutes, the film opens to a very Hitchcockian scene of a pretty blonde lady in her apartment, with the radio on. She's wandering around, applying lipstick, dolling herself up, and ignoring the news report of a serial killer on the loose. Of course, the serial killer is in her house, and monitoring her moves, knife in hand. She hears a noise, looks in a room, and there is her partner in a pool of blood. At the very point of her screams, she turns around to be faced with the knife-wielding maniac, who stabs her repeatedly in a brutal and horrifying act.... ...then something odd happens. As the woman convulses in her death throes, the killer sits down and takes out a cigarette to watch his victim perish. Before he finds his lighter, his cigarette is lit...from someone else in the room! The camera pans out, and we realise that there are more and more people in the room, some taking notes, some filming, some recording the death, and that the lady is taking an awfully long time to die, and making a very hammy job of it too. When the audience realises what's going on, and the whole scene is part of a film, the suspenseful and horrific scene takes on an element of humour. *End Scene Spoiler* I have highlighted this opening scene for several reasons. Firstly, it portrays the atmosphere of the whole movie perfectly. A thriller in the style of Hitchcock or De Palma, with some very disorientating, and even blackly humorous moments. - It conveys a central subject matter (that of the difference between a 'movie screen death' and a 'snuff film death', an issue which is elaborated on later in the film), and finally, it introduces the viewer to the characters, all as silently as possible. The plot of Mute Witness centres around Billy Hughes, an American special effects make-up artist who is working on the set of the film, being shot in a large warehouse in Moscow. Billy cannot speak, but she communicates in sign language through her sister. After the end of an evening's filming, Billy inadvertently finds herself locked in the warehouse by accident, and in her attempt to escape, is witness to two of the crew making what first appears to be a porno film, but turns out to be a snuff movie. Suddenly, her escape from the warehouse is a matter of life and death. Without doubt, the first half of the film is powerful and absolutely gripping. Billy's saving grace, and her handicap is the fact that she isn't able to utter a sound. (In fact, in my opinion, one of the best aspects of the film is the fact that it isn't chock-full of women screaming). There are some utterly disturbing moments, and some superb set-pieces of real suspense (The corridoor, and the elevator shaft are perfect examples). The timing is fluid, and the whole first half is an incredibly satisfying experience in itself. The second half of the film introduces new concepts. While there are still several suspenseful moments, the focus is on plot twists. New characters are introduced, and it is ambiguous as to whose side they are on. While there is nothing wrong per se with the second half of the film, it just doesn't quite measure up to the first half. There are some neat moments of black humour that perfectly juxtapose and punctuate some very dramatic scenes, but there are also some very lame comedy moments (coming specifically from Billy's sister and her fianc&eacute;e, who happens to be the director of the movie Billy is working on), that almost ruin the film, just because they are badly misplaced and/or mistimed and ruin the pace. - At the end, the twists keep coming at a rapid-fire speed, and the climax of the film is, appropriately, as tense as the first half. There are several things that really make the movie work. The barriers of communication that Billy must face, both as a mute, and as an American in Moscow, mean that even an emergency call for help becomes a dangerous situation. The actress that plays Billy, Natasha Zudina, does a wonderful job in the film, with an engaging on-screen prescence, and a brilliant performance, and finally, the direction as a whole, but most particularly in the first half of the film, which truly is a study in Alfred Hitchcock's suspense/thriller film techniques. As I have already said, though, the let-downs in the film are from some terrible comic relief moments that really do not need to be added. There is already a consistent and effective streak of dark humour that appears in the film without the need for the characters of Karen Hughes and Andy Clarke (The sister and the moviemaker) to turn their scenes into some unusual sit-com. However, despite these shortcomings, the film is a thoroughly enjoyable thriller, and ideal for a group viewing at halloween. (Certainly better than the usual slasher horror film...!)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Words cannot express the horror.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lost-in-limbo
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Billy Hughes is a mute young lady working for make-up on a cheap horror picture being filmed in Moscow by an American director. One night Billy gets locked in the movie studio. Later that night she hears that someone might be in the building and goes to check it out. That's when she stumbles across a woman being brutally murdered, while being filmed. After escaping the clutches of the murderers, Billy informs the authorities, only to be red-faced when the men show it was an act. Billy knows what she saw and soon her life is in turmoil again from underground figures that believe she has something of importance. I don't know how this heart-pounding sleeper passed me by, but I thought it was a much older flick. There's one thing though, it's got to be one of the most jarringly, and intense thrillers I've seen in quite a while. It's just a great suspense builder and mostly everything clicks into place! The first half of the feature is surprisingly gripping with taut sequences that have your heart in your throat and clouds us with an atmospherically foreboding environment of alienation. Underling this is a humorously wicked black streak. Faults do pop up in the story, as it does lose that furious grip it held so early and goofy humour (or better putter comic relief) between Fay Ripley and Evan Richard's characters is a hit and miss affair by being too forceful. In the long run, it probably could have done without. Despite some cringe moments, this aspect didn't hinder my enjoyment of it. For me, the soft ending they decided to go with just didn't feel right. The interestingly mysterious premise was eerie to the bone and packed some unsettling goods. So multi-facet was the context and its thrills, there was something fresh to how this all plays out and the nervy jolts and unbearable tension are weaved into a range of sudden plot turns and twists. Really, they made superb use of the novel idea of this disability and to handicap the situation, by staging it in a foreign place where not too many spoke English and so we are caught up in the confusion too. The delicate Marina Zudina gives a harrowing portrayal of the American mute girl Billy. The way she able to display the erratic emotions through her eyes and actions gave it some gruff and believability. Director Anthony Waller shoots the flick in a rather stylish, well-timed and skillful manner, without loosing that grimy look that eventuates from its rigid surroundings and a powerfully airy music score persistently nags at you. The only real name to make an appearance was small cameo part by Alec Guinness. The performances by the cast were all fine, especially the nail biting turns by Oleg Yankovsky and Igor Volkov as the Russian murderers. This riveting feature that's mostly made up of unknowns, is way better than your average dark thriller. Highly Recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Highly recommended despite some silliness towards the end
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    coachjacki
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The first half to 3/4 of this movie are top quality suspense with a fine smattering of dark humor. The director uses camera angles and location beautifully and the screenplay makes a brilliant job of using the lead characters vulnerabilities (her inability to speak and being in a foreign country)as a major plot device. The chase through the building sequence is one of the most thrilling chase scenes I've witnessed - and all without special effects or big explosions! The movie had me on the edge of my seat and I lost several nails due to biting them, which no movie has managed in quite some time!! It reminded me of Wait Until Dark & The Spiral Staircase (original) and was every bit as beautifully directed as those awesome classics of old. I particularly loved the use of some very well thought-out close-ups and slo-mo camera sequences that added a unique style to the movie and enhanced it's sense of dread and danger. BUT I have to agree with other reviewers that unfortunately things fall apart a bit in the last half hour. Not enough to completely ruin the movie but certainly enough to pull the viewer out of the suspense and involvement that we'd been enjoying until then. (for some viewers this might actually be a good thing tho!!) I liked the ambiguity of the character that was introduced, I thought that worked well because we could not tell where he stood. But the other "surprises" and strange plot twists became a bit over the top and the movie lost a lot of it's very well developed feeling of reality. As for the sister/husband act in that last bit, they could easily have been left out (they were not important to the plot) and the movie would have been far better off for it. It really does feel like someone else took over and put together the ending because it's so different to the rest of it. But in the end this still rates as one of the best thrillers I've seen in recent times - as long as you don't count the ending. I highly recommend it. (I gave it a 7 but with a few adjustments to the screenplay it could easily have been a 9 & a new classic)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Still Great after Eighteen Years
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Claudio Carvalho
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In Moscow, the clumsy director Andy Clarke (Evan Richards) is making a slasher movie in a studio set with Russian and American cast and crew. The responsible for the makeup is the mute Billy Hughes (Marina Sudina), who is the sister of Andy's girlfriend Karen Hughes (Fay Ripley). One day, Billy needs to find a mask for the shot on the next day and she stays after hours in the studio set seeking out the object. However, the janitor locks her in the studio alone and Billy cannot find a way out. When Billy sees light in the studio, she accidentally witnesses the Russians Arkadi (Igor Volkov) and Lyosha (Sergej Karlenkov) making a porn snuff movie and brutally killing a woman. Billy succeeds to escape, but the police officers do not trust on her. Further, the powerful Russian mafia chases her believing that Billy has a diskette with evidences against the mobsters. I saw "Mute Witness" eighteen years ago and I loved this film. Yesterday I saw it again, now on DVD, and it still is a great film that combines thriller and horror with black humor in a plot with many twists. The director Anthony Waller masterly raises tension and relieves with black humor, startling the viewer and then making him or her laugh. Unfortunately the conclusion is a little disappointing but it is worthwhile watching this wonderful little film. My vote is eight. Title (Brazil): "Testemunha Muda" ("Mute Witness")
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    superb action-comedy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nose_smasher
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/8/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Man, I never laughed so much this year, and it's quite hard to make me laugh. While I expected some Hostel-style movie, the smile came to my face even from the beginning. This film-inside-film start with a female stabbed "victim" messing the whole set until she finally "die". Her overacting drive the director nuts and his funny reaction tell us, the viewers, that Mute Witness is not a typically horror movie. The main character, the mute American make-up artist Billy Hughes, is played by the beautiful yet talented Russian actress Marina Zudina. Her performance is top-notch; her character can't speak, so the body language and the emotions on her face must compensate.And, oh boy, she did a wonderful job. Her sister (Fay Ripley) is the girlfriend or the fianc&eacute;e or the wife of the "in-film director" (Evan Richards). They were both very funny most of the time. I won't spoil more, but the scenes following the bathtub moment, with them both, the fake policemen and later the angry neighbor were plain brilliant black comedy. The plot got twisted near the end, possibly misleading at one particular moment. But don't worry. Such a delicious movie can be viewed in family or with your boy-/girl-/friend.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gripping and Tense Thriller !!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    prabanand-c
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/5/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I don't know how this film went unnoticed for so long. I saw this film on TV, i was flipping through the channels and came across this unexpectedly well made film. i missed the first, probably , 10 minutes, but that does not matter..this film literally gripped me, it is a real spine chiller. The absence of well known actors in the film adds on to the effect,u do not know what to expect from the actors because they are new. U never know when they will get killed or what they are up to. so it is all the more tense.Even though there are many new faces their performances were top class. The filmmakers play with your mind, just revealing enough gore to make imagine the rest. The shock, fear, horror and helplessness are also brought out well by characters in the film. The well written situations n twists,fast camera movements, slick editing and superb direction makes it an excellent suspense thriller. This film actually switches between the genres - horror and suspense thriller leaving the viewer clueless and tensed. Undoubtedly comparable to Hitchcock. I could not even move from the TV even during the commercial breaks .. i was the helpless MUTE WITNESS to this superb film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The first hour was really good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sashank_kini-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/11/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The first half of the Mute Witness was really understandable and thrilling- it made sense. The start of the movie, which takes us into a studio where a murder is being rehearsed, is really shot well. Then, we are introduced to a mute make-up artist, her sister and her sister's husband, who is the director of the film. It has quirky moments in the beginning, which is actually funny and witty, and you know that these things must be occurring during a film's shooting. Side-actors thinking they are the prime actors and trying to lengthen the screen to show their presence to the audience, even though their role is miserly, many a times, happens in cinemas. So you could relate the plot. Then, at night, the mute lady, is mistakenly locked at the studio- what could she do, she couldn't shout as she was dumb. She calls her sister, then witnesses a murder taking place in the studio by two of the people working in the film and decides to fled. The murderers search for her and find her when her sister and her husband arrive at the spot and she explains to them with gestures and hand movements about the murder. But no one except her sister pays any heed to her as the accused have eradicated all their evidence. Then, we are shown that the accused are working for someone who tells them to kill the witness. They attack her at her house but she outwits them and while her sister, worried, and her husband arrive at her place. Till here, the story is perfectly clear. I loved everyone's acting and found their performances strong. The way they show the lady being murdered is quiet brutal and intense, though not scary in my opinion. The way they show the mute girl escaping is shot really well. The camera effects, the sudden silence, the heavy breathing, all are taken in such a way that the audience is glued to the film. There is some dark humor in this film but in the first hour only, it gels with the film pretty well. The agitated sister, who is so worried about her sister, gives a power-packed performance, while her husband, who takes the matter lightly, too, gives a real good role. As the film is shot in Russia, many of the people speak in foreign language, but you can cope up with them because there is a translator in the beginning and well, you can understand. The scene where the girl is lying in the tub is taken pretty well, in slow-motion and I loved the camera-effects, the 'plopping' of the water. Really strong. But after that, we are introduced to a person who is from the police and rescues the girl. Then, there is a mish-mash where the story turns way too stupid and confusing that I was perplexed at the end, not with the story at all. The 'Reaper' thing was all c**p and the film became more sleazy. The sister and the husband's role became quite unnecessary and stupid as from a powerful role, their role turn absolutely stupid, and they were more kept as the funny guys. The mute-girl too became childish and a side-kick while the police-man became the hero of the film all of a sudden. I reckon that there would have been different script writers for the first and the second part, because after about an hour, the film became the complete opposite. Its reputation tumbled down and that's the main reason I am giving it a six out of ten. THe first have surely deserved an eight.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Another Hitchcock wannabe...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JoeytheBrit
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/9/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Mute Witness begins strongly with a simple but intense set-up that has a mute American make-up girl accidentally getting locked in the decrepit Russian film studio in which she is working on a US film being directed by her brother-in-law. While trying to find her way out she inadvertently witnesses the filming of a snuff movie and subsequently finds herself hunted through the deserted studio's dimly-lit corridors. All of this is well paced and filmed  the murder scene, like Hitchcock's famous shower scene, cleverly uses the viewer's imagination to provide the gory details  and the film manages to create an increasingly claustrophobic atmosphere as the heroine's avenues of escape are systematically reduced. Unfortunately, it can't sustain this level of tension for long, and once the plot is opened out things start to unravel. For some unfathomable reason, writer/director Anthony Waller decides to introduce a 'comedy' element in the guise of the heroine's film director brother-in-law, and the whole thing nearly falls apart completely as he and his wife (the heroine's sister) are given increasingly larger amounts of screen time. The story grows a little confused as it widens from a lady-in-peril thriller to more of a conspiracy plot involving a shadowy figure called The Reaper (Alec Guinness in a cameo he filmed about nine years before the rest of the film was shot!) and police complicity in the snuff trade, and by its climax, Waller has thrown in so many twists and red herrings to try and disguise some glaring plot holes that you're left deflated by thinking about what could have been.. Waller was obviously trying to deliver a Hitchcock homage, but this is all the evidence you need that aiming for Hitch on your debut effort is aiming way too high.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Well worth watching
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    shornby-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/3/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you enjoy suspense this movie has it. The fact that Marina Zudina portrays a mute adds to her haplessness and increases the suspense. Alec Guiness's appearance was nice, but didn't really add to the movie. I'm not sure if Evan Richard's part as Andy Clarke was an attempt to add a little humor or if he was supposed to just be a bumbling idiot. I thought the cinematography was excellent. This added not just to the quality of the production but to the suspense as well. The bathtub seen with the water droplets in slow motion was wonderful. Also the scene where the knife comes down and then it switches to Andy Clarke cutting an extremely rare piece of meat was very well done. I would call it overall good entertainment
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Tense and gritty little thriller!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    The_Void
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/2/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I went into this film expecting a slasher, and while Mute Witness does take influence from said style of film-making, this is much more than just your average slash flick. There are a number of thrillers that focus on a certain disability - blindness is more common (Blind Terror, Wait Until Dark, Cat o'Nine Tails to name a handful), but the implications of having a mute lead in a thriller such as this are well portrayed, and actually integral to the plot as the fact that the lead character can't speak is often the reason why she finds herself in dangerous situations that would be easy for anyone else to get out of. Our mute witness is Billy Hughes, a make-up artist working on a horror film production at a studio in Moscow. She finds herself locked in after hours one night, and after attempting to phone her sister for help, she stumbles upon what at first appears to be the making of an illicit sex flick, but soon turns out to be a snuff movie! She tries to convince the authorities of what she's seen, but finds that no one believes her story... Recently Hostel made the headlines for showing snuff movie making in a foreign country, but this film did it first and actually does a better job. It's maybe not quite as nasty as Eli Roth's opus, but the gore is more effective, and since director Anthony Waller (who went on to direct one of my favourite modern thrillers with 'The Guilty') implements a good sense of humour into the proceedings, Mute Witness is both sufficiently gory and fun to watch. The director certainly has a talent for crafting suspenseful thrill rides, as this one never stands still. The plot is put into action quickly, and Waller constantly introduces plot twists which give a big helping hand to the overall entertainment value of the film. The acting isn't bad for a B-movie, with young performers Marina Zudina, Fay Ripley and Evan Richards delivering good performances. The atmosphere is gritty, and the Russian locations are suitably unfriendly, which helps the film to retain a foreboding atmosphere. Overall, Mute Witness is a much better film than you might expect it to be. The plot flows well, and the atmosphere and tension are spot on.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A great, fun and effective (if sadly overlooked) thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Trelloskilos
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/10/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It is always a well-known, and important directorial device to set up the atmosphere of a film within the first 5 minutes. In the crucial opening scenes, the film should assert itself and make the viewers take notice and get interested in the rest of the film. Here, in "Mute Witness", we find a prime example of this. *Scene spoiler* In the first 5-10 minutes, the film opens to a very Hitchcockian scene of a pretty blonde lady in her apartment, with the radio on. She's wandering around, applying lipstick, dolling herself up, and ignoring the news report of a serial killer on the loose. Of course, the serial killer is in her house, and monitoring her moves, knife in hand. She hears a noise, looks in a room, and there is her partner in a pool of blood. At the very point of her screams, she turns around to be faced with the knife-wielding maniac, who stabs her repeatedly in a brutal and horrifying act.... ...then something odd happens. As the woman convulses in her death throes, the killer sits down and takes out a cigarette to watch his victim perish. Before he finds his lighter, his cigarette is lit...from someone else in the room! The camera pans out, and we realise that there are more and more people in the room, some taking notes, some filming, some recording the death, and that the lady is taking an awfully long time to die, and making a very hammy job of it too. When the audience realises what's going on, and the whole scene is part of a film, the suspenseful and horrific scene takes on an element of humour. *End Scene Spoiler* I have highlighted this opening scene for several reasons. Firstly, it portrays the atmosphere of the whole movie perfectly. A thriller in the style of Hitchcock or De Palma, with some very disorientating, and even blackly humorous moments. - It conveys a central subject matter (that of the difference between a 'movie screen death' and a 'snuff film death', an issue which is elaborated on later in the film), and finally, it introduces the viewer to the characters, all as silently as possible. The plot of Mute Witness centres around Billy Hughes, an American special effects make-up artist who is working on the set of the film, being shot in a large warehouse in Moscow. Billy cannot speak, but she communicates in sign language through her sister. After the end of an evening's filming, Billy inadvertently finds herself locked in the warehouse by accident, and in her attempt to escape, is witness to two of the crew making what first appears to be a porno film, but turns out to be a snuff movie. Suddenly, her escape from the warehouse is a matter of life and death. Without doubt, the first half of the film is powerful and absolutely gripping. Billy's saving grace, and her handicap is the fact that she isn't able to utter a sound. (In fact, in my opinion, one of the best aspects of the film is the fact that it isn't chock-full of women screaming). There are some utterly disturbing moments, and some superb set-pieces of real suspense (The corridoor, and the elevator shaft are perfect examples). The timing is fluid, and the whole first half is an incredibly satisfying experience in itself. The second half of the film introduces new concepts. While there are still several suspenseful moments, the focus is on plot twists. New characters are introduced, and it is ambiguous as to whose side they are on. While there is nothing wrong per se with the second half of the film, it just doesn't quite measure up to the first half. There are some neat moments of black humour that perfectly juxtapose and punctuate some very dramatic scenes, but there are also some very lame comedy moments (coming specifically from Billy's sister and her fianc&eacute;e, who happens to be the director of the movie Billy is working on), that almost ruin the film, just because they are badly misplaced and/or mistimed and ruin the pace. - At the end, the twists keep coming at a rapid-fire speed, and the climax of the film is, appropriately, as tense as the first half. There are several things that really make the movie work. The barriers of communication that Billy must face, both as a mute, and as an American in Moscow, mean that even an emergency call for help becomes a dangerous situation. The actress that plays Billy, Natasha Zudina, does a wonderful job in the film, with an engaging on-screen prescence, and a brilliant performance, and finally, the direction as a whole, but most particularly in the first half of the film, which truly is a study in Alfred Hitchcock's suspense/thriller film techniques. As I have already said, though, the let-downs in the film are from some terrible comic relief moments that really do not need to be added. There is already a consistent and effective streak of dark humour that appears in the film without the need for the characters of Karen Hughes and Andy Clarke (The sister and the moviemaker) to turn their scenes into some unusual sit-com. However, despite these shortcomings, the film is a thoroughly enjoyable thriller, and ideal for a group viewing at halloween. (Certainly better than the usual slasher horror film...!)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Words cannot express the horror.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lost-in-limbo
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Billy Hughes is a mute young lady working for make-up on a cheap horror picture being filmed in Moscow by an American director. One night Billy gets locked in the movie studio. Later that night she hears that someone might be in the building and goes to check it out. That's when she stumbles across a woman being brutally murdered, while being filmed. After escaping the clutches of the murderers, Billy informs the authorities, only to be red-faced when the men show it was an act. Billy knows what she saw and soon her life is in turmoil again from underground figures that believe she has something of importance. I don't know how this heart-pounding sleeper passed me by, but I thought it was a much older flick. There's one thing though, it's got to be one of the most jarringly, and intense thrillers I've seen in quite a while. It's just a great suspense builder and mostly everything clicks into place! The first half of the feature is surprisingly gripping with taut sequences that have your heart in your throat and clouds us with an atmospherically foreboding environment of alienation. Underling this is a humorously wicked black streak. Faults do pop up in the story, as it does lose that furious grip it held so early and goofy humour (or better putter comic relief) between Fay Ripley and Evan Richard's characters is a hit and miss affair by being too forceful. In the long run, it probably could have done without. Despite some cringe moments, this aspect didn't hinder my enjoyment of it. For me, the soft ending they decided to go with just didn't feel right. The interestingly mysterious premise was eerie to the bone and packed some unsettling goods. So multi-facet was the context and its thrills, there was something fresh to how this all plays out and the nervy jolts and unbearable tension are weaved into a range of sudden plot turns and twists. Really, they made superb use of the novel idea of this disability and to handicap the situation, by staging it in a foreign place where not too many spoke English and so we are caught up in the confusion too. The delicate Marina Zudina gives a harrowing portrayal of the American mute girl Billy. The way she able to display the erratic emotions through her eyes and actions gave it some gruff and believability. Director Anthony Waller shoots the flick in a rather stylish, well-timed and skillful manner, without loosing that grimy look that eventuates from its rigid surroundings and a powerfully airy music score persistently nags at you. The only real name to make an appearance was small cameo part by Alec Guinness. The performances by the cast were all fine, especially the nail biting turns by Oleg Yankovsky and Igor Volkov as the Russian murderers. This riveting feature that's mostly made up of unknowns, is way better than your average dark thriller. Highly Recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Highly recommended despite some silliness towards the end
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    coachjacki
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The first half to 3/4 of this movie are top quality suspense with a fine smattering of dark humor. The director uses camera angles and location beautifully and the screenplay makes a brilliant job of using the lead characters vulnerabilities (her inability to speak and being in a foreign country)as a major plot device. The chase through the building sequence is one of the most thrilling chase scenes I've witnessed - and all without special effects or big explosions! The movie had me on the edge of my seat and I lost several nails due to biting them, which no movie has managed in quite some time!! It reminded me of Wait Until Dark & The Spiral Staircase (original) and was every bit as beautifully directed as those awesome classics of old. I particularly loved the use of some very well thought-out close-ups and slo-mo camera sequences that added a unique style to the movie and enhanced it's sense of dread and danger. BUT I have to agree with other reviewers that unfortunately things fall apart a bit in the last half hour. Not enough to completely ruin the movie but certainly enough to pull the viewer out of the suspense and involvement that we'd been enjoying until then. (for some viewers this might actually be a good thing tho!!) I liked the ambiguity of the character that was introduced, I thought that worked well because we could not tell where he stood. But the other "surprises" and strange plot twists became a bit over the top and the movie lost a lot of it's very well developed feeling of reality. As for the sister/husband act in that last bit, they could easily have been left out (they were not important to the plot) and the movie would have been far better off for it. It really does feel like someone else took over and put together the ending because it's so different to the rest of it. But in the end this still rates as one of the best thrillers I've seen in recent times - as long as you don't count the ending. I highly recommend it. (I gave it a 7 but with a few adjustments to the screenplay it could easily have been a 9 & a new classic)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Still Great after Eighteen Years
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Claudio Carvalho
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In Moscow, the clumsy director Andy Clarke (Evan Richards) is making a slasher movie in a studio set with Russian and American cast and crew. The responsible for the makeup is the mute Billy Hughes (Marina Sudina), who is the sister of Andy's girlfriend Karen Hughes (Fay Ripley). One day, Billy needs to find a mask for the shot on the next day and she stays after hours in the studio set seeking out the object. However, the janitor locks her in the studio alone and Billy cannot find a way out. When Billy sees light in the studio, she accidentally witnesses the Russians Arkadi (Igor Volkov) and Lyosha (Sergej Karlenkov) making a porn snuff movie and brutally killing a woman. Billy succeeds to escape, but the police officers do not trust on her. Further, the powerful Russian mafia chases her believing that Billy has a diskette with evidences against the mobsters. I saw "Mute Witness" eighteen years ago and I loved this film. Yesterday I saw it again, now on DVD, and it still is a great film that combines thriller and horror with black humor in a plot with many twists. The director Anthony Waller masterly raises tension and relieves with black humor, startling the viewer and then making him or her laugh. Unfortunately the conclusion is a little disappointing but it is worthwhile watching this wonderful little film. My vote is eight. Title (Brazil): "Testemunha Muda" ("Mute Witness")
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    superb action-comedy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nose_smasher
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/8/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Man, I never laughed so much this year, and it's quite hard to make me laugh. While I expected some Hostel-style movie, the smile came to my face even from the beginning. This film-inside-film start with a female stabbed "victim" messing the whole set until she finally "die". Her overacting drive the director nuts and his funny reaction tell us, the viewers, that Mute Witness is not a typically horror movie. The main character, the mute American make-up artist Billy Hughes, is played by the beautiful yet talented Russian actress Marina Zudina. Her performance is top-notch; her character can't speak, so the body language and the emotions on her face must compensate.And, oh boy, she did a wonderful job. Her sister (Fay Ripley) is the girlfriend or the fianc&eacute;e or the wife of the "in-film director" (Evan Richards). They were both very funny most of the time. I won't spoil more, but the scenes following the bathtub moment, with them both, the fake policemen and later the angry neighbor were plain brilliant black comedy. The plot got twisted near the end, possibly misleading at one particular moment. But don't worry. Such a delicious movie can be viewed in family or with your boy-/girl-/friend.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gripping and Tense Thriller !!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    prabanand-c
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/5/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I don't know how this film went unnoticed for so long. I saw this film on TV, i was flipping through the channels and came across this unexpectedly well made film. i missed the first, probably , 10 minutes, but that does not matter..this film literally gripped me, it is a real spine chiller. The absence of well known actors in the film adds on to the effect,u do not know what to expect from the actors because they are new. U never know when they will get killed or what they are up to. so it is all the more tense.Even though there are many new faces their performances were top class. The filmmakers play with your mind, just revealing enough gore to make imagine the rest. The shock, fear, horror and helplessness are also brought out well by characters in the film. The well written situations n twists,fast camera movements, slick editing and superb direction makes it an excellent suspense thriller. This film actually switches between the genres - horror and suspense thriller leaving the viewer clueless and tensed. Undoubtedly comparable to Hitchcock. I could not even move from the TV even during the commercial breaks .. i was the helpless MUTE WITNESS to this superb film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The first hour was really good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sashank_kini-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/11/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The first half of the Mute Witness was really understandable and thrilling- it made sense. The start of the movie, which takes us into a studio where a murder is being rehearsed, is really shot well. Then, we are introduced to a mute make-up artist, her sister and her sister's husband, who is the director of the film. It has quirky moments in the beginning, which is actually funny and witty, and you know that these things must be occurring during a film's shooting. Side-actors thinking they are the prime actors and trying to lengthen the screen to show their presence to the audience, even though their role is miserly, many a times, happens in cinemas. So you could relate the plot. Then, at night, the mute lady, is mistakenly locked at the studio- what could she do, she couldn't shout as she was dumb. She calls her sister, then witnesses a murder taking place in the studio by two of the people working in the film and decides to fled. The murderers search for her and find her when her sister and her husband arrive at the spot and she explains to them with gestures and hand movements about the murder. But no one except her sister pays any heed to her as the accused have eradicated all their evidence. Then, we are shown that the accused are working for someone who tells them to kill the witness. They attack her at her house but she outwits them and while her sister, worried, and her husband arrive at her place. Till here, the story is perfectly clear. I loved everyone's acting and found their performances strong. The way they show the lady being murdered is quiet brutal and intense, though not scary in my opinion. The way they show the mute girl escaping is shot really well. The camera effects, the sudden silence, the heavy breathing, all are taken in such a way that the audience is glued to the film. There is some dark humor in this film but in the first hour only, it gels with the film pretty well. The agitated sister, who is so worried about her sister, gives a power-packed performance, while her husband, who takes the matter lightly, too, gives a real good role. As the film is shot in Russia, many of the people speak in foreign language, but you can cope up with them because there is a translator in the beginning and well, you can understand. The scene where the girl is lying in the tub is taken pretty well, in slow-motion and I loved the camera-effects, the 'plopping' of the water. Really strong. But after that, we are introduced to a person who is from the police and rescues the girl. Then, there is a mish-mash where the story turns way too stupid and confusing that I was perplexed at the end, not with the story at all. The 'Reaper' thing was all c**p and the film became more sleazy. The sister and the husband's role became quite unnecessary and stupid as from a powerful role, their role turn absolutely stupid, and they were more kept as the funny guys. The mute-girl too became childish and a side-kick while the police-man became the hero of the film all of a sudden. I reckon that there would have been different script writers for the first and the second part, because after about an hour, the film became the complete opposite. Its reputation tumbled down and that's the main reason I am giving it a six out of ten. THe first have surely deserved an eight.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Another Hitchcock wannabe...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JoeytheBrit
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/9/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Mute Witness begins strongly with a simple but intense set-up that has a mute American make-up girl accidentally getting locked in the decrepit Russian film studio in which she is working on a US film being directed by her brother-in-law. While trying to find her way out she inadvertently witnesses the filming of a snuff movie and subsequently finds herself hunted through the deserted studio's dimly-lit corridors. All of this is well paced and filmed  the murder scene, like Hitchcock's famous shower scene, cleverly uses the viewer's imagination to provide the gory details  and the film manages to create an increasingly claustrophobic atmosphere as the heroine's avenues of escape are systematically reduced. Unfortunately, it can't sustain this level of tension for long, and once the plot is opened out things start to unravel. For some unfathomable reason, writer/director Anthony Waller decides to introduce a 'comedy' element in the guise of the heroine's film director brother-in-law, and the whole thing nearly falls apart completely as he and his wife (the heroine's sister) are given increasingly larger amounts of screen time. The story grows a little confused as it widens from a lady-in-peril thriller to more of a conspiracy plot involving a shadowy figure called The Reaper (Alec Guinness in a cameo he filmed about nine years before the rest of the film was shot!) and police complicity in the snuff trade, and by its climax, Waller has thrown in so many twists and red herrings to try and disguise some glaring plot holes that you're left deflated by thinking about what could have been.. Waller was obviously trying to deliver a Hitchcock homage, but this is all the evidence you need that aiming for Hitch on your debut effort is aiming way too high.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Well worth watching
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    shornby-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/3/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you enjoy suspense this movie has it. The fact that Marina Zudina portrays a mute adds to her haplessness and increases the suspense. Alec Guiness's appearance was nice, but didn't really add to the movie. I'm not sure if Evan Richard's part as Andy Clarke was an attempt to add a little humor or if he was supposed to just be a bumbling idiot. I thought the cinematography was excellent. This added not just to the quality of the production but to the suspense as well. The bathtub seen with the water droplets in slow motion was wonderful. Also the scene where the knife comes down and then it switches to Andy Clarke cutting an extremely rare piece of meat was very well done. I would call it overall good entertainment
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Tense and gritty little thriller!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    The_Void
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/2/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I went into this film expecting a slasher, and while Mute Witness does take influence from said style of film-making, this is much more than just your average slash flick. There are a number of thrillers that focus on a certain disability - blindness is more common (Blind Terror, Wait Until Dark, Cat o'Nine Tails to name a handful), but the implications of having a mute lead in a thriller such as this are well portrayed, and actually integral to the plot as the fact that the lead character can't speak is often the reason why she finds herself in dangerous situations that would be easy for anyone else to get out of. Our mute witness is Billy Hughes, a make-up artist working on a horror film production at a studio in Moscow. She finds herself locked in after hours one night, and after attempting to phone her sister for help, she stumbles upon what at first appears to be the making of an illicit sex flick, but soon turns out to be a snuff movie! She tries to convince the authorities of what she's seen, but finds that no one believes her story... Recently Hostel made the headlines for showing snuff movie making in a foreign country, but this film did it first and actually does a better job. It's maybe not quite as nasty as Eli Roth's opus, but the gore is more effective, and since director Anthony Waller (who went on to direct one of my favourite modern thrillers with 'The Guilty') implements a good sense of humour into the proceedings, Mute Witness is both sufficiently gory and fun to watch. The director certainly has a talent for crafting suspenseful thrill rides, as this one never stands still. The plot is put into action quickly, and Waller constantly introduces plot twists which give a big helping hand to the overall entertainment value of the film. The acting isn't bad for a B-movie, with young performers Marina Zudina, Fay Ripley and Evan Richards delivering good performances. The atmosphere is gritty, and the Russian locations are suitably unfriendly, which helps the film to retain a foreboding atmosphere. Overall, Mute Witness is a much better film than you might expect it to be. The plot flows well, and the atmosphere and tension are spot on.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A great, fun and effective (if sadly overlooked) thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Trelloskilos
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/10/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It is always a well-known, and important directorial device to set up the atmosphere of a film within the first 5 minutes. In the crucial opening scenes, the film should assert itself and make the viewers take notice and get interested in the rest of the film. Here, in "Mute Witness", we find a prime example of this. *Scene spoiler* In the first 5-10 minutes, the film opens to a very Hitchcockian scene of a pretty blonde lady in her apartment, with the radio on. She's wandering around, applying lipstick, dolling herself up, and ignoring the news report of a serial killer on the loose. Of course, the serial killer is in her house, and monitoring her moves, knife in hand. She hears a noise, looks in a room, and there is her partner in a pool of blood. At the very point of her screams, she turns around to be faced with the knife-wielding maniac, who stabs her repeatedly in a brutal and horrifying act.... ...then something odd happens. As the woman convulses in her death throes, the killer sits down and takes out a cigarette to watch his victim perish. Before he finds his lighter, his cigarette is lit...from someone else in the room! The camera pans out, and we realise that there are more and more people in the room, some taking notes, some filming, some recording the death, and that the lady is taking an awfully long time to die, and making a very hammy job of it too. When the audience realises what's going on, and the whole scene is part of a film, the suspenseful and horrific scene takes on an element of humour. *End Scene Spoiler* I have highlighted this opening scene for several reasons. Firstly, it portrays the atmosphere of the whole movie perfectly. A thriller in the style of Hitchcock or De Palma, with some very disorientating, and even blackly humorous moments. - It conveys a central subject matter (that of the difference between a 'movie screen death' and a 'snuff film death', an issue which is elaborated on later in the film), and finally, it introduces the viewer to the characters, all as silently as possible. The plot of Mute Witness centres around Billy Hughes, an American special effects make-up artist who is working on the set of the film, being shot in a large warehouse in Moscow. Billy cannot speak, but she communicates in sign language through her sister. After the end of an evening's filming, Billy inadvertently finds herself locked in the warehouse by accident, and in her attempt to escape, is witness to two of the crew making what first appears to be a porno film, but turns out to be a snuff movie. Suddenly, her escape from the warehouse is a matter of life and death. Without doubt, the first half of the film is powerful and absolutely gripping. Billy's saving grace, and her handicap is the fact that she isn't able to utter a sound. (In fact, in my opinion, one of the best aspects of the film is the fact that it isn't chock-full of women screaming). There are some utterly disturbing moments, and some superb set-pieces of real suspense (The corridoor, and the elevator shaft are perfect examples). The timing is fluid, and the whole first half is an incredibly satisfying experience in itself. The second half of the film introduces new concepts. While there are still several suspenseful moments, the focus is on plot twists. New characters are introduced, and it is ambiguous as to whose side they are on. While there is nothing wrong per se with the second half of the film, it just doesn't quite measure up to the first half. There are some neat moments of black humour that perfectly juxtapose and punctuate some very dramatic scenes, but there are also some very lame comedy moments (coming specifically from Billy's sister and her fianc&eacute;e, who happens to be the director of the movie Billy is working on), that almost ruin the film, just because they are badly misplaced and/or mistimed and ruin the pace. - At the end, the twists keep coming at a rapid-fire speed, and the climax of the film is, appropriately, as tense as the first half. There are several things that really make the movie work. The barriers of communication that Billy must face, both as a mute, and as an American in Moscow, mean that even an emergency call for help becomes a dangerous situation. The actress that plays Billy, Natasha Zudina, does a wonderful job in the film, with an engaging on-screen prescence, and a brilliant performance, and finally, the direction as a whole, but most particularly in the first half of the film, which truly is a study in Alfred Hitchcock's suspense/thriller film techniques. As I have already said, though, the let-downs in the film are from some terrible comic relief moments that really do not need to be added. There is already a consistent and effective streak of dark humour that appears in the film without the need for the characters of Karen Hughes and Andy Clarke (The sister and the moviemaker) to turn their scenes into some unusual sit-com. However, despite these shortcomings, the film is a thoroughly enjoyable thriller, and ideal for a group viewing at halloween. (Certainly better than the usual slasher horror film...!)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Words cannot express the horror.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lost-in-limbo
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Billy Hughes is a mute young lady working for make-up on a cheap horror picture being filmed in Moscow by an American director. One night Billy gets locked in the movie studio. Later that night she hears that someone might be in the building and goes to check it out. That's when she stumbles across a woman being brutally murdered, while being filmed. After escaping the clutches of the murderers, Billy informs the authorities, only to be red-faced when the men show it was an act. Billy knows what she saw and soon her life is in turmoil again from underground figures that believe she has something of importance. I don't know how this heart-pounding sleeper passed me by, but I thought it was a much older flick. There's one thing though, it's got to be one of the most jarringly, and intense thrillers I've seen in quite a while. It's just a great suspense builder and mostly everything clicks into place! The first half of the feature is surprisingly gripping with taut sequences that have your heart in your throat and clouds us with an atmospherically foreboding environment of alienation. Underling this is a humorously wicked black streak. Faults do pop up in the story, as it does lose that furious grip it held so early and goofy humour (or better putter comic relief) between Fay Ripley and Evan Richard's characters is a hit and miss affair by being too forceful. In the long run, it probably could have done without. Despite some cringe moments, this aspect didn't hinder my enjoyment of it. For me, the soft ending they decided to go with just didn't feel right. The interestingly mysterious premise was eerie to the bone and packed some unsettling goods. So multi-facet was the context and its thrills, there was something fresh to how this all plays out and the nervy jolts and unbearable tension are weaved into a range of sudden plot turns and twists. Really, they made superb use of the novel idea of this disability and to handicap the situation, by staging it in a foreign place where not too many spoke English and so we are caught up in the confusion too. The delicate Marina Zudina gives a harrowing portrayal of the American mute girl Billy. The way she able to display the erratic emotions through her eyes and actions gave it some gruff and believability. Director Anthony Waller shoots the flick in a rather stylish, well-timed and skillful manner, without loosing that grimy look that eventuates from its rigid surroundings and a powerfully airy music score persistently nags at you. The only real name to make an appearance was small cameo part by Alec Guinness. The performances by the cast were all fine, especially the nail biting turns by Oleg Yankovsky and Igor Volkov as the Russian murderers. This riveting feature that's mostly made up of unknowns, is way better than your average dark thriller. Highly Recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Highly recommended despite some silliness towards the end
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    coachjacki
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The first half to 3/4 of this movie are top quality suspense with a fine smattering of dark humor. The director uses camera angles and location beautifully and the screenplay makes a brilliant job of using the lead characters vulnerabilities (her inability to speak and being in a foreign country)as a major plot device. The chase through the building sequence is one of the most thrilling chase scenes I've witnessed - and all without special effects or big explosions! The movie had me on the edge of my seat and I lost several nails due to biting them, which no movie has managed in quite some time!! It reminded me of Wait Until Dark & The Spiral Staircase (original) and was every bit as beautifully directed as those awesome classics of old. I particularly loved the use of some very well thought-out close-ups and slo-mo camera sequences that added a unique style to the movie and enhanced it's sense of dread and danger. BUT I have to agree with other reviewers that unfortunately things fall apart a bit in the last half hour. Not enough to completely ruin the movie but certainly enough to pull the viewer out of the suspense and involvement that we'd been enjoying until then. (for some viewers this might actually be a good thing tho!!) I liked the ambiguity of the character that was introduced, I thought that worked well because we could not tell where he stood. But the other "surprises" and strange plot twists became a bit over the top and the movie lost a lot of it's very well developed feeling of reality. As for the sister/husband act in that last bit, they could easily have been left out (they were not important to the plot) and the movie would have been far better off for it. It really does feel like someone else took over and put together the ending because it's so different to the rest of it. But in the end this still rates as one of the best thrillers I've seen in recent times - as long as you don't count the ending. I highly recommend it. (I gave it a 7 but with a few adjustments to the screenplay it could easily have been a 9 & a new classic)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Still Great after Eighteen Years
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Claudio Carvalho
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In Moscow, the clumsy director Andy Clarke (Evan Richards) is making a slasher movie in a studio set with Russian and American cast and crew. The responsible for the makeup is the mute Billy Hughes (Marina Sudina), who is the sister of Andy's girlfriend Karen Hughes (Fay Ripley). One day, Billy needs to find a mask for the shot on the next day and she stays after hours in the studio set seeking out the object. However, the janitor locks her in the studio alone and Billy cannot find a way out. When Billy sees light in the studio, she accidentally witnesses the Russians Arkadi (Igor Volkov) and Lyosha (Sergej Karlenkov) making a porn snuff movie and brutally killing a woman. Billy succeeds to escape, but the police officers do not trust on her. Further, the powerful Russian mafia chases her believing that Billy has a diskette with evidences against the mobsters. I saw "Mute Witness" eighteen years ago and I loved this film. Yesterday I saw it again, now on DVD, and it still is a great film that combines thriller and horror with black humor in a plot with many twists. The director Anthony Waller masterly raises tension and relieves with black humor, startling the viewer and then making him or her laugh. Unfortunately the conclusion is a little disappointing but it is worthwhile watching this wonderful little film. My vote is eight. Title (Brazil): "Testemunha Muda" ("Mute Witness")
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    superb action-comedy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nose_smasher
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/8/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Man, I never laughed so much this year, and it's quite hard to make me laugh. While I expected some Hostel-style movie, the smile came to my face even from the beginning. This film-inside-film start with a female stabbed "victim" messing the whole set until she finally "die". Her overacting drive the director nuts and his funny reaction tell us, the viewers, that Mute Witness is not a typically horror movie. The main character, the mute American make-up artist Billy Hughes, is played by the beautiful yet talented Russian actress Marina Zudina. Her performance is top-notch; her character can't speak, so the body language and the emotions on her face must compensate.And, oh boy, she did a wonderful job. Her sister (Fay Ripley) is the girlfriend or the fianc&eacute;e or the wife of the "in-film director" (Evan Richards). They were both very funny most of the time. I won't spoil more, but the scenes following the bathtub moment, with them both, the fake policemen and later the angry neighbor were plain brilliant black comedy. The plot got twisted near the end, possibly misleading at one particular moment. But don't worry. Such a delicious movie can be viewed in family or with your boy-/girl-/friend.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Gripping and Tense Thriller !!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    prabanand-c
   </autor>
   <data>
    17/5/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I don't know how this film went unnoticed for so long. I saw this film on TV, i was flipping through the channels and came across this unexpectedly well made film. i missed the first, probably , 10 minutes, but that does not matter..this film literally gripped me, it is a real spine chiller. The absence of well known actors in the film adds on to the effect,u do not know what to expect from the actors because they are new. U never know when they will get killed or what they are up to. so it is all the more tense.Even though there are many new faces their performances were top class. The filmmakers play with your mind, just revealing enough gore to make imagine the rest. The shock, fear, horror and helplessness are also brought out well by characters in the film. The well written situations n twists,fast camera movements, slick editing and superb direction makes it an excellent suspense thriller. This film actually switches between the genres - horror and suspense thriller leaving the viewer clueless and tensed. Undoubtedly comparable to Hitchcock. I could not even move from the TV even during the commercial breaks .. i was the helpless MUTE WITNESS to this superb film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The first hour was really good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    sashank_kini-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/11/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The first half of the Mute Witness was really understandable and thrilling- it made sense. The start of the movie, which takes us into a studio where a murder is being rehearsed, is really shot well. Then, we are introduced to a mute make-up artist, her sister and her sister's husband, who is the director of the film. It has quirky moments in the beginning, which is actually funny and witty, and you know that these things must be occurring during a film's shooting. Side-actors thinking they are the prime actors and trying to lengthen the screen to show their presence to the audience, even though their role is miserly, many a times, happens in cinemas. So you could relate the plot. Then, at night, the mute lady, is mistakenly locked at the studio- what could she do, she couldn't shout as she was dumb. She calls her sister, then witnesses a murder taking place in the studio by two of the people working in the film and decides to fled. The murderers search for her and find her when her sister and her husband arrive at the spot and she explains to them with gestures and hand movements about the murder. But no one except her sister pays any heed to her as the accused have eradicated all their evidence. Then, we are shown that the accused are working for someone who tells them to kill the witness. They attack her at her house but she outwits them and while her sister, worried, and her husband arrive at her place. Till here, the story is perfectly clear. I loved everyone's acting and found their performances strong. The way they show the lady being murdered is quiet brutal and intense, though not scary in my opinion. The way they show the mute girl escaping is shot really well. The camera effects, the sudden silence, the heavy breathing, all are taken in such a way that the audience is glued to the film. There is some dark humor in this film but in the first hour only, it gels with the film pretty well. The agitated sister, who is so worried about her sister, gives a power-packed performance, while her husband, who takes the matter lightly, too, gives a real good role. As the film is shot in Russia, many of the people speak in foreign language, but you can cope up with them because there is a translator in the beginning and well, you can understand. The scene where the girl is lying in the tub is taken pretty well, in slow-motion and I loved the camera-effects, the 'plopping' of the water. Really strong. But after that, we are introduced to a person who is from the police and rescues the girl. Then, there is a mish-mash where the story turns way too stupid and confusing that I was perplexed at the end, not with the story at all. The 'Reaper' thing was all c**p and the film became more sleazy. The sister and the husband's role became quite unnecessary and stupid as from a powerful role, their role turn absolutely stupid, and they were more kept as the funny guys. The mute-girl too became childish and a side-kick while the police-man became the hero of the film all of a sudden. I reckon that there would have been different script writers for the first and the second part, because after about an hour, the film became the complete opposite. Its reputation tumbled down and that's the main reason I am giving it a six out of ten. THe first have surely deserved an eight.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Another Hitchcock wannabe...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    JoeytheBrit
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/9/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Mute Witness begins strongly with a simple but intense set-up that has a mute American make-up girl accidentally getting locked in the decrepit Russian film studio in which she is working on a US film being directed by her brother-in-law. While trying to find her way out she inadvertently witnesses the filming of a snuff movie and subsequently finds herself hunted through the deserted studio's dimly-lit corridors. All of this is well paced and filmed  the murder scene, like Hitchcock's famous shower scene, cleverly uses the viewer's imagination to provide the gory details  and the film manages to create an increasingly claustrophobic atmosphere as the heroine's avenues of escape are systematically reduced. Unfortunately, it can't sustain this level of tension for long, and once the plot is opened out things start to unravel. For some unfathomable reason, writer/director Anthony Waller decides to introduce a 'comedy' element in the guise of the heroine's film director brother-in-law, and the whole thing nearly falls apart completely as he and his wife (the heroine's sister) are given increasingly larger amounts of screen time. The story grows a little confused as it widens from a lady-in-peril thriller to more of a conspiracy plot involving a shadowy figure called The Reaper (Alec Guinness in a cameo he filmed about nine years before the rest of the film was shot!) and police complicity in the snuff trade, and by its climax, Waller has thrown in so many twists and red herrings to try and disguise some glaring plot holes that you're left deflated by thinking about what could have been.. Waller was obviously trying to deliver a Hitchcock homage, but this is all the evidence you need that aiming for Hitch on your debut effort is aiming way too high.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Well worth watching
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    shornby-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/3/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you enjoy suspense this movie has it. The fact that Marina Zudina portrays a mute adds to her haplessness and increases the suspense. Alec Guiness's appearance was nice, but didn't really add to the movie. I'm not sure if Evan Richard's part as Andy Clarke was an attempt to add a little humor or if he was supposed to just be a bumbling idiot. I thought the cinematography was excellent. This added not just to the quality of the production but to the suspense as well. The bathtub seen with the water droplets in slow motion was wonderful. Also the scene where the knife comes down and then it switches to Andy Clarke cutting an extremely rare piece of meat was very well done. I would call it overall good entertainment
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Tense and gritty little thriller!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    The_Void
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/2/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I went into this film expecting a slasher, and while Mute Witness does take influence from said style of film-making, this is much more than just your average slash flick. There are a number of thrillers that focus on a certain disability - blindness is more common (Blind Terror, Wait Until Dark, Cat o'Nine Tails to name a handful), but the implications of having a mute lead in a thriller such as this are well portrayed, and actually integral to the plot as the fact that the lead character can't speak is often the reason why she finds herself in dangerous situations that would be easy for anyone else to get out of. Our mute witness is Billy Hughes, a make-up artist working on a horror film production at a studio in Moscow. She finds herself locked in after hours one night, and after attempting to phone her sister for help, she stumbles upon what at first appears to be the making of an illicit sex flick, but soon turns out to be a snuff movie! She tries to convince the authorities of what she's seen, but finds that no one believes her story... Recently Hostel made the headlines for showing snuff movie making in a foreign country, but this film did it first and actually does a better job. It's maybe not quite as nasty as Eli Roth's opus, but the gore is more effective, and since director Anthony Waller (who went on to direct one of my favourite modern thrillers with 'The Guilty') implements a good sense of humour into the proceedings, Mute Witness is both sufficiently gory and fun to watch. The director certainly has a talent for crafting suspenseful thrill rides, as this one never stands still. The plot is put into action quickly, and Waller constantly introduces plot twists which give a big helping hand to the overall entertainment value of the film. The acting isn't bad for a B-movie, with young performers Marina Zudina, Fay Ripley and Evan Richards delivering good performances. The atmosphere is gritty, and the Russian locations are suitably unfriendly, which helps the film to retain a foreboding atmosphere. Overall, Mute Witness is a much better film than you might expect it to be. The plot flows well, and the atmosphere and tension are spot on.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A great, fun and effective (if sadly overlooked) thriller
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Trelloskilos
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/10/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It is always a well-known, and important directorial device to set up the atmosphere of a film within the first 5 minutes. In the crucial opening scenes, the film should assert itself and make the viewers take notice and get interested in the rest of the film. Here, in "Mute Witness", we find a prime example of this. *Scene spoiler* In the first 5-10 minutes, the film opens to a very Hitchcockian scene of a pretty blonde lady in her apartment, with the radio on. She's wandering around, applying lipstick, dolling herself up, and ignoring the news report of a serial killer on the loose. Of course, the serial killer is in her house, and monitoring her moves, knife in hand. She hears a noise, looks in a room, and there is her partner in a pool of blood. At the very point of her screams, she turns around to be faced with the knife-wielding maniac, who stabs her repeatedly in a brutal and horrifying act.... ...then something odd happens. As the woman convulses in her death throes, the killer sits down and takes out a cigarette to watch his victim perish. Before he finds his lighter, his cigarette is lit...from someone else in the room! The camera pans out, and we realise that there are more and more people in the room, some taking notes, some filming, some recording the death, and that the lady is taking an awfully long time to die, and making a very hammy job of it too. When the audience realises what's going on, and the whole scene is part of a film, the suspenseful and horrific scene takes on an element of humour. *End Scene Spoiler* I have highlighted this opening scene for several reasons. Firstly, it portrays the atmosphere of the whole movie perfectly. A thriller in the style of Hitchcock or De Palma, with some very disorientating, and even blackly humorous moments. - It conveys a central subject matter (that of the difference between a 'movie screen death' and a 'snuff film death', an issue which is elaborated on later in the film), and finally, it introduces the viewer to the characters, all as silently as possible. The plot of Mute Witness centres around Billy Hughes, an American special effects make-up artist who is working on the set of the film, being shot in a large warehouse in Moscow. Billy cannot speak, but she communicates in sign language through her sister. After the end of an evening's filming, Billy inadvertently finds herself locked in the warehouse by accident, and in her attempt to escape, is witness to two of the crew making what first appears to be a porno film, but turns out to be a snuff movie. Suddenly, her escape from the warehouse is a matter of life and death. Without doubt, the first half of the film is powerful and absolutely gripping. Billy's saving grace, and her handicap is the fact that she isn't able to utter a sound. (In fact, in my opinion, one of the best aspects of the film is the fact that it isn't chock-full of women screaming). There are some utterly disturbing moments, and some superb set-pieces of real suspense (The corridoor, and the elevator shaft are perfect examples). The timing is fluid, and the whole first half is an incredibly satisfying experience in itself. The second half of the film introduces new concepts. While there are still several suspenseful moments, the focus is on plot twists. New characters are introduced, and it is ambiguous as to whose side they are on. While there is nothing wrong per se with the second half of the film, it just doesn't quite measure up to the first half. There are some neat moments of black humour that perfectly juxtapose and punctuate some very dramatic scenes, but there are also some very lame comedy moments (coming specifically from Billy's sister and her fianc&eacute;e, who happens to be the director of the movie Billy is working on), that almost ruin the film, just because they are badly misplaced and/or mistimed and ruin the pace. - At the end, the twists keep coming at a rapid-fire speed, and the climax of the film is, appropriately, as tense as the first half. There are several things that really make the movie work. The barriers of communication that Billy must face, both as a mute, and as an American in Moscow, mean that even an emergency call for help becomes a dangerous situation. The actress that plays Billy, Natasha Zudina, does a wonderful job in the film, with an engaging on-screen prescence, and a brilliant performance, and finally, the direction as a whole, but most particularly in the first half of the film, which truly is a study in Alfred Hitchcock's suspense/thriller film techniques. As I have already said, though, the let-downs in the film are from some terrible comic relief moments that really do not need to be added. There is already a consistent and effective streak of dark humour that appears in the film without the need for the characters of Karen Hughes and Andy Clarke (The sister and the moviemaker) to turn their scenes into some unusual sit-com. However, despite these shortcomings, the film is a thoroughly enjoyable thriller, and ideal for a group viewing at halloween. (Certainly better than the usual slasher horror film...!)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Words cannot express the horror.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lost-in-limbo
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Billy Hughes is a mute young lady working for make-up on a cheap horror picture being filmed in Moscow by an American director. One night Billy gets locked in the movie studio. Later that night she hears that someone might be in the building and goes to check it out. That's when she stumbles across a woman being brutally murdered, while being filmed. After escaping the clutches of the murderers, Billy informs the authorities, only to be red-faced when the men show it was an act. Billy knows what she saw and soon her life is in turmoil again from underground figures that believe she has something of importance. I don't know how this heart-pounding sleeper passed me by, but I thought it was a much older flick. There's one thing though, it's got to be one of the most jarringly, and intense thrillers I've seen in quite a while. It's just a great suspense builder and mostly everything clicks into place! The first half of the feature is surprisingly gripping with taut sequences that have your heart in your throat and clouds us with an atmospherically foreboding environment of alienation. Underling this is a humorously wicked black streak. Faults do pop up in the story, as it does lose that furious grip it held so early and goofy humour (or better putter comic relief) between Fay Ripley and Evan Richard's characters is a hit and miss affair by being too forceful. In the long run, it probably could have done without. Despite some cringe moments, this aspect didn't hinder my enjoyment of it. For me, the soft ending they decided to go with just didn't feel right. The interestingly mysterious premise was eerie to the bone and packed some unsettling goods. So multi-facet was the context and its thrills, there was something fresh to how this all plays out and the nervy jolts and unbearable tension are weaved into a range of sudden plot turns and twists. Really, they made superb use of the novel idea of this disability and to handicap the situation, by staging it in a foreign place where not too many spoke English and so we are caught up in the confusion too. The delicate Marina Zudina gives a harrowing portrayal of the American mute girl Billy. The way she able to display the erratic emotions through her eyes and actions gave it some gruff and believability. Director Anthony Waller shoots the flick in a rather stylish, well-timed and skillful manner, without loosing that grimy look that eventuates from its rigid surroundings and a powerfully airy music score persistently nags at you. The only real name to make an appearance was small cameo part by Alec Guinness. The performances by the cast were all fine, especially the nail biting turns by Oleg Yankovsky and Igor Volkov as the Russian murderers. This riveting feature that's mostly made up of unknowns, is way better than your average dark thriller. Highly Recommended.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
