<filme>
 <id>
  778
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0112883
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1994
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Don Juan DeMarco
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.6
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  A psychiatrist must cure a young patient that presents himself as Don Juan, the greatest lover in the world.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Dr Jack Mickler, a psychiatrist, is only 10 days away from his retirement. A week before he is due to leave, he encounters a young man who attempts suicide- would be a pretty straightforward case except the young man claims to be Don Juan, the fabled Spanish nobleman and world renowned seducer/lover of woman. Despite original hostility from his coworkers Jack manages to persuade his associates to put the boy in his care for 10 days after which the boy will undergo an evaluation to be either released from psychiatric care or sent to a mental institution. However, as the 10 days progresses Dr Mickler and the other staff become gradually drawn into to the young man's exotic world of love, passion and pleasure as he recounts his story to them. Whilst doing so the man's philosophies and zeal for life and love begins to revive Dr MIckler's somewhat passionless relationship with his wife, Marilyn as well as challenging his own views and ethics to the point where both he and the audience ...
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Romance
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   don juan
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   psychiatrist
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   love
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   patient
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   mental institution
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Jeremy Leven
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Lord Byron
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Jeremy Leven
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Johnny Depp
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Marlon Brando
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Faye Dunaway
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just enjoy !!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    redx1708
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Great Picture. Maybe not a masterpiece...(well, probably not), but nonetheless a completely joyful experience. The question whether Depps story is fact or fiction is really really neither here nor there. If it's not true, it bloody well should be !! lol. And if the story doesn't catch you, the performances should. Marlon Brando and Johnny Depp. Each one among the greatest actors of their generations. What a pleasure to Watch them working together. This is what acting is all about. They both shine as does Faye Dunaway (wow, she's still a beauty). And while the movie won't be considered among the highlights of their careers, I'll still highly recommend it to all movie lovers.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Don Juan DeMarco Will Put The Viewer Into An Amorous Mood
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Don Juan DeMarco is a romantic comedy starring Johnny Depp as John Arnold DeMarco, a man who believes himself to be Don Juan, the greatest lover in the world. Clad in a cape and domino mask, DeMarco undergoes psychiatric treatment with Marlon Brando's character, Dr. Jack Mickler, to cure him of his apparent delusion. But the psychiatric sessions have an unexpected effect on the psychiatric staff, some of whom find themselves inspired by DeMarco's delusion; the most profoundly affected is Dr. Mickler himself, who rekindles the romance in his complacent marriage.The movie also stars Faye Dunaway.The movie is based on two different sources: the modern-day story is based on director/screenwriter Jeremy Leven's short story Don Juan DeMarco and the Centerfold and the familiar legend of Don Juan,wherein flashbacks depicting DeMarco's back-story are based on. In the movie,a psychiatrist treats a most unusual patient, only to find that the doctor is the one who gains the most from their sessions. A young man in a mask and cape is standing atop a billboard, threatening to jump. When the potential suicide is finally talked down, he's brought to a psychiatric facility where after one doctor washes his hands of the case, he's placed under the supervision of Dr. Jack Mickler, an aging psychiatrist soon to retire. The patient informs Mickler that he is actually the great lover Don Juan, who has seduced over 1,500 women, but has fallen into a deep depression after being unable to win the hand of the woman of his dreams. Mickler has ten days to work with his patient and after which he will either be released on medication or committed to a long-term stay in a mental hospital. As Mickler talks with the young man, who speaks rapturously of the art of love, the doctor finds that his philosophies are helping to kick start his failing relationship with his wife, and he slowly becomes convinced that his patient might really be Don Juan after all. Walking a fine line between precious comedy, wistful drama, and delicate fantasy, it gets a big dose of charm from its esteemed cast, with Johnny Depp delivering dialogue that would have sounded ludicrous from a lesser actor.While the performances by Marlon Brando and Faye Dunaway elevate this likable comedy about love, illusion and delusion way above its inconsequential text.This may not be a great movie, but it is guaranteed to put you in an amorous mood.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Johnny Depp + Marlon Brando... What did you expect?!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ludovico Giannotti
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie as incredible and can't believe it's low rating on here. Johnny Depp puts in a very good performance and so does Marlon Brando, in portraying a beautiful story, very touching and moving. I just liked the movie in all it's aspects. The film seems superficial and banal but it has a fairly deep underlying theme about love and its philosophy. I would definitely recommend this movie to everybody as it is really good and entertaining. It is a film for everybody, young and the older will both find it very interesting and captivating so don't watch the low score and just go watch it: it is amazing! x
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Sweet Must-See Movies for Lovers!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mlzema
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I recently watched this one again after having not seen it in quite a while and I was pleasantly surprised to find that it was still one of the sweetest little movies I have ever seen, and for a person of my cynical nature that is really saying something. One of the secrets of this movie is the casting of Brando and Depp, two actors whom I consider to be "blank slates" and are thus quite adept at falling into and being believable in whatever role is given to them. I thought Brando in particular was sublime as the about-to-retire psychiatrist who appears to be rudderless regarding his impending life of retirement. Johnny Depp's character has some really beautifully-written lines, most of which are quoted on this site, from which we as men and husbands could learn a thing or two. Yes, it's plot is totally implausible but I'm begging you to buy in to the premise and let yourself get lost for a little while. I promise you that you will be holding your wife's hand almost before you know it!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Despite a rather dopey plot, it's enjoyable because of a couple nice performances.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you've ever seen the Joanne Woodward and George C. Scott film "They Might Be Giants", then you'll no doubt recognize this plot in "Don Juan DeMarco". The film begins with Johnny Depp making a sexual conquest in modern day America---yet he THINKS he's the legendary lover Don Juan. Later, when this lover suddenly is found contemplating suicide, an aging psychiatrist (Marlon Brando) is called in to help. Not surprisingly, Don Juan DeMarco is committed to the institution where Brando works and Brando fights hard to get assigned him as a patient--even though he's due to retire very soon. The Doctor tries hard as he works with his new patient NOT to medicate him. After all, the Doc LIKES hearing all of his patient's weird stories of love, sex and adventure. And, through the course of the film, DeMarco starts rubbing off on his doctor--to the delight of the man's wife! Johnny Depp is very nice playing a suave Latin lover and Brando is really good because he seems nice and relaxed. My only big complaint is not them but the bafflingly stupid ending. Really. Up until then, I could suspend disbelief and enjoy the film, but the ending really left me shocked at its silliness. Still, worth a look.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Silly Accent, Done-To-Death Plot, Great Actors with No Roles to Play
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    good-decision
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was very disappointed in this movie. I rented it with such great expectations from a movie that has Marlon Brando and Johnny Depp in one and in the same movie. Alas, there was nothing but flat characters, the silliest accent I have ever heard an actor come up with, and suspension of disbelief was so hard I had to call a friend to moan what a silly movie it was. In fact was it not for my love for both Marlon and Depp I would have given it a zero! In an interview with the Actor's Studio, Depp said that the hardest thing about acting with Brando was trying to keep a straight face. I imagine Brando knew from the get go that the movie was a joke.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Another Quirky Movies from Depp
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    princebansal1982
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Johnny Depp has made a career of doing quirky movies. This is a charming, soft, quirky movie ideal for a lazy afternoon. Just go without any expectations. It is about a young man who thinks he is Don Juan DeMarco and his interactions with his psychiatrist who is trying to cure him. Though it is not really clear whether he is really delusional or not, it doesn't matters really. It is more about his exploits true or imagined, then anything else. It is about living life on your own terms. While the movie wasn't really very realistic it was pleasant, not recommended for those who try to fit every movie into a genre.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of Depp's most underrated movies. Funny, heartwarming and creative.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    callanvass
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    (Credit IMDb) A young man (who is the legendary Don Juan?), comes to New York in search of his lost love. Feeling like he has nothing to live for, he attempts to commit suicide from atop a billboard. Dr. Mickler is a soon retiring psychiatrist who helps Don Juan, come to his senses. He brings the costumed boy to the psychiatric hospital , in hopes of helping Don Juan find his identity. The doctor works with him for ten days, in which Don tells his life story. Mickler begins to believe that the young man is truly Don Juan, but the rest of the staff doesn't agree. The doctor knows that the only way out for Don Juan, is to pretend he's an average boy whose fantasy got the best of him. This isn't really talked about as one of Depp's best movies, but it sure should be. What I liked most about this movie was the eccentricity. Depp's character has it in spades. The movie was smart to have us wondering if De Marco was delusional about his story or if he was telling the truth. We never really know throughout the movie, but I loved the way they decided to end it. The scenery itself is beautiful. Performances. Johnny Depp can do no wrong in my eyes. 95% of the time he is bang on, and here is no different. He is so good, we aren't ever really sure if he's crazy or not. His chemistry with Brando is on the money. Marlon Brando is not a favorite of mine but he excelled here. He is wonderfully classy, and I loved his old-school approach. Faye Dunnaway is charming in her screen time. Bottom line. It's a wonderful little treat of a movie, one that is severely underrated on Depp's resume. It's not about if it was real or not, it's about what I learned. A must see in my books. 9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Don Not Di Recto (DVD)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leplatypus
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have got mixed feelings about this movie. It has everything to be a hit: Coppola at the production, a great song of the duo Adams / Kamen (better than their Robin Hood hit), the finest French Actress (Pailhas), the most talented of the new generation (Deep) and of the old generation (Brando, Dunaway) and a very romantic and original story (it's not easy to make out what's reality and what's fantasy, thus having set the movie in the psychiatric world is brilliant). For sure, having Brando finding his youth again is moving, because as he was such a tremendous actor, this movie has surely talked to him: retirement is coming, is love doomed then ? I am amazed how he can be younger actually in this movie than while he was playing old Vito Corleone. But as I watched it, I found it dull. I think the culprit is found in the writer/director Leven because he gives us a cold soup with all those tasteful components: Then, beware of Leven because he can't level up a movie! in addition, i have got only french version so i lost all the original voices!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very satisfying movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lise-93
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After watching this movie I sat at least 5 minutes with a smile on my face. It's an original movie, not a standard romantic comedy. Johnny Depp is excellent, I could not imagine a better actor for the part. And also Marlon Brando and Faye Dunaway are great as the couple that had been together very long, and find their passion again. I love the fact that in the end you still don't really know what the truth is, I think this is the best way to end the movie. The whole atmosphere of the movie is very nice, the music and sets are beautiful and really make the movie even better. It's not like other romantic comedy's just about finding love, it actually has a deeper story, the story that it doesn't really matter whether what you believe is reality or not, just as long as you believe it. I give this movie 9 out of 10, 'cause I definitely want to see it again.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just enjoy !!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    redx1708
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Great Picture. Maybe not a masterpiece...(well, probably not), but nonetheless a completely joyful experience. The question whether Depps story is fact or fiction is really really neither here nor there. If it's not true, it bloody well should be !! lol. And if the story doesn't catch you, the performances should. Marlon Brando and Johnny Depp. Each one among the greatest actors of their generations. What a pleasure to Watch them working together. This is what acting is all about. They both shine as does Faye Dunaway (wow, she's still a beauty). And while the movie won't be considered among the highlights of their careers, I'll still highly recommend it to all movie lovers.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Don Juan DeMarco Will Put The Viewer Into An Amorous Mood
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Don Juan DeMarco is a romantic comedy starring Johnny Depp as John Arnold DeMarco, a man who believes himself to be Don Juan, the greatest lover in the world. Clad in a cape and domino mask, DeMarco undergoes psychiatric treatment with Marlon Brando's character, Dr. Jack Mickler, to cure him of his apparent delusion. But the psychiatric sessions have an unexpected effect on the psychiatric staff, some of whom find themselves inspired by DeMarco's delusion; the most profoundly affected is Dr. Mickler himself, who rekindles the romance in his complacent marriage.The movie also stars Faye Dunaway.The movie is based on two different sources: the modern-day story is based on director/screenwriter Jeremy Leven's short story Don Juan DeMarco and the Centerfold and the familiar legend of Don Juan,wherein flashbacks depicting DeMarco's back-story are based on. In the movie,a psychiatrist treats a most unusual patient, only to find that the doctor is the one who gains the most from their sessions. A young man in a mask and cape is standing atop a billboard, threatening to jump. When the potential suicide is finally talked down, he's brought to a psychiatric facility where after one doctor washes his hands of the case, he's placed under the supervision of Dr. Jack Mickler, an aging psychiatrist soon to retire. The patient informs Mickler that he is actually the great lover Don Juan, who has seduced over 1,500 women, but has fallen into a deep depression after being unable to win the hand of the woman of his dreams. Mickler has ten days to work with his patient and after which he will either be released on medication or committed to a long-term stay in a mental hospital. As Mickler talks with the young man, who speaks rapturously of the art of love, the doctor finds that his philosophies are helping to kick start his failing relationship with his wife, and he slowly becomes convinced that his patient might really be Don Juan after all. Walking a fine line between precious comedy, wistful drama, and delicate fantasy, it gets a big dose of charm from its esteemed cast, with Johnny Depp delivering dialogue that would have sounded ludicrous from a lesser actor.While the performances by Marlon Brando and Faye Dunaway elevate this likable comedy about love, illusion and delusion way above its inconsequential text.This may not be a great movie, but it is guaranteed to put you in an amorous mood.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Johnny Depp + Marlon Brando... What did you expect?!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ludovico Giannotti
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie as incredible and can't believe it's low rating on here. Johnny Depp puts in a very good performance and so does Marlon Brando, in portraying a beautiful story, very touching and moving. I just liked the movie in all it's aspects. The film seems superficial and banal but it has a fairly deep underlying theme about love and its philosophy. I would definitely recommend this movie to everybody as it is really good and entertaining. It is a film for everybody, young and the older will both find it very interesting and captivating so don't watch the low score and just go watch it: it is amazing! x
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Sweet Must-See Movies for Lovers!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mlzema
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I recently watched this one again after having not seen it in quite a while and I was pleasantly surprised to find that it was still one of the sweetest little movies I have ever seen, and for a person of my cynical nature that is really saying something. One of the secrets of this movie is the casting of Brando and Depp, two actors whom I consider to be "blank slates" and are thus quite adept at falling into and being believable in whatever role is given to them. I thought Brando in particular was sublime as the about-to-retire psychiatrist who appears to be rudderless regarding his impending life of retirement. Johnny Depp's character has some really beautifully-written lines, most of which are quoted on this site, from which we as men and husbands could learn a thing or two. Yes, it's plot is totally implausible but I'm begging you to buy in to the premise and let yourself get lost for a little while. I promise you that you will be holding your wife's hand almost before you know it!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Despite a rather dopey plot, it's enjoyable because of a couple nice performances.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you've ever seen the Joanne Woodward and George C. Scott film "They Might Be Giants", then you'll no doubt recognize this plot in "Don Juan DeMarco". The film begins with Johnny Depp making a sexual conquest in modern day America---yet he THINKS he's the legendary lover Don Juan. Later, when this lover suddenly is found contemplating suicide, an aging psychiatrist (Marlon Brando) is called in to help. Not surprisingly, Don Juan DeMarco is committed to the institution where Brando works and Brando fights hard to get assigned him as a patient--even though he's due to retire very soon. The Doctor tries hard as he works with his new patient NOT to medicate him. After all, the Doc LIKES hearing all of his patient's weird stories of love, sex and adventure. And, through the course of the film, DeMarco starts rubbing off on his doctor--to the delight of the man's wife! Johnny Depp is very nice playing a suave Latin lover and Brando is really good because he seems nice and relaxed. My only big complaint is not them but the bafflingly stupid ending. Really. Up until then, I could suspend disbelief and enjoy the film, but the ending really left me shocked at its silliness. Still, worth a look.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Silly Accent, Done-To-Death Plot, Great Actors with No Roles to Play
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    good-decision
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was very disappointed in this movie. I rented it with such great expectations from a movie that has Marlon Brando and Johnny Depp in one and in the same movie. Alas, there was nothing but flat characters, the silliest accent I have ever heard an actor come up with, and suspension of disbelief was so hard I had to call a friend to moan what a silly movie it was. In fact was it not for my love for both Marlon and Depp I would have given it a zero! In an interview with the Actor's Studio, Depp said that the hardest thing about acting with Brando was trying to keep a straight face. I imagine Brando knew from the get go that the movie was a joke.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Another Quirky Movies from Depp
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    princebansal1982
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Johnny Depp has made a career of doing quirky movies. This is a charming, soft, quirky movie ideal for a lazy afternoon. Just go without any expectations. It is about a young man who thinks he is Don Juan DeMarco and his interactions with his psychiatrist who is trying to cure him. Though it is not really clear whether he is really delusional or not, it doesn't matters really. It is more about his exploits true or imagined, then anything else. It is about living life on your own terms. While the movie wasn't really very realistic it was pleasant, not recommended for those who try to fit every movie into a genre.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of Depp's most underrated movies. Funny, heartwarming and creative.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    callanvass
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    (Credit IMDb) A young man (who is the legendary Don Juan?), comes to New York in search of his lost love. Feeling like he has nothing to live for, he attempts to commit suicide from atop a billboard. Dr. Mickler is a soon retiring psychiatrist who helps Don Juan, come to his senses. He brings the costumed boy to the psychiatric hospital , in hopes of helping Don Juan find his identity. The doctor works with him for ten days, in which Don tells his life story. Mickler begins to believe that the young man is truly Don Juan, but the rest of the staff doesn't agree. The doctor knows that the only way out for Don Juan, is to pretend he's an average boy whose fantasy got the best of him. This isn't really talked about as one of Depp's best movies, but it sure should be. What I liked most about this movie was the eccentricity. Depp's character has it in spades. The movie was smart to have us wondering if De Marco was delusional about his story or if he was telling the truth. We never really know throughout the movie, but I loved the way they decided to end it. The scenery itself is beautiful. Performances. Johnny Depp can do no wrong in my eyes. 95% of the time he is bang on, and here is no different. He is so good, we aren't ever really sure if he's crazy or not. His chemistry with Brando is on the money. Marlon Brando is not a favorite of mine but he excelled here. He is wonderfully classy, and I loved his old-school approach. Faye Dunnaway is charming in her screen time. Bottom line. It's a wonderful little treat of a movie, one that is severely underrated on Depp's resume. It's not about if it was real or not, it's about what I learned. A must see in my books. 9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Don Not Di Recto (DVD)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leplatypus
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have got mixed feelings about this movie. It has everything to be a hit: Coppola at the production, a great song of the duo Adams / Kamen (better than their Robin Hood hit), the finest French Actress (Pailhas), the most talented of the new generation (Deep) and of the old generation (Brando, Dunaway) and a very romantic and original story (it's not easy to make out what's reality and what's fantasy, thus having set the movie in the psychiatric world is brilliant). For sure, having Brando finding his youth again is moving, because as he was such a tremendous actor, this movie has surely talked to him: retirement is coming, is love doomed then ? I am amazed how he can be younger actually in this movie than while he was playing old Vito Corleone. But as I watched it, I found it dull. I think the culprit is found in the writer/director Leven because he gives us a cold soup with all those tasteful components: Then, beware of Leven because he can't level up a movie! in addition, i have got only french version so i lost all the original voices!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very satisfying movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lise-93
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After watching this movie I sat at least 5 minutes with a smile on my face. It's an original movie, not a standard romantic comedy. Johnny Depp is excellent, I could not imagine a better actor for the part. And also Marlon Brando and Faye Dunaway are great as the couple that had been together very long, and find their passion again. I love the fact that in the end you still don't really know what the truth is, I think this is the best way to end the movie. The whole atmosphere of the movie is very nice, the music and sets are beautiful and really make the movie even better. It's not like other romantic comedy's just about finding love, it actually has a deeper story, the story that it doesn't really matter whether what you believe is reality or not, just as long as you believe it. I give this movie 9 out of 10, 'cause I definitely want to see it again.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just enjoy !!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    redx1708
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Great Picture. Maybe not a masterpiece...(well, probably not), but nonetheless a completely joyful experience. The question whether Depps story is fact or fiction is really really neither here nor there. If it's not true, it bloody well should be !! lol. And if the story doesn't catch you, the performances should. Marlon Brando and Johnny Depp. Each one among the greatest actors of their generations. What a pleasure to Watch them working together. This is what acting is all about. They both shine as does Faye Dunaway (wow, she's still a beauty). And while the movie won't be considered among the highlights of their careers, I'll still highly recommend it to all movie lovers.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Don Juan DeMarco Will Put The Viewer Into An Amorous Mood
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Don Juan DeMarco is a romantic comedy starring Johnny Depp as John Arnold DeMarco, a man who believes himself to be Don Juan, the greatest lover in the world. Clad in a cape and domino mask, DeMarco undergoes psychiatric treatment with Marlon Brando's character, Dr. Jack Mickler, to cure him of his apparent delusion. But the psychiatric sessions have an unexpected effect on the psychiatric staff, some of whom find themselves inspired by DeMarco's delusion; the most profoundly affected is Dr. Mickler himself, who rekindles the romance in his complacent marriage.The movie also stars Faye Dunaway.The movie is based on two different sources: the modern-day story is based on director/screenwriter Jeremy Leven's short story Don Juan DeMarco and the Centerfold and the familiar legend of Don Juan,wherein flashbacks depicting DeMarco's back-story are based on. In the movie,a psychiatrist treats a most unusual patient, only to find that the doctor is the one who gains the most from their sessions. A young man in a mask and cape is standing atop a billboard, threatening to jump. When the potential suicide is finally talked down, he's brought to a psychiatric facility where after one doctor washes his hands of the case, he's placed under the supervision of Dr. Jack Mickler, an aging psychiatrist soon to retire. The patient informs Mickler that he is actually the great lover Don Juan, who has seduced over 1,500 women, but has fallen into a deep depression after being unable to win the hand of the woman of his dreams. Mickler has ten days to work with his patient and after which he will either be released on medication or committed to a long-term stay in a mental hospital. As Mickler talks with the young man, who speaks rapturously of the art of love, the doctor finds that his philosophies are helping to kick start his failing relationship with his wife, and he slowly becomes convinced that his patient might really be Don Juan after all. Walking a fine line between precious comedy, wistful drama, and delicate fantasy, it gets a big dose of charm from its esteemed cast, with Johnny Depp delivering dialogue that would have sounded ludicrous from a lesser actor.While the performances by Marlon Brando and Faye Dunaway elevate this likable comedy about love, illusion and delusion way above its inconsequential text.This may not be a great movie, but it is guaranteed to put you in an amorous mood.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Johnny Depp + Marlon Brando... What did you expect?!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ludovico Giannotti
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie as incredible and can't believe it's low rating on here. Johnny Depp puts in a very good performance and so does Marlon Brando, in portraying a beautiful story, very touching and moving. I just liked the movie in all it's aspects. The film seems superficial and banal but it has a fairly deep underlying theme about love and its philosophy. I would definitely recommend this movie to everybody as it is really good and entertaining. It is a film for everybody, young and the older will both find it very interesting and captivating so don't watch the low score and just go watch it: it is amazing! x
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Sweet Must-See Movies for Lovers!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mlzema
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I recently watched this one again after having not seen it in quite a while and I was pleasantly surprised to find that it was still one of the sweetest little movies I have ever seen, and for a person of my cynical nature that is really saying something. One of the secrets of this movie is the casting of Brando and Depp, two actors whom I consider to be "blank slates" and are thus quite adept at falling into and being believable in whatever role is given to them. I thought Brando in particular was sublime as the about-to-retire psychiatrist who appears to be rudderless regarding his impending life of retirement. Johnny Depp's character has some really beautifully-written lines, most of which are quoted on this site, from which we as men and husbands could learn a thing or two. Yes, it's plot is totally implausible but I'm begging you to buy in to the premise and let yourself get lost for a little while. I promise you that you will be holding your wife's hand almost before you know it!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Despite a rather dopey plot, it's enjoyable because of a couple nice performances.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you've ever seen the Joanne Woodward and George C. Scott film "They Might Be Giants", then you'll no doubt recognize this plot in "Don Juan DeMarco". The film begins with Johnny Depp making a sexual conquest in modern day America---yet he THINKS he's the legendary lover Don Juan. Later, when this lover suddenly is found contemplating suicide, an aging psychiatrist (Marlon Brando) is called in to help. Not surprisingly, Don Juan DeMarco is committed to the institution where Brando works and Brando fights hard to get assigned him as a patient--even though he's due to retire very soon. The Doctor tries hard as he works with his new patient NOT to medicate him. After all, the Doc LIKES hearing all of his patient's weird stories of love, sex and adventure. And, through the course of the film, DeMarco starts rubbing off on his doctor--to the delight of the man's wife! Johnny Depp is very nice playing a suave Latin lover and Brando is really good because he seems nice and relaxed. My only big complaint is not them but the bafflingly stupid ending. Really. Up until then, I could suspend disbelief and enjoy the film, but the ending really left me shocked at its silliness. Still, worth a look.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Silly Accent, Done-To-Death Plot, Great Actors with No Roles to Play
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    good-decision
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was very disappointed in this movie. I rented it with such great expectations from a movie that has Marlon Brando and Johnny Depp in one and in the same movie. Alas, there was nothing but flat characters, the silliest accent I have ever heard an actor come up with, and suspension of disbelief was so hard I had to call a friend to moan what a silly movie it was. In fact was it not for my love for both Marlon and Depp I would have given it a zero! In an interview with the Actor's Studio, Depp said that the hardest thing about acting with Brando was trying to keep a straight face. I imagine Brando knew from the get go that the movie was a joke.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Another Quirky Movies from Depp
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    princebansal1982
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Johnny Depp has made a career of doing quirky movies. This is a charming, soft, quirky movie ideal for a lazy afternoon. Just go without any expectations. It is about a young man who thinks he is Don Juan DeMarco and his interactions with his psychiatrist who is trying to cure him. Though it is not really clear whether he is really delusional or not, it doesn't matters really. It is more about his exploits true or imagined, then anything else. It is about living life on your own terms. While the movie wasn't really very realistic it was pleasant, not recommended for those who try to fit every movie into a genre.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of Depp's most underrated movies. Funny, heartwarming and creative.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    callanvass
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    (Credit IMDb) A young man (who is the legendary Don Juan?), comes to New York in search of his lost love. Feeling like he has nothing to live for, he attempts to commit suicide from atop a billboard. Dr. Mickler is a soon retiring psychiatrist who helps Don Juan, come to his senses. He brings the costumed boy to the psychiatric hospital , in hopes of helping Don Juan find his identity. The doctor works with him for ten days, in which Don tells his life story. Mickler begins to believe that the young man is truly Don Juan, but the rest of the staff doesn't agree. The doctor knows that the only way out for Don Juan, is to pretend he's an average boy whose fantasy got the best of him. This isn't really talked about as one of Depp's best movies, but it sure should be. What I liked most about this movie was the eccentricity. Depp's character has it in spades. The movie was smart to have us wondering if De Marco was delusional about his story or if he was telling the truth. We never really know throughout the movie, but I loved the way they decided to end it. The scenery itself is beautiful. Performances. Johnny Depp can do no wrong in my eyes. 95% of the time he is bang on, and here is no different. He is so good, we aren't ever really sure if he's crazy or not. His chemistry with Brando is on the money. Marlon Brando is not a favorite of mine but he excelled here. He is wonderfully classy, and I loved his old-school approach. Faye Dunnaway is charming in her screen time. Bottom line. It's a wonderful little treat of a movie, one that is severely underrated on Depp's resume. It's not about if it was real or not, it's about what I learned. A must see in my books. 9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Don Not Di Recto (DVD)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leplatypus
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have got mixed feelings about this movie. It has everything to be a hit: Coppola at the production, a great song of the duo Adams / Kamen (better than their Robin Hood hit), the finest French Actress (Pailhas), the most talented of the new generation (Deep) and of the old generation (Brando, Dunaway) and a very romantic and original story (it's not easy to make out what's reality and what's fantasy, thus having set the movie in the psychiatric world is brilliant). For sure, having Brando finding his youth again is moving, because as he was such a tremendous actor, this movie has surely talked to him: retirement is coming, is love doomed then ? I am amazed how he can be younger actually in this movie than while he was playing old Vito Corleone. But as I watched it, I found it dull. I think the culprit is found in the writer/director Leven because he gives us a cold soup with all those tasteful components: Then, beware of Leven because he can't level up a movie! in addition, i have got only french version so i lost all the original voices!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very satisfying movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lise-93
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After watching this movie I sat at least 5 minutes with a smile on my face. It's an original movie, not a standard romantic comedy. Johnny Depp is excellent, I could not imagine a better actor for the part. And also Marlon Brando and Faye Dunaway are great as the couple that had been together very long, and find their passion again. I love the fact that in the end you still don't really know what the truth is, I think this is the best way to end the movie. The whole atmosphere of the movie is very nice, the music and sets are beautiful and really make the movie even better. It's not like other romantic comedy's just about finding love, it actually has a deeper story, the story that it doesn't really matter whether what you believe is reality or not, just as long as you believe it. I give this movie 9 out of 10, 'cause I definitely want to see it again.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just enjoy !!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    redx1708
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Great Picture. Maybe not a masterpiece...(well, probably not), but nonetheless a completely joyful experience. The question whether Depps story is fact or fiction is really really neither here nor there. If it's not true, it bloody well should be !! lol. And if the story doesn't catch you, the performances should. Marlon Brando and Johnny Depp. Each one among the greatest actors of their generations. What a pleasure to Watch them working together. This is what acting is all about. They both shine as does Faye Dunaway (wow, she's still a beauty). And while the movie won't be considered among the highlights of their careers, I'll still highly recommend it to all movie lovers.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Don Juan DeMarco Will Put The Viewer Into An Amorous Mood
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Don Juan DeMarco is a romantic comedy starring Johnny Depp as John Arnold DeMarco, a man who believes himself to be Don Juan, the greatest lover in the world. Clad in a cape and domino mask, DeMarco undergoes psychiatric treatment with Marlon Brando's character, Dr. Jack Mickler, to cure him of his apparent delusion. But the psychiatric sessions have an unexpected effect on the psychiatric staff, some of whom find themselves inspired by DeMarco's delusion; the most profoundly affected is Dr. Mickler himself, who rekindles the romance in his complacent marriage.The movie also stars Faye Dunaway.The movie is based on two different sources: the modern-day story is based on director/screenwriter Jeremy Leven's short story Don Juan DeMarco and the Centerfold and the familiar legend of Don Juan,wherein flashbacks depicting DeMarco's back-story are based on. In the movie,a psychiatrist treats a most unusual patient, only to find that the doctor is the one who gains the most from their sessions. A young man in a mask and cape is standing atop a billboard, threatening to jump. When the potential suicide is finally talked down, he's brought to a psychiatric facility where after one doctor washes his hands of the case, he's placed under the supervision of Dr. Jack Mickler, an aging psychiatrist soon to retire. The patient informs Mickler that he is actually the great lover Don Juan, who has seduced over 1,500 women, but has fallen into a deep depression after being unable to win the hand of the woman of his dreams. Mickler has ten days to work with his patient and after which he will either be released on medication or committed to a long-term stay in a mental hospital. As Mickler talks with the young man, who speaks rapturously of the art of love, the doctor finds that his philosophies are helping to kick start his failing relationship with his wife, and he slowly becomes convinced that his patient might really be Don Juan after all. Walking a fine line between precious comedy, wistful drama, and delicate fantasy, it gets a big dose of charm from its esteemed cast, with Johnny Depp delivering dialogue that would have sounded ludicrous from a lesser actor.While the performances by Marlon Brando and Faye Dunaway elevate this likable comedy about love, illusion and delusion way above its inconsequential text.This may not be a great movie, but it is guaranteed to put you in an amorous mood.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Johnny Depp + Marlon Brando... What did you expect?!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ludovico Giannotti
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie as incredible and can't believe it's low rating on here. Johnny Depp puts in a very good performance and so does Marlon Brando, in portraying a beautiful story, very touching and moving. I just liked the movie in all it's aspects. The film seems superficial and banal but it has a fairly deep underlying theme about love and its philosophy. I would definitely recommend this movie to everybody as it is really good and entertaining. It is a film for everybody, young and the older will both find it very interesting and captivating so don't watch the low score and just go watch it: it is amazing! x
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Sweet Must-See Movies for Lovers!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mlzema
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I recently watched this one again after having not seen it in quite a while and I was pleasantly surprised to find that it was still one of the sweetest little movies I have ever seen, and for a person of my cynical nature that is really saying something. One of the secrets of this movie is the casting of Brando and Depp, two actors whom I consider to be "blank slates" and are thus quite adept at falling into and being believable in whatever role is given to them. I thought Brando in particular was sublime as the about-to-retire psychiatrist who appears to be rudderless regarding his impending life of retirement. Johnny Depp's character has some really beautifully-written lines, most of which are quoted on this site, from which we as men and husbands could learn a thing or two. Yes, it's plot is totally implausible but I'm begging you to buy in to the premise and let yourself get lost for a little while. I promise you that you will be holding your wife's hand almost before you know it!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Despite a rather dopey plot, it's enjoyable because of a couple nice performances.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you've ever seen the Joanne Woodward and George C. Scott film "They Might Be Giants", then you'll no doubt recognize this plot in "Don Juan DeMarco". The film begins with Johnny Depp making a sexual conquest in modern day America---yet he THINKS he's the legendary lover Don Juan. Later, when this lover suddenly is found contemplating suicide, an aging psychiatrist (Marlon Brando) is called in to help. Not surprisingly, Don Juan DeMarco is committed to the institution where Brando works and Brando fights hard to get assigned him as a patient--even though he's due to retire very soon. The Doctor tries hard as he works with his new patient NOT to medicate him. After all, the Doc LIKES hearing all of his patient's weird stories of love, sex and adventure. And, through the course of the film, DeMarco starts rubbing off on his doctor--to the delight of the man's wife! Johnny Depp is very nice playing a suave Latin lover and Brando is really good because he seems nice and relaxed. My only big complaint is not them but the bafflingly stupid ending. Really. Up until then, I could suspend disbelief and enjoy the film, but the ending really left me shocked at its silliness. Still, worth a look.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Silly Accent, Done-To-Death Plot, Great Actors with No Roles to Play
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    good-decision
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was very disappointed in this movie. I rented it with such great expectations from a movie that has Marlon Brando and Johnny Depp in one and in the same movie. Alas, there was nothing but flat characters, the silliest accent I have ever heard an actor come up with, and suspension of disbelief was so hard I had to call a friend to moan what a silly movie it was. In fact was it not for my love for both Marlon and Depp I would have given it a zero! In an interview with the Actor's Studio, Depp said that the hardest thing about acting with Brando was trying to keep a straight face. I imagine Brando knew from the get go that the movie was a joke.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Another Quirky Movies from Depp
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    princebansal1982
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Johnny Depp has made a career of doing quirky movies. This is a charming, soft, quirky movie ideal for a lazy afternoon. Just go without any expectations. It is about a young man who thinks he is Don Juan DeMarco and his interactions with his psychiatrist who is trying to cure him. Though it is not really clear whether he is really delusional or not, it doesn't matters really. It is more about his exploits true or imagined, then anything else. It is about living life on your own terms. While the movie wasn't really very realistic it was pleasant, not recommended for those who try to fit every movie into a genre.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of Depp's most underrated movies. Funny, heartwarming and creative.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    callanvass
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    (Credit IMDb) A young man (who is the legendary Don Juan?), comes to New York in search of his lost love. Feeling like he has nothing to live for, he attempts to commit suicide from atop a billboard. Dr. Mickler is a soon retiring psychiatrist who helps Don Juan, come to his senses. He brings the costumed boy to the psychiatric hospital , in hopes of helping Don Juan find his identity. The doctor works with him for ten days, in which Don tells his life story. Mickler begins to believe that the young man is truly Don Juan, but the rest of the staff doesn't agree. The doctor knows that the only way out for Don Juan, is to pretend he's an average boy whose fantasy got the best of him. This isn't really talked about as one of Depp's best movies, but it sure should be. What I liked most about this movie was the eccentricity. Depp's character has it in spades. The movie was smart to have us wondering if De Marco was delusional about his story or if he was telling the truth. We never really know throughout the movie, but I loved the way they decided to end it. The scenery itself is beautiful. Performances. Johnny Depp can do no wrong in my eyes. 95% of the time he is bang on, and here is no different. He is so good, we aren't ever really sure if he's crazy or not. His chemistry with Brando is on the money. Marlon Brando is not a favorite of mine but he excelled here. He is wonderfully classy, and I loved his old-school approach. Faye Dunnaway is charming in her screen time. Bottom line. It's a wonderful little treat of a movie, one that is severely underrated on Depp's resume. It's not about if it was real or not, it's about what I learned. A must see in my books. 9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Don Not Di Recto (DVD)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leplatypus
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have got mixed feelings about this movie. It has everything to be a hit: Coppola at the production, a great song of the duo Adams / Kamen (better than their Robin Hood hit), the finest French Actress (Pailhas), the most talented of the new generation (Deep) and of the old generation (Brando, Dunaway) and a very romantic and original story (it's not easy to make out what's reality and what's fantasy, thus having set the movie in the psychiatric world is brilliant). For sure, having Brando finding his youth again is moving, because as he was such a tremendous actor, this movie has surely talked to him: retirement is coming, is love doomed then ? I am amazed how he can be younger actually in this movie than while he was playing old Vito Corleone. But as I watched it, I found it dull. I think the culprit is found in the writer/director Leven because he gives us a cold soup with all those tasteful components: Then, beware of Leven because he can't level up a movie! in addition, i have got only french version so i lost all the original voices!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very satisfying movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lise-93
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After watching this movie I sat at least 5 minutes with a smile on my face. It's an original movie, not a standard romantic comedy. Johnny Depp is excellent, I could not imagine a better actor for the part. And also Marlon Brando and Faye Dunaway are great as the couple that had been together very long, and find their passion again. I love the fact that in the end you still don't really know what the truth is, I think this is the best way to end the movie. The whole atmosphere of the movie is very nice, the music and sets are beautiful and really make the movie even better. It's not like other romantic comedy's just about finding love, it actually has a deeper story, the story that it doesn't really matter whether what you believe is reality or not, just as long as you believe it. I give this movie 9 out of 10, 'cause I definitely want to see it again.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just enjoy !!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    redx1708
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Great Picture. Maybe not a masterpiece...(well, probably not), but nonetheless a completely joyful experience. The question whether Depps story is fact or fiction is really really neither here nor there. If it's not true, it bloody well should be !! lol. And if the story doesn't catch you, the performances should. Marlon Brando and Johnny Depp. Each one among the greatest actors of their generations. What a pleasure to Watch them working together. This is what acting is all about. They both shine as does Faye Dunaway (wow, she's still a beauty). And while the movie won't be considered among the highlights of their careers, I'll still highly recommend it to all movie lovers.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Don Juan DeMarco Will Put The Viewer Into An Amorous Mood
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Don Juan DeMarco is a romantic comedy starring Johnny Depp as John Arnold DeMarco, a man who believes himself to be Don Juan, the greatest lover in the world. Clad in a cape and domino mask, DeMarco undergoes psychiatric treatment with Marlon Brando's character, Dr. Jack Mickler, to cure him of his apparent delusion. But the psychiatric sessions have an unexpected effect on the psychiatric staff, some of whom find themselves inspired by DeMarco's delusion; the most profoundly affected is Dr. Mickler himself, who rekindles the romance in his complacent marriage.The movie also stars Faye Dunaway.The movie is based on two different sources: the modern-day story is based on director/screenwriter Jeremy Leven's short story Don Juan DeMarco and the Centerfold and the familiar legend of Don Juan,wherein flashbacks depicting DeMarco's back-story are based on. In the movie,a psychiatrist treats a most unusual patient, only to find that the doctor is the one who gains the most from their sessions. A young man in a mask and cape is standing atop a billboard, threatening to jump. When the potential suicide is finally talked down, he's brought to a psychiatric facility where after one doctor washes his hands of the case, he's placed under the supervision of Dr. Jack Mickler, an aging psychiatrist soon to retire. The patient informs Mickler that he is actually the great lover Don Juan, who has seduced over 1,500 women, but has fallen into a deep depression after being unable to win the hand of the woman of his dreams. Mickler has ten days to work with his patient and after which he will either be released on medication or committed to a long-term stay in a mental hospital. As Mickler talks with the young man, who speaks rapturously of the art of love, the doctor finds that his philosophies are helping to kick start his failing relationship with his wife, and he slowly becomes convinced that his patient might really be Don Juan after all. Walking a fine line between precious comedy, wistful drama, and delicate fantasy, it gets a big dose of charm from its esteemed cast, with Johnny Depp delivering dialogue that would have sounded ludicrous from a lesser actor.While the performances by Marlon Brando and Faye Dunaway elevate this likable comedy about love, illusion and delusion way above its inconsequential text.This may not be a great movie, but it is guaranteed to put you in an amorous mood.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Johnny Depp + Marlon Brando... What did you expect?!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ludovico Giannotti
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie as incredible and can't believe it's low rating on here. Johnny Depp puts in a very good performance and so does Marlon Brando, in portraying a beautiful story, very touching and moving. I just liked the movie in all it's aspects. The film seems superficial and banal but it has a fairly deep underlying theme about love and its philosophy. I would definitely recommend this movie to everybody as it is really good and entertaining. It is a film for everybody, young and the older will both find it very interesting and captivating so don't watch the low score and just go watch it: it is amazing! x
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Sweet Must-See Movies for Lovers!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mlzema
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I recently watched this one again after having not seen it in quite a while and I was pleasantly surprised to find that it was still one of the sweetest little movies I have ever seen, and for a person of my cynical nature that is really saying something. One of the secrets of this movie is the casting of Brando and Depp, two actors whom I consider to be "blank slates" and are thus quite adept at falling into and being believable in whatever role is given to them. I thought Brando in particular was sublime as the about-to-retire psychiatrist who appears to be rudderless regarding his impending life of retirement. Johnny Depp's character has some really beautifully-written lines, most of which are quoted on this site, from which we as men and husbands could learn a thing or two. Yes, it's plot is totally implausible but I'm begging you to buy in to the premise and let yourself get lost for a little while. I promise you that you will be holding your wife's hand almost before you know it!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Despite a rather dopey plot, it's enjoyable because of a couple nice performances.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you've ever seen the Joanne Woodward and George C. Scott film "They Might Be Giants", then you'll no doubt recognize this plot in "Don Juan DeMarco". The film begins with Johnny Depp making a sexual conquest in modern day America---yet he THINKS he's the legendary lover Don Juan. Later, when this lover suddenly is found contemplating suicide, an aging psychiatrist (Marlon Brando) is called in to help. Not surprisingly, Don Juan DeMarco is committed to the institution where Brando works and Brando fights hard to get assigned him as a patient--even though he's due to retire very soon. The Doctor tries hard as he works with his new patient NOT to medicate him. After all, the Doc LIKES hearing all of his patient's weird stories of love, sex and adventure. And, through the course of the film, DeMarco starts rubbing off on his doctor--to the delight of the man's wife! Johnny Depp is very nice playing a suave Latin lover and Brando is really good because he seems nice and relaxed. My only big complaint is not them but the bafflingly stupid ending. Really. Up until then, I could suspend disbelief and enjoy the film, but the ending really left me shocked at its silliness. Still, worth a look.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Silly Accent, Done-To-Death Plot, Great Actors with No Roles to Play
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    good-decision
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was very disappointed in this movie. I rented it with such great expectations from a movie that has Marlon Brando and Johnny Depp in one and in the same movie. Alas, there was nothing but flat characters, the silliest accent I have ever heard an actor come up with, and suspension of disbelief was so hard I had to call a friend to moan what a silly movie it was. In fact was it not for my love for both Marlon and Depp I would have given it a zero! In an interview with the Actor's Studio, Depp said that the hardest thing about acting with Brando was trying to keep a straight face. I imagine Brando knew from the get go that the movie was a joke.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Another Quirky Movies from Depp
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    princebansal1982
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Johnny Depp has made a career of doing quirky movies. This is a charming, soft, quirky movie ideal for a lazy afternoon. Just go without any expectations. It is about a young man who thinks he is Don Juan DeMarco and his interactions with his psychiatrist who is trying to cure him. Though it is not really clear whether he is really delusional or not, it doesn't matters really. It is more about his exploits true or imagined, then anything else. It is about living life on your own terms. While the movie wasn't really very realistic it was pleasant, not recommended for those who try to fit every movie into a genre.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of Depp's most underrated movies. Funny, heartwarming and creative.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    callanvass
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    (Credit IMDb) A young man (who is the legendary Don Juan?), comes to New York in search of his lost love. Feeling like he has nothing to live for, he attempts to commit suicide from atop a billboard. Dr. Mickler is a soon retiring psychiatrist who helps Don Juan, come to his senses. He brings the costumed boy to the psychiatric hospital , in hopes of helping Don Juan find his identity. The doctor works with him for ten days, in which Don tells his life story. Mickler begins to believe that the young man is truly Don Juan, but the rest of the staff doesn't agree. The doctor knows that the only way out for Don Juan, is to pretend he's an average boy whose fantasy got the best of him. This isn't really talked about as one of Depp's best movies, but it sure should be. What I liked most about this movie was the eccentricity. Depp's character has it in spades. The movie was smart to have us wondering if De Marco was delusional about his story or if he was telling the truth. We never really know throughout the movie, but I loved the way they decided to end it. The scenery itself is beautiful. Performances. Johnny Depp can do no wrong in my eyes. 95% of the time he is bang on, and here is no different. He is so good, we aren't ever really sure if he's crazy or not. His chemistry with Brando is on the money. Marlon Brando is not a favorite of mine but he excelled here. He is wonderfully classy, and I loved his old-school approach. Faye Dunnaway is charming in her screen time. Bottom line. It's a wonderful little treat of a movie, one that is severely underrated on Depp's resume. It's not about if it was real or not, it's about what I learned. A must see in my books. 9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Don Not Di Recto (DVD)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leplatypus
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have got mixed feelings about this movie. It has everything to be a hit: Coppola at the production, a great song of the duo Adams / Kamen (better than their Robin Hood hit), the finest French Actress (Pailhas), the most talented of the new generation (Deep) and of the old generation (Brando, Dunaway) and a very romantic and original story (it's not easy to make out what's reality and what's fantasy, thus having set the movie in the psychiatric world is brilliant). For sure, having Brando finding his youth again is moving, because as he was such a tremendous actor, this movie has surely talked to him: retirement is coming, is love doomed then ? I am amazed how he can be younger actually in this movie than while he was playing old Vito Corleone. But as I watched it, I found it dull. I think the culprit is found in the writer/director Leven because he gives us a cold soup with all those tasteful components: Then, beware of Leven because he can't level up a movie! in addition, i have got only french version so i lost all the original voices!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very satisfying movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lise-93
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After watching this movie I sat at least 5 minutes with a smile on my face. It's an original movie, not a standard romantic comedy. Johnny Depp is excellent, I could not imagine a better actor for the part. And also Marlon Brando and Faye Dunaway are great as the couple that had been together very long, and find their passion again. I love the fact that in the end you still don't really know what the truth is, I think this is the best way to end the movie. The whole atmosphere of the movie is very nice, the music and sets are beautiful and really make the movie even better. It's not like other romantic comedy's just about finding love, it actually has a deeper story, the story that it doesn't really matter whether what you believe is reality or not, just as long as you believe it. I give this movie 9 out of 10, 'cause I definitely want to see it again.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just enjoy !!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    redx1708
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Great Picture. Maybe not a masterpiece...(well, probably not), but nonetheless a completely joyful experience. The question whether Depps story is fact or fiction is really really neither here nor there. If it's not true, it bloody well should be !! lol. And if the story doesn't catch you, the performances should. Marlon Brando and Johnny Depp. Each one among the greatest actors of their generations. What a pleasure to Watch them working together. This is what acting is all about. They both shine as does Faye Dunaway (wow, she's still a beauty). And while the movie won't be considered among the highlights of their careers, I'll still highly recommend it to all movie lovers.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Don Juan DeMarco Will Put The Viewer Into An Amorous Mood
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Don Juan DeMarco is a romantic comedy starring Johnny Depp as John Arnold DeMarco, a man who believes himself to be Don Juan, the greatest lover in the world. Clad in a cape and domino mask, DeMarco undergoes psychiatric treatment with Marlon Brando's character, Dr. Jack Mickler, to cure him of his apparent delusion. But the psychiatric sessions have an unexpected effect on the psychiatric staff, some of whom find themselves inspired by DeMarco's delusion; the most profoundly affected is Dr. Mickler himself, who rekindles the romance in his complacent marriage.The movie also stars Faye Dunaway.The movie is based on two different sources: the modern-day story is based on director/screenwriter Jeremy Leven's short story Don Juan DeMarco and the Centerfold and the familiar legend of Don Juan,wherein flashbacks depicting DeMarco's back-story are based on. In the movie,a psychiatrist treats a most unusual patient, only to find that the doctor is the one who gains the most from their sessions. A young man in a mask and cape is standing atop a billboard, threatening to jump. When the potential suicide is finally talked down, he's brought to a psychiatric facility where after one doctor washes his hands of the case, he's placed under the supervision of Dr. Jack Mickler, an aging psychiatrist soon to retire. The patient informs Mickler that he is actually the great lover Don Juan, who has seduced over 1,500 women, but has fallen into a deep depression after being unable to win the hand of the woman of his dreams. Mickler has ten days to work with his patient and after which he will either be released on medication or committed to a long-term stay in a mental hospital. As Mickler talks with the young man, who speaks rapturously of the art of love, the doctor finds that his philosophies are helping to kick start his failing relationship with his wife, and he slowly becomes convinced that his patient might really be Don Juan after all. Walking a fine line between precious comedy, wistful drama, and delicate fantasy, it gets a big dose of charm from its esteemed cast, with Johnny Depp delivering dialogue that would have sounded ludicrous from a lesser actor.While the performances by Marlon Brando and Faye Dunaway elevate this likable comedy about love, illusion and delusion way above its inconsequential text.This may not be a great movie, but it is guaranteed to put you in an amorous mood.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Johnny Depp + Marlon Brando... What did you expect?!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ludovico Giannotti
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie as incredible and can't believe it's low rating on here. Johnny Depp puts in a very good performance and so does Marlon Brando, in portraying a beautiful story, very touching and moving. I just liked the movie in all it's aspects. The film seems superficial and banal but it has a fairly deep underlying theme about love and its philosophy. I would definitely recommend this movie to everybody as it is really good and entertaining. It is a film for everybody, young and the older will both find it very interesting and captivating so don't watch the low score and just go watch it: it is amazing! x
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Sweet Must-See Movies for Lovers!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mlzema
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I recently watched this one again after having not seen it in quite a while and I was pleasantly surprised to find that it was still one of the sweetest little movies I have ever seen, and for a person of my cynical nature that is really saying something. One of the secrets of this movie is the casting of Brando and Depp, two actors whom I consider to be "blank slates" and are thus quite adept at falling into and being believable in whatever role is given to them. I thought Brando in particular was sublime as the about-to-retire psychiatrist who appears to be rudderless regarding his impending life of retirement. Johnny Depp's character has some really beautifully-written lines, most of which are quoted on this site, from which we as men and husbands could learn a thing or two. Yes, it's plot is totally implausible but I'm begging you to buy in to the premise and let yourself get lost for a little while. I promise you that you will be holding your wife's hand almost before you know it!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Despite a rather dopey plot, it's enjoyable because of a couple nice performances.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you've ever seen the Joanne Woodward and George C. Scott film "They Might Be Giants", then you'll no doubt recognize this plot in "Don Juan DeMarco". The film begins with Johnny Depp making a sexual conquest in modern day America---yet he THINKS he's the legendary lover Don Juan. Later, when this lover suddenly is found contemplating suicide, an aging psychiatrist (Marlon Brando) is called in to help. Not surprisingly, Don Juan DeMarco is committed to the institution where Brando works and Brando fights hard to get assigned him as a patient--even though he's due to retire very soon. The Doctor tries hard as he works with his new patient NOT to medicate him. After all, the Doc LIKES hearing all of his patient's weird stories of love, sex and adventure. And, through the course of the film, DeMarco starts rubbing off on his doctor--to the delight of the man's wife! Johnny Depp is very nice playing a suave Latin lover and Brando is really good because he seems nice and relaxed. My only big complaint is not them but the bafflingly stupid ending. Really. Up until then, I could suspend disbelief and enjoy the film, but the ending really left me shocked at its silliness. Still, worth a look.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Silly Accent, Done-To-Death Plot, Great Actors with No Roles to Play
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    good-decision
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was very disappointed in this movie. I rented it with such great expectations from a movie that has Marlon Brando and Johnny Depp in one and in the same movie. Alas, there was nothing but flat characters, the silliest accent I have ever heard an actor come up with, and suspension of disbelief was so hard I had to call a friend to moan what a silly movie it was. In fact was it not for my love for both Marlon and Depp I would have given it a zero! In an interview with the Actor's Studio, Depp said that the hardest thing about acting with Brando was trying to keep a straight face. I imagine Brando knew from the get go that the movie was a joke.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Another Quirky Movies from Depp
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    princebansal1982
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Johnny Depp has made a career of doing quirky movies. This is a charming, soft, quirky movie ideal for a lazy afternoon. Just go without any expectations. It is about a young man who thinks he is Don Juan DeMarco and his interactions with his psychiatrist who is trying to cure him. Though it is not really clear whether he is really delusional or not, it doesn't matters really. It is more about his exploits true or imagined, then anything else. It is about living life on your own terms. While the movie wasn't really very realistic it was pleasant, not recommended for those who try to fit every movie into a genre.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of Depp's most underrated movies. Funny, heartwarming and creative.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    callanvass
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    (Credit IMDb) A young man (who is the legendary Don Juan?), comes to New York in search of his lost love. Feeling like he has nothing to live for, he attempts to commit suicide from atop a billboard. Dr. Mickler is a soon retiring psychiatrist who helps Don Juan, come to his senses. He brings the costumed boy to the psychiatric hospital , in hopes of helping Don Juan find his identity. The doctor works with him for ten days, in which Don tells his life story. Mickler begins to believe that the young man is truly Don Juan, but the rest of the staff doesn't agree. The doctor knows that the only way out for Don Juan, is to pretend he's an average boy whose fantasy got the best of him. This isn't really talked about as one of Depp's best movies, but it sure should be. What I liked most about this movie was the eccentricity. Depp's character has it in spades. The movie was smart to have us wondering if De Marco was delusional about his story or if he was telling the truth. We never really know throughout the movie, but I loved the way they decided to end it. The scenery itself is beautiful. Performances. Johnny Depp can do no wrong in my eyes. 95% of the time he is bang on, and here is no different. He is so good, we aren't ever really sure if he's crazy or not. His chemistry with Brando is on the money. Marlon Brando is not a favorite of mine but he excelled here. He is wonderfully classy, and I loved his old-school approach. Faye Dunnaway is charming in her screen time. Bottom line. It's a wonderful little treat of a movie, one that is severely underrated on Depp's resume. It's not about if it was real or not, it's about what I learned. A must see in my books. 9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Don Not Di Recto (DVD)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leplatypus
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have got mixed feelings about this movie. It has everything to be a hit: Coppola at the production, a great song of the duo Adams / Kamen (better than their Robin Hood hit), the finest French Actress (Pailhas), the most talented of the new generation (Deep) and of the old generation (Brando, Dunaway) and a very romantic and original story (it's not easy to make out what's reality and what's fantasy, thus having set the movie in the psychiatric world is brilliant). For sure, having Brando finding his youth again is moving, because as he was such a tremendous actor, this movie has surely talked to him: retirement is coming, is love doomed then ? I am amazed how he can be younger actually in this movie than while he was playing old Vito Corleone. But as I watched it, I found it dull. I think the culprit is found in the writer/director Leven because he gives us a cold soup with all those tasteful components: Then, beware of Leven because he can't level up a movie! in addition, i have got only french version so i lost all the original voices!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very satisfying movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lise-93
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After watching this movie I sat at least 5 minutes with a smile on my face. It's an original movie, not a standard romantic comedy. Johnny Depp is excellent, I could not imagine a better actor for the part. And also Marlon Brando and Faye Dunaway are great as the couple that had been together very long, and find their passion again. I love the fact that in the end you still don't really know what the truth is, I think this is the best way to end the movie. The whole atmosphere of the movie is very nice, the music and sets are beautiful and really make the movie even better. It's not like other romantic comedy's just about finding love, it actually has a deeper story, the story that it doesn't really matter whether what you believe is reality or not, just as long as you believe it. I give this movie 9 out of 10, 'cause I definitely want to see it again.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just enjoy !!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    redx1708
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Great Picture. Maybe not a masterpiece...(well, probably not), but nonetheless a completely joyful experience. The question whether Depps story is fact or fiction is really really neither here nor there. If it's not true, it bloody well should be !! lol. And if the story doesn't catch you, the performances should. Marlon Brando and Johnny Depp. Each one among the greatest actors of their generations. What a pleasure to Watch them working together. This is what acting is all about. They both shine as does Faye Dunaway (wow, she's still a beauty). And while the movie won't be considered among the highlights of their careers, I'll still highly recommend it to all movie lovers.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Don Juan DeMarco Will Put The Viewer Into An Amorous Mood
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Don Juan DeMarco is a romantic comedy starring Johnny Depp as John Arnold DeMarco, a man who believes himself to be Don Juan, the greatest lover in the world. Clad in a cape and domino mask, DeMarco undergoes psychiatric treatment with Marlon Brando's character, Dr. Jack Mickler, to cure him of his apparent delusion. But the psychiatric sessions have an unexpected effect on the psychiatric staff, some of whom find themselves inspired by DeMarco's delusion; the most profoundly affected is Dr. Mickler himself, who rekindles the romance in his complacent marriage.The movie also stars Faye Dunaway.The movie is based on two different sources: the modern-day story is based on director/screenwriter Jeremy Leven's short story Don Juan DeMarco and the Centerfold and the familiar legend of Don Juan,wherein flashbacks depicting DeMarco's back-story are based on. In the movie,a psychiatrist treats a most unusual patient, only to find that the doctor is the one who gains the most from their sessions. A young man in a mask and cape is standing atop a billboard, threatening to jump. When the potential suicide is finally talked down, he's brought to a psychiatric facility where after one doctor washes his hands of the case, he's placed under the supervision of Dr. Jack Mickler, an aging psychiatrist soon to retire. The patient informs Mickler that he is actually the great lover Don Juan, who has seduced over 1,500 women, but has fallen into a deep depression after being unable to win the hand of the woman of his dreams. Mickler has ten days to work with his patient and after which he will either be released on medication or committed to a long-term stay in a mental hospital. As Mickler talks with the young man, who speaks rapturously of the art of love, the doctor finds that his philosophies are helping to kick start his failing relationship with his wife, and he slowly becomes convinced that his patient might really be Don Juan after all. Walking a fine line between precious comedy, wistful drama, and delicate fantasy, it gets a big dose of charm from its esteemed cast, with Johnny Depp delivering dialogue that would have sounded ludicrous from a lesser actor.While the performances by Marlon Brando and Faye Dunaway elevate this likable comedy about love, illusion and delusion way above its inconsequential text.This may not be a great movie, but it is guaranteed to put you in an amorous mood.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Johnny Depp + Marlon Brando... What did you expect?!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ludovico Giannotti
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie as incredible and can't believe it's low rating on here. Johnny Depp puts in a very good performance and so does Marlon Brando, in portraying a beautiful story, very touching and moving. I just liked the movie in all it's aspects. The film seems superficial and banal but it has a fairly deep underlying theme about love and its philosophy. I would definitely recommend this movie to everybody as it is really good and entertaining. It is a film for everybody, young and the older will both find it very interesting and captivating so don't watch the low score and just go watch it: it is amazing! x
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Sweet Must-See Movies for Lovers!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mlzema
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I recently watched this one again after having not seen it in quite a while and I was pleasantly surprised to find that it was still one of the sweetest little movies I have ever seen, and for a person of my cynical nature that is really saying something. One of the secrets of this movie is the casting of Brando and Depp, two actors whom I consider to be "blank slates" and are thus quite adept at falling into and being believable in whatever role is given to them. I thought Brando in particular was sublime as the about-to-retire psychiatrist who appears to be rudderless regarding his impending life of retirement. Johnny Depp's character has some really beautifully-written lines, most of which are quoted on this site, from which we as men and husbands could learn a thing or two. Yes, it's plot is totally implausible but I'm begging you to buy in to the premise and let yourself get lost for a little while. I promise you that you will be holding your wife's hand almost before you know it!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Despite a rather dopey plot, it's enjoyable because of a couple nice performances.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you've ever seen the Joanne Woodward and George C. Scott film "They Might Be Giants", then you'll no doubt recognize this plot in "Don Juan DeMarco". The film begins with Johnny Depp making a sexual conquest in modern day America---yet he THINKS he's the legendary lover Don Juan. Later, when this lover suddenly is found contemplating suicide, an aging psychiatrist (Marlon Brando) is called in to help. Not surprisingly, Don Juan DeMarco is committed to the institution where Brando works and Brando fights hard to get assigned him as a patient--even though he's due to retire very soon. The Doctor tries hard as he works with his new patient NOT to medicate him. After all, the Doc LIKES hearing all of his patient's weird stories of love, sex and adventure. And, through the course of the film, DeMarco starts rubbing off on his doctor--to the delight of the man's wife! Johnny Depp is very nice playing a suave Latin lover and Brando is really good because he seems nice and relaxed. My only big complaint is not them but the bafflingly stupid ending. Really. Up until then, I could suspend disbelief and enjoy the film, but the ending really left me shocked at its silliness. Still, worth a look.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Silly Accent, Done-To-Death Plot, Great Actors with No Roles to Play
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    good-decision
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was very disappointed in this movie. I rented it with such great expectations from a movie that has Marlon Brando and Johnny Depp in one and in the same movie. Alas, there was nothing but flat characters, the silliest accent I have ever heard an actor come up with, and suspension of disbelief was so hard I had to call a friend to moan what a silly movie it was. In fact was it not for my love for both Marlon and Depp I would have given it a zero! In an interview with the Actor's Studio, Depp said that the hardest thing about acting with Brando was trying to keep a straight face. I imagine Brando knew from the get go that the movie was a joke.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Another Quirky Movies from Depp
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    princebansal1982
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Johnny Depp has made a career of doing quirky movies. This is a charming, soft, quirky movie ideal for a lazy afternoon. Just go without any expectations. It is about a young man who thinks he is Don Juan DeMarco and his interactions with his psychiatrist who is trying to cure him. Though it is not really clear whether he is really delusional or not, it doesn't matters really. It is more about his exploits true or imagined, then anything else. It is about living life on your own terms. While the movie wasn't really very realistic it was pleasant, not recommended for those who try to fit every movie into a genre.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of Depp's most underrated movies. Funny, heartwarming and creative.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    callanvass
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    (Credit IMDb) A young man (who is the legendary Don Juan?), comes to New York in search of his lost love. Feeling like he has nothing to live for, he attempts to commit suicide from atop a billboard. Dr. Mickler is a soon retiring psychiatrist who helps Don Juan, come to his senses. He brings the costumed boy to the psychiatric hospital , in hopes of helping Don Juan find his identity. The doctor works with him for ten days, in which Don tells his life story. Mickler begins to believe that the young man is truly Don Juan, but the rest of the staff doesn't agree. The doctor knows that the only way out for Don Juan, is to pretend he's an average boy whose fantasy got the best of him. This isn't really talked about as one of Depp's best movies, but it sure should be. What I liked most about this movie was the eccentricity. Depp's character has it in spades. The movie was smart to have us wondering if De Marco was delusional about his story or if he was telling the truth. We never really know throughout the movie, but I loved the way they decided to end it. The scenery itself is beautiful. Performances. Johnny Depp can do no wrong in my eyes. 95% of the time he is bang on, and here is no different. He is so good, we aren't ever really sure if he's crazy or not. His chemistry with Brando is on the money. Marlon Brando is not a favorite of mine but he excelled here. He is wonderfully classy, and I loved his old-school approach. Faye Dunnaway is charming in her screen time. Bottom line. It's a wonderful little treat of a movie, one that is severely underrated on Depp's resume. It's not about if it was real or not, it's about what I learned. A must see in my books. 9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Don Not Di Recto (DVD)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leplatypus
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have got mixed feelings about this movie. It has everything to be a hit: Coppola at the production, a great song of the duo Adams / Kamen (better than their Robin Hood hit), the finest French Actress (Pailhas), the most talented of the new generation (Deep) and of the old generation (Brando, Dunaway) and a very romantic and original story (it's not easy to make out what's reality and what's fantasy, thus having set the movie in the psychiatric world is brilliant). For sure, having Brando finding his youth again is moving, because as he was such a tremendous actor, this movie has surely talked to him: retirement is coming, is love doomed then ? I am amazed how he can be younger actually in this movie than while he was playing old Vito Corleone. But as I watched it, I found it dull. I think the culprit is found in the writer/director Leven because he gives us a cold soup with all those tasteful components: Then, beware of Leven because he can't level up a movie! in addition, i have got only french version so i lost all the original voices!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very satisfying movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lise-93
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After watching this movie I sat at least 5 minutes with a smile on my face. It's an original movie, not a standard romantic comedy. Johnny Depp is excellent, I could not imagine a better actor for the part. And also Marlon Brando and Faye Dunaway are great as the couple that had been together very long, and find their passion again. I love the fact that in the end you still don't really know what the truth is, I think this is the best way to end the movie. The whole atmosphere of the movie is very nice, the music and sets are beautiful and really make the movie even better. It's not like other romantic comedy's just about finding love, it actually has a deeper story, the story that it doesn't really matter whether what you believe is reality or not, just as long as you believe it. I give this movie 9 out of 10, 'cause I definitely want to see it again.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just enjoy !!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    redx1708
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Great Picture. Maybe not a masterpiece...(well, probably not), but nonetheless a completely joyful experience. The question whether Depps story is fact or fiction is really really neither here nor there. If it's not true, it bloody well should be !! lol. And if the story doesn't catch you, the performances should. Marlon Brando and Johnny Depp. Each one among the greatest actors of their generations. What a pleasure to Watch them working together. This is what acting is all about. They both shine as does Faye Dunaway (wow, she's still a beauty). And while the movie won't be considered among the highlights of their careers, I'll still highly recommend it to all movie lovers.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Don Juan DeMarco Will Put The Viewer Into An Amorous Mood
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Don Juan DeMarco is a romantic comedy starring Johnny Depp as John Arnold DeMarco, a man who believes himself to be Don Juan, the greatest lover in the world. Clad in a cape and domino mask, DeMarco undergoes psychiatric treatment with Marlon Brando's character, Dr. Jack Mickler, to cure him of his apparent delusion. But the psychiatric sessions have an unexpected effect on the psychiatric staff, some of whom find themselves inspired by DeMarco's delusion; the most profoundly affected is Dr. Mickler himself, who rekindles the romance in his complacent marriage.The movie also stars Faye Dunaway.The movie is based on two different sources: the modern-day story is based on director/screenwriter Jeremy Leven's short story Don Juan DeMarco and the Centerfold and the familiar legend of Don Juan,wherein flashbacks depicting DeMarco's back-story are based on. In the movie,a psychiatrist treats a most unusual patient, only to find that the doctor is the one who gains the most from their sessions. A young man in a mask and cape is standing atop a billboard, threatening to jump. When the potential suicide is finally talked down, he's brought to a psychiatric facility where after one doctor washes his hands of the case, he's placed under the supervision of Dr. Jack Mickler, an aging psychiatrist soon to retire. The patient informs Mickler that he is actually the great lover Don Juan, who has seduced over 1,500 women, but has fallen into a deep depression after being unable to win the hand of the woman of his dreams. Mickler has ten days to work with his patient and after which he will either be released on medication or committed to a long-term stay in a mental hospital. As Mickler talks with the young man, who speaks rapturously of the art of love, the doctor finds that his philosophies are helping to kick start his failing relationship with his wife, and he slowly becomes convinced that his patient might really be Don Juan after all. Walking a fine line between precious comedy, wistful drama, and delicate fantasy, it gets a big dose of charm from its esteemed cast, with Johnny Depp delivering dialogue that would have sounded ludicrous from a lesser actor.While the performances by Marlon Brando and Faye Dunaway elevate this likable comedy about love, illusion and delusion way above its inconsequential text.This may not be a great movie, but it is guaranteed to put you in an amorous mood.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Johnny Depp + Marlon Brando... What did you expect?!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ludovico Giannotti
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie as incredible and can't believe it's low rating on here. Johnny Depp puts in a very good performance and so does Marlon Brando, in portraying a beautiful story, very touching and moving. I just liked the movie in all it's aspects. The film seems superficial and banal but it has a fairly deep underlying theme about love and its philosophy. I would definitely recommend this movie to everybody as it is really good and entertaining. It is a film for everybody, young and the older will both find it very interesting and captivating so don't watch the low score and just go watch it: it is amazing! x
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Sweet Must-See Movies for Lovers!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mlzema
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I recently watched this one again after having not seen it in quite a while and I was pleasantly surprised to find that it was still one of the sweetest little movies I have ever seen, and for a person of my cynical nature that is really saying something. One of the secrets of this movie is the casting of Brando and Depp, two actors whom I consider to be "blank slates" and are thus quite adept at falling into and being believable in whatever role is given to them. I thought Brando in particular was sublime as the about-to-retire psychiatrist who appears to be rudderless regarding his impending life of retirement. Johnny Depp's character has some really beautifully-written lines, most of which are quoted on this site, from which we as men and husbands could learn a thing or two. Yes, it's plot is totally implausible but I'm begging you to buy in to the premise and let yourself get lost for a little while. I promise you that you will be holding your wife's hand almost before you know it!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Despite a rather dopey plot, it's enjoyable because of a couple nice performances.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you've ever seen the Joanne Woodward and George C. Scott film "They Might Be Giants", then you'll no doubt recognize this plot in "Don Juan DeMarco". The film begins with Johnny Depp making a sexual conquest in modern day America---yet he THINKS he's the legendary lover Don Juan. Later, when this lover suddenly is found contemplating suicide, an aging psychiatrist (Marlon Brando) is called in to help. Not surprisingly, Don Juan DeMarco is committed to the institution where Brando works and Brando fights hard to get assigned him as a patient--even though he's due to retire very soon. The Doctor tries hard as he works with his new patient NOT to medicate him. After all, the Doc LIKES hearing all of his patient's weird stories of love, sex and adventure. And, through the course of the film, DeMarco starts rubbing off on his doctor--to the delight of the man's wife! Johnny Depp is very nice playing a suave Latin lover and Brando is really good because he seems nice and relaxed. My only big complaint is not them but the bafflingly stupid ending. Really. Up until then, I could suspend disbelief and enjoy the film, but the ending really left me shocked at its silliness. Still, worth a look.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Silly Accent, Done-To-Death Plot, Great Actors with No Roles to Play
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    good-decision
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was very disappointed in this movie. I rented it with such great expectations from a movie that has Marlon Brando and Johnny Depp in one and in the same movie. Alas, there was nothing but flat characters, the silliest accent I have ever heard an actor come up with, and suspension of disbelief was so hard I had to call a friend to moan what a silly movie it was. In fact was it not for my love for both Marlon and Depp I would have given it a zero! In an interview with the Actor's Studio, Depp said that the hardest thing about acting with Brando was trying to keep a straight face. I imagine Brando knew from the get go that the movie was a joke.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Another Quirky Movies from Depp
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    princebansal1982
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Johnny Depp has made a career of doing quirky movies. This is a charming, soft, quirky movie ideal for a lazy afternoon. Just go without any expectations. It is about a young man who thinks he is Don Juan DeMarco and his interactions with his psychiatrist who is trying to cure him. Though it is not really clear whether he is really delusional or not, it doesn't matters really. It is more about his exploits true or imagined, then anything else. It is about living life on your own terms. While the movie wasn't really very realistic it was pleasant, not recommended for those who try to fit every movie into a genre.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of Depp's most underrated movies. Funny, heartwarming and creative.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    callanvass
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    (Credit IMDb) A young man (who is the legendary Don Juan?), comes to New York in search of his lost love. Feeling like he has nothing to live for, he attempts to commit suicide from atop a billboard. Dr. Mickler is a soon retiring psychiatrist who helps Don Juan, come to his senses. He brings the costumed boy to the psychiatric hospital , in hopes of helping Don Juan find his identity. The doctor works with him for ten days, in which Don tells his life story. Mickler begins to believe that the young man is truly Don Juan, but the rest of the staff doesn't agree. The doctor knows that the only way out for Don Juan, is to pretend he's an average boy whose fantasy got the best of him. This isn't really talked about as one of Depp's best movies, but it sure should be. What I liked most about this movie was the eccentricity. Depp's character has it in spades. The movie was smart to have us wondering if De Marco was delusional about his story or if he was telling the truth. We never really know throughout the movie, but I loved the way they decided to end it. The scenery itself is beautiful. Performances. Johnny Depp can do no wrong in my eyes. 95% of the time he is bang on, and here is no different. He is so good, we aren't ever really sure if he's crazy or not. His chemistry with Brando is on the money. Marlon Brando is not a favorite of mine but he excelled here. He is wonderfully classy, and I loved his old-school approach. Faye Dunnaway is charming in her screen time. Bottom line. It's a wonderful little treat of a movie, one that is severely underrated on Depp's resume. It's not about if it was real or not, it's about what I learned. A must see in my books. 9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Don Not Di Recto (DVD)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leplatypus
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have got mixed feelings about this movie. It has everything to be a hit: Coppola at the production, a great song of the duo Adams / Kamen (better than their Robin Hood hit), the finest French Actress (Pailhas), the most talented of the new generation (Deep) and of the old generation (Brando, Dunaway) and a very romantic and original story (it's not easy to make out what's reality and what's fantasy, thus having set the movie in the psychiatric world is brilliant). For sure, having Brando finding his youth again is moving, because as he was such a tremendous actor, this movie has surely talked to him: retirement is coming, is love doomed then ? I am amazed how he can be younger actually in this movie than while he was playing old Vito Corleone. But as I watched it, I found it dull. I think the culprit is found in the writer/director Leven because he gives us a cold soup with all those tasteful components: Then, beware of Leven because he can't level up a movie! in addition, i have got only french version so i lost all the original voices!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very satisfying movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lise-93
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After watching this movie I sat at least 5 minutes with a smile on my face. It's an original movie, not a standard romantic comedy. Johnny Depp is excellent, I could not imagine a better actor for the part. And also Marlon Brando and Faye Dunaway are great as the couple that had been together very long, and find their passion again. I love the fact that in the end you still don't really know what the truth is, I think this is the best way to end the movie. The whole atmosphere of the movie is very nice, the music and sets are beautiful and really make the movie even better. It's not like other romantic comedy's just about finding love, it actually has a deeper story, the story that it doesn't really matter whether what you believe is reality or not, just as long as you believe it. I give this movie 9 out of 10, 'cause I definitely want to see it again.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just enjoy !!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    redx1708
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Great Picture. Maybe not a masterpiece...(well, probably not), but nonetheless a completely joyful experience. The question whether Depps story is fact or fiction is really really neither here nor there. If it's not true, it bloody well should be !! lol. And if the story doesn't catch you, the performances should. Marlon Brando and Johnny Depp. Each one among the greatest actors of their generations. What a pleasure to Watch them working together. This is what acting is all about. They both shine as does Faye Dunaway (wow, she's still a beauty). And while the movie won't be considered among the highlights of their careers, I'll still highly recommend it to all movie lovers.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Don Juan DeMarco Will Put The Viewer Into An Amorous Mood
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Don Juan DeMarco is a romantic comedy starring Johnny Depp as John Arnold DeMarco, a man who believes himself to be Don Juan, the greatest lover in the world. Clad in a cape and domino mask, DeMarco undergoes psychiatric treatment with Marlon Brando's character, Dr. Jack Mickler, to cure him of his apparent delusion. But the psychiatric sessions have an unexpected effect on the psychiatric staff, some of whom find themselves inspired by DeMarco's delusion; the most profoundly affected is Dr. Mickler himself, who rekindles the romance in his complacent marriage.The movie also stars Faye Dunaway.The movie is based on two different sources: the modern-day story is based on director/screenwriter Jeremy Leven's short story Don Juan DeMarco and the Centerfold and the familiar legend of Don Juan,wherein flashbacks depicting DeMarco's back-story are based on. In the movie,a psychiatrist treats a most unusual patient, only to find that the doctor is the one who gains the most from their sessions. A young man in a mask and cape is standing atop a billboard, threatening to jump. When the potential suicide is finally talked down, he's brought to a psychiatric facility where after one doctor washes his hands of the case, he's placed under the supervision of Dr. Jack Mickler, an aging psychiatrist soon to retire. The patient informs Mickler that he is actually the great lover Don Juan, who has seduced over 1,500 women, but has fallen into a deep depression after being unable to win the hand of the woman of his dreams. Mickler has ten days to work with his patient and after which he will either be released on medication or committed to a long-term stay in a mental hospital. As Mickler talks with the young man, who speaks rapturously of the art of love, the doctor finds that his philosophies are helping to kick start his failing relationship with his wife, and he slowly becomes convinced that his patient might really be Don Juan after all. Walking a fine line between precious comedy, wistful drama, and delicate fantasy, it gets a big dose of charm from its esteemed cast, with Johnny Depp delivering dialogue that would have sounded ludicrous from a lesser actor.While the performances by Marlon Brando and Faye Dunaway elevate this likable comedy about love, illusion and delusion way above its inconsequential text.This may not be a great movie, but it is guaranteed to put you in an amorous mood.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Johnny Depp + Marlon Brando... What did you expect?!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ludovico Giannotti
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie as incredible and can't believe it's low rating on here. Johnny Depp puts in a very good performance and so does Marlon Brando, in portraying a beautiful story, very touching and moving. I just liked the movie in all it's aspects. The film seems superficial and banal but it has a fairly deep underlying theme about love and its philosophy. I would definitely recommend this movie to everybody as it is really good and entertaining. It is a film for everybody, young and the older will both find it very interesting and captivating so don't watch the low score and just go watch it: it is amazing! x
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Sweet Must-See Movies for Lovers!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mlzema
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I recently watched this one again after having not seen it in quite a while and I was pleasantly surprised to find that it was still one of the sweetest little movies I have ever seen, and for a person of my cynical nature that is really saying something. One of the secrets of this movie is the casting of Brando and Depp, two actors whom I consider to be "blank slates" and are thus quite adept at falling into and being believable in whatever role is given to them. I thought Brando in particular was sublime as the about-to-retire psychiatrist who appears to be rudderless regarding his impending life of retirement. Johnny Depp's character has some really beautifully-written lines, most of which are quoted on this site, from which we as men and husbands could learn a thing or two. Yes, it's plot is totally implausible but I'm begging you to buy in to the premise and let yourself get lost for a little while. I promise you that you will be holding your wife's hand almost before you know it!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Despite a rather dopey plot, it's enjoyable because of a couple nice performances.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you've ever seen the Joanne Woodward and George C. Scott film "They Might Be Giants", then you'll no doubt recognize this plot in "Don Juan DeMarco". The film begins with Johnny Depp making a sexual conquest in modern day America---yet he THINKS he's the legendary lover Don Juan. Later, when this lover suddenly is found contemplating suicide, an aging psychiatrist (Marlon Brando) is called in to help. Not surprisingly, Don Juan DeMarco is committed to the institution where Brando works and Brando fights hard to get assigned him as a patient--even though he's due to retire very soon. The Doctor tries hard as he works with his new patient NOT to medicate him. After all, the Doc LIKES hearing all of his patient's weird stories of love, sex and adventure. And, through the course of the film, DeMarco starts rubbing off on his doctor--to the delight of the man's wife! Johnny Depp is very nice playing a suave Latin lover and Brando is really good because he seems nice and relaxed. My only big complaint is not them but the bafflingly stupid ending. Really. Up until then, I could suspend disbelief and enjoy the film, but the ending really left me shocked at its silliness. Still, worth a look.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Silly Accent, Done-To-Death Plot, Great Actors with No Roles to Play
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    good-decision
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was very disappointed in this movie. I rented it with such great expectations from a movie that has Marlon Brando and Johnny Depp in one and in the same movie. Alas, there was nothing but flat characters, the silliest accent I have ever heard an actor come up with, and suspension of disbelief was so hard I had to call a friend to moan what a silly movie it was. In fact was it not for my love for both Marlon and Depp I would have given it a zero! In an interview with the Actor's Studio, Depp said that the hardest thing about acting with Brando was trying to keep a straight face. I imagine Brando knew from the get go that the movie was a joke.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Another Quirky Movies from Depp
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    princebansal1982
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Johnny Depp has made a career of doing quirky movies. This is a charming, soft, quirky movie ideal for a lazy afternoon. Just go without any expectations. It is about a young man who thinks he is Don Juan DeMarco and his interactions with his psychiatrist who is trying to cure him. Though it is not really clear whether he is really delusional or not, it doesn't matters really. It is more about his exploits true or imagined, then anything else. It is about living life on your own terms. While the movie wasn't really very realistic it was pleasant, not recommended for those who try to fit every movie into a genre.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of Depp's most underrated movies. Funny, heartwarming and creative.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    callanvass
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    (Credit IMDb) A young man (who is the legendary Don Juan?), comes to New York in search of his lost love. Feeling like he has nothing to live for, he attempts to commit suicide from atop a billboard. Dr. Mickler is a soon retiring psychiatrist who helps Don Juan, come to his senses. He brings the costumed boy to the psychiatric hospital , in hopes of helping Don Juan find his identity. The doctor works with him for ten days, in which Don tells his life story. Mickler begins to believe that the young man is truly Don Juan, but the rest of the staff doesn't agree. The doctor knows that the only way out for Don Juan, is to pretend he's an average boy whose fantasy got the best of him. This isn't really talked about as one of Depp's best movies, but it sure should be. What I liked most about this movie was the eccentricity. Depp's character has it in spades. The movie was smart to have us wondering if De Marco was delusional about his story or if he was telling the truth. We never really know throughout the movie, but I loved the way they decided to end it. The scenery itself is beautiful. Performances. Johnny Depp can do no wrong in my eyes. 95% of the time he is bang on, and here is no different. He is so good, we aren't ever really sure if he's crazy or not. His chemistry with Brando is on the money. Marlon Brando is not a favorite of mine but he excelled here. He is wonderfully classy, and I loved his old-school approach. Faye Dunnaway is charming in her screen time. Bottom line. It's a wonderful little treat of a movie, one that is severely underrated on Depp's resume. It's not about if it was real or not, it's about what I learned. A must see in my books. 9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Don Not Di Recto (DVD)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leplatypus
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have got mixed feelings about this movie. It has everything to be a hit: Coppola at the production, a great song of the duo Adams / Kamen (better than their Robin Hood hit), the finest French Actress (Pailhas), the most talented of the new generation (Deep) and of the old generation (Brando, Dunaway) and a very romantic and original story (it's not easy to make out what's reality and what's fantasy, thus having set the movie in the psychiatric world is brilliant). For sure, having Brando finding his youth again is moving, because as he was such a tremendous actor, this movie has surely talked to him: retirement is coming, is love doomed then ? I am amazed how he can be younger actually in this movie than while he was playing old Vito Corleone. But as I watched it, I found it dull. I think the culprit is found in the writer/director Leven because he gives us a cold soup with all those tasteful components: Then, beware of Leven because he can't level up a movie! in addition, i have got only french version so i lost all the original voices!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very satisfying movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lise-93
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After watching this movie I sat at least 5 minutes with a smile on my face. It's an original movie, not a standard romantic comedy. Johnny Depp is excellent, I could not imagine a better actor for the part. And also Marlon Brando and Faye Dunaway are great as the couple that had been together very long, and find their passion again. I love the fact that in the end you still don't really know what the truth is, I think this is the best way to end the movie. The whole atmosphere of the movie is very nice, the music and sets are beautiful and really make the movie even better. It's not like other romantic comedy's just about finding love, it actually has a deeper story, the story that it doesn't really matter whether what you believe is reality or not, just as long as you believe it. I give this movie 9 out of 10, 'cause I definitely want to see it again.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Just enjoy !!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    redx1708
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Great Picture. Maybe not a masterpiece...(well, probably not), but nonetheless a completely joyful experience. The question whether Depps story is fact or fiction is really really neither here nor there. If it's not true, it bloody well should be !! lol. And if the story doesn't catch you, the performances should. Marlon Brando and Johnny Depp. Each one among the greatest actors of their generations. What a pleasure to Watch them working together. This is what acting is all about. They both shine as does Faye Dunaway (wow, she's still a beauty). And while the movie won't be considered among the highlights of their careers, I'll still highly recommend it to all movie lovers.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Don Juan DeMarco Will Put The Viewer Into An Amorous Mood
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    SiliconDesertMan40
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Don Juan DeMarco is a romantic comedy starring Johnny Depp as John Arnold DeMarco, a man who believes himself to be Don Juan, the greatest lover in the world. Clad in a cape and domino mask, DeMarco undergoes psychiatric treatment with Marlon Brando's character, Dr. Jack Mickler, to cure him of his apparent delusion. But the psychiatric sessions have an unexpected effect on the psychiatric staff, some of whom find themselves inspired by DeMarco's delusion; the most profoundly affected is Dr. Mickler himself, who rekindles the romance in his complacent marriage.The movie also stars Faye Dunaway.The movie is based on two different sources: the modern-day story is based on director/screenwriter Jeremy Leven's short story Don Juan DeMarco and the Centerfold and the familiar legend of Don Juan,wherein flashbacks depicting DeMarco's back-story are based on. In the movie,a psychiatrist treats a most unusual patient, only to find that the doctor is the one who gains the most from their sessions. A young man in a mask and cape is standing atop a billboard, threatening to jump. When the potential suicide is finally talked down, he's brought to a psychiatric facility where after one doctor washes his hands of the case, he's placed under the supervision of Dr. Jack Mickler, an aging psychiatrist soon to retire. The patient informs Mickler that he is actually the great lover Don Juan, who has seduced over 1,500 women, but has fallen into a deep depression after being unable to win the hand of the woman of his dreams. Mickler has ten days to work with his patient and after which he will either be released on medication or committed to a long-term stay in a mental hospital. As Mickler talks with the young man, who speaks rapturously of the art of love, the doctor finds that his philosophies are helping to kick start his failing relationship with his wife, and he slowly becomes convinced that his patient might really be Don Juan after all. Walking a fine line between precious comedy, wistful drama, and delicate fantasy, it gets a big dose of charm from its esteemed cast, with Johnny Depp delivering dialogue that would have sounded ludicrous from a lesser actor.While the performances by Marlon Brando and Faye Dunaway elevate this likable comedy about love, illusion and delusion way above its inconsequential text.This may not be a great movie, but it is guaranteed to put you in an amorous mood.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Johnny Depp + Marlon Brando... What did you expect?!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Ludovico Giannotti
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie as incredible and can't believe it's low rating on here. Johnny Depp puts in a very good performance and so does Marlon Brando, in portraying a beautiful story, very touching and moving. I just liked the movie in all it's aspects. The film seems superficial and banal but it has a fairly deep underlying theme about love and its philosophy. I would definitely recommend this movie to everybody as it is really good and entertaining. It is a film for everybody, young and the older will both find it very interesting and captivating so don't watch the low score and just go watch it: it is amazing! x
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Sweet Must-See Movies for Lovers!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    mlzema
   </autor>
   <data>
    15/9/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I recently watched this one again after having not seen it in quite a while and I was pleasantly surprised to find that it was still one of the sweetest little movies I have ever seen, and for a person of my cynical nature that is really saying something. One of the secrets of this movie is the casting of Brando and Depp, two actors whom I consider to be "blank slates" and are thus quite adept at falling into and being believable in whatever role is given to them. I thought Brando in particular was sublime as the about-to-retire psychiatrist who appears to be rudderless regarding his impending life of retirement. Johnny Depp's character has some really beautifully-written lines, most of which are quoted on this site, from which we as men and husbands could learn a thing or two. Yes, it's plot is totally implausible but I'm begging you to buy in to the premise and let yourself get lost for a little while. I promise you that you will be holding your wife's hand almost before you know it!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Despite a rather dopey plot, it's enjoyable because of a couple nice performances.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    planktonrules
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If you've ever seen the Joanne Woodward and George C. Scott film "They Might Be Giants", then you'll no doubt recognize this plot in "Don Juan DeMarco". The film begins with Johnny Depp making a sexual conquest in modern day America---yet he THINKS he's the legendary lover Don Juan. Later, when this lover suddenly is found contemplating suicide, an aging psychiatrist (Marlon Brando) is called in to help. Not surprisingly, Don Juan DeMarco is committed to the institution where Brando works and Brando fights hard to get assigned him as a patient--even though he's due to retire very soon. The Doctor tries hard as he works with his new patient NOT to medicate him. After all, the Doc LIKES hearing all of his patient's weird stories of love, sex and adventure. And, through the course of the film, DeMarco starts rubbing off on his doctor--to the delight of the man's wife! Johnny Depp is very nice playing a suave Latin lover and Brando is really good because he seems nice and relaxed. My only big complaint is not them but the bafflingly stupid ending. Really. Up until then, I could suspend disbelief and enjoy the film, but the ending really left me shocked at its silliness. Still, worth a look.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Silly Accent, Done-To-Death Plot, Great Actors with No Roles to Play
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    good-decision
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was very disappointed in this movie. I rented it with such great expectations from a movie that has Marlon Brando and Johnny Depp in one and in the same movie. Alas, there was nothing but flat characters, the silliest accent I have ever heard an actor come up with, and suspension of disbelief was so hard I had to call a friend to moan what a silly movie it was. In fact was it not for my love for both Marlon and Depp I would have given it a zero! In an interview with the Actor's Studio, Depp said that the hardest thing about acting with Brando was trying to keep a straight face. I imagine Brando knew from the get go that the movie was a joke.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Another Quirky Movies from Depp
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    princebansal1982
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Johnny Depp has made a career of doing quirky movies. This is a charming, soft, quirky movie ideal for a lazy afternoon. Just go without any expectations. It is about a young man who thinks he is Don Juan DeMarco and his interactions with his psychiatrist who is trying to cure him. Though it is not really clear whether he is really delusional or not, it doesn't matters really. It is more about his exploits true or imagined, then anything else. It is about living life on your own terms. While the movie wasn't really very realistic it was pleasant, not recommended for those who try to fit every movie into a genre.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of Depp's most underrated movies. Funny, heartwarming and creative.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    callanvass
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/3/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    (Credit IMDb) A young man (who is the legendary Don Juan?), comes to New York in search of his lost love. Feeling like he has nothing to live for, he attempts to commit suicide from atop a billboard. Dr. Mickler is a soon retiring psychiatrist who helps Don Juan, come to his senses. He brings the costumed boy to the psychiatric hospital , in hopes of helping Don Juan find his identity. The doctor works with him for ten days, in which Don tells his life story. Mickler begins to believe that the young man is truly Don Juan, but the rest of the staff doesn't agree. The doctor knows that the only way out for Don Juan, is to pretend he's an average boy whose fantasy got the best of him. This isn't really talked about as one of Depp's best movies, but it sure should be. What I liked most about this movie was the eccentricity. Depp's character has it in spades. The movie was smart to have us wondering if De Marco was delusional about his story or if he was telling the truth. We never really know throughout the movie, but I loved the way they decided to end it. The scenery itself is beautiful. Performances. Johnny Depp can do no wrong in my eyes. 95% of the time he is bang on, and here is no different. He is so good, we aren't ever really sure if he's crazy or not. His chemistry with Brando is on the money. Marlon Brando is not a favorite of mine but he excelled here. He is wonderfully classy, and I loved his old-school approach. Faye Dunnaway is charming in her screen time. Bottom line. It's a wonderful little treat of a movie, one that is severely underrated on Depp's resume. It's not about if it was real or not, it's about what I learned. A must see in my books. 9/10
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Don Not Di Recto (DVD)
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    leplatypus
   </autor>
   <data>
    9/11/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I have got mixed feelings about this movie. It has everything to be a hit: Coppola at the production, a great song of the duo Adams / Kamen (better than their Robin Hood hit), the finest French Actress (Pailhas), the most talented of the new generation (Deep) and of the old generation (Brando, Dunaway) and a very romantic and original story (it's not easy to make out what's reality and what's fantasy, thus having set the movie in the psychiatric world is brilliant). For sure, having Brando finding his youth again is moving, because as he was such a tremendous actor, this movie has surely talked to him: retirement is coming, is love doomed then ? I am amazed how he can be younger actually in this movie than while he was playing old Vito Corleone. But as I watched it, I found it dull. I think the culprit is found in the writer/director Leven because he gives us a cold soup with all those tasteful components: Then, beware of Leven because he can't level up a movie! in addition, i have got only french version so i lost all the original voices!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Very satisfying movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lise-93
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/2/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    After watching this movie I sat at least 5 minutes with a smile on my face. It's an original movie, not a standard romantic comedy. Johnny Depp is excellent, I could not imagine a better actor for the part. And also Marlon Brando and Faye Dunaway are great as the couple that had been together very long, and find their passion again. I love the fact that in the end you still don't really know what the truth is, I think this is the best way to end the movie. The whole atmosphere of the movie is very nice, the music and sets are beautiful and really make the movie even better. It's not like other romantic comedy's just about finding love, it actually has a deeper story, the story that it doesn't really matter whether what you believe is reality or not, just as long as you believe it. I give this movie 9 out of 10, 'cause I definitely want to see it again.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
