<filme>
 <id>
  783
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0110516
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1994
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  As Apar&ecirc;ncias Enganam
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  5.2
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Young Frank and his pals get an idea for the ultimate in excitement. They decide to pool their savings, bicycle to the nearby Big City, and hire some woman of the streets to strip for them.... &nbsp;&raquo;
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Young Frank and his pals get an idea for the ultimate in excitement. They decide to pool their savings, bicycle to the nearby Big City, and hire some woman of the streets to strip for them. Things do not work out that simply, but they do meet V, a Hooker With A Heart Of Gold, who ends up giving them a ride home. Soon she is living in Frank's treehouse, unbeknownst to Frank's widowed father Tom, who thinks she is one of Frank's teachers. Soon, however, the evil Waltzer comes looking for V.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Romance
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   treehouse
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   hooker
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   gangster
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   female removes her dress
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   suburbia
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Richard Benjamin
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   John Mattson
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Melanie Griffith
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Ed Harris
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Michael Patrick Carter
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    milk money is worth your money
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    froberts73-379-217403
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Milk Money," every now and then looked like it was landing in the land of sleaze. It came close but never really crossed the line. Add to that no cuss words, no nudity, and a quickie anti-smoking message. Considering the theme - a trio of boys grabbing their milk money for a quick look at a naked lady - the pic was relatively PGish. It was at times funny, at times warm and, at all times thoroughly enjoyable. The youngster was delightful, Ed Harris was quite good, but Melanie Griffith out-prosted Julia Roberts. Her portrayal of the age old prosty with a heart of gold was dead on. All in all, unless you are totally nervous about the theme, I can guarantee much enjoyment
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Excellent Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David_Brown
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I simply cannot believe some of the reviews of this film. Two people view it through the liberal vs conservative prism, others compare it to "Pretty Woman", and one person actually thinks the money burned in the car. It is obvious none of these people actually saw the film, because they would know it is not about politics, "V" (Melanie Griffith) did not end up with a rich person (Like Julia Robers did in "Pretty Woman."), and the money did not burn in a car. What this film is about very lonely, desperate people who are living a very sad, pathetic life, and through fate in the end found happiness. (Major Spoilers Ahead). What actually happened was after getting permission from the local Godfather Jerry The Pope (Phillip Bosco), to exit the prostitution business, "V" was leaving her drab apartment, and heading for places unknown, and as she was closing the door, spotted a bag with a lightening bolt, and found the money inside and because of it, was able to rescue herself, and purchase an environmental sensitive portion of land and gave it to Ed Harris, who was heartbroken over losing "V" and having developers ruin the wetland. As "V" says at the end of the film, 'The way to capture a woman is through her heart.", and because of that, will stay in the town to be with Tom (Ed Harris) & help take care of Frank (Michael Patrick Carter), while owning and running the ice cream shop where she first met Frank. ps. I am very politically conservative, and hate liberal propaganda, and this film is not about that trust me. 10/10 Stars
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Old Fashioned Romantic Comedy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Isaac5855
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/6/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    MILK MONEY is a lovely and sentimental romantic comedy about a precocious pre-teen who decides to set up his widowed father with a warm-hearted prostitute, who is on the run from some bad people. This film is a warm slice of contemporary Americana, beautifully conveying small town sensibilities and their positive and negative effects on the fictional hamlet of Middleton. The story is simple (though it does take Dad a little too long to figure out what this girl does for a living)and the environmental subplot is underdeveloped, but the movie is filled with believable characters and funny scenes, including one very funny scene where the boy uses the hooker as a visual aide for a school project on the female anatomy. Melanie Griffith shines in a tailor-made role as V,the proverbial hooker-with-a-heart-of-gold, in her most appealing performance since WORKING GIRL and Ed Harris is charming and sexy as the dad. Michael Patrick Carter is utterly charming as the boy and Malcolm McDowell and Anne Heche offer funny supporting turns as a gangster and his ditzy moll, V's best friend. An entertaining romantic comedy that's beauty lies in its simplicity.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    In some cases better then...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    steff-50
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/11/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In some cases I'd say this is better then Pretty Woman. I say "some" with weight because Pretty Woman is a classic. But Milk Money fills that "hole" you had watching pretty woman. Ed Harris's character is sincere and attentive which matches Melanie's softness (which at the best of times can spoil her on screen performances) perfectly. It's a classic boy meets girl movie with that dash of "damsel in distress but is now hardened and tough due to life being so rough and who now finally meets a man who breaks through it all and understands and loves her for who she is" - as far as romantic comedies go- it was better then I thought it would be and even gets the heart strings welling when Ed Harris tells her "this could hurt"...The story itself can be at times almost childish, but in the end that's part of it's charm.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wrong-turn girl gets a chance of living a TV-life
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Minted_Lamb
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/1/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Melannie finds her life as a hooker is much over-rated with a nasty pimp ripping-off his mob-associates & finding herself accused of stealing the missing money. Escaping to the suburbs she finds life as a future step-mom is just like that portrayed on TV. Helping the son of the bloke she has taken a shine to pass his school-biology presentation her past life catches-up when a former client recognises Melannie & demands her services. Unaware the stolen money is hidden in the car she is driving Melannie has no way to prove her innocence to her pimps mob-associates or rumoured mob-boss under pressure from the media leading to a life on-the-run.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hollywood's Twisted Values - Exhibit A
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ccthemovieman-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/10/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie SO typifies Hollywood. We get (1) another prostitute who is gorgeous, sweet and with a heart of gold. (2) the prostitutes are nothing but victims of the cruel and abusive male pimps; (3) kids ages 10-12 are obsessed with sex (I'm talking about how Hollwyood sees the culture); (4) there are few higher callings than being a tree-hugger, this one chaining himself to a tree to save some wetlands. On and on and on it goes in ultra-Liberal, politically-correct, morally-clueless Hollywood. Well, to be fair, the movie did have lots of charm and it's always nice to see Ed Harris actually play against type, meaning play a decent human being. Melanie Griffith never looked better, either. Too bad the story was so stupid and insulting.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    some things we milk for all that they're worth
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw "Milk Money" when I was eleven; much of what happens in the movie is the sort of stuff that would make any eleven-year-old boy think "Whoa...cool!" Looking back on it, I still think that it was pretty funny, but was it the most mature movie? No, and it doesn't pretend to be. I read somewhere that this movie was sexist; I wouldn't know one way or the other. All that I interpreted was that the movie was a nice, horny excuse to have fun. Richard Benjamin has proved himself to be quite capable as a director, and this adds to that. I know, the prostitute-with-a-heart-of-gold context is a clich&eacute;, but this is a comedy, so it passes. And believe you me, this V (Melanie Griffith) is definitely a V for vendetta! Also starring Ed Harris, Malcolm McDowell, Casey Siemaszko, and a very young Anne Heche. Really entertaining, especially the report on the female reproductive system.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Lots of Comedy & Fun
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    whpratt1
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/7/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Melanie Griffith,(V) played a woman of the streets who meets up with three boys who want to see what a girl looks like in the nude. Of course, if they really wanted to do it the correct way, they could ask their dad's and possibly their mothers. However, this is a Hollywood film and it made the entire story quite funny, especially when they have a sex education class and decided to use a rather non-kosher way of presenting the facts. Ed Harris,(Tom Wheeler) plays the father to Michael Patrick Carter,(Frank Wheeler) who gets to be good friends with Melanie Griffith and introduces her to his father. This is a very entertaining film and you can find fault with this film whether you are on the left or right side in life, but comedy and laughs are good for everyone and I recommend this film for great viewing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pretty woman meets the suburbs
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lkmpullum
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I liked the movie. There were really excellently staged scenes in the movie with the child actors and they provide a great way to keep the plot moving and giving the audience information that we might not pick up on. The kids in this movie also become more aware of the world around them than the adults, whom seem too naive to realize that Melanie Griffith is a hooker. There are also some great tongue in check moments between Griffith and Ed Harris before everything hits the fan about Griffith being a hooker. Though many may feel that there are too many plot twists involved in this movie the writer and director do an excellent job of weaving them all together in a way that makes the audience want to believe that this could happen. I like to think of this movie as Pretty Woman meets the suburbs, but I realize that some Julia Roberts fanatics may strongly disagree.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Wonderful Movie!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sela Freuler
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/7/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I LOVED this movie, all of those bad reviews you've just read are completely wrong. It is so sweet, and realistic when it comes to the terrible reality of the modern-day slaves: prostitutes. It was wonderful that they showed that "hookers" are really human, despite their less-than-normal job. The little boy, Frank, was adorable in everything he did, the actor who played him was wonderful. It was heart-warming to see just how much he cared for V, even though he knew what she did for a living. I would have my kids see this movie if I had kids; it has underlying morals, such as anti-prejudice and the like. This movie definitely deserves a ten!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    milk money is worth your money
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    froberts73-379-217403
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Milk Money," every now and then looked like it was landing in the land of sleaze. It came close but never really crossed the line. Add to that no cuss words, no nudity, and a quickie anti-smoking message. Considering the theme - a trio of boys grabbing their milk money for a quick look at a naked lady - the pic was relatively PGish. It was at times funny, at times warm and, at all times thoroughly enjoyable. The youngster was delightful, Ed Harris was quite good, but Melanie Griffith out-prosted Julia Roberts. Her portrayal of the age old prosty with a heart of gold was dead on. All in all, unless you are totally nervous about the theme, I can guarantee much enjoyment
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Excellent Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David_Brown
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I simply cannot believe some of the reviews of this film. Two people view it through the liberal vs conservative prism, others compare it to "Pretty Woman", and one person actually thinks the money burned in the car. It is obvious none of these people actually saw the film, because they would know it is not about politics, "V" (Melanie Griffith) did not end up with a rich person (Like Julia Robers did in "Pretty Woman."), and the money did not burn in a car. What this film is about very lonely, desperate people who are living a very sad, pathetic life, and through fate in the end found happiness. (Major Spoilers Ahead). What actually happened was after getting permission from the local Godfather Jerry The Pope (Phillip Bosco), to exit the prostitution business, "V" was leaving her drab apartment, and heading for places unknown, and as she was closing the door, spotted a bag with a lightening bolt, and found the money inside and because of it, was able to rescue herself, and purchase an environmental sensitive portion of land and gave it to Ed Harris, who was heartbroken over losing "V" and having developers ruin the wetland. As "V" says at the end of the film, 'The way to capture a woman is through her heart.", and because of that, will stay in the town to be with Tom (Ed Harris) & help take care of Frank (Michael Patrick Carter), while owning and running the ice cream shop where she first met Frank. ps. I am very politically conservative, and hate liberal propaganda, and this film is not about that trust me. 10/10 Stars
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Old Fashioned Romantic Comedy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Isaac5855
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/6/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    MILK MONEY is a lovely and sentimental romantic comedy about a precocious pre-teen who decides to set up his widowed father with a warm-hearted prostitute, who is on the run from some bad people. This film is a warm slice of contemporary Americana, beautifully conveying small town sensibilities and their positive and negative effects on the fictional hamlet of Middleton. The story is simple (though it does take Dad a little too long to figure out what this girl does for a living)and the environmental subplot is underdeveloped, but the movie is filled with believable characters and funny scenes, including one very funny scene where the boy uses the hooker as a visual aide for a school project on the female anatomy. Melanie Griffith shines in a tailor-made role as V,the proverbial hooker-with-a-heart-of-gold, in her most appealing performance since WORKING GIRL and Ed Harris is charming and sexy as the dad. Michael Patrick Carter is utterly charming as the boy and Malcolm McDowell and Anne Heche offer funny supporting turns as a gangster and his ditzy moll, V's best friend. An entertaining romantic comedy that's beauty lies in its simplicity.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    In some cases better then...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    steff-50
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/11/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In some cases I'd say this is better then Pretty Woman. I say "some" with weight because Pretty Woman is a classic. But Milk Money fills that "hole" you had watching pretty woman. Ed Harris's character is sincere and attentive which matches Melanie's softness (which at the best of times can spoil her on screen performances) perfectly. It's a classic boy meets girl movie with that dash of "damsel in distress but is now hardened and tough due to life being so rough and who now finally meets a man who breaks through it all and understands and loves her for who she is" - as far as romantic comedies go- it was better then I thought it would be and even gets the heart strings welling when Ed Harris tells her "this could hurt"...The story itself can be at times almost childish, but in the end that's part of it's charm.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wrong-turn girl gets a chance of living a TV-life
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Minted_Lamb
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/1/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Melannie finds her life as a hooker is much over-rated with a nasty pimp ripping-off his mob-associates & finding herself accused of stealing the missing money. Escaping to the suburbs she finds life as a future step-mom is just like that portrayed on TV. Helping the son of the bloke she has taken a shine to pass his school-biology presentation her past life catches-up when a former client recognises Melannie & demands her services. Unaware the stolen money is hidden in the car she is driving Melannie has no way to prove her innocence to her pimps mob-associates or rumoured mob-boss under pressure from the media leading to a life on-the-run.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hollywood's Twisted Values - Exhibit A
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ccthemovieman-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/10/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie SO typifies Hollywood. We get (1) another prostitute who is gorgeous, sweet and with a heart of gold. (2) the prostitutes are nothing but victims of the cruel and abusive male pimps; (3) kids ages 10-12 are obsessed with sex (I'm talking about how Hollwyood sees the culture); (4) there are few higher callings than being a tree-hugger, this one chaining himself to a tree to save some wetlands. On and on and on it goes in ultra-Liberal, politically-correct, morally-clueless Hollywood. Well, to be fair, the movie did have lots of charm and it's always nice to see Ed Harris actually play against type, meaning play a decent human being. Melanie Griffith never looked better, either. Too bad the story was so stupid and insulting.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    some things we milk for all that they're worth
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw "Milk Money" when I was eleven; much of what happens in the movie is the sort of stuff that would make any eleven-year-old boy think "Whoa...cool!" Looking back on it, I still think that it was pretty funny, but was it the most mature movie? No, and it doesn't pretend to be. I read somewhere that this movie was sexist; I wouldn't know one way or the other. All that I interpreted was that the movie was a nice, horny excuse to have fun. Richard Benjamin has proved himself to be quite capable as a director, and this adds to that. I know, the prostitute-with-a-heart-of-gold context is a clich&eacute;, but this is a comedy, so it passes. And believe you me, this V (Melanie Griffith) is definitely a V for vendetta! Also starring Ed Harris, Malcolm McDowell, Casey Siemaszko, and a very young Anne Heche. Really entertaining, especially the report on the female reproductive system.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Lots of Comedy & Fun
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    whpratt1
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/7/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Melanie Griffith,(V) played a woman of the streets who meets up with three boys who want to see what a girl looks like in the nude. Of course, if they really wanted to do it the correct way, they could ask their dad's and possibly their mothers. However, this is a Hollywood film and it made the entire story quite funny, especially when they have a sex education class and decided to use a rather non-kosher way of presenting the facts. Ed Harris,(Tom Wheeler) plays the father to Michael Patrick Carter,(Frank Wheeler) who gets to be good friends with Melanie Griffith and introduces her to his father. This is a very entertaining film and you can find fault with this film whether you are on the left or right side in life, but comedy and laughs are good for everyone and I recommend this film for great viewing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pretty woman meets the suburbs
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lkmpullum
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I liked the movie. There were really excellently staged scenes in the movie with the child actors and they provide a great way to keep the plot moving and giving the audience information that we might not pick up on. The kids in this movie also become more aware of the world around them than the adults, whom seem too naive to realize that Melanie Griffith is a hooker. There are also some great tongue in check moments between Griffith and Ed Harris before everything hits the fan about Griffith being a hooker. Though many may feel that there are too many plot twists involved in this movie the writer and director do an excellent job of weaving them all together in a way that makes the audience want to believe that this could happen. I like to think of this movie as Pretty Woman meets the suburbs, but I realize that some Julia Roberts fanatics may strongly disagree.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Wonderful Movie!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sela Freuler
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/7/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I LOVED this movie, all of those bad reviews you've just read are completely wrong. It is so sweet, and realistic when it comes to the terrible reality of the modern-day slaves: prostitutes. It was wonderful that they showed that "hookers" are really human, despite their less-than-normal job. The little boy, Frank, was adorable in everything he did, the actor who played him was wonderful. It was heart-warming to see just how much he cared for V, even though he knew what she did for a living. I would have my kids see this movie if I had kids; it has underlying morals, such as anti-prejudice and the like. This movie definitely deserves a ten!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    milk money is worth your money
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    froberts73-379-217403
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Milk Money," every now and then looked like it was landing in the land of sleaze. It came close but never really crossed the line. Add to that no cuss words, no nudity, and a quickie anti-smoking message. Considering the theme - a trio of boys grabbing their milk money for a quick look at a naked lady - the pic was relatively PGish. It was at times funny, at times warm and, at all times thoroughly enjoyable. The youngster was delightful, Ed Harris was quite good, but Melanie Griffith out-prosted Julia Roberts. Her portrayal of the age old prosty with a heart of gold was dead on. All in all, unless you are totally nervous about the theme, I can guarantee much enjoyment
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Excellent Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David_Brown
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I simply cannot believe some of the reviews of this film. Two people view it through the liberal vs conservative prism, others compare it to "Pretty Woman", and one person actually thinks the money burned in the car. It is obvious none of these people actually saw the film, because they would know it is not about politics, "V" (Melanie Griffith) did not end up with a rich person (Like Julia Robers did in "Pretty Woman."), and the money did not burn in a car. What this film is about very lonely, desperate people who are living a very sad, pathetic life, and through fate in the end found happiness. (Major Spoilers Ahead). What actually happened was after getting permission from the local Godfather Jerry The Pope (Phillip Bosco), to exit the prostitution business, "V" was leaving her drab apartment, and heading for places unknown, and as she was closing the door, spotted a bag with a lightening bolt, and found the money inside and because of it, was able to rescue herself, and purchase an environmental sensitive portion of land and gave it to Ed Harris, who was heartbroken over losing "V" and having developers ruin the wetland. As "V" says at the end of the film, 'The way to capture a woman is through her heart.", and because of that, will stay in the town to be with Tom (Ed Harris) & help take care of Frank (Michael Patrick Carter), while owning and running the ice cream shop where she first met Frank. ps. I am very politically conservative, and hate liberal propaganda, and this film is not about that trust me. 10/10 Stars
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Old Fashioned Romantic Comedy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Isaac5855
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/6/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    MILK MONEY is a lovely and sentimental romantic comedy about a precocious pre-teen who decides to set up his widowed father with a warm-hearted prostitute, who is on the run from some bad people. This film is a warm slice of contemporary Americana, beautifully conveying small town sensibilities and their positive and negative effects on the fictional hamlet of Middleton. The story is simple (though it does take Dad a little too long to figure out what this girl does for a living)and the environmental subplot is underdeveloped, but the movie is filled with believable characters and funny scenes, including one very funny scene where the boy uses the hooker as a visual aide for a school project on the female anatomy. Melanie Griffith shines in a tailor-made role as V,the proverbial hooker-with-a-heart-of-gold, in her most appealing performance since WORKING GIRL and Ed Harris is charming and sexy as the dad. Michael Patrick Carter is utterly charming as the boy and Malcolm McDowell and Anne Heche offer funny supporting turns as a gangster and his ditzy moll, V's best friend. An entertaining romantic comedy that's beauty lies in its simplicity.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    In some cases better then...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    steff-50
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/11/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In some cases I'd say this is better then Pretty Woman. I say "some" with weight because Pretty Woman is a classic. But Milk Money fills that "hole" you had watching pretty woman. Ed Harris's character is sincere and attentive which matches Melanie's softness (which at the best of times can spoil her on screen performances) perfectly. It's a classic boy meets girl movie with that dash of "damsel in distress but is now hardened and tough due to life being so rough and who now finally meets a man who breaks through it all and understands and loves her for who she is" - as far as romantic comedies go- it was better then I thought it would be and even gets the heart strings welling when Ed Harris tells her "this could hurt"...The story itself can be at times almost childish, but in the end that's part of it's charm.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wrong-turn girl gets a chance of living a TV-life
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Minted_Lamb
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/1/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Melannie finds her life as a hooker is much over-rated with a nasty pimp ripping-off his mob-associates & finding herself accused of stealing the missing money. Escaping to the suburbs she finds life as a future step-mom is just like that portrayed on TV. Helping the son of the bloke she has taken a shine to pass his school-biology presentation her past life catches-up when a former client recognises Melannie & demands her services. Unaware the stolen money is hidden in the car she is driving Melannie has no way to prove her innocence to her pimps mob-associates or rumoured mob-boss under pressure from the media leading to a life on-the-run.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hollywood's Twisted Values - Exhibit A
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ccthemovieman-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/10/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie SO typifies Hollywood. We get (1) another prostitute who is gorgeous, sweet and with a heart of gold. (2) the prostitutes are nothing but victims of the cruel and abusive male pimps; (3) kids ages 10-12 are obsessed with sex (I'm talking about how Hollwyood sees the culture); (4) there are few higher callings than being a tree-hugger, this one chaining himself to a tree to save some wetlands. On and on and on it goes in ultra-Liberal, politically-correct, morally-clueless Hollywood. Well, to be fair, the movie did have lots of charm and it's always nice to see Ed Harris actually play against type, meaning play a decent human being. Melanie Griffith never looked better, either. Too bad the story was so stupid and insulting.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    some things we milk for all that they're worth
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw "Milk Money" when I was eleven; much of what happens in the movie is the sort of stuff that would make any eleven-year-old boy think "Whoa...cool!" Looking back on it, I still think that it was pretty funny, but was it the most mature movie? No, and it doesn't pretend to be. I read somewhere that this movie was sexist; I wouldn't know one way or the other. All that I interpreted was that the movie was a nice, horny excuse to have fun. Richard Benjamin has proved himself to be quite capable as a director, and this adds to that. I know, the prostitute-with-a-heart-of-gold context is a clich&eacute;, but this is a comedy, so it passes. And believe you me, this V (Melanie Griffith) is definitely a V for vendetta! Also starring Ed Harris, Malcolm McDowell, Casey Siemaszko, and a very young Anne Heche. Really entertaining, especially the report on the female reproductive system.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Lots of Comedy & Fun
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    whpratt1
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/7/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Melanie Griffith,(V) played a woman of the streets who meets up with three boys who want to see what a girl looks like in the nude. Of course, if they really wanted to do it the correct way, they could ask their dad's and possibly their mothers. However, this is a Hollywood film and it made the entire story quite funny, especially when they have a sex education class and decided to use a rather non-kosher way of presenting the facts. Ed Harris,(Tom Wheeler) plays the father to Michael Patrick Carter,(Frank Wheeler) who gets to be good friends with Melanie Griffith and introduces her to his father. This is a very entertaining film and you can find fault with this film whether you are on the left or right side in life, but comedy and laughs are good for everyone and I recommend this film for great viewing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pretty woman meets the suburbs
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lkmpullum
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I liked the movie. There were really excellently staged scenes in the movie with the child actors and they provide a great way to keep the plot moving and giving the audience information that we might not pick up on. The kids in this movie also become more aware of the world around them than the adults, whom seem too naive to realize that Melanie Griffith is a hooker. There are also some great tongue in check moments between Griffith and Ed Harris before everything hits the fan about Griffith being a hooker. Though many may feel that there are too many plot twists involved in this movie the writer and director do an excellent job of weaving them all together in a way that makes the audience want to believe that this could happen. I like to think of this movie as Pretty Woman meets the suburbs, but I realize that some Julia Roberts fanatics may strongly disagree.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Wonderful Movie!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sela Freuler
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/7/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I LOVED this movie, all of those bad reviews you've just read are completely wrong. It is so sweet, and realistic when it comes to the terrible reality of the modern-day slaves: prostitutes. It was wonderful that they showed that "hookers" are really human, despite their less-than-normal job. The little boy, Frank, was adorable in everything he did, the actor who played him was wonderful. It was heart-warming to see just how much he cared for V, even though he knew what she did for a living. I would have my kids see this movie if I had kids; it has underlying morals, such as anti-prejudice and the like. This movie definitely deserves a ten!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    milk money is worth your money
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    froberts73-379-217403
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/7/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    "Milk Money," every now and then looked like it was landing in the land of sleaze. It came close but never really crossed the line. Add to that no cuss words, no nudity, and a quickie anti-smoking message. Considering the theme - a trio of boys grabbing their milk money for a quick look at a naked lady - the pic was relatively PGish. It was at times funny, at times warm and, at all times thoroughly enjoyable. The youngster was delightful, Ed Harris was quite good, but Melanie Griffith out-prosted Julia Roberts. Her portrayal of the age old prosty with a heart of gold was dead on. All in all, unless you are totally nervous about the theme, I can guarantee much enjoyment
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Excellent Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    David_Brown
   </autor>
   <data>
    22/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I simply cannot believe some of the reviews of this film. Two people view it through the liberal vs conservative prism, others compare it to "Pretty Woman", and one person actually thinks the money burned in the car. It is obvious none of these people actually saw the film, because they would know it is not about politics, "V" (Melanie Griffith) did not end up with a rich person (Like Julia Robers did in "Pretty Woman."), and the money did not burn in a car. What this film is about very lonely, desperate people who are living a very sad, pathetic life, and through fate in the end found happiness. (Major Spoilers Ahead). What actually happened was after getting permission from the local Godfather Jerry The Pope (Phillip Bosco), to exit the prostitution business, "V" was leaving her drab apartment, and heading for places unknown, and as she was closing the door, spotted a bag with a lightening bolt, and found the money inside and because of it, was able to rescue herself, and purchase an environmental sensitive portion of land and gave it to Ed Harris, who was heartbroken over losing "V" and having developers ruin the wetland. As "V" says at the end of the film, 'The way to capture a woman is through her heart.", and because of that, will stay in the town to be with Tom (Ed Harris) & help take care of Frank (Michael Patrick Carter), while owning and running the ice cream shop where she first met Frank. ps. I am very politically conservative, and hate liberal propaganda, and this film is not about that trust me. 10/10 Stars
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Old Fashioned Romantic Comedy
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Isaac5855
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/6/2008
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    MILK MONEY is a lovely and sentimental romantic comedy about a precocious pre-teen who decides to set up his widowed father with a warm-hearted prostitute, who is on the run from some bad people. This film is a warm slice of contemporary Americana, beautifully conveying small town sensibilities and their positive and negative effects on the fictional hamlet of Middleton. The story is simple (though it does take Dad a little too long to figure out what this girl does for a living)and the environmental subplot is underdeveloped, but the movie is filled with believable characters and funny scenes, including one very funny scene where the boy uses the hooker as a visual aide for a school project on the female anatomy. Melanie Griffith shines in a tailor-made role as V,the proverbial hooker-with-a-heart-of-gold, in her most appealing performance since WORKING GIRL and Ed Harris is charming and sexy as the dad. Michael Patrick Carter is utterly charming as the boy and Malcolm McDowell and Anne Heche offer funny supporting turns as a gangster and his ditzy moll, V's best friend. An entertaining romantic comedy that's beauty lies in its simplicity.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    In some cases better then...
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    steff-50
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/11/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In some cases I'd say this is better then Pretty Woman. I say "some" with weight because Pretty Woman is a classic. But Milk Money fills that "hole" you had watching pretty woman. Ed Harris's character is sincere and attentive which matches Melanie's softness (which at the best of times can spoil her on screen performances) perfectly. It's a classic boy meets girl movie with that dash of "damsel in distress but is now hardened and tough due to life being so rough and who now finally meets a man who breaks through it all and understands and loves her for who she is" - as far as romantic comedies go- it was better then I thought it would be and even gets the heart strings welling when Ed Harris tells her "this could hurt"...The story itself can be at times almost childish, but in the end that's part of it's charm.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Wrong-turn girl gets a chance of living a TV-life
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Minted_Lamb
   </autor>
   <data>
    23/1/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Melannie finds her life as a hooker is much over-rated with a nasty pimp ripping-off his mob-associates & finding herself accused of stealing the missing money. Escaping to the suburbs she finds life as a future step-mom is just like that portrayed on TV. Helping the son of the bloke she has taken a shine to pass his school-biology presentation her past life catches-up when a former client recognises Melannie & demands her services. Unaware the stolen money is hidden in the car she is driving Melannie has no way to prove her innocence to her pimps mob-associates or rumoured mob-boss under pressure from the media leading to a life on-the-run.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Hollywood's Twisted Values - Exhibit A
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ccthemovieman-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/10/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie SO typifies Hollywood. We get (1) another prostitute who is gorgeous, sweet and with a heart of gold. (2) the prostitutes are nothing but victims of the cruel and abusive male pimps; (3) kids ages 10-12 are obsessed with sex (I'm talking about how Hollwyood sees the culture); (4) there are few higher callings than being a tree-hugger, this one chaining himself to a tree to save some wetlands. On and on and on it goes in ultra-Liberal, politically-correct, morally-clueless Hollywood. Well, to be fair, the movie did have lots of charm and it's always nice to see Ed Harris actually play against type, meaning play a decent human being. Melanie Griffith never looked better, either. Too bad the story was so stupid and insulting.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    some things we milk for all that they're worth
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/9/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I saw "Milk Money" when I was eleven; much of what happens in the movie is the sort of stuff that would make any eleven-year-old boy think "Whoa...cool!" Looking back on it, I still think that it was pretty funny, but was it the most mature movie? No, and it doesn't pretend to be. I read somewhere that this movie was sexist; I wouldn't know one way or the other. All that I interpreted was that the movie was a nice, horny excuse to have fun. Richard Benjamin has proved himself to be quite capable as a director, and this adds to that. I know, the prostitute-with-a-heart-of-gold context is a clich&eacute;, but this is a comedy, so it passes. And believe you me, this V (Melanie Griffith) is definitely a V for vendetta! Also starring Ed Harris, Malcolm McDowell, Casey Siemaszko, and a very young Anne Heche. Really entertaining, especially the report on the female reproductive system.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Lots of Comedy & Fun
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    whpratt1
   </autor>
   <data>
    26/7/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Melanie Griffith,(V) played a woman of the streets who meets up with three boys who want to see what a girl looks like in the nude. Of course, if they really wanted to do it the correct way, they could ask their dad's and possibly their mothers. However, this is a Hollywood film and it made the entire story quite funny, especially when they have a sex education class and decided to use a rather non-kosher way of presenting the facts. Ed Harris,(Tom Wheeler) plays the father to Michael Patrick Carter,(Frank Wheeler) who gets to be good friends with Melanie Griffith and introduces her to his father. This is a very entertaining film and you can find fault with this film whether you are on the left or right side in life, but comedy and laughs are good for everyone and I recommend this film for great viewing.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Pretty woman meets the suburbs
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    lkmpullum
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/7/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I liked the movie. There were really excellently staged scenes in the movie with the child actors and they provide a great way to keep the plot moving and giving the audience information that we might not pick up on. The kids in this movie also become more aware of the world around them than the adults, whom seem too naive to realize that Melanie Griffith is a hooker. There are also some great tongue in check moments between Griffith and Ed Harris before everything hits the fan about Griffith being a hooker. Though many may feel that there are too many plot twists involved in this movie the writer and director do an excellent job of weaving them all together in a way that makes the audience want to believe that this could happen. I like to think of this movie as Pretty Woman meets the suburbs, but I realize that some Julia Roberts fanatics may strongly disagree.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A Wonderful Movie!!!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sela Freuler
   </autor>
   <data>
    1/7/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I LOVED this movie, all of those bad reviews you've just read are completely wrong. It is so sweet, and realistic when it comes to the terrible reality of the modern-day slaves: prostitutes. It was wonderful that they showed that "hookers" are really human, despite their less-than-normal job. The little boy, Frank, was adorable in everything he did, the actor who played him was wonderful. It was heart-warming to see just how much he cared for V, even though he knew what she did for a living. I would have my kids see this movie if I had kids; it has underlying morals, such as anti-prejudice and the like. This movie definitely deserves a ten!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
