<filme>
 <id>
  789
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0114594
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1994
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  O Pre&ccedil;o da Ambi&ccedil;&atilde;o
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  7.0
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  A young, naive Hollywood studio assistant finally turns the tables on his incredibly abusive producer boss.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  A young Hollywood executive becomes the assistant to a big time movie producer who is the worst boss imaginable: abusive, abrasive and cruel. But soon things turn around when the young executive kidnaps his boss and visits all the cruelties back on him.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Crime
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   boss
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   assistant
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   movie producer
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   torture
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   revenge
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   George Huang
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   George Huang
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Kevin Spacey
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Frank Whaley
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Michelle Forbes
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If You Ever Worked in Hollywood, You May Relate to this Fantasy of a Minno Getting Revenge on a Shark
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    classicalsteve
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Because the Hollywood industry is saturated with those who dream of being on the "inside", some people at the higher levels abuse their positions of power. Some of these regard themselves as the equivalent of demi-gods or priest-like figures, guarding the gates of the temple of the film/entertainment industry. They expect to be worshiped or at least revered, allowing the initiated to pass through. Those who are given a chance to become initiates are sometimes subjected to a kind of hazing process in which the poor initiate is subjected to the whims of the high elites. Kevin Spacey plays Buddy Ackerman, the perfect Hollywood shark, a studio executive who believes everything he says and does should be viewed as "gospel" by those who work under him. Guy (Frank Whaley) is his new assistant, or better stated, his new whipping boy. Guy is greener than an unripe tomato, replacing Rex (Benicio del Toro) of whom Buddy says "is a good for nothing mongoloid" on the first day. But before the first day is over, Guy realizes that this is going to be long term abuse. Spacey makes the perfect vain studio executive. One of the best aspects of his performance is that he wavers between seeming reasonable than flying into rages which would give your average wolverine a runs for its money. He berates Guy for giving him the wrong artificial sweetener. He throws books and papers at him. Even occasionally food. He even makes his assistant embark on impossible tasks, such as destroying every single copy of a Time Magazine issue which contained a scathing article about him. Ackerman's motto is "You are nothing. You're opinion means nothing". As book ends to the narrative, we flash to another part of the story: Guy has kidnapped Ackerman and has tied him. He's torturing him as payback. But the abuse is not the only reason Guy wants Buddy to suffer. As bad as Guy's mistreatment, the worst aspect is the executive's habit of taking credit for the deeds of others. In a poignant scene, Ackerman pretends to praise Guy to another executive, but Guy realizes it was false. A very interesting film, mostly for those who have either worked for or been associated with ego-maniacs. The movie industry is chock full of people who believe they are above everyone else because of certain successes. This gives some of them license to abuse others, particularly because so many desire what few positions are available. As Buddy himself says "Life is not a movie. Good guys lose, everybody lies, and love... does not conquer all."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    tongue in cheek brilliance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    charles-okell
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Its so very quotable and finds Spacey in fine form - "my pencil eraser means more to me than you do" has been uttered often by all my team in the studio! Given it has got low production values, the lighting is grainy and their attention to continuity is poor rather than 'on purpose' it does have a jovial, dark hummer that is much more widely accessible than say the likes of Anchor Man which was equally low budget relying on star quality. Do give it a go with friends and a few beers, it improves the experience no end and then watch Horrible Bosses, 21, Casino Jack and hope that Spacey churns the same character out at least a few more times before he disappears into the artistic roles his Thespian bent so clearly desires - he is a film treasure, under utilized and always great in a film... even when the film is rubbish (Casino Jack....)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Kevin Spacey always puts on a great performance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    T Cady
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of those movies where a great actor turns a run of the mill film into a good one. Kevin Spacey is just the sort of actor that always seems to do that. "Swimming with Sharks," is the story of a young man, Guy ( Frank Whaley), who is determined to make his mark in the Movie industry. He lands a job as the assistant to big time Hollywood executive, Buddy Ackerman (Kevin Spacey), and thinks he has the start to launch him into the big time. It turns out that Buddy is not only a bigshot executive but also makes ridiculous demands, and is a downright cruel demanding boss, that seems to have no regard for his assistant or anyone for that matter. How far can Buddy push Guy until he snaps? This is not a new story line, it has been done time after time, but it is a horrible boss story, so everyone can relate to it. I am not a fan of Frank Whaley and actually can't stand him, but he does a decent job in this one. As I said this movie wasn't very original and I probably wouldn't have liked this movie at all if it wasn't for Kevin Spacey. Kevin Spacey did a great job portraying the evil, demanding boss.In my mind, he was what made this movie. Everything in this movie says boring and done before, but Kevin Spacey's performance turns it into a good movie. It's rare that one actor could do that by himself but in this case it is true. Not to reveal anything, but the end takes a twist that is actually a pretty good one. So overall, it was a good movie, not a great one. Spacey turns out to be the only one driving it, but somehow it was enough to make it watchable and at times enjoyable. Like my reviews, hate em? Any questions or comments, or if you want a DVD reviewed just shoot me an e-mail at: subliminal.lithium@gmail.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Here's to all the schmucks who can't tell Sweet'n Low from Equal
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steve Pulaski
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Kevin Spacey, more often than not, gets handed the sharpest, funniest, cleverest, most desirable monologues in his roles. In Glengarry Glen Ross, he delivered cold lines of fury when talking to his deadbeat employees and took some severe blows to the ego when he was jabbed with personal insults. In American Beauty, it was entrancing to hear him narrate his story with such gratitude and depth, along with giving us one of the best performances of the decade. And in K-PAX, he convincingly played an alleged extraterrestrial who seemed to appear out of thin air and turn a skeptical psychiatrist into a true believer. The man is a treasure often shorthanded and under-valued. Spacey gives yet another fantastic performance of true power and control in Swimming With Sharks, a black comedy that is heavy on the laughs and insight, and easy on the levels of conformity and monotony. This is a biting drama of business and progress in the work world, with some of the toughest and most brutal insight into the corporate world that can only be compared to the level of truths brought in Kevin Smith's Clerks and Mike Judge's Office Space. This deserves a spot in the same league. Guy (Frank Whaley) is a young writer who is extremely satisfied to get a job working as the assistant for movie mogul Buddy Ackerman, played by Kevin Spacey. Guy expects the job to be beneficial and insightful, until he sees Buddy's true side, which is loud, obnoxious, pretentious, smothering, overbearing, and just plain unforgiving behavior as he takes pride in being belligerent and disrespectful to his assistants. In an extremely well written scene involving Guy trying to reason with Buddy about his yelling and his uncontrollable tirades, Buddy browbeats him relentlessly by telling him, "my bathmat means more to me than you," at the same time throwing pencils at him saying, "these pencils more important, these pens more important." The key to this scene is that both men have extremely valid points; Guy is trying to speak on a human-level with Buddy and brings up the idea of how in a business relationship, one must have the skill and ability to hold a grown-up discussion with one another. On the other hand, Buddy remarks on how you need to be a man to do the job and you must accept the torment as a means to get somewhere in the world. Further commentary is provided when we open up and see Buddy as more than a cynic, but how he got to be one and whether or not guy is on the same track heading to the same inevitable destination. The film is intercut with scenes showing Guy breaking in to Buddy's home, taking him hostage by tying him to his chair, and preceding to torture him mercilessly, reminding him of all the times he was demanding and ruthless to him. Again, the scene is not supposed to inspire moments of shock and jolts as it is to prove to the audience that both these men have perfectly valid points. Are Guy's actions justifiable? Yes, but they're not particularly right. Are Buddy's reasons for being mean and ruthless to his assistants justified? Yes, but they're not particularly right either. Writer/director George Huang wrote the film based off of what he experienced as an executive assistant at Columbia Pictures. Whether or not the acts he was involved in were this extreme or are fabricated to fit film's high standard I can not say, but Huang clearly knows what aspiring young cinephiles (or just business man on the lowest step of the corporate ladder) must go through and put up with in order to make it big. Where Huang scores effortlessly is in the writing, which is sharp, brutal, and all around satisfying. Seeing these men spit out some of the foulest things imaginable is unbelievably satisfying and is not only played for laughs but for intelligence. While the moments of darkness and subversive violence that are spliced in with the moments of typical office conundrums and tribulations may be a bit abrupt, they are nonetheless faithful and necessary to the film's point. I've always seen film as a device used to depict either morals, ideas, ideologies, places usually left unexplored, utopias, etc, but I've too seen it has a brilliant way to showcase events, lifestyles, and modern quirks. Swimming With Sharks is a brutally well written piece brilliantly taking us into the life of an overworked and under-appreciated businessman who is just looking for respect and fair treatment. Starring: Kevin Spacey and Frank Whaley. Directed by: George Huang.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One Man And His Dog
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    writers_reign
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If it turned out that Kevin Spacey paid the Producers to play this role I wouldn't be surprised given that it is an actor's dream role and one that makes Kirk Douglas's Jonathan Shields in The Bad And The Beautiful seem like a wimp. Douglas himself, who revelled in playing characters like this would have probably gone to the mat with Robert Ryan to play Buddy Ackerman had this film been written when Douglas and Ryan were in their heyday. As it is Spacey hits one out of the park without even trying and the best thing is that there is fine support from the other two leads. Cyanide-laced screenplays about Hollywood are not exactly thin on the ground - we can cite, in chronological order, Sunset Boulevard, The Bad And The Beautiful and Cliff Odets' The Big Knife off the top of our heads and they all appeared within six years of each other in the fifties. Swimming With Sharks may lack the skillful screenplays all three boasted but it is still well worth a look.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Outstanding film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tpaladino
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was originally led to believe (via my Netflix queue) that Swimming With Sharks would be a (dark) comedy. And while there are certain moments of humor, this film is firmly planted in drama territory. But, no matter what label they give it, the film is excellent and very much worth watching. The writing is sharp and interesting, and Spacey and the small cast do a great job with it. It's a very small movie, comprised of a very few actors and locations, but never feels small, thanks to the great depth that the characters are given, as well as the engrossing story. I don't want to reveal too much about the plot, but sufficed to say, it explores the dysfunctional and often tragic professional relationships that are abundant in Hollywood, and the extreme ends that an otherwise reasonable individual can be pushed to. Worth watching for sure.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great flick!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jerry-peanu
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ackerman obviously has problems or he wouldn't be acting quite in the way that he is, but director George Huang and Spacey are also careful to show that Ackerman has a lot more going on than surface behavior--he's acting the way that he is purposefully, both to get his due now as part of the establishment and to coyly manipulate his young, meek and abused underling, Guy (Frank Whaley), along with everyone else he comes into contact with. His aim is to mold Guy in a particular way--a way that works even though Guy thinks that he's severely breaking form in the extended penultimate scene that's intercut with Guy and Ackerman's history. Huang shows professional relationships as consisting mostly of politicking and manipulation. That's true at every level--certainly even Guy is doing this. There is very little authenticity to anyone in their working relationships. That seems pretty accurate to me, unfortunately. It's notable that the one dream of authenticity in the film--Guy talking about moving to Wyoming with Dawn (Michelle Forbes)--is treated and dispensed with as an unreachable fantasy, and it's also notable (and is fairly literally pointed out in the film) that Dawn, the one character who tries to demand being more authentic amidst the "shark infested waters" of the professional world, basically never gets anywhere. In the highly metaphorical ending of the film, things remain manipulative, political and backstabbing, and in that climate, at least two out of three characters "win". Huang seems to be suggesting that the professional world ain't likely to change any time soon, and that even if you try to change it or manipulate the game itself, you're likely to just get eaten up by it, processed by it and incorporated into it anyway. Again, I can't say I disagree with him.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Essay on the Origins of a Corporate Monster
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sean Lamberger
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Not entirely what you'd expect from the promo art, this strange hybrid of chilling suspense and black comedy bears a surprisingly deep, developed cast of characters and a bitter, intense message about the origins of a corporate monster. Kevin Spacey is at his usual best as the pompous, demeaning studio executive with a finger in every pie, while journeyman Frank Whaley (Brett from Pulp Fiction) overplays the wide-eyed, naive farmboy act as Spacey's hapless assistant at the edge. But while early scenes hint this is just another predictable, pull-for-the-little-man light comedy, the narrative's regular flashes forward in the timeline paint a larger, more sinister picture. When the dust settles, Spacey is revealed to be far more complicated and damaged than he lets on, Whaley has worked himself into a deep, dark pit of trouble and neither man is who they were at the outset. Bewildering at times due to the jolting changes in tone and atmosphere, it lingers with the viewer well after the credits have rolled.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Worth a watch
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    itamarscomix
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Swimming With Sharks is original and daring, but very uneven. I've always been a sucker for films about filmmaking and Hollywood and as such I was willing to let a lot slide, but it had a few too many ups and downs, starting out with a very problematic and ambiguous mix of comedy and tragedy; it then reaches its peak in the second half, when it turns more and more into a full drama; but then disappoints with the ending. And without that ending, it would have been a truly singular film. As it is, it's still an interesting one well worth a watch, if only for Kevin Spacey's performance in the second half, that turns from over-the-top ham to utter and nasty subtlety.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fanaticalaboutfilms Review: Swimming With Sharks
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    James (Fanaticalaboutfilms)
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Swimming With Sharks is set in the cut throat world of the film industry although this doesn't dictate the plot as much as you might think. It follows Guy (Frank Whaley) who is a clean-shaven enthusiastic new recruit into this unique world landing himself a job as the personal assistant to Buddy Ackerman (Kevin Spacey) an expletive throwing repugnant studio executive whose addition to your CV opens every door imaginable but is counteracted so much by his demeanour that many would find it not worth the trouble. Guy seems to have the determination to see it through helped by script writer and love interest Dawn (Michelle Forbes) but after working for the man for over a year, cracks begin to surface and Guy is finally pushed too far showing up at Buddy's home in the middle of the night intent on revenge. What plays out over the 100 minutes is a mixture between the past year of his life and the present unfolding situation. This was George Huang's first (and it would seem only notable) foray into the world of writing and directing and credit must be given to him. The script is impressive with Whaley engrossing himself into the character topped only by Spacey's exceptional performance where he looks set to star in a similar, albeit toned down, role in Horrible Bosses. He not only excels in many of his 'throwing a tantrum' scenes but somehow brings sympathy and compassion to a character that we should not feel anything for. Even when being held hostage he emits a certain smug arrogance that would be misplaced in any other character apart from this one. I felt conflicted given the knowledge at the beginning that Guy kidnaps his boss. It somewhat limits the sympathy you can show towards him regardless of finding out what Buddy did to drive him to such lengths. I wouldn't class this as a comedy per say as this is not going to have you laughing a great deal but rather an extremely dark satire of life in Hollywood and the means required to keep your head above the water. It shows us that the calling of the bright lights can change a man with only a few have what is required to make it. Add all of this together to an unexpected ending and it makes for an interesting watch. Yes there are moments where I felt things were not quite working and the relationship between Dawn and Guy lacked that believability factor but Swimming With Sharks certainly made the time fly and has enough to keep it fresh in the mind for a couple of days at the very least. For further reviews feel free to check out: http://www.fanaticalaboutfilms.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If You Ever Worked in Hollywood, You May Relate to this Fantasy of a Minno Getting Revenge on a Shark
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    classicalsteve
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Because the Hollywood industry is saturated with those who dream of being on the "inside", some people at the higher levels abuse their positions of power. Some of these regard themselves as the equivalent of demi-gods or priest-like figures, guarding the gates of the temple of the film/entertainment industry. They expect to be worshiped or at least revered, allowing the initiated to pass through. Those who are given a chance to become initiates are sometimes subjected to a kind of hazing process in which the poor initiate is subjected to the whims of the high elites. Kevin Spacey plays Buddy Ackerman, the perfect Hollywood shark, a studio executive who believes everything he says and does should be viewed as "gospel" by those who work under him. Guy (Frank Whaley) is his new assistant, or better stated, his new whipping boy. Guy is greener than an unripe tomato, replacing Rex (Benicio del Toro) of whom Buddy says "is a good for nothing mongoloid" on the first day. But before the first day is over, Guy realizes that this is going to be long term abuse. Spacey makes the perfect vain studio executive. One of the best aspects of his performance is that he wavers between seeming reasonable than flying into rages which would give your average wolverine a runs for its money. He berates Guy for giving him the wrong artificial sweetener. He throws books and papers at him. Even occasionally food. He even makes his assistant embark on impossible tasks, such as destroying every single copy of a Time Magazine issue which contained a scathing article about him. Ackerman's motto is "You are nothing. You're opinion means nothing". As book ends to the narrative, we flash to another part of the story: Guy has kidnapped Ackerman and has tied him. He's torturing him as payback. But the abuse is not the only reason Guy wants Buddy to suffer. As bad as Guy's mistreatment, the worst aspect is the executive's habit of taking credit for the deeds of others. In a poignant scene, Ackerman pretends to praise Guy to another executive, but Guy realizes it was false. A very interesting film, mostly for those who have either worked for or been associated with ego-maniacs. The movie industry is chock full of people who believe they are above everyone else because of certain successes. This gives some of them license to abuse others, particularly because so many desire what few positions are available. As Buddy himself says "Life is not a movie. Good guys lose, everybody lies, and love... does not conquer all."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    tongue in cheek brilliance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    charles-okell
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Its so very quotable and finds Spacey in fine form - "my pencil eraser means more to me than you do" has been uttered often by all my team in the studio! Given it has got low production values, the lighting is grainy and their attention to continuity is poor rather than 'on purpose' it does have a jovial, dark hummer that is much more widely accessible than say the likes of Anchor Man which was equally low budget relying on star quality. Do give it a go with friends and a few beers, it improves the experience no end and then watch Horrible Bosses, 21, Casino Jack and hope that Spacey churns the same character out at least a few more times before he disappears into the artistic roles his Thespian bent so clearly desires - he is a film treasure, under utilized and always great in a film... even when the film is rubbish (Casino Jack....)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Kevin Spacey always puts on a great performance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    T Cady
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of those movies where a great actor turns a run of the mill film into a good one. Kevin Spacey is just the sort of actor that always seems to do that. "Swimming with Sharks," is the story of a young man, Guy ( Frank Whaley), who is determined to make his mark in the Movie industry. He lands a job as the assistant to big time Hollywood executive, Buddy Ackerman (Kevin Spacey), and thinks he has the start to launch him into the big time. It turns out that Buddy is not only a bigshot executive but also makes ridiculous demands, and is a downright cruel demanding boss, that seems to have no regard for his assistant or anyone for that matter. How far can Buddy push Guy until he snaps? This is not a new story line, it has been done time after time, but it is a horrible boss story, so everyone can relate to it. I am not a fan of Frank Whaley and actually can't stand him, but he does a decent job in this one. As I said this movie wasn't very original and I probably wouldn't have liked this movie at all if it wasn't for Kevin Spacey. Kevin Spacey did a great job portraying the evil, demanding boss.In my mind, he was what made this movie. Everything in this movie says boring and done before, but Kevin Spacey's performance turns it into a good movie. It's rare that one actor could do that by himself but in this case it is true. Not to reveal anything, but the end takes a twist that is actually a pretty good one. So overall, it was a good movie, not a great one. Spacey turns out to be the only one driving it, but somehow it was enough to make it watchable and at times enjoyable. Like my reviews, hate em? Any questions or comments, or if you want a DVD reviewed just shoot me an e-mail at: subliminal.lithium@gmail.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Here's to all the schmucks who can't tell Sweet'n Low from Equal
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steve Pulaski
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Kevin Spacey, more often than not, gets handed the sharpest, funniest, cleverest, most desirable monologues in his roles. In Glengarry Glen Ross, he delivered cold lines of fury when talking to his deadbeat employees and took some severe blows to the ego when he was jabbed with personal insults. In American Beauty, it was entrancing to hear him narrate his story with such gratitude and depth, along with giving us one of the best performances of the decade. And in K-PAX, he convincingly played an alleged extraterrestrial who seemed to appear out of thin air and turn a skeptical psychiatrist into a true believer. The man is a treasure often shorthanded and under-valued. Spacey gives yet another fantastic performance of true power and control in Swimming With Sharks, a black comedy that is heavy on the laughs and insight, and easy on the levels of conformity and monotony. This is a biting drama of business and progress in the work world, with some of the toughest and most brutal insight into the corporate world that can only be compared to the level of truths brought in Kevin Smith's Clerks and Mike Judge's Office Space. This deserves a spot in the same league. Guy (Frank Whaley) is a young writer who is extremely satisfied to get a job working as the assistant for movie mogul Buddy Ackerman, played by Kevin Spacey. Guy expects the job to be beneficial and insightful, until he sees Buddy's true side, which is loud, obnoxious, pretentious, smothering, overbearing, and just plain unforgiving behavior as he takes pride in being belligerent and disrespectful to his assistants. In an extremely well written scene involving Guy trying to reason with Buddy about his yelling and his uncontrollable tirades, Buddy browbeats him relentlessly by telling him, "my bathmat means more to me than you," at the same time throwing pencils at him saying, "these pencils more important, these pens more important." The key to this scene is that both men have extremely valid points; Guy is trying to speak on a human-level with Buddy and brings up the idea of how in a business relationship, one must have the skill and ability to hold a grown-up discussion with one another. On the other hand, Buddy remarks on how you need to be a man to do the job and you must accept the torment as a means to get somewhere in the world. Further commentary is provided when we open up and see Buddy as more than a cynic, but how he got to be one and whether or not guy is on the same track heading to the same inevitable destination. The film is intercut with scenes showing Guy breaking in to Buddy's home, taking him hostage by tying him to his chair, and preceding to torture him mercilessly, reminding him of all the times he was demanding and ruthless to him. Again, the scene is not supposed to inspire moments of shock and jolts as it is to prove to the audience that both these men have perfectly valid points. Are Guy's actions justifiable? Yes, but they're not particularly right. Are Buddy's reasons for being mean and ruthless to his assistants justified? Yes, but they're not particularly right either. Writer/director George Huang wrote the film based off of what he experienced as an executive assistant at Columbia Pictures. Whether or not the acts he was involved in were this extreme or are fabricated to fit film's high standard I can not say, but Huang clearly knows what aspiring young cinephiles (or just business man on the lowest step of the corporate ladder) must go through and put up with in order to make it big. Where Huang scores effortlessly is in the writing, which is sharp, brutal, and all around satisfying. Seeing these men spit out some of the foulest things imaginable is unbelievably satisfying and is not only played for laughs but for intelligence. While the moments of darkness and subversive violence that are spliced in with the moments of typical office conundrums and tribulations may be a bit abrupt, they are nonetheless faithful and necessary to the film's point. I've always seen film as a device used to depict either morals, ideas, ideologies, places usually left unexplored, utopias, etc, but I've too seen it has a brilliant way to showcase events, lifestyles, and modern quirks. Swimming With Sharks is a brutally well written piece brilliantly taking us into the life of an overworked and under-appreciated businessman who is just looking for respect and fair treatment. Starring: Kevin Spacey and Frank Whaley. Directed by: George Huang.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One Man And His Dog
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    writers_reign
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If it turned out that Kevin Spacey paid the Producers to play this role I wouldn't be surprised given that it is an actor's dream role and one that makes Kirk Douglas's Jonathan Shields in The Bad And The Beautiful seem like a wimp. Douglas himself, who revelled in playing characters like this would have probably gone to the mat with Robert Ryan to play Buddy Ackerman had this film been written when Douglas and Ryan were in their heyday. As it is Spacey hits one out of the park without even trying and the best thing is that there is fine support from the other two leads. Cyanide-laced screenplays about Hollywood are not exactly thin on the ground - we can cite, in chronological order, Sunset Boulevard, The Bad And The Beautiful and Cliff Odets' The Big Knife off the top of our heads and they all appeared within six years of each other in the fifties. Swimming With Sharks may lack the skillful screenplays all three boasted but it is still well worth a look.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Outstanding film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tpaladino
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was originally led to believe (via my Netflix queue) that Swimming With Sharks would be a (dark) comedy. And while there are certain moments of humor, this film is firmly planted in drama territory. But, no matter what label they give it, the film is excellent and very much worth watching. The writing is sharp and interesting, and Spacey and the small cast do a great job with it. It's a very small movie, comprised of a very few actors and locations, but never feels small, thanks to the great depth that the characters are given, as well as the engrossing story. I don't want to reveal too much about the plot, but sufficed to say, it explores the dysfunctional and often tragic professional relationships that are abundant in Hollywood, and the extreme ends that an otherwise reasonable individual can be pushed to. Worth watching for sure.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great flick!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jerry-peanu
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ackerman obviously has problems or he wouldn't be acting quite in the way that he is, but director George Huang and Spacey are also careful to show that Ackerman has a lot more going on than surface behavior--he's acting the way that he is purposefully, both to get his due now as part of the establishment and to coyly manipulate his young, meek and abused underling, Guy (Frank Whaley), along with everyone else he comes into contact with. His aim is to mold Guy in a particular way--a way that works even though Guy thinks that he's severely breaking form in the extended penultimate scene that's intercut with Guy and Ackerman's history. Huang shows professional relationships as consisting mostly of politicking and manipulation. That's true at every level--certainly even Guy is doing this. There is very little authenticity to anyone in their working relationships. That seems pretty accurate to me, unfortunately. It's notable that the one dream of authenticity in the film--Guy talking about moving to Wyoming with Dawn (Michelle Forbes)--is treated and dispensed with as an unreachable fantasy, and it's also notable (and is fairly literally pointed out in the film) that Dawn, the one character who tries to demand being more authentic amidst the "shark infested waters" of the professional world, basically never gets anywhere. In the highly metaphorical ending of the film, things remain manipulative, political and backstabbing, and in that climate, at least two out of three characters "win". Huang seems to be suggesting that the professional world ain't likely to change any time soon, and that even if you try to change it or manipulate the game itself, you're likely to just get eaten up by it, processed by it and incorporated into it anyway. Again, I can't say I disagree with him.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Essay on the Origins of a Corporate Monster
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sean Lamberger
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Not entirely what you'd expect from the promo art, this strange hybrid of chilling suspense and black comedy bears a surprisingly deep, developed cast of characters and a bitter, intense message about the origins of a corporate monster. Kevin Spacey is at his usual best as the pompous, demeaning studio executive with a finger in every pie, while journeyman Frank Whaley (Brett from Pulp Fiction) overplays the wide-eyed, naive farmboy act as Spacey's hapless assistant at the edge. But while early scenes hint this is just another predictable, pull-for-the-little-man light comedy, the narrative's regular flashes forward in the timeline paint a larger, more sinister picture. When the dust settles, Spacey is revealed to be far more complicated and damaged than he lets on, Whaley has worked himself into a deep, dark pit of trouble and neither man is who they were at the outset. Bewildering at times due to the jolting changes in tone and atmosphere, it lingers with the viewer well after the credits have rolled.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Worth a watch
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    itamarscomix
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Swimming With Sharks is original and daring, but very uneven. I've always been a sucker for films about filmmaking and Hollywood and as such I was willing to let a lot slide, but it had a few too many ups and downs, starting out with a very problematic and ambiguous mix of comedy and tragedy; it then reaches its peak in the second half, when it turns more and more into a full drama; but then disappoints with the ending. And without that ending, it would have been a truly singular film. As it is, it's still an interesting one well worth a watch, if only for Kevin Spacey's performance in the second half, that turns from over-the-top ham to utter and nasty subtlety.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fanaticalaboutfilms Review: Swimming With Sharks
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    James (Fanaticalaboutfilms)
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Swimming With Sharks is set in the cut throat world of the film industry although this doesn't dictate the plot as much as you might think. It follows Guy (Frank Whaley) who is a clean-shaven enthusiastic new recruit into this unique world landing himself a job as the personal assistant to Buddy Ackerman (Kevin Spacey) an expletive throwing repugnant studio executive whose addition to your CV opens every door imaginable but is counteracted so much by his demeanour that many would find it not worth the trouble. Guy seems to have the determination to see it through helped by script writer and love interest Dawn (Michelle Forbes) but after working for the man for over a year, cracks begin to surface and Guy is finally pushed too far showing up at Buddy's home in the middle of the night intent on revenge. What plays out over the 100 minutes is a mixture between the past year of his life and the present unfolding situation. This was George Huang's first (and it would seem only notable) foray into the world of writing and directing and credit must be given to him. The script is impressive with Whaley engrossing himself into the character topped only by Spacey's exceptional performance where he looks set to star in a similar, albeit toned down, role in Horrible Bosses. He not only excels in many of his 'throwing a tantrum' scenes but somehow brings sympathy and compassion to a character that we should not feel anything for. Even when being held hostage he emits a certain smug arrogance that would be misplaced in any other character apart from this one. I felt conflicted given the knowledge at the beginning that Guy kidnaps his boss. It somewhat limits the sympathy you can show towards him regardless of finding out what Buddy did to drive him to such lengths. I wouldn't class this as a comedy per say as this is not going to have you laughing a great deal but rather an extremely dark satire of life in Hollywood and the means required to keep your head above the water. It shows us that the calling of the bright lights can change a man with only a few have what is required to make it. Add all of this together to an unexpected ending and it makes for an interesting watch. Yes there are moments where I felt things were not quite working and the relationship between Dawn and Guy lacked that believability factor but Swimming With Sharks certainly made the time fly and has enough to keep it fresh in the mind for a couple of days at the very least. For further reviews feel free to check out: http://www.fanaticalaboutfilms.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If You Ever Worked in Hollywood, You May Relate to this Fantasy of a Minno Getting Revenge on a Shark
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    classicalsteve
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Because the Hollywood industry is saturated with those who dream of being on the "inside", some people at the higher levels abuse their positions of power. Some of these regard themselves as the equivalent of demi-gods or priest-like figures, guarding the gates of the temple of the film/entertainment industry. They expect to be worshiped or at least revered, allowing the initiated to pass through. Those who are given a chance to become initiates are sometimes subjected to a kind of hazing process in which the poor initiate is subjected to the whims of the high elites. Kevin Spacey plays Buddy Ackerman, the perfect Hollywood shark, a studio executive who believes everything he says and does should be viewed as "gospel" by those who work under him. Guy (Frank Whaley) is his new assistant, or better stated, his new whipping boy. Guy is greener than an unripe tomato, replacing Rex (Benicio del Toro) of whom Buddy says "is a good for nothing mongoloid" on the first day. But before the first day is over, Guy realizes that this is going to be long term abuse. Spacey makes the perfect vain studio executive. One of the best aspects of his performance is that he wavers between seeming reasonable than flying into rages which would give your average wolverine a runs for its money. He berates Guy for giving him the wrong artificial sweetener. He throws books and papers at him. Even occasionally food. He even makes his assistant embark on impossible tasks, such as destroying every single copy of a Time Magazine issue which contained a scathing article about him. Ackerman's motto is "You are nothing. You're opinion means nothing". As book ends to the narrative, we flash to another part of the story: Guy has kidnapped Ackerman and has tied him. He's torturing him as payback. But the abuse is not the only reason Guy wants Buddy to suffer. As bad as Guy's mistreatment, the worst aspect is the executive's habit of taking credit for the deeds of others. In a poignant scene, Ackerman pretends to praise Guy to another executive, but Guy realizes it was false. A very interesting film, mostly for those who have either worked for or been associated with ego-maniacs. The movie industry is chock full of people who believe they are above everyone else because of certain successes. This gives some of them license to abuse others, particularly because so many desire what few positions are available. As Buddy himself says "Life is not a movie. Good guys lose, everybody lies, and love... does not conquer all."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    tongue in cheek brilliance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    charles-okell
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Its so very quotable and finds Spacey in fine form - "my pencil eraser means more to me than you do" has been uttered often by all my team in the studio! Given it has got low production values, the lighting is grainy and their attention to continuity is poor rather than 'on purpose' it does have a jovial, dark hummer that is much more widely accessible than say the likes of Anchor Man which was equally low budget relying on star quality. Do give it a go with friends and a few beers, it improves the experience no end and then watch Horrible Bosses, 21, Casino Jack and hope that Spacey churns the same character out at least a few more times before he disappears into the artistic roles his Thespian bent so clearly desires - he is a film treasure, under utilized and always great in a film... even when the film is rubbish (Casino Jack....)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Kevin Spacey always puts on a great performance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    T Cady
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of those movies where a great actor turns a run of the mill film into a good one. Kevin Spacey is just the sort of actor that always seems to do that. "Swimming with Sharks," is the story of a young man, Guy ( Frank Whaley), who is determined to make his mark in the Movie industry. He lands a job as the assistant to big time Hollywood executive, Buddy Ackerman (Kevin Spacey), and thinks he has the start to launch him into the big time. It turns out that Buddy is not only a bigshot executive but also makes ridiculous demands, and is a downright cruel demanding boss, that seems to have no regard for his assistant or anyone for that matter. How far can Buddy push Guy until he snaps? This is not a new story line, it has been done time after time, but it is a horrible boss story, so everyone can relate to it. I am not a fan of Frank Whaley and actually can't stand him, but he does a decent job in this one. As I said this movie wasn't very original and I probably wouldn't have liked this movie at all if it wasn't for Kevin Spacey. Kevin Spacey did a great job portraying the evil, demanding boss.In my mind, he was what made this movie. Everything in this movie says boring and done before, but Kevin Spacey's performance turns it into a good movie. It's rare that one actor could do that by himself but in this case it is true. Not to reveal anything, but the end takes a twist that is actually a pretty good one. So overall, it was a good movie, not a great one. Spacey turns out to be the only one driving it, but somehow it was enough to make it watchable and at times enjoyable. Like my reviews, hate em? Any questions or comments, or if you want a DVD reviewed just shoot me an e-mail at: subliminal.lithium@gmail.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Here's to all the schmucks who can't tell Sweet'n Low from Equal
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steve Pulaski
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Kevin Spacey, more often than not, gets handed the sharpest, funniest, cleverest, most desirable monologues in his roles. In Glengarry Glen Ross, he delivered cold lines of fury when talking to his deadbeat employees and took some severe blows to the ego when he was jabbed with personal insults. In American Beauty, it was entrancing to hear him narrate his story with such gratitude and depth, along with giving us one of the best performances of the decade. And in K-PAX, he convincingly played an alleged extraterrestrial who seemed to appear out of thin air and turn a skeptical psychiatrist into a true believer. The man is a treasure often shorthanded and under-valued. Spacey gives yet another fantastic performance of true power and control in Swimming With Sharks, a black comedy that is heavy on the laughs and insight, and easy on the levels of conformity and monotony. This is a biting drama of business and progress in the work world, with some of the toughest and most brutal insight into the corporate world that can only be compared to the level of truths brought in Kevin Smith's Clerks and Mike Judge's Office Space. This deserves a spot in the same league. Guy (Frank Whaley) is a young writer who is extremely satisfied to get a job working as the assistant for movie mogul Buddy Ackerman, played by Kevin Spacey. Guy expects the job to be beneficial and insightful, until he sees Buddy's true side, which is loud, obnoxious, pretentious, smothering, overbearing, and just plain unforgiving behavior as he takes pride in being belligerent and disrespectful to his assistants. In an extremely well written scene involving Guy trying to reason with Buddy about his yelling and his uncontrollable tirades, Buddy browbeats him relentlessly by telling him, "my bathmat means more to me than you," at the same time throwing pencils at him saying, "these pencils more important, these pens more important." The key to this scene is that both men have extremely valid points; Guy is trying to speak on a human-level with Buddy and brings up the idea of how in a business relationship, one must have the skill and ability to hold a grown-up discussion with one another. On the other hand, Buddy remarks on how you need to be a man to do the job and you must accept the torment as a means to get somewhere in the world. Further commentary is provided when we open up and see Buddy as more than a cynic, but how he got to be one and whether or not guy is on the same track heading to the same inevitable destination. The film is intercut with scenes showing Guy breaking in to Buddy's home, taking him hostage by tying him to his chair, and preceding to torture him mercilessly, reminding him of all the times he was demanding and ruthless to him. Again, the scene is not supposed to inspire moments of shock and jolts as it is to prove to the audience that both these men have perfectly valid points. Are Guy's actions justifiable? Yes, but they're not particularly right. Are Buddy's reasons for being mean and ruthless to his assistants justified? Yes, but they're not particularly right either. Writer/director George Huang wrote the film based off of what he experienced as an executive assistant at Columbia Pictures. Whether or not the acts he was involved in were this extreme or are fabricated to fit film's high standard I can not say, but Huang clearly knows what aspiring young cinephiles (or just business man on the lowest step of the corporate ladder) must go through and put up with in order to make it big. Where Huang scores effortlessly is in the writing, which is sharp, brutal, and all around satisfying. Seeing these men spit out some of the foulest things imaginable is unbelievably satisfying and is not only played for laughs but for intelligence. While the moments of darkness and subversive violence that are spliced in with the moments of typical office conundrums and tribulations may be a bit abrupt, they are nonetheless faithful and necessary to the film's point. I've always seen film as a device used to depict either morals, ideas, ideologies, places usually left unexplored, utopias, etc, but I've too seen it has a brilliant way to showcase events, lifestyles, and modern quirks. Swimming With Sharks is a brutally well written piece brilliantly taking us into the life of an overworked and under-appreciated businessman who is just looking for respect and fair treatment. Starring: Kevin Spacey and Frank Whaley. Directed by: George Huang.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One Man And His Dog
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    writers_reign
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If it turned out that Kevin Spacey paid the Producers to play this role I wouldn't be surprised given that it is an actor's dream role and one that makes Kirk Douglas's Jonathan Shields in The Bad And The Beautiful seem like a wimp. Douglas himself, who revelled in playing characters like this would have probably gone to the mat with Robert Ryan to play Buddy Ackerman had this film been written when Douglas and Ryan were in their heyday. As it is Spacey hits one out of the park without even trying and the best thing is that there is fine support from the other two leads. Cyanide-laced screenplays about Hollywood are not exactly thin on the ground - we can cite, in chronological order, Sunset Boulevard, The Bad And The Beautiful and Cliff Odets' The Big Knife off the top of our heads and they all appeared within six years of each other in the fifties. Swimming With Sharks may lack the skillful screenplays all three boasted but it is still well worth a look.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Outstanding film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tpaladino
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was originally led to believe (via my Netflix queue) that Swimming With Sharks would be a (dark) comedy. And while there are certain moments of humor, this film is firmly planted in drama territory. But, no matter what label they give it, the film is excellent and very much worth watching. The writing is sharp and interesting, and Spacey and the small cast do a great job with it. It's a very small movie, comprised of a very few actors and locations, but never feels small, thanks to the great depth that the characters are given, as well as the engrossing story. I don't want to reveal too much about the plot, but sufficed to say, it explores the dysfunctional and often tragic professional relationships that are abundant in Hollywood, and the extreme ends that an otherwise reasonable individual can be pushed to. Worth watching for sure.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great flick!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jerry-peanu
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ackerman obviously has problems or he wouldn't be acting quite in the way that he is, but director George Huang and Spacey are also careful to show that Ackerman has a lot more going on than surface behavior--he's acting the way that he is purposefully, both to get his due now as part of the establishment and to coyly manipulate his young, meek and abused underling, Guy (Frank Whaley), along with everyone else he comes into contact with. His aim is to mold Guy in a particular way--a way that works even though Guy thinks that he's severely breaking form in the extended penultimate scene that's intercut with Guy and Ackerman's history. Huang shows professional relationships as consisting mostly of politicking and manipulation. That's true at every level--certainly even Guy is doing this. There is very little authenticity to anyone in their working relationships. That seems pretty accurate to me, unfortunately. It's notable that the one dream of authenticity in the film--Guy talking about moving to Wyoming with Dawn (Michelle Forbes)--is treated and dispensed with as an unreachable fantasy, and it's also notable (and is fairly literally pointed out in the film) that Dawn, the one character who tries to demand being more authentic amidst the "shark infested waters" of the professional world, basically never gets anywhere. In the highly metaphorical ending of the film, things remain manipulative, political and backstabbing, and in that climate, at least two out of three characters "win". Huang seems to be suggesting that the professional world ain't likely to change any time soon, and that even if you try to change it or manipulate the game itself, you're likely to just get eaten up by it, processed by it and incorporated into it anyway. Again, I can't say I disagree with him.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Essay on the Origins of a Corporate Monster
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sean Lamberger
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Not entirely what you'd expect from the promo art, this strange hybrid of chilling suspense and black comedy bears a surprisingly deep, developed cast of characters and a bitter, intense message about the origins of a corporate monster. Kevin Spacey is at his usual best as the pompous, demeaning studio executive with a finger in every pie, while journeyman Frank Whaley (Brett from Pulp Fiction) overplays the wide-eyed, naive farmboy act as Spacey's hapless assistant at the edge. But while early scenes hint this is just another predictable, pull-for-the-little-man light comedy, the narrative's regular flashes forward in the timeline paint a larger, more sinister picture. When the dust settles, Spacey is revealed to be far more complicated and damaged than he lets on, Whaley has worked himself into a deep, dark pit of trouble and neither man is who they were at the outset. Bewildering at times due to the jolting changes in tone and atmosphere, it lingers with the viewer well after the credits have rolled.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Worth a watch
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    itamarscomix
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Swimming With Sharks is original and daring, but very uneven. I've always been a sucker for films about filmmaking and Hollywood and as such I was willing to let a lot slide, but it had a few too many ups and downs, starting out with a very problematic and ambiguous mix of comedy and tragedy; it then reaches its peak in the second half, when it turns more and more into a full drama; but then disappoints with the ending. And without that ending, it would have been a truly singular film. As it is, it's still an interesting one well worth a watch, if only for Kevin Spacey's performance in the second half, that turns from over-the-top ham to utter and nasty subtlety.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fanaticalaboutfilms Review: Swimming With Sharks
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    James (Fanaticalaboutfilms)
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Swimming With Sharks is set in the cut throat world of the film industry although this doesn't dictate the plot as much as you might think. It follows Guy (Frank Whaley) who is a clean-shaven enthusiastic new recruit into this unique world landing himself a job as the personal assistant to Buddy Ackerman (Kevin Spacey) an expletive throwing repugnant studio executive whose addition to your CV opens every door imaginable but is counteracted so much by his demeanour that many would find it not worth the trouble. Guy seems to have the determination to see it through helped by script writer and love interest Dawn (Michelle Forbes) but after working for the man for over a year, cracks begin to surface and Guy is finally pushed too far showing up at Buddy's home in the middle of the night intent on revenge. What plays out over the 100 minutes is a mixture between the past year of his life and the present unfolding situation. This was George Huang's first (and it would seem only notable) foray into the world of writing and directing and credit must be given to him. The script is impressive with Whaley engrossing himself into the character topped only by Spacey's exceptional performance where he looks set to star in a similar, albeit toned down, role in Horrible Bosses. He not only excels in many of his 'throwing a tantrum' scenes but somehow brings sympathy and compassion to a character that we should not feel anything for. Even when being held hostage he emits a certain smug arrogance that would be misplaced in any other character apart from this one. I felt conflicted given the knowledge at the beginning that Guy kidnaps his boss. It somewhat limits the sympathy you can show towards him regardless of finding out what Buddy did to drive him to such lengths. I wouldn't class this as a comedy per say as this is not going to have you laughing a great deal but rather an extremely dark satire of life in Hollywood and the means required to keep your head above the water. It shows us that the calling of the bright lights can change a man with only a few have what is required to make it. Add all of this together to an unexpected ending and it makes for an interesting watch. Yes there are moments where I felt things were not quite working and the relationship between Dawn and Guy lacked that believability factor but Swimming With Sharks certainly made the time fly and has enough to keep it fresh in the mind for a couple of days at the very least. For further reviews feel free to check out: http://www.fanaticalaboutfilms.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If You Ever Worked in Hollywood, You May Relate to this Fantasy of a Minno Getting Revenge on a Shark
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    classicalsteve
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Because the Hollywood industry is saturated with those who dream of being on the "inside", some people at the higher levels abuse their positions of power. Some of these regard themselves as the equivalent of demi-gods or priest-like figures, guarding the gates of the temple of the film/entertainment industry. They expect to be worshiped or at least revered, allowing the initiated to pass through. Those who are given a chance to become initiates are sometimes subjected to a kind of hazing process in which the poor initiate is subjected to the whims of the high elites. Kevin Spacey plays Buddy Ackerman, the perfect Hollywood shark, a studio executive who believes everything he says and does should be viewed as "gospel" by those who work under him. Guy (Frank Whaley) is his new assistant, or better stated, his new whipping boy. Guy is greener than an unripe tomato, replacing Rex (Benicio del Toro) of whom Buddy says "is a good for nothing mongoloid" on the first day. But before the first day is over, Guy realizes that this is going to be long term abuse. Spacey makes the perfect vain studio executive. One of the best aspects of his performance is that he wavers between seeming reasonable than flying into rages which would give your average wolverine a runs for its money. He berates Guy for giving him the wrong artificial sweetener. He throws books and papers at him. Even occasionally food. He even makes his assistant embark on impossible tasks, such as destroying every single copy of a Time Magazine issue which contained a scathing article about him. Ackerman's motto is "You are nothing. You're opinion means nothing". As book ends to the narrative, we flash to another part of the story: Guy has kidnapped Ackerman and has tied him. He's torturing him as payback. But the abuse is not the only reason Guy wants Buddy to suffer. As bad as Guy's mistreatment, the worst aspect is the executive's habit of taking credit for the deeds of others. In a poignant scene, Ackerman pretends to praise Guy to another executive, but Guy realizes it was false. A very interesting film, mostly for those who have either worked for or been associated with ego-maniacs. The movie industry is chock full of people who believe they are above everyone else because of certain successes. This gives some of them license to abuse others, particularly because so many desire what few positions are available. As Buddy himself says "Life is not a movie. Good guys lose, everybody lies, and love... does not conquer all."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    tongue in cheek brilliance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    charles-okell
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Its so very quotable and finds Spacey in fine form - "my pencil eraser means more to me than you do" has been uttered often by all my team in the studio! Given it has got low production values, the lighting is grainy and their attention to continuity is poor rather than 'on purpose' it does have a jovial, dark hummer that is much more widely accessible than say the likes of Anchor Man which was equally low budget relying on star quality. Do give it a go with friends and a few beers, it improves the experience no end and then watch Horrible Bosses, 21, Casino Jack and hope that Spacey churns the same character out at least a few more times before he disappears into the artistic roles his Thespian bent so clearly desires - he is a film treasure, under utilized and always great in a film... even when the film is rubbish (Casino Jack....)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Kevin Spacey always puts on a great performance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    T Cady
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of those movies where a great actor turns a run of the mill film into a good one. Kevin Spacey is just the sort of actor that always seems to do that. "Swimming with Sharks," is the story of a young man, Guy ( Frank Whaley), who is determined to make his mark in the Movie industry. He lands a job as the assistant to big time Hollywood executive, Buddy Ackerman (Kevin Spacey), and thinks he has the start to launch him into the big time. It turns out that Buddy is not only a bigshot executive but also makes ridiculous demands, and is a downright cruel demanding boss, that seems to have no regard for his assistant or anyone for that matter. How far can Buddy push Guy until he snaps? This is not a new story line, it has been done time after time, but it is a horrible boss story, so everyone can relate to it. I am not a fan of Frank Whaley and actually can't stand him, but he does a decent job in this one. As I said this movie wasn't very original and I probably wouldn't have liked this movie at all if it wasn't for Kevin Spacey. Kevin Spacey did a great job portraying the evil, demanding boss.In my mind, he was what made this movie. Everything in this movie says boring and done before, but Kevin Spacey's performance turns it into a good movie. It's rare that one actor could do that by himself but in this case it is true. Not to reveal anything, but the end takes a twist that is actually a pretty good one. So overall, it was a good movie, not a great one. Spacey turns out to be the only one driving it, but somehow it was enough to make it watchable and at times enjoyable. Like my reviews, hate em? Any questions or comments, or if you want a DVD reviewed just shoot me an e-mail at: subliminal.lithium@gmail.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Here's to all the schmucks who can't tell Sweet'n Low from Equal
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steve Pulaski
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Kevin Spacey, more often than not, gets handed the sharpest, funniest, cleverest, most desirable monologues in his roles. In Glengarry Glen Ross, he delivered cold lines of fury when talking to his deadbeat employees and took some severe blows to the ego when he was jabbed with personal insults. In American Beauty, it was entrancing to hear him narrate his story with such gratitude and depth, along with giving us one of the best performances of the decade. And in K-PAX, he convincingly played an alleged extraterrestrial who seemed to appear out of thin air and turn a skeptical psychiatrist into a true believer. The man is a treasure often shorthanded and under-valued. Spacey gives yet another fantastic performance of true power and control in Swimming With Sharks, a black comedy that is heavy on the laughs and insight, and easy on the levels of conformity and monotony. This is a biting drama of business and progress in the work world, with some of the toughest and most brutal insight into the corporate world that can only be compared to the level of truths brought in Kevin Smith's Clerks and Mike Judge's Office Space. This deserves a spot in the same league. Guy (Frank Whaley) is a young writer who is extremely satisfied to get a job working as the assistant for movie mogul Buddy Ackerman, played by Kevin Spacey. Guy expects the job to be beneficial and insightful, until he sees Buddy's true side, which is loud, obnoxious, pretentious, smothering, overbearing, and just plain unforgiving behavior as he takes pride in being belligerent and disrespectful to his assistants. In an extremely well written scene involving Guy trying to reason with Buddy about his yelling and his uncontrollable tirades, Buddy browbeats him relentlessly by telling him, "my bathmat means more to me than you," at the same time throwing pencils at him saying, "these pencils more important, these pens more important." The key to this scene is that both men have extremely valid points; Guy is trying to speak on a human-level with Buddy and brings up the idea of how in a business relationship, one must have the skill and ability to hold a grown-up discussion with one another. On the other hand, Buddy remarks on how you need to be a man to do the job and you must accept the torment as a means to get somewhere in the world. Further commentary is provided when we open up and see Buddy as more than a cynic, but how he got to be one and whether or not guy is on the same track heading to the same inevitable destination. The film is intercut with scenes showing Guy breaking in to Buddy's home, taking him hostage by tying him to his chair, and preceding to torture him mercilessly, reminding him of all the times he was demanding and ruthless to him. Again, the scene is not supposed to inspire moments of shock and jolts as it is to prove to the audience that both these men have perfectly valid points. Are Guy's actions justifiable? Yes, but they're not particularly right. Are Buddy's reasons for being mean and ruthless to his assistants justified? Yes, but they're not particularly right either. Writer/director George Huang wrote the film based off of what he experienced as an executive assistant at Columbia Pictures. Whether or not the acts he was involved in were this extreme or are fabricated to fit film's high standard I can not say, but Huang clearly knows what aspiring young cinephiles (or just business man on the lowest step of the corporate ladder) must go through and put up with in order to make it big. Where Huang scores effortlessly is in the writing, which is sharp, brutal, and all around satisfying. Seeing these men spit out some of the foulest things imaginable is unbelievably satisfying and is not only played for laughs but for intelligence. While the moments of darkness and subversive violence that are spliced in with the moments of typical office conundrums and tribulations may be a bit abrupt, they are nonetheless faithful and necessary to the film's point. I've always seen film as a device used to depict either morals, ideas, ideologies, places usually left unexplored, utopias, etc, but I've too seen it has a brilliant way to showcase events, lifestyles, and modern quirks. Swimming With Sharks is a brutally well written piece brilliantly taking us into the life of an overworked and under-appreciated businessman who is just looking for respect and fair treatment. Starring: Kevin Spacey and Frank Whaley. Directed by: George Huang.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One Man And His Dog
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    writers_reign
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If it turned out that Kevin Spacey paid the Producers to play this role I wouldn't be surprised given that it is an actor's dream role and one that makes Kirk Douglas's Jonathan Shields in The Bad And The Beautiful seem like a wimp. Douglas himself, who revelled in playing characters like this would have probably gone to the mat with Robert Ryan to play Buddy Ackerman had this film been written when Douglas and Ryan were in their heyday. As it is Spacey hits one out of the park without even trying and the best thing is that there is fine support from the other two leads. Cyanide-laced screenplays about Hollywood are not exactly thin on the ground - we can cite, in chronological order, Sunset Boulevard, The Bad And The Beautiful and Cliff Odets' The Big Knife off the top of our heads and they all appeared within six years of each other in the fifties. Swimming With Sharks may lack the skillful screenplays all three boasted but it is still well worth a look.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Outstanding film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tpaladino
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was originally led to believe (via my Netflix queue) that Swimming With Sharks would be a (dark) comedy. And while there are certain moments of humor, this film is firmly planted in drama territory. But, no matter what label they give it, the film is excellent and very much worth watching. The writing is sharp and interesting, and Spacey and the small cast do a great job with it. It's a very small movie, comprised of a very few actors and locations, but never feels small, thanks to the great depth that the characters are given, as well as the engrossing story. I don't want to reveal too much about the plot, but sufficed to say, it explores the dysfunctional and often tragic professional relationships that are abundant in Hollywood, and the extreme ends that an otherwise reasonable individual can be pushed to. Worth watching for sure.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great flick!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jerry-peanu
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ackerman obviously has problems or he wouldn't be acting quite in the way that he is, but director George Huang and Spacey are also careful to show that Ackerman has a lot more going on than surface behavior--he's acting the way that he is purposefully, both to get his due now as part of the establishment and to coyly manipulate his young, meek and abused underling, Guy (Frank Whaley), along with everyone else he comes into contact with. His aim is to mold Guy in a particular way--a way that works even though Guy thinks that he's severely breaking form in the extended penultimate scene that's intercut with Guy and Ackerman's history. Huang shows professional relationships as consisting mostly of politicking and manipulation. That's true at every level--certainly even Guy is doing this. There is very little authenticity to anyone in their working relationships. That seems pretty accurate to me, unfortunately. It's notable that the one dream of authenticity in the film--Guy talking about moving to Wyoming with Dawn (Michelle Forbes)--is treated and dispensed with as an unreachable fantasy, and it's also notable (and is fairly literally pointed out in the film) that Dawn, the one character who tries to demand being more authentic amidst the "shark infested waters" of the professional world, basically never gets anywhere. In the highly metaphorical ending of the film, things remain manipulative, political and backstabbing, and in that climate, at least two out of three characters "win". Huang seems to be suggesting that the professional world ain't likely to change any time soon, and that even if you try to change it or manipulate the game itself, you're likely to just get eaten up by it, processed by it and incorporated into it anyway. Again, I can't say I disagree with him.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Essay on the Origins of a Corporate Monster
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sean Lamberger
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Not entirely what you'd expect from the promo art, this strange hybrid of chilling suspense and black comedy bears a surprisingly deep, developed cast of characters and a bitter, intense message about the origins of a corporate monster. Kevin Spacey is at his usual best as the pompous, demeaning studio executive with a finger in every pie, while journeyman Frank Whaley (Brett from Pulp Fiction) overplays the wide-eyed, naive farmboy act as Spacey's hapless assistant at the edge. But while early scenes hint this is just another predictable, pull-for-the-little-man light comedy, the narrative's regular flashes forward in the timeline paint a larger, more sinister picture. When the dust settles, Spacey is revealed to be far more complicated and damaged than he lets on, Whaley has worked himself into a deep, dark pit of trouble and neither man is who they were at the outset. Bewildering at times due to the jolting changes in tone and atmosphere, it lingers with the viewer well after the credits have rolled.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Worth a watch
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    itamarscomix
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Swimming With Sharks is original and daring, but very uneven. I've always been a sucker for films about filmmaking and Hollywood and as such I was willing to let a lot slide, but it had a few too many ups and downs, starting out with a very problematic and ambiguous mix of comedy and tragedy; it then reaches its peak in the second half, when it turns more and more into a full drama; but then disappoints with the ending. And without that ending, it would have been a truly singular film. As it is, it's still an interesting one well worth a watch, if only for Kevin Spacey's performance in the second half, that turns from over-the-top ham to utter and nasty subtlety.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fanaticalaboutfilms Review: Swimming With Sharks
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    James (Fanaticalaboutfilms)
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Swimming With Sharks is set in the cut throat world of the film industry although this doesn't dictate the plot as much as you might think. It follows Guy (Frank Whaley) who is a clean-shaven enthusiastic new recruit into this unique world landing himself a job as the personal assistant to Buddy Ackerman (Kevin Spacey) an expletive throwing repugnant studio executive whose addition to your CV opens every door imaginable but is counteracted so much by his demeanour that many would find it not worth the trouble. Guy seems to have the determination to see it through helped by script writer and love interest Dawn (Michelle Forbes) but after working for the man for over a year, cracks begin to surface and Guy is finally pushed too far showing up at Buddy's home in the middle of the night intent on revenge. What plays out over the 100 minutes is a mixture between the past year of his life and the present unfolding situation. This was George Huang's first (and it would seem only notable) foray into the world of writing and directing and credit must be given to him. The script is impressive with Whaley engrossing himself into the character topped only by Spacey's exceptional performance where he looks set to star in a similar, albeit toned down, role in Horrible Bosses. He not only excels in many of his 'throwing a tantrum' scenes but somehow brings sympathy and compassion to a character that we should not feel anything for. Even when being held hostage he emits a certain smug arrogance that would be misplaced in any other character apart from this one. I felt conflicted given the knowledge at the beginning that Guy kidnaps his boss. It somewhat limits the sympathy you can show towards him regardless of finding out what Buddy did to drive him to such lengths. I wouldn't class this as a comedy per say as this is not going to have you laughing a great deal but rather an extremely dark satire of life in Hollywood and the means required to keep your head above the water. It shows us that the calling of the bright lights can change a man with only a few have what is required to make it. Add all of this together to an unexpected ending and it makes for an interesting watch. Yes there are moments where I felt things were not quite working and the relationship between Dawn and Guy lacked that believability factor but Swimming With Sharks certainly made the time fly and has enough to keep it fresh in the mind for a couple of days at the very least. For further reviews feel free to check out: http://www.fanaticalaboutfilms.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If You Ever Worked in Hollywood, You May Relate to this Fantasy of a Minno Getting Revenge on a Shark
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    classicalsteve
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Because the Hollywood industry is saturated with those who dream of being on the "inside", some people at the higher levels abuse their positions of power. Some of these regard themselves as the equivalent of demi-gods or priest-like figures, guarding the gates of the temple of the film/entertainment industry. They expect to be worshiped or at least revered, allowing the initiated to pass through. Those who are given a chance to become initiates are sometimes subjected to a kind of hazing process in which the poor initiate is subjected to the whims of the high elites. Kevin Spacey plays Buddy Ackerman, the perfect Hollywood shark, a studio executive who believes everything he says and does should be viewed as "gospel" by those who work under him. Guy (Frank Whaley) is his new assistant, or better stated, his new whipping boy. Guy is greener than an unripe tomato, replacing Rex (Benicio del Toro) of whom Buddy says "is a good for nothing mongoloid" on the first day. But before the first day is over, Guy realizes that this is going to be long term abuse. Spacey makes the perfect vain studio executive. One of the best aspects of his performance is that he wavers between seeming reasonable than flying into rages which would give your average wolverine a runs for its money. He berates Guy for giving him the wrong artificial sweetener. He throws books and papers at him. Even occasionally food. He even makes his assistant embark on impossible tasks, such as destroying every single copy of a Time Magazine issue which contained a scathing article about him. Ackerman's motto is "You are nothing. You're opinion means nothing". As book ends to the narrative, we flash to another part of the story: Guy has kidnapped Ackerman and has tied him. He's torturing him as payback. But the abuse is not the only reason Guy wants Buddy to suffer. As bad as Guy's mistreatment, the worst aspect is the executive's habit of taking credit for the deeds of others. In a poignant scene, Ackerman pretends to praise Guy to another executive, but Guy realizes it was false. A very interesting film, mostly for those who have either worked for or been associated with ego-maniacs. The movie industry is chock full of people who believe they are above everyone else because of certain successes. This gives some of them license to abuse others, particularly because so many desire what few positions are available. As Buddy himself says "Life is not a movie. Good guys lose, everybody lies, and love... does not conquer all."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    tongue in cheek brilliance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    charles-okell
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Its so very quotable and finds Spacey in fine form - "my pencil eraser means more to me than you do" has been uttered often by all my team in the studio! Given it has got low production values, the lighting is grainy and their attention to continuity is poor rather than 'on purpose' it does have a jovial, dark hummer that is much more widely accessible than say the likes of Anchor Man which was equally low budget relying on star quality. Do give it a go with friends and a few beers, it improves the experience no end and then watch Horrible Bosses, 21, Casino Jack and hope that Spacey churns the same character out at least a few more times before he disappears into the artistic roles his Thespian bent so clearly desires - he is a film treasure, under utilized and always great in a film... even when the film is rubbish (Casino Jack....)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Kevin Spacey always puts on a great performance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    T Cady
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of those movies where a great actor turns a run of the mill film into a good one. Kevin Spacey is just the sort of actor that always seems to do that. "Swimming with Sharks," is the story of a young man, Guy ( Frank Whaley), who is determined to make his mark in the Movie industry. He lands a job as the assistant to big time Hollywood executive, Buddy Ackerman (Kevin Spacey), and thinks he has the start to launch him into the big time. It turns out that Buddy is not only a bigshot executive but also makes ridiculous demands, and is a downright cruel demanding boss, that seems to have no regard for his assistant or anyone for that matter. How far can Buddy push Guy until he snaps? This is not a new story line, it has been done time after time, but it is a horrible boss story, so everyone can relate to it. I am not a fan of Frank Whaley and actually can't stand him, but he does a decent job in this one. As I said this movie wasn't very original and I probably wouldn't have liked this movie at all if it wasn't for Kevin Spacey. Kevin Spacey did a great job portraying the evil, demanding boss.In my mind, he was what made this movie. Everything in this movie says boring and done before, but Kevin Spacey's performance turns it into a good movie. It's rare that one actor could do that by himself but in this case it is true. Not to reveal anything, but the end takes a twist that is actually a pretty good one. So overall, it was a good movie, not a great one. Spacey turns out to be the only one driving it, but somehow it was enough to make it watchable and at times enjoyable. Like my reviews, hate em? Any questions or comments, or if you want a DVD reviewed just shoot me an e-mail at: subliminal.lithium@gmail.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Here's to all the schmucks who can't tell Sweet'n Low from Equal
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steve Pulaski
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Kevin Spacey, more often than not, gets handed the sharpest, funniest, cleverest, most desirable monologues in his roles. In Glengarry Glen Ross, he delivered cold lines of fury when talking to his deadbeat employees and took some severe blows to the ego when he was jabbed with personal insults. In American Beauty, it was entrancing to hear him narrate his story with such gratitude and depth, along with giving us one of the best performances of the decade. And in K-PAX, he convincingly played an alleged extraterrestrial who seemed to appear out of thin air and turn a skeptical psychiatrist into a true believer. The man is a treasure often shorthanded and under-valued. Spacey gives yet another fantastic performance of true power and control in Swimming With Sharks, a black comedy that is heavy on the laughs and insight, and easy on the levels of conformity and monotony. This is a biting drama of business and progress in the work world, with some of the toughest and most brutal insight into the corporate world that can only be compared to the level of truths brought in Kevin Smith's Clerks and Mike Judge's Office Space. This deserves a spot in the same league. Guy (Frank Whaley) is a young writer who is extremely satisfied to get a job working as the assistant for movie mogul Buddy Ackerman, played by Kevin Spacey. Guy expects the job to be beneficial and insightful, until he sees Buddy's true side, which is loud, obnoxious, pretentious, smothering, overbearing, and just plain unforgiving behavior as he takes pride in being belligerent and disrespectful to his assistants. In an extremely well written scene involving Guy trying to reason with Buddy about his yelling and his uncontrollable tirades, Buddy browbeats him relentlessly by telling him, "my bathmat means more to me than you," at the same time throwing pencils at him saying, "these pencils more important, these pens more important." The key to this scene is that both men have extremely valid points; Guy is trying to speak on a human-level with Buddy and brings up the idea of how in a business relationship, one must have the skill and ability to hold a grown-up discussion with one another. On the other hand, Buddy remarks on how you need to be a man to do the job and you must accept the torment as a means to get somewhere in the world. Further commentary is provided when we open up and see Buddy as more than a cynic, but how he got to be one and whether or not guy is on the same track heading to the same inevitable destination. The film is intercut with scenes showing Guy breaking in to Buddy's home, taking him hostage by tying him to his chair, and preceding to torture him mercilessly, reminding him of all the times he was demanding and ruthless to him. Again, the scene is not supposed to inspire moments of shock and jolts as it is to prove to the audience that both these men have perfectly valid points. Are Guy's actions justifiable? Yes, but they're not particularly right. Are Buddy's reasons for being mean and ruthless to his assistants justified? Yes, but they're not particularly right either. Writer/director George Huang wrote the film based off of what he experienced as an executive assistant at Columbia Pictures. Whether or not the acts he was involved in were this extreme or are fabricated to fit film's high standard I can not say, but Huang clearly knows what aspiring young cinephiles (or just business man on the lowest step of the corporate ladder) must go through and put up with in order to make it big. Where Huang scores effortlessly is in the writing, which is sharp, brutal, and all around satisfying. Seeing these men spit out some of the foulest things imaginable is unbelievably satisfying and is not only played for laughs but for intelligence. While the moments of darkness and subversive violence that are spliced in with the moments of typical office conundrums and tribulations may be a bit abrupt, they are nonetheless faithful and necessary to the film's point. I've always seen film as a device used to depict either morals, ideas, ideologies, places usually left unexplored, utopias, etc, but I've too seen it has a brilliant way to showcase events, lifestyles, and modern quirks. Swimming With Sharks is a brutally well written piece brilliantly taking us into the life of an overworked and under-appreciated businessman who is just looking for respect and fair treatment. Starring: Kevin Spacey and Frank Whaley. Directed by: George Huang.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One Man And His Dog
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    writers_reign
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If it turned out that Kevin Spacey paid the Producers to play this role I wouldn't be surprised given that it is an actor's dream role and one that makes Kirk Douglas's Jonathan Shields in The Bad And The Beautiful seem like a wimp. Douglas himself, who revelled in playing characters like this would have probably gone to the mat with Robert Ryan to play Buddy Ackerman had this film been written when Douglas and Ryan were in their heyday. As it is Spacey hits one out of the park without even trying and the best thing is that there is fine support from the other two leads. Cyanide-laced screenplays about Hollywood are not exactly thin on the ground - we can cite, in chronological order, Sunset Boulevard, The Bad And The Beautiful and Cliff Odets' The Big Knife off the top of our heads and they all appeared within six years of each other in the fifties. Swimming With Sharks may lack the skillful screenplays all three boasted but it is still well worth a look.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Outstanding film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tpaladino
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was originally led to believe (via my Netflix queue) that Swimming With Sharks would be a (dark) comedy. And while there are certain moments of humor, this film is firmly planted in drama territory. But, no matter what label they give it, the film is excellent and very much worth watching. The writing is sharp and interesting, and Spacey and the small cast do a great job with it. It's a very small movie, comprised of a very few actors and locations, but never feels small, thanks to the great depth that the characters are given, as well as the engrossing story. I don't want to reveal too much about the plot, but sufficed to say, it explores the dysfunctional and often tragic professional relationships that are abundant in Hollywood, and the extreme ends that an otherwise reasonable individual can be pushed to. Worth watching for sure.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great flick!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jerry-peanu
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ackerman obviously has problems or he wouldn't be acting quite in the way that he is, but director George Huang and Spacey are also careful to show that Ackerman has a lot more going on than surface behavior--he's acting the way that he is purposefully, both to get his due now as part of the establishment and to coyly manipulate his young, meek and abused underling, Guy (Frank Whaley), along with everyone else he comes into contact with. His aim is to mold Guy in a particular way--a way that works even though Guy thinks that he's severely breaking form in the extended penultimate scene that's intercut with Guy and Ackerman's history. Huang shows professional relationships as consisting mostly of politicking and manipulation. That's true at every level--certainly even Guy is doing this. There is very little authenticity to anyone in their working relationships. That seems pretty accurate to me, unfortunately. It's notable that the one dream of authenticity in the film--Guy talking about moving to Wyoming with Dawn (Michelle Forbes)--is treated and dispensed with as an unreachable fantasy, and it's also notable (and is fairly literally pointed out in the film) that Dawn, the one character who tries to demand being more authentic amidst the "shark infested waters" of the professional world, basically never gets anywhere. In the highly metaphorical ending of the film, things remain manipulative, political and backstabbing, and in that climate, at least two out of three characters "win". Huang seems to be suggesting that the professional world ain't likely to change any time soon, and that even if you try to change it or manipulate the game itself, you're likely to just get eaten up by it, processed by it and incorporated into it anyway. Again, I can't say I disagree with him.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Essay on the Origins of a Corporate Monster
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sean Lamberger
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Not entirely what you'd expect from the promo art, this strange hybrid of chilling suspense and black comedy bears a surprisingly deep, developed cast of characters and a bitter, intense message about the origins of a corporate monster. Kevin Spacey is at his usual best as the pompous, demeaning studio executive with a finger in every pie, while journeyman Frank Whaley (Brett from Pulp Fiction) overplays the wide-eyed, naive farmboy act as Spacey's hapless assistant at the edge. But while early scenes hint this is just another predictable, pull-for-the-little-man light comedy, the narrative's regular flashes forward in the timeline paint a larger, more sinister picture. When the dust settles, Spacey is revealed to be far more complicated and damaged than he lets on, Whaley has worked himself into a deep, dark pit of trouble and neither man is who they were at the outset. Bewildering at times due to the jolting changes in tone and atmosphere, it lingers with the viewer well after the credits have rolled.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Worth a watch
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    itamarscomix
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Swimming With Sharks is original and daring, but very uneven. I've always been a sucker for films about filmmaking and Hollywood and as such I was willing to let a lot slide, but it had a few too many ups and downs, starting out with a very problematic and ambiguous mix of comedy and tragedy; it then reaches its peak in the second half, when it turns more and more into a full drama; but then disappoints with the ending. And without that ending, it would have been a truly singular film. As it is, it's still an interesting one well worth a watch, if only for Kevin Spacey's performance in the second half, that turns from over-the-top ham to utter and nasty subtlety.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fanaticalaboutfilms Review: Swimming With Sharks
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    James (Fanaticalaboutfilms)
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Swimming With Sharks is set in the cut throat world of the film industry although this doesn't dictate the plot as much as you might think. It follows Guy (Frank Whaley) who is a clean-shaven enthusiastic new recruit into this unique world landing himself a job as the personal assistant to Buddy Ackerman (Kevin Spacey) an expletive throwing repugnant studio executive whose addition to your CV opens every door imaginable but is counteracted so much by his demeanour that many would find it not worth the trouble. Guy seems to have the determination to see it through helped by script writer and love interest Dawn (Michelle Forbes) but after working for the man for over a year, cracks begin to surface and Guy is finally pushed too far showing up at Buddy's home in the middle of the night intent on revenge. What plays out over the 100 minutes is a mixture between the past year of his life and the present unfolding situation. This was George Huang's first (and it would seem only notable) foray into the world of writing and directing and credit must be given to him. The script is impressive with Whaley engrossing himself into the character topped only by Spacey's exceptional performance where he looks set to star in a similar, albeit toned down, role in Horrible Bosses. He not only excels in many of his 'throwing a tantrum' scenes but somehow brings sympathy and compassion to a character that we should not feel anything for. Even when being held hostage he emits a certain smug arrogance that would be misplaced in any other character apart from this one. I felt conflicted given the knowledge at the beginning that Guy kidnaps his boss. It somewhat limits the sympathy you can show towards him regardless of finding out what Buddy did to drive him to such lengths. I wouldn't class this as a comedy per say as this is not going to have you laughing a great deal but rather an extremely dark satire of life in Hollywood and the means required to keep your head above the water. It shows us that the calling of the bright lights can change a man with only a few have what is required to make it. Add all of this together to an unexpected ending and it makes for an interesting watch. Yes there are moments where I felt things were not quite working and the relationship between Dawn and Guy lacked that believability factor but Swimming With Sharks certainly made the time fly and has enough to keep it fresh in the mind for a couple of days at the very least. For further reviews feel free to check out: http://www.fanaticalaboutfilms.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If You Ever Worked in Hollywood, You May Relate to this Fantasy of a Minno Getting Revenge on a Shark
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    classicalsteve
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Because the Hollywood industry is saturated with those who dream of being on the "inside", some people at the higher levels abuse their positions of power. Some of these regard themselves as the equivalent of demi-gods or priest-like figures, guarding the gates of the temple of the film/entertainment industry. They expect to be worshiped or at least revered, allowing the initiated to pass through. Those who are given a chance to become initiates are sometimes subjected to a kind of hazing process in which the poor initiate is subjected to the whims of the high elites. Kevin Spacey plays Buddy Ackerman, the perfect Hollywood shark, a studio executive who believes everything he says and does should be viewed as "gospel" by those who work under him. Guy (Frank Whaley) is his new assistant, or better stated, his new whipping boy. Guy is greener than an unripe tomato, replacing Rex (Benicio del Toro) of whom Buddy says "is a good for nothing mongoloid" on the first day. But before the first day is over, Guy realizes that this is going to be long term abuse. Spacey makes the perfect vain studio executive. One of the best aspects of his performance is that he wavers between seeming reasonable than flying into rages which would give your average wolverine a runs for its money. He berates Guy for giving him the wrong artificial sweetener. He throws books and papers at him. Even occasionally food. He even makes his assistant embark on impossible tasks, such as destroying every single copy of a Time Magazine issue which contained a scathing article about him. Ackerman's motto is "You are nothing. You're opinion means nothing". As book ends to the narrative, we flash to another part of the story: Guy has kidnapped Ackerman and has tied him. He's torturing him as payback. But the abuse is not the only reason Guy wants Buddy to suffer. As bad as Guy's mistreatment, the worst aspect is the executive's habit of taking credit for the deeds of others. In a poignant scene, Ackerman pretends to praise Guy to another executive, but Guy realizes it was false. A very interesting film, mostly for those who have either worked for or been associated with ego-maniacs. The movie industry is chock full of people who believe they are above everyone else because of certain successes. This gives some of them license to abuse others, particularly because so many desire what few positions are available. As Buddy himself says "Life is not a movie. Good guys lose, everybody lies, and love... does not conquer all."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    tongue in cheek brilliance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    charles-okell
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Its so very quotable and finds Spacey in fine form - "my pencil eraser means more to me than you do" has been uttered often by all my team in the studio! Given it has got low production values, the lighting is grainy and their attention to continuity is poor rather than 'on purpose' it does have a jovial, dark hummer that is much more widely accessible than say the likes of Anchor Man which was equally low budget relying on star quality. Do give it a go with friends and a few beers, it improves the experience no end and then watch Horrible Bosses, 21, Casino Jack and hope that Spacey churns the same character out at least a few more times before he disappears into the artistic roles his Thespian bent so clearly desires - he is a film treasure, under utilized and always great in a film... even when the film is rubbish (Casino Jack....)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Kevin Spacey always puts on a great performance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    T Cady
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of those movies where a great actor turns a run of the mill film into a good one. Kevin Spacey is just the sort of actor that always seems to do that. "Swimming with Sharks," is the story of a young man, Guy ( Frank Whaley), who is determined to make his mark in the Movie industry. He lands a job as the assistant to big time Hollywood executive, Buddy Ackerman (Kevin Spacey), and thinks he has the start to launch him into the big time. It turns out that Buddy is not only a bigshot executive but also makes ridiculous demands, and is a downright cruel demanding boss, that seems to have no regard for his assistant or anyone for that matter. How far can Buddy push Guy until he snaps? This is not a new story line, it has been done time after time, but it is a horrible boss story, so everyone can relate to it. I am not a fan of Frank Whaley and actually can't stand him, but he does a decent job in this one. As I said this movie wasn't very original and I probably wouldn't have liked this movie at all if it wasn't for Kevin Spacey. Kevin Spacey did a great job portraying the evil, demanding boss.In my mind, he was what made this movie. Everything in this movie says boring and done before, but Kevin Spacey's performance turns it into a good movie. It's rare that one actor could do that by himself but in this case it is true. Not to reveal anything, but the end takes a twist that is actually a pretty good one. So overall, it was a good movie, not a great one. Spacey turns out to be the only one driving it, but somehow it was enough to make it watchable and at times enjoyable. Like my reviews, hate em? Any questions or comments, or if you want a DVD reviewed just shoot me an e-mail at: subliminal.lithium@gmail.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Here's to all the schmucks who can't tell Sweet'n Low from Equal
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steve Pulaski
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Kevin Spacey, more often than not, gets handed the sharpest, funniest, cleverest, most desirable monologues in his roles. In Glengarry Glen Ross, he delivered cold lines of fury when talking to his deadbeat employees and took some severe blows to the ego when he was jabbed with personal insults. In American Beauty, it was entrancing to hear him narrate his story with such gratitude and depth, along with giving us one of the best performances of the decade. And in K-PAX, he convincingly played an alleged extraterrestrial who seemed to appear out of thin air and turn a skeptical psychiatrist into a true believer. The man is a treasure often shorthanded and under-valued. Spacey gives yet another fantastic performance of true power and control in Swimming With Sharks, a black comedy that is heavy on the laughs and insight, and easy on the levels of conformity and monotony. This is a biting drama of business and progress in the work world, with some of the toughest and most brutal insight into the corporate world that can only be compared to the level of truths brought in Kevin Smith's Clerks and Mike Judge's Office Space. This deserves a spot in the same league. Guy (Frank Whaley) is a young writer who is extremely satisfied to get a job working as the assistant for movie mogul Buddy Ackerman, played by Kevin Spacey. Guy expects the job to be beneficial and insightful, until he sees Buddy's true side, which is loud, obnoxious, pretentious, smothering, overbearing, and just plain unforgiving behavior as he takes pride in being belligerent and disrespectful to his assistants. In an extremely well written scene involving Guy trying to reason with Buddy about his yelling and his uncontrollable tirades, Buddy browbeats him relentlessly by telling him, "my bathmat means more to me than you," at the same time throwing pencils at him saying, "these pencils more important, these pens more important." The key to this scene is that both men have extremely valid points; Guy is trying to speak on a human-level with Buddy and brings up the idea of how in a business relationship, one must have the skill and ability to hold a grown-up discussion with one another. On the other hand, Buddy remarks on how you need to be a man to do the job and you must accept the torment as a means to get somewhere in the world. Further commentary is provided when we open up and see Buddy as more than a cynic, but how he got to be one and whether or not guy is on the same track heading to the same inevitable destination. The film is intercut with scenes showing Guy breaking in to Buddy's home, taking him hostage by tying him to his chair, and preceding to torture him mercilessly, reminding him of all the times he was demanding and ruthless to him. Again, the scene is not supposed to inspire moments of shock and jolts as it is to prove to the audience that both these men have perfectly valid points. Are Guy's actions justifiable? Yes, but they're not particularly right. Are Buddy's reasons for being mean and ruthless to his assistants justified? Yes, but they're not particularly right either. Writer/director George Huang wrote the film based off of what he experienced as an executive assistant at Columbia Pictures. Whether or not the acts he was involved in were this extreme or are fabricated to fit film's high standard I can not say, but Huang clearly knows what aspiring young cinephiles (or just business man on the lowest step of the corporate ladder) must go through and put up with in order to make it big. Where Huang scores effortlessly is in the writing, which is sharp, brutal, and all around satisfying. Seeing these men spit out some of the foulest things imaginable is unbelievably satisfying and is not only played for laughs but for intelligence. While the moments of darkness and subversive violence that are spliced in with the moments of typical office conundrums and tribulations may be a bit abrupt, they are nonetheless faithful and necessary to the film's point. I've always seen film as a device used to depict either morals, ideas, ideologies, places usually left unexplored, utopias, etc, but I've too seen it has a brilliant way to showcase events, lifestyles, and modern quirks. Swimming With Sharks is a brutally well written piece brilliantly taking us into the life of an overworked and under-appreciated businessman who is just looking for respect and fair treatment. Starring: Kevin Spacey and Frank Whaley. Directed by: George Huang.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One Man And His Dog
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    writers_reign
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If it turned out that Kevin Spacey paid the Producers to play this role I wouldn't be surprised given that it is an actor's dream role and one that makes Kirk Douglas's Jonathan Shields in The Bad And The Beautiful seem like a wimp. Douglas himself, who revelled in playing characters like this would have probably gone to the mat with Robert Ryan to play Buddy Ackerman had this film been written when Douglas and Ryan were in their heyday. As it is Spacey hits one out of the park without even trying and the best thing is that there is fine support from the other two leads. Cyanide-laced screenplays about Hollywood are not exactly thin on the ground - we can cite, in chronological order, Sunset Boulevard, The Bad And The Beautiful and Cliff Odets' The Big Knife off the top of our heads and they all appeared within six years of each other in the fifties. Swimming With Sharks may lack the skillful screenplays all three boasted but it is still well worth a look.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Outstanding film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tpaladino
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was originally led to believe (via my Netflix queue) that Swimming With Sharks would be a (dark) comedy. And while there are certain moments of humor, this film is firmly planted in drama territory. But, no matter what label they give it, the film is excellent and very much worth watching. The writing is sharp and interesting, and Spacey and the small cast do a great job with it. It's a very small movie, comprised of a very few actors and locations, but never feels small, thanks to the great depth that the characters are given, as well as the engrossing story. I don't want to reveal too much about the plot, but sufficed to say, it explores the dysfunctional and often tragic professional relationships that are abundant in Hollywood, and the extreme ends that an otherwise reasonable individual can be pushed to. Worth watching for sure.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great flick!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jerry-peanu
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ackerman obviously has problems or he wouldn't be acting quite in the way that he is, but director George Huang and Spacey are also careful to show that Ackerman has a lot more going on than surface behavior--he's acting the way that he is purposefully, both to get his due now as part of the establishment and to coyly manipulate his young, meek and abused underling, Guy (Frank Whaley), along with everyone else he comes into contact with. His aim is to mold Guy in a particular way--a way that works even though Guy thinks that he's severely breaking form in the extended penultimate scene that's intercut with Guy and Ackerman's history. Huang shows professional relationships as consisting mostly of politicking and manipulation. That's true at every level--certainly even Guy is doing this. There is very little authenticity to anyone in their working relationships. That seems pretty accurate to me, unfortunately. It's notable that the one dream of authenticity in the film--Guy talking about moving to Wyoming with Dawn (Michelle Forbes)--is treated and dispensed with as an unreachable fantasy, and it's also notable (and is fairly literally pointed out in the film) that Dawn, the one character who tries to demand being more authentic amidst the "shark infested waters" of the professional world, basically never gets anywhere. In the highly metaphorical ending of the film, things remain manipulative, political and backstabbing, and in that climate, at least two out of three characters "win". Huang seems to be suggesting that the professional world ain't likely to change any time soon, and that even if you try to change it or manipulate the game itself, you're likely to just get eaten up by it, processed by it and incorporated into it anyway. Again, I can't say I disagree with him.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Essay on the Origins of a Corporate Monster
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sean Lamberger
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Not entirely what you'd expect from the promo art, this strange hybrid of chilling suspense and black comedy bears a surprisingly deep, developed cast of characters and a bitter, intense message about the origins of a corporate monster. Kevin Spacey is at his usual best as the pompous, demeaning studio executive with a finger in every pie, while journeyman Frank Whaley (Brett from Pulp Fiction) overplays the wide-eyed, naive farmboy act as Spacey's hapless assistant at the edge. But while early scenes hint this is just another predictable, pull-for-the-little-man light comedy, the narrative's regular flashes forward in the timeline paint a larger, more sinister picture. When the dust settles, Spacey is revealed to be far more complicated and damaged than he lets on, Whaley has worked himself into a deep, dark pit of trouble and neither man is who they were at the outset. Bewildering at times due to the jolting changes in tone and atmosphere, it lingers with the viewer well after the credits have rolled.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Worth a watch
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    itamarscomix
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Swimming With Sharks is original and daring, but very uneven. I've always been a sucker for films about filmmaking and Hollywood and as such I was willing to let a lot slide, but it had a few too many ups and downs, starting out with a very problematic and ambiguous mix of comedy and tragedy; it then reaches its peak in the second half, when it turns more and more into a full drama; but then disappoints with the ending. And without that ending, it would have been a truly singular film. As it is, it's still an interesting one well worth a watch, if only for Kevin Spacey's performance in the second half, that turns from over-the-top ham to utter and nasty subtlety.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fanaticalaboutfilms Review: Swimming With Sharks
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    James (Fanaticalaboutfilms)
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Swimming With Sharks is set in the cut throat world of the film industry although this doesn't dictate the plot as much as you might think. It follows Guy (Frank Whaley) who is a clean-shaven enthusiastic new recruit into this unique world landing himself a job as the personal assistant to Buddy Ackerman (Kevin Spacey) an expletive throwing repugnant studio executive whose addition to your CV opens every door imaginable but is counteracted so much by his demeanour that many would find it not worth the trouble. Guy seems to have the determination to see it through helped by script writer and love interest Dawn (Michelle Forbes) but after working for the man for over a year, cracks begin to surface and Guy is finally pushed too far showing up at Buddy's home in the middle of the night intent on revenge. What plays out over the 100 minutes is a mixture between the past year of his life and the present unfolding situation. This was George Huang's first (and it would seem only notable) foray into the world of writing and directing and credit must be given to him. The script is impressive with Whaley engrossing himself into the character topped only by Spacey's exceptional performance where he looks set to star in a similar, albeit toned down, role in Horrible Bosses. He not only excels in many of his 'throwing a tantrum' scenes but somehow brings sympathy and compassion to a character that we should not feel anything for. Even when being held hostage he emits a certain smug arrogance that would be misplaced in any other character apart from this one. I felt conflicted given the knowledge at the beginning that Guy kidnaps his boss. It somewhat limits the sympathy you can show towards him regardless of finding out what Buddy did to drive him to such lengths. I wouldn't class this as a comedy per say as this is not going to have you laughing a great deal but rather an extremely dark satire of life in Hollywood and the means required to keep your head above the water. It shows us that the calling of the bright lights can change a man with only a few have what is required to make it. Add all of this together to an unexpected ending and it makes for an interesting watch. Yes there are moments where I felt things were not quite working and the relationship between Dawn and Guy lacked that believability factor but Swimming With Sharks certainly made the time fly and has enough to keep it fresh in the mind for a couple of days at the very least. For further reviews feel free to check out: http://www.fanaticalaboutfilms.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If You Ever Worked in Hollywood, You May Relate to this Fantasy of a Minno Getting Revenge on a Shark
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    classicalsteve
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Because the Hollywood industry is saturated with those who dream of being on the "inside", some people at the higher levels abuse their positions of power. Some of these regard themselves as the equivalent of demi-gods or priest-like figures, guarding the gates of the temple of the film/entertainment industry. They expect to be worshiped or at least revered, allowing the initiated to pass through. Those who are given a chance to become initiates are sometimes subjected to a kind of hazing process in which the poor initiate is subjected to the whims of the high elites. Kevin Spacey plays Buddy Ackerman, the perfect Hollywood shark, a studio executive who believes everything he says and does should be viewed as "gospel" by those who work under him. Guy (Frank Whaley) is his new assistant, or better stated, his new whipping boy. Guy is greener than an unripe tomato, replacing Rex (Benicio del Toro) of whom Buddy says "is a good for nothing mongoloid" on the first day. But before the first day is over, Guy realizes that this is going to be long term abuse. Spacey makes the perfect vain studio executive. One of the best aspects of his performance is that he wavers between seeming reasonable than flying into rages which would give your average wolverine a runs for its money. He berates Guy for giving him the wrong artificial sweetener. He throws books and papers at him. Even occasionally food. He even makes his assistant embark on impossible tasks, such as destroying every single copy of a Time Magazine issue which contained a scathing article about him. Ackerman's motto is "You are nothing. You're opinion means nothing". As book ends to the narrative, we flash to another part of the story: Guy has kidnapped Ackerman and has tied him. He's torturing him as payback. But the abuse is not the only reason Guy wants Buddy to suffer. As bad as Guy's mistreatment, the worst aspect is the executive's habit of taking credit for the deeds of others. In a poignant scene, Ackerman pretends to praise Guy to another executive, but Guy realizes it was false. A very interesting film, mostly for those who have either worked for or been associated with ego-maniacs. The movie industry is chock full of people who believe they are above everyone else because of certain successes. This gives some of them license to abuse others, particularly because so many desire what few positions are available. As Buddy himself says "Life is not a movie. Good guys lose, everybody lies, and love... does not conquer all."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    tongue in cheek brilliance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    charles-okell
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Its so very quotable and finds Spacey in fine form - "my pencil eraser means more to me than you do" has been uttered often by all my team in the studio! Given it has got low production values, the lighting is grainy and their attention to continuity is poor rather than 'on purpose' it does have a jovial, dark hummer that is much more widely accessible than say the likes of Anchor Man which was equally low budget relying on star quality. Do give it a go with friends and a few beers, it improves the experience no end and then watch Horrible Bosses, 21, Casino Jack and hope that Spacey churns the same character out at least a few more times before he disappears into the artistic roles his Thespian bent so clearly desires - he is a film treasure, under utilized and always great in a film... even when the film is rubbish (Casino Jack....)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Kevin Spacey always puts on a great performance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    T Cady
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of those movies where a great actor turns a run of the mill film into a good one. Kevin Spacey is just the sort of actor that always seems to do that. "Swimming with Sharks," is the story of a young man, Guy ( Frank Whaley), who is determined to make his mark in the Movie industry. He lands a job as the assistant to big time Hollywood executive, Buddy Ackerman (Kevin Spacey), and thinks he has the start to launch him into the big time. It turns out that Buddy is not only a bigshot executive but also makes ridiculous demands, and is a downright cruel demanding boss, that seems to have no regard for his assistant or anyone for that matter. How far can Buddy push Guy until he snaps? This is not a new story line, it has been done time after time, but it is a horrible boss story, so everyone can relate to it. I am not a fan of Frank Whaley and actually can't stand him, but he does a decent job in this one. As I said this movie wasn't very original and I probably wouldn't have liked this movie at all if it wasn't for Kevin Spacey. Kevin Spacey did a great job portraying the evil, demanding boss.In my mind, he was what made this movie. Everything in this movie says boring and done before, but Kevin Spacey's performance turns it into a good movie. It's rare that one actor could do that by himself but in this case it is true. Not to reveal anything, but the end takes a twist that is actually a pretty good one. So overall, it was a good movie, not a great one. Spacey turns out to be the only one driving it, but somehow it was enough to make it watchable and at times enjoyable. Like my reviews, hate em? Any questions or comments, or if you want a DVD reviewed just shoot me an e-mail at: subliminal.lithium@gmail.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Here's to all the schmucks who can't tell Sweet'n Low from Equal
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steve Pulaski
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Kevin Spacey, more often than not, gets handed the sharpest, funniest, cleverest, most desirable monologues in his roles. In Glengarry Glen Ross, he delivered cold lines of fury when talking to his deadbeat employees and took some severe blows to the ego when he was jabbed with personal insults. In American Beauty, it was entrancing to hear him narrate his story with such gratitude and depth, along with giving us one of the best performances of the decade. And in K-PAX, he convincingly played an alleged extraterrestrial who seemed to appear out of thin air and turn a skeptical psychiatrist into a true believer. The man is a treasure often shorthanded and under-valued. Spacey gives yet another fantastic performance of true power and control in Swimming With Sharks, a black comedy that is heavy on the laughs and insight, and easy on the levels of conformity and monotony. This is a biting drama of business and progress in the work world, with some of the toughest and most brutal insight into the corporate world that can only be compared to the level of truths brought in Kevin Smith's Clerks and Mike Judge's Office Space. This deserves a spot in the same league. Guy (Frank Whaley) is a young writer who is extremely satisfied to get a job working as the assistant for movie mogul Buddy Ackerman, played by Kevin Spacey. Guy expects the job to be beneficial and insightful, until he sees Buddy's true side, which is loud, obnoxious, pretentious, smothering, overbearing, and just plain unforgiving behavior as he takes pride in being belligerent and disrespectful to his assistants. In an extremely well written scene involving Guy trying to reason with Buddy about his yelling and his uncontrollable tirades, Buddy browbeats him relentlessly by telling him, "my bathmat means more to me than you," at the same time throwing pencils at him saying, "these pencils more important, these pens more important." The key to this scene is that both men have extremely valid points; Guy is trying to speak on a human-level with Buddy and brings up the idea of how in a business relationship, one must have the skill and ability to hold a grown-up discussion with one another. On the other hand, Buddy remarks on how you need to be a man to do the job and you must accept the torment as a means to get somewhere in the world. Further commentary is provided when we open up and see Buddy as more than a cynic, but how he got to be one and whether or not guy is on the same track heading to the same inevitable destination. The film is intercut with scenes showing Guy breaking in to Buddy's home, taking him hostage by tying him to his chair, and preceding to torture him mercilessly, reminding him of all the times he was demanding and ruthless to him. Again, the scene is not supposed to inspire moments of shock and jolts as it is to prove to the audience that both these men have perfectly valid points. Are Guy's actions justifiable? Yes, but they're not particularly right. Are Buddy's reasons for being mean and ruthless to his assistants justified? Yes, but they're not particularly right either. Writer/director George Huang wrote the film based off of what he experienced as an executive assistant at Columbia Pictures. Whether or not the acts he was involved in were this extreme or are fabricated to fit film's high standard I can not say, but Huang clearly knows what aspiring young cinephiles (or just business man on the lowest step of the corporate ladder) must go through and put up with in order to make it big. Where Huang scores effortlessly is in the writing, which is sharp, brutal, and all around satisfying. Seeing these men spit out some of the foulest things imaginable is unbelievably satisfying and is not only played for laughs but for intelligence. While the moments of darkness and subversive violence that are spliced in with the moments of typical office conundrums and tribulations may be a bit abrupt, they are nonetheless faithful and necessary to the film's point. I've always seen film as a device used to depict either morals, ideas, ideologies, places usually left unexplored, utopias, etc, but I've too seen it has a brilliant way to showcase events, lifestyles, and modern quirks. Swimming With Sharks is a brutally well written piece brilliantly taking us into the life of an overworked and under-appreciated businessman who is just looking for respect and fair treatment. Starring: Kevin Spacey and Frank Whaley. Directed by: George Huang.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One Man And His Dog
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    writers_reign
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If it turned out that Kevin Spacey paid the Producers to play this role I wouldn't be surprised given that it is an actor's dream role and one that makes Kirk Douglas's Jonathan Shields in The Bad And The Beautiful seem like a wimp. Douglas himself, who revelled in playing characters like this would have probably gone to the mat with Robert Ryan to play Buddy Ackerman had this film been written when Douglas and Ryan were in their heyday. As it is Spacey hits one out of the park without even trying and the best thing is that there is fine support from the other two leads. Cyanide-laced screenplays about Hollywood are not exactly thin on the ground - we can cite, in chronological order, Sunset Boulevard, The Bad And The Beautiful and Cliff Odets' The Big Knife off the top of our heads and they all appeared within six years of each other in the fifties. Swimming With Sharks may lack the skillful screenplays all three boasted but it is still well worth a look.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Outstanding film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tpaladino
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was originally led to believe (via my Netflix queue) that Swimming With Sharks would be a (dark) comedy. And while there are certain moments of humor, this film is firmly planted in drama territory. But, no matter what label they give it, the film is excellent and very much worth watching. The writing is sharp and interesting, and Spacey and the small cast do a great job with it. It's a very small movie, comprised of a very few actors and locations, but never feels small, thanks to the great depth that the characters are given, as well as the engrossing story. I don't want to reveal too much about the plot, but sufficed to say, it explores the dysfunctional and often tragic professional relationships that are abundant in Hollywood, and the extreme ends that an otherwise reasonable individual can be pushed to. Worth watching for sure.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great flick!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jerry-peanu
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ackerman obviously has problems or he wouldn't be acting quite in the way that he is, but director George Huang and Spacey are also careful to show that Ackerman has a lot more going on than surface behavior--he's acting the way that he is purposefully, both to get his due now as part of the establishment and to coyly manipulate his young, meek and abused underling, Guy (Frank Whaley), along with everyone else he comes into contact with. His aim is to mold Guy in a particular way--a way that works even though Guy thinks that he's severely breaking form in the extended penultimate scene that's intercut with Guy and Ackerman's history. Huang shows professional relationships as consisting mostly of politicking and manipulation. That's true at every level--certainly even Guy is doing this. There is very little authenticity to anyone in their working relationships. That seems pretty accurate to me, unfortunately. It's notable that the one dream of authenticity in the film--Guy talking about moving to Wyoming with Dawn (Michelle Forbes)--is treated and dispensed with as an unreachable fantasy, and it's also notable (and is fairly literally pointed out in the film) that Dawn, the one character who tries to demand being more authentic amidst the "shark infested waters" of the professional world, basically never gets anywhere. In the highly metaphorical ending of the film, things remain manipulative, political and backstabbing, and in that climate, at least two out of three characters "win". Huang seems to be suggesting that the professional world ain't likely to change any time soon, and that even if you try to change it or manipulate the game itself, you're likely to just get eaten up by it, processed by it and incorporated into it anyway. Again, I can't say I disagree with him.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Essay on the Origins of a Corporate Monster
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sean Lamberger
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Not entirely what you'd expect from the promo art, this strange hybrid of chilling suspense and black comedy bears a surprisingly deep, developed cast of characters and a bitter, intense message about the origins of a corporate monster. Kevin Spacey is at his usual best as the pompous, demeaning studio executive with a finger in every pie, while journeyman Frank Whaley (Brett from Pulp Fiction) overplays the wide-eyed, naive farmboy act as Spacey's hapless assistant at the edge. But while early scenes hint this is just another predictable, pull-for-the-little-man light comedy, the narrative's regular flashes forward in the timeline paint a larger, more sinister picture. When the dust settles, Spacey is revealed to be far more complicated and damaged than he lets on, Whaley has worked himself into a deep, dark pit of trouble and neither man is who they were at the outset. Bewildering at times due to the jolting changes in tone and atmosphere, it lingers with the viewer well after the credits have rolled.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Worth a watch
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    itamarscomix
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Swimming With Sharks is original and daring, but very uneven. I've always been a sucker for films about filmmaking and Hollywood and as such I was willing to let a lot slide, but it had a few too many ups and downs, starting out with a very problematic and ambiguous mix of comedy and tragedy; it then reaches its peak in the second half, when it turns more and more into a full drama; but then disappoints with the ending. And without that ending, it would have been a truly singular film. As it is, it's still an interesting one well worth a watch, if only for Kevin Spacey's performance in the second half, that turns from over-the-top ham to utter and nasty subtlety.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fanaticalaboutfilms Review: Swimming With Sharks
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    James (Fanaticalaboutfilms)
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Swimming With Sharks is set in the cut throat world of the film industry although this doesn't dictate the plot as much as you might think. It follows Guy (Frank Whaley) who is a clean-shaven enthusiastic new recruit into this unique world landing himself a job as the personal assistant to Buddy Ackerman (Kevin Spacey) an expletive throwing repugnant studio executive whose addition to your CV opens every door imaginable but is counteracted so much by his demeanour that many would find it not worth the trouble. Guy seems to have the determination to see it through helped by script writer and love interest Dawn (Michelle Forbes) but after working for the man for over a year, cracks begin to surface and Guy is finally pushed too far showing up at Buddy's home in the middle of the night intent on revenge. What plays out over the 100 minutes is a mixture between the past year of his life and the present unfolding situation. This was George Huang's first (and it would seem only notable) foray into the world of writing and directing and credit must be given to him. The script is impressive with Whaley engrossing himself into the character topped only by Spacey's exceptional performance where he looks set to star in a similar, albeit toned down, role in Horrible Bosses. He not only excels in many of his 'throwing a tantrum' scenes but somehow brings sympathy and compassion to a character that we should not feel anything for. Even when being held hostage he emits a certain smug arrogance that would be misplaced in any other character apart from this one. I felt conflicted given the knowledge at the beginning that Guy kidnaps his boss. It somewhat limits the sympathy you can show towards him regardless of finding out what Buddy did to drive him to such lengths. I wouldn't class this as a comedy per say as this is not going to have you laughing a great deal but rather an extremely dark satire of life in Hollywood and the means required to keep your head above the water. It shows us that the calling of the bright lights can change a man with only a few have what is required to make it. Add all of this together to an unexpected ending and it makes for an interesting watch. Yes there are moments where I felt things were not quite working and the relationship between Dawn and Guy lacked that believability factor but Swimming With Sharks certainly made the time fly and has enough to keep it fresh in the mind for a couple of days at the very least. For further reviews feel free to check out: http://www.fanaticalaboutfilms.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If You Ever Worked in Hollywood, You May Relate to this Fantasy of a Minno Getting Revenge on a Shark
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    classicalsteve
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Because the Hollywood industry is saturated with those who dream of being on the "inside", some people at the higher levels abuse their positions of power. Some of these regard themselves as the equivalent of demi-gods or priest-like figures, guarding the gates of the temple of the film/entertainment industry. They expect to be worshiped or at least revered, allowing the initiated to pass through. Those who are given a chance to become initiates are sometimes subjected to a kind of hazing process in which the poor initiate is subjected to the whims of the high elites. Kevin Spacey plays Buddy Ackerman, the perfect Hollywood shark, a studio executive who believes everything he says and does should be viewed as "gospel" by those who work under him. Guy (Frank Whaley) is his new assistant, or better stated, his new whipping boy. Guy is greener than an unripe tomato, replacing Rex (Benicio del Toro) of whom Buddy says "is a good for nothing mongoloid" on the first day. But before the first day is over, Guy realizes that this is going to be long term abuse. Spacey makes the perfect vain studio executive. One of the best aspects of his performance is that he wavers between seeming reasonable than flying into rages which would give your average wolverine a runs for its money. He berates Guy for giving him the wrong artificial sweetener. He throws books and papers at him. Even occasionally food. He even makes his assistant embark on impossible tasks, such as destroying every single copy of a Time Magazine issue which contained a scathing article about him. Ackerman's motto is "You are nothing. You're opinion means nothing". As book ends to the narrative, we flash to another part of the story: Guy has kidnapped Ackerman and has tied him. He's torturing him as payback. But the abuse is not the only reason Guy wants Buddy to suffer. As bad as Guy's mistreatment, the worst aspect is the executive's habit of taking credit for the deeds of others. In a poignant scene, Ackerman pretends to praise Guy to another executive, but Guy realizes it was false. A very interesting film, mostly for those who have either worked for or been associated with ego-maniacs. The movie industry is chock full of people who believe they are above everyone else because of certain successes. This gives some of them license to abuse others, particularly because so many desire what few positions are available. As Buddy himself says "Life is not a movie. Good guys lose, everybody lies, and love... does not conquer all."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    tongue in cheek brilliance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    charles-okell
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Its so very quotable and finds Spacey in fine form - "my pencil eraser means more to me than you do" has been uttered often by all my team in the studio! Given it has got low production values, the lighting is grainy and their attention to continuity is poor rather than 'on purpose' it does have a jovial, dark hummer that is much more widely accessible than say the likes of Anchor Man which was equally low budget relying on star quality. Do give it a go with friends and a few beers, it improves the experience no end and then watch Horrible Bosses, 21, Casino Jack and hope that Spacey churns the same character out at least a few more times before he disappears into the artistic roles his Thespian bent so clearly desires - he is a film treasure, under utilized and always great in a film... even when the film is rubbish (Casino Jack....)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Kevin Spacey always puts on a great performance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    T Cady
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of those movies where a great actor turns a run of the mill film into a good one. Kevin Spacey is just the sort of actor that always seems to do that. "Swimming with Sharks," is the story of a young man, Guy ( Frank Whaley), who is determined to make his mark in the Movie industry. He lands a job as the assistant to big time Hollywood executive, Buddy Ackerman (Kevin Spacey), and thinks he has the start to launch him into the big time. It turns out that Buddy is not only a bigshot executive but also makes ridiculous demands, and is a downright cruel demanding boss, that seems to have no regard for his assistant or anyone for that matter. How far can Buddy push Guy until he snaps? This is not a new story line, it has been done time after time, but it is a horrible boss story, so everyone can relate to it. I am not a fan of Frank Whaley and actually can't stand him, but he does a decent job in this one. As I said this movie wasn't very original and I probably wouldn't have liked this movie at all if it wasn't for Kevin Spacey. Kevin Spacey did a great job portraying the evil, demanding boss.In my mind, he was what made this movie. Everything in this movie says boring and done before, but Kevin Spacey's performance turns it into a good movie. It's rare that one actor could do that by himself but in this case it is true. Not to reveal anything, but the end takes a twist that is actually a pretty good one. So overall, it was a good movie, not a great one. Spacey turns out to be the only one driving it, but somehow it was enough to make it watchable and at times enjoyable. Like my reviews, hate em? Any questions or comments, or if you want a DVD reviewed just shoot me an e-mail at: subliminal.lithium@gmail.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Here's to all the schmucks who can't tell Sweet'n Low from Equal
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steve Pulaski
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Kevin Spacey, more often than not, gets handed the sharpest, funniest, cleverest, most desirable monologues in his roles. In Glengarry Glen Ross, he delivered cold lines of fury when talking to his deadbeat employees and took some severe blows to the ego when he was jabbed with personal insults. In American Beauty, it was entrancing to hear him narrate his story with such gratitude and depth, along with giving us one of the best performances of the decade. And in K-PAX, he convincingly played an alleged extraterrestrial who seemed to appear out of thin air and turn a skeptical psychiatrist into a true believer. The man is a treasure often shorthanded and under-valued. Spacey gives yet another fantastic performance of true power and control in Swimming With Sharks, a black comedy that is heavy on the laughs and insight, and easy on the levels of conformity and monotony. This is a biting drama of business and progress in the work world, with some of the toughest and most brutal insight into the corporate world that can only be compared to the level of truths brought in Kevin Smith's Clerks and Mike Judge's Office Space. This deserves a spot in the same league. Guy (Frank Whaley) is a young writer who is extremely satisfied to get a job working as the assistant for movie mogul Buddy Ackerman, played by Kevin Spacey. Guy expects the job to be beneficial and insightful, until he sees Buddy's true side, which is loud, obnoxious, pretentious, smothering, overbearing, and just plain unforgiving behavior as he takes pride in being belligerent and disrespectful to his assistants. In an extremely well written scene involving Guy trying to reason with Buddy about his yelling and his uncontrollable tirades, Buddy browbeats him relentlessly by telling him, "my bathmat means more to me than you," at the same time throwing pencils at him saying, "these pencils more important, these pens more important." The key to this scene is that both men have extremely valid points; Guy is trying to speak on a human-level with Buddy and brings up the idea of how in a business relationship, one must have the skill and ability to hold a grown-up discussion with one another. On the other hand, Buddy remarks on how you need to be a man to do the job and you must accept the torment as a means to get somewhere in the world. Further commentary is provided when we open up and see Buddy as more than a cynic, but how he got to be one and whether or not guy is on the same track heading to the same inevitable destination. The film is intercut with scenes showing Guy breaking in to Buddy's home, taking him hostage by tying him to his chair, and preceding to torture him mercilessly, reminding him of all the times he was demanding and ruthless to him. Again, the scene is not supposed to inspire moments of shock and jolts as it is to prove to the audience that both these men have perfectly valid points. Are Guy's actions justifiable? Yes, but they're not particularly right. Are Buddy's reasons for being mean and ruthless to his assistants justified? Yes, but they're not particularly right either. Writer/director George Huang wrote the film based off of what he experienced as an executive assistant at Columbia Pictures. Whether or not the acts he was involved in were this extreme or are fabricated to fit film's high standard I can not say, but Huang clearly knows what aspiring young cinephiles (or just business man on the lowest step of the corporate ladder) must go through and put up with in order to make it big. Where Huang scores effortlessly is in the writing, which is sharp, brutal, and all around satisfying. Seeing these men spit out some of the foulest things imaginable is unbelievably satisfying and is not only played for laughs but for intelligence. While the moments of darkness and subversive violence that are spliced in with the moments of typical office conundrums and tribulations may be a bit abrupt, they are nonetheless faithful and necessary to the film's point. I've always seen film as a device used to depict either morals, ideas, ideologies, places usually left unexplored, utopias, etc, but I've too seen it has a brilliant way to showcase events, lifestyles, and modern quirks. Swimming With Sharks is a brutally well written piece brilliantly taking us into the life of an overworked and under-appreciated businessman who is just looking for respect and fair treatment. Starring: Kevin Spacey and Frank Whaley. Directed by: George Huang.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One Man And His Dog
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    writers_reign
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If it turned out that Kevin Spacey paid the Producers to play this role I wouldn't be surprised given that it is an actor's dream role and one that makes Kirk Douglas's Jonathan Shields in The Bad And The Beautiful seem like a wimp. Douglas himself, who revelled in playing characters like this would have probably gone to the mat with Robert Ryan to play Buddy Ackerman had this film been written when Douglas and Ryan were in their heyday. As it is Spacey hits one out of the park without even trying and the best thing is that there is fine support from the other two leads. Cyanide-laced screenplays about Hollywood are not exactly thin on the ground - we can cite, in chronological order, Sunset Boulevard, The Bad And The Beautiful and Cliff Odets' The Big Knife off the top of our heads and they all appeared within six years of each other in the fifties. Swimming With Sharks may lack the skillful screenplays all three boasted but it is still well worth a look.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Outstanding film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tpaladino
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was originally led to believe (via my Netflix queue) that Swimming With Sharks would be a (dark) comedy. And while there are certain moments of humor, this film is firmly planted in drama territory. But, no matter what label they give it, the film is excellent and very much worth watching. The writing is sharp and interesting, and Spacey and the small cast do a great job with it. It's a very small movie, comprised of a very few actors and locations, but never feels small, thanks to the great depth that the characters are given, as well as the engrossing story. I don't want to reveal too much about the plot, but sufficed to say, it explores the dysfunctional and often tragic professional relationships that are abundant in Hollywood, and the extreme ends that an otherwise reasonable individual can be pushed to. Worth watching for sure.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great flick!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jerry-peanu
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ackerman obviously has problems or he wouldn't be acting quite in the way that he is, but director George Huang and Spacey are also careful to show that Ackerman has a lot more going on than surface behavior--he's acting the way that he is purposefully, both to get his due now as part of the establishment and to coyly manipulate his young, meek and abused underling, Guy (Frank Whaley), along with everyone else he comes into contact with. His aim is to mold Guy in a particular way--a way that works even though Guy thinks that he's severely breaking form in the extended penultimate scene that's intercut with Guy and Ackerman's history. Huang shows professional relationships as consisting mostly of politicking and manipulation. That's true at every level--certainly even Guy is doing this. There is very little authenticity to anyone in their working relationships. That seems pretty accurate to me, unfortunately. It's notable that the one dream of authenticity in the film--Guy talking about moving to Wyoming with Dawn (Michelle Forbes)--is treated and dispensed with as an unreachable fantasy, and it's also notable (and is fairly literally pointed out in the film) that Dawn, the one character who tries to demand being more authentic amidst the "shark infested waters" of the professional world, basically never gets anywhere. In the highly metaphorical ending of the film, things remain manipulative, political and backstabbing, and in that climate, at least two out of three characters "win". Huang seems to be suggesting that the professional world ain't likely to change any time soon, and that even if you try to change it or manipulate the game itself, you're likely to just get eaten up by it, processed by it and incorporated into it anyway. Again, I can't say I disagree with him.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Essay on the Origins of a Corporate Monster
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sean Lamberger
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Not entirely what you'd expect from the promo art, this strange hybrid of chilling suspense and black comedy bears a surprisingly deep, developed cast of characters and a bitter, intense message about the origins of a corporate monster. Kevin Spacey is at his usual best as the pompous, demeaning studio executive with a finger in every pie, while journeyman Frank Whaley (Brett from Pulp Fiction) overplays the wide-eyed, naive farmboy act as Spacey's hapless assistant at the edge. But while early scenes hint this is just another predictable, pull-for-the-little-man light comedy, the narrative's regular flashes forward in the timeline paint a larger, more sinister picture. When the dust settles, Spacey is revealed to be far more complicated and damaged than he lets on, Whaley has worked himself into a deep, dark pit of trouble and neither man is who they were at the outset. Bewildering at times due to the jolting changes in tone and atmosphere, it lingers with the viewer well after the credits have rolled.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Worth a watch
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    itamarscomix
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Swimming With Sharks is original and daring, but very uneven. I've always been a sucker for films about filmmaking and Hollywood and as such I was willing to let a lot slide, but it had a few too many ups and downs, starting out with a very problematic and ambiguous mix of comedy and tragedy; it then reaches its peak in the second half, when it turns more and more into a full drama; but then disappoints with the ending. And without that ending, it would have been a truly singular film. As it is, it's still an interesting one well worth a watch, if only for Kevin Spacey's performance in the second half, that turns from over-the-top ham to utter and nasty subtlety.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fanaticalaboutfilms Review: Swimming With Sharks
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    James (Fanaticalaboutfilms)
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Swimming With Sharks is set in the cut throat world of the film industry although this doesn't dictate the plot as much as you might think. It follows Guy (Frank Whaley) who is a clean-shaven enthusiastic new recruit into this unique world landing himself a job as the personal assistant to Buddy Ackerman (Kevin Spacey) an expletive throwing repugnant studio executive whose addition to your CV opens every door imaginable but is counteracted so much by his demeanour that many would find it not worth the trouble. Guy seems to have the determination to see it through helped by script writer and love interest Dawn (Michelle Forbes) but after working for the man for over a year, cracks begin to surface and Guy is finally pushed too far showing up at Buddy's home in the middle of the night intent on revenge. What plays out over the 100 minutes is a mixture between the past year of his life and the present unfolding situation. This was George Huang's first (and it would seem only notable) foray into the world of writing and directing and credit must be given to him. The script is impressive with Whaley engrossing himself into the character topped only by Spacey's exceptional performance where he looks set to star in a similar, albeit toned down, role in Horrible Bosses. He not only excels in many of his 'throwing a tantrum' scenes but somehow brings sympathy and compassion to a character that we should not feel anything for. Even when being held hostage he emits a certain smug arrogance that would be misplaced in any other character apart from this one. I felt conflicted given the knowledge at the beginning that Guy kidnaps his boss. It somewhat limits the sympathy you can show towards him regardless of finding out what Buddy did to drive him to such lengths. I wouldn't class this as a comedy per say as this is not going to have you laughing a great deal but rather an extremely dark satire of life in Hollywood and the means required to keep your head above the water. It shows us that the calling of the bright lights can change a man with only a few have what is required to make it. Add all of this together to an unexpected ending and it makes for an interesting watch. Yes there are moments where I felt things were not quite working and the relationship between Dawn and Guy lacked that believability factor but Swimming With Sharks certainly made the time fly and has enough to keep it fresh in the mind for a couple of days at the very least. For further reviews feel free to check out: http://www.fanaticalaboutfilms.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If You Ever Worked in Hollywood, You May Relate to this Fantasy of a Minno Getting Revenge on a Shark
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    classicalsteve
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Because the Hollywood industry is saturated with those who dream of being on the "inside", some people at the higher levels abuse their positions of power. Some of these regard themselves as the equivalent of demi-gods or priest-like figures, guarding the gates of the temple of the film/entertainment industry. They expect to be worshiped or at least revered, allowing the initiated to pass through. Those who are given a chance to become initiates are sometimes subjected to a kind of hazing process in which the poor initiate is subjected to the whims of the high elites. Kevin Spacey plays Buddy Ackerman, the perfect Hollywood shark, a studio executive who believes everything he says and does should be viewed as "gospel" by those who work under him. Guy (Frank Whaley) is his new assistant, or better stated, his new whipping boy. Guy is greener than an unripe tomato, replacing Rex (Benicio del Toro) of whom Buddy says "is a good for nothing mongoloid" on the first day. But before the first day is over, Guy realizes that this is going to be long term abuse. Spacey makes the perfect vain studio executive. One of the best aspects of his performance is that he wavers between seeming reasonable than flying into rages which would give your average wolverine a runs for its money. He berates Guy for giving him the wrong artificial sweetener. He throws books and papers at him. Even occasionally food. He even makes his assistant embark on impossible tasks, such as destroying every single copy of a Time Magazine issue which contained a scathing article about him. Ackerman's motto is "You are nothing. You're opinion means nothing". As book ends to the narrative, we flash to another part of the story: Guy has kidnapped Ackerman and has tied him. He's torturing him as payback. But the abuse is not the only reason Guy wants Buddy to suffer. As bad as Guy's mistreatment, the worst aspect is the executive's habit of taking credit for the deeds of others. In a poignant scene, Ackerman pretends to praise Guy to another executive, but Guy realizes it was false. A very interesting film, mostly for those who have either worked for or been associated with ego-maniacs. The movie industry is chock full of people who believe they are above everyone else because of certain successes. This gives some of them license to abuse others, particularly because so many desire what few positions are available. As Buddy himself says "Life is not a movie. Good guys lose, everybody lies, and love... does not conquer all."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    tongue in cheek brilliance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    charles-okell
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Its so very quotable and finds Spacey in fine form - "my pencil eraser means more to me than you do" has been uttered often by all my team in the studio! Given it has got low production values, the lighting is grainy and their attention to continuity is poor rather than 'on purpose' it does have a jovial, dark hummer that is much more widely accessible than say the likes of Anchor Man which was equally low budget relying on star quality. Do give it a go with friends and a few beers, it improves the experience no end and then watch Horrible Bosses, 21, Casino Jack and hope that Spacey churns the same character out at least a few more times before he disappears into the artistic roles his Thespian bent so clearly desires - he is a film treasure, under utilized and always great in a film... even when the film is rubbish (Casino Jack....)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Kevin Spacey always puts on a great performance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    T Cady
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of those movies where a great actor turns a run of the mill film into a good one. Kevin Spacey is just the sort of actor that always seems to do that. "Swimming with Sharks," is the story of a young man, Guy ( Frank Whaley), who is determined to make his mark in the Movie industry. He lands a job as the assistant to big time Hollywood executive, Buddy Ackerman (Kevin Spacey), and thinks he has the start to launch him into the big time. It turns out that Buddy is not only a bigshot executive but also makes ridiculous demands, and is a downright cruel demanding boss, that seems to have no regard for his assistant or anyone for that matter. How far can Buddy push Guy until he snaps? This is not a new story line, it has been done time after time, but it is a horrible boss story, so everyone can relate to it. I am not a fan of Frank Whaley and actually can't stand him, but he does a decent job in this one. As I said this movie wasn't very original and I probably wouldn't have liked this movie at all if it wasn't for Kevin Spacey. Kevin Spacey did a great job portraying the evil, demanding boss.In my mind, he was what made this movie. Everything in this movie says boring and done before, but Kevin Spacey's performance turns it into a good movie. It's rare that one actor could do that by himself but in this case it is true. Not to reveal anything, but the end takes a twist that is actually a pretty good one. So overall, it was a good movie, not a great one. Spacey turns out to be the only one driving it, but somehow it was enough to make it watchable and at times enjoyable. Like my reviews, hate em? Any questions or comments, or if you want a DVD reviewed just shoot me an e-mail at: subliminal.lithium@gmail.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Here's to all the schmucks who can't tell Sweet'n Low from Equal
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steve Pulaski
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Kevin Spacey, more often than not, gets handed the sharpest, funniest, cleverest, most desirable monologues in his roles. In Glengarry Glen Ross, he delivered cold lines of fury when talking to his deadbeat employees and took some severe blows to the ego when he was jabbed with personal insults. In American Beauty, it was entrancing to hear him narrate his story with such gratitude and depth, along with giving us one of the best performances of the decade. And in K-PAX, he convincingly played an alleged extraterrestrial who seemed to appear out of thin air and turn a skeptical psychiatrist into a true believer. The man is a treasure often shorthanded and under-valued. Spacey gives yet another fantastic performance of true power and control in Swimming With Sharks, a black comedy that is heavy on the laughs and insight, and easy on the levels of conformity and monotony. This is a biting drama of business and progress in the work world, with some of the toughest and most brutal insight into the corporate world that can only be compared to the level of truths brought in Kevin Smith's Clerks and Mike Judge's Office Space. This deserves a spot in the same league. Guy (Frank Whaley) is a young writer who is extremely satisfied to get a job working as the assistant for movie mogul Buddy Ackerman, played by Kevin Spacey. Guy expects the job to be beneficial and insightful, until he sees Buddy's true side, which is loud, obnoxious, pretentious, smothering, overbearing, and just plain unforgiving behavior as he takes pride in being belligerent and disrespectful to his assistants. In an extremely well written scene involving Guy trying to reason with Buddy about his yelling and his uncontrollable tirades, Buddy browbeats him relentlessly by telling him, "my bathmat means more to me than you," at the same time throwing pencils at him saying, "these pencils more important, these pens more important." The key to this scene is that both men have extremely valid points; Guy is trying to speak on a human-level with Buddy and brings up the idea of how in a business relationship, one must have the skill and ability to hold a grown-up discussion with one another. On the other hand, Buddy remarks on how you need to be a man to do the job and you must accept the torment as a means to get somewhere in the world. Further commentary is provided when we open up and see Buddy as more than a cynic, but how he got to be one and whether or not guy is on the same track heading to the same inevitable destination. The film is intercut with scenes showing Guy breaking in to Buddy's home, taking him hostage by tying him to his chair, and preceding to torture him mercilessly, reminding him of all the times he was demanding and ruthless to him. Again, the scene is not supposed to inspire moments of shock and jolts as it is to prove to the audience that both these men have perfectly valid points. Are Guy's actions justifiable? Yes, but they're not particularly right. Are Buddy's reasons for being mean and ruthless to his assistants justified? Yes, but they're not particularly right either. Writer/director George Huang wrote the film based off of what he experienced as an executive assistant at Columbia Pictures. Whether or not the acts he was involved in were this extreme or are fabricated to fit film's high standard I can not say, but Huang clearly knows what aspiring young cinephiles (or just business man on the lowest step of the corporate ladder) must go through and put up with in order to make it big. Where Huang scores effortlessly is in the writing, which is sharp, brutal, and all around satisfying. Seeing these men spit out some of the foulest things imaginable is unbelievably satisfying and is not only played for laughs but for intelligence. While the moments of darkness and subversive violence that are spliced in with the moments of typical office conundrums and tribulations may be a bit abrupt, they are nonetheless faithful and necessary to the film's point. I've always seen film as a device used to depict either morals, ideas, ideologies, places usually left unexplored, utopias, etc, but I've too seen it has a brilliant way to showcase events, lifestyles, and modern quirks. Swimming With Sharks is a brutally well written piece brilliantly taking us into the life of an overworked and under-appreciated businessman who is just looking for respect and fair treatment. Starring: Kevin Spacey and Frank Whaley. Directed by: George Huang.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One Man And His Dog
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    writers_reign
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If it turned out that Kevin Spacey paid the Producers to play this role I wouldn't be surprised given that it is an actor's dream role and one that makes Kirk Douglas's Jonathan Shields in The Bad And The Beautiful seem like a wimp. Douglas himself, who revelled in playing characters like this would have probably gone to the mat with Robert Ryan to play Buddy Ackerman had this film been written when Douglas and Ryan were in their heyday. As it is Spacey hits one out of the park without even trying and the best thing is that there is fine support from the other two leads. Cyanide-laced screenplays about Hollywood are not exactly thin on the ground - we can cite, in chronological order, Sunset Boulevard, The Bad And The Beautiful and Cliff Odets' The Big Knife off the top of our heads and they all appeared within six years of each other in the fifties. Swimming With Sharks may lack the skillful screenplays all three boasted but it is still well worth a look.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Outstanding film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tpaladino
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was originally led to believe (via my Netflix queue) that Swimming With Sharks would be a (dark) comedy. And while there are certain moments of humor, this film is firmly planted in drama territory. But, no matter what label they give it, the film is excellent and very much worth watching. The writing is sharp and interesting, and Spacey and the small cast do a great job with it. It's a very small movie, comprised of a very few actors and locations, but never feels small, thanks to the great depth that the characters are given, as well as the engrossing story. I don't want to reveal too much about the plot, but sufficed to say, it explores the dysfunctional and often tragic professional relationships that are abundant in Hollywood, and the extreme ends that an otherwise reasonable individual can be pushed to. Worth watching for sure.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great flick!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jerry-peanu
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ackerman obviously has problems or he wouldn't be acting quite in the way that he is, but director George Huang and Spacey are also careful to show that Ackerman has a lot more going on than surface behavior--he's acting the way that he is purposefully, both to get his due now as part of the establishment and to coyly manipulate his young, meek and abused underling, Guy (Frank Whaley), along with everyone else he comes into contact with. His aim is to mold Guy in a particular way--a way that works even though Guy thinks that he's severely breaking form in the extended penultimate scene that's intercut with Guy and Ackerman's history. Huang shows professional relationships as consisting mostly of politicking and manipulation. That's true at every level--certainly even Guy is doing this. There is very little authenticity to anyone in their working relationships. That seems pretty accurate to me, unfortunately. It's notable that the one dream of authenticity in the film--Guy talking about moving to Wyoming with Dawn (Michelle Forbes)--is treated and dispensed with as an unreachable fantasy, and it's also notable (and is fairly literally pointed out in the film) that Dawn, the one character who tries to demand being more authentic amidst the "shark infested waters" of the professional world, basically never gets anywhere. In the highly metaphorical ending of the film, things remain manipulative, political and backstabbing, and in that climate, at least two out of three characters "win". Huang seems to be suggesting that the professional world ain't likely to change any time soon, and that even if you try to change it or manipulate the game itself, you're likely to just get eaten up by it, processed by it and incorporated into it anyway. Again, I can't say I disagree with him.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Essay on the Origins of a Corporate Monster
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sean Lamberger
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Not entirely what you'd expect from the promo art, this strange hybrid of chilling suspense and black comedy bears a surprisingly deep, developed cast of characters and a bitter, intense message about the origins of a corporate monster. Kevin Spacey is at his usual best as the pompous, demeaning studio executive with a finger in every pie, while journeyman Frank Whaley (Brett from Pulp Fiction) overplays the wide-eyed, naive farmboy act as Spacey's hapless assistant at the edge. But while early scenes hint this is just another predictable, pull-for-the-little-man light comedy, the narrative's regular flashes forward in the timeline paint a larger, more sinister picture. When the dust settles, Spacey is revealed to be far more complicated and damaged than he lets on, Whaley has worked himself into a deep, dark pit of trouble and neither man is who they were at the outset. Bewildering at times due to the jolting changes in tone and atmosphere, it lingers with the viewer well after the credits have rolled.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Worth a watch
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    itamarscomix
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Swimming With Sharks is original and daring, but very uneven. I've always been a sucker for films about filmmaking and Hollywood and as such I was willing to let a lot slide, but it had a few too many ups and downs, starting out with a very problematic and ambiguous mix of comedy and tragedy; it then reaches its peak in the second half, when it turns more and more into a full drama; but then disappoints with the ending. And without that ending, it would have been a truly singular film. As it is, it's still an interesting one well worth a watch, if only for Kevin Spacey's performance in the second half, that turns from over-the-top ham to utter and nasty subtlety.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fanaticalaboutfilms Review: Swimming With Sharks
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    James (Fanaticalaboutfilms)
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Swimming With Sharks is set in the cut throat world of the film industry although this doesn't dictate the plot as much as you might think. It follows Guy (Frank Whaley) who is a clean-shaven enthusiastic new recruit into this unique world landing himself a job as the personal assistant to Buddy Ackerman (Kevin Spacey) an expletive throwing repugnant studio executive whose addition to your CV opens every door imaginable but is counteracted so much by his demeanour that many would find it not worth the trouble. Guy seems to have the determination to see it through helped by script writer and love interest Dawn (Michelle Forbes) but after working for the man for over a year, cracks begin to surface and Guy is finally pushed too far showing up at Buddy's home in the middle of the night intent on revenge. What plays out over the 100 minutes is a mixture between the past year of his life and the present unfolding situation. This was George Huang's first (and it would seem only notable) foray into the world of writing and directing and credit must be given to him. The script is impressive with Whaley engrossing himself into the character topped only by Spacey's exceptional performance where he looks set to star in a similar, albeit toned down, role in Horrible Bosses. He not only excels in many of his 'throwing a tantrum' scenes but somehow brings sympathy and compassion to a character that we should not feel anything for. Even when being held hostage he emits a certain smug arrogance that would be misplaced in any other character apart from this one. I felt conflicted given the knowledge at the beginning that Guy kidnaps his boss. It somewhat limits the sympathy you can show towards him regardless of finding out what Buddy did to drive him to such lengths. I wouldn't class this as a comedy per say as this is not going to have you laughing a great deal but rather an extremely dark satire of life in Hollywood and the means required to keep your head above the water. It shows us that the calling of the bright lights can change a man with only a few have what is required to make it. Add all of this together to an unexpected ending and it makes for an interesting watch. Yes there are moments where I felt things were not quite working and the relationship between Dawn and Guy lacked that believability factor but Swimming With Sharks certainly made the time fly and has enough to keep it fresh in the mind for a couple of days at the very least. For further reviews feel free to check out: http://www.fanaticalaboutfilms.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    If You Ever Worked in Hollywood, You May Relate to this Fantasy of a Minno Getting Revenge on a Shark
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    classicalsteve
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Because the Hollywood industry is saturated with those who dream of being on the "inside", some people at the higher levels abuse their positions of power. Some of these regard themselves as the equivalent of demi-gods or priest-like figures, guarding the gates of the temple of the film/entertainment industry. They expect to be worshiped or at least revered, allowing the initiated to pass through. Those who are given a chance to become initiates are sometimes subjected to a kind of hazing process in which the poor initiate is subjected to the whims of the high elites. Kevin Spacey plays Buddy Ackerman, the perfect Hollywood shark, a studio executive who believes everything he says and does should be viewed as "gospel" by those who work under him. Guy (Frank Whaley) is his new assistant, or better stated, his new whipping boy. Guy is greener than an unripe tomato, replacing Rex (Benicio del Toro) of whom Buddy says "is a good for nothing mongoloid" on the first day. But before the first day is over, Guy realizes that this is going to be long term abuse. Spacey makes the perfect vain studio executive. One of the best aspects of his performance is that he wavers between seeming reasonable than flying into rages which would give your average wolverine a runs for its money. He berates Guy for giving him the wrong artificial sweetener. He throws books and papers at him. Even occasionally food. He even makes his assistant embark on impossible tasks, such as destroying every single copy of a Time Magazine issue which contained a scathing article about him. Ackerman's motto is "You are nothing. You're opinion means nothing". As book ends to the narrative, we flash to another part of the story: Guy has kidnapped Ackerman and has tied him. He's torturing him as payback. But the abuse is not the only reason Guy wants Buddy to suffer. As bad as Guy's mistreatment, the worst aspect is the executive's habit of taking credit for the deeds of others. In a poignant scene, Ackerman pretends to praise Guy to another executive, but Guy realizes it was false. A very interesting film, mostly for those who have either worked for or been associated with ego-maniacs. The movie industry is chock full of people who believe they are above everyone else because of certain successes. This gives some of them license to abuse others, particularly because so many desire what few positions are available. As Buddy himself says "Life is not a movie. Good guys lose, everybody lies, and love... does not conquer all."
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    tongue in cheek brilliance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    charles-okell
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/11/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Its so very quotable and finds Spacey in fine form - "my pencil eraser means more to me than you do" has been uttered often by all my team in the studio! Given it has got low production values, the lighting is grainy and their attention to continuity is poor rather than 'on purpose' it does have a jovial, dark hummer that is much more widely accessible than say the likes of Anchor Man which was equally low budget relying on star quality. Do give it a go with friends and a few beers, it improves the experience no end and then watch Horrible Bosses, 21, Casino Jack and hope that Spacey churns the same character out at least a few more times before he disappears into the artistic roles his Thespian bent so clearly desires - he is a film treasure, under utilized and always great in a film... even when the film is rubbish (Casino Jack....)
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Kevin Spacey always puts on a great performance
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    T Cady
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is one of those movies where a great actor turns a run of the mill film into a good one. Kevin Spacey is just the sort of actor that always seems to do that. "Swimming with Sharks," is the story of a young man, Guy ( Frank Whaley), who is determined to make his mark in the Movie industry. He lands a job as the assistant to big time Hollywood executive, Buddy Ackerman (Kevin Spacey), and thinks he has the start to launch him into the big time. It turns out that Buddy is not only a bigshot executive but also makes ridiculous demands, and is a downright cruel demanding boss, that seems to have no regard for his assistant or anyone for that matter. How far can Buddy push Guy until he snaps? This is not a new story line, it has been done time after time, but it is a horrible boss story, so everyone can relate to it. I am not a fan of Frank Whaley and actually can't stand him, but he does a decent job in this one. As I said this movie wasn't very original and I probably wouldn't have liked this movie at all if it wasn't for Kevin Spacey. Kevin Spacey did a great job portraying the evil, demanding boss.In my mind, he was what made this movie. Everything in this movie says boring and done before, but Kevin Spacey's performance turns it into a good movie. It's rare that one actor could do that by himself but in this case it is true. Not to reveal anything, but the end takes a twist that is actually a pretty good one. So overall, it was a good movie, not a great one. Spacey turns out to be the only one driving it, but somehow it was enough to make it watchable and at times enjoyable. Like my reviews, hate em? Any questions or comments, or if you want a DVD reviewed just shoot me an e-mail at: subliminal.lithium@gmail.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Here's to all the schmucks who can't tell Sweet'n Low from Equal
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steve Pulaski
   </autor>
   <data>
    31/7/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Kevin Spacey, more often than not, gets handed the sharpest, funniest, cleverest, most desirable monologues in his roles. In Glengarry Glen Ross, he delivered cold lines of fury when talking to his deadbeat employees and took some severe blows to the ego when he was jabbed with personal insults. In American Beauty, it was entrancing to hear him narrate his story with such gratitude and depth, along with giving us one of the best performances of the decade. And in K-PAX, he convincingly played an alleged extraterrestrial who seemed to appear out of thin air and turn a skeptical psychiatrist into a true believer. The man is a treasure often shorthanded and under-valued. Spacey gives yet another fantastic performance of true power and control in Swimming With Sharks, a black comedy that is heavy on the laughs and insight, and easy on the levels of conformity and monotony. This is a biting drama of business and progress in the work world, with some of the toughest and most brutal insight into the corporate world that can only be compared to the level of truths brought in Kevin Smith's Clerks and Mike Judge's Office Space. This deserves a spot in the same league. Guy (Frank Whaley) is a young writer who is extremely satisfied to get a job working as the assistant for movie mogul Buddy Ackerman, played by Kevin Spacey. Guy expects the job to be beneficial and insightful, until he sees Buddy's true side, which is loud, obnoxious, pretentious, smothering, overbearing, and just plain unforgiving behavior as he takes pride in being belligerent and disrespectful to his assistants. In an extremely well written scene involving Guy trying to reason with Buddy about his yelling and his uncontrollable tirades, Buddy browbeats him relentlessly by telling him, "my bathmat means more to me than you," at the same time throwing pencils at him saying, "these pencils more important, these pens more important." The key to this scene is that both men have extremely valid points; Guy is trying to speak on a human-level with Buddy and brings up the idea of how in a business relationship, one must have the skill and ability to hold a grown-up discussion with one another. On the other hand, Buddy remarks on how you need to be a man to do the job and you must accept the torment as a means to get somewhere in the world. Further commentary is provided when we open up and see Buddy as more than a cynic, but how he got to be one and whether or not guy is on the same track heading to the same inevitable destination. The film is intercut with scenes showing Guy breaking in to Buddy's home, taking him hostage by tying him to his chair, and preceding to torture him mercilessly, reminding him of all the times he was demanding and ruthless to him. Again, the scene is not supposed to inspire moments of shock and jolts as it is to prove to the audience that both these men have perfectly valid points. Are Guy's actions justifiable? Yes, but they're not particularly right. Are Buddy's reasons for being mean and ruthless to his assistants justified? Yes, but they're not particularly right either. Writer/director George Huang wrote the film based off of what he experienced as an executive assistant at Columbia Pictures. Whether or not the acts he was involved in were this extreme or are fabricated to fit film's high standard I can not say, but Huang clearly knows what aspiring young cinephiles (or just business man on the lowest step of the corporate ladder) must go through and put up with in order to make it big. Where Huang scores effortlessly is in the writing, which is sharp, brutal, and all around satisfying. Seeing these men spit out some of the foulest things imaginable is unbelievably satisfying and is not only played for laughs but for intelligence. While the moments of darkness and subversive violence that are spliced in with the moments of typical office conundrums and tribulations may be a bit abrupt, they are nonetheless faithful and necessary to the film's point. I've always seen film as a device used to depict either morals, ideas, ideologies, places usually left unexplored, utopias, etc, but I've too seen it has a brilliant way to showcase events, lifestyles, and modern quirks. Swimming With Sharks is a brutally well written piece brilliantly taking us into the life of an overworked and under-appreciated businessman who is just looking for respect and fair treatment. Starring: Kevin Spacey and Frank Whaley. Directed by: George Huang.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One Man And His Dog
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    writers_reign
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    If it turned out that Kevin Spacey paid the Producers to play this role I wouldn't be surprised given that it is an actor's dream role and one that makes Kirk Douglas's Jonathan Shields in The Bad And The Beautiful seem like a wimp. Douglas himself, who revelled in playing characters like this would have probably gone to the mat with Robert Ryan to play Buddy Ackerman had this film been written when Douglas and Ryan were in their heyday. As it is Spacey hits one out of the park without even trying and the best thing is that there is fine support from the other two leads. Cyanide-laced screenplays about Hollywood are not exactly thin on the ground - we can cite, in chronological order, Sunset Boulevard, The Bad And The Beautiful and Cliff Odets' The Big Knife off the top of our heads and they all appeared within six years of each other in the fifties. Swimming With Sharks may lack the skillful screenplays all three boasted but it is still well worth a look.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Outstanding film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tpaladino
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/4/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I was originally led to believe (via my Netflix queue) that Swimming With Sharks would be a (dark) comedy. And while there are certain moments of humor, this film is firmly planted in drama territory. But, no matter what label they give it, the film is excellent and very much worth watching. The writing is sharp and interesting, and Spacey and the small cast do a great job with it. It's a very small movie, comprised of a very few actors and locations, but never feels small, thanks to the great depth that the characters are given, as well as the engrossing story. I don't want to reveal too much about the plot, but sufficed to say, it explores the dysfunctional and often tragic professional relationships that are abundant in Hollywood, and the extreme ends that an otherwise reasonable individual can be pushed to. Worth watching for sure.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Great flick!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jerry-peanu
   </autor>
   <data>
    7/3/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ackerman obviously has problems or he wouldn't be acting quite in the way that he is, but director George Huang and Spacey are also careful to show that Ackerman has a lot more going on than surface behavior--he's acting the way that he is purposefully, both to get his due now as part of the establishment and to coyly manipulate his young, meek and abused underling, Guy (Frank Whaley), along with everyone else he comes into contact with. His aim is to mold Guy in a particular way--a way that works even though Guy thinks that he's severely breaking form in the extended penultimate scene that's intercut with Guy and Ackerman's history. Huang shows professional relationships as consisting mostly of politicking and manipulation. That's true at every level--certainly even Guy is doing this. There is very little authenticity to anyone in their working relationships. That seems pretty accurate to me, unfortunately. It's notable that the one dream of authenticity in the film--Guy talking about moving to Wyoming with Dawn (Michelle Forbes)--is treated and dispensed with as an unreachable fantasy, and it's also notable (and is fairly literally pointed out in the film) that Dawn, the one character who tries to demand being more authentic amidst the "shark infested waters" of the professional world, basically never gets anywhere. In the highly metaphorical ending of the film, things remain manipulative, political and backstabbing, and in that climate, at least two out of three characters "win". Huang seems to be suggesting that the professional world ain't likely to change any time soon, and that even if you try to change it or manipulate the game itself, you're likely to just get eaten up by it, processed by it and incorporated into it anyway. Again, I can't say I disagree with him.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Essay on the Origins of a Corporate Monster
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Sean Lamberger
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Not entirely what you'd expect from the promo art, this strange hybrid of chilling suspense and black comedy bears a surprisingly deep, developed cast of characters and a bitter, intense message about the origins of a corporate monster. Kevin Spacey is at his usual best as the pompous, demeaning studio executive with a finger in every pie, while journeyman Frank Whaley (Brett from Pulp Fiction) overplays the wide-eyed, naive farmboy act as Spacey's hapless assistant at the edge. But while early scenes hint this is just another predictable, pull-for-the-little-man light comedy, the narrative's regular flashes forward in the timeline paint a larger, more sinister picture. When the dust settles, Spacey is revealed to be far more complicated and damaged than he lets on, Whaley has worked himself into a deep, dark pit of trouble and neither man is who they were at the outset. Bewildering at times due to the jolting changes in tone and atmosphere, it lingers with the viewer well after the credits have rolled.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Worth a watch
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    itamarscomix
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/1/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Swimming With Sharks is original and daring, but very uneven. I've always been a sucker for films about filmmaking and Hollywood and as such I was willing to let a lot slide, but it had a few too many ups and downs, starting out with a very problematic and ambiguous mix of comedy and tragedy; it then reaches its peak in the second half, when it turns more and more into a full drama; but then disappoints with the ending. And without that ending, it would have been a truly singular film. As it is, it's still an interesting one well worth a watch, if only for Kevin Spacey's performance in the second half, that turns from over-the-top ham to utter and nasty subtlety.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Fanaticalaboutfilms Review: Swimming With Sharks
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    James (Fanaticalaboutfilms)
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/6/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Swimming With Sharks is set in the cut throat world of the film industry although this doesn't dictate the plot as much as you might think. It follows Guy (Frank Whaley) who is a clean-shaven enthusiastic new recruit into this unique world landing himself a job as the personal assistant to Buddy Ackerman (Kevin Spacey) an expletive throwing repugnant studio executive whose addition to your CV opens every door imaginable but is counteracted so much by his demeanour that many would find it not worth the trouble. Guy seems to have the determination to see it through helped by script writer and love interest Dawn (Michelle Forbes) but after working for the man for over a year, cracks begin to surface and Guy is finally pushed too far showing up at Buddy's home in the middle of the night intent on revenge. What plays out over the 100 minutes is a mixture between the past year of his life and the present unfolding situation. This was George Huang's first (and it would seem only notable) foray into the world of writing and directing and credit must be given to him. The script is impressive with Whaley engrossing himself into the character topped only by Spacey's exceptional performance where he looks set to star in a similar, albeit toned down, role in Horrible Bosses. He not only excels in many of his 'throwing a tantrum' scenes but somehow brings sympathy and compassion to a character that we should not feel anything for. Even when being held hostage he emits a certain smug arrogance that would be misplaced in any other character apart from this one. I felt conflicted given the knowledge at the beginning that Guy kidnaps his boss. It somewhat limits the sympathy you can show towards him regardless of finding out what Buddy did to drive him to such lengths. I wouldn't class this as a comedy per say as this is not going to have you laughing a great deal but rather an extremely dark satire of life in Hollywood and the means required to keep your head above the water. It shows us that the calling of the bright lights can change a man with only a few have what is required to make it. Add all of this together to an unexpected ending and it makes for an interesting watch. Yes there are moments where I felt things were not quite working and the relationship between Dawn and Guy lacked that believability factor but Swimming With Sharks certainly made the time fly and has enough to keep it fresh in the mind for a couple of days at the very least. For further reviews feel free to check out: http://www.fanaticalaboutfilms.com
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
