<filme>
 <id>
  793
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0109504
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1994
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Crooklyn
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.6
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  From Spike Lee comes this vibrant semi-autobiographical portrait of a school-teacher, her stubborn jazz-musician husband and their five kids living in '70s Brooklyn.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  From Spike Lee comes this vibrant semi-autobiographical portrait of a school-teacher, her stubborn jazz-musician husband and their five kids living in '70s Brooklyn.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   semi autobiographical
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   dog
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   domineering mother
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   poverty
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   1970s
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Spike Lee
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Cinqu&eacute; Lee
  </escritor>
  <escritor>
   Joie Lee
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Alfre Woodard
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Delroy Lindo
  </ator>
  <ator>
   David Patrick Kelly
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    GREAT except for Distortion effect
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kimbakat
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The distortion doesn't complement anything...and certainly doesn't communicate the blatant literal attempt it tries to. It just takes away from the wonderfully acted and designed set that captures living in the midwest 1970s so well...that now the distortion takes away from it. The distortion is a really bad idea because your audience is immediately distracted by the first thought as to 'What is wrong with the projectionist?" Next thought is you are now well aware you are in a theatre watching a possible technically error. Thanks for reminding me I'm in a movie...watching a movie....because that's the goal of all filmmakers. At that point, your train of thought has taken you away from the action happening in wonderful detail in the actors expression and set design you fail to miss this "blatant literal" attempt to tell your audience that they can't possibly understand this change in the character's environment so now "I'm going to help you because you are too stupid by the 40 minutes of Brooklyn living to see the difference between the two environments!" Either Spike felt his actors were so bad or his audience to stupid to get it. Sorry Spike...most of us were exposed to slumber parties in other households as children where the culture and environment was vastly different from our own. We didn't need distortion glasses then to know our environment changed...trust me..your audience get's it and would've better appreciated your art departments, wardrobe's work and the actors performance better without the distortion. Do you really need to be that literal? Are Brooklynites that stupid to get and you put it in there for them? Or do you think people in the suburbs would be too stupid to get it? Really? Any chance of releasing a "Fixed Crooklyn" version so that every time I see that scene....I don't feel like I'm being spoon-fed a narrow viewpoint of a Brooklynite that never got out of their house for a slumber party in the 70s or couldn't fathom other lifestyles? I'm sorry..I don't know about the Brooklyn school system but we had geography and social studies in Middle School. We were taught about other cultures way back in the 70s. I would have expected you would've known about the other world outside your neighborhood by the time you made this movie. The distortion effect is an epic fail on really one of your best family drama films. It's like a turd in the middle of this great Brooklyn experience of a story. Other than that...it's a great movie with a lot of replay value. If you ever watch Soul Train back in the 70s or been to a slumber party.....this movie captures the period in a very realistic way! Too bad the distortion takes away from the reality of the suburb scene. I wonder why he didn't distort any of the reality of the Brooklyn scenes? I would think someone coming to Brooklyn from the burbs would expect to see all their movies shot in Brooklyn to have a distorted effect in their local theatres. Hmmm...call me stupid!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Charmingly fitting patchwork
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Shamek Stepien
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Thrust back to the past in a Spike Lee joint with an unwinking essence of 1970s, "Crooklyn" is a semi-autobiographical coming-of-age story, which goes nowhere, but nonetheless vividly portrays a certain mystic detachment of youthful bliss. Focused on the Carmicheal family, where Carolyn (Alfre Woodard) carries the household working as a teacher, while her husband Woody (Delroy Lindo), a jazz musician, attempts to find livelihood off a solo career. In the midst of all this jazz is their family of five, where are eyes into the world is the only girl of the rat-pack - Troy (a remarkable Zelda Harris). Spike Lee's younger self of sorts is an unmistakeably geekishly freakish four-eyes Clinton (Carlton Williams), the eldest brother and antagonist of tomboy Troy. Constructed more on tidbits of memories and recollections "Crooklyn" reminds a patchwork of visions, occurrences and situations, which irrelevant by themselves create a striking personal picture of the family (and ergo Lee's youthful days). Chaotic and lively, simultaneously packed with intimacy, Spike Lee manages to deliver a movie lacking his overwhelming preachiness, which despite being somewhat laid back packs a strong emotional punch. Fronted by a charismatic Zelda Harris and packed with bootie-tastic pop music hits it has a unmissable lure and light aura, that makes this possible Spike Lee's easiest and undoubtedly his most family-friendly feature, which steers far clear of mawkish dramaturgy, instead coming from the heart with a subtle triumph.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Spike Lee's Crooklyn is a nice look back at '70s Brooklyn
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tavm
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just watched this Spike Lee Joint on YouTube. It's largely about a family in Brooklyn during the early '70s based on Spike's siblings and parents during that part when he was growing up there. The mother Carolyn (Alfre Woodard) is the breadwinner as a teacher who constantly gets upset whenever her kids-Clinton (Carlton Williams) who is based on Spike himself, Wendell (Sharif Rashed), Nate (Chris Knowings), and Joseph (Tse-Mach Washington) disobey her orders. The same goes to her musician husband Woody (Delroy Lindo) who no longer is willing to compromise himself for his autonomy. Only her daughter Troy (Zelda Harris) seems to mostly escape her wrath. She's based on Spike's real-life sis Joie Susannah Lee who plays Aunt Maxine here and helped write the screenplay with Spike and other sibling Cinque. There's plenty of drama and some laughs like when Troy goes down South to visit her Aunt Song (Frances Foster), Uncle Clem (Norman Matlock), and cousin Viola (Patriece Nelson) especially when Aunt Song inadvertently offends Troy in commenting on her hair. That scene is shot in a distorted way that is pretty alienating though whenever it's on Troy and Viola, there's still some joy to be had especially when The Jackson 5's "ABC" is playing. In fact, several of the songs from that period evoke such a nostalgia on my part that when the YouTube upload went silent because of some copyright infringement on the part of Warner Music Group because of some song that they own, the subtitles took care of what was playing and I was at least able to imagine how the scene played with the music. Anyway, I liked this movie despite some of what I cited and recommend it highly. P.S. Lee himself appears as Snuffy and familiar faces like RuPaul, Isaiah Washington, and Vondie Curtis-Hall as Uncle Brown are also fun to look for. And I dedicate this review in memory of the late Don Cornelius whose "Soul Train" plays as part of the ending.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Relate,maybe
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (dunsuls@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Released in 1994 and running a little long at 115 minutes.My favorite hard ass director goes soft trying to be edgy in this whimsical story of growing up in Brooklyn back in the day.I loved it but not as a Spike picture,rather as remembering what a neighborhood was all about and family and kids and just because they are all black there is a lot I remember like it.About as edgy as it gets is Spike in a small role as Snuffy,gets hit in the head by Zelda Harris as Troy,the real star of this film and gezz I wonder where she went?? Alfre Woodard as Carolyn Carmichael and Delroy Lindo as Woody Carmichael are great as the parents who are trying to raise their 5 kids in Crooklyn but it's hard and there are tragic things that happen and at the end young Troy is now the anchor of the family and it's future is not certain.The soundtrack is wonderful representing music from the 70's,the acting is first rate as Spike always finds talent and the story, while soft by Spike standards ,is still very strong by white standards and sad in many ways besides being hopeful.I'm white and was raised in Brooklyn and I thought I had it easy after seeing this film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of my favorites of all times
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jjbsdoll
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am a long-time Spike Lee fan and I saw Crooklyn when it first came out. I just watched it again. Seventeen years later, my love for this movie hasn't waned. This is a simple movie about regular human beings living ordinary lives in a specific time and place fondly remembered by Spike Lee (and those of us who grew up in large urban centers in the 70s). It's not in your face, it doesn't preach, it doesn't alienate. It just is-and it's something everyone can relate to who has been a sister/brother/child/parent/close relative/kid enjoying his or her summer. Because of that, I believe this movie is Spike Lee's crowning achievement. Indeed, I think it's a movie that could be envied by other film makers who attempt "slice of life" movies.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Crooklyn-Stereotyping At Its Best ***
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You wonder how N.Y.C. teachers can put up with what they have to after viewing this 1994 film. After all, Alfre Woodard plays a teacher herself who heads a dysfunctional family. She and Delroy Lindo give credible performances as parents trying to cope in urban society with 5 children. The children act like too many of our children act today. Rude, loud, boisterous, fighting and again I heard the familiar expression-"Get off of me" when I taught as well. There are 4 boys and 1 girl. When the girl goes stay with family in Virginia during the summer, we find a beautiful home but there is that constant bickering again this time between the uncle and aunt with an adopted teenage daughter. It only takes for a family tragedy for the children to come together. Sad, but unfortunately true, there is tremendous stereotyping here of the African American family. This is not the Cosby show.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A tree grows in Crooklyn
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Newsense
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/1/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ahhh who can forget the good Ol' days of Spike Lee films that had heart as well as insight? Who can forget this gem? Crooklyn is loosely based on Spike Lee's life growing up. Its mostly a story that mostly details the struggles of a family growing up in Brooklyn as seen through the eyes of Troy(played by Zelda Harris). There are beautiful performances to be seen here. Alfre Woodard's presence is felt as the stern but loving mother of four kids and Delroy Lindo's is great as the father who is also dealing with pressure as a struggling musician and trying to pay the rent on time. They go through the normal strife that any black family has to go through in poor areas but they still find a way to maintain. I remember as a kid that the last scene with the mom passing on had me choked up. Troy and her brother holding hands at the reception for the funeral was a touching scene too. They drove each other crazy but it was still love in the end. Crooklyn has brief moments of awareness like one scene in particular: Troy's aunt comparing troy's hair to her adopted child's hair saying that the adopted child's hair was good hair and that Troy's hair was rough was a subtle form of self-hatred but most people wouldn't pick up on that. Of course Spike Lee has to make an appearance in the movie. He plays a junkie who chases kids around trying to steal money from them. In short Crooklyn stands out as one the best dramas of all time and one of Spike Lee's best work. The characters are ones that you care about, their struggles are real and anybody who has been there can also relate. Two thumbs up for Spike Lee's work of art on film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a pleasantly buoyant and personal Spike Lee film that only feels disconnected in the last act
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MisterWhiplash
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/8/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Crooklyn has that subjective texture by someone of the New York independent school of film-making (which means it's a cool school more often than not), where personal expression through the medium leads directly into, or out of, the creator's own life experiences. It's a direct approach to call it autobiography, which I would imagine it is for not just Spike Lee (who could be seen, more or less, as the one Carmichael kid who wears big glasses and is obsessed with the Knicks), but Joie (the lead Troy perhaps ?) and Cinque (one of the younger kids I'd suppose as the youngest Lee sibling), who all wrote the script. It's about a family getting by and going through the struggles of the small kind (change the channel, turn off the TV, don't bother your sister/brother, did you steal that from him, etc) to the larger issues (parents arguing over money) that many families in urban sections of the cities have to go through every day. Only here the family is sassy, rude, cool, a little square, a little hip, and very identifiable in one aspect or another in just how siblings relate, how the neighbors get on nerves (in this case with a slight racial edge, it is a Spike Lee movie after all), and yet deep down lots of love all around. The Lee's inject a good deal of humor and warmth for a good 2/3 of the film, even when Spike moves the scene down south where Troy (Zelda Harris) has to stay with relatives for a little while, and Lee takes off the widescreen anamorphic process in order to make it a consistently distorted image. This is actually quite a cool move, if at first a little uneasy, as it goes in and out sometimes of looking like its distorted and then it will look like the characters and set pieces are skinny and such (the fate of the relative's dog, by the way, is one of the biggest, if cruelest, laughs in the whole film). At Crooklyn's best, there's a whole feeling to the proceedings, much like Do the Right Thing- and going back as well to the early work of Scorsese- where just a small section of New York city opens up to the viewer as being as vivid and true as possible that the lack of a usual plot doesn't matter much. Sometimes a scene might not work quite as much as another, or one of the many songs Lee lays on (and there are many, as it's one of the best soundtracks he's presented) overrides what could do without in the scene. But in general these are small quibbles. The biggest problem that the film has- and it's not without truth to Lee's real life- is the death of mother Carolyn. It happens as soon as Troy comes back from the south that she's in the hospital, and two scenes later she's gone. It's a sudden shift in the story that doesn't really feel as true as it could, almost as if Lee and his sibling writers don't know where to go once Troy gets back except to go towards sentimentality. It's still well-acted, particularly by Delroy Lindo, who overall gives one of his best performances to date as the struggling father of the family, but it's an odd jolt that doesn't rightly click (especially with a bit where a funeral scene is interrupted by what looks like a dream scene involving Spike himself, sporting a big afro, as a target of Troy's). And yet, I wouldn't stop anyone from seeing the Crooklyn, if they want to get to see some of the less politically charged and more personal and bittersweet side of Lee, and for those who have fond memories of New York (and TV or the Knicks) in the 70s.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Uneven Joint
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    OllieZ
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/5/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Although I wouldn't say this is a great Lee film, it is still very solid. There isn't a story as such, instead it is a love letter to childhood and family life in Brooklyn. Imagine Radio Days, including the sentimental streak. The actors are great and this movie only goes to prove that Delroy Lindo is one of the best actors around. Zelda Harris as the young girl, Troy, is also brilliant. Alfre Woodard is the pivot of the film, around which most of the film revolves around - even if she has less than Troy. Tonally the film doesn't quite click. Sometimes the original music is quite sour and does not fit with the images. Some scenes seem forced. But the amazing soundtrack helps put things right. Even though the film isn't perfect, it has a great soundtrack and a very unique take on things.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Family is Family
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jzappa
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/12/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is just something about Spike Lee's films that has such an intensity and a natural beginning-to-end flow to its jabs at the heart. They're not sentimental nor are they necessarily depressing or mournful; they simply send you head first into the action of the characters, making you literally feel as if you are actually there with them. At least for me, he succeeds in doing this almost magical thing with every single one of his films, from She's Gotta Have It to Inside Man. Even with the films of his that aren't very good, like Girl 6 and She Hate Me, I'm still completely enthralled in the story. Crooklyn has a story with no main focus. Its characters just exist, and life just happens to them, sometimes nudging them like a begging dog and sometimes splashing in their faces like a bucket of soap. I feel cleansed while and after watching it. Anyone who's clicked on my name and has read through other comments of mine on other films may not find it surprising that I'm appalled at the scene where the dog pops out of the couch when the bed is being pulled out. There is really no need for this scene at all. Why kill the dog? Like it's some joke to get back on the woman for being annoying? However, miraculously, as it's very hard for me to forgive a movie when an inexplicable animal death or scene or cruelty towards any animal occurs, I still love this film. The single bias I have that can nearly always ruin a movie for me otherwise is hesitantly but irresistibly dismissed. Spike Lee's films are things we should put in time capsules if global warming dooms the world. When some civilization discovers the ruins of our ravaged existence, they are some of the things that should be found. And of course a projector or a TV or something to play the movies on, otherwise there's no point. Crooklyn is one of the great family films and also one of the great slice of life movies, because it does what the majority of movies don't do but are supposed to do, which is send you through the emotions that the characters are feeling and become immersed in their world. The music, its placement, the clear and forceful and even sometimes jolting cinematography, the strong performances by Alfre Woodard, Delroy Lindo, and virtually all of the children, and the intense and inspiring reality and freshness of the writing making Crooklyn very much worth a look.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    GREAT except for Distortion effect
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kimbakat
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The distortion doesn't complement anything...and certainly doesn't communicate the blatant literal attempt it tries to. It just takes away from the wonderfully acted and designed set that captures living in the midwest 1970s so well...that now the distortion takes away from it. The distortion is a really bad idea because your audience is immediately distracted by the first thought as to 'What is wrong with the projectionist?" Next thought is you are now well aware you are in a theatre watching a possible technically error. Thanks for reminding me I'm in a movie...watching a movie....because that's the goal of all filmmakers. At that point, your train of thought has taken you away from the action happening in wonderful detail in the actors expression and set design you fail to miss this "blatant literal" attempt to tell your audience that they can't possibly understand this change in the character's environment so now "I'm going to help you because you are too stupid by the 40 minutes of Brooklyn living to see the difference between the two environments!" Either Spike felt his actors were so bad or his audience to stupid to get it. Sorry Spike...most of us were exposed to slumber parties in other households as children where the culture and environment was vastly different from our own. We didn't need distortion glasses then to know our environment changed...trust me..your audience get's it and would've better appreciated your art departments, wardrobe's work and the actors performance better without the distortion. Do you really need to be that literal? Are Brooklynites that stupid to get and you put it in there for them? Or do you think people in the suburbs would be too stupid to get it? Really? Any chance of releasing a "Fixed Crooklyn" version so that every time I see that scene....I don't feel like I'm being spoon-fed a narrow viewpoint of a Brooklynite that never got out of their house for a slumber party in the 70s or couldn't fathom other lifestyles? I'm sorry..I don't know about the Brooklyn school system but we had geography and social studies in Middle School. We were taught about other cultures way back in the 70s. I would have expected you would've known about the other world outside your neighborhood by the time you made this movie. The distortion effect is an epic fail on really one of your best family drama films. It's like a turd in the middle of this great Brooklyn experience of a story. Other than that...it's a great movie with a lot of replay value. If you ever watch Soul Train back in the 70s or been to a slumber party.....this movie captures the period in a very realistic way! Too bad the distortion takes away from the reality of the suburb scene. I wonder why he didn't distort any of the reality of the Brooklyn scenes? I would think someone coming to Brooklyn from the burbs would expect to see all their movies shot in Brooklyn to have a distorted effect in their local theatres. Hmmm...call me stupid!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Charmingly fitting patchwork
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Shamek Stepien
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Thrust back to the past in a Spike Lee joint with an unwinking essence of 1970s, "Crooklyn" is a semi-autobiographical coming-of-age story, which goes nowhere, but nonetheless vividly portrays a certain mystic detachment of youthful bliss. Focused on the Carmicheal family, where Carolyn (Alfre Woodard) carries the household working as a teacher, while her husband Woody (Delroy Lindo), a jazz musician, attempts to find livelihood off a solo career. In the midst of all this jazz is their family of five, where are eyes into the world is the only girl of the rat-pack - Troy (a remarkable Zelda Harris). Spike Lee's younger self of sorts is an unmistakeably geekishly freakish four-eyes Clinton (Carlton Williams), the eldest brother and antagonist of tomboy Troy. Constructed more on tidbits of memories and recollections "Crooklyn" reminds a patchwork of visions, occurrences and situations, which irrelevant by themselves create a striking personal picture of the family (and ergo Lee's youthful days). Chaotic and lively, simultaneously packed with intimacy, Spike Lee manages to deliver a movie lacking his overwhelming preachiness, which despite being somewhat laid back packs a strong emotional punch. Fronted by a charismatic Zelda Harris and packed with bootie-tastic pop music hits it has a unmissable lure and light aura, that makes this possible Spike Lee's easiest and undoubtedly his most family-friendly feature, which steers far clear of mawkish dramaturgy, instead coming from the heart with a subtle triumph.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Spike Lee's Crooklyn is a nice look back at '70s Brooklyn
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tavm
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just watched this Spike Lee Joint on YouTube. It's largely about a family in Brooklyn during the early '70s based on Spike's siblings and parents during that part when he was growing up there. The mother Carolyn (Alfre Woodard) is the breadwinner as a teacher who constantly gets upset whenever her kids-Clinton (Carlton Williams) who is based on Spike himself, Wendell (Sharif Rashed), Nate (Chris Knowings), and Joseph (Tse-Mach Washington) disobey her orders. The same goes to her musician husband Woody (Delroy Lindo) who no longer is willing to compromise himself for his autonomy. Only her daughter Troy (Zelda Harris) seems to mostly escape her wrath. She's based on Spike's real-life sis Joie Susannah Lee who plays Aunt Maxine here and helped write the screenplay with Spike and other sibling Cinque. There's plenty of drama and some laughs like when Troy goes down South to visit her Aunt Song (Frances Foster), Uncle Clem (Norman Matlock), and cousin Viola (Patriece Nelson) especially when Aunt Song inadvertently offends Troy in commenting on her hair. That scene is shot in a distorted way that is pretty alienating though whenever it's on Troy and Viola, there's still some joy to be had especially when The Jackson 5's "ABC" is playing. In fact, several of the songs from that period evoke such a nostalgia on my part that when the YouTube upload went silent because of some copyright infringement on the part of Warner Music Group because of some song that they own, the subtitles took care of what was playing and I was at least able to imagine how the scene played with the music. Anyway, I liked this movie despite some of what I cited and recommend it highly. P.S. Lee himself appears as Snuffy and familiar faces like RuPaul, Isaiah Washington, and Vondie Curtis-Hall as Uncle Brown are also fun to look for. And I dedicate this review in memory of the late Don Cornelius whose "Soul Train" plays as part of the ending.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Relate,maybe
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (dunsuls@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Released in 1994 and running a little long at 115 minutes.My favorite hard ass director goes soft trying to be edgy in this whimsical story of growing up in Brooklyn back in the day.I loved it but not as a Spike picture,rather as remembering what a neighborhood was all about and family and kids and just because they are all black there is a lot I remember like it.About as edgy as it gets is Spike in a small role as Snuffy,gets hit in the head by Zelda Harris as Troy,the real star of this film and gezz I wonder where she went?? Alfre Woodard as Carolyn Carmichael and Delroy Lindo as Woody Carmichael are great as the parents who are trying to raise their 5 kids in Crooklyn but it's hard and there are tragic things that happen and at the end young Troy is now the anchor of the family and it's future is not certain.The soundtrack is wonderful representing music from the 70's,the acting is first rate as Spike always finds talent and the story, while soft by Spike standards ,is still very strong by white standards and sad in many ways besides being hopeful.I'm white and was raised in Brooklyn and I thought I had it easy after seeing this film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of my favorites of all times
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jjbsdoll
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am a long-time Spike Lee fan and I saw Crooklyn when it first came out. I just watched it again. Seventeen years later, my love for this movie hasn't waned. This is a simple movie about regular human beings living ordinary lives in a specific time and place fondly remembered by Spike Lee (and those of us who grew up in large urban centers in the 70s). It's not in your face, it doesn't preach, it doesn't alienate. It just is-and it's something everyone can relate to who has been a sister/brother/child/parent/close relative/kid enjoying his or her summer. Because of that, I believe this movie is Spike Lee's crowning achievement. Indeed, I think it's a movie that could be envied by other film makers who attempt "slice of life" movies.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Crooklyn-Stereotyping At Its Best ***
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You wonder how N.Y.C. teachers can put up with what they have to after viewing this 1994 film. After all, Alfre Woodard plays a teacher herself who heads a dysfunctional family. She and Delroy Lindo give credible performances as parents trying to cope in urban society with 5 children. The children act like too many of our children act today. Rude, loud, boisterous, fighting and again I heard the familiar expression-"Get off of me" when I taught as well. There are 4 boys and 1 girl. When the girl goes stay with family in Virginia during the summer, we find a beautiful home but there is that constant bickering again this time between the uncle and aunt with an adopted teenage daughter. It only takes for a family tragedy for the children to come together. Sad, but unfortunately true, there is tremendous stereotyping here of the African American family. This is not the Cosby show.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A tree grows in Crooklyn
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Newsense
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/1/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ahhh who can forget the good Ol' days of Spike Lee films that had heart as well as insight? Who can forget this gem? Crooklyn is loosely based on Spike Lee's life growing up. Its mostly a story that mostly details the struggles of a family growing up in Brooklyn as seen through the eyes of Troy(played by Zelda Harris). There are beautiful performances to be seen here. Alfre Woodard's presence is felt as the stern but loving mother of four kids and Delroy Lindo's is great as the father who is also dealing with pressure as a struggling musician and trying to pay the rent on time. They go through the normal strife that any black family has to go through in poor areas but they still find a way to maintain. I remember as a kid that the last scene with the mom passing on had me choked up. Troy and her brother holding hands at the reception for the funeral was a touching scene too. They drove each other crazy but it was still love in the end. Crooklyn has brief moments of awareness like one scene in particular: Troy's aunt comparing troy's hair to her adopted child's hair saying that the adopted child's hair was good hair and that Troy's hair was rough was a subtle form of self-hatred but most people wouldn't pick up on that. Of course Spike Lee has to make an appearance in the movie. He plays a junkie who chases kids around trying to steal money from them. In short Crooklyn stands out as one the best dramas of all time and one of Spike Lee's best work. The characters are ones that you care about, their struggles are real and anybody who has been there can also relate. Two thumbs up for Spike Lee's work of art on film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a pleasantly buoyant and personal Spike Lee film that only feels disconnected in the last act
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MisterWhiplash
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/8/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Crooklyn has that subjective texture by someone of the New York independent school of film-making (which means it's a cool school more often than not), where personal expression through the medium leads directly into, or out of, the creator's own life experiences. It's a direct approach to call it autobiography, which I would imagine it is for not just Spike Lee (who could be seen, more or less, as the one Carmichael kid who wears big glasses and is obsessed with the Knicks), but Joie (the lead Troy perhaps ?) and Cinque (one of the younger kids I'd suppose as the youngest Lee sibling), who all wrote the script. It's about a family getting by and going through the struggles of the small kind (change the channel, turn off the TV, don't bother your sister/brother, did you steal that from him, etc) to the larger issues (parents arguing over money) that many families in urban sections of the cities have to go through every day. Only here the family is sassy, rude, cool, a little square, a little hip, and very identifiable in one aspect or another in just how siblings relate, how the neighbors get on nerves (in this case with a slight racial edge, it is a Spike Lee movie after all), and yet deep down lots of love all around. The Lee's inject a good deal of humor and warmth for a good 2/3 of the film, even when Spike moves the scene down south where Troy (Zelda Harris) has to stay with relatives for a little while, and Lee takes off the widescreen anamorphic process in order to make it a consistently distorted image. This is actually quite a cool move, if at first a little uneasy, as it goes in and out sometimes of looking like its distorted and then it will look like the characters and set pieces are skinny and such (the fate of the relative's dog, by the way, is one of the biggest, if cruelest, laughs in the whole film). At Crooklyn's best, there's a whole feeling to the proceedings, much like Do the Right Thing- and going back as well to the early work of Scorsese- where just a small section of New York city opens up to the viewer as being as vivid and true as possible that the lack of a usual plot doesn't matter much. Sometimes a scene might not work quite as much as another, or one of the many songs Lee lays on (and there are many, as it's one of the best soundtracks he's presented) overrides what could do without in the scene. But in general these are small quibbles. The biggest problem that the film has- and it's not without truth to Lee's real life- is the death of mother Carolyn. It happens as soon as Troy comes back from the south that she's in the hospital, and two scenes later she's gone. It's a sudden shift in the story that doesn't really feel as true as it could, almost as if Lee and his sibling writers don't know where to go once Troy gets back except to go towards sentimentality. It's still well-acted, particularly by Delroy Lindo, who overall gives one of his best performances to date as the struggling father of the family, but it's an odd jolt that doesn't rightly click (especially with a bit where a funeral scene is interrupted by what looks like a dream scene involving Spike himself, sporting a big afro, as a target of Troy's). And yet, I wouldn't stop anyone from seeing the Crooklyn, if they want to get to see some of the less politically charged and more personal and bittersweet side of Lee, and for those who have fond memories of New York (and TV or the Knicks) in the 70s.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Uneven Joint
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    OllieZ
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/5/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Although I wouldn't say this is a great Lee film, it is still very solid. There isn't a story as such, instead it is a love letter to childhood and family life in Brooklyn. Imagine Radio Days, including the sentimental streak. The actors are great and this movie only goes to prove that Delroy Lindo is one of the best actors around. Zelda Harris as the young girl, Troy, is also brilliant. Alfre Woodard is the pivot of the film, around which most of the film revolves around - even if she has less than Troy. Tonally the film doesn't quite click. Sometimes the original music is quite sour and does not fit with the images. Some scenes seem forced. But the amazing soundtrack helps put things right. Even though the film isn't perfect, it has a great soundtrack and a very unique take on things.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Family is Family
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jzappa
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/12/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is just something about Spike Lee's films that has such an intensity and a natural beginning-to-end flow to its jabs at the heart. They're not sentimental nor are they necessarily depressing or mournful; they simply send you head first into the action of the characters, making you literally feel as if you are actually there with them. At least for me, he succeeds in doing this almost magical thing with every single one of his films, from She's Gotta Have It to Inside Man. Even with the films of his that aren't very good, like Girl 6 and She Hate Me, I'm still completely enthralled in the story. Crooklyn has a story with no main focus. Its characters just exist, and life just happens to them, sometimes nudging them like a begging dog and sometimes splashing in their faces like a bucket of soap. I feel cleansed while and after watching it. Anyone who's clicked on my name and has read through other comments of mine on other films may not find it surprising that I'm appalled at the scene where the dog pops out of the couch when the bed is being pulled out. There is really no need for this scene at all. Why kill the dog? Like it's some joke to get back on the woman for being annoying? However, miraculously, as it's very hard for me to forgive a movie when an inexplicable animal death or scene or cruelty towards any animal occurs, I still love this film. The single bias I have that can nearly always ruin a movie for me otherwise is hesitantly but irresistibly dismissed. Spike Lee's films are things we should put in time capsules if global warming dooms the world. When some civilization discovers the ruins of our ravaged existence, they are some of the things that should be found. And of course a projector or a TV or something to play the movies on, otherwise there's no point. Crooklyn is one of the great family films and also one of the great slice of life movies, because it does what the majority of movies don't do but are supposed to do, which is send you through the emotions that the characters are feeling and become immersed in their world. The music, its placement, the clear and forceful and even sometimes jolting cinematography, the strong performances by Alfre Woodard, Delroy Lindo, and virtually all of the children, and the intense and inspiring reality and freshness of the writing making Crooklyn very much worth a look.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    GREAT except for Distortion effect
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kimbakat
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The distortion doesn't complement anything...and certainly doesn't communicate the blatant literal attempt it tries to. It just takes away from the wonderfully acted and designed set that captures living in the midwest 1970s so well...that now the distortion takes away from it. The distortion is a really bad idea because your audience is immediately distracted by the first thought as to 'What is wrong with the projectionist?" Next thought is you are now well aware you are in a theatre watching a possible technically error. Thanks for reminding me I'm in a movie...watching a movie....because that's the goal of all filmmakers. At that point, your train of thought has taken you away from the action happening in wonderful detail in the actors expression and set design you fail to miss this "blatant literal" attempt to tell your audience that they can't possibly understand this change in the character's environment so now "I'm going to help you because you are too stupid by the 40 minutes of Brooklyn living to see the difference between the two environments!" Either Spike felt his actors were so bad or his audience to stupid to get it. Sorry Spike...most of us were exposed to slumber parties in other households as children where the culture and environment was vastly different from our own. We didn't need distortion glasses then to know our environment changed...trust me..your audience get's it and would've better appreciated your art departments, wardrobe's work and the actors performance better without the distortion. Do you really need to be that literal? Are Brooklynites that stupid to get and you put it in there for them? Or do you think people in the suburbs would be too stupid to get it? Really? Any chance of releasing a "Fixed Crooklyn" version so that every time I see that scene....I don't feel like I'm being spoon-fed a narrow viewpoint of a Brooklynite that never got out of their house for a slumber party in the 70s or couldn't fathom other lifestyles? I'm sorry..I don't know about the Brooklyn school system but we had geography and social studies in Middle School. We were taught about other cultures way back in the 70s. I would have expected you would've known about the other world outside your neighborhood by the time you made this movie. The distortion effect is an epic fail on really one of your best family drama films. It's like a turd in the middle of this great Brooklyn experience of a story. Other than that...it's a great movie with a lot of replay value. If you ever watch Soul Train back in the 70s or been to a slumber party.....this movie captures the period in a very realistic way! Too bad the distortion takes away from the reality of the suburb scene. I wonder why he didn't distort any of the reality of the Brooklyn scenes? I would think someone coming to Brooklyn from the burbs would expect to see all their movies shot in Brooklyn to have a distorted effect in their local theatres. Hmmm...call me stupid!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Charmingly fitting patchwork
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Shamek Stepien
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Thrust back to the past in a Spike Lee joint with an unwinking essence of 1970s, "Crooklyn" is a semi-autobiographical coming-of-age story, which goes nowhere, but nonetheless vividly portrays a certain mystic detachment of youthful bliss. Focused on the Carmicheal family, where Carolyn (Alfre Woodard) carries the household working as a teacher, while her husband Woody (Delroy Lindo), a jazz musician, attempts to find livelihood off a solo career. In the midst of all this jazz is their family of five, where are eyes into the world is the only girl of the rat-pack - Troy (a remarkable Zelda Harris). Spike Lee's younger self of sorts is an unmistakeably geekishly freakish four-eyes Clinton (Carlton Williams), the eldest brother and antagonist of tomboy Troy. Constructed more on tidbits of memories and recollections "Crooklyn" reminds a patchwork of visions, occurrences and situations, which irrelevant by themselves create a striking personal picture of the family (and ergo Lee's youthful days). Chaotic and lively, simultaneously packed with intimacy, Spike Lee manages to deliver a movie lacking his overwhelming preachiness, which despite being somewhat laid back packs a strong emotional punch. Fronted by a charismatic Zelda Harris and packed with bootie-tastic pop music hits it has a unmissable lure and light aura, that makes this possible Spike Lee's easiest and undoubtedly his most family-friendly feature, which steers far clear of mawkish dramaturgy, instead coming from the heart with a subtle triumph.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Spike Lee's Crooklyn is a nice look back at '70s Brooklyn
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tavm
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just watched this Spike Lee Joint on YouTube. It's largely about a family in Brooklyn during the early '70s based on Spike's siblings and parents during that part when he was growing up there. The mother Carolyn (Alfre Woodard) is the breadwinner as a teacher who constantly gets upset whenever her kids-Clinton (Carlton Williams) who is based on Spike himself, Wendell (Sharif Rashed), Nate (Chris Knowings), and Joseph (Tse-Mach Washington) disobey her orders. The same goes to her musician husband Woody (Delroy Lindo) who no longer is willing to compromise himself for his autonomy. Only her daughter Troy (Zelda Harris) seems to mostly escape her wrath. She's based on Spike's real-life sis Joie Susannah Lee who plays Aunt Maxine here and helped write the screenplay with Spike and other sibling Cinque. There's plenty of drama and some laughs like when Troy goes down South to visit her Aunt Song (Frances Foster), Uncle Clem (Norman Matlock), and cousin Viola (Patriece Nelson) especially when Aunt Song inadvertently offends Troy in commenting on her hair. That scene is shot in a distorted way that is pretty alienating though whenever it's on Troy and Viola, there's still some joy to be had especially when The Jackson 5's "ABC" is playing. In fact, several of the songs from that period evoke such a nostalgia on my part that when the YouTube upload went silent because of some copyright infringement on the part of Warner Music Group because of some song that they own, the subtitles took care of what was playing and I was at least able to imagine how the scene played with the music. Anyway, I liked this movie despite some of what I cited and recommend it highly. P.S. Lee himself appears as Snuffy and familiar faces like RuPaul, Isaiah Washington, and Vondie Curtis-Hall as Uncle Brown are also fun to look for. And I dedicate this review in memory of the late Don Cornelius whose "Soul Train" plays as part of the ending.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Relate,maybe
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (dunsuls@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Released in 1994 and running a little long at 115 minutes.My favorite hard ass director goes soft trying to be edgy in this whimsical story of growing up in Brooklyn back in the day.I loved it but not as a Spike picture,rather as remembering what a neighborhood was all about and family and kids and just because they are all black there is a lot I remember like it.About as edgy as it gets is Spike in a small role as Snuffy,gets hit in the head by Zelda Harris as Troy,the real star of this film and gezz I wonder where she went?? Alfre Woodard as Carolyn Carmichael and Delroy Lindo as Woody Carmichael are great as the parents who are trying to raise their 5 kids in Crooklyn but it's hard and there are tragic things that happen and at the end young Troy is now the anchor of the family and it's future is not certain.The soundtrack is wonderful representing music from the 70's,the acting is first rate as Spike always finds talent and the story, while soft by Spike standards ,is still very strong by white standards and sad in many ways besides being hopeful.I'm white and was raised in Brooklyn and I thought I had it easy after seeing this film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of my favorites of all times
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jjbsdoll
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am a long-time Spike Lee fan and I saw Crooklyn when it first came out. I just watched it again. Seventeen years later, my love for this movie hasn't waned. This is a simple movie about regular human beings living ordinary lives in a specific time and place fondly remembered by Spike Lee (and those of us who grew up in large urban centers in the 70s). It's not in your face, it doesn't preach, it doesn't alienate. It just is-and it's something everyone can relate to who has been a sister/brother/child/parent/close relative/kid enjoying his or her summer. Because of that, I believe this movie is Spike Lee's crowning achievement. Indeed, I think it's a movie that could be envied by other film makers who attempt "slice of life" movies.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Crooklyn-Stereotyping At Its Best ***
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You wonder how N.Y.C. teachers can put up with what they have to after viewing this 1994 film. After all, Alfre Woodard plays a teacher herself who heads a dysfunctional family. She and Delroy Lindo give credible performances as parents trying to cope in urban society with 5 children. The children act like too many of our children act today. Rude, loud, boisterous, fighting and again I heard the familiar expression-"Get off of me" when I taught as well. There are 4 boys and 1 girl. When the girl goes stay with family in Virginia during the summer, we find a beautiful home but there is that constant bickering again this time between the uncle and aunt with an adopted teenage daughter. It only takes for a family tragedy for the children to come together. Sad, but unfortunately true, there is tremendous stereotyping here of the African American family. This is not the Cosby show.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A tree grows in Crooklyn
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Newsense
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/1/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ahhh who can forget the good Ol' days of Spike Lee films that had heart as well as insight? Who can forget this gem? Crooklyn is loosely based on Spike Lee's life growing up. Its mostly a story that mostly details the struggles of a family growing up in Brooklyn as seen through the eyes of Troy(played by Zelda Harris). There are beautiful performances to be seen here. Alfre Woodard's presence is felt as the stern but loving mother of four kids and Delroy Lindo's is great as the father who is also dealing with pressure as a struggling musician and trying to pay the rent on time. They go through the normal strife that any black family has to go through in poor areas but they still find a way to maintain. I remember as a kid that the last scene with the mom passing on had me choked up. Troy and her brother holding hands at the reception for the funeral was a touching scene too. They drove each other crazy but it was still love in the end. Crooklyn has brief moments of awareness like one scene in particular: Troy's aunt comparing troy's hair to her adopted child's hair saying that the adopted child's hair was good hair and that Troy's hair was rough was a subtle form of self-hatred but most people wouldn't pick up on that. Of course Spike Lee has to make an appearance in the movie. He plays a junkie who chases kids around trying to steal money from them. In short Crooklyn stands out as one the best dramas of all time and one of Spike Lee's best work. The characters are ones that you care about, their struggles are real and anybody who has been there can also relate. Two thumbs up for Spike Lee's work of art on film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a pleasantly buoyant and personal Spike Lee film that only feels disconnected in the last act
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MisterWhiplash
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/8/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Crooklyn has that subjective texture by someone of the New York independent school of film-making (which means it's a cool school more often than not), where personal expression through the medium leads directly into, or out of, the creator's own life experiences. It's a direct approach to call it autobiography, which I would imagine it is for not just Spike Lee (who could be seen, more or less, as the one Carmichael kid who wears big glasses and is obsessed with the Knicks), but Joie (the lead Troy perhaps ?) and Cinque (one of the younger kids I'd suppose as the youngest Lee sibling), who all wrote the script. It's about a family getting by and going through the struggles of the small kind (change the channel, turn off the TV, don't bother your sister/brother, did you steal that from him, etc) to the larger issues (parents arguing over money) that many families in urban sections of the cities have to go through every day. Only here the family is sassy, rude, cool, a little square, a little hip, and very identifiable in one aspect or another in just how siblings relate, how the neighbors get on nerves (in this case with a slight racial edge, it is a Spike Lee movie after all), and yet deep down lots of love all around. The Lee's inject a good deal of humor and warmth for a good 2/3 of the film, even when Spike moves the scene down south where Troy (Zelda Harris) has to stay with relatives for a little while, and Lee takes off the widescreen anamorphic process in order to make it a consistently distorted image. This is actually quite a cool move, if at first a little uneasy, as it goes in and out sometimes of looking like its distorted and then it will look like the characters and set pieces are skinny and such (the fate of the relative's dog, by the way, is one of the biggest, if cruelest, laughs in the whole film). At Crooklyn's best, there's a whole feeling to the proceedings, much like Do the Right Thing- and going back as well to the early work of Scorsese- where just a small section of New York city opens up to the viewer as being as vivid and true as possible that the lack of a usual plot doesn't matter much. Sometimes a scene might not work quite as much as another, or one of the many songs Lee lays on (and there are many, as it's one of the best soundtracks he's presented) overrides what could do without in the scene. But in general these are small quibbles. The biggest problem that the film has- and it's not without truth to Lee's real life- is the death of mother Carolyn. It happens as soon as Troy comes back from the south that she's in the hospital, and two scenes later she's gone. It's a sudden shift in the story that doesn't really feel as true as it could, almost as if Lee and his sibling writers don't know where to go once Troy gets back except to go towards sentimentality. It's still well-acted, particularly by Delroy Lindo, who overall gives one of his best performances to date as the struggling father of the family, but it's an odd jolt that doesn't rightly click (especially with a bit where a funeral scene is interrupted by what looks like a dream scene involving Spike himself, sporting a big afro, as a target of Troy's). And yet, I wouldn't stop anyone from seeing the Crooklyn, if they want to get to see some of the less politically charged and more personal and bittersweet side of Lee, and for those who have fond memories of New York (and TV or the Knicks) in the 70s.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Uneven Joint
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    OllieZ
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/5/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Although I wouldn't say this is a great Lee film, it is still very solid. There isn't a story as such, instead it is a love letter to childhood and family life in Brooklyn. Imagine Radio Days, including the sentimental streak. The actors are great and this movie only goes to prove that Delroy Lindo is one of the best actors around. Zelda Harris as the young girl, Troy, is also brilliant. Alfre Woodard is the pivot of the film, around which most of the film revolves around - even if she has less than Troy. Tonally the film doesn't quite click. Sometimes the original music is quite sour and does not fit with the images. Some scenes seem forced. But the amazing soundtrack helps put things right. Even though the film isn't perfect, it has a great soundtrack and a very unique take on things.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Family is Family
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jzappa
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/12/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is just something about Spike Lee's films that has such an intensity and a natural beginning-to-end flow to its jabs at the heart. They're not sentimental nor are they necessarily depressing or mournful; they simply send you head first into the action of the characters, making you literally feel as if you are actually there with them. At least for me, he succeeds in doing this almost magical thing with every single one of his films, from She's Gotta Have It to Inside Man. Even with the films of his that aren't very good, like Girl 6 and She Hate Me, I'm still completely enthralled in the story. Crooklyn has a story with no main focus. Its characters just exist, and life just happens to them, sometimes nudging them like a begging dog and sometimes splashing in their faces like a bucket of soap. I feel cleansed while and after watching it. Anyone who's clicked on my name and has read through other comments of mine on other films may not find it surprising that I'm appalled at the scene where the dog pops out of the couch when the bed is being pulled out. There is really no need for this scene at all. Why kill the dog? Like it's some joke to get back on the woman for being annoying? However, miraculously, as it's very hard for me to forgive a movie when an inexplicable animal death or scene or cruelty towards any animal occurs, I still love this film. The single bias I have that can nearly always ruin a movie for me otherwise is hesitantly but irresistibly dismissed. Spike Lee's films are things we should put in time capsules if global warming dooms the world. When some civilization discovers the ruins of our ravaged existence, they are some of the things that should be found. And of course a projector or a TV or something to play the movies on, otherwise there's no point. Crooklyn is one of the great family films and also one of the great slice of life movies, because it does what the majority of movies don't do but are supposed to do, which is send you through the emotions that the characters are feeling and become immersed in their world. The music, its placement, the clear and forceful and even sometimes jolting cinematography, the strong performances by Alfre Woodard, Delroy Lindo, and virtually all of the children, and the intense and inspiring reality and freshness of the writing making Crooklyn very much worth a look.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    GREAT except for Distortion effect
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    kimbakat
   </autor>
   <data>
    8/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The distortion doesn't complement anything...and certainly doesn't communicate the blatant literal attempt it tries to. It just takes away from the wonderfully acted and designed set that captures living in the midwest 1970s so well...that now the distortion takes away from it. The distortion is a really bad idea because your audience is immediately distracted by the first thought as to 'What is wrong with the projectionist?" Next thought is you are now well aware you are in a theatre watching a possible technically error. Thanks for reminding me I'm in a movie...watching a movie....because that's the goal of all filmmakers. At that point, your train of thought has taken you away from the action happening in wonderful detail in the actors expression and set design you fail to miss this "blatant literal" attempt to tell your audience that they can't possibly understand this change in the character's environment so now "I'm going to help you because you are too stupid by the 40 minutes of Brooklyn living to see the difference between the two environments!" Either Spike felt his actors were so bad or his audience to stupid to get it. Sorry Spike...most of us were exposed to slumber parties in other households as children where the culture and environment was vastly different from our own. We didn't need distortion glasses then to know our environment changed...trust me..your audience get's it and would've better appreciated your art departments, wardrobe's work and the actors performance better without the distortion. Do you really need to be that literal? Are Brooklynites that stupid to get and you put it in there for them? Or do you think people in the suburbs would be too stupid to get it? Really? Any chance of releasing a "Fixed Crooklyn" version so that every time I see that scene....I don't feel like I'm being spoon-fed a narrow viewpoint of a Brooklynite that never got out of their house for a slumber party in the 70s or couldn't fathom other lifestyles? I'm sorry..I don't know about the Brooklyn school system but we had geography and social studies in Middle School. We were taught about other cultures way back in the 70s. I would have expected you would've known about the other world outside your neighborhood by the time you made this movie. The distortion effect is an epic fail on really one of your best family drama films. It's like a turd in the middle of this great Brooklyn experience of a story. Other than that...it's a great movie with a lot of replay value. If you ever watch Soul Train back in the 70s or been to a slumber party.....this movie captures the period in a very realistic way! Too bad the distortion takes away from the reality of the suburb scene. I wonder why he didn't distort any of the reality of the Brooklyn scenes? I would think someone coming to Brooklyn from the burbs would expect to see all their movies shot in Brooklyn to have a distorted effect in their local theatres. Hmmm...call me stupid!!!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Charmingly fitting patchwork
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Shamek Stepien
   </autor>
   <data>
    16/10/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Thrust back to the past in a Spike Lee joint with an unwinking essence of 1970s, "Crooklyn" is a semi-autobiographical coming-of-age story, which goes nowhere, but nonetheless vividly portrays a certain mystic detachment of youthful bliss. Focused on the Carmicheal family, where Carolyn (Alfre Woodard) carries the household working as a teacher, while her husband Woody (Delroy Lindo), a jazz musician, attempts to find livelihood off a solo career. In the midst of all this jazz is their family of five, where are eyes into the world is the only girl of the rat-pack - Troy (a remarkable Zelda Harris). Spike Lee's younger self of sorts is an unmistakeably geekishly freakish four-eyes Clinton (Carlton Williams), the eldest brother and antagonist of tomboy Troy. Constructed more on tidbits of memories and recollections "Crooklyn" reminds a patchwork of visions, occurrences and situations, which irrelevant by themselves create a striking personal picture of the family (and ergo Lee's youthful days). Chaotic and lively, simultaneously packed with intimacy, Spike Lee manages to deliver a movie lacking his overwhelming preachiness, which despite being somewhat laid back packs a strong emotional punch. Fronted by a charismatic Zelda Harris and packed with bootie-tastic pop music hits it has a unmissable lure and light aura, that makes this possible Spike Lee's easiest and undoubtedly his most family-friendly feature, which steers far clear of mawkish dramaturgy, instead coming from the heart with a subtle triumph.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Spike Lee's Crooklyn is a nice look back at '70s Brooklyn
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tavm
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Just watched this Spike Lee Joint on YouTube. It's largely about a family in Brooklyn during the early '70s based on Spike's siblings and parents during that part when he was growing up there. The mother Carolyn (Alfre Woodard) is the breadwinner as a teacher who constantly gets upset whenever her kids-Clinton (Carlton Williams) who is based on Spike himself, Wendell (Sharif Rashed), Nate (Chris Knowings), and Joseph (Tse-Mach Washington) disobey her orders. The same goes to her musician husband Woody (Delroy Lindo) who no longer is willing to compromise himself for his autonomy. Only her daughter Troy (Zelda Harris) seems to mostly escape her wrath. She's based on Spike's real-life sis Joie Susannah Lee who plays Aunt Maxine here and helped write the screenplay with Spike and other sibling Cinque. There's plenty of drama and some laughs like when Troy goes down South to visit her Aunt Song (Frances Foster), Uncle Clem (Norman Matlock), and cousin Viola (Patriece Nelson) especially when Aunt Song inadvertently offends Troy in commenting on her hair. That scene is shot in a distorted way that is pretty alienating though whenever it's on Troy and Viola, there's still some joy to be had especially when The Jackson 5's "ABC" is playing. In fact, several of the songs from that period evoke such a nostalgia on my part that when the YouTube upload went silent because of some copyright infringement on the part of Warner Music Group because of some song that they own, the subtitles took care of what was playing and I was at least able to imagine how the scene played with the music. Anyway, I liked this movie despite some of what I cited and recommend it highly. P.S. Lee himself appears as Snuffy and familiar faces like RuPaul, Isaiah Washington, and Vondie Curtis-Hall as Uncle Brown are also fun to look for. And I dedicate this review in memory of the late Don Cornelius whose "Soul Train" plays as part of the ending.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Relate,maybe
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    (dunsuls@hotmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    27/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Released in 1994 and running a little long at 115 minutes.My favorite hard ass director goes soft trying to be edgy in this whimsical story of growing up in Brooklyn back in the day.I loved it but not as a Spike picture,rather as remembering what a neighborhood was all about and family and kids and just because they are all black there is a lot I remember like it.About as edgy as it gets is Spike in a small role as Snuffy,gets hit in the head by Zelda Harris as Troy,the real star of this film and gezz I wonder where she went?? Alfre Woodard as Carolyn Carmichael and Delroy Lindo as Woody Carmichael are great as the parents who are trying to raise their 5 kids in Crooklyn but it's hard and there are tragic things that happen and at the end young Troy is now the anchor of the family and it's future is not certain.The soundtrack is wonderful representing music from the 70's,the acting is first rate as Spike always finds talent and the story, while soft by Spike standards ,is still very strong by white standards and sad in many ways besides being hopeful.I'm white and was raised in Brooklyn and I thought I had it easy after seeing this film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of my favorites of all times
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jjbsdoll
   </autor>
   <data>
    25/5/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I am a long-time Spike Lee fan and I saw Crooklyn when it first came out. I just watched it again. Seventeen years later, my love for this movie hasn't waned. This is a simple movie about regular human beings living ordinary lives in a specific time and place fondly remembered by Spike Lee (and those of us who grew up in large urban centers in the 70s). It's not in your face, it doesn't preach, it doesn't alienate. It just is-and it's something everyone can relate to who has been a sister/brother/child/parent/close relative/kid enjoying his or her summer. Because of that, I believe this movie is Spike Lee's crowning achievement. Indeed, I think it's a movie that could be envied by other film makers who attempt "slice of life" movies.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Crooklyn-Stereotyping At Its Best ***
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    edwagreen
   </autor>
   <data>
    12/6/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    You wonder how N.Y.C. teachers can put up with what they have to after viewing this 1994 film. After all, Alfre Woodard plays a teacher herself who heads a dysfunctional family. She and Delroy Lindo give credible performances as parents trying to cope in urban society with 5 children. The children act like too many of our children act today. Rude, loud, boisterous, fighting and again I heard the familiar expression-"Get off of me" when I taught as well. There are 4 boys and 1 girl. When the girl goes stay with family in Virginia during the summer, we find a beautiful home but there is that constant bickering again this time between the uncle and aunt with an adopted teenage daughter. It only takes for a family tragedy for the children to come together. Sad, but unfortunately true, there is tremendous stereotyping here of the African American family. This is not the Cosby show.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A tree grows in Crooklyn
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Newsense
   </autor>
   <data>
    3/1/2009
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Ahhh who can forget the good Ol' days of Spike Lee films that had heart as well as insight? Who can forget this gem? Crooklyn is loosely based on Spike Lee's life growing up. Its mostly a story that mostly details the struggles of a family growing up in Brooklyn as seen through the eyes of Troy(played by Zelda Harris). There are beautiful performances to be seen here. Alfre Woodard's presence is felt as the stern but loving mother of four kids and Delroy Lindo's is great as the father who is also dealing with pressure as a struggling musician and trying to pay the rent on time. They go through the normal strife that any black family has to go through in poor areas but they still find a way to maintain. I remember as a kid that the last scene with the mom passing on had me choked up. Troy and her brother holding hands at the reception for the funeral was a touching scene too. They drove each other crazy but it was still love in the end. Crooklyn has brief moments of awareness like one scene in particular: Troy's aunt comparing troy's hair to her adopted child's hair saying that the adopted child's hair was good hair and that Troy's hair was rough was a subtle form of self-hatred but most people wouldn't pick up on that. Of course Spike Lee has to make an appearance in the movie. He plays a junkie who chases kids around trying to steal money from them. In short Crooklyn stands out as one the best dramas of all time and one of Spike Lee's best work. The characters are ones that you care about, their struggles are real and anybody who has been there can also relate. Two thumbs up for Spike Lee's work of art on film.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    a pleasantly buoyant and personal Spike Lee film that only feels disconnected in the last act
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MisterWhiplash
   </autor>
   <data>
    4/8/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Crooklyn has that subjective texture by someone of the New York independent school of film-making (which means it's a cool school more often than not), where personal expression through the medium leads directly into, or out of, the creator's own life experiences. It's a direct approach to call it autobiography, which I would imagine it is for not just Spike Lee (who could be seen, more or less, as the one Carmichael kid who wears big glasses and is obsessed with the Knicks), but Joie (the lead Troy perhaps ?) and Cinque (one of the younger kids I'd suppose as the youngest Lee sibling), who all wrote the script. It's about a family getting by and going through the struggles of the small kind (change the channel, turn off the TV, don't bother your sister/brother, did you steal that from him, etc) to the larger issues (parents arguing over money) that many families in urban sections of the cities have to go through every day. Only here the family is sassy, rude, cool, a little square, a little hip, and very identifiable in one aspect or another in just how siblings relate, how the neighbors get on nerves (in this case with a slight racial edge, it is a Spike Lee movie after all), and yet deep down lots of love all around. The Lee's inject a good deal of humor and warmth for a good 2/3 of the film, even when Spike moves the scene down south where Troy (Zelda Harris) has to stay with relatives for a little while, and Lee takes off the widescreen anamorphic process in order to make it a consistently distorted image. This is actually quite a cool move, if at first a little uneasy, as it goes in and out sometimes of looking like its distorted and then it will look like the characters and set pieces are skinny and such (the fate of the relative's dog, by the way, is one of the biggest, if cruelest, laughs in the whole film). At Crooklyn's best, there's a whole feeling to the proceedings, much like Do the Right Thing- and going back as well to the early work of Scorsese- where just a small section of New York city opens up to the viewer as being as vivid and true as possible that the lack of a usual plot doesn't matter much. Sometimes a scene might not work quite as much as another, or one of the many songs Lee lays on (and there are many, as it's one of the best soundtracks he's presented) overrides what could do without in the scene. But in general these are small quibbles. The biggest problem that the film has- and it's not without truth to Lee's real life- is the death of mother Carolyn. It happens as soon as Troy comes back from the south that she's in the hospital, and two scenes later she's gone. It's a sudden shift in the story that doesn't really feel as true as it could, almost as if Lee and his sibling writers don't know where to go once Troy gets back except to go towards sentimentality. It's still well-acted, particularly by Delroy Lindo, who overall gives one of his best performances to date as the struggling father of the family, but it's an odd jolt that doesn't rightly click (especially with a bit where a funeral scene is interrupted by what looks like a dream scene involving Spike himself, sporting a big afro, as a target of Troy's). And yet, I wouldn't stop anyone from seeing the Crooklyn, if they want to get to see some of the less politically charged and more personal and bittersweet side of Lee, and for those who have fond memories of New York (and TV or the Knicks) in the 70s.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Uneven Joint
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    OllieZ
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/5/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Although I wouldn't say this is a great Lee film, it is still very solid. There isn't a story as such, instead it is a love letter to childhood and family life in Brooklyn. Imagine Radio Days, including the sentimental streak. The actors are great and this movie only goes to prove that Delroy Lindo is one of the best actors around. Zelda Harris as the young girl, Troy, is also brilliant. Alfre Woodard is the pivot of the film, around which most of the film revolves around - even if she has less than Troy. Tonally the film doesn't quite click. Sometimes the original music is quite sour and does not fit with the images. Some scenes seem forced. But the amazing soundtrack helps put things right. Even though the film isn't perfect, it has a great soundtrack and a very unique take on things.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Family is Family
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jzappa
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/12/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    There is just something about Spike Lee's films that has such an intensity and a natural beginning-to-end flow to its jabs at the heart. They're not sentimental nor are they necessarily depressing or mournful; they simply send you head first into the action of the characters, making you literally feel as if you are actually there with them. At least for me, he succeeds in doing this almost magical thing with every single one of his films, from She's Gotta Have It to Inside Man. Even with the films of his that aren't very good, like Girl 6 and She Hate Me, I'm still completely enthralled in the story. Crooklyn has a story with no main focus. Its characters just exist, and life just happens to them, sometimes nudging them like a begging dog and sometimes splashing in their faces like a bucket of soap. I feel cleansed while and after watching it. Anyone who's clicked on my name and has read through other comments of mine on other films may not find it surprising that I'm appalled at the scene where the dog pops out of the couch when the bed is being pulled out. There is really no need for this scene at all. Why kill the dog? Like it's some joke to get back on the woman for being annoying? However, miraculously, as it's very hard for me to forgive a movie when an inexplicable animal death or scene or cruelty towards any animal occurs, I still love this film. The single bias I have that can nearly always ruin a movie for me otherwise is hesitantly but irresistibly dismissed. Spike Lee's films are things we should put in time capsules if global warming dooms the world. When some civilization discovers the ruins of our ravaged existence, they are some of the things that should be found. And of course a projector or a TV or something to play the movies on, otherwise there's no point. Crooklyn is one of the great family films and also one of the great slice of life movies, because it does what the majority of movies don't do but are supposed to do, which is send you through the emotions that the characters are feeling and become immersed in their world. The music, its placement, the clear and forceful and even sometimes jolting cinematography, the strong performances by Alfre Woodard, Delroy Lindo, and virtually all of the children, and the intense and inspiring reality and freshness of the writing making Crooklyn very much worth a look.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
