<filme>
 <id>
  794
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0110167
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1994
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Atra&iacute;dos Pelo Destino
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  6.2
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  A police officer promises to share his lottery ticket with a waitress in lieu of a tip.
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Charlie and Muriel Lang have led simple lives - for most of their existance. That's until they win $4 million on the lottery! There is a problem, however. Prior to winning the lottery, Charlie had eaten at a cafe and hadn't been able to tip the waitress. He had promised her, jokingly, that if he won the lottery he'd give her half of it. This is why his wife, Muriel decides to leave him. She doesn't want the waitress to get a cent of their money. Infact she wants all $4 million for herself!
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Drama
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Romance
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   lottery
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   waitress
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   money
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   police officer
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   ticket
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Andrew Bergman
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Jane Anderson
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Nicolas Cage
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Bridget Fonda
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Rosie Perez
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It Could Happen to You is a Real Sweet Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tbills2
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It was some many years before I ever got around to watching this lovely film, but as I've seen it multiple times in the last five years or so, now I hold it dear as one of the fonder movies. It has such a real decency to it. It's realistic display of depicting a very kind gesture, sharing millions of lottery winnings money with a complete stranger, makes it simultaneously edgy while homely. It Could Happen to You is a soft-spoken hit film. There's not a lot of fuss to how good it is, it's just there, and it's just good. It's lead by its acting, with such good actors and actresses. Nicolas Cage, Bridget Fonda, and Rosie Perez are all very good for the viewing. I really like all three of these movie stars. This is one of Nic Cage's more appreciative films, and he has so darn many. Bridget Fonda gives a good, lovely performance starring in one of her best, most memorable movies. Rosie Perez is so good and she's doing her best to try to steal the show, but there's no way she would have been able to. The beautiful growing relationship between Charlie and Yvonne is too good in It Could Happen to You. It Could Happen to You is a great, great, great film to get lost in, really good to lose yourself in for a time. It's wonderful, and it really makes you think. After all, it could happen to you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The best Nicolas Cage movie ever!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael Thompson
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is my second review of this wonderful and true story movie. And this is the best movie Nicholas Cage has ever made. Bridget Fonda is also superb in this film. Her performance is outstanding. The premise is simple, a New York Cop gives a waitress in a nearby Cafe half his lottery win as a promise he made when he could not tip her last time he came in the caf&eacute;. The resulting events churn the stomach, but they are meant to. I've seen this movie twice, I could see it again anytime. There is something about the film that takes you in, time and time again. And it's not truly obvious what it is. If anybody reading this can tell me of a similar movie, I would like to know. Email me at, michaelt2702085@yahoo.co.uk
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of my favorite movies of all time!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    uscmd
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Could be considered to have spoilers!!!! Its not Hitchcock, great. Its not Casablanca or Gone with the wind, great. The cinematography is nothing special, nor is the acting. The characters are cartoonishly simplistic. But the story is so special, so rich in the depiction of the poverty of the wife, and the riches of the waitress, even as she is filing bankruptcy. Brings tears to my eyes. In the quotes section: Yvonne Biasi: Because of me, you have nothing. Charlie Lang: Because of you, I have you. And the ending, on both sides.......simply couldn't be better. So if you need a hug, this is the movie equivalent.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Feels Good. Yum Yum.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It resembles one of those movies out of Hollywood in the 1930s, with people like Jean Arthur and Jimmy Stewart. It's a light-hearted comedy that warms the cockles of your heart, if your heart has any cockles at all. Nicholas Cage is a police officer who lives in Woodside, Queens, with his wife Rosie Perez. She'd love to get out of Queens but Cage has grown up there and rather likes the working class ambiance. He likes his job too. She's restless. They don't have too much to say to one another anymore, although that doesn't stop Rosie Perez from talking. One afternoon, Cage and his partner (an affable African-American) stop in a luncheonette for coffee. Bridget Fonda, who has just run out of money and declared bankruptcy that morning, is their waitress. Her caddish husband, Stanley Tucci, maxed out their credit cards and took off on her. She's a nice girl. Well, I mean, she treats guys with AIDS with special consideration, obeys her mean boss's orders to the best of her ability, is efficient, and he co-workers like her. When Cage tries to pay the bill, he realizes he doesn't have enough change to leave her a tip. Cage gives Fonda a choice: Double the tip tomorrow, or no tip at all but half his winnings in case he wins the New York State lottery. She's been so battered by life that she chooses "door number two," figuring nothing will come of either choice. Of course something does come of it. Life is a bed of pain but sometimes the maid leaves a bonbon on the pillow case. Cage wins four million bucks. And he's such a good guy that he honors his promise to Fonda to give her half of it -- much to the chagrin of his wife who, at this point, has begun to sound like a yapping little chihuahua. Perez gets into re-doing their apartment in a manner so ugly that even I -- who live in what looks like the reincarnation of an Egyptian whorehouse from 1910 -- noticed its ugliness. She buys expensive furs and has her boobs done, and she takes up with an older guy who knows how to make her money work for her. I leave it to the discerning viewer to guess what happens between nice Bridget Fonda and nice Nicholas Cage. I also leave it to the viewer to guess whether the two of them find that money is far from the most important thing in life. Nicholas Cage usually brings something interesting to his roles, and here he's at least believable in a part that -- let's face facts -- is essentially a challenge to our phenomenological reduction. A New York cop who loves Queens and won't quit his job no matter what. Bridget Fonda is an exceptionally attractive woman with rather broad, bony shoulders, a nice figure, and legs that slither when she walks, but this isn't her kind of part. She's not a New York waitress. She's a California surfer girl who doesn't know what we achieved independence from on July 4th. She thinks Independence Day is just an excuse for fireworks and parades. Stanley Tucci, as the manipulative husband, isn't around much but I can't think of a performance of his that I haven't admired. The rest of the supporting cast is pretty good. But now I've had time to rethink things. In that hypothetical 1930s movie? Delete Jean Arthur. She whines too much. Substitute Rosalind Russell, who is better at being driven to frenzy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A strong moral upbringing and a heart of gold may just land you in a small slump
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steve Pulaski
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sometimes, a film comes subtly by and sweeps you off your feet. That's exactly the case with It Could Happen to You, a sweet, serene comedy that avoids emotional manipulation and gooey sentimentality currently plagued by many romantic comedies. This is a wholesome exercise involving great characters, a charming cast, a funny, kind-hearted script, and a delightful ode to human nature. I'm starting to loosen my grip around Nicolas Cage. Perhaps I have been relying too much on his current films to judge him as a whole. The last three films I've seen by him, this, Leaving Las Vegas, and Vampire's Kiss, were surprisingly well done, and he played a big reason why. Cage plays a New York cop named Charlie Lang, a soft-spoken, everyman with a big heart and a good moral upbringing. His wife is the ditzy, controlling diva from hell, Muriel, played efficiently by Rosie Perez. They live a humble life in the Queens, which Charlie likes, but Muriel despises. One day, Charlie and his cop partner go into a small diner where they meet Yvonne Biasi (Fonda), a hard-luck waitress who is enduring a hell day after she has been informed her credit card debt is $12,000 thanks to her unruly husband. Unable to grant her a tip, Charlie, whom bought a lottery ticket for his greedy wife earlier, says that if he wins the lottery he'll give half his earnings to her. It turns out Charlie and Muriel win $4 million dollars. It would've been a greater amount, but a bowling team gets an extra percentage since they chose the same numbers. Conflict emerges when Muriel believes that Yvonne is unworthy of the $2 million, or any amount. Charlie does the right thing, keeping his promise and awarding Yvonne $2 million. Inevitably, we can see what will happen, but the film does a great job of getting us to the expected conclusion. And sometimes, with a capable cast, a worthy script, and a nice sense of direction, a clich&eacute; story can be told like a surprising one. Not to mention, It Could Happen to You goes beyond its rom-com nature to tell a fascinating story about great characters, who are morally strong, yet are brought down in value by materialistic louses who want everything handed to them. Charlie seems like the man who deserves a good life, but instead, is always controlled and one-upped by his wife who expects him to bring home a hefty paycheck and be supportive of everything she brings up (case in point, a breast augmentation). Yvonne is beautiful, yet is leached off of by her lackadaisical husband who, again, expects her to put up with everything he puts down. These are characters we can truly side with. Some of them may be us and some of the villains may be people we know, and the film does a great job of illustrating that. The film doesn't over-exaggerate certain points just to do so. Although the story occupies a slight inkling of contrivance, the whole concept isn't entirely implausible. I've been told that this was a true story, and it bares a resemblance to those "random acts of kindness" stories you read in the tabloids. The film, itself, cracked my inner-cynic and made me feel warmer than any other romantic comedy in a long time. How many films could you truly say that about? Starring: Nicolas Cage, Bridget Fonda, Rosie Perez, Wendell Pierce, Isaac Hayes, and Stanley Tucci. Directed by: Andrew Bergman.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This is definitely a movie worth seeing!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nightowl227
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is such a cute movie! I love how the characters-Yvonne and Charlie, win the lottery yet remain the same as they were before winning. They're still kind and selfless and I have to admire that. This is definitely a movie worth seeing. The acting is very good, I'm very impressed. I just don't know how Charlie married Muriel! They are totally different people. You have Muriel who wouldn't dare give money to a homeless man instead she would buy something for herself whereas Charlie is the complete opposite. Others come first and I think that's a lesson learned. The plot of this movie is so positive and so uplifting! I just love it! Charlie's character reminds me a bit of George Bailey from 'It's A Wonderful Life', another movie that I categorize into my favorites. So yes, you can say this is a positive review.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Basic human decency.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    michael thompson
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    On the face of it, "It could happen to you" could be regarded by cynics as a load of romantic slush, but it's far from that, and made even better because "It could happen to you" is based on a true story, and I, with my wife, enjoyed every minute of it. To start with every time she and I think of Nicholas Cage this is the film that comes to mind, in fact in our view Nicholas Cage has done nothing to equal this wonderfully beautiful and just plain nice film, since. Nicholas Cage could have been born a New York cop, because in this film he is the image of how I see the perfect cop, and this perfect cop goes through hell following a lottery win he promises to share with a waitress played by the wonderful Bridget Fonda even before he buys the ticket. Bridget Fonda excels as the hard working, hard done by Waitress whom Nicholas Cage meets up with in the cafe she works. This film is a miniature "Its a wonderful life" because it gives people hope, and if tears aren't in your eyes at the end, then you are just not human.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Charming and cute feel-good movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What a lovely little film. Mind you, I didn't see this until fairly recently, and when I did see it, I was glad I did so. It Could Happen to You was nice, charming and cute. There are a couple of moments that drag in the middle but that is the only thing really I could find to criticise. What It Could Happen to You is is a film that tries to be charming and succeeds. What I loved about this movie was that it has a lovely, sweet tone to it. This is complete with a nice story and plenty of lovely scenes such as when Charlie and Yvonne miss the boat and spend time together. Then It Could Happen to You has a wonderful soundtrack, striking scenery and efficient direction. And the acting is very good. Both the characters of Charlie and Yvonne are down-to-earth, sympathetic characters, and Nicolas Cage and Bridget Fonda both do wonderful jobs. Even better is Rosie Perez, admittedly Muriel is a character you love to hate and my impression was you were supposed to hate her, but Perez's performance was deliciously bitchy and delightful. Overall, a lovely film, very charming. 9/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Yvonne "Because of me you have nothing."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stephanlinsenhoff
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In the shadow of selfish greed: unselfish sharing. As example the movie It Could Happen to You (realitybased http://www.snopes.com/luck/lottery.htm; Cunningham, a thirty-year police veteran, was a regular diner at Sal's, where he liked to order linguine with clam sauce and maintain a steady flow of banter with Penzo, other employees, and regular customers. True to his lighthearted style, Cunningham was making a sort of joke on Friday evening, March 30, 1984, when he offered his favorite waitress an unusual tip: a half-interest in a lottery ticket. Each picked three of the six numbers; Cunningham walked across the street and bought their ticket. Penzo laughed, then forgot the incident until the next night, when the detective walked into Sal's Pizzeria after work with the winning ticket triumphantly clutched in his hand. It was worth six million dollars: three million for each of them. Cunningham, who ordinarily might have left a couple of dollars on the restaurant table, had no regrets about splitting the prize. After all, he says, Penzo helped pick the winning numbers). The movie balances Capras It's a wonderful life. It Could Happen to You is hollywoodfun. Reported by NYT 3 April 1984 it is framed as a New York Post fairy tale, as the 'Cinde-fucking-rella' Pretty Womans promised fairy tale. The photographer Angel Dupree narrates the seven chapters: 1. Cop gives waitress 2 $ M tip, 2. Lotto Robin Hood, 3. A night at the Plaza  Lotto Love, 4. The trial begins, 5. Lotto & waitress lost, 6. Their darkest hour and  after the first three minutes we know the happy ending: 7. Cop weds waitress. Foolish peoples 'silly' but good ideas are often responded by jealous greed and to want more, more and more. The naive good is luckily hidden behind the screaming selfish 'Muriels'. When finally Muriel is unable to take more of her husbands sharing style wants divorce, happy for his "A night at the Plaza Lotto Love" with his waitress. She wants not only his share of the lottery tip, also the promised away. But here she has crossed for Charlie the line. Charlie goes to court: "The trial begins" and the verdict: "The cop & waitress lost". The average rule: to get everything, everything must be lost is part of this fairy tale. "Keep falsehood and lies far from me; give me neither poverty nor riches, but give me only my daily bread", Proverbs 30:8. Attached the/a winning lottery ticket is the disappointment of all those who have bought a lottery ticket and lost, infecting the winner. The good example for this is Muriels sky rocking greed  and Charlie's lack to be infected, falling into the tempting trap. Charlie and soul mate Yvonne have the sharing in the backbone (as childpractised by the founder of the Camphill Movement Karl K&ouml;nig 1902-1966 and showed to the staff for the disabled, among them dear friend Stefan Engqvist 1942-1980 (send to by food but gave the money to the needed in front of the store). When still in charge of the 'infected' money, Charlie and Yvonne try to balance with warm deeds: paying for the train journeys of passengers of the subway, treating the children of his neighborhood to a day out at Yankee Stadium, small gifts here and there unnoticed. And fail. When all is lost (Yvonne: "Because of me you have nothing", exclaims the waitress) the as a poor customer disguised photographer Angel asks at the Caf&eacute; the couple for a bowl of soup. The published photos in the next day's New York Post publicly eulogizes their willingness to feed a hungry and poor man in "Their darkest hour". Their generosity is answered by the citizens of New York City: thousands of letters with tips are send to them. This warm gesture is the answer why the screaming Michelle had the law with her. The verdict (above the judge are the words: In God we trust) tells that Gods ways are unpredictable not know but understandable then. The cop and the waitress had to win and to loose  getting everything. The 'Angel' Dupree and the 'angels' in Wim Wenders movie Wings of Desire help humans when they are able to contact their own angel, the child within. Some hear and listen, some not: the screaming environment is too loud. Muriel screams and can't. But Charlie can. But: was he really good all the way? When offering Yvonne the choice: Twice the tip amount, or half the lottery, if he won? Charlie was tempted for a moment, forgetting what he stands for. So Yvonne, tempted by choosing the infected lottery tip. But as sharing is their second nature, they woke up, avoiding in the last second deceiving corruption. Charlie's decision to go to court remembered him to be put back on track. Not a few remember and do not listen: " give me neither poverty nor riches, but give me only my daily bread", Proverbs 30:8.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Finally a movie that makes you feel good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    green0693
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is a movie of good taste and true life. The story, set in New York, has a fairy tale charm to it that delivers so well that you start to believe it to the point of feeling the emotions of the characters. From laughing to crying to hating to loving, this movie has all the emotions you could expect from the perfect film. I was, surprisingly, extremely happy with the choice of watching this movie, and it turned out to now be one of my favorites. Unlike many other films of the genre, this movie does not once get boring or slow... the pace is always just right and the scenes never tire. Overall, this movie is sure to make you feel good about humanity, people, yourself, and life. I would recommend this movie 100% and hope you give it a chance. You will not be disappointed!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It Could Happen to You is a Real Sweet Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tbills2
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It was some many years before I ever got around to watching this lovely film, but as I've seen it multiple times in the last five years or so, now I hold it dear as one of the fonder movies. It has such a real decency to it. It's realistic display of depicting a very kind gesture, sharing millions of lottery winnings money with a complete stranger, makes it simultaneously edgy while homely. It Could Happen to You is a soft-spoken hit film. There's not a lot of fuss to how good it is, it's just there, and it's just good. It's lead by its acting, with such good actors and actresses. Nicolas Cage, Bridget Fonda, and Rosie Perez are all very good for the viewing. I really like all three of these movie stars. This is one of Nic Cage's more appreciative films, and he has so darn many. Bridget Fonda gives a good, lovely performance starring in one of her best, most memorable movies. Rosie Perez is so good and she's doing her best to try to steal the show, but there's no way she would have been able to. The beautiful growing relationship between Charlie and Yvonne is too good in It Could Happen to You. It Could Happen to You is a great, great, great film to get lost in, really good to lose yourself in for a time. It's wonderful, and it really makes you think. After all, it could happen to you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The best Nicolas Cage movie ever!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael Thompson
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is my second review of this wonderful and true story movie. And this is the best movie Nicholas Cage has ever made. Bridget Fonda is also superb in this film. Her performance is outstanding. The premise is simple, a New York Cop gives a waitress in a nearby Cafe half his lottery win as a promise he made when he could not tip her last time he came in the caf&eacute;. The resulting events churn the stomach, but they are meant to. I've seen this movie twice, I could see it again anytime. There is something about the film that takes you in, time and time again. And it's not truly obvious what it is. If anybody reading this can tell me of a similar movie, I would like to know. Email me at, michaelt2702085@yahoo.co.uk
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of my favorite movies of all time!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    uscmd
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Could be considered to have spoilers!!!! Its not Hitchcock, great. Its not Casablanca or Gone with the wind, great. The cinematography is nothing special, nor is the acting. The characters are cartoonishly simplistic. But the story is so special, so rich in the depiction of the poverty of the wife, and the riches of the waitress, even as she is filing bankruptcy. Brings tears to my eyes. In the quotes section: Yvonne Biasi: Because of me, you have nothing. Charlie Lang: Because of you, I have you. And the ending, on both sides.......simply couldn't be better. So if you need a hug, this is the movie equivalent.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Feels Good. Yum Yum.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It resembles one of those movies out of Hollywood in the 1930s, with people like Jean Arthur and Jimmy Stewart. It's a light-hearted comedy that warms the cockles of your heart, if your heart has any cockles at all. Nicholas Cage is a police officer who lives in Woodside, Queens, with his wife Rosie Perez. She'd love to get out of Queens but Cage has grown up there and rather likes the working class ambiance. He likes his job too. She's restless. They don't have too much to say to one another anymore, although that doesn't stop Rosie Perez from talking. One afternoon, Cage and his partner (an affable African-American) stop in a luncheonette for coffee. Bridget Fonda, who has just run out of money and declared bankruptcy that morning, is their waitress. Her caddish husband, Stanley Tucci, maxed out their credit cards and took off on her. She's a nice girl. Well, I mean, she treats guys with AIDS with special consideration, obeys her mean boss's orders to the best of her ability, is efficient, and he co-workers like her. When Cage tries to pay the bill, he realizes he doesn't have enough change to leave her a tip. Cage gives Fonda a choice: Double the tip tomorrow, or no tip at all but half his winnings in case he wins the New York State lottery. She's been so battered by life that she chooses "door number two," figuring nothing will come of either choice. Of course something does come of it. Life is a bed of pain but sometimes the maid leaves a bonbon on the pillow case. Cage wins four million bucks. And he's such a good guy that he honors his promise to Fonda to give her half of it -- much to the chagrin of his wife who, at this point, has begun to sound like a yapping little chihuahua. Perez gets into re-doing their apartment in a manner so ugly that even I -- who live in what looks like the reincarnation of an Egyptian whorehouse from 1910 -- noticed its ugliness. She buys expensive furs and has her boobs done, and she takes up with an older guy who knows how to make her money work for her. I leave it to the discerning viewer to guess what happens between nice Bridget Fonda and nice Nicholas Cage. I also leave it to the viewer to guess whether the two of them find that money is far from the most important thing in life. Nicholas Cage usually brings something interesting to his roles, and here he's at least believable in a part that -- let's face facts -- is essentially a challenge to our phenomenological reduction. A New York cop who loves Queens and won't quit his job no matter what. Bridget Fonda is an exceptionally attractive woman with rather broad, bony shoulders, a nice figure, and legs that slither when she walks, but this isn't her kind of part. She's not a New York waitress. She's a California surfer girl who doesn't know what we achieved independence from on July 4th. She thinks Independence Day is just an excuse for fireworks and parades. Stanley Tucci, as the manipulative husband, isn't around much but I can't think of a performance of his that I haven't admired. The rest of the supporting cast is pretty good. But now I've had time to rethink things. In that hypothetical 1930s movie? Delete Jean Arthur. She whines too much. Substitute Rosalind Russell, who is better at being driven to frenzy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A strong moral upbringing and a heart of gold may just land you in a small slump
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steve Pulaski
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sometimes, a film comes subtly by and sweeps you off your feet. That's exactly the case with It Could Happen to You, a sweet, serene comedy that avoids emotional manipulation and gooey sentimentality currently plagued by many romantic comedies. This is a wholesome exercise involving great characters, a charming cast, a funny, kind-hearted script, and a delightful ode to human nature. I'm starting to loosen my grip around Nicolas Cage. Perhaps I have been relying too much on his current films to judge him as a whole. The last three films I've seen by him, this, Leaving Las Vegas, and Vampire's Kiss, were surprisingly well done, and he played a big reason why. Cage plays a New York cop named Charlie Lang, a soft-spoken, everyman with a big heart and a good moral upbringing. His wife is the ditzy, controlling diva from hell, Muriel, played efficiently by Rosie Perez. They live a humble life in the Queens, which Charlie likes, but Muriel despises. One day, Charlie and his cop partner go into a small diner where they meet Yvonne Biasi (Fonda), a hard-luck waitress who is enduring a hell day after she has been informed her credit card debt is $12,000 thanks to her unruly husband. Unable to grant her a tip, Charlie, whom bought a lottery ticket for his greedy wife earlier, says that if he wins the lottery he'll give half his earnings to her. It turns out Charlie and Muriel win $4 million dollars. It would've been a greater amount, but a bowling team gets an extra percentage since they chose the same numbers. Conflict emerges when Muriel believes that Yvonne is unworthy of the $2 million, or any amount. Charlie does the right thing, keeping his promise and awarding Yvonne $2 million. Inevitably, we can see what will happen, but the film does a great job of getting us to the expected conclusion. And sometimes, with a capable cast, a worthy script, and a nice sense of direction, a clich&eacute; story can be told like a surprising one. Not to mention, It Could Happen to You goes beyond its rom-com nature to tell a fascinating story about great characters, who are morally strong, yet are brought down in value by materialistic louses who want everything handed to them. Charlie seems like the man who deserves a good life, but instead, is always controlled and one-upped by his wife who expects him to bring home a hefty paycheck and be supportive of everything she brings up (case in point, a breast augmentation). Yvonne is beautiful, yet is leached off of by her lackadaisical husband who, again, expects her to put up with everything he puts down. These are characters we can truly side with. Some of them may be us and some of the villains may be people we know, and the film does a great job of illustrating that. The film doesn't over-exaggerate certain points just to do so. Although the story occupies a slight inkling of contrivance, the whole concept isn't entirely implausible. I've been told that this was a true story, and it bares a resemblance to those "random acts of kindness" stories you read in the tabloids. The film, itself, cracked my inner-cynic and made me feel warmer than any other romantic comedy in a long time. How many films could you truly say that about? Starring: Nicolas Cage, Bridget Fonda, Rosie Perez, Wendell Pierce, Isaac Hayes, and Stanley Tucci. Directed by: Andrew Bergman.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This is definitely a movie worth seeing!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nightowl227
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is such a cute movie! I love how the characters-Yvonne and Charlie, win the lottery yet remain the same as they were before winning. They're still kind and selfless and I have to admire that. This is definitely a movie worth seeing. The acting is very good, I'm very impressed. I just don't know how Charlie married Muriel! They are totally different people. You have Muriel who wouldn't dare give money to a homeless man instead she would buy something for herself whereas Charlie is the complete opposite. Others come first and I think that's a lesson learned. The plot of this movie is so positive and so uplifting! I just love it! Charlie's character reminds me a bit of George Bailey from 'It's A Wonderful Life', another movie that I categorize into my favorites. So yes, you can say this is a positive review.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Basic human decency.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    michael thompson
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    On the face of it, "It could happen to you" could be regarded by cynics as a load of romantic slush, but it's far from that, and made even better because "It could happen to you" is based on a true story, and I, with my wife, enjoyed every minute of it. To start with every time she and I think of Nicholas Cage this is the film that comes to mind, in fact in our view Nicholas Cage has done nothing to equal this wonderfully beautiful and just plain nice film, since. Nicholas Cage could have been born a New York cop, because in this film he is the image of how I see the perfect cop, and this perfect cop goes through hell following a lottery win he promises to share with a waitress played by the wonderful Bridget Fonda even before he buys the ticket. Bridget Fonda excels as the hard working, hard done by Waitress whom Nicholas Cage meets up with in the cafe she works. This film is a miniature "Its a wonderful life" because it gives people hope, and if tears aren't in your eyes at the end, then you are just not human.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Charming and cute feel-good movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What a lovely little film. Mind you, I didn't see this until fairly recently, and when I did see it, I was glad I did so. It Could Happen to You was nice, charming and cute. There are a couple of moments that drag in the middle but that is the only thing really I could find to criticise. What It Could Happen to You is is a film that tries to be charming and succeeds. What I loved about this movie was that it has a lovely, sweet tone to it. This is complete with a nice story and plenty of lovely scenes such as when Charlie and Yvonne miss the boat and spend time together. Then It Could Happen to You has a wonderful soundtrack, striking scenery and efficient direction. And the acting is very good. Both the characters of Charlie and Yvonne are down-to-earth, sympathetic characters, and Nicolas Cage and Bridget Fonda both do wonderful jobs. Even better is Rosie Perez, admittedly Muriel is a character you love to hate and my impression was you were supposed to hate her, but Perez's performance was deliciously bitchy and delightful. Overall, a lovely film, very charming. 9/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Yvonne "Because of me you have nothing."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stephanlinsenhoff
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In the shadow of selfish greed: unselfish sharing. As example the movie It Could Happen to You (realitybased http://www.snopes.com/luck/lottery.htm; Cunningham, a thirty-year police veteran, was a regular diner at Sal's, where he liked to order linguine with clam sauce and maintain a steady flow of banter with Penzo, other employees, and regular customers. True to his lighthearted style, Cunningham was making a sort of joke on Friday evening, March 30, 1984, when he offered his favorite waitress an unusual tip: a half-interest in a lottery ticket. Each picked three of the six numbers; Cunningham walked across the street and bought their ticket. Penzo laughed, then forgot the incident until the next night, when the detective walked into Sal's Pizzeria after work with the winning ticket triumphantly clutched in his hand. It was worth six million dollars: three million for each of them. Cunningham, who ordinarily might have left a couple of dollars on the restaurant table, had no regrets about splitting the prize. After all, he says, Penzo helped pick the winning numbers). The movie balances Capras It's a wonderful life. It Could Happen to You is hollywoodfun. Reported by NYT 3 April 1984 it is framed as a New York Post fairy tale, as the 'Cinde-fucking-rella' Pretty Womans promised fairy tale. The photographer Angel Dupree narrates the seven chapters: 1. Cop gives waitress 2 $ M tip, 2. Lotto Robin Hood, 3. A night at the Plaza  Lotto Love, 4. The trial begins, 5. Lotto & waitress lost, 6. Their darkest hour and  after the first three minutes we know the happy ending: 7. Cop weds waitress. Foolish peoples 'silly' but good ideas are often responded by jealous greed and to want more, more and more. The naive good is luckily hidden behind the screaming selfish 'Muriels'. When finally Muriel is unable to take more of her husbands sharing style wants divorce, happy for his "A night at the Plaza Lotto Love" with his waitress. She wants not only his share of the lottery tip, also the promised away. But here she has crossed for Charlie the line. Charlie goes to court: "The trial begins" and the verdict: "The cop & waitress lost". The average rule: to get everything, everything must be lost is part of this fairy tale. "Keep falsehood and lies far from me; give me neither poverty nor riches, but give me only my daily bread", Proverbs 30:8. Attached the/a winning lottery ticket is the disappointment of all those who have bought a lottery ticket and lost, infecting the winner. The good example for this is Muriels sky rocking greed  and Charlie's lack to be infected, falling into the tempting trap. Charlie and soul mate Yvonne have the sharing in the backbone (as childpractised by the founder of the Camphill Movement Karl K&ouml;nig 1902-1966 and showed to the staff for the disabled, among them dear friend Stefan Engqvist 1942-1980 (send to by food but gave the money to the needed in front of the store). When still in charge of the 'infected' money, Charlie and Yvonne try to balance with warm deeds: paying for the train journeys of passengers of the subway, treating the children of his neighborhood to a day out at Yankee Stadium, small gifts here and there unnoticed. And fail. When all is lost (Yvonne: "Because of me you have nothing", exclaims the waitress) the as a poor customer disguised photographer Angel asks at the Caf&eacute; the couple for a bowl of soup. The published photos in the next day's New York Post publicly eulogizes their willingness to feed a hungry and poor man in "Their darkest hour". Their generosity is answered by the citizens of New York City: thousands of letters with tips are send to them. This warm gesture is the answer why the screaming Michelle had the law with her. The verdict (above the judge are the words: In God we trust) tells that Gods ways are unpredictable not know but understandable then. The cop and the waitress had to win and to loose  getting everything. The 'Angel' Dupree and the 'angels' in Wim Wenders movie Wings of Desire help humans when they are able to contact their own angel, the child within. Some hear and listen, some not: the screaming environment is too loud. Muriel screams and can't. But Charlie can. But: was he really good all the way? When offering Yvonne the choice: Twice the tip amount, or half the lottery, if he won? Charlie was tempted for a moment, forgetting what he stands for. So Yvonne, tempted by choosing the infected lottery tip. But as sharing is their second nature, they woke up, avoiding in the last second deceiving corruption. Charlie's decision to go to court remembered him to be put back on track. Not a few remember and do not listen: " give me neither poverty nor riches, but give me only my daily bread", Proverbs 30:8.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Finally a movie that makes you feel good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    green0693
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is a movie of good taste and true life. The story, set in New York, has a fairy tale charm to it that delivers so well that you start to believe it to the point of feeling the emotions of the characters. From laughing to crying to hating to loving, this movie has all the emotions you could expect from the perfect film. I was, surprisingly, extremely happy with the choice of watching this movie, and it turned out to now be one of my favorites. Unlike many other films of the genre, this movie does not once get boring or slow... the pace is always just right and the scenes never tire. Overall, this movie is sure to make you feel good about humanity, people, yourself, and life. I would recommend this movie 100% and hope you give it a chance. You will not be disappointed!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It Could Happen to You is a Real Sweet Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tbills2
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It was some many years before I ever got around to watching this lovely film, but as I've seen it multiple times in the last five years or so, now I hold it dear as one of the fonder movies. It has such a real decency to it. It's realistic display of depicting a very kind gesture, sharing millions of lottery winnings money with a complete stranger, makes it simultaneously edgy while homely. It Could Happen to You is a soft-spoken hit film. There's not a lot of fuss to how good it is, it's just there, and it's just good. It's lead by its acting, with such good actors and actresses. Nicolas Cage, Bridget Fonda, and Rosie Perez are all very good for the viewing. I really like all three of these movie stars. This is one of Nic Cage's more appreciative films, and he has so darn many. Bridget Fonda gives a good, lovely performance starring in one of her best, most memorable movies. Rosie Perez is so good and she's doing her best to try to steal the show, but there's no way she would have been able to. The beautiful growing relationship between Charlie and Yvonne is too good in It Could Happen to You. It Could Happen to You is a great, great, great film to get lost in, really good to lose yourself in for a time. It's wonderful, and it really makes you think. After all, it could happen to you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The best Nicolas Cage movie ever!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael Thompson
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is my second review of this wonderful and true story movie. And this is the best movie Nicholas Cage has ever made. Bridget Fonda is also superb in this film. Her performance is outstanding. The premise is simple, a New York Cop gives a waitress in a nearby Cafe half his lottery win as a promise he made when he could not tip her last time he came in the caf&eacute;. The resulting events churn the stomach, but they are meant to. I've seen this movie twice, I could see it again anytime. There is something about the film that takes you in, time and time again. And it's not truly obvious what it is. If anybody reading this can tell me of a similar movie, I would like to know. Email me at, michaelt2702085@yahoo.co.uk
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of my favorite movies of all time!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    uscmd
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Could be considered to have spoilers!!!! Its not Hitchcock, great. Its not Casablanca or Gone with the wind, great. The cinematography is nothing special, nor is the acting. The characters are cartoonishly simplistic. But the story is so special, so rich in the depiction of the poverty of the wife, and the riches of the waitress, even as she is filing bankruptcy. Brings tears to my eyes. In the quotes section: Yvonne Biasi: Because of me, you have nothing. Charlie Lang: Because of you, I have you. And the ending, on both sides.......simply couldn't be better. So if you need a hug, this is the movie equivalent.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Feels Good. Yum Yum.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It resembles one of those movies out of Hollywood in the 1930s, with people like Jean Arthur and Jimmy Stewart. It's a light-hearted comedy that warms the cockles of your heart, if your heart has any cockles at all. Nicholas Cage is a police officer who lives in Woodside, Queens, with his wife Rosie Perez. She'd love to get out of Queens but Cage has grown up there and rather likes the working class ambiance. He likes his job too. She's restless. They don't have too much to say to one another anymore, although that doesn't stop Rosie Perez from talking. One afternoon, Cage and his partner (an affable African-American) stop in a luncheonette for coffee. Bridget Fonda, who has just run out of money and declared bankruptcy that morning, is their waitress. Her caddish husband, Stanley Tucci, maxed out their credit cards and took off on her. She's a nice girl. Well, I mean, she treats guys with AIDS with special consideration, obeys her mean boss's orders to the best of her ability, is efficient, and he co-workers like her. When Cage tries to pay the bill, he realizes he doesn't have enough change to leave her a tip. Cage gives Fonda a choice: Double the tip tomorrow, or no tip at all but half his winnings in case he wins the New York State lottery. She's been so battered by life that she chooses "door number two," figuring nothing will come of either choice. Of course something does come of it. Life is a bed of pain but sometimes the maid leaves a bonbon on the pillow case. Cage wins four million bucks. And he's such a good guy that he honors his promise to Fonda to give her half of it -- much to the chagrin of his wife who, at this point, has begun to sound like a yapping little chihuahua. Perez gets into re-doing their apartment in a manner so ugly that even I -- who live in what looks like the reincarnation of an Egyptian whorehouse from 1910 -- noticed its ugliness. She buys expensive furs and has her boobs done, and she takes up with an older guy who knows how to make her money work for her. I leave it to the discerning viewer to guess what happens between nice Bridget Fonda and nice Nicholas Cage. I also leave it to the viewer to guess whether the two of them find that money is far from the most important thing in life. Nicholas Cage usually brings something interesting to his roles, and here he's at least believable in a part that -- let's face facts -- is essentially a challenge to our phenomenological reduction. A New York cop who loves Queens and won't quit his job no matter what. Bridget Fonda is an exceptionally attractive woman with rather broad, bony shoulders, a nice figure, and legs that slither when she walks, but this isn't her kind of part. She's not a New York waitress. She's a California surfer girl who doesn't know what we achieved independence from on July 4th. She thinks Independence Day is just an excuse for fireworks and parades. Stanley Tucci, as the manipulative husband, isn't around much but I can't think of a performance of his that I haven't admired. The rest of the supporting cast is pretty good. But now I've had time to rethink things. In that hypothetical 1930s movie? Delete Jean Arthur. She whines too much. Substitute Rosalind Russell, who is better at being driven to frenzy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A strong moral upbringing and a heart of gold may just land you in a small slump
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steve Pulaski
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sometimes, a film comes subtly by and sweeps you off your feet. That's exactly the case with It Could Happen to You, a sweet, serene comedy that avoids emotional manipulation and gooey sentimentality currently plagued by many romantic comedies. This is a wholesome exercise involving great characters, a charming cast, a funny, kind-hearted script, and a delightful ode to human nature. I'm starting to loosen my grip around Nicolas Cage. Perhaps I have been relying too much on his current films to judge him as a whole. The last three films I've seen by him, this, Leaving Las Vegas, and Vampire's Kiss, were surprisingly well done, and he played a big reason why. Cage plays a New York cop named Charlie Lang, a soft-spoken, everyman with a big heart and a good moral upbringing. His wife is the ditzy, controlling diva from hell, Muriel, played efficiently by Rosie Perez. They live a humble life in the Queens, which Charlie likes, but Muriel despises. One day, Charlie and his cop partner go into a small diner where they meet Yvonne Biasi (Fonda), a hard-luck waitress who is enduring a hell day after she has been informed her credit card debt is $12,000 thanks to her unruly husband. Unable to grant her a tip, Charlie, whom bought a lottery ticket for his greedy wife earlier, says that if he wins the lottery he'll give half his earnings to her. It turns out Charlie and Muriel win $4 million dollars. It would've been a greater amount, but a bowling team gets an extra percentage since they chose the same numbers. Conflict emerges when Muriel believes that Yvonne is unworthy of the $2 million, or any amount. Charlie does the right thing, keeping his promise and awarding Yvonne $2 million. Inevitably, we can see what will happen, but the film does a great job of getting us to the expected conclusion. And sometimes, with a capable cast, a worthy script, and a nice sense of direction, a clich&eacute; story can be told like a surprising one. Not to mention, It Could Happen to You goes beyond its rom-com nature to tell a fascinating story about great characters, who are morally strong, yet are brought down in value by materialistic louses who want everything handed to them. Charlie seems like the man who deserves a good life, but instead, is always controlled and one-upped by his wife who expects him to bring home a hefty paycheck and be supportive of everything she brings up (case in point, a breast augmentation). Yvonne is beautiful, yet is leached off of by her lackadaisical husband who, again, expects her to put up with everything he puts down. These are characters we can truly side with. Some of them may be us and some of the villains may be people we know, and the film does a great job of illustrating that. The film doesn't over-exaggerate certain points just to do so. Although the story occupies a slight inkling of contrivance, the whole concept isn't entirely implausible. I've been told that this was a true story, and it bares a resemblance to those "random acts of kindness" stories you read in the tabloids. The film, itself, cracked my inner-cynic and made me feel warmer than any other romantic comedy in a long time. How many films could you truly say that about? Starring: Nicolas Cage, Bridget Fonda, Rosie Perez, Wendell Pierce, Isaac Hayes, and Stanley Tucci. Directed by: Andrew Bergman.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This is definitely a movie worth seeing!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nightowl227
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is such a cute movie! I love how the characters-Yvonne and Charlie, win the lottery yet remain the same as they were before winning. They're still kind and selfless and I have to admire that. This is definitely a movie worth seeing. The acting is very good, I'm very impressed. I just don't know how Charlie married Muriel! They are totally different people. You have Muriel who wouldn't dare give money to a homeless man instead she would buy something for herself whereas Charlie is the complete opposite. Others come first and I think that's a lesson learned. The plot of this movie is so positive and so uplifting! I just love it! Charlie's character reminds me a bit of George Bailey from 'It's A Wonderful Life', another movie that I categorize into my favorites. So yes, you can say this is a positive review.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Basic human decency.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    michael thompson
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    On the face of it, "It could happen to you" could be regarded by cynics as a load of romantic slush, but it's far from that, and made even better because "It could happen to you" is based on a true story, and I, with my wife, enjoyed every minute of it. To start with every time she and I think of Nicholas Cage this is the film that comes to mind, in fact in our view Nicholas Cage has done nothing to equal this wonderfully beautiful and just plain nice film, since. Nicholas Cage could have been born a New York cop, because in this film he is the image of how I see the perfect cop, and this perfect cop goes through hell following a lottery win he promises to share with a waitress played by the wonderful Bridget Fonda even before he buys the ticket. Bridget Fonda excels as the hard working, hard done by Waitress whom Nicholas Cage meets up with in the cafe she works. This film is a miniature "Its a wonderful life" because it gives people hope, and if tears aren't in your eyes at the end, then you are just not human.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Charming and cute feel-good movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What a lovely little film. Mind you, I didn't see this until fairly recently, and when I did see it, I was glad I did so. It Could Happen to You was nice, charming and cute. There are a couple of moments that drag in the middle but that is the only thing really I could find to criticise. What It Could Happen to You is is a film that tries to be charming and succeeds. What I loved about this movie was that it has a lovely, sweet tone to it. This is complete with a nice story and plenty of lovely scenes such as when Charlie and Yvonne miss the boat and spend time together. Then It Could Happen to You has a wonderful soundtrack, striking scenery and efficient direction. And the acting is very good. Both the characters of Charlie and Yvonne are down-to-earth, sympathetic characters, and Nicolas Cage and Bridget Fonda both do wonderful jobs. Even better is Rosie Perez, admittedly Muriel is a character you love to hate and my impression was you were supposed to hate her, but Perez's performance was deliciously bitchy and delightful. Overall, a lovely film, very charming. 9/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Yvonne "Because of me you have nothing."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stephanlinsenhoff
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In the shadow of selfish greed: unselfish sharing. As example the movie It Could Happen to You (realitybased http://www.snopes.com/luck/lottery.htm; Cunningham, a thirty-year police veteran, was a regular diner at Sal's, where he liked to order linguine with clam sauce and maintain a steady flow of banter with Penzo, other employees, and regular customers. True to his lighthearted style, Cunningham was making a sort of joke on Friday evening, March 30, 1984, when he offered his favorite waitress an unusual tip: a half-interest in a lottery ticket. Each picked three of the six numbers; Cunningham walked across the street and bought their ticket. Penzo laughed, then forgot the incident until the next night, when the detective walked into Sal's Pizzeria after work with the winning ticket triumphantly clutched in his hand. It was worth six million dollars: three million for each of them. Cunningham, who ordinarily might have left a couple of dollars on the restaurant table, had no regrets about splitting the prize. After all, he says, Penzo helped pick the winning numbers). The movie balances Capras It's a wonderful life. It Could Happen to You is hollywoodfun. Reported by NYT 3 April 1984 it is framed as a New York Post fairy tale, as the 'Cinde-fucking-rella' Pretty Womans promised fairy tale. The photographer Angel Dupree narrates the seven chapters: 1. Cop gives waitress 2 $ M tip, 2. Lotto Robin Hood, 3. A night at the Plaza  Lotto Love, 4. The trial begins, 5. Lotto & waitress lost, 6. Their darkest hour and  after the first three minutes we know the happy ending: 7. Cop weds waitress. Foolish peoples 'silly' but good ideas are often responded by jealous greed and to want more, more and more. The naive good is luckily hidden behind the screaming selfish 'Muriels'. When finally Muriel is unable to take more of her husbands sharing style wants divorce, happy for his "A night at the Plaza Lotto Love" with his waitress. She wants not only his share of the lottery tip, also the promised away. But here she has crossed for Charlie the line. Charlie goes to court: "The trial begins" and the verdict: "The cop & waitress lost". The average rule: to get everything, everything must be lost is part of this fairy tale. "Keep falsehood and lies far from me; give me neither poverty nor riches, but give me only my daily bread", Proverbs 30:8. Attached the/a winning lottery ticket is the disappointment of all those who have bought a lottery ticket and lost, infecting the winner. The good example for this is Muriels sky rocking greed  and Charlie's lack to be infected, falling into the tempting trap. Charlie and soul mate Yvonne have the sharing in the backbone (as childpractised by the founder of the Camphill Movement Karl K&ouml;nig 1902-1966 and showed to the staff for the disabled, among them dear friend Stefan Engqvist 1942-1980 (send to by food but gave the money to the needed in front of the store). When still in charge of the 'infected' money, Charlie and Yvonne try to balance with warm deeds: paying for the train journeys of passengers of the subway, treating the children of his neighborhood to a day out at Yankee Stadium, small gifts here and there unnoticed. And fail. When all is lost (Yvonne: "Because of me you have nothing", exclaims the waitress) the as a poor customer disguised photographer Angel asks at the Caf&eacute; the couple for a bowl of soup. The published photos in the next day's New York Post publicly eulogizes their willingness to feed a hungry and poor man in "Their darkest hour". Their generosity is answered by the citizens of New York City: thousands of letters with tips are send to them. This warm gesture is the answer why the screaming Michelle had the law with her. The verdict (above the judge are the words: In God we trust) tells that Gods ways are unpredictable not know but understandable then. The cop and the waitress had to win and to loose  getting everything. The 'Angel' Dupree and the 'angels' in Wim Wenders movie Wings of Desire help humans when they are able to contact their own angel, the child within. Some hear and listen, some not: the screaming environment is too loud. Muriel screams and can't. But Charlie can. But: was he really good all the way? When offering Yvonne the choice: Twice the tip amount, or half the lottery, if he won? Charlie was tempted for a moment, forgetting what he stands for. So Yvonne, tempted by choosing the infected lottery tip. But as sharing is their second nature, they woke up, avoiding in the last second deceiving corruption. Charlie's decision to go to court remembered him to be put back on track. Not a few remember and do not listen: " give me neither poverty nor riches, but give me only my daily bread", Proverbs 30:8.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Finally a movie that makes you feel good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    green0693
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is a movie of good taste and true life. The story, set in New York, has a fairy tale charm to it that delivers so well that you start to believe it to the point of feeling the emotions of the characters. From laughing to crying to hating to loving, this movie has all the emotions you could expect from the perfect film. I was, surprisingly, extremely happy with the choice of watching this movie, and it turned out to now be one of my favorites. Unlike many other films of the genre, this movie does not once get boring or slow... the pace is always just right and the scenes never tire. Overall, this movie is sure to make you feel good about humanity, people, yourself, and life. I would recommend this movie 100% and hope you give it a chance. You will not be disappointed!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It Could Happen to You is a Real Sweet Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tbills2
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It was some many years before I ever got around to watching this lovely film, but as I've seen it multiple times in the last five years or so, now I hold it dear as one of the fonder movies. It has such a real decency to it. It's realistic display of depicting a very kind gesture, sharing millions of lottery winnings money with a complete stranger, makes it simultaneously edgy while homely. It Could Happen to You is a soft-spoken hit film. There's not a lot of fuss to how good it is, it's just there, and it's just good. It's lead by its acting, with such good actors and actresses. Nicolas Cage, Bridget Fonda, and Rosie Perez are all very good for the viewing. I really like all three of these movie stars. This is one of Nic Cage's more appreciative films, and he has so darn many. Bridget Fonda gives a good, lovely performance starring in one of her best, most memorable movies. Rosie Perez is so good and she's doing her best to try to steal the show, but there's no way she would have been able to. The beautiful growing relationship between Charlie and Yvonne is too good in It Could Happen to You. It Could Happen to You is a great, great, great film to get lost in, really good to lose yourself in for a time. It's wonderful, and it really makes you think. After all, it could happen to you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The best Nicolas Cage movie ever!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael Thompson
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is my second review of this wonderful and true story movie. And this is the best movie Nicholas Cage has ever made. Bridget Fonda is also superb in this film. Her performance is outstanding. The premise is simple, a New York Cop gives a waitress in a nearby Cafe half his lottery win as a promise he made when he could not tip her last time he came in the caf&eacute;. The resulting events churn the stomach, but they are meant to. I've seen this movie twice, I could see it again anytime. There is something about the film that takes you in, time and time again. And it's not truly obvious what it is. If anybody reading this can tell me of a similar movie, I would like to know. Email me at, michaelt2702085@yahoo.co.uk
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of my favorite movies of all time!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    uscmd
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Could be considered to have spoilers!!!! Its not Hitchcock, great. Its not Casablanca or Gone with the wind, great. The cinematography is nothing special, nor is the acting. The characters are cartoonishly simplistic. But the story is so special, so rich in the depiction of the poverty of the wife, and the riches of the waitress, even as she is filing bankruptcy. Brings tears to my eyes. In the quotes section: Yvonne Biasi: Because of me, you have nothing. Charlie Lang: Because of you, I have you. And the ending, on both sides.......simply couldn't be better. So if you need a hug, this is the movie equivalent.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Feels Good. Yum Yum.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It resembles one of those movies out of Hollywood in the 1930s, with people like Jean Arthur and Jimmy Stewart. It's a light-hearted comedy that warms the cockles of your heart, if your heart has any cockles at all. Nicholas Cage is a police officer who lives in Woodside, Queens, with his wife Rosie Perez. She'd love to get out of Queens but Cage has grown up there and rather likes the working class ambiance. He likes his job too. She's restless. They don't have too much to say to one another anymore, although that doesn't stop Rosie Perez from talking. One afternoon, Cage and his partner (an affable African-American) stop in a luncheonette for coffee. Bridget Fonda, who has just run out of money and declared bankruptcy that morning, is their waitress. Her caddish husband, Stanley Tucci, maxed out their credit cards and took off on her. She's a nice girl. Well, I mean, she treats guys with AIDS with special consideration, obeys her mean boss's orders to the best of her ability, is efficient, and he co-workers like her. When Cage tries to pay the bill, he realizes he doesn't have enough change to leave her a tip. Cage gives Fonda a choice: Double the tip tomorrow, or no tip at all but half his winnings in case he wins the New York State lottery. She's been so battered by life that she chooses "door number two," figuring nothing will come of either choice. Of course something does come of it. Life is a bed of pain but sometimes the maid leaves a bonbon on the pillow case. Cage wins four million bucks. And he's such a good guy that he honors his promise to Fonda to give her half of it -- much to the chagrin of his wife who, at this point, has begun to sound like a yapping little chihuahua. Perez gets into re-doing their apartment in a manner so ugly that even I -- who live in what looks like the reincarnation of an Egyptian whorehouse from 1910 -- noticed its ugliness. She buys expensive furs and has her boobs done, and she takes up with an older guy who knows how to make her money work for her. I leave it to the discerning viewer to guess what happens between nice Bridget Fonda and nice Nicholas Cage. I also leave it to the viewer to guess whether the two of them find that money is far from the most important thing in life. Nicholas Cage usually brings something interesting to his roles, and here he's at least believable in a part that -- let's face facts -- is essentially a challenge to our phenomenological reduction. A New York cop who loves Queens and won't quit his job no matter what. Bridget Fonda is an exceptionally attractive woman with rather broad, bony shoulders, a nice figure, and legs that slither when she walks, but this isn't her kind of part. She's not a New York waitress. She's a California surfer girl who doesn't know what we achieved independence from on July 4th. She thinks Independence Day is just an excuse for fireworks and parades. Stanley Tucci, as the manipulative husband, isn't around much but I can't think of a performance of his that I haven't admired. The rest of the supporting cast is pretty good. But now I've had time to rethink things. In that hypothetical 1930s movie? Delete Jean Arthur. She whines too much. Substitute Rosalind Russell, who is better at being driven to frenzy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A strong moral upbringing and a heart of gold may just land you in a small slump
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steve Pulaski
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sometimes, a film comes subtly by and sweeps you off your feet. That's exactly the case with It Could Happen to You, a sweet, serene comedy that avoids emotional manipulation and gooey sentimentality currently plagued by many romantic comedies. This is a wholesome exercise involving great characters, a charming cast, a funny, kind-hearted script, and a delightful ode to human nature. I'm starting to loosen my grip around Nicolas Cage. Perhaps I have been relying too much on his current films to judge him as a whole. The last three films I've seen by him, this, Leaving Las Vegas, and Vampire's Kiss, were surprisingly well done, and he played a big reason why. Cage plays a New York cop named Charlie Lang, a soft-spoken, everyman with a big heart and a good moral upbringing. His wife is the ditzy, controlling diva from hell, Muriel, played efficiently by Rosie Perez. They live a humble life in the Queens, which Charlie likes, but Muriel despises. One day, Charlie and his cop partner go into a small diner where they meet Yvonne Biasi (Fonda), a hard-luck waitress who is enduring a hell day after she has been informed her credit card debt is $12,000 thanks to her unruly husband. Unable to grant her a tip, Charlie, whom bought a lottery ticket for his greedy wife earlier, says that if he wins the lottery he'll give half his earnings to her. It turns out Charlie and Muriel win $4 million dollars. It would've been a greater amount, but a bowling team gets an extra percentage since they chose the same numbers. Conflict emerges when Muriel believes that Yvonne is unworthy of the $2 million, or any amount. Charlie does the right thing, keeping his promise and awarding Yvonne $2 million. Inevitably, we can see what will happen, but the film does a great job of getting us to the expected conclusion. And sometimes, with a capable cast, a worthy script, and a nice sense of direction, a clich&eacute; story can be told like a surprising one. Not to mention, It Could Happen to You goes beyond its rom-com nature to tell a fascinating story about great characters, who are morally strong, yet are brought down in value by materialistic louses who want everything handed to them. Charlie seems like the man who deserves a good life, but instead, is always controlled and one-upped by his wife who expects him to bring home a hefty paycheck and be supportive of everything she brings up (case in point, a breast augmentation). Yvonne is beautiful, yet is leached off of by her lackadaisical husband who, again, expects her to put up with everything he puts down. These are characters we can truly side with. Some of them may be us and some of the villains may be people we know, and the film does a great job of illustrating that. The film doesn't over-exaggerate certain points just to do so. Although the story occupies a slight inkling of contrivance, the whole concept isn't entirely implausible. I've been told that this was a true story, and it bares a resemblance to those "random acts of kindness" stories you read in the tabloids. The film, itself, cracked my inner-cynic and made me feel warmer than any other romantic comedy in a long time. How many films could you truly say that about? Starring: Nicolas Cage, Bridget Fonda, Rosie Perez, Wendell Pierce, Isaac Hayes, and Stanley Tucci. Directed by: Andrew Bergman.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This is definitely a movie worth seeing!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nightowl227
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is such a cute movie! I love how the characters-Yvonne and Charlie, win the lottery yet remain the same as they were before winning. They're still kind and selfless and I have to admire that. This is definitely a movie worth seeing. The acting is very good, I'm very impressed. I just don't know how Charlie married Muriel! They are totally different people. You have Muriel who wouldn't dare give money to a homeless man instead she would buy something for herself whereas Charlie is the complete opposite. Others come first and I think that's a lesson learned. The plot of this movie is so positive and so uplifting! I just love it! Charlie's character reminds me a bit of George Bailey from 'It's A Wonderful Life', another movie that I categorize into my favorites. So yes, you can say this is a positive review.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Basic human decency.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    michael thompson
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    On the face of it, "It could happen to you" could be regarded by cynics as a load of romantic slush, but it's far from that, and made even better because "It could happen to you" is based on a true story, and I, with my wife, enjoyed every minute of it. To start with every time she and I think of Nicholas Cage this is the film that comes to mind, in fact in our view Nicholas Cage has done nothing to equal this wonderfully beautiful and just plain nice film, since. Nicholas Cage could have been born a New York cop, because in this film he is the image of how I see the perfect cop, and this perfect cop goes through hell following a lottery win he promises to share with a waitress played by the wonderful Bridget Fonda even before he buys the ticket. Bridget Fonda excels as the hard working, hard done by Waitress whom Nicholas Cage meets up with in the cafe she works. This film is a miniature "Its a wonderful life" because it gives people hope, and if tears aren't in your eyes at the end, then you are just not human.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Charming and cute feel-good movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What a lovely little film. Mind you, I didn't see this until fairly recently, and when I did see it, I was glad I did so. It Could Happen to You was nice, charming and cute. There are a couple of moments that drag in the middle but that is the only thing really I could find to criticise. What It Could Happen to You is is a film that tries to be charming and succeeds. What I loved about this movie was that it has a lovely, sweet tone to it. This is complete with a nice story and plenty of lovely scenes such as when Charlie and Yvonne miss the boat and spend time together. Then It Could Happen to You has a wonderful soundtrack, striking scenery and efficient direction. And the acting is very good. Both the characters of Charlie and Yvonne are down-to-earth, sympathetic characters, and Nicolas Cage and Bridget Fonda both do wonderful jobs. Even better is Rosie Perez, admittedly Muriel is a character you love to hate and my impression was you were supposed to hate her, but Perez's performance was deliciously bitchy and delightful. Overall, a lovely film, very charming. 9/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Yvonne "Because of me you have nothing."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stephanlinsenhoff
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In the shadow of selfish greed: unselfish sharing. As example the movie It Could Happen to You (realitybased http://www.snopes.com/luck/lottery.htm; Cunningham, a thirty-year police veteran, was a regular diner at Sal's, where he liked to order linguine with clam sauce and maintain a steady flow of banter with Penzo, other employees, and regular customers. True to his lighthearted style, Cunningham was making a sort of joke on Friday evening, March 30, 1984, when he offered his favorite waitress an unusual tip: a half-interest in a lottery ticket. Each picked three of the six numbers; Cunningham walked across the street and bought their ticket. Penzo laughed, then forgot the incident until the next night, when the detective walked into Sal's Pizzeria after work with the winning ticket triumphantly clutched in his hand. It was worth six million dollars: three million for each of them. Cunningham, who ordinarily might have left a couple of dollars on the restaurant table, had no regrets about splitting the prize. After all, he says, Penzo helped pick the winning numbers). The movie balances Capras It's a wonderful life. It Could Happen to You is hollywoodfun. Reported by NYT 3 April 1984 it is framed as a New York Post fairy tale, as the 'Cinde-fucking-rella' Pretty Womans promised fairy tale. The photographer Angel Dupree narrates the seven chapters: 1. Cop gives waitress 2 $ M tip, 2. Lotto Robin Hood, 3. A night at the Plaza  Lotto Love, 4. The trial begins, 5. Lotto & waitress lost, 6. Their darkest hour and  after the first three minutes we know the happy ending: 7. Cop weds waitress. Foolish peoples 'silly' but good ideas are often responded by jealous greed and to want more, more and more. The naive good is luckily hidden behind the screaming selfish 'Muriels'. When finally Muriel is unable to take more of her husbands sharing style wants divorce, happy for his "A night at the Plaza Lotto Love" with his waitress. She wants not only his share of the lottery tip, also the promised away. But here she has crossed for Charlie the line. Charlie goes to court: "The trial begins" and the verdict: "The cop & waitress lost". The average rule: to get everything, everything must be lost is part of this fairy tale. "Keep falsehood and lies far from me; give me neither poverty nor riches, but give me only my daily bread", Proverbs 30:8. Attached the/a winning lottery ticket is the disappointment of all those who have bought a lottery ticket and lost, infecting the winner. The good example for this is Muriels sky rocking greed  and Charlie's lack to be infected, falling into the tempting trap. Charlie and soul mate Yvonne have the sharing in the backbone (as childpractised by the founder of the Camphill Movement Karl K&ouml;nig 1902-1966 and showed to the staff for the disabled, among them dear friend Stefan Engqvist 1942-1980 (send to by food but gave the money to the needed in front of the store). When still in charge of the 'infected' money, Charlie and Yvonne try to balance with warm deeds: paying for the train journeys of passengers of the subway, treating the children of his neighborhood to a day out at Yankee Stadium, small gifts here and there unnoticed. And fail. When all is lost (Yvonne: "Because of me you have nothing", exclaims the waitress) the as a poor customer disguised photographer Angel asks at the Caf&eacute; the couple for a bowl of soup. The published photos in the next day's New York Post publicly eulogizes their willingness to feed a hungry and poor man in "Their darkest hour". Their generosity is answered by the citizens of New York City: thousands of letters with tips are send to them. This warm gesture is the answer why the screaming Michelle had the law with her. The verdict (above the judge are the words: In God we trust) tells that Gods ways are unpredictable not know but understandable then. The cop and the waitress had to win and to loose  getting everything. The 'Angel' Dupree and the 'angels' in Wim Wenders movie Wings of Desire help humans when they are able to contact their own angel, the child within. Some hear and listen, some not: the screaming environment is too loud. Muriel screams and can't. But Charlie can. But: was he really good all the way? When offering Yvonne the choice: Twice the tip amount, or half the lottery, if he won? Charlie was tempted for a moment, forgetting what he stands for. So Yvonne, tempted by choosing the infected lottery tip. But as sharing is their second nature, they woke up, avoiding in the last second deceiving corruption. Charlie's decision to go to court remembered him to be put back on track. Not a few remember and do not listen: " give me neither poverty nor riches, but give me only my daily bread", Proverbs 30:8.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Finally a movie that makes you feel good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    green0693
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is a movie of good taste and true life. The story, set in New York, has a fairy tale charm to it that delivers so well that you start to believe it to the point of feeling the emotions of the characters. From laughing to crying to hating to loving, this movie has all the emotions you could expect from the perfect film. I was, surprisingly, extremely happy with the choice of watching this movie, and it turned out to now be one of my favorites. Unlike many other films of the genre, this movie does not once get boring or slow... the pace is always just right and the scenes never tire. Overall, this movie is sure to make you feel good about humanity, people, yourself, and life. I would recommend this movie 100% and hope you give it a chance. You will not be disappointed!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It Could Happen to You is a Real Sweet Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tbills2
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It was some many years before I ever got around to watching this lovely film, but as I've seen it multiple times in the last five years or so, now I hold it dear as one of the fonder movies. It has such a real decency to it. It's realistic display of depicting a very kind gesture, sharing millions of lottery winnings money with a complete stranger, makes it simultaneously edgy while homely. It Could Happen to You is a soft-spoken hit film. There's not a lot of fuss to how good it is, it's just there, and it's just good. It's lead by its acting, with such good actors and actresses. Nicolas Cage, Bridget Fonda, and Rosie Perez are all very good for the viewing. I really like all three of these movie stars. This is one of Nic Cage's more appreciative films, and he has so darn many. Bridget Fonda gives a good, lovely performance starring in one of her best, most memorable movies. Rosie Perez is so good and she's doing her best to try to steal the show, but there's no way she would have been able to. The beautiful growing relationship between Charlie and Yvonne is too good in It Could Happen to You. It Could Happen to You is a great, great, great film to get lost in, really good to lose yourself in for a time. It's wonderful, and it really makes you think. After all, it could happen to you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The best Nicolas Cage movie ever!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael Thompson
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is my second review of this wonderful and true story movie. And this is the best movie Nicholas Cage has ever made. Bridget Fonda is also superb in this film. Her performance is outstanding. The premise is simple, a New York Cop gives a waitress in a nearby Cafe half his lottery win as a promise he made when he could not tip her last time he came in the caf&eacute;. The resulting events churn the stomach, but they are meant to. I've seen this movie twice, I could see it again anytime. There is something about the film that takes you in, time and time again. And it's not truly obvious what it is. If anybody reading this can tell me of a similar movie, I would like to know. Email me at, michaelt2702085@yahoo.co.uk
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of my favorite movies of all time!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    uscmd
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Could be considered to have spoilers!!!! Its not Hitchcock, great. Its not Casablanca or Gone with the wind, great. The cinematography is nothing special, nor is the acting. The characters are cartoonishly simplistic. But the story is so special, so rich in the depiction of the poverty of the wife, and the riches of the waitress, even as she is filing bankruptcy. Brings tears to my eyes. In the quotes section: Yvonne Biasi: Because of me, you have nothing. Charlie Lang: Because of you, I have you. And the ending, on both sides.......simply couldn't be better. So if you need a hug, this is the movie equivalent.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Feels Good. Yum Yum.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It resembles one of those movies out of Hollywood in the 1930s, with people like Jean Arthur and Jimmy Stewart. It's a light-hearted comedy that warms the cockles of your heart, if your heart has any cockles at all. Nicholas Cage is a police officer who lives in Woodside, Queens, with his wife Rosie Perez. She'd love to get out of Queens but Cage has grown up there and rather likes the working class ambiance. He likes his job too. She's restless. They don't have too much to say to one another anymore, although that doesn't stop Rosie Perez from talking. One afternoon, Cage and his partner (an affable African-American) stop in a luncheonette for coffee. Bridget Fonda, who has just run out of money and declared bankruptcy that morning, is their waitress. Her caddish husband, Stanley Tucci, maxed out their credit cards and took off on her. She's a nice girl. Well, I mean, she treats guys with AIDS with special consideration, obeys her mean boss's orders to the best of her ability, is efficient, and he co-workers like her. When Cage tries to pay the bill, he realizes he doesn't have enough change to leave her a tip. Cage gives Fonda a choice: Double the tip tomorrow, or no tip at all but half his winnings in case he wins the New York State lottery. She's been so battered by life that she chooses "door number two," figuring nothing will come of either choice. Of course something does come of it. Life is a bed of pain but sometimes the maid leaves a bonbon on the pillow case. Cage wins four million bucks. And he's such a good guy that he honors his promise to Fonda to give her half of it -- much to the chagrin of his wife who, at this point, has begun to sound like a yapping little chihuahua. Perez gets into re-doing their apartment in a manner so ugly that even I -- who live in what looks like the reincarnation of an Egyptian whorehouse from 1910 -- noticed its ugliness. She buys expensive furs and has her boobs done, and she takes up with an older guy who knows how to make her money work for her. I leave it to the discerning viewer to guess what happens between nice Bridget Fonda and nice Nicholas Cage. I also leave it to the viewer to guess whether the two of them find that money is far from the most important thing in life. Nicholas Cage usually brings something interesting to his roles, and here he's at least believable in a part that -- let's face facts -- is essentially a challenge to our phenomenological reduction. A New York cop who loves Queens and won't quit his job no matter what. Bridget Fonda is an exceptionally attractive woman with rather broad, bony shoulders, a nice figure, and legs that slither when she walks, but this isn't her kind of part. She's not a New York waitress. She's a California surfer girl who doesn't know what we achieved independence from on July 4th. She thinks Independence Day is just an excuse for fireworks and parades. Stanley Tucci, as the manipulative husband, isn't around much but I can't think of a performance of his that I haven't admired. The rest of the supporting cast is pretty good. But now I've had time to rethink things. In that hypothetical 1930s movie? Delete Jean Arthur. She whines too much. Substitute Rosalind Russell, who is better at being driven to frenzy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A strong moral upbringing and a heart of gold may just land you in a small slump
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steve Pulaski
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sometimes, a film comes subtly by and sweeps you off your feet. That's exactly the case with It Could Happen to You, a sweet, serene comedy that avoids emotional manipulation and gooey sentimentality currently plagued by many romantic comedies. This is a wholesome exercise involving great characters, a charming cast, a funny, kind-hearted script, and a delightful ode to human nature. I'm starting to loosen my grip around Nicolas Cage. Perhaps I have been relying too much on his current films to judge him as a whole. The last three films I've seen by him, this, Leaving Las Vegas, and Vampire's Kiss, were surprisingly well done, and he played a big reason why. Cage plays a New York cop named Charlie Lang, a soft-spoken, everyman with a big heart and a good moral upbringing. His wife is the ditzy, controlling diva from hell, Muriel, played efficiently by Rosie Perez. They live a humble life in the Queens, which Charlie likes, but Muriel despises. One day, Charlie and his cop partner go into a small diner where they meet Yvonne Biasi (Fonda), a hard-luck waitress who is enduring a hell day after she has been informed her credit card debt is $12,000 thanks to her unruly husband. Unable to grant her a tip, Charlie, whom bought a lottery ticket for his greedy wife earlier, says that if he wins the lottery he'll give half his earnings to her. It turns out Charlie and Muriel win $4 million dollars. It would've been a greater amount, but a bowling team gets an extra percentage since they chose the same numbers. Conflict emerges when Muriel believes that Yvonne is unworthy of the $2 million, or any amount. Charlie does the right thing, keeping his promise and awarding Yvonne $2 million. Inevitably, we can see what will happen, but the film does a great job of getting us to the expected conclusion. And sometimes, with a capable cast, a worthy script, and a nice sense of direction, a clich&eacute; story can be told like a surprising one. Not to mention, It Could Happen to You goes beyond its rom-com nature to tell a fascinating story about great characters, who are morally strong, yet are brought down in value by materialistic louses who want everything handed to them. Charlie seems like the man who deserves a good life, but instead, is always controlled and one-upped by his wife who expects him to bring home a hefty paycheck and be supportive of everything she brings up (case in point, a breast augmentation). Yvonne is beautiful, yet is leached off of by her lackadaisical husband who, again, expects her to put up with everything he puts down. These are characters we can truly side with. Some of them may be us and some of the villains may be people we know, and the film does a great job of illustrating that. The film doesn't over-exaggerate certain points just to do so. Although the story occupies a slight inkling of contrivance, the whole concept isn't entirely implausible. I've been told that this was a true story, and it bares a resemblance to those "random acts of kindness" stories you read in the tabloids. The film, itself, cracked my inner-cynic and made me feel warmer than any other romantic comedy in a long time. How many films could you truly say that about? Starring: Nicolas Cage, Bridget Fonda, Rosie Perez, Wendell Pierce, Isaac Hayes, and Stanley Tucci. Directed by: Andrew Bergman.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This is definitely a movie worth seeing!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nightowl227
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is such a cute movie! I love how the characters-Yvonne and Charlie, win the lottery yet remain the same as they were before winning. They're still kind and selfless and I have to admire that. This is definitely a movie worth seeing. The acting is very good, I'm very impressed. I just don't know how Charlie married Muriel! They are totally different people. You have Muriel who wouldn't dare give money to a homeless man instead she would buy something for herself whereas Charlie is the complete opposite. Others come first and I think that's a lesson learned. The plot of this movie is so positive and so uplifting! I just love it! Charlie's character reminds me a bit of George Bailey from 'It's A Wonderful Life', another movie that I categorize into my favorites. So yes, you can say this is a positive review.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Basic human decency.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    michael thompson
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    On the face of it, "It could happen to you" could be regarded by cynics as a load of romantic slush, but it's far from that, and made even better because "It could happen to you" is based on a true story, and I, with my wife, enjoyed every minute of it. To start with every time she and I think of Nicholas Cage this is the film that comes to mind, in fact in our view Nicholas Cage has done nothing to equal this wonderfully beautiful and just plain nice film, since. Nicholas Cage could have been born a New York cop, because in this film he is the image of how I see the perfect cop, and this perfect cop goes through hell following a lottery win he promises to share with a waitress played by the wonderful Bridget Fonda even before he buys the ticket. Bridget Fonda excels as the hard working, hard done by Waitress whom Nicholas Cage meets up with in the cafe she works. This film is a miniature "Its a wonderful life" because it gives people hope, and if tears aren't in your eyes at the end, then you are just not human.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Charming and cute feel-good movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What a lovely little film. Mind you, I didn't see this until fairly recently, and when I did see it, I was glad I did so. It Could Happen to You was nice, charming and cute. There are a couple of moments that drag in the middle but that is the only thing really I could find to criticise. What It Could Happen to You is is a film that tries to be charming and succeeds. What I loved about this movie was that it has a lovely, sweet tone to it. This is complete with a nice story and plenty of lovely scenes such as when Charlie and Yvonne miss the boat and spend time together. Then It Could Happen to You has a wonderful soundtrack, striking scenery and efficient direction. And the acting is very good. Both the characters of Charlie and Yvonne are down-to-earth, sympathetic characters, and Nicolas Cage and Bridget Fonda both do wonderful jobs. Even better is Rosie Perez, admittedly Muriel is a character you love to hate and my impression was you were supposed to hate her, but Perez's performance was deliciously bitchy and delightful. Overall, a lovely film, very charming. 9/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Yvonne "Because of me you have nothing."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stephanlinsenhoff
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In the shadow of selfish greed: unselfish sharing. As example the movie It Could Happen to You (realitybased http://www.snopes.com/luck/lottery.htm; Cunningham, a thirty-year police veteran, was a regular diner at Sal's, where he liked to order linguine with clam sauce and maintain a steady flow of banter with Penzo, other employees, and regular customers. True to his lighthearted style, Cunningham was making a sort of joke on Friday evening, March 30, 1984, when he offered his favorite waitress an unusual tip: a half-interest in a lottery ticket. Each picked three of the six numbers; Cunningham walked across the street and bought their ticket. Penzo laughed, then forgot the incident until the next night, when the detective walked into Sal's Pizzeria after work with the winning ticket triumphantly clutched in his hand. It was worth six million dollars: three million for each of them. Cunningham, who ordinarily might have left a couple of dollars on the restaurant table, had no regrets about splitting the prize. After all, he says, Penzo helped pick the winning numbers). The movie balances Capras It's a wonderful life. It Could Happen to You is hollywoodfun. Reported by NYT 3 April 1984 it is framed as a New York Post fairy tale, as the 'Cinde-fucking-rella' Pretty Womans promised fairy tale. The photographer Angel Dupree narrates the seven chapters: 1. Cop gives waitress 2 $ M tip, 2. Lotto Robin Hood, 3. A night at the Plaza  Lotto Love, 4. The trial begins, 5. Lotto & waitress lost, 6. Their darkest hour and  after the first three minutes we know the happy ending: 7. Cop weds waitress. Foolish peoples 'silly' but good ideas are often responded by jealous greed and to want more, more and more. The naive good is luckily hidden behind the screaming selfish 'Muriels'. When finally Muriel is unable to take more of her husbands sharing style wants divorce, happy for his "A night at the Plaza Lotto Love" with his waitress. She wants not only his share of the lottery tip, also the promised away. But here she has crossed for Charlie the line. Charlie goes to court: "The trial begins" and the verdict: "The cop & waitress lost". The average rule: to get everything, everything must be lost is part of this fairy tale. "Keep falsehood and lies far from me; give me neither poverty nor riches, but give me only my daily bread", Proverbs 30:8. Attached the/a winning lottery ticket is the disappointment of all those who have bought a lottery ticket and lost, infecting the winner. The good example for this is Muriels sky rocking greed  and Charlie's lack to be infected, falling into the tempting trap. Charlie and soul mate Yvonne have the sharing in the backbone (as childpractised by the founder of the Camphill Movement Karl K&ouml;nig 1902-1966 and showed to the staff for the disabled, among them dear friend Stefan Engqvist 1942-1980 (send to by food but gave the money to the needed in front of the store). When still in charge of the 'infected' money, Charlie and Yvonne try to balance with warm deeds: paying for the train journeys of passengers of the subway, treating the children of his neighborhood to a day out at Yankee Stadium, small gifts here and there unnoticed. And fail. When all is lost (Yvonne: "Because of me you have nothing", exclaims the waitress) the as a poor customer disguised photographer Angel asks at the Caf&eacute; the couple for a bowl of soup. The published photos in the next day's New York Post publicly eulogizes their willingness to feed a hungry and poor man in "Their darkest hour". Their generosity is answered by the citizens of New York City: thousands of letters with tips are send to them. This warm gesture is the answer why the screaming Michelle had the law with her. The verdict (above the judge are the words: In God we trust) tells that Gods ways are unpredictable not know but understandable then. The cop and the waitress had to win and to loose  getting everything. The 'Angel' Dupree and the 'angels' in Wim Wenders movie Wings of Desire help humans when they are able to contact their own angel, the child within. Some hear and listen, some not: the screaming environment is too loud. Muriel screams and can't. But Charlie can. But: was he really good all the way? When offering Yvonne the choice: Twice the tip amount, or half the lottery, if he won? Charlie was tempted for a moment, forgetting what he stands for. So Yvonne, tempted by choosing the infected lottery tip. But as sharing is their second nature, they woke up, avoiding in the last second deceiving corruption. Charlie's decision to go to court remembered him to be put back on track. Not a few remember and do not listen: " give me neither poverty nor riches, but give me only my daily bread", Proverbs 30:8.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Finally a movie that makes you feel good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    green0693
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is a movie of good taste and true life. The story, set in New York, has a fairy tale charm to it that delivers so well that you start to believe it to the point of feeling the emotions of the characters. From laughing to crying to hating to loving, this movie has all the emotions you could expect from the perfect film. I was, surprisingly, extremely happy with the choice of watching this movie, and it turned out to now be one of my favorites. Unlike many other films of the genre, this movie does not once get boring or slow... the pace is always just right and the scenes never tire. Overall, this movie is sure to make you feel good about humanity, people, yourself, and life. I would recommend this movie 100% and hope you give it a chance. You will not be disappointed!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It Could Happen to You is a Real Sweet Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tbills2
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It was some many years before I ever got around to watching this lovely film, but as I've seen it multiple times in the last five years or so, now I hold it dear as one of the fonder movies. It has such a real decency to it. It's realistic display of depicting a very kind gesture, sharing millions of lottery winnings money with a complete stranger, makes it simultaneously edgy while homely. It Could Happen to You is a soft-spoken hit film. There's not a lot of fuss to how good it is, it's just there, and it's just good. It's lead by its acting, with such good actors and actresses. Nicolas Cage, Bridget Fonda, and Rosie Perez are all very good for the viewing. I really like all three of these movie stars. This is one of Nic Cage's more appreciative films, and he has so darn many. Bridget Fonda gives a good, lovely performance starring in one of her best, most memorable movies. Rosie Perez is so good and she's doing her best to try to steal the show, but there's no way she would have been able to. The beautiful growing relationship between Charlie and Yvonne is too good in It Could Happen to You. It Could Happen to You is a great, great, great film to get lost in, really good to lose yourself in for a time. It's wonderful, and it really makes you think. After all, it could happen to you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The best Nicolas Cage movie ever!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael Thompson
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is my second review of this wonderful and true story movie. And this is the best movie Nicholas Cage has ever made. Bridget Fonda is also superb in this film. Her performance is outstanding. The premise is simple, a New York Cop gives a waitress in a nearby Cafe half his lottery win as a promise he made when he could not tip her last time he came in the caf&eacute;. The resulting events churn the stomach, but they are meant to. I've seen this movie twice, I could see it again anytime. There is something about the film that takes you in, time and time again. And it's not truly obvious what it is. If anybody reading this can tell me of a similar movie, I would like to know. Email me at, michaelt2702085@yahoo.co.uk
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of my favorite movies of all time!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    uscmd
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Could be considered to have spoilers!!!! Its not Hitchcock, great. Its not Casablanca or Gone with the wind, great. The cinematography is nothing special, nor is the acting. The characters are cartoonishly simplistic. But the story is so special, so rich in the depiction of the poverty of the wife, and the riches of the waitress, even as she is filing bankruptcy. Brings tears to my eyes. In the quotes section: Yvonne Biasi: Because of me, you have nothing. Charlie Lang: Because of you, I have you. And the ending, on both sides.......simply couldn't be better. So if you need a hug, this is the movie equivalent.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Feels Good. Yum Yum.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It resembles one of those movies out of Hollywood in the 1930s, with people like Jean Arthur and Jimmy Stewart. It's a light-hearted comedy that warms the cockles of your heart, if your heart has any cockles at all. Nicholas Cage is a police officer who lives in Woodside, Queens, with his wife Rosie Perez. She'd love to get out of Queens but Cage has grown up there and rather likes the working class ambiance. He likes his job too. She's restless. They don't have too much to say to one another anymore, although that doesn't stop Rosie Perez from talking. One afternoon, Cage and his partner (an affable African-American) stop in a luncheonette for coffee. Bridget Fonda, who has just run out of money and declared bankruptcy that morning, is their waitress. Her caddish husband, Stanley Tucci, maxed out their credit cards and took off on her. She's a nice girl. Well, I mean, she treats guys with AIDS with special consideration, obeys her mean boss's orders to the best of her ability, is efficient, and he co-workers like her. When Cage tries to pay the bill, he realizes he doesn't have enough change to leave her a tip. Cage gives Fonda a choice: Double the tip tomorrow, or no tip at all but half his winnings in case he wins the New York State lottery. She's been so battered by life that she chooses "door number two," figuring nothing will come of either choice. Of course something does come of it. Life is a bed of pain but sometimes the maid leaves a bonbon on the pillow case. Cage wins four million bucks. And he's such a good guy that he honors his promise to Fonda to give her half of it -- much to the chagrin of his wife who, at this point, has begun to sound like a yapping little chihuahua. Perez gets into re-doing their apartment in a manner so ugly that even I -- who live in what looks like the reincarnation of an Egyptian whorehouse from 1910 -- noticed its ugliness. She buys expensive furs and has her boobs done, and she takes up with an older guy who knows how to make her money work for her. I leave it to the discerning viewer to guess what happens between nice Bridget Fonda and nice Nicholas Cage. I also leave it to the viewer to guess whether the two of them find that money is far from the most important thing in life. Nicholas Cage usually brings something interesting to his roles, and here he's at least believable in a part that -- let's face facts -- is essentially a challenge to our phenomenological reduction. A New York cop who loves Queens and won't quit his job no matter what. Bridget Fonda is an exceptionally attractive woman with rather broad, bony shoulders, a nice figure, and legs that slither when she walks, but this isn't her kind of part. She's not a New York waitress. She's a California surfer girl who doesn't know what we achieved independence from on July 4th. She thinks Independence Day is just an excuse for fireworks and parades. Stanley Tucci, as the manipulative husband, isn't around much but I can't think of a performance of his that I haven't admired. The rest of the supporting cast is pretty good. But now I've had time to rethink things. In that hypothetical 1930s movie? Delete Jean Arthur. She whines too much. Substitute Rosalind Russell, who is better at being driven to frenzy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A strong moral upbringing and a heart of gold may just land you in a small slump
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steve Pulaski
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sometimes, a film comes subtly by and sweeps you off your feet. That's exactly the case with It Could Happen to You, a sweet, serene comedy that avoids emotional manipulation and gooey sentimentality currently plagued by many romantic comedies. This is a wholesome exercise involving great characters, a charming cast, a funny, kind-hearted script, and a delightful ode to human nature. I'm starting to loosen my grip around Nicolas Cage. Perhaps I have been relying too much on his current films to judge him as a whole. The last three films I've seen by him, this, Leaving Las Vegas, and Vampire's Kiss, were surprisingly well done, and he played a big reason why. Cage plays a New York cop named Charlie Lang, a soft-spoken, everyman with a big heart and a good moral upbringing. His wife is the ditzy, controlling diva from hell, Muriel, played efficiently by Rosie Perez. They live a humble life in the Queens, which Charlie likes, but Muriel despises. One day, Charlie and his cop partner go into a small diner where they meet Yvonne Biasi (Fonda), a hard-luck waitress who is enduring a hell day after she has been informed her credit card debt is $12,000 thanks to her unruly husband. Unable to grant her a tip, Charlie, whom bought a lottery ticket for his greedy wife earlier, says that if he wins the lottery he'll give half his earnings to her. It turns out Charlie and Muriel win $4 million dollars. It would've been a greater amount, but a bowling team gets an extra percentage since they chose the same numbers. Conflict emerges when Muriel believes that Yvonne is unworthy of the $2 million, or any amount. Charlie does the right thing, keeping his promise and awarding Yvonne $2 million. Inevitably, we can see what will happen, but the film does a great job of getting us to the expected conclusion. And sometimes, with a capable cast, a worthy script, and a nice sense of direction, a clich&eacute; story can be told like a surprising one. Not to mention, It Could Happen to You goes beyond its rom-com nature to tell a fascinating story about great characters, who are morally strong, yet are brought down in value by materialistic louses who want everything handed to them. Charlie seems like the man who deserves a good life, but instead, is always controlled and one-upped by his wife who expects him to bring home a hefty paycheck and be supportive of everything she brings up (case in point, a breast augmentation). Yvonne is beautiful, yet is leached off of by her lackadaisical husband who, again, expects her to put up with everything he puts down. These are characters we can truly side with. Some of them may be us and some of the villains may be people we know, and the film does a great job of illustrating that. The film doesn't over-exaggerate certain points just to do so. Although the story occupies a slight inkling of contrivance, the whole concept isn't entirely implausible. I've been told that this was a true story, and it bares a resemblance to those "random acts of kindness" stories you read in the tabloids. The film, itself, cracked my inner-cynic and made me feel warmer than any other romantic comedy in a long time. How many films could you truly say that about? Starring: Nicolas Cage, Bridget Fonda, Rosie Perez, Wendell Pierce, Isaac Hayes, and Stanley Tucci. Directed by: Andrew Bergman.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This is definitely a movie worth seeing!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nightowl227
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is such a cute movie! I love how the characters-Yvonne and Charlie, win the lottery yet remain the same as they were before winning. They're still kind and selfless and I have to admire that. This is definitely a movie worth seeing. The acting is very good, I'm very impressed. I just don't know how Charlie married Muriel! They are totally different people. You have Muriel who wouldn't dare give money to a homeless man instead she would buy something for herself whereas Charlie is the complete opposite. Others come first and I think that's a lesson learned. The plot of this movie is so positive and so uplifting! I just love it! Charlie's character reminds me a bit of George Bailey from 'It's A Wonderful Life', another movie that I categorize into my favorites. So yes, you can say this is a positive review.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Basic human decency.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    michael thompson
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    On the face of it, "It could happen to you" could be regarded by cynics as a load of romantic slush, but it's far from that, and made even better because "It could happen to you" is based on a true story, and I, with my wife, enjoyed every minute of it. To start with every time she and I think of Nicholas Cage this is the film that comes to mind, in fact in our view Nicholas Cage has done nothing to equal this wonderfully beautiful and just plain nice film, since. Nicholas Cage could have been born a New York cop, because in this film he is the image of how I see the perfect cop, and this perfect cop goes through hell following a lottery win he promises to share with a waitress played by the wonderful Bridget Fonda even before he buys the ticket. Bridget Fonda excels as the hard working, hard done by Waitress whom Nicholas Cage meets up with in the cafe she works. This film is a miniature "Its a wonderful life" because it gives people hope, and if tears aren't in your eyes at the end, then you are just not human.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Charming and cute feel-good movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What a lovely little film. Mind you, I didn't see this until fairly recently, and when I did see it, I was glad I did so. It Could Happen to You was nice, charming and cute. There are a couple of moments that drag in the middle but that is the only thing really I could find to criticise. What It Could Happen to You is is a film that tries to be charming and succeeds. What I loved about this movie was that it has a lovely, sweet tone to it. This is complete with a nice story and plenty of lovely scenes such as when Charlie and Yvonne miss the boat and spend time together. Then It Could Happen to You has a wonderful soundtrack, striking scenery and efficient direction. And the acting is very good. Both the characters of Charlie and Yvonne are down-to-earth, sympathetic characters, and Nicolas Cage and Bridget Fonda both do wonderful jobs. Even better is Rosie Perez, admittedly Muriel is a character you love to hate and my impression was you were supposed to hate her, but Perez's performance was deliciously bitchy and delightful. Overall, a lovely film, very charming. 9/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Yvonne "Because of me you have nothing."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stephanlinsenhoff
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In the shadow of selfish greed: unselfish sharing. As example the movie It Could Happen to You (realitybased http://www.snopes.com/luck/lottery.htm; Cunningham, a thirty-year police veteran, was a regular diner at Sal's, where he liked to order linguine with clam sauce and maintain a steady flow of banter with Penzo, other employees, and regular customers. True to his lighthearted style, Cunningham was making a sort of joke on Friday evening, March 30, 1984, when he offered his favorite waitress an unusual tip: a half-interest in a lottery ticket. Each picked three of the six numbers; Cunningham walked across the street and bought their ticket. Penzo laughed, then forgot the incident until the next night, when the detective walked into Sal's Pizzeria after work with the winning ticket triumphantly clutched in his hand. It was worth six million dollars: three million for each of them. Cunningham, who ordinarily might have left a couple of dollars on the restaurant table, had no regrets about splitting the prize. After all, he says, Penzo helped pick the winning numbers). The movie balances Capras It's a wonderful life. It Could Happen to You is hollywoodfun. Reported by NYT 3 April 1984 it is framed as a New York Post fairy tale, as the 'Cinde-fucking-rella' Pretty Womans promised fairy tale. The photographer Angel Dupree narrates the seven chapters: 1. Cop gives waitress 2 $ M tip, 2. Lotto Robin Hood, 3. A night at the Plaza  Lotto Love, 4. The trial begins, 5. Lotto & waitress lost, 6. Their darkest hour and  after the first three minutes we know the happy ending: 7. Cop weds waitress. Foolish peoples 'silly' but good ideas are often responded by jealous greed and to want more, more and more. The naive good is luckily hidden behind the screaming selfish 'Muriels'. When finally Muriel is unable to take more of her husbands sharing style wants divorce, happy for his "A night at the Plaza Lotto Love" with his waitress. She wants not only his share of the lottery tip, also the promised away. But here she has crossed for Charlie the line. Charlie goes to court: "The trial begins" and the verdict: "The cop & waitress lost". The average rule: to get everything, everything must be lost is part of this fairy tale. "Keep falsehood and lies far from me; give me neither poverty nor riches, but give me only my daily bread", Proverbs 30:8. Attached the/a winning lottery ticket is the disappointment of all those who have bought a lottery ticket and lost, infecting the winner. The good example for this is Muriels sky rocking greed  and Charlie's lack to be infected, falling into the tempting trap. Charlie and soul mate Yvonne have the sharing in the backbone (as childpractised by the founder of the Camphill Movement Karl K&ouml;nig 1902-1966 and showed to the staff for the disabled, among them dear friend Stefan Engqvist 1942-1980 (send to by food but gave the money to the needed in front of the store). When still in charge of the 'infected' money, Charlie and Yvonne try to balance with warm deeds: paying for the train journeys of passengers of the subway, treating the children of his neighborhood to a day out at Yankee Stadium, small gifts here and there unnoticed. And fail. When all is lost (Yvonne: "Because of me you have nothing", exclaims the waitress) the as a poor customer disguised photographer Angel asks at the Caf&eacute; the couple for a bowl of soup. The published photos in the next day's New York Post publicly eulogizes their willingness to feed a hungry and poor man in "Their darkest hour". Their generosity is answered by the citizens of New York City: thousands of letters with tips are send to them. This warm gesture is the answer why the screaming Michelle had the law with her. The verdict (above the judge are the words: In God we trust) tells that Gods ways are unpredictable not know but understandable then. The cop and the waitress had to win and to loose  getting everything. The 'Angel' Dupree and the 'angels' in Wim Wenders movie Wings of Desire help humans when they are able to contact their own angel, the child within. Some hear and listen, some not: the screaming environment is too loud. Muriel screams and can't. But Charlie can. But: was he really good all the way? When offering Yvonne the choice: Twice the tip amount, or half the lottery, if he won? Charlie was tempted for a moment, forgetting what he stands for. So Yvonne, tempted by choosing the infected lottery tip. But as sharing is their second nature, they woke up, avoiding in the last second deceiving corruption. Charlie's decision to go to court remembered him to be put back on track. Not a few remember and do not listen: " give me neither poverty nor riches, but give me only my daily bread", Proverbs 30:8.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Finally a movie that makes you feel good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    green0693
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is a movie of good taste and true life. The story, set in New York, has a fairy tale charm to it that delivers so well that you start to believe it to the point of feeling the emotions of the characters. From laughing to crying to hating to loving, this movie has all the emotions you could expect from the perfect film. I was, surprisingly, extremely happy with the choice of watching this movie, and it turned out to now be one of my favorites. Unlike many other films of the genre, this movie does not once get boring or slow... the pace is always just right and the scenes never tire. Overall, this movie is sure to make you feel good about humanity, people, yourself, and life. I would recommend this movie 100% and hope you give it a chance. You will not be disappointed!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    It Could Happen to You is a Real Sweet Film
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    tbills2
   </autor>
   <data>
    5/8/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It was some many years before I ever got around to watching this lovely film, but as I've seen it multiple times in the last five years or so, now I hold it dear as one of the fonder movies. It has such a real decency to it. It's realistic display of depicting a very kind gesture, sharing millions of lottery winnings money with a complete stranger, makes it simultaneously edgy while homely. It Could Happen to You is a soft-spoken hit film. There's not a lot of fuss to how good it is, it's just there, and it's just good. It's lead by its acting, with such good actors and actresses. Nicolas Cage, Bridget Fonda, and Rosie Perez are all very good for the viewing. I really like all three of these movie stars. This is one of Nic Cage's more appreciative films, and he has so darn many. Bridget Fonda gives a good, lovely performance starring in one of her best, most memorable movies. Rosie Perez is so good and she's doing her best to try to steal the show, but there's no way she would have been able to. The beautiful growing relationship between Charlie and Yvonne is too good in It Could Happen to You. It Could Happen to You is a great, great, great film to get lost in, really good to lose yourself in for a time. It's wonderful, and it really makes you think. After all, it could happen to you.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    The best Nicolas Cage movie ever!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Michael Thompson
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/5/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is my second review of this wonderful and true story movie. And this is the best movie Nicholas Cage has ever made. Bridget Fonda is also superb in this film. Her performance is outstanding. The premise is simple, a New York Cop gives a waitress in a nearby Cafe half his lottery win as a promise he made when he could not tip her last time he came in the caf&eacute;. The resulting events churn the stomach, but they are meant to. I've seen this movie twice, I could see it again anytime. There is something about the film that takes you in, time and time again. And it's not truly obvious what it is. If anybody reading this can tell me of a similar movie, I would like to know. Email me at, michaelt2702085@yahoo.co.uk
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    One of my favorite movies of all time!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    uscmd
   </autor>
   <data>
    24/1/2013
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Could be considered to have spoilers!!!! Its not Hitchcock, great. Its not Casablanca or Gone with the wind, great. The cinematography is nothing special, nor is the acting. The characters are cartoonishly simplistic. But the story is so special, so rich in the depiction of the poverty of the wife, and the riches of the waitress, even as she is filing bankruptcy. Brings tears to my eyes. In the quotes section: Yvonne Biasi: Because of me, you have nothing. Charlie Lang: Because of you, I have you. And the ending, on both sides.......simply couldn't be better. So if you need a hug, this is the movie equivalent.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Feels Good. Yum Yum.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Robert J. Maxwell (rmax304823@yahoo.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/8/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    It resembles one of those movies out of Hollywood in the 1930s, with people like Jean Arthur and Jimmy Stewart. It's a light-hearted comedy that warms the cockles of your heart, if your heart has any cockles at all. Nicholas Cage is a police officer who lives in Woodside, Queens, with his wife Rosie Perez. She'd love to get out of Queens but Cage has grown up there and rather likes the working class ambiance. He likes his job too. She's restless. They don't have too much to say to one another anymore, although that doesn't stop Rosie Perez from talking. One afternoon, Cage and his partner (an affable African-American) stop in a luncheonette for coffee. Bridget Fonda, who has just run out of money and declared bankruptcy that morning, is their waitress. Her caddish husband, Stanley Tucci, maxed out their credit cards and took off on her. She's a nice girl. Well, I mean, she treats guys with AIDS with special consideration, obeys her mean boss's orders to the best of her ability, is efficient, and he co-workers like her. When Cage tries to pay the bill, he realizes he doesn't have enough change to leave her a tip. Cage gives Fonda a choice: Double the tip tomorrow, or no tip at all but half his winnings in case he wins the New York State lottery. She's been so battered by life that she chooses "door number two," figuring nothing will come of either choice. Of course something does come of it. Life is a bed of pain but sometimes the maid leaves a bonbon on the pillow case. Cage wins four million bucks. And he's such a good guy that he honors his promise to Fonda to give her half of it -- much to the chagrin of his wife who, at this point, has begun to sound like a yapping little chihuahua. Perez gets into re-doing their apartment in a manner so ugly that even I -- who live in what looks like the reincarnation of an Egyptian whorehouse from 1910 -- noticed its ugliness. She buys expensive furs and has her boobs done, and she takes up with an older guy who knows how to make her money work for her. I leave it to the discerning viewer to guess what happens between nice Bridget Fonda and nice Nicholas Cage. I also leave it to the viewer to guess whether the two of them find that money is far from the most important thing in life. Nicholas Cage usually brings something interesting to his roles, and here he's at least believable in a part that -- let's face facts -- is essentially a challenge to our phenomenological reduction. A New York cop who loves Queens and won't quit his job no matter what. Bridget Fonda is an exceptionally attractive woman with rather broad, bony shoulders, a nice figure, and legs that slither when she walks, but this isn't her kind of part. She's not a New York waitress. She's a California surfer girl who doesn't know what we achieved independence from on July 4th. She thinks Independence Day is just an excuse for fireworks and parades. Stanley Tucci, as the manipulative husband, isn't around much but I can't think of a performance of his that I haven't admired. The rest of the supporting cast is pretty good. But now I've had time to rethink things. In that hypothetical 1930s movie? Delete Jean Arthur. She whines too much. Substitute Rosalind Russell, who is better at being driven to frenzy.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A strong moral upbringing and a heart of gold may just land you in a small slump
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Steve Pulaski
   </autor>
   <data>
    20/2/2012
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Sometimes, a film comes subtly by and sweeps you off your feet. That's exactly the case with It Could Happen to You, a sweet, serene comedy that avoids emotional manipulation and gooey sentimentality currently plagued by many romantic comedies. This is a wholesome exercise involving great characters, a charming cast, a funny, kind-hearted script, and a delightful ode to human nature. I'm starting to loosen my grip around Nicolas Cage. Perhaps I have been relying too much on his current films to judge him as a whole. The last three films I've seen by him, this, Leaving Las Vegas, and Vampire's Kiss, were surprisingly well done, and he played a big reason why. Cage plays a New York cop named Charlie Lang, a soft-spoken, everyman with a big heart and a good moral upbringing. His wife is the ditzy, controlling diva from hell, Muriel, played efficiently by Rosie Perez. They live a humble life in the Queens, which Charlie likes, but Muriel despises. One day, Charlie and his cop partner go into a small diner where they meet Yvonne Biasi (Fonda), a hard-luck waitress who is enduring a hell day after she has been informed her credit card debt is $12,000 thanks to her unruly husband. Unable to grant her a tip, Charlie, whom bought a lottery ticket for his greedy wife earlier, says that if he wins the lottery he'll give half his earnings to her. It turns out Charlie and Muriel win $4 million dollars. It would've been a greater amount, but a bowling team gets an extra percentage since they chose the same numbers. Conflict emerges when Muriel believes that Yvonne is unworthy of the $2 million, or any amount. Charlie does the right thing, keeping his promise and awarding Yvonne $2 million. Inevitably, we can see what will happen, but the film does a great job of getting us to the expected conclusion. And sometimes, with a capable cast, a worthy script, and a nice sense of direction, a clich&eacute; story can be told like a surprising one. Not to mention, It Could Happen to You goes beyond its rom-com nature to tell a fascinating story about great characters, who are morally strong, yet are brought down in value by materialistic louses who want everything handed to them. Charlie seems like the man who deserves a good life, but instead, is always controlled and one-upped by his wife who expects him to bring home a hefty paycheck and be supportive of everything she brings up (case in point, a breast augmentation). Yvonne is beautiful, yet is leached off of by her lackadaisical husband who, again, expects her to put up with everything he puts down. These are characters we can truly side with. Some of them may be us and some of the villains may be people we know, and the film does a great job of illustrating that. The film doesn't over-exaggerate certain points just to do so. Although the story occupies a slight inkling of contrivance, the whole concept isn't entirely implausible. I've been told that this was a true story, and it bares a resemblance to those "random acts of kindness" stories you read in the tabloids. The film, itself, cracked my inner-cynic and made me feel warmer than any other romantic comedy in a long time. How many films could you truly say that about? Starring: Nicolas Cage, Bridget Fonda, Rosie Perez, Wendell Pierce, Isaac Hayes, and Stanley Tucci. Directed by: Andrew Bergman.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This is definitely a movie worth seeing!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    nightowl227
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/7/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This is such a cute movie! I love how the characters-Yvonne and Charlie, win the lottery yet remain the same as they were before winning. They're still kind and selfless and I have to admire that. This is definitely a movie worth seeing. The acting is very good, I'm very impressed. I just don't know how Charlie married Muriel! They are totally different people. You have Muriel who wouldn't dare give money to a homeless man instead she would buy something for herself whereas Charlie is the complete opposite. Others come first and I think that's a lesson learned. The plot of this movie is so positive and so uplifting! I just love it! Charlie's character reminds me a bit of George Bailey from 'It's A Wonderful Life', another movie that I categorize into my favorites. So yes, you can say this is a positive review.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Basic human decency.
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    michael thompson
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/1/2011
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    On the face of it, "It could happen to you" could be regarded by cynics as a load of romantic slush, but it's far from that, and made even better because "It could happen to you" is based on a true story, and I, with my wife, enjoyed every minute of it. To start with every time she and I think of Nicholas Cage this is the film that comes to mind, in fact in our view Nicholas Cage has done nothing to equal this wonderfully beautiful and just plain nice film, since. Nicholas Cage could have been born a New York cop, because in this film he is the image of how I see the perfect cop, and this perfect cop goes through hell following a lottery win he promises to share with a waitress played by the wonderful Bridget Fonda even before he buys the ticket. Bridget Fonda excels as the hard working, hard done by Waitress whom Nicholas Cage meets up with in the cafe she works. This film is a miniature "Its a wonderful life" because it gives people hope, and if tears aren't in your eyes at the end, then you are just not human.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Charming and cute feel-good movie
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    TheLittleSongbird
   </autor>
   <data>
    2/8/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    What a lovely little film. Mind you, I didn't see this until fairly recently, and when I did see it, I was glad I did so. It Could Happen to You was nice, charming and cute. There are a couple of moments that drag in the middle but that is the only thing really I could find to criticise. What It Could Happen to You is is a film that tries to be charming and succeeds. What I loved about this movie was that it has a lovely, sweet tone to it. This is complete with a nice story and plenty of lovely scenes such as when Charlie and Yvonne miss the boat and spend time together. Then It Could Happen to You has a wonderful soundtrack, striking scenery and efficient direction. And the acting is very good. Both the characters of Charlie and Yvonne are down-to-earth, sympathetic characters, and Nicolas Cage and Bridget Fonda both do wonderful jobs. Even better is Rosie Perez, admittedly Muriel is a character you love to hate and my impression was you were supposed to hate her, but Perez's performance was deliciously bitchy and delightful. Overall, a lovely film, very charming. 9/10 Bethany Cox
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Yvonne "Because of me you have nothing."
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    stephanlinsenhoff
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/7/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    In the shadow of selfish greed: unselfish sharing. As example the movie It Could Happen to You (realitybased http://www.snopes.com/luck/lottery.htm; Cunningham, a thirty-year police veteran, was a regular diner at Sal's, where he liked to order linguine with clam sauce and maintain a steady flow of banter with Penzo, other employees, and regular customers. True to his lighthearted style, Cunningham was making a sort of joke on Friday evening, March 30, 1984, when he offered his favorite waitress an unusual tip: a half-interest in a lottery ticket. Each picked three of the six numbers; Cunningham walked across the street and bought their ticket. Penzo laughed, then forgot the incident until the next night, when the detective walked into Sal's Pizzeria after work with the winning ticket triumphantly clutched in his hand. It was worth six million dollars: three million for each of them. Cunningham, who ordinarily might have left a couple of dollars on the restaurant table, had no regrets about splitting the prize. After all, he says, Penzo helped pick the winning numbers). The movie balances Capras It's a wonderful life. It Could Happen to You is hollywoodfun. Reported by NYT 3 April 1984 it is framed as a New York Post fairy tale, as the 'Cinde-fucking-rella' Pretty Womans promised fairy tale. The photographer Angel Dupree narrates the seven chapters: 1. Cop gives waitress 2 $ M tip, 2. Lotto Robin Hood, 3. A night at the Plaza  Lotto Love, 4. The trial begins, 5. Lotto & waitress lost, 6. Their darkest hour and  after the first three minutes we know the happy ending: 7. Cop weds waitress. Foolish peoples 'silly' but good ideas are often responded by jealous greed and to want more, more and more. The naive good is luckily hidden behind the screaming selfish 'Muriels'. When finally Muriel is unable to take more of her husbands sharing style wants divorce, happy for his "A night at the Plaza Lotto Love" with his waitress. She wants not only his share of the lottery tip, also the promised away. But here she has crossed for Charlie the line. Charlie goes to court: "The trial begins" and the verdict: "The cop & waitress lost". The average rule: to get everything, everything must be lost is part of this fairy tale. "Keep falsehood and lies far from me; give me neither poverty nor riches, but give me only my daily bread", Proverbs 30:8. Attached the/a winning lottery ticket is the disappointment of all those who have bought a lottery ticket and lost, infecting the winner. The good example for this is Muriels sky rocking greed  and Charlie's lack to be infected, falling into the tempting trap. Charlie and soul mate Yvonne have the sharing in the backbone (as childpractised by the founder of the Camphill Movement Karl K&ouml;nig 1902-1966 and showed to the staff for the disabled, among them dear friend Stefan Engqvist 1942-1980 (send to by food but gave the money to the needed in front of the store). When still in charge of the 'infected' money, Charlie and Yvonne try to balance with warm deeds: paying for the train journeys of passengers of the subway, treating the children of his neighborhood to a day out at Yankee Stadium, small gifts here and there unnoticed. And fail. When all is lost (Yvonne: "Because of me you have nothing", exclaims the waitress) the as a poor customer disguised photographer Angel asks at the Caf&eacute; the couple for a bowl of soup. The published photos in the next day's New York Post publicly eulogizes their willingness to feed a hungry and poor man in "Their darkest hour". Their generosity is answered by the citizens of New York City: thousands of letters with tips are send to them. This warm gesture is the answer why the screaming Michelle had the law with her. The verdict (above the judge are the words: In God we trust) tells that Gods ways are unpredictable not know but understandable then. The cop and the waitress had to win and to loose  getting everything. The 'Angel' Dupree and the 'angels' in Wim Wenders movie Wings of Desire help humans when they are able to contact their own angel, the child within. Some hear and listen, some not: the screaming environment is too loud. Muriel screams and can't. But Charlie can. But: was he really good all the way? When offering Yvonne the choice: Twice the tip amount, or half the lottery, if he won? Charlie was tempted for a moment, forgetting what he stands for. So Yvonne, tempted by choosing the infected lottery tip. But as sharing is their second nature, they woke up, avoiding in the last second deceiving corruption. Charlie's decision to go to court remembered him to be put back on track. Not a few remember and do not listen: " give me neither poverty nor riches, but give me only my daily bread", Proverbs 30:8.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Finally a movie that makes you feel good
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    green0693
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/4/2010
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    This movie is a movie of good taste and true life. The story, set in New York, has a fairy tale charm to it that delivers so well that you start to believe it to the point of feeling the emotions of the characters. From laughing to crying to hating to loving, this movie has all the emotions you could expect from the perfect film. I was, surprisingly, extremely happy with the choice of watching this movie, and it turned out to now be one of my favorites. Unlike many other films of the genre, this movie does not once get boring or slow... the pace is always just right and the scenes never tire. Overall, this movie is sure to make you feel good about humanity, people, yourself, and life. I would recommend this movie 100% and hope you give it a chance. You will not be disappointed!
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
