<filme>
 <id>
  801
 </id>
 <imdburl>
  http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0109067
 </imdburl>
 <ano>
  1994
 </ano>
 <titulo>
  Um Gigante de Talento
 </titulo>
 <rating>
  5.3
 </rating>
 <sinopse>
  Jimmy Dolan is a college basketball coach who wants a big promotion. To get it, he needs to make a dramatic find. He ends up deep in Africa, hoping to recruit Saleh, a huge basketball ... &nbsp;&raquo;
 </sinopse>
 <storyline>
  Jimmy Dolan is a college basketball coach who wants a big promotion. To get it, he needs to make a dramatic find. He ends up deep in Africa, hoping to recruit Saleh, a huge basketball prodigy Jimmy glimpsed in a home movie. But Saleh is the chief's son and has responsibilities at home, since the tribe's land is threatened by a mining company with its own hotshot basketball team.
 </storyline>
 <generos>
  <genero>
   Comedy
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Family
  </genero>
  <genero>
   Sport
  </genero>
 </generos>
 <keywords>
  <keyword>
   basketball
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   africa
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   college basketball
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   athletic scout
  </keyword>
  <keyword>
   tall man
  </keyword>
 </keywords>
 <diretores>
  <diretor>
   Paul Michael Glaser
  </diretor>
 </diretores>
 <escritores>
  <escritor>
   Max Apple
  </escritor>
 </escritores>
 <atores>
  <ator>
   Kevin Bacon
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Charles Gitonga Maina
  </ator>
  <ator>
   Yolanda Vazquez
  </ator>
 </atores>
 <reviews>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This movie "Shakes and Bakes!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billshattner
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/3/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    So, without delving too deeply into the annals of "worst-to-first" sports movies, or counting off the multitude of "cultures in contact" stories, let me simply say this about the movie, "The Air Up There:" it succeeds, quite well in the mind of this critic, at what it sets out to accomplish. It is thematic, formulaic, and a tad predictable in parts, but none of that degrades its overall quality as a film. In fact, despite this movie getting lost somewhere in the recent history of film (and being overshadowed by similar movies such as "The Mighty Ducks"), I genuinely believe it to be the best movie of that genre, maybe ever, but certainly of this era. Now, I'm aware some of you might raise eyebrows at that statement, but let me elaborate; Not only is the scenery absolutely breathtaking, but all of the artistic design, costume styling, and cinematography is beautiful. On top of that, the story is engaging, regardless of one's ability to forecast the ending at any point. Additionally, the mere fact that themes such as maturation, redemption, independence, loyalty, "progress," and family all play central roles in this film, should qualify it is a deeper work of art than countless (sports) movies of today. Most significantly, this film contains something else that is occasionally lost in similar movies: DECENT ACTING. Say what you will about Kevin Bacon, or even this movie, but without a doubt, Kevin gives a wonderful, believable performance. He excellently displays the passion that is a prerequisite to be an athlete or coach in highly competitive sports such as College Athletics. Furthermore, the character Jimmy Dolan exhibits a wide gamut of emotions over the course of the story, and Mr. Bacon plays this perfectly. Interestingly, the best performance of the movie (and there are plenty of good ones: 'Kid' Sithole as Nyaga, Wilson Ntshona as Urudu, and Dikembe Mutombo's brother, Ilo, as Mifundo) comes not from Bacon, but from Charles Gitonga Maina, who inexplicably, has only appeared in one episode of SeaQuest DSV since this movie was made. He is immensely likable, charming, and completely believable as a star basketball player (after all, he was a world class sprinter in real life!) from a humble village. Truly, his performance is absolutely spectacular, even when placed within the context of the other stellar performances in the movie. Is this movie perfect, devoid of all stereotypes and patronizing cinematic techniques? No. And yet, nothing is lost because of that fact. As it was over a decade ago, it remains a wonderful, adventurous, heart-warming movie, one that deserves a far more solid place in cinematic history than it has been relegated to. I, for one, love this movie, and usually watch it a couple times a year, enjoying it every bit as much with each successive viewing (in fact, I feel the truth of the matter is, I enjoy this film MORE with each successive watching, as I continue to find noteworthy facets every time). In summation, I implore you to do yourself a favor: the next time you're feeling depressed, inadequate, or entirely stressed, rent or buy this movie, and watch it. I guarantee, you won't be able to make it to the end without a smile finding it's way onto your face.... :D
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    great movie!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    aaginadi
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/9/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I loved this movie. It is one of my favorite movies of all time. Charle Gitonga Maina (Saleh) is absolutely gorgeous! My favorite line is "Are you very sad Jimmy Dolan?" I say this to my husband whose name is Jimmy also, whenever he is upset or mad at me. It always makes us laugh. I have watched this movie at least 25 times although my husband swears it is 125! The little kid that is looking through the window in the clinic is so darn cute, too I loved it all!The man that runs the town is someone you would love to hate and I am glad when Saleh's brother leaves him. The pawn shop part of the movie is very good. I also liked Saleh's father.It is an excellent family movie, I encouraged my grand kids to watch it. Kevin Bacon is a good sport in this movie, it made me like him.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    way up
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/4/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As someone who's never really been into sports, "The Air Up There" hardly seems like the sort of movie that I would like, but I did. When basketball talent scout Jimmy Dolan (Kevin Bacon) goes to Kenya to recruit a new player, he ends up finding Saleh, a chief's son whose skills exceed what anyone could have imagined. But before he moves to the states, there are some things that both sides are going to have to deal with. This movie is interesting mainly for two reasons: it's good to see a sports movie that's not all about machismo, and a movie that looks at Kenyan culture (not one that we usually get to see). The movie isn't really any kind of masterpiece, but it never pretends to be one. There are some scenes that look like they were thrown in for comic relief (namely the goat milk). Pretty interesting.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Lightweight Fare Is Just That: Fair (as in "mediocre")
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ccthemovieman-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/3/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Kevin Bacon totally dominates this film. In fact, he's the only "name" actor in it. You won't recognize anybody else in here. The story is lightweight entertainment with the most notable aspect being the African music, which is very good and a small tour of Kenya, which is interesting, both with beauty and poverty. Bacon plays as basketball assistant coach, an ex-point guard, who goes to Africa to recruit this great player "Saleh" (Charles Gitangra Marina) for his team back in the States. The adventures of the trip pretty much are the story. One negative: another irreverent slam to get a few cheap laughs at the Catholic church. A nun in here uses profanity and gives Bacon a big kiss on the lips. It's one more example of trying to make clerical people appear worldly like the rest of us.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Two Movies
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jldmp1 (jldmp1@aol.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Your standard fish out of water story...except... It is constructed out of movie notions. This is unexpected from Glaser, who ranks among the hammiest of actors, and is known for seeing things in character based/TV realities. Bacon needs to score a recruiting coup (Glaser needs a hit movie). He is inspired by a 'movie', to undertake the quest, which is the movie. Along the way, he takes on a personal movie task of his own, which dovetails the two 'movies' together (he 'makes the cut' and joins the tribe). Clever stuff. I suspect that the producers seriously whittled this down, so the movie ideas would fit through what they perceived as half-open minds...it's a shame that young people can't be allowed to figure out the narratives for themselves. Glaser acknowledges this, by defending the tribe from the white missionary/elites, who are compelled to 'save the savages' from a hoodwinking. The natives out in the bush are noble, and the town natives are ignoble, guilty of the worst kind of frontier crime: cattle rustling, an old, old movie theme.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Warm, Heartfelt and Charming
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    heathentart
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/2/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I do so hate sports. I despise sports. My eyes glaze over when a sports game or show comes on. I don't talk about sports. This should give you an idea of my expectations of this movie. However, it was early morning, I was up with little to do, so I settled back, half in the hope it would send me to sleep. How wrong I was! I enjoy Kevin Bacon when he chooses good roles - and this isn't often the case. Not expecting much from its bland beginning, I was beginning to nod off when Kevin's character, Jimmy Dolan, arrived in Kenya in search of a young African man he spied on a documentary. Jimmy is an assistant coach for a university, and in order to save his job, needs to find the next basketball star. If you're a sports fan, there might be enough action in this to hold your attention. But if you're someone who enjoys heart, warmth, character and some of the most beautiful land ever caught on film, this movie will come to mean more to you. For me, the country of Kenya played a lead role. The depth and color of the culture made this film a rich, living tapestry of tradition butting heads with progress. Charles Gitanga Maina, as Saleh the prospective ball star, is breathtakingly handsome with a winsome sweetness that blasts from the screen. While this film was meant to be about Jimmy Dolan and his growth as a man and human being, it's also about remembering humanity's history and respecting it for itself. It's also about bowing to progress with dignity and respecting the rewards that it, too, can offer. Paul Michael Glaser proves - once more - that he can find the heart of a film and unwrap all its petals to reveal the core. He is a wonderful director. He must be, for I watched the challenge basketball game with my breath caught, my heart pounding and feeling all the joy of the people of the Winabi tribe. And I hate sports.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Light and really entertaining
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Isabelle Michelet
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/1/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Kenya -1990s. St Joe's basketball team is famous but runs into a double crisis. For one, the acclaimed coach is going to retire and must name his successor. Moreover, the team is in dire need of a hoop star. Jimmy Dolan, ex-player and deputy coach, has therefore no choice but to find the star: his career is at stake. On a short video of a mission in Winabi (Kenya), he sees the star he needs. How to get there, to identify the player and to convince him to go back to the USA with him will however be quite a challenge! The spectator should not expect anything remotely intellectual or an even slightly probable description of Africa. But Kevin Bacon is good and the movie hilarious at times. A very entertaining, light movie, which beyond the classical story of friendship between two young men of different cultures (for once not too patronizing), shows quite interesting scenes of beautiful basketball and demonstrates a bit the incredible cult Americans make of sports in the environment of what is supposed to be tertiary education.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Watchable film with a phenomenal Kevin Bacon as a basketball coach
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ma-cortes
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/12/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie talks upon an assistant basketball trainer called Jimmy Dolan(Kevin Bacon)who seeing a documentary observes an b-ball African player.Then he heads toward Africa hoping to recruit him in the biggest US team.He's a giant and talented called Saleh but doesn't want to leave the tribe because is the throne's heir.The tribe is constituted by a natives type Massai.Then they make a wager playing one team against another.Besides the protagonist will must surpass hardships proofs with purport of converting in warrior and can to play in tribe's team. The picture is an amused sports comedy with agreeable and likable interpretation of its principal starring.Argument sometimes is a little ridiculous and absurd and utilizes tired stereotypical however the film is entertained and funny.Besides there are a slight exposition about habits and customs of the tribe,where is seen as the cows are essential in their life and particulars ceremonies,rites,dances and marriage ceremony. Plus has an exciting and moving final tournament that is truly exciting ,being the end climatic game the highlight film. Jolly and lively music with African sound by David Newman. Glimmer and colorfully cinematography is by Dick Pope(Mike Leigh's photographer)as is reflected in spectacular African outdoors. The motion picture is accurately directed by Paul Michael Glaser(Starsky and Hutch).The flick will like to basketball interested. Rating :Average but bemused.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A humorous look at NCAA recruiting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ray-280
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/9/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    College coaches are known for going to great lengths to woo their recruits. They meet the family, the athlete, and try to present themselves as being just like them, with similar views and values. They kiss up to the parents while singing the praises of the fine institution which pays them. In Jimmy Dolan's (Kevin Bacon) case, his limits are tested when he finds a star player, Saleh (Charles Gitonga Maina) in a documentary video of an African school sponsored by an American. Once he sees Saleh, it's off to Kenya. In Kenya, Dolan meets with the predictable culture shock and skepticism/hostility from the locals, who wonder why a white guy from America would travel all the way to their land. He "befriends" the local nun/missionary, Sister Susan (Yolanda Vasquez), who advises him of the futility of trying to recruit the firstborn son of the tribe leader, who is duty-bound to his people. Enter an evil mining-company owner from a neighboring tribe who is trying to steal the Winabe tribe's lane, however, and the next thing we know, Dolan has joined the Winabe tribe (a swipe at American coaches who no doubt have bonded with their recruits in similar ways), and is their player-coach for the big game, a game where the Winabe land and Saleh's promise to play at St. Joe's if they win are on the line. Bacon captures Dolan's essence very well, as an unsympathetic character placed into a very sympathetic situation. The movie is his coming-of-age tale, as we watch him mature from self-centered assistant coach to full-fledged mentor.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Interesting Spin on a Great Theme
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MAStalling
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/7/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I loved this movie and watch it over and over. A real classic with reluctant heroes, bad guys, comic relief and very pertinent underlying morals. No sex, vulgarity or graphic violence. Just a great plot, good acting, great directing and gorgeous scenery. It contains all the elements I love in a movie that run you through the gamut of laughter, anger, sadness and joy. Paul Michael Glaser did a tremendous job in capturing the essence of Kenya and it's people. We visited Kenya last year and now I even enjoy the movie more, if that's possible. I don't think it's meant to be a side splitting comedy. Kevin Bacon's performance was great. You really believed he was an arrogant basketball coach with a superior attitude. It's wonderful what going back to the cradle of civilization will do towards humbling even the most haughty. I highly recommend this movie to anyone who wants a taste of a good quality flick.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This movie "Shakes and Bakes!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billshattner
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/3/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    So, without delving too deeply into the annals of "worst-to-first" sports movies, or counting off the multitude of "cultures in contact" stories, let me simply say this about the movie, "The Air Up There:" it succeeds, quite well in the mind of this critic, at what it sets out to accomplish. It is thematic, formulaic, and a tad predictable in parts, but none of that degrades its overall quality as a film. In fact, despite this movie getting lost somewhere in the recent history of film (and being overshadowed by similar movies such as "The Mighty Ducks"), I genuinely believe it to be the best movie of that genre, maybe ever, but certainly of this era. Now, I'm aware some of you might raise eyebrows at that statement, but let me elaborate; Not only is the scenery absolutely breathtaking, but all of the artistic design, costume styling, and cinematography is beautiful. On top of that, the story is engaging, regardless of one's ability to forecast the ending at any point. Additionally, the mere fact that themes such as maturation, redemption, independence, loyalty, "progress," and family all play central roles in this film, should qualify it is a deeper work of art than countless (sports) movies of today. Most significantly, this film contains something else that is occasionally lost in similar movies: DECENT ACTING. Say what you will about Kevin Bacon, or even this movie, but without a doubt, Kevin gives a wonderful, believable performance. He excellently displays the passion that is a prerequisite to be an athlete or coach in highly competitive sports such as College Athletics. Furthermore, the character Jimmy Dolan exhibits a wide gamut of emotions over the course of the story, and Mr. Bacon plays this perfectly. Interestingly, the best performance of the movie (and there are plenty of good ones: 'Kid' Sithole as Nyaga, Wilson Ntshona as Urudu, and Dikembe Mutombo's brother, Ilo, as Mifundo) comes not from Bacon, but from Charles Gitonga Maina, who inexplicably, has only appeared in one episode of SeaQuest DSV since this movie was made. He is immensely likable, charming, and completely believable as a star basketball player (after all, he was a world class sprinter in real life!) from a humble village. Truly, his performance is absolutely spectacular, even when placed within the context of the other stellar performances in the movie. Is this movie perfect, devoid of all stereotypes and patronizing cinematic techniques? No. And yet, nothing is lost because of that fact. As it was over a decade ago, it remains a wonderful, adventurous, heart-warming movie, one that deserves a far more solid place in cinematic history than it has been relegated to. I, for one, love this movie, and usually watch it a couple times a year, enjoying it every bit as much with each successive viewing (in fact, I feel the truth of the matter is, I enjoy this film MORE with each successive watching, as I continue to find noteworthy facets every time). In summation, I implore you to do yourself a favor: the next time you're feeling depressed, inadequate, or entirely stressed, rent or buy this movie, and watch it. I guarantee, you won't be able to make it to the end without a smile finding it's way onto your face.... :D
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    great movie!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    aaginadi
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/9/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I loved this movie. It is one of my favorite movies of all time. Charle Gitonga Maina (Saleh) is absolutely gorgeous! My favorite line is "Are you very sad Jimmy Dolan?" I say this to my husband whose name is Jimmy also, whenever he is upset or mad at me. It always makes us laugh. I have watched this movie at least 25 times although my husband swears it is 125! The little kid that is looking through the window in the clinic is so darn cute, too I loved it all!The man that runs the town is someone you would love to hate and I am glad when Saleh's brother leaves him. The pawn shop part of the movie is very good. I also liked Saleh's father.It is an excellent family movie, I encouraged my grand kids to watch it. Kevin Bacon is a good sport in this movie, it made me like him.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    way up
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/4/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As someone who's never really been into sports, "The Air Up There" hardly seems like the sort of movie that I would like, but I did. When basketball talent scout Jimmy Dolan (Kevin Bacon) goes to Kenya to recruit a new player, he ends up finding Saleh, a chief's son whose skills exceed what anyone could have imagined. But before he moves to the states, there are some things that both sides are going to have to deal with. This movie is interesting mainly for two reasons: it's good to see a sports movie that's not all about machismo, and a movie that looks at Kenyan culture (not one that we usually get to see). The movie isn't really any kind of masterpiece, but it never pretends to be one. There are some scenes that look like they were thrown in for comic relief (namely the goat milk). Pretty interesting.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Lightweight Fare Is Just That: Fair (as in "mediocre")
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ccthemovieman-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/3/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Kevin Bacon totally dominates this film. In fact, he's the only "name" actor in it. You won't recognize anybody else in here. The story is lightweight entertainment with the most notable aspect being the African music, which is very good and a small tour of Kenya, which is interesting, both with beauty and poverty. Bacon plays as basketball assistant coach, an ex-point guard, who goes to Africa to recruit this great player "Saleh" (Charles Gitangra Marina) for his team back in the States. The adventures of the trip pretty much are the story. One negative: another irreverent slam to get a few cheap laughs at the Catholic church. A nun in here uses profanity and gives Bacon a big kiss on the lips. It's one more example of trying to make clerical people appear worldly like the rest of us.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Two Movies
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jldmp1 (jldmp1@aol.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Your standard fish out of water story...except... It is constructed out of movie notions. This is unexpected from Glaser, who ranks among the hammiest of actors, and is known for seeing things in character based/TV realities. Bacon needs to score a recruiting coup (Glaser needs a hit movie). He is inspired by a 'movie', to undertake the quest, which is the movie. Along the way, he takes on a personal movie task of his own, which dovetails the two 'movies' together (he 'makes the cut' and joins the tribe). Clever stuff. I suspect that the producers seriously whittled this down, so the movie ideas would fit through what they perceived as half-open minds...it's a shame that young people can't be allowed to figure out the narratives for themselves. Glaser acknowledges this, by defending the tribe from the white missionary/elites, who are compelled to 'save the savages' from a hoodwinking. The natives out in the bush are noble, and the town natives are ignoble, guilty of the worst kind of frontier crime: cattle rustling, an old, old movie theme.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Warm, Heartfelt and Charming
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    heathentart
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/2/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I do so hate sports. I despise sports. My eyes glaze over when a sports game or show comes on. I don't talk about sports. This should give you an idea of my expectations of this movie. However, it was early morning, I was up with little to do, so I settled back, half in the hope it would send me to sleep. How wrong I was! I enjoy Kevin Bacon when he chooses good roles - and this isn't often the case. Not expecting much from its bland beginning, I was beginning to nod off when Kevin's character, Jimmy Dolan, arrived in Kenya in search of a young African man he spied on a documentary. Jimmy is an assistant coach for a university, and in order to save his job, needs to find the next basketball star. If you're a sports fan, there might be enough action in this to hold your attention. But if you're someone who enjoys heart, warmth, character and some of the most beautiful land ever caught on film, this movie will come to mean more to you. For me, the country of Kenya played a lead role. The depth and color of the culture made this film a rich, living tapestry of tradition butting heads with progress. Charles Gitanga Maina, as Saleh the prospective ball star, is breathtakingly handsome with a winsome sweetness that blasts from the screen. While this film was meant to be about Jimmy Dolan and his growth as a man and human being, it's also about remembering humanity's history and respecting it for itself. It's also about bowing to progress with dignity and respecting the rewards that it, too, can offer. Paul Michael Glaser proves - once more - that he can find the heart of a film and unwrap all its petals to reveal the core. He is a wonderful director. He must be, for I watched the challenge basketball game with my breath caught, my heart pounding and feeling all the joy of the people of the Winabi tribe. And I hate sports.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Light and really entertaining
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Isabelle Michelet
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/1/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Kenya -1990s. St Joe's basketball team is famous but runs into a double crisis. For one, the acclaimed coach is going to retire and must name his successor. Moreover, the team is in dire need of a hoop star. Jimmy Dolan, ex-player and deputy coach, has therefore no choice but to find the star: his career is at stake. On a short video of a mission in Winabi (Kenya), he sees the star he needs. How to get there, to identify the player and to convince him to go back to the USA with him will however be quite a challenge! The spectator should not expect anything remotely intellectual or an even slightly probable description of Africa. But Kevin Bacon is good and the movie hilarious at times. A very entertaining, light movie, which beyond the classical story of friendship between two young men of different cultures (for once not too patronizing), shows quite interesting scenes of beautiful basketball and demonstrates a bit the incredible cult Americans make of sports in the environment of what is supposed to be tertiary education.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Watchable film with a phenomenal Kevin Bacon as a basketball coach
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ma-cortes
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/12/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie talks upon an assistant basketball trainer called Jimmy Dolan(Kevin Bacon)who seeing a documentary observes an b-ball African player.Then he heads toward Africa hoping to recruit him in the biggest US team.He's a giant and talented called Saleh but doesn't want to leave the tribe because is the throne's heir.The tribe is constituted by a natives type Massai.Then they make a wager playing one team against another.Besides the protagonist will must surpass hardships proofs with purport of converting in warrior and can to play in tribe's team. The picture is an amused sports comedy with agreeable and likable interpretation of its principal starring.Argument sometimes is a little ridiculous and absurd and utilizes tired stereotypical however the film is entertained and funny.Besides there are a slight exposition about habits and customs of the tribe,where is seen as the cows are essential in their life and particulars ceremonies,rites,dances and marriage ceremony. Plus has an exciting and moving final tournament that is truly exciting ,being the end climatic game the highlight film. Jolly and lively music with African sound by David Newman. Glimmer and colorfully cinematography is by Dick Pope(Mike Leigh's photographer)as is reflected in spectacular African outdoors. The motion picture is accurately directed by Paul Michael Glaser(Starsky and Hutch).The flick will like to basketball interested. Rating :Average but bemused.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A humorous look at NCAA recruiting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ray-280
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/9/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    College coaches are known for going to great lengths to woo their recruits. They meet the family, the athlete, and try to present themselves as being just like them, with similar views and values. They kiss up to the parents while singing the praises of the fine institution which pays them. In Jimmy Dolan's (Kevin Bacon) case, his limits are tested when he finds a star player, Saleh (Charles Gitonga Maina) in a documentary video of an African school sponsored by an American. Once he sees Saleh, it's off to Kenya. In Kenya, Dolan meets with the predictable culture shock and skepticism/hostility from the locals, who wonder why a white guy from America would travel all the way to their land. He "befriends" the local nun/missionary, Sister Susan (Yolanda Vasquez), who advises him of the futility of trying to recruit the firstborn son of the tribe leader, who is duty-bound to his people. Enter an evil mining-company owner from a neighboring tribe who is trying to steal the Winabe tribe's lane, however, and the next thing we know, Dolan has joined the Winabe tribe (a swipe at American coaches who no doubt have bonded with their recruits in similar ways), and is their player-coach for the big game, a game where the Winabe land and Saleh's promise to play at St. Joe's if they win are on the line. Bacon captures Dolan's essence very well, as an unsympathetic character placed into a very sympathetic situation. The movie is his coming-of-age tale, as we watch him mature from self-centered assistant coach to full-fledged mentor.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Interesting Spin on a Great Theme
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MAStalling
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/7/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I loved this movie and watch it over and over. A real classic with reluctant heroes, bad guys, comic relief and very pertinent underlying morals. No sex, vulgarity or graphic violence. Just a great plot, good acting, great directing and gorgeous scenery. It contains all the elements I love in a movie that run you through the gamut of laughter, anger, sadness and joy. Paul Michael Glaser did a tremendous job in capturing the essence of Kenya and it's people. We visited Kenya last year and now I even enjoy the movie more, if that's possible. I don't think it's meant to be a side splitting comedy. Kevin Bacon's performance was great. You really believed he was an arrogant basketball coach with a superior attitude. It's wonderful what going back to the cradle of civilization will do towards humbling even the most haughty. I highly recommend this movie to anyone who wants a taste of a good quality flick.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    This movie "Shakes and Bakes!"
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    billshattner
   </autor>
   <data>
    28/3/2007
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    So, without delving too deeply into the annals of "worst-to-first" sports movies, or counting off the multitude of "cultures in contact" stories, let me simply say this about the movie, "The Air Up There:" it succeeds, quite well in the mind of this critic, at what it sets out to accomplish. It is thematic, formulaic, and a tad predictable in parts, but none of that degrades its overall quality as a film. In fact, despite this movie getting lost somewhere in the recent history of film (and being overshadowed by similar movies such as "The Mighty Ducks"), I genuinely believe it to be the best movie of that genre, maybe ever, but certainly of this era. Now, I'm aware some of you might raise eyebrows at that statement, but let me elaborate; Not only is the scenery absolutely breathtaking, but all of the artistic design, costume styling, and cinematography is beautiful. On top of that, the story is engaging, regardless of one's ability to forecast the ending at any point. Additionally, the mere fact that themes such as maturation, redemption, independence, loyalty, "progress," and family all play central roles in this film, should qualify it is a deeper work of art than countless (sports) movies of today. Most significantly, this film contains something else that is occasionally lost in similar movies: DECENT ACTING. Say what you will about Kevin Bacon, or even this movie, but without a doubt, Kevin gives a wonderful, believable performance. He excellently displays the passion that is a prerequisite to be an athlete or coach in highly competitive sports such as College Athletics. Furthermore, the character Jimmy Dolan exhibits a wide gamut of emotions over the course of the story, and Mr. Bacon plays this perfectly. Interestingly, the best performance of the movie (and there are plenty of good ones: 'Kid' Sithole as Nyaga, Wilson Ntshona as Urudu, and Dikembe Mutombo's brother, Ilo, as Mifundo) comes not from Bacon, but from Charles Gitonga Maina, who inexplicably, has only appeared in one episode of SeaQuest DSV since this movie was made. He is immensely likable, charming, and completely believable as a star basketball player (after all, he was a world class sprinter in real life!) from a humble village. Truly, his performance is absolutely spectacular, even when placed within the context of the other stellar performances in the movie. Is this movie perfect, devoid of all stereotypes and patronizing cinematic techniques? No. And yet, nothing is lost because of that fact. As it was over a decade ago, it remains a wonderful, adventurous, heart-warming movie, one that deserves a far more solid place in cinematic history than it has been relegated to. I, for one, love this movie, and usually watch it a couple times a year, enjoying it every bit as much with each successive viewing (in fact, I feel the truth of the matter is, I enjoy this film MORE with each successive watching, as I continue to find noteworthy facets every time). In summation, I implore you to do yourself a favor: the next time you're feeling depressed, inadequate, or entirely stressed, rent or buy this movie, and watch it. I guarantee, you won't be able to make it to the end without a smile finding it's way onto your face.... :D
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    great movie!
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    aaginadi
   </autor>
   <data>
    6/9/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I loved this movie. It is one of my favorite movies of all time. Charle Gitonga Maina (Saleh) is absolutely gorgeous! My favorite line is "Are you very sad Jimmy Dolan?" I say this to my husband whose name is Jimmy also, whenever he is upset or mad at me. It always makes us laugh. I have watched this movie at least 25 times although my husband swears it is 125! The little kid that is looking through the window in the clinic is so darn cute, too I loved it all!The man that runs the town is someone you would love to hate and I am glad when Saleh's brother leaves him. The pawn shop part of the movie is very good. I also liked Saleh's father.It is an excellent family movie, I encouraged my grand kids to watch it. Kevin Bacon is a good sport in this movie, it made me like him.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    way up
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Lee Eisenberg (eisenberg.lee@gmail.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/4/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    As someone who's never really been into sports, "The Air Up There" hardly seems like the sort of movie that I would like, but I did. When basketball talent scout Jimmy Dolan (Kevin Bacon) goes to Kenya to recruit a new player, he ends up finding Saleh, a chief's son whose skills exceed what anyone could have imagined. But before he moves to the states, there are some things that both sides are going to have to deal with. This movie is interesting mainly for two reasons: it's good to see a sports movie that's not all about machismo, and a movie that looks at Kenyan culture (not one that we usually get to see). The movie isn't really any kind of masterpiece, but it never pretends to be one. There are some scenes that look like they were thrown in for comic relief (namely the goat milk). Pretty interesting.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Lightweight Fare Is Just That: Fair (as in "mediocre")
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ccthemovieman-1
   </autor>
   <data>
    29/3/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Kevin Bacon totally dominates this film. In fact, he's the only "name" actor in it. You won't recognize anybody else in here. The story is lightweight entertainment with the most notable aspect being the African music, which is very good and a small tour of Kenya, which is interesting, both with beauty and poverty. Bacon plays as basketball assistant coach, an ex-point guard, who goes to Africa to recruit this great player "Saleh" (Charles Gitangra Marina) for his team back in the States. The adventures of the trip pretty much are the story. One negative: another irreverent slam to get a few cheap laughs at the Catholic church. A nun in here uses profanity and gives Bacon a big kiss on the lips. It's one more example of trying to make clerical people appear worldly like the rest of us.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Two Movies
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    jldmp1 (jldmp1@aol.com)
   </autor>
   <data>
    19/2/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Your standard fish out of water story...except... It is constructed out of movie notions. This is unexpected from Glaser, who ranks among the hammiest of actors, and is known for seeing things in character based/TV realities. Bacon needs to score a recruiting coup (Glaser needs a hit movie). He is inspired by a 'movie', to undertake the quest, which is the movie. Along the way, he takes on a personal movie task of his own, which dovetails the two 'movies' together (he 'makes the cut' and joins the tribe). Clever stuff. I suspect that the producers seriously whittled this down, so the movie ideas would fit through what they perceived as half-open minds...it's a shame that young people can't be allowed to figure out the narratives for themselves. Glaser acknowledges this, by defending the tribe from the white missionary/elites, who are compelled to 'save the savages' from a hoodwinking. The natives out in the bush are noble, and the town natives are ignoble, guilty of the worst kind of frontier crime: cattle rustling, an old, old movie theme.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Warm, Heartfelt and Charming
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    heathentart
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/2/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I do so hate sports. I despise sports. My eyes glaze over when a sports game or show comes on. I don't talk about sports. This should give you an idea of my expectations of this movie. However, it was early morning, I was up with little to do, so I settled back, half in the hope it would send me to sleep. How wrong I was! I enjoy Kevin Bacon when he chooses good roles - and this isn't often the case. Not expecting much from its bland beginning, I was beginning to nod off when Kevin's character, Jimmy Dolan, arrived in Kenya in search of a young African man he spied on a documentary. Jimmy is an assistant coach for a university, and in order to save his job, needs to find the next basketball star. If you're a sports fan, there might be enough action in this to hold your attention. But if you're someone who enjoys heart, warmth, character and some of the most beautiful land ever caught on film, this movie will come to mean more to you. For me, the country of Kenya played a lead role. The depth and color of the culture made this film a rich, living tapestry of tradition butting heads with progress. Charles Gitanga Maina, as Saleh the prospective ball star, is breathtakingly handsome with a winsome sweetness that blasts from the screen. While this film was meant to be about Jimmy Dolan and his growth as a man and human being, it's also about remembering humanity's history and respecting it for itself. It's also about bowing to progress with dignity and respecting the rewards that it, too, can offer. Paul Michael Glaser proves - once more - that he can find the heart of a film and unwrap all its petals to reveal the core. He is a wonderful director. He must be, for I watched the challenge basketball game with my breath caught, my heart pounding and feeling all the joy of the people of the Winabi tribe. And I hate sports.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Light and really entertaining
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    Isabelle Michelet
   </autor>
   <data>
    14/1/2006
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    Kenya -1990s. St Joe's basketball team is famous but runs into a double crisis. For one, the acclaimed coach is going to retire and must name his successor. Moreover, the team is in dire need of a hoop star. Jimmy Dolan, ex-player and deputy coach, has therefore no choice but to find the star: his career is at stake. On a short video of a mission in Winabi (Kenya), he sees the star he needs. How to get there, to identify the player and to convince him to go back to the USA with him will however be quite a challenge! The spectator should not expect anything remotely intellectual or an even slightly probable description of Africa. But Kevin Bacon is good and the movie hilarious at times. A very entertaining, light movie, which beyond the classical story of friendship between two young men of different cultures (for once not too patronizing), shows quite interesting scenes of beautiful basketball and demonstrates a bit the incredible cult Americans make of sports in the environment of what is supposed to be tertiary education.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    Watchable film with a phenomenal Kevin Bacon as a basketball coach
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ma-cortes
   </autor>
   <data>
    30/12/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    The movie talks upon an assistant basketball trainer called Jimmy Dolan(Kevin Bacon)who seeing a documentary observes an b-ball African player.Then he heads toward Africa hoping to recruit him in the biggest US team.He's a giant and talented called Saleh but doesn't want to leave the tribe because is the throne's heir.The tribe is constituted by a natives type Massai.Then they make a wager playing one team against another.Besides the protagonist will must surpass hardships proofs with purport of converting in warrior and can to play in tribe's team. The picture is an amused sports comedy with agreeable and likable interpretation of its principal starring.Argument sometimes is a little ridiculous and absurd and utilizes tired stereotypical however the film is entertained and funny.Besides there are a slight exposition about habits and customs of the tribe,where is seen as the cows are essential in their life and particulars ceremonies,rites,dances and marriage ceremony. Plus has an exciting and moving final tournament that is truly exciting ,being the end climatic game the highlight film. Jolly and lively music with African sound by David Newman. Glimmer and colorfully cinematography is by Dick Pope(Mike Leigh's photographer)as is reflected in spectacular African outdoors. The motion picture is accurately directed by Paul Michael Glaser(Starsky and Hutch).The flick will like to basketball interested. Rating :Average but bemused.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    A humorous look at NCAA recruiting
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    ray-280
   </autor>
   <data>
    18/9/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    College coaches are known for going to great lengths to woo their recruits. They meet the family, the athlete, and try to present themselves as being just like them, with similar views and values. They kiss up to the parents while singing the praises of the fine institution which pays them. In Jimmy Dolan's (Kevin Bacon) case, his limits are tested when he finds a star player, Saleh (Charles Gitonga Maina) in a documentary video of an African school sponsored by an American. Once he sees Saleh, it's off to Kenya. In Kenya, Dolan meets with the predictable culture shock and skepticism/hostility from the locals, who wonder why a white guy from America would travel all the way to their land. He "befriends" the local nun/missionary, Sister Susan (Yolanda Vasquez), who advises him of the futility of trying to recruit the firstborn son of the tribe leader, who is duty-bound to his people. Enter an evil mining-company owner from a neighboring tribe who is trying to steal the Winabe tribe's lane, however, and the next thing we know, Dolan has joined the Winabe tribe (a swipe at American coaches who no doubt have bonded with their recruits in similar ways), and is their player-coach for the big game, a game where the Winabe land and Saleh's promise to play at St. Joe's if they win are on the line. Bacon captures Dolan's essence very well, as an unsympathetic character placed into a very sympathetic situation. The movie is his coming-of-age tale, as we watch him mature from self-centered assistant coach to full-fledged mentor.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
  <review>
   <titulo>
    An Interesting Spin on a Great Theme
   </titulo>
   <autor>
    MAStalling
   </autor>
   <data>
    21/7/2005
   </data>
   <conteudo>
    I loved this movie and watch it over and over. A real classic with reluctant heroes, bad guys, comic relief and very pertinent underlying morals. No sex, vulgarity or graphic violence. Just a great plot, good acting, great directing and gorgeous scenery. It contains all the elements I love in a movie that run you through the gamut of laughter, anger, sadness and joy. Paul Michael Glaser did a tremendous job in capturing the essence of Kenya and it's people. We visited Kenya last year and now I even enjoy the movie more, if that's possible. I don't think it's meant to be a side splitting comedy. Kevin Bacon's performance was great. You really believed he was an arrogant basketball coach with a superior attitude. It's wonderful what going back to the cradle of civilization will do towards humbling even the most haughty. I highly recommend this movie to anyone who wants a taste of a good quality flick.
   </conteudo>
  </review>
 </reviews>
</filme>
